<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10051</id><name>PaRappa the Rapper 2</name><description>PaRappa the Rapper 2 is the sequel the Playstation's quirky music-rhythm game. The game continues the story of the lovable dog PaRappa and his girlfriend Sunny Funny. The gameplay uses timed button presses that are shown on a line at the top of the screen. The "Instructor" in each level will show you what buttons to press at each time and then you must copy him or her as close as possible. Another large feature of the game is the ability to freestyle. Instead of copying your instructor, you can press any combination of buttons that are in rhythm. The result of free styling can increase your in-game grade, which ranges from awful to cool. The only way to achieve the highest level, Cool, is to freestyle in rhythm. The story is about PaRappa winning a contest in which the prize is a lifetime supply of noodles. After having so many noodles, he is now very sick of them and wishes to eat another food. When his girlfriend Sunny makes him noodles, he runs away from her house and into the city. This sparks an inner conflict PaRappa has throughout the game about what it takes to be a man. Meanwhile, an evil villain is turning all of the world's foods into noodles, and it's up to PaRappa, his friend PJ, Sunny, and many more to save the world from "Noodlization". The game was not as well received as the original when it was released in January 2002. The complaint was that the sole game mechanic was becoming dated and the sequel did not change this mechanic enough. This was the last original PaRappa game that was created.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9860">Rock Band</game><game id="21422">Cool Cool Toon</game><game id="7919">Spice World</game><game id="20872">Battle of the Bands</game><game id="20714">Rock Band 2</game><game id="14916">Guitar Hero II</game><game id="6311">Guitar Hero</game><game id="20635">Rock Revolution</game><game id="4031">Guitar Hero III: Legends of Rock</game><game id="20673">Guitar Hero World Tour</game><game id="2520">Donkey Konga</game><game id="19832">Donkey Konga 2</game><game id="7907">Donkey Konga 3: Tabe-houdai! Haru Mogitate 50 Kyoku</game><game id="21099">Wii Music</game><game id="19513">Bust A Groove</game><game id="2873">Bust a Groove 2</game><game id="7466">Space Channel 5</game><game id="113">Space Channel 5: Part 2</game><game id="25988">Cool Cool Jam</game><game id="30838">TVDJ</game><game id="35917">Gitaroo Man Lives!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1881079-box_parappa2.png</image></root>