<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10081</id><name>Tekken</name><description>PlotHeihachi Mishima is the ruthless owner of the multi-national Mishima Zaibatsu company. He announces to the world the beginning of the first King of Iron Fist Tournament, with a prize reward of one billion dollars. 8 of the finest competitors in the world arrive to take part in the tournament. One of them, Heihachi's own son Kazuya, is not drawn towards the enormous cash reward but is fueled by revenge.When Kazuya was five years old Heihachi cast him from the top of a cliff, as he wanted to judge the power and determination of his son. Kazuya indeed survived the fall but it left a deep scar on his chest. Kazuya's blood loss would have proven fatal had the Devil not shown up to offer him the chance to seek revenge on his father in exchange for his soul. 21 years later and Kazuya is an undefeated fighting champion, he hears about the existence of his father's tournament and considers this his opportunity to seek revenge.GameplayTekken immediately sets itself apart from most other fighting games with its button scheme. Whereas most fighting game control schemes have different buttons corresponding to the power of the attacks (such as strong kick or light punch), in Tekken, each button corresponds with a limb (square for left punch, circle for right kick, ect.). Like most fighting games, there is a default setting of two rounds per match, and Tekken consists of the usual 1 on 1 combat found in fighting games, where you win after you deplete your opponents health bar. The player can get a "perfect" if they win a round without suffering any damage, a "great" if they win a round with a health bar that had less then about 5% health left and double K.O.'s can also occur. If the time limit expires (usually 60 seconds), the player with the least health loses.CharactersThe default cast of eight characters in the original Tekken were:Kazuya MishimaPaul PhoenixNina WilliamsYoshimitsuMarshall LawJackKingMichelle ChangUnlockable CharactersLee ChaolanAnna WilliamsGanryuDevilHeihachi MishimaKunimistuArmor KingPrototype JackWang JinreiKumaLocationsKing George IslandMarine StadiumAngkor WatVeneziaAcropolisMonument ValleyWindermereChicagoSzechwanFijiKyoto</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5238">Battle Arena Toshinden</game><game id="20678">Soulcalibur IV</game><game id="19738">Bloody Roar</game><game id="6153">Soul Blade</game><game id="12411">Soulcalibur</game><game id="7792">Dead or Alive 4</game><game id="41">Virtua Fighter 2</game><game id="15584">Virtua Fighter</game><game id="3839">Dead or Alive</game><game id="10872">Wu-Tang: Shaolin Style</game><game id="2895">Battle Arena Toshinden 3</game><game id="10651">Mortal Kombat: Unchained</game><game id="3760">Street Fighter: The Movie</game><game id="9603">Star Wars: Masters of Teräs Käsi</game><game id="19043">Fighters Megamix</game><game id="2045">Dead or Alive 2</game><game id="21878">Tobal No. 1</game><game id="22305">Street Fighter III: 2nd Impact</game><game id="11065">Shaman King: Power of Spirit</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="16842">Street Fighter: Anniversary Collection</game><game id="13753">Dead or Alive Ultimate</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="22895">Godzilla Kaiju Daikessen</game><game id="23220">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja</game><game id="22519">Naruto: Uzumaki Chronicles 2</game><game id="23007">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja Heroes</game><game id="21582">Naruto Shippuuden: Gekitou Ninja Taisen! EX 2</game><game id="23368">Ranma 1/2 Battle Renaissance</game><game id="18645">Dragon Ball GT: Final Bout</game><game id="9658">Dynasty Warriors</game><game id="10126">X-Men: Next Dimension</game><game id="3965">X-Men: Mutant Academy 2</game><game id="383">Mortal Kombat: Deception</game><game id="13875">Plasma Sword: Nightmare of Bilstein</game><game id="21277">Ultimate Mortal Kombat</game><game id="25109">Dragonball: Evolution</game><game id="13172">Fighters Destiny</game><game id="31276">Yusha - Heaven's Gate</game><game id="31109">Kinnikuman Muscle Grand Prix MAX</game><game id="6409">Kensei: Sacred Fist</game><game id="12862">Zero Divide</game><game id="11081">FX Fighter</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1791096-box_t1.png</image></root>