<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10097</id><name>Worms 2</name><description>OverviewThe annelid carnage continues unabated.As the direct sequel to Team 17's wacky strategic artillery game, Worms, Worms 2 continues the original's tradition of turn-based invertebrate violence, outlandish locales, and bizarre weaponry. The most immediately apparent difference between Worms 2 and its predecessors is its visuals, which were entirely redone in order to give it a lighthearted hand-animated look that provides a direct contrast to the non-stop carnage that the Worms series traffics in. This art style would later come to be one of the signatures of the Worms franchise, being adopted for use in all future Worms titles. Outside of its graphical overhaul, Worms 2 remains a game very much in keeping with the spirit of mayhem and zaniness found in previous Worms releases, though it is notable in its own right for being the first Worms game to include an online multiplayer component. Most of the original game's armaments, like the Banana Bomb and the Concrete Donkey, to name just a few, make their triumphant return in Worms 2, though they are also accompanied by a fair number of new additions. As always, the objective of Worms is simply to use the weapons and tools at one's disposal more effectively than one's opponent (or opponents), with the ultimate goal of becoming the undisputed master of the small patch of land on which the opposing teams faced off.GameplayGameplay in an average Worms 2 match consists of encounters between two or more teams of worms, with each player controlling a single team. Using a sequence determined randomly at the beginning of the match, players take turns engaging one another with the objective of killing all non-allied worms. Only one worm can be moved in each turn, and it is the player's primary goal to use this worm together with the implements at hand to harm and ideally kill as many enemy worms as possible. In addition to squirming and jumping, various other forms of locomotion (Ninja Ropes, Teleports) are available to the player in order to move about the two-dimensional field of play. Once a worm has attacked, taken damage, or expended their allotted turn time, their turn ends, and the next player's turn begins. New weapons and additional health may often be found in the environment, as well as extra hazards like mines and oil drums. If at any point only a single player's worms are left standing, gameplay ends and the remaining team is declared the winner.The Concrete Donkey lays waste to two Red Team worms.All worms begin each match with equal health, represented as a number value over each worm's head which is reduced by weapon attacks, fall damage, or environmental hazards. If a worm's health reaches zero, it will fall to the ground and explode, a process which can harm nearby worms and also leaves behind a headstone in place of the former worm which can also explode if it takes enough damage. Other than health depletion, a worm can be killed instantly regardless of health by being knocked into the water or outside the boundaries of the map. Falling off of the map becomes more of a danger as matches progress, as almost all weapons will cause permanent deformation to the terrain which gradually reduces the size of the playing field. While it is clearly a game intended to be played with other people, Worms 2 does also contain the ability to engage in skirmishes with computer-controlled opponents as well as a rudimentary single-player campaign which consists of a procession of scenarios with unique challenges and weapon configurations. The game includes no ability to save one's campaign progress, instead opting for a password system which allows any scenario to be played at any time by inputting the associated code. Though the opponent worm artificial intelligence is very skilled in some areas (such as preternatural ability with the Bazooka and Grenades), it is fairly inconsistent in its propensity to fully capitalize on advantageous situations, which means an experienced human foe will usually present a far greater challenge.CustomizationWorms 2 is an extremely customizable experience, allowing players to alter a large number of variables affecting different aspects of the game. Some of these variables, such as worm names and voices, have little or no impact on gameplay, while others yield noticeable effects. Any changes that a player makes to gameplay can be saved as a scheme in order to be easily accessed later on. Schemes are further divided into weapon schemes and option schemes. Weapon schemes represent not only what quantity and variety of weapons players will start with, but also governs how weapons behave and dictates other weapon-related statistics such as the probability of certain armaments appearing in crates. Option schemes represent any gameplay variable not directly relating to weapons. An option scheme determines the length of players' turns, for instance, as well as crate drop rates and the specifics of how Sudden Death plays out, among many other things.Worms 2's terrain editorWhile the game's maps can be randomly generated in order to provide quick play with as much variety as possible, the player is also able to create their own custom environments using a terrain editor accessible through the main menu. From the editor, players are able to create the specific shape of a map which can then be populated with items and landmarks. Players can also choose to invert their map, which changes open areas to land masses, and vice versa. Several different terrain themes are available (as well as hidden ones from the original game), and water color may be changed as well. Worms 2 levels are classified as either an "Open" or a "Cavern" map. An "Open" map is any open-air level which contains one or more landmasses and no ceiling, while a "Cavern" map is generally a more enclosed space with an impenetrable barrier above it. The two are quite different from a gameplay perspective, as the utility of certain weapons can change quite dramatically based on the characteristics of the environment.WeaponsThe weapons of Worms 2, at a glanceWith combat being the entire focus of its gameplay, Worms 2 comes with an expansive arsenal to keep things from getting stale. These weapons have varying degrees of rarity, from the ordinary (Bazooka, Grenades) to the extremely uncommon (Concrete Donkey, Patsy's Magic Bullet). They range from the mundane to the fanciful, and from the mildly annoying to the extremely deadly. Some weapons may be locked until a certain number of rounds have passed, and the rarest types are typically only found in Weapon Crates. In addition to armaments, Worms 2 contains a number of mobility tools such as the Ninja Rope and Parachute that are essential for map traversal.Worms 2 features around 40 different weapons as well as a handful of movement utilities, some of which also double as weapons. Armaments are generally grouped by hotkey with other similar weapons (F1 for missiles, F2 for grenades, F3 for firearms, and so on.), making it fairly easy to cycle through all available weapons in a particular category. In addition to hotkeys, players can pull up a weapon panel at any time which displays a list of selectable icons representing all currently usable weapons. Weapons that are not currently usable but will become available for use during later turns appear in this menu as grayed out icons.BazookaBazookaOne of the series' standard armaments, the Bazooka is the quintessential skill-based weapon, with expert use requiring a solid grasp of its trajectory and how said trajectory is affected by wind. A player's proficiency with the Bazooka is often a good indicator of their overall Worms aptitude, and being that ammo for it is usually unlimited, having a solid amount of practice with it will pay dividends in countless scenarios where other less experienced players might be at a loss.Damage: Up to 50 HPHotkey: F1Homing MissileHoming MissileWhile certainly easier to deploy successfully at long range than the Bazooka, the Homing Missile is not the foolproof weapon it might seem to be. It requires a few moments in order to activate after being fired, and once it does the homing effect is somewhat gradual, requiring a fair amount of space for it to find its target. It is a fairly common practice on open-air maps to simply fire a Homing Missile high into the air where it will have ample space to arm and track its target.Damage: Up to 50 HPHotkey: F1 (2x)MortarMortarUnlike other weapons in its class, the Mortar does not have adjustable strength, instead being fired at full strength by default. The initial impact does relatively little damage, but it releases a number of explosive clusters thereafter that cause further injury. Trajectory is very important when firing, as it determines where these clusters will fall. In fact, it is in some cases preferable to fire at a point on the landscape rather than at an enemy so that its clusters will fly back at a favorable angle.Damage: Up to 20 HP per impactHotkey: F1 (3x)Homing PigeonHoming PigeonAn upgraded version of the Homing Missile, the Pigeon is both more powerful and more intelligent in seeking out its target. It will actively avoid terrain obstacles in its flight path, though it will fall to the ground and explode if it does not find its quarry quickly enough. It can still be confused by certain types of terrain, especially ones that involve long, complicated paths to its target, and it also cannot travel underwater, so it falls just short of being a fire-and-forget weapon.Damage: Up to 75 HPHotkey: F1 (4x)GrenadeGrenadeGrenade proficiency is a good indicator of player skill in much the same fashion as Bazooka aptitude. With an adjustable fuse duration and variable bounce settings, the Grenade can be used for everything from impressive and improbable trick shots to simple long fuse "drop-and-run" tactics. Grenades are not affected by wind, and expert players are known for adjusting their Grenade throws so that the explosion happens at the very instant they reach their target.Damage: Up to 50 HPHotkey: F2Cluster BombCluster BombThough potentially more devastating than a Grenade, the Cluster Bomb is in reality only advisable to use over a Grenade in very confined spaces, as otherwise its clusters are apt to spread over a large area, resulting in less damage to their target than a standard Grenade would have caused. Enemy worms that are trapped in a small hole are the ideal targets for the Cluster Bomb, though a peculiar glitch not present in later games can cause a Cluster Bomb and all clusters to explode immediately when placed directly upon a worm's head.Damage: Up to 20 HP per impactHotkey: F2 (2x)Banana BombBanana BombWorms' signature "Soft Fruit of Doom," the Banana Bomb is as powerful as it is unpredictable. It is in essence an extremely bouncy Cluster Bomb that explodes with the force of Dynamite once its fuse expires, releasing several equally powerful bananas afterward that explode on contact with the ground, causing destruction over a massive area. The Banana Bomb's potential radius of destruction is so large and its effects so erratic that it is advisable to be as far from the target area as possible when deploying it.Damage: Up to 75 HP per bananaHotkey: F2 (3x)Homing Cluster BombHoming Cluster BombUnlike regular Cluster Bombs, the Homing variant is best used in open areas where its clusters will have ample space to lock onto its target without risk of colliding with the environment. One common tactic is to hurl it straight into the air with a short fuse so that its clusters will rain down upon their target. In practice, the Homing Cluster Bomb is not so different from the Homing Missile, though its inherent fuse detonation allows for some trick shots that are not possible with the Homing Missile.Damage: Up to 20 HP per impactHotkey: F2 (4x)ShotgunShotgunWhile the individual blasts of the Shotgun are only moderately damaging, the true utility of the weapon is its ability to be used twice in a single turn. This has various tactical possibilities, such as attacking two different targets or attacking once before seeking cover. It is perhaps the easiest way to kill two badly damaged worms in one turn if they are not close together, and there are further tactical possibilities, such as creating a hole with the first shot that a worm will fall into with the subsequent shot.Damage: Up to 25 HP per shellHotkey: F3HandgunHandgunWhile not an efficient means of killing an opponent in and of itself, the Handgun has the advantage of a fair amount of accuracy and six individual shots. This can be used to slowly push an enemy worm toward an environmental hazard or off of a cliff. Though there are situations in which a Handgun might be ideally suited, it is more often than not used to taunt an opponent or to provide them with a particularly humiliating (and humorous) execution.Damage: Up to 5 HP per bulletHotkey: F3 (2x)UziUziFiring ten bullets in rapid fashion, the Uzi has higher potential damage than the Handgun. It is somewhat less accurate, unfortunately, and also cannot be aimed while firing, meaning that it has a significantly shorter effective range, though it can be used similarly to propel worms across terrain while also damaging them. In order to achieve maximum damage against one's target, it is important to make sure a target is pinned against the environment so that they are not propelled away from subsequent shots.Damage: Up to 5 HP per bulletHotkey: F3 (3x)MinigunMinigunUnloading an impressive twenty bullets in short order, the Minigun is essentially a beefed up Uzi. It can kill even a healthy worm under ideal circumstances, though if an opponent's back is not against a wall, it is very likely that the weapon's knock back will cause quite a few shots to miss their target. The force of the Minigun can propel worms a great distance, so it can also be used in some cases to knock worms into mines (or vice versa).Damage: Up to 5 HP per bulletHotkey: F3 (4x)Fire PunchFire PunchThough it does a respectable amount of damage, the primary attribute of the Fire Punch is the predictable trajectory in which it knocks its target. Since there will usually be more damaging means of attack, it is primarily used to knock worms into the water for an instant kill. Fire Punch can also be used while jumping, and has a fairly significant vertical reach as well, so it can be used effectively to strike worms perched above a player's worm.Damage: 30 HPHotkey: F4Dragon BallDragon BallThe Dragon Ball is very similar in use to the Fire Punch, though it sends its target much farther horizontally than vertically. If there are no obstructions blocking its trajectory, the Dragon Ball can send a worm into the water even if they are not particularly close to the edge of the map. As is the case with the Fire Punch, the Dragon Ball is not usually used to kill a target in and of itself, but in situations where it is advantageous to propel one's foe a great distance, it is quite useful.Damage: 30 HPHotkey: F4 (2x)KamikazeKamikazeAs one would expect, the Kamikaze attack results in the death of any worm who uses it. Before it goes, however, it can fly in any of eight directions, cutting through landscape and damaging any worm it touches before exploding to cause even more damage to those nearby. For obvious reasons, a player should only consider using this attack when their worm is nearly dead, or when the advantage its use creates far outweighs the loss of a worm.Damage: Up to 80 HPHotkey: F4 (3x)ProdProdThe Prod causes its user to give an adjacent worm a slight shove which causes no actual damage. Its only real use is on the rare occasion that a worm is standing dangerously close to a precipice, where it can be easily pushed into water, mines, or the like. Death by Prod is considered particularly humiliating, as it is viewed as a sign of the prodded player's incompetence at having left their own worm in such a compromising position to begin with.Damage: NoneHotkey: F4 (4x)DynamiteDynamiteWith high damage and a large area of effect, Dynamite's only real weakness is that it must be placed manually, potentially placing its user in a dangerous position. For this reason it is a frequent favorite for use with the Ninja Rope, where a hasty getaway can be staged to avoid the significant blast radius. Its power is such that most schemes give players very limited quantities of Dynamite (one stick, in most cases), thus forcing them to be very judicious with their use of it.Damage: Up to 75 HPHotkey: F5MineMineThe ostensible purpose of the Mine is to create persistent hazards and block off areas of the map. Sadly, randomly generated Mines do this better than player ones, as they have variable fuses that user Mines lack. Since players can therefore predict the behavior of other player's mines with complete accuracy, it becomes a trivial matter for a skilled player to disarm one without taking damage, thus relegating Mines to the status of an underpowered Dynamite substitute.Damage: Up to 50 HPHotkey: F5 (2x)SheepSheepSheep can be thought of as bouncing sticks of Dynamite. Once released, a Sheep will go forward, hopping up and down until the player presses the fire button again, at which point it explodes. Sheep will usually turn around when they reach a barrier, though they will sometimes continue to bounce at the obstruction instead. It is also worth noting that Sheep, like many other animal weapons, can pick up Weapon Crates on the player's behalf before going on to detonate.Damage: Up to 75 HPHotkey: F5 (3x)Super SheepSuper SheepReleasing a Super Sheep is initially no different than unleashing their normal counterpart. Rather than an explosion, however, pressing the fire button again sends the sheep flying into the air under the player's direct control, where they can be piloted into the user's target of choice. This essentially makes them into player-guided Homing Missiles. Super Sheep travel at a fairly rapid clip, so learning to successfully pilot them can take some practice, especially in enclosed environments.Damage: Up to 75 HPHotkey: F5 (4x)Air StrikeAir StrikeUpon selecting a target, an Air Strike drops a series of missiles in the vicinity of the targeted area. The Air Strike's angle of delivery can be changed to arc from either the left or right, which is an important factor to consider, as some targets may be more vulnerable from a particular angle. While useful, the presence of protective cover can make the Air Strike's results unreliable at best, and the weapon is useless on cavern maps, as are all strike weapons.Damage: Up to 30 HP per impactHotkey: F6Homing Air StrikeHoming Air StrikeA much more concentrated version of the Air Strike, a Homing Strike will funnel all of its missiles toward the player's target rather than spreading over a larger area. The targeted worm is almost always killed upon a direct hit due to the sheer number of explosions. The Homing Strike is much more predictable than a normal Air Strike, though the player has less control over its angle of delivery than they would have with a standard Homing Missile.Damage: Up to 30 HP per impactHotkey: F6 (2x)Napalm StrikeNapalm StrikeWhile the Napalm Strike starts out much like a normal Air Strike, its missiles explode shortly before reaching the ground, blanketing a wide area with fire. Not only does this cause considerable damage to worms caught within it, but it also is quite good at pushing worms off the map. The flames unleashed by the Napalm Strike are heavily influenced by wind conditions, so care should be taken in order to prevent the spread of fire to unintended areas.Damage: VariableHotkey: F6 (3x)Postal StrikePostal StrikeThe Postal Strike unleashes a number of powerful letter bombs that float at a somewhat leisurely pace toward the ground. While these letters are more powerful than normal strike missiles, they are also much more susceptible to wind conditions, requiring players to adjust their aim significantly depending on wind strength and direction. Particularly when dropped on a group of enemies, the Postal Strike can have a devastating effect.Damage: Up to 50 HP per impactHotkey: F6 (4x)Blow TorchBlow TorchWhile it can be used offensively (usually to disrespect one's opponent), the main use of the Blow Torch is to burrow a worm horizontally into the landscape either to hide or to reach a different part of the level. It can be angled upward, downward or in a straight horizontal line. The Blow Torch is one of the primary means of defending one's self in Worms 2, as dislodging a burrowed worm can be a lengthy, not to mention annoying, process.Damage: 15 HP minimumHotkey: F7DrillDrillEssentially a vertically oriented Blow Torch, the Drill heads straight down for a duration of five seconds. It has somewhat greater offensive potential than the Blow Torch, as a worm trapped in the hole created by the Drill can take a fair amount of damage, though it is still a utility first and foremost. Ideally the Drill should be used when no enemy worms are nearby, since having explosive ordinance dropped on one's head after drilling a hole is a fairly ignominious way to die.Damage: 15 HP minimumHotkey: F7 (2x)GirderGirderThe Girder is an adjustable piece of player created terrain that can serve a number of purposes. Placed directly over a worm, it can function as a shield against enemy fire, or it can also form a land bridge to reach previously inaccessible areas. A Girder can be rotated and positioned before being placed, and once it has been used it behaves exactly as any other piece of landscape would, and can therefore be destroyed by any normal weapon fire.Damage: NoneHotkey: F7 (3x)Baseball BatBaseball BatSimilarly to other melee weapons, the Baseball Bat is most frequently used when it will result in a kill, usually by knocking a player off the map. Unlike the Fire Punch and Dragon Ball, the trajectory can be controlled by the player to an extent by aiming up or down before swinging. Other than that, it has no inherent benefits over the aforementioned weapons. It is also a popular way to knock worms into Mines, or Mines into worms, if one is especially daring (or stupid).Damage: Up to 30 HPHotkey: F7 (4x)Ninja RopeNinja RopePerhaps the most important movement tool in the Worms series, the Ninja Rope increases in utility the more familiar a player is with its properties. It can be used to cover ground quite rapidly and to attack before retreating to a better position. For those who dedicate themselves to mastering the ways of the Ninja Rope, there is no corner of the map which they cannot reach, and no worm that is truly safe from their grasp.Damage: NoneHotkey: F8BungeeBungeeWhile equipped, the Bungee will automatically activate after a worm drops from a ledge. From there, it functions like a stretchy Ninja Rope complete with the option to drop weapons on enemies' heads. Though it is not quite as universally useful as the Ninja Rope, more advanced users can fling worms across the map or up to higher places with proper use of the Bungee, though this requires considerable proficiency to perform reliably.Damage: NoneHotkey: F8 (2x)ParachuteParachuteThe Parachute is used to glide gradually from a higher location. Weapons can also be dropped while gliding, which is considered a fairly advanced maneuver since the Parachute's path is not entirely under the player's control. Players can maneuver left or right while using it, however heavy winds can greatly impact its range of movement. Parachutes can be manually deployed, though if a user falls far enough with the Parachute equipped that they might sustain fall damage, it activates automatically.Damage: NoneHotkey: F8 (3x)TeleportTeleportThe Teleport transports a worm to any empty space on the map. It is the easiest and most versatile movement tool to use, though despite this it is generally advisable to use only when absolutely necessary, as it will immediately end the player's turn. Because of this, it is crucial to pick a spot to teleport to which will not leave one's worm vulnerable in the next turn. Often times, Teleports are used to obtain Weapon Crates or to escape near-certain death.Damage: NoneHotkey: F8 (4x)Super BananaSuper BananaThe Super Banana is functionally identical to the Banana Bomb save for a crucial difference: both the initial explosion and those of the subsequently released bananas can be directly triggered by the player, making for a significantly more predictable outcome with less chance of self-injury. Still, it is always prudent to be far away from the epicenter of the Super Banana's explosion, as the trajectories of the bananas it unleashes are hard to gauge.Damage: Up to 75 HP per bananaHotkey: F9Holy Hand GrenadeHoly Hand GrenadeThe Holy Hand Grenade, or HHG as it is often known, is a supremely powerful grenade-class weapon that leaves an incredibly large crater in its wake. It functions for the most part like a regular Grenade, though its fuse and bounce settings are fixed and it will detonate only when it has come to a complete stop. More so than most weapons, it is important to be nowhere near the HHG when it goes off, as the area of effect it produces is absolutely massive.Damage: Up to 100 HPHotkey: F9 (2x)Salvation ArmySalvation ArmyThe Salvation Army offers essentially a variation on the Old Lady, adding not only the ability to manually trigger her detonation, but also spreading a number of explosive tambourines in the aftermath, which gives her a significantly larger area of effect and multiplies her potential damage greatly over the Old Lady. She will explode after ten seconds if not otherwise detonated by the player, though this is more than enough time for her to reach her target in most scenarios.Damage: Up to 75 HP per impactHotkey: F9 (3x)MB BombMB BombA bizarre form of Air Strike, the MB Bomb delivers a single massive bomb from the sky, which floats gradually downward before causing a huge explosion. Due to the significant amount of time it spends in the air, wind conditions greatly affect the MB Bomb, requiring a substantial amount of foresight. In this respect it should be thought of as a variation on the Postal Strike, with one large explosive in place of several smaller ones.Damage: Up to 100 HPHotkey: F9 (4x)Petrol BombPetrol BombThe Petrol Bomb has only a modest explosion radius, though it spreads fire over the surrounding area. Due to fire's unpredictability, it is easiest to achieve high damage on worms who are trapped in confined spaces. The flames that are released when the Petrol Bomb bursts are quite susceptible to wind, which can potentially carry the bottle's contents away from its intended target. With some forethought, however, wind conditions can also be used to one's advantage.Damage: VariableHotkey: F10Priceless Ming VasePriceless Ming VaseThe Ming Vase is dropped at its target's feet much like Dynamite, with a five second timer allotted for the user's escape. Once it explodes, fragments of the vase break off similar to a Cluster Bomb, creating several ancillary explosions. It is somewhat of a rarity in most matches, though, as they are powerful tools capable of killing multiple worms when used correctly. Obtaining one in a Weapon Crate could easily change a team's fortunes.Damage: Up to 75 HP per impactHotkey: F10 (2x)Sheep StrikeSheep StrikeThe Sheep Strike is a very powerful strike weapon that hurls several sheep toward the targeted area. While the bouncing properties of its payload make it somewhat unpredictable, massive destruction is always the result. All sheep in the flock bounce a single time before exploding, and each member is comparable in force to a stick of Dynamite. With such an extreme likelihood of causing widespread chaos, group targets are of course preferred.Damage: Up to 75 HP per sheepHotkey: F10 (3x)Mike's Carpet BombMike's Carpet BombUnlike a real carpet bombing, Worms 2's Carpet Bomb drops several actual carpet rolls that bounce and explode multiple times. Like the Sheep Strike, the results are hard to predict with total accuracy, though destruction is always guaranteed. Unlike the Sheep Strike, which bounces once before exploding on second contact, each carpet roll unleashed by Mike's Carpet Bomb bounces five times, exploding each time it touches the ground.Damage: Up to 75 per impactHotkey: F10 (4x)Mad CowsMad CowsUsing this weapon releases between one and five Mad Cows in the direction the player is facing. Each cow will walk forward and explode on contact with an enemy or any other obstruction for that matter. A player's facing can be changed during use to release cows on either side, thereby attacking multiple foes. It is also possible to use the initial cows to blast through an environmental obstruction before blowing up a target on the other side with the remaining cows.Damage: Up to 75 HP per cowHotkey: F11Old LadyOld LadyThe Old Lady is in essence an ambulatory stick of Dynamite right down to the five second fuse. Since she can't be manually detonated, effective use requires either a knowledge on the player's part of exactly how far she can amble in that five second period or a confined space which she cannot escape from. Her behavior while walking forward is similar to that of the Mad Cow, but unlike cows, the Old Lady will never jump when faced with a drop.Damage: Up to 75 HPHotkey: F11 (2x)Cloned SheepCloned SheepThe Cloned Sheep weapon is a combination of the Mad Cows and regular Sheep. Up to five sheep may be released on either side of the player. While they look different, Cloned Sheep behave more or less like their normal counterparts, hopping along blissfully until they come across a suitable target to destroy. Players may not manually detonate them as they can with normal Sheep, instead controlling only the number of Sheep and the direction in which they are unleashed.Damage: Up to 75 HP per sheepHotkey: F11 (3x)Concrete DonkeyConcrete DonkeyWhile dropped from the air like any strike weapon, the effect of the Concrete Donkey is unlike any other weapon in the game. Once unleashed, it bounces up and down continuously, exploding each time it touches the terrain, simultaneously obliterating a large vertical section of the map and any worms within it. Few things in Worms 2 are feared more than the Concrete Donkey. Even worms burrowed deep underground are not safe from its destruction.Damage: Well over 100 HPHotkey: F11 (4x)Skip GoSkip GoSkip Go simply ends a player's turn without forcing them to attack or wait out the clock. While this might seem cowardly, it is often more advantageous to remain idle if it means that an enemy will be forced to expose their own worms. If a worm has no viable means to move or attack, Skip Go also helps to stave off the advance of Sudden Death, since any time remaining on the clock will not be deducted from the overall time when a player skips their turn.Damage: NoneHotkey: F12SurrenderSurrenderThough certainly not an advisable course of action, the white flag exists for any player wishing to cede a match to their opponent(s). In matches with more than two players, surrendered worms will persist an the map as cannon fodder for other players, though they will be stripped of any unique names they may have had and will be easily distinguishable from other worms by the white flags that they wave.Damage: NoneHotkey: F12 (2x)Nuclear BombNuclear BombThe Nuclear Bomb's only effect is to raise the map's water level significantly and permanently. For reasons that should be readily apparent, this is only really useful if there happen to be one or more enemy worms near the water line, and likewise its use should be avoided at all costs when a player has worms of their own near the water's edge. The Nuke is encountered so rarely that many players may simply fail to account for it, especially if Sudden Death is not enabled.Damage: NoneHotkey: F12 (3x)Patsy's Magic BulletPatsy's Magic BulletThe ultimate in worm-seeking weaponry, Patsy's Magic Bullet is incomparably powerful while also being more quick and accurate than either the Homing Missile or Homing Pigeon. Unfortunately, it is also almost impossible to find by normal means. The only thing it can't do is travel underwater. This one weakness aside, the Magic Bullet is an extremely reliable way to take out targets regardless of range or the complexity of the path to the target.Damage: Up to 100 HPHotkey: F12 (4x)Environmental ItemsOn top of the normal arsenal, Worms 2 includes a small number of randomly occurring items in the maps themselves intended to both assist and hinder players in their efforts to dominate their invertebrate enemies. All of these items have the potential to be either beneficial or detrimental, as even the First Aid Crate can cause damage if it is detonated by a nearby explosion. Crate drops have a chance to appear throughout a match before the start of a turn, while Mines and Oil Drums appear only at the beginning of a match.Weapon CrateWeapon CrateTrue to the unpredictable nature of Worms 2, Weapon Crates can turn the tide of a battle or spell certain doom for a greedy player. While enormously useful weapons like the Concrete Donkey can typically only be found through them, a crate might also be booby trapped to unleash fiery death on the first worm that touches it. Grabbing a Weapon Crate is therefore somewhat of a calculated risk. When using custom schemes, everything from the probability of individual weapon drops, to the frequency of crate appearances, to the odds of a booby trap can be controlled by the player.First Aid CrateFirst Aid CrateThe First Aid Crate is the only means available to a worm of healing itself mid-match. The standard increment of health bestowed is 25 hit points, though like most things in the game this can be altered through an option scheme to grant varying degrees of healing to the user. This crate is useful in any situation since even a worm that has not sustained damage can be healed past its starting health value. First Aid Crates will never by booby trapped in the same manner that Weapon Crates can be, though they can be destroyed by weapons fire, which can cause damage to nearby worms.MineMineWhile its appearance is identical to that of a Mine dropped by a player, an environmental Mine is in fact much more unpredictable (and therefore dangerous) due to its random fuse length (between zero and three seconds). For this reason it is rarely a good idea to approach one despite the fact that duds do occur on occasion. Knocking worms into a Mine or dislodging a Mine so that it will fall into a worm is an excellent source of extra damage for skilled players, and with any luck chain reactions involving multiple Mines can turn a single attack into a horrific worm massacre.Oil DrumOil DrumAccessible via a special code, Oil Drums act as a replacement for the standard Mine. They do not detonate automatically when approached but rather after they have sustained damage, so players can navigate around them without (as much) fear. When they do explode, Oil Drums leave fire behind which continues burning for a short period of time and causes further damage to any worms that touch it. When they are present on the battlefield, skillful players will often be on the lookout for opportunities to use them against their opponents as an extra source of damage.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13773">Soldat</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5822/852157-worms_2_front.jpg</image></root>