<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10148</id><name>Nintendogs</name><description>Taking advantage of the massive appeal of puppies, Nintendogs allows you to raise several breeds of dog up from the puppy stage and contribute to their development. Nintendogs makes full and extensive use of the DS hardware, allowing you to use both the microphone and stylus to interact with their virtual dog. You can use the microphone to create custom voice commands to control your dog, and through this system the dog can be trained to do follow, sit, play dead, and so on. The game was released simultaneously in three varieties -- Dachshund  Friends, Lab  Friends, Chihuahua  Friends -- which offered the same core game but differed in the breeds of dog on offer. In general, the player uses the bottom screen and stylus to manipulate the environment and interact with the dog by petting it, grooming it, and performing other actions designed to make the player a good dog owner and the dog a happy puppy. You can purchase supplies and toys for the dog, and as you earn more money, more dogs and environments become available. The dogs have a full range of needs and wants, and if the player discourages the dog or doesn't play the game for a significant amount of time, the dog will become unhappy or even run away and the player will need to start the game again. Nintendogs has proven itself to be inordinately popular, especially among the female demographic, and upon its initial release drove the sale of many DS units in Japan and the United States. Nintendogs was very well received by critics; it was awarded numerous high scores, and received the coveted maximum score of 40 from Famitsu, which had only awarded the score six times previously in its history. Nintendogs is also responsible for creating a wide range of clones and "me-too" titles which cashed in on its success.</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1442">Seaman</game><game id="2316">Dogz</game><game id="20558">Petz: Catz 2</game><game id="20561">Petz: Horsez 2</game><game id="20560">Petz: Hamsterz 2</game><game id="20559">Petz: Dogz 2</game><game id="21351">Tamagotchi Connection Corner Shop 3</game><game id="7580">Paws &amp; Claws Pet Vet</game><game id="21060">Spore Creatures</game><game id="21054">The Sims 2: Apartment Pets</game><game id="23787">Build-A-Bear Workshop</game><game id="24511">National Geographic Panda</game><game id="25121">Spore Creature Keeper</game><game id="16463">N.U.D.E. Natural Ultimate Digital Experiment</game><game id="5857">Dog's Life</game><game id="26064">Pet Pals</game><game id="26356">Purr Pals</game><game id="26851">Petz Pony Beauty Pageant</game><game id="26945">Discovery Kids: Parrot Pals</game><game id="22466">Discovery Kids: Puppy Playtime</game><game id="26826">Milo and Kate</game><game id="27081">Kawaii Koneko DS 2</game><game id="27252">Touch Pets: Dogs</game><game id="23493">EyePet</game><game id="28237">Animal Paradise</game><game id="29227">Petz Dogz Talent Show</game><game id="29470">Littlest Pet Shop</game><game id="29804">Me and My Dogs: Friends Forever</game><game id="31702">Kinectimals</game><game id="33435">Petz Catz Clan</game><game id="31736">Nintendogs + Cats</game><game id="35674">Pet Zombies</game><game id="36211">Wappy Dog</game><game id="36655">Puppies 3D</game><game id="37136">My Pet Puppy 3D</game><game id="43529">PlayStation Vita Pets</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3971/375493-nint_2.jpg</image></root>