<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10228</id><name>Medal of Honor: European Assault</name><description>OverviewMedal of Honor: European Assault was a return to the roots of the Medal of Honor series by taking the focus of the game from the Pacific, from Medal of Honor Rising Sun, and turned it back toward Europe.The game consisted of 4 chapters, each with a few missions. The chapters were based in the campaigns in northern France, North Africa, Russia (Stalingrad) , and Belgium (Battle of the Bulge) against the Nazis. In the missions you played as William Holt, an American soldier assigned with the British SAS. You had a squad of men, usually 3, and you directed them around with a basic 'click and go there' mechanic you were also able to heal yourself and your squadmates by using medkits found around the stages.Officer Holt  squadmates.Through out level you also were tasked with collecting intel and completing bonus objectives. In each mission there were also mini bosses that you often were given the choice of killing. If you killed the boss it would fill in as a bonus objective. You also had an adrenaline meter that filled up with enhanced abilities such as head shots, melee attacks, boss kills, completing bonus objectives, kill streaks, ect. When the adrenaline meter filled you could activate it and it would give you invincibility while it lasted, unlimited ammo, and for most guns, no reloading, the effect generally lasted for about 10 seconds. At the end of each mission you were rated on how many primary and bonus objectives you for filled, by how many intel documents you found, and by how many squad mates you brought through the level with you. You were then given a bronze, silver, or gold medal, and based on which medal you got you were given a certain number of extra revives to start out the next level, and how ever many squad mates you brought through you were given an according number of med-kits to start the next level with.MissionsFranceOperation: ChariotRaid On St. NazaireLights Out In The Port CityEscape At DawnNorth AfricaOperation: BlindfoldOperation: V2 SilenceRussiaRoad To StalingradClimbing Mamayev HillBattle of the BulgeMission To RocherathFarmhouse LiberationOperation: Virus HouseMultiplayerThe game did not support any online play on any platforms, but did have up to 4 player multiplayer on all 3 consoles. The game modes were very standard and no new modes were introduced into the world, and with only 4 players the team based modes weren't very well received. To play with a full 4 players on the PS2 you had to have a multitap.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13502">Brothers in Arms DS</game><game id="16711">Call of Duty 2: Big Red One</game><game id="10049">Medal of Honor: Underground</game><game id="21646">Battlefield 2: Modern Combat</game><game id="3232">Call of Duty: Finest Hour</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1988888-box_mohea.png</image></root>