<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10235</id><name>Saban's Power Rangers Zeo: Battle Racers</name><description>OverviewPower Rangers Zeo: Battle Racers is a racing game for the SNES often regarded as the only video game released based on the Zeo Power Rangers. However, Power Rangers Zeo: Full Tilt Battle Pinball for the PlayStation, and Power Rangers Zeo Versus The Machine Empire for the PC were also released. Zeo: Battle Racers is a vehicular racing game featuring the Zeo Power Rangers riding their respective colored vehicles.GameplayIn Power Rangers Zeo: Battle Racers, players control the Power Rangers, King Mondo, or a Cog Soldier are race each other. While racing, players can drift around corners, jump over obstacles, and fire blasters. By drifting, players do not lose as much speed as slowing down for a corner, but drifting too much can cause the player to spin out. Players can also jump over oil slicks and rough patches on the track. Jumping can also be used to avoid blaster shots, if timed correctly. Typically, each racer only has five blaster rounds available for the entire race. These shots home in on the closest racer and can be fired backwards as well as forwards.CharactersZeo Ranger Red: Tommy OliverZeo Ranger Blue: Rocky DeSantosZeo Ranger Green: Adam ParkZeo Ranger Yellow: Tanya SloanZeo Ranger Pink: Kat HillardZeo Ranger Gold: Jason Lee ScottKing MondoCog SoldierCog Ace (Secret Character)Red Ranger and Gold Ranger have well-rounded stats. The Blue and Pink Ranger have better acceleration. The Yellow and Green Rangers focus in handling. King Mondo has the highest top speed. Cog Soldier has the highest rated grip.ModesRace Mode takes players on a progression of tracks that must be completed in order to unlock the next set of tracks. Each set of tracks is cleared by ranking in the top two of a points bracket. This progression continues until all the tracks are clear. This mode is also available in a two player version.Time Trial Mode is where players race to get the fastest time on a track. There are no CPU controlled characters.VS CPU Mode is a race mode where players race against a single CPU controlled character. This mode is available as a two player option.There are three modes exclusive to two players: Point Race, Bumper Chase, and Blaster Master. Point Race is a timed event where two players fight to control as many territories found on the map as possible. In Bumper Chase, the objective is to knock the other player off of the edge of the track before time expires. Blaster Master is a fight between two players using their blasters. Players have 5 hit points before they are defeated, and unlike in race modes, blaster shots are unlimited and they do not home in on targets.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="38076">Battle Racers</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/14/149200/2115829-saban_s_power_rangers_zeo_battle_racers.jpg</image></root>