<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10265</id><name>Pinball Hall of Fame: The Gottlieb Collection</name><description>OverviewThe Gottlieb Collection is a pinball game based on the tables of the well known manufacturer. All the tables in the game are replicated from real life tables, including some extremely rare ones.Unlockable FeaturesEach table in The Gottlieb Collection has a specific goal that when completed will unlock a feature. The goal for each table can be viewed by going to the table menu and selecting goal.Tournament ModeTournament mode is based on some real life scoring modes created by pinball players for tournaments. Tournament mode can be played with up to 4 players at a time. The first replay score for a table is divided by 10, and then equals one tournament point. Each time a player reaches reaches the scoring threshold, another point will be awarded. The total amount of tournament points are accumulated across all seven of the tables, and the player with the most tournament points at the end wins.XoltenXolten is a fortune telling machine that can be unlocked by fulfilling certain requirements. Custom BallThe custom ball feature will allow the player to change the appearance of the pinball.Love MeterThe love meter is another unlockable machine that is non-pinball. The player holds a button down and the machine will tell the "love level".Gottlieb Factory TourThe Gottlieb factory tour is a slideshow of various images showing what the Gottlieb factory looked like in the 1960's.  GameplayPinball machines included in the game:PlayboyAce HighCentral ParkBig ShotGenieBlack HoleGoin' NutsEl DoradoVictoryTee'd OffStrikes N' Spares</description><genres><genre id="30">Pinball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5436">Metroid Prime Pinball</game><game id="24088">Akira Psycho Ball</game><game id="19154">Pokémon Pinball</game><game id="4287">Mario Pinball Land</game><game id="18592">Sonic the Hedgehog: Spinball</game><game id="20885">Pinball</game><game id="6313">Flipnic: Ultimate Pinball</game><game id="29223">Pinball Heroes</game><game id="20994">Pinball Hall of Fame: The Williams Collection</game><game id="43553">Ultimate Pro Pinball</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2536373-box_phoftgc.png</image></root>