<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10366</id><name>Fuzion Frenzy 2</name><description>Fuzion Frenzy 2 is a party game from    Microsoft. You are able to select from a group of characters and participate in mini-games. There are several modes to be played in Fuzion Frenzy 2 such as  All of the characters from the original Fuzion Frenzy are back in this game.Tournament Mode, Custom Mode, Mini-Game Frenzy, and there is online as well.Tournament mode lets you, and your friends if you have more players, pick a character and compete in mini-games. There are around 7 different worlds with mini-games that fall into their category. For example, there is a world called Blazer. Obviously, all of the mini-games that have fire in them or anything that falls into that category will be playable in this world during Tournament Mode. Tournament Mode is set like a game show with a host. He will pick the first world, and you must win the mini-games in the worlds to earn points. You'll also get cards which will do certain things such as multiply your total points earned in one mini-game times 2, 4, or 6 times. There are also cards which enable you to pick a mini-game, even if you didn't place first in the last one, steal card effects from other players, or divide the total point value of another player rather than having them multiply it. Once you finish three mini-games, you will be in a mini-game that has you fight the other players. Whoever has the highest amount of points collected from all the mini-games in the world will win that world. After that, you go to another world to win that one. You can set it to either first to win two worlds all the way up to five worlds. The host of the game show.Mini-Game Frenzy is pretty self-explanatory. You can choose from a list of 40  games to play and you can play them. Custom Mode allows you to create your own little tournament with your friends. You can pick up to 40 mini-games and you'll get points for how well you do in the mini-game. Obviously if you place first, you will get the most points. After all the mini-games are done, the game will total up the point values and the player with the highest points wins the Custom Tournament. It should also be noted that these modes can also be played online.As mentioned above in the last sentence, all of these modes (Tournament, Mini-Game Frenzy, and Custom Mode) can also be played online. One player will host a match in which four players can join. If there are only two players and nobody else is joining, the host has the option to have computers play as the last two characters and set the difficulty to even out the game.Before Fuzion Frenzy 2 was released, a demo came out on the   Xbox Live Marketplace. This demo allowed you to play three mini-games from the actual game, Conveyor Belt Chaos, Sumo Paint, and Ice Treasure Hunt. Fuzion Frenzy 2 was released exclusively on the  Xbox 360 January 30, 2007.</description><genres><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16650">Fuzion Frenzy</game><game id="21617">Rayman: Raving Rabbids</game><game id="24844">Every Party</game><game id="20520">Hail to the Chimp</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2275991-box_ff2.png</image></root>