<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10360</id><name>Mercs</name><description>MERCS, referred as Senjou No Ookami II in Japan, is a run and gun arcade style military shooter developed by Capcom in 1990. It is the sequel to the 1985 Commando game. The third game in the series, Wolf of the Battlefield was released in 2008.Get Behind Enemy LinesThe world is faced with the worst outbreak of revolutions and terrorism that it has ever seen. The forces that seek to disrupt peace will stop at nothing to get what they want!The U.S. government has tried its best to eliminate these threats using the military. But the military is ineffective against the guerilla warfare and terrorist tactics of the enemy. The U.S. government cannot afford to take sides in the rapidly changing power structures of war-torn countries. The government needs a way to accomplish its missions with a minimum of casualties.Now, the decision is made to send a group of professional mercenaries, known as the Mercs, who are well-trained in anti-terrorist activities.As a Merc, you must penetrate enemy lines to accomplish secret missions for the U.S. government. You must battle through treacherous displays of enemy war machinery where no ordinary soldier would dare to go!PortsThe game has been ported to various platforms, the latest being on the PSP in 2006 in Capcom Classics Collection Reloaded.The Genesis version of the game will come to the Wii Virtual Console in early 2009 under the name "Wolf of the Battlefield: Mercs." Capcom has loosely alluded to copyright issues over the Mercs name as the reason for the change.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1619">Ikari Warriors</game><game id="2390">Ikari Warriors II: Victory Road</game><game id="18805">Ikari III: The Rescue</game><game id="3114">Rambo</game><game id="5222">Assault Heroes</game><game id="20657">Assault Heroes 2</game><game id="20332">Shock Troopers: 2nd Squad</game><game id="13388">Shock Troopers</game><game id="2893">Re-Loaded</game><game id="24253">Burn Zombie Burn!</game><game id="14750">Airborne Ranger</game><game id="6850">Commando</game><game id="25407">Bounty Arms</game><game id="1761">KiKi KaiKai</game><game id="13678">Pocky &amp; Rocky 2</game><game id="14991">Crack Down</game><game id="2432">Bloody Wolf</game><game id="4213">SWAT</game><game id="28183">Warzone</game><game id="948">The Chaos Engine</game><game id="19058">The Chaos Engine 2</game><game id="2138">Capcom Classics Collection</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/7/73970/1308803-mercs.jpg</image></root>