<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10385</id><name>Meteos</name><description>OverviewMeteos, released in June 2005 by Q Entertainment, Nintendo, and Bandai; challenges players to attempt to clear a screen of falling blocks, or "Meteos". By creating links of similarly colored Meteos, the blocks are sent towards the top of screen by jet propulsion. As the game progresses and the player launches more Meteos off the screen, the Meteos begin to rain faster, forcing the player to rely on split-second reflexes.GameplayThe game is played on of 32 different "Planets", each with individual characteristics that affect or impede gameplay - for example, some planets increase or decrease the size of the Meteos, whilst others may change the effect of gravity upon the falling Meteos and the way they are launched.ControlsThe game is playable by using either the DS Touch-screen and stylus or through the use of the D-pad and buttons. However, due to the fast-paced nature of the game, players often use the stylus control scheme. ReceptionUpon its release in 2005, Meteos received high critical acclaim. It was rated the rated the 52nd best game made on a Nintendo System in Nintendo Power's Top 200 Games list, as well as attaining an aggregate score of 88/100 on both Metacritic and Game Rankings.SequelsMeteos has spawned a number of sequels, including: Meteos: Disney Magic, Released February 27, 2007Meteos Online Meteos for mobile phones and other wireless devices Meteos Wars for Xbox Live Arcade in December 2008Game ModesStar TripStar Trip is the story mode of Meteos, in which you travel from world to world choosing which path to take, each world you visit has different objectives, and whether or not you meet these objectives determines which worlds will be available to you on the next leg of your journey.Simple  In simple mode you play a single world of your choosing, you can set your difficulty and how many lives you have. This mode is particularly useful for gathering elements that can be used in Fusion in which you can use the elements you gather as currency to purchase more planets to play in simple and deluge modes.DelugeDeluge in an even simpler mode then Simple, in this mode you play with one life on the world of your choosing until you fail.Time War Time War is broken up into four separate modes2:00 Time War: Here you have 2 minutes to get the high score on the planet Geolyte.5:00 Time War: You have 5 minutes to get the high score on the planet Layazero.100 Meteos: Clear 100 Meteos on the planet Firim as fast as possible.1000 Meteos: Clear 1000 Meteos on the planet Hevendor as fast as possible.SoundtrackGeolyte Set "Bravo"Bavoom Set "Funky Horn"Firim Set "Rocking Spirit"Jel Jel Set "Hall of Horrors"Oleana Set "Shinin"Freaze Set "Winter Impasse"Anasaze Set "Wild West Cowboy"Forte Set "Stepped On"Cavious Set "Ambient Pipes"Grannest Set "Tech 'n' Knock"Mekks Set "Famicomic"Suburbion Set "Hot Revival"Gravitas Set "Metallia"Layazero Set "Eurorockitude"Boggob Set "Cha-Cha Chop"Wuud Set "Earth Rhythms"Megadom Set "Major Tempo"Dawndus Set "Drumline"Thirnova Set "Bossa Cafe"Gigagush Set "Aliens"Hevendor Set "Space-Time Continuum"Brabbit Set "Pon!"Yodj Set "Number 5"Hotted Set "Transpace"Vubble Set "Natural Paradise"Wiral Set "Speed of Magic"Florias Set "Indie Music Troupe"Globin Set "Inner Bubbles"Starrii Set "Holiday Laughter"Lastar Set "Solar Chimes"Luna=Luna Set "The Scratch Show"Meteo Set "Planet Meteo"</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5057">Lumines: Puzzle Fusion</game><game id="1916">Puyo Puyo</game><game id="21635">Neves</game><game id="8887">Every Extend Extra</game><game id="17641">Dr. Mario</game><game id="21610">Crosswords DS</game><game id="21069">Rollin’ Rascals</game><game id="2320">Every Extend Extra Extreme</game><game id="15464">Polarium Advance</game><game id="23694">Lumines Supernova</game><game id="13577">Baku Baku</game><game id="10234">Tetris DS</game><game id="25317">Rain Drops</game><game id="11138">Polarium</game><game id="25766">Puyo Puyo 7</game><game id="25947">Yosumin!</game><game id="26172">BeatBlox</game><game id="23234">Tetris Party</game><game id="31017">Trioncube</game><game id="31140">Tetris Party Deluxe</game><game id="30013">Tetris Party Live</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14097/611544-cover1.jpg</image></root>