<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10472</id><name>Darkness Within: In Pursuit of Loath Nolder</name><description>OverviewDarkness Within: In Pursuit of Loath Nolder is a first-person adventure game with themes of Lovecraftian horror. It is the first part of the Darkness Within series.StoryDetective Howard E. Loreid is investigating the death of a wealthy middle aged man, Clark Field. The prime suspect of the case is former private investigator, Loath Nolder. Loath’s last case made him suddenly suspend his job and dissapear for five years. During that time he visited some African and Oceania countries where he lived with the native people and learned a lot of things from tribe shamans and sorcerers. After his trip he was no longer the oldLoath Nolder's officeLoath Nolder.The game begins inside Howard’s dream, where you see the bizarre and twisted version of the world through his eyes. After waking Howard gets the call about the case and heads into the office where he catches up on the case. Then he drives off to Loath’s office where he finds his first clues that point him to investigate the residence of Clark Field. At Clark’s house Howard finds several pages of reading about the occult and old religions. Does Loath have something to do with all this?During the investigation Howard begins to hear and see things. He has nightmares and wakes up after days asleep and is starting to lose his sanity. After awhile the line between dream and reality gets thinner. What is real and what is imagined? System requirements Minimum System RequirementsOperating System: Windows® 2000 / XP / Vista™ CPU: 1 GHz Intel® Pentium® processor or AMD® Athlon™ processor RAM Memory: 256 MB (512 MB Recommended for Windows Vista™) Video Card: 128 MB DirectX® 9.0c compatible or better video card (nVidia GeForce™ 3 Ti 200) Sound Card: DirectX® 9.0c compatible sound card (Hard Disk Space: 1.1 GB DirectX®: 9.0cPeripherals: Mouse, Keyboard and Sound Speakers  Recommended System RequirementsOperating System: Windows® 2000 / XP / Vista™ CPU: 1.4 GHz Intel® Pentium® processor or AMD® Athlon™ processor RAM Memory: 512 MB (1 GB Recommended for Windows Vista™) Video Card: 128 MB DirectX® 9.0c compatible or better video card (nVidia GeForce™ 6 / ATI® Radeon® 9600 Pro / comparable) and Pixel/Vertex Shader 2.0 support Sound Card: DirectX® 9.0c compatible sound card (Sound Blaster® X-Fi™ series sound card recommended)Hard Disk Space: 1.1 GB DirectX®: 9.0cPeripherals: Mouse, Keyboard and 5.1 or 4.1 Surround Sound Speakers</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="31169">Darkness Within 2: The Dark Lineage</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1987/725688-darkness_within_front.jpg</image></root>