<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10475</id><name>Commandos: Beyond the Call of Duty</name><description>OverviewCommandos: Beyond the Call of Duty is an expansion pack to the game   Commandos: Behind Enemy Lines.  It offers more challenging missions than the original games. The game is also set in the  Second World War, and it has one more character than the first original game. Commandos  Diver Real name: James Blackwood. Birthday: 3 August 1911. Birthplace:  Melbourne,    Australia.Can use his scuba gear to dive underwater and stay there indefinitely. This is useful to disarm underwater objects such as sea mines. He is also the only commando who can pilot boats. Also has a grappling hook and can throw knives at enemies.  Driver Real name: Sid Perkins. Birthday: 4 April 1910. Birthplace: Brooklyn,  USA.Only commando that can operate tanks. He can also set various traps and use molotov cocktails and smoke grenades.  Green BeretReal name: Jerry McHale.Birthday: 10 October 1909.Birthplace:  Dublin,    Ireland.The Strongest of the commandos. Green Beret has the ability to carry heavy objects. He can also bury himself in certain areas. His main attribute is his Knife, which he can use to silently take out enemy units without attracting attention.  Army boxing champion from 1934 to 1937.  Sapper Real name: Thomas Hancock. Birthday: 14 January 1911. Birthplace:  Liverpool, England.He is an expert in heavy weapons and explosives such as C4 and flamethrowers.  SniperReal name: Sir Francis T. Woolridge. Birthday: 21 March 1909. Birthplace: Sheffield,  England.Has the ability to shoot enemies at very long range. To initiate this the player must place the cross hairs over the unit to be shot.  Spy Real name: Rene Duchamp. Birthday: 20 November 1911. Birthplace:  Lyon,  France.Can disguise himself in the clothes of enemies and walk through enemies without attraction attention. While in an enemy uniform the spy can distract guards and, if wearing a high ranking uniform, order low ranking soldiers to face a certain direction.  Seductress Real name: Natasha Van Der Zand/Natasha Nikochevski. Birthplace: Netherlands/ Kiev,    Soviet Union.Character is best used for distraction, she can seduce enemy soldiers. She can also use a sniper rifle.  PC System Requirements Minimum: Microsoft Windows 95/98P166MHz32MB RAM1MB SVGA cardDirectX 6.1 compatible sound cardDirectX 6.1225MB hard drive space  Recommended: Pentium II 233 MHz64 MB RAM    </description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14444">Warhammer 40,000: Chaos Gate</game><game id="6173">Soldiers: Heroes of World War II</game><game id="10756">Desperados: Wanted Dead or Alive</game><game id="9608">Helldorado</game><game id="11730">Soldiers at War</game><game id="19692">Korea: Forgotten Conflict</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15228/820098-commando.jpeg</image></root>