<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10537</id><name>Jagged Alliance</name><description>OverviewJagged Alliance is a tactical role-playing game released originally in 1994 for MS-DOS, and then re-released in 2009 for the Nintendo DS. It was followed by the sequels Jagged Alliance: Deadly Games in 1995 and Jagged Alliance 2 in 1999. The game takes place on the fictional island of Metavira in the south Atlantic. The island's trees have been altered by nuclear testing and are later discovered by scientist Brenda Richards to produce a sap of great medical value. However, the trees cannot reproduce. Lucas Santino, Brenda's assistant, convinces the leader of the scientific mission, Jack Richards (Brenda's father), to establish a new, independent science team on the other side of the island. Lucas, in hopes of getting rich off the sap, takes control over the entire island through force. Players are invited by Jack Richards to the island and requested by Brenda and Jack to hire mercenaries through A.I.M. (the Association of International Mercenaries) to take back the island from Lucas.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="196">X-COM: UFO Defense</game><game id="6346">Fallout Tactics: Brotherhood of Steel</game><game id="4638">Knights of Legend</game><game id="4676">Shadow Watch</game><game id="11424">The Fall: Last Days of Gaia</game><game id="5951">Police Quest: SWAT 2</game><game id="17276">Rebelstar: Tactical Command</game><game id="1379">UFO:Extraterrestrials</game><game id="3251">X-COM: Terror from the Deep</game><game id="4777">X-COM: Apocalypse</game><game id="10967">S2: Silent Storm</game><game id="8757">S3: Silent Storm - Sentinels</game><game id="15416">Hammer &amp; Sickle</game><game id="10415">Brigade E5: New Jagged Union</game><game id="29553">Hired Guns: The Jagged Edge</game><game id="888">7.62mm</game><game id="599">Pathway to Glory: Ikusa Islands</game><game id="4846">Star Trek: Away Team</game><game id="21198">Shadowrun</game><game id="31575">Ground Zero</game><game id="1437">Wages of War: The Business of Battle</game><game id="31771">Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon: Shadow Wars</game><game id="6594">Robin Hood: The Legend of Sherwood</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2324/293503-ja_000.png</image></root>