<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10553</id><name>Carmageddon II: Carpocalypse Now</name><description>OverviewCarmageddon 2: Carpocalypse Now is a racing game, where you can beat most levels in three ways. Race, kill every living thing, or destroy all your opponents.Developed by Stainless Games, and published by Sales Curve Interactive, it comes for both PC and MAC. The game features several different levels, which have different laps in different races. Levels are unlocked in sets, where you have three races followed by a mission. This must be solved to advance to the next set.Racing, or killing?In Carmageddon 2 there are as stated three ways to beat a normal level.Racing: Every race has a set of checkpoints you must race through in order to finish the level. Number of laps depends on the level. Time is usually scarce in the beginning, and it is hard to beat a race without running over pedestrians, or crashing into your opponents.Kill Every Living Thing: Wipe out all the pedestrians and animals on the level. There are usually about a 1000 pedestrians on each level, which makes this approach somewhat hard.Destroy Every Opponent: To win this way, every opponent must be totaled. Some cars are easier to waste, while some need a lot of work. Once a car has been totaled, it can also be bought after the race. This is the only way to get new cars.Races usually turn out to be a mix of these. Luckily, you need not decide what kind of race you want to run at the beginning, you simply chose to do what you want. Trying to finish the race by checkpoints often turns into a killing spree.CarsThis was one of the few games at the time which contained demolishable cars. Not only having a health system, they also got deformed, bent and crashed realistically. You can actually bend cars almost double, and slice it in half. The latter was fatal, but if you where airborne when the car was sliced, you could repair it before you hit the ground.You can repair cars in game, and also "recover" to a safe spot. This costs money, which you can also use to upgrade cars. This carries over from car to car.There are many different cars in the game, from normal race cars to a bulldozer. There is even a grounded Stuka plane available.NamePhotoDriverInformationAbba Cab"Pulls like a train, and quick, once it gets going. And once it's going, it's not gonna to stop."Magnum MagnumssonOpponent number 29Short name MagnumRace number 99Status icon Top speed 120 mphKerb weight 6.0 tons0 - 60 mph in 9.9 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 5Cost 1,750,000 creditsNetwork availability allBig Dump"When you can afford this baby, your troubles are over. Unless you need to get through a checkpoint..."Psycho PitbullOpponent number 30Short name PitbullRace number no numberStatus icon Top speed 150 mphKerb weight 35.0 tons0 - 60 mph in 9.4 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 80Cost 8,800,000 creditsNetwork availability allThe Bimmer"Try to hang onto your hat, and your lunch, in this experimental high-octane thriller."Kurt BlasthoffOpponent number 33Short name KurtRace number 14Status icon Top speed 240 mphKerb weight 1.13 tons0 - 60 mph in 2.9 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 2Cost 120,000 creditsNetwork availability allBlood Riviera"A classic fast musclecar with enhanced foe-grating front grill. Slice 'n' dice time."Dan DeadOpponent number 24Short name DandeadRace number 54Status icon Top speed 160 mphKerb weigh 1.16 tons0 - 60 mph in 4.9 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 3Cost 383,200 creditsNetwork availability allBugga"This nippy little all-terrain buggy suits the off-road races, but avoid taking on those trucks..."BuggaOpponent number 1Short name ScumRace number ☺Status icon Top speed 140 mphKerb weight 1.15 tons0 - 60 mph in 5.4 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 1Cost 72,000 creditsNetwork availability allThe Buzzmobile"Small, light, fast, and soft as shite. If you're a racer, this is for you."Buzz LightweightOpponent number 4Short name BuzzRace number 69Status icon Top speed 160 mphKerb weight 0.5 tons0 - 60 mph in 3.9 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 1Cost 69,000 creditsNetwork availability allCopcar"It's got a Cop motor, a 440 cubic inch plant. It's got Cop tyres. Cop suspension. Cop shocks..."The CopsOpponent number 51Short name CopRace number 206Status icon Top speed 140 mphKerb weight 1.6 tons0 - 60 mph in 5.4 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 5Cost 540,000 creditsNetwork availability allCoupe De Grace"Super-streamlined hot rod with super-pointy front end for deflecting foe and skewering victim."Grace FullOpponent number 18Short name GraceRace number 95Status icon Top speed 170 mphKerb weight 1.6 tons0 - 60 mph in 6.2 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 2Cost 273,000 creditsNetwork availability allCow Poker"If you can afford this baby, you've earned your spurs. Go get 'em, cowboy."Slim ChanceOpponent number 13Short name SlimRace number 53 (maybe)Status icon Top speed 120 mphKerb weight 2.0 tons0 - 60 mph in 7.2 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 3Cost 480,000 creditsNetwork availability allDC Codbra"Superfast 2-seater with tri-blade "knock-off" wheels. You'll knock off some opposition in this."Shawnee SmittOpponent number 17Short name ShawneeRace number 96Status icon Top speed 180 mphKerb weight 1.1 tons0 - 60 mph in 5.2 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 3Cost 789,000 creditsNetwork availability allDeathcruiser"Powered by a huge gas-turbine engine, this old tourbus is very hard and very, very fast."Mike HuntOpponent number 19Short name MikeRace number 79Status icon Top speed 190 mphKerb weight 8.0 tons0 - 60 mph in 3.8 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 5Cost 1,500,000 creditsNetwork availability allDeGory'Un 2"Not too hot on the performance front, but usefully adorned up front."Russ TOpponent number 36Short name RussRace number no numberStatus icon Top speed 140 mphKerb weight 1.6 tons0 - 60 mph in 6.9 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 3Cost 631,000 creditsNetwork availability allEagle 3"The Eagle is back, and it's badder and better than ever."Max DamageOpponent number 0Short name MaxRace number 1Status icon Top speed 200 mphKerb weight 1.5 tons0 - 60 mph in 3.4 secondsStrength (1 - 5) -1Cost 50000 creditsNetwork availability eagleFlower Power"Tank tracks, tank engine, tank armour, and a very nice floral paintjob..."Moon ChildOpponent number 30Short name MoonRace number 37Status icon Top speed 150 mphKerb weight 2.5 tons0 - 60 mph in 9.9 secondsStrength (1 - 5) -1Cost 12,000,000 creditsNetwork availability allForking Ada"Not the most effective race car on the track, but it's a real crowd pleaser and useful in a scrap."Ada NuffOpponent number 16Short name AdaRace number 6Status icon Top speed 110 mphKerb weight 2.06 tons0 - 60 mph in 12.2 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 3Cost 212,000 creditsNetwork availability allThe Harvester"Faster than a speeding Bullock (just). Watch them bale out when you hit the road with this."Farmer FrightOpponent number 35Short name FarmerRace number 90Status icon Top speed 190 mphKerb weight 5.0 tons0 - 60 mph in 2.9 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 5Cost 1,720,000 creditsNetwork availability allHawk 3"Die's back, with a superslick rival to the all-round great Eagle. A similar vehicle, but faster."Die AnnaOpponent number 22Short name AnnaRace number 1Status icon Top speed 240 mphKerb weight 1.3 tons0 - 60 mph in 3.2 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 3Cost 495,000 creditsNetwork availability neverHellrod"Quite a car... dead fast, dead hard, dead set on causing maximum damage with minimum effort."Rod HellOpponent number 52Short name RodRace number 666Status icon Top speed 180 mphKerb weight 2.5 tons0 - 60 mph in 4.0 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 4Cost 340,000 creditsNetwork availability allHick Pickup"Not the most sophisticated drive, but 2 tons of iron and a V8 can come in handy in a fight."Banjo StrummyOpponent number 10Short name BanjoRace number 66Status icon Top speed 120 mphKerb weight 3.0 tons0 - 60 mph in 8.2 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 4Cost 842,000 creditsNetwork availability allJetcar"A car. A jet engine. A jetcar. Too fast for it's own good, really. And not too good at cornering."Jenny TayliaOpponent number 20Short name JennyRace number 6Status icon Top speed 140 mphKerb weight 2.0 tons0 - 60 mph in 3.8 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 1Cost 115,000 creditsNetwork availability allLadyBug2"A lively racer with pedigree, slightly fragile and hard to handle. the car's the same."Lady BugOpponent number 2Short name LadyBRace number 8Status icon Top speed 180 mphKerb weight 1.0 tons0 - 60 mph in 6.4 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 2Cost 165,000 creditsNetwork availability allLamb O'Genie"Carve up the field with the genie, but don't hit anyone too hard, it'll hurt you more."KutterOpponent number 5Short name KutterRace number 97Status icon Top speed 200 mphKerb weight 1.5 tons0 - 60 mph in 4.2 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 3Cost 315,000 creditsNetwork availability allLoggerhead"Catch someone with this, and they'll wish they never got up this morning. Joust the job."Halfwit HarryOpponent number 32Short name HarryRace number 110Status icon Top speed 140 mphKerb weight 20.0 tons0 - 60 mph in 7.9 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 5Cost 2,500,000 creditsNetwork availability allMach 13"50′s view of the future of automation. Fast, light, and super-manouverable. But so soft."Su BorgOpponent number 1Short name SuRace number 101Status icon Top speed 190 mphKerb weight 1.5 tons0 - 60 mph in 3.8 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 2Cost 26,300 creditsNetwork availability allMad Morris"An unlikely combination of high speed and early British design makes for a robust but unstable vehicle."Maurice StalwartOpponent number 14Short name MauriceRace number 42Status icon Top speed 120 mphKerb weight 1.6 tons0 - 60 mph in 9.2 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 4Cost 389,000 creditsNetwork availability allMonster Beatle"Hard to hit anything when you're mounted on all that rubber... but it's fun to try"Herb 'E'Opponent number 15Short name HerbRace number 35Status icon Top speed 150 mphKerb weight 3.45 tons0 - 60 mph in 5.3 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 4Cost 542,000 creditsNetwork availability allPiranha"Well armoured off-roader, with good offensive capabilities, if a little light."Auto ScumOpponent number 9Short name PiranhaRace number noneStatus icon Top speed 130 mphKerb weight 1.66 tons0 - 60 mph in 6.2 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 2Cost 187,000 creditsNetwork availability allThe Plow Mk. 2"Built to shift Don along at speed, The Plow will go straight through most solid objects. Handy."Don DumpsterOpponent number 11Short name DonRace number 24Status icon Top speed 120 mphKerb weight 10.0 tons0 - 60 mph in 7.2 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 5Cost 1,000,000 creditsNetwork availability allPorker 2"Updated and improved, in top race spec, the Porker 2 is dead fast but deadly on the limit."Herr KooledOpponent number 23Short name HerrkooledRace number 70Status icon Top speed 170 mphKerb weight 2.0 tons0 - 60 mph in 3.9 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 3Cost 540,000 creditsNetwork availability allProp Shafter"A useful mixture of car and fighter plane, ideal for offering a free trim to your opponent."Silvester StallionOpponent number 34Short name SilvesterRace number 75Status icon Top speed 190 mphKerb weight 1.18 tons0 - 60 mph in 2.9 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 2Cost 210,000 creditsNetwork availability allPurple Piledriver"They don't come much quicker than this... just try not to crash it."BatmadOpponent number 3Short name BatmadRace number 8Status icon Top speed 220 mphKerb weight 1.1 tons0 - 60 mph in 3.7 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 3Cost 375,000 creditsNetwork availability allRazorback"Well armoured off-roader, with good offensive capabilities, if a little light."Auto ScumOpponent number 8Short name RazorRace number Piranha symbolStatus icon Top speed 130 mphKerb weight 0.83 tons0 - 60 mph in 6.2 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 1Cost 110,000 creditsNetwork availability allThe Red Vet"The metal mangling mother of all classic Americans, with a highly tuned V8. Punch it!"AshteroidOpponent number 27Short name AshRace number 37Status icon Top speed 140 mphKerb weight 2.0 tons0 - 60 mph in 5.9 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 4Cost 732,000 creditsNetwork availability allScrewie 2"The ‘supercar/monster truck/light aircraft/mole machine’ vehicle for the discerning nutter."Screwie LewieOpponent number 37Short name ScrewieRace number 12Status icon Top speed 200 mphKerb weight 3.0 tons0 - 60 mph in 3.9 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 4Cost 892,000 creditsNetwork availability allSemi Mk.2"The enormous semi is reborn, and there's not much on the road that can take it on."Mother TruckerOpponent number 25Short name MotherRace number no numberStatus icon Top speed 140 mphKerb weight 8.0 tons0 - 60 mph in 6.9 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 5Cost 1,450,000 creditsNetwork availability allSlam Sedan"Serious metal. Smooth, comfortable, easy to drive. An auto smash has never been so relaxing."Otis P JivefunkOpponent number 12Short name OtisRace number 2Status icon Top speed 120 mphKerb weight 1.7 tons0 - 60 mph in 7.2 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 3Cost 460,000 creditsNetwork availability allStreet Machine"Commit sonic murder with the speakers in the back of this baby  blow yer opponents bowels open!"Wide BoyOpponent number 7Short name WideboyRace number 28Status icon Top speed 140 mphKerb weight 1.37 tons0 - 60 mph in 5.9 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 2Cost 210,000 creditsNetwork availability allThe Supastuka"Now, here's something you don't see every day. A WW2 fighter-bomber for the road. Cool!"Heinz FaustOpponent number 6Short name HeinzRace number 633Status icon Top speed 400 mphKerb weight 4.0 tons0 - 60 mph in 4.2 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 4Cost 395,000 creditsNetwork availability allTashita2"A fiercely fast and technologically advanced racing machine from the far east."Ed 101Opponent number 26Short name Ed101Race number 23Status icon Top speed 190 mphKerb weight 1.5 tons0 - 60 mph in 3.9 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 2Cost 170,000 creditsNetwork availability allThunderbucket"Maximum weight, minimum suspension damping gives that "Is it a car, is it a boat?" feeling."SintheaOpponent number 31Short name SintheaRace number 56Status icon Top speed 180 mphKerb weight 3.0 tons0 - 60 mph in 5.9 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 2Cost 175,000 creditsNetwork availability allVlad 3"Fine in a straight line, with the highest top speed. Just don't try to corner it."VladOpponent number 28Short name VladRace number 3Status icon Top speed 240 mphKerb weight 1.0 tons0 - 60 mph in 1.9 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 1Cost 82,000 creditsNetwork availability allControversyLike the first Carmageddon game, this got criticized for its level of violence. This led it to be censored in some countries. Pedestrians were switched to zombies, red blood became green slime, and animals were removed. You can also remove animals from the game in the options for the game."Blood patches" were released online, which made it possible for people with censored versions to un-censor it.ModdingThis is a bloody game.The game has seen a lot of new cars made by modders, as well as skins, maps and other mods.The Spray Shop and WASTED! are two such sites.MusicCarmageddon 2 features music from the popular heavy metal band Iron Maiden. Some of the tracks included in the game are Man on the Edge, Aces High, Be Quick Or Be Dead, and The Trooper. In addition to Iron Maiden Carmageddon 2 also contained a few edited instrumentals tracks from Sentience's album "An Eye For An Eye".PC RequirementsWindows 95/98/Me/XP;Pentium 166 (Min.), Pentium 200 (Rec.);4x CD-ROM Drive;16MB RAM (Min.), 32MB (Rec.);DirectX 6.0 compatible 2MB graphics card (Min.);DirectX 6.0 compatible sound card;200MB free hard drive space;Mouse  Keyboard.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16436">Twisted Metal 2</game><game id="5279">Interstate '76</game><game id="786">Destruction Derby</game><game id="13200">Vigilante 8</game><game id="7468">Vigilante 8: 2nd Offense</game><game id="13177">FlatOut</game><game id="9017">Mad Max</game><game id="12364">Battle Cars</game><game id="23527">Hardware 2</game><game id="16728">Powerslide</game><game id="25512">Clutch</game><game id="12283">Quarantine</game><game id="31863">Carmageddon 64</game><game id="37266">Smash 'n' Survive</game><game id="4543">Quarantine II: Road Warrior</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2130/629107-carma2.jpg</image></root>