<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10628</id><name>Kirby's Star Stacker</name><description>OverviewStar-stacker Kirby stacks stars.Kirby's Star Stacker is a puzzle game where the object is to collect as many stars as possible. To do this, the player must sandwich the stars either vertically or horizontally between two identical friends. These friends are Rick, Kine, and Coo, Kirby's buddies from the "Dream Land" series. Objects fall from the sky in pairs of two. If the pile of friends and stars reaches the top of the gameplay area, the game is over. King DeDeDe's head sits on the right hand side of the screen. DeDeDe is there to make sure that Kirby makes as little progress as possible, and if he doesn't like what he sees, his head will turn into a fist. When this fist pounds down and shakes the screen, the level of blocks on the playing area will increase. Like in Tetris, if the blocks on the playing field reach to the top of the screen and no more can fit onto it without being pushed off the top, then the game will be over.ChainsCreating a chain reaction will cause stars to fall from the sky. In other words, if deleting one pair of blocks causes another pair of blocks to be deleted, then more star blocks will fall from the top of the playing field and potentially create even more chain reactions, which will in turn cause even greater numbers of stars to drop onto the playing field. These star blocks always count towards your total score, and will always instantly disappear if they don't cause a reaction, preventing them from messing up the field.Game ModesRound Clear - Clear a certain number of stars to proceed to the next round.Challenge - The game's endless mode, clear as many stars as possible before you lose.Time Attack - Clear as many stars as possible in exactly three minutes.Vs. - A multi-player mode.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1896">Tetris</game><game id="10234">Tetris DS</game><game id="16966">Yoshi's Cookie</game><game id="2582">Wario's Woods</game><game id="12562">Tetris 2</game><game id="796">Tetris DX</game><game id="19197">Yoshi</game><game id="17985">Hatris</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2417948-gb_kirbysstarstacker_cropped.jpg</image></root>