<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10636</id><name>Summoner 2</name><description>OverviewThe main story follows Maia, Queen of Halassar and goddess reborn, as she tries to learn how to fulfill her prophecy to become the goddess Laharah and heal the Tree of Eleh. She is joined by a number of companions on her quest such as Yago, a character from the original Summoner game, who is searching for his missing daughter Rosalind. She must also combat the forces of the Tempest, a mysterious evil force who is trying to prevent her from fulfilling her destiny. The adventure takes the character all over the kingdom of Halassar and even to a different  dimension called "the Twilight Realm". CombatDuring the game you will acquire a number of allies though while traveling through the game you can only control a party of three characters.  Each time you enter a level you have to choose your party of three much like Mass Effect. You can only directly control one character though you can easily switch which of the three you are controlling. The majority of combat takes place in real-time and the game is paused when you want to cast a spell, use an ability or use an item. Summoner 2 uses a single button combat system, though there are seperate buttons for certain special abilities, spell casting and a block button. There is also a lock-on button which makes focusing on a single character easier, or you can just swing away at a group of enemies. Weapon CombatThe game includes the usual selection of fantasy RPG weapons such as swords, crossbows, hammer etc. with the exception of a robotic character that has an energy based ranged attack. All weapons are mapped to the same button, though the ranged weapons have a zoom function which makes sniping at distant characters possible. The weapons are character specific, and although there are no character classes each character fits a traditional RPG class archetype such as mage, warrior etc. The mage characters can only equip staff weapons, the warrior heavy swords and axes and so on. Also one of the charcters uses martial arts and does not equip any weapons. Magic CombatEvery character can use certain magic types or special abilities. There are a number of magic schools such as healing, cold, fire and so on and they range from direct combat magic to support magic. The spells in each school range from a simple fire arrow to causing a meteor-storm, and one of the characters even has a spell which encases the enemy in an iron maiden. When casting a spell the game is briefly paused while you choose a spell and target, though you can map one spell to the magic/item button to make casting faster. Casting spells and using abilities consumes ability points (AP) which can be replenished by consuming potions. SummoningMaia is the only character that can uses sumoning magic, just as Joseph was the only one able to summon in the original game and this limitation is story related. Unlike most games, including the original Summoner, in Summoner 2 instead of the summon being a seperate character, Maia actually turns into the chosen summon. This changes her appearance, attributes, spells etc. to those of the summoned creature. The summon has a time limit and Maia reverts to her original form when the time of the summon runs out or the summon is killed.  The time of the summon can be extended by increasing the summon skill and through the use of certain items such as rings which can even totally negate the time limit. The are 4 different summonable creatures each of which has 3 different forms which are uncovered through the story by finding speacial runes, which permanently upgrade one chosen creature. Once all upgrades are achieved a final 'ultimate' summon is unlocked. ItemsThe game includes the usual range of items found in most RPG games such as armor sets, enchanted jewelry, potions and scrolls as well as a whole range of miscellaneous items such as valuable gems and quest items.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2059">Dungeon Siege</game><game id="20238">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion</game><game id="1119">Diablo II</game><game id="17367">The Elder Scrolls III: Morrowind</game><game id="16449">Gauntlet: Seven Sorrows</game><game id="12245">Gauntlet Legends</game><game id="3156">Champions: Return to Arms</game><game id="13091">Baldur's Gate: Dark Alliance</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/4/48222/1464370-summoner2palfront.jpg</image></root>