<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1064</id><name>Ultimate Soccer Manager</name><description>OverviewUltimate soccer manager is a football management title that came to prominance in 1995. It was developed by Impressions games and published by Sierra Online. The title was a more light hearted and less hardcore alternative to the championship manager series at the time although it did contain some extra features over its competitor that lead to it still being talked about today.Features Stadium DevelopmentStadium DevelopmentIt was possible in the game to totally redevelop your stadium as long as you had the cash to pay. It was also the only football management title to date in which your stadium, or more accurately a stand of your stadium could burn down, leading to reduced attendances until the stand could be redeveloped. Other stadium options included the ability to set the prices and type of confectionary sold at the stadium as well as setting ticket pricesBriberyBribery was also an option in the game. It was possible to attempt to bribe the referee into helping your team win a game thought this often led to you being caught and sacked so a save game before the bribery attempt was a must. TeleTextTeletextOne of the most distinct features of the game was the ingame use of teletext. Teletext was used by you the manager to check football results league tables and other footballing news. although it seems outdated now, at the time this was a quirky way of accessing information that mirrored real life as the internet was not as widely accessible as it is today.TransfersTransfers in Ultimate Soccer Manager were staggeringly easy. As long as you had the funds and the player was not in the league above you transfers were generally accepted. Transfers also happened immediatly and there was no ongoing negotiations like you see in modern football management titles.Match EngineMatch engineThe match engine was a simplistic top down match engine that enabled the player to see his matches and tactics being played out with the aim of spotting tactical errors. In reality the match engine was just a collection of pre defined routines but there was a sufficient amount of them to make it unnoticeable.FutureUltimate Soccer Manager has been rumored to be a future XBLA release although nothing has been mentioned since the initial rumor.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="40">Soccer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1586">Total Club Manager 2003</game><game id="20784">Football Manager 2008</game><game id="22117">Worldwide Soccer Manager 2006</game><game id="8108">Championship Manager Season 97/98</game><game id="17370">Championship Manager: Season 01/02</game><game id="17239">Premier Manager 3 De-Luxe</game><game id="13826">Premier Manager 2</game><game id="13">Premier Manager 98</game><game id="6697">Premier Manager Ninety Nine</game><game id="5762">Premier Manager 3</game><game id="41450">Premier Manager</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5000/537634-ult_socc_man.jpg</image></root>