<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10682</id><name>Hercules: The Legendary Journeys</name><description>Plot (taken directly from opening of game)                   This is the story of a time long ago, a time of myth and legend, when the ancient      gods were petty and cruel, and plagued mankind with suffering.                    Only one man dared to challenge their power --     Hercules! Hercules possessed a strength the world had never seen, a strength surpassed only by the power of his heart. Wherever there was evil, wherever an innocent would suffer, there would be Hercules!                    Drinking an       elixir poisoned by Hera, Zeus, the almighty king of the gods, fell ill. This gave Ares, son of Zeus and half brother to Hercules, an opportunity to seize the throne. These events transpired unnoticed by the rest of the gods, who merely sensed an imbalance in the godly plane of existence. Most fled to the mortal plane to investigate the cause of this disturbance, causing turmoil among the mortals on Gaea. As most of the gods were either too busy or too petty to care about the mortals, it would be up to Hercules, and you, to save them. Are you up to the challenge? (unofficial summary)                           Ares, Hercules' brother, forms a plan to dethrone         Zeus with the help of        Hera. With Zeus ill, a struggle for power corrupts the immortal realm. The Gods, unaware of the true nature of the disturbance, flee to the mortal realm in a search to find the reason for the turmoil. Hercules, a man with strength unlike none ever seen, is the only one who can save the world, both mortal and immortal, and his father from certain doom. You take control of the legendary hero as you travel around the land in search of a cure, and to stop Ares from completing his plan. DescriptionHercules: The Legendary Journeys is a Nintendo 64 and Game Boy Color game from Titus (based on the hit television show). It centers around one of the most popular Grecian myths, that of Heracles, or, as he is better known,           Hercules. The game involves a combination of skirmishes with random enemies and bosses, elementary puzzles, and numerous trading sequences and side quests similar to the ones found in            Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time. The player can also play as two of Herc's friends, Lolaus and Serena (or the Golden Hind, as the half woman, half horse character is referred to in the game): they each have their own unique attacks and weapons. Legendary Journeys is known to have many bugs and technical issues (alongside its clunky controls) that make the game frustrating and unnecessarily difficult in numerous places. This game proved to be another high profile failure for the once beloved Titus as it continued to plunge deeper into the territory of poorly developed action/adventure games; directly following the release of the critically-despised             Superman 64.   Playable Characters     Though Hercules is the primary player character, the player does take  control of Lolaus and the Golden Hind during certain moments of the  game. Each of these characters have a unique control scheme;  unfortunately, perhaps due to a lack of care in the game's development,  the other two characters are both exceedingly difficult to control and  considerably weaker than Hercules. Nonetheless, the character's  attributes are listed below:    Hercules - The strongest and most primarily used of the  characters, Hercules' primary attack is the punch by way of pressing the  B button. Upon holding the B button, Hercules can also use a "super  punch" that does greater damage and can be used to break through  weakened walls. Furthermore, although all characters will stun enemies  after a certain number of hits (bosses excluded), Hercules is the only  character capable of picking up and throwing enemies; instantly killing  both the enemy and any other enemies with which the thrown one makes  contact. Furthermore, Herc is the only character that can purchase  potions from the tavern owner (who exists in all of the game's towns)  that unleash lavish special attacks centered around four elements:  earth, fire, lightning, and ice. The earth potion drops rocks from the  sky upon his unexpecting enemies; the fire potion unleashes burning  balls of molten lava upon Herc's adversaries; the lightning potion  performs a similar attack by way of giant, thundering lightning bolts;  and the ice potion temporarily freezes one's foe(s). These potions are  accessed via the C buttons. Although Hercules is the most overpowered of  the game's characters, his portions can be nonetheless difficult to  play due to a weak camera and the lack of a lock-on system.Lolaus - The sidekick of Hercules, Lolaus is useful as the  only character in the game capable of climbing vines (which have an odd  graphical similarity to those in Ocarina of Time). However, once he has  climbed said vines and reached whatever dangers await him at the top, he  is faced with the difficulty of fighting with his exceedingly  underpowered staff (perhaps he is Herc's sidekick for a reason, eh?).  Lolaus is also useful in one instance in which the snowy alps can only  be crossed by a body small enough to fit into the only available winter  coat. Lolaus cannot leave any of his designated playable areas however,  if the player tries, they are met with the message: "Perhaps I should  let Herc take care of this."The Golden Hind - Though christened Serena in the  television series, the game (for some unbeknownst reason) refers to her  as The Golden Hind. This lady Centaur is, in fact, the weakest of the  three characters. The Hind's only method of attack is the shooting of  her arrows, done in a first person mode. Although the arrows can be shot  in the standard third-person perspective, they are guaranteed to strike  nothing unless the enemy lies directly in front of the Hind. The  first-person mode is troubling however, as the controls are so  unbearably clunky and difficult to use that the player will have almost  certainly lost a considerable amount of health by the time he/she was  even capable of training his/her sights upon his/her adversaries.  Fortunately, The Golden Hind also has the smallest amount of game time  between the three characters; and, like Lolaus, is restrained to her  respective areas with a message identical to his.  </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12572">The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time</game><game id="20702">Superman</game><game id="8939">Xena: Warrior Princess - The Talisman of Fate</game><game id="4973">Xena: Warrior Princess</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/628/300446-hercules_01.jpg</image></root>