<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10693</id><name>Rags to Riches</name><description>This is a side-scrolling game in which the player plays a drifter wandering into the south side of a city, Starting areawhich is divided into four parts (with the original names such as North, East, South and West).The goal of the game is to earn $1,000,000. Since you start up as a drifter you need to begin by getting some money in order to get a haircut ( which is needed to get a job ). Money can be found on the streets in form of dimes and $1 notes. Empty bottles can also be found on the streets and then exchanged for money at several stores.When enough money is gathered the next goal is to get an education, first in High school and then College.The City  South - starting point in the game. This part of the city contains cheap food and hotels. There is a soup kithen in this part of town where you can fill up your rest/food meter for free. Money, in this part of the City is made by gathering dimes, notes and bottles on the streets. Rooms can be rent by the day cheaply. West - In this part of the City you need some money to survive as it is more expensive to live here. Money can be earnt here by doing random jobs. In order to get a job you first need to get a haircut and a shave (hair grows back in 5 days). Rooms are available only by the week. East - The Highschool and College lies in this part of town. Education is needed in order to get a high paying job in the north part of the City. North - High paying jobs are available here, so to reach the goal of $1,000,000 you need to work hard and invest your money. Just watch out for the IRS.  Dangers in the city The player need to avoid couple things in the game. Player in City Jail.   Police - if you do not have a haircut, the police will arrest you and put you in jail for some time in the South side of the City.  Robbers appear from time to time and if he catches up with you he will take all your dollar bills. IRS agents will take all your money except for dollar bills and dimes.  </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/343/754323-rags_jail.jpg</image></root>