<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10692</id><name>Heroes of Might and Magic IV</name><description>Heroes of Might and Magic IV is the fourth installment in the critically acclaimed turn-based strategy game series, and the last game to be developed by  New World Computing.The game includes 6 different factions, each with unique constructions , units and abilities. In order to conquer land and collect treasure, creatures and heroes must be recruited. Heroes in the game can advance up to level 70 and can learn skills that are based on other factions. An unique feature in this installment of the franchise is the inclusion of heroes on the battlefield. Previous games had the heroes play a more passive supporter role from the sidelines.The battle system in the game is similar to chess in that both players take turns to make their moves, by deciding where their unit shall move or attack.Each creature has its own damage , defense , and ability skill  during combat.  In game you need resources to build and recruit units and also to buy potions and some minor items for your heroes . The resources are:         Gold,        crystals ,       gems ,     wood ,     ore ,    sulphur and mercury .  FACTIONS 1) Might 2) Life 3) Death 4) Order 5) Chaos 6) Nature  Might - StrongholdThe Might faction relies solely on creatures with non-magic abilities, with the exception of the Ogre Magi. The heroes of the Might faction are the Barbarians.  LevelsDwellingsUnits Level 1Longhouse Centaur Stables                                          Berserkers                                           CentaursLevel 2 Nomad Tents Harpy PeakNomads                                         HarpiesLevel 3 Ogre Fort Cyclops Cave                                       Ogre Magi                                       CyclopesLevel 4 Behemoth Crag Cliff Nest                                      Behemoths Thunderbirds Life - HavenThis faction is centered around humans who have allied themselves with Angels. Life is allied with Order and Nature, and its heroes are the Knights and Priests. LevelsDwellings UnitsLevel 1Squire's Guild Archery RangeSquires CrossbowmenLevel 2Ballista Works Guardhouse                                    Ballistae PikemenLevel 3Monastery Barracks                                   Monks CrusadersLevel 4Altar of Light Knight's Chapter                                  Angels Champions Death - NecropolisThe Death faction is based on demonic and undead creatures. It is allied with both Order and Chaos, and is governed by Death Knights and Necromancers. Levels DwellingsUnitsLevel 1 Torture Chamber Cemetery                                 Imps                                 SkeletonsLevel 2 Kennels Barrow Mound                               Cerberi                               GhostsLevel 3 Spawning Pit MansionVenom Spawn                              VampiresLevel 4 Temple of the Damned Dragon Graveyard                            Devils                            Bone Dragons Order - AcademyThis faction use creatures that are based on resources, magic, and mechanics. It is allied with Life and Death, and perceive both Nature and Chaos to be untamed. Its heroes are the Lords and Magi.   LevelsDwellingsUnitsLevel 1 Halfling Burrow Dwarven Mines                          Halflings                          DwarvesLevel 2 Golem Factory Mage Tower                        Golems                        MagiLevel 3 Golden Pavillion Altar of Wisher                      Nagas                      GeniesLevel 4 Dragon Factory Cloud CastleDragon Golems                     Titans  Chaos - Asylum The Chaos faction is based on destruction and disorder, and supports all kinds of vile creatures. It opposes Order and Life. Its heroes are the Thieves and Sorcerers.  LevelsDwellingsUnitsLevel 1 Orc Towers Den of Thieves                   Orcs BanditsLevel 2 Statuary Garden LabyrinthMedusae MinotaursLevel 3 Volcanic Vent Black Wood                  Efreeti                  NightmaresLevel 4 Dragon Cave Hydra Pond                Black Dragons                Hydras  Nature - PreserveThis faction is the home to all Nature spirits, animals and elementals alike. Its natural enemies are Order and Death. The faction heroes are the Druids and Archers.  LevelsDwellingsUnitsLevel 1 Fae Trees Wolf Den              Sprites              WolvesLevel 2 Treetop Lodge Tiger Den            Elves White TigersLevel 3 Unicorn Glade Griffin Cliffs           Unicorns           GriffinsLevel 4 Magic Forest PyreFaerie Dragons          Phoenixes</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6919">Warlords III: Darklords Rising</game><game id="15976">Age of Wonders II: The Wizard's Throne</game><game id="15406">Disciples II: Dark Prophecy</game><game id="20359">Etherlords</game><game id="18414">Age of Wonders</game><game id="21130">Disciples III: Renaissance</game><game id="19052">Disciples II: Rise of the Elves</game><game id="18279">Age of Wonders: Shadow Magic</game><game id="9446">Dominions 3: The Awakening</game><game id="14504">Warlords IV: Heroes of Etheria</game><game id="32640">King's Bounty: Crossworlds</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/864/688349-heroes_of_might_and_magic_iv.jpg</image></root>