<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10751</id><name>Final Fantasy XII: Revenant Wings</name><description>OverviewFinal Fantasy: Revenant Wings is a spin-off of Final Fantasy 12 developed my Square-Enix.  Final Fantasy: Revenant wings, rather than take a pseudo-turn based approach to gameplay like its sister title, is a Real Time Strategy.   The story stars Vaan, now a sky pirate, faced with a new adventure.  Most of the cast from FF12 are included in this game and have the same amount impact on the story as they did in FF12 .  FF: Revanant wings sold around 421,000 copies in japan and it was very well received in North America receiving a 81% Metacritic Score. Plot Overview Vaan in FF:Revanant WingsThe story starts off with Vaan and his fellow adventurers fleeing away from a cavern after they have stolen two mysterious crystals. Vaan later, steals a vacant ship that is seems to become  active when the crystal is inside the main bay of the ship. When the ship is activated, it takes Vaan and his friends to a unknown series of islands. On one of the islands the gang meets an Aegyl(a Race of people in FF: revanant wings) named Llyud. Llyud informs the gang that his people are fighting off sky pirates that are trying to steal treasure and artifacts from the Aegyl people. Throughout the game you battle against many enemies and experience twists and turns in the story. GameplayThe gameplay in Revanant wings takes a step away from the turn based and tactics gameplay that is normally used in handheld Final Fantasies. In Revanant wings the gameplay is in the form of a Real Time Strategy game that focusses on the use of the stylus. You create a box over troops to select them then you tap an enemy to attack and tap the ground to move. The combat is focussed around your troops, each troop being led by your hero. In the game there are a total of 5 squads and each squad is led by one hero character. Each hero character has a set list of special abilities, for example some characters can revive and heal. For Gameplay of Revanant wingsevery hero character there is a choice of setting a gambit, so you can set one person to always heal when it is needed. There are 3 monsters at your disposal for each squad. These creatures (Known as "Espers" in the game) vary from three different types, a flying creature, a hand to hand combat creature, and a magic user. Each type of creature is stronger or weaker than another type, like a game of rock paper scissors. Flying creatures are weak to magic, hand to hand combat is weak to flying, and magic is weak to hand to hand combat fighters.There is also a summoning aspect to the game, meaning players must capture summoning circles and with these circles they can summon Espers to their party. These are mainly used to replenish the players numbers after troops have been destroyed. In Revanant wings heroes need to be revived in a different way, they are only revived if there are summoning crystals are on the field. These crystals respawn the dead hero.Revanant wings takes a throw back to the old Final Fantasies by giving the player a full world map to explore. The player can explore through different Islands on their Ship and move across the map to points in the area in order to initiate new missions.   On the top screen is the basic map of the battle field. On this screen you get to see where enemies are located, treasures you can collect, summoning circles, summoning crystals, and where squad members are located. Out of combat the top screen shows where missions are located and it's description. In cutscenes the top screen is used for objects to pan up and down providing more space for visuals in the cutscenes.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20571">Rondo of Swords</game><game id="6453">LostMagic</game><game id="21626">Heroes of Mana</game><game id="11939">Advance Wars: Dual Strike</game><game id="24124">Eco Creatures: Save the Forest</game><game id="22990">Blue Dragon Plus</game><game id="21642">Knights in the Nightmare</game><game id="17786">Growlanser Generations</game><game id="24075">Infinite Space</game><game id="25798">Takt of Magic</game><game id="26476">Dragon Quest Wars</game><game id="24252">Hero's Saga Laevatein Tactics</game><game id="27680">Luminous Arc 3</game><game id="12876">Mech Platoon</game><game id="22885">Robocalypse</game><game id="27338">Spectral Force Genesis</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1814637-box_ff12rw.png</image></root>