<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10852</id><name>Faceball 2000</name><description>OverviewThe November 1991 issue of Nintendo Power where Faceball 2000 was reviewed.Faceball 2000 is a first-person shooter developed by Xanth Software and published by Bullet Proof Software for the Game Boy on December 10, 1991 and the Super Nintendo Entertainment System on September 1992. Based on MIDI Maze for the Atari ST, Bullet Proof Software acquired the console publishing rights to the game and released the game in America, Europe and Japan. Players move around a mazed arena as giant floating happy faces, shooting large orbs at enemies to "tag them out". The game was also published for the Game Gear in Japan on December 17, 1993 by Riverhill Software. The Game Boy and Game Gear versions featured local multiplayer via the use of link cables (up to sixteen players on the Game Boy version and two players on the Game Gear version), while the SNES version featured two-player split-screen multiplayer. The four player link cable, which was only packed in with Nintendo’s F1-race, was necessary for playing the multiplayer.GameplayAn early level of Cyberzone mode.The game is a first-person shooter, where the player controls a floating head inside of a giant maze. Your goal is to eliminate enemy heads by shooting large orbs.The game features two normal modes and one hidden mode. The first mode is called Cyberzone, in which players must eliminate a set number of opponents before an exit opens up and they can progress to the next level of increasing difficulties. The second mode is called Arena, in which players can choose from a variety of enemies and stages to play on, with the goal of defeating all the enemies. The final, and hardest mode, is called Cyperscape. Instead of having to eliminate a set number of enemies, Cyberscape is much more maze-focused, not having a map for players like other modes. This mode can only be unlocked by entering a code in the player select screen. All modes can be played with two players.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23137">Maze War</game><game id="16825">Midi-Maze</game><game id="6611">Hovertank</game><game id="3276">Battlezone</game><game id="6413">Ultima Underworld: The Stygian Abyss</game><game id="921">Spectre</game><game id="14233">3-Demon</game><game id="27531">Greg Hastings Paintball 2</game><game id="34079">Pac-Man &amp; Galaga Dimensions</game><game id="2">Breakfree</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9560/1303159-faceball_front.jpg</image></root>