<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10857</id><name>The Journeyman Project</name><description>HistoryIn the twenty-fourth century, world peace is finally realized. However, the horrific nuclear war that had occurred prior has destroyed everything mankind has ever worked for. World in flame, humanity launches an airborne utopia known as Caldoria. Shorty thereafter, an alien race known as the Cyrollans invite mankind to join the Symbiotry of Peaceful Beings, an intergalactic UN of sorts. In 2308, a Cyrollan ship passed over the city of Caldoria and relayed a message over all communication devices. The message stated that the Cyrollans felt that mankind was ready to join the Symbiotry and that they would allow ten years of deliberation of their proposal. Then, as quick as it came, the ship sped off into deep space.PlotThe player assumes the role of Agent 5 (later identified as Gage Blackwood in the sequels) of the Temporal Security Agency, a covert organization that was formed after the construction of the world's first successful time machine. The machine, called the Pegasus Device, was dismantled and moved to a secret location after the potential to do great damage to the flow of history presented itself. The TSA was formed to safeguard history and protect it from those who would wish to alter it. In the year 2318, the Cyrollans return to Caldoria to receive mankind's answer to their invitation. Elliot Sinclair, who was believed to be the first human to discover time travel, plotted an assassination of the Cyrollan delegate. He had hoped his attempt would sway the Cyrollans into thinking mankind wanted no part in the Symbiotry. He also sends three robots back in time to prevent the Cyrollans from even thinking to invite mankind in the first place.Versions and RemakesThe original version pushed the limits of system requirements at the time, and was plagued by bugs and performance problems, especially in the PC version. Sanctuary Woods released a "Turbo!" version in 1994 that advertised up to a 300% performance increase over the original game. In 1997, Bandai Digital Entertainment released The Journeyman Project: Pegasus Prime, a substantial remake that added seamless animated sequences in the style of the sequel The Journeyman Project 2: Buried in Time.SoundtrackThe early releases of The Journeyman Project CD-ROM contained 9 tracks composed by Geno Andrews that could be played back on any audio CD player. These tracks were not included in the "Turbo!" version and were re-released later as part of The Journeyman Project: Pegasus Prime - The Original Soundtrack.No.Track TitleLength (11:32)01.Through the Roof1:0502.Temporal Quartet0:4903.Time Rings1:0204.Coprates Minor0:5305.Mars Maze2:5306.Caldoria Kiosk0:4107.Organic Walls0:2608.Plasma Rock1:2309.Journeyman Theme2:19</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3970">Myst</game><game id="16230">Riven: The Sequel to Myst</game><game id="18742">Myst III: Exile</game><game id="6125">Return to Zork</game><game id="11227">Jewels of the Oracle</game><game id="15225">DogDay</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/19013/761032-thejourneymanproject.jpg</image></root>