<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10872</id><name>Wu-Tang: Shaolin Style</name><description>OverviewWu-Tang: Shaolin Style is a four-player fighting game for the PlayStation. The engine for the game was originally developed for the game Thrill Kill, which when that game was abruptly cancelled, the developers, wishing to not have all their work go to waste, ported it to the making of various other games, such as this game and X-Men: Mutant Academy. The game was controversial for containing "offensive" content. It was released on October 31, 1999.StoryWhen the last master of the ancient kung-fu style of Wu-Tang, Master Xin, is kidnapped by the evil Mong Zhu, who plans on discovering the powerful secrets of Wu-Tang, Master Xin's students, who also happen to be the members of the Wu-Tang Clan, vow to track down Zhu and rescue their master. Their journey takes the Clan from Staten Island to China, and on the way, they must battle with the many minions of Mong Zhu until they can finally face off against Zhu himself. But when they arrive in China, they find out that Zhu has already found out the secret of Wu-Tang and killed Master Xin, Mong Zhu then realizes that the Wu-Tang Clan Ain't Nuthing ta Fuck Wit.GameplayThe combat in Shaolin Syle is similar to many fighting games in that it uses 2 punch buttons and 2 kick buttons along with buttons assigned to crouching and blocking. However, where it differentiates itself from other fighters is that it can have up to four people fighting simultaneously, and instead of rounds, each character has a pre-determined amount of lives in each battle. When a character loses a life, he respawns immediately, until no life is left; then he is out of the game.The game also features fatalities, but unlike most other games with fatalities, they don't involve inputting a special button sequence. Instead the fatality depends purely on what button was used to deal the finishing blow. Up to 5 fatalities can be unlocked for each character, 4 representing each of the face buttons and 1 for the throw move.The game features each member of the Wu-Tang Clan as a playable character each with a different fighting style. For example, ODB uses drunken boxing, Masta Killa is a ninja with a big knife, Raekwon is a master of shadow boxing and therefore fights only using punches, The RZA fights with two swords, like a certain member of the TMNT and The GZA fights with a so-called "Liquid Sword", which is basically a chain with a knife on the end. Mong Zhu and his minions are also unlockable characters.Wu Tang "W" Shaped ControllerA special edition of Wu Tang: Shaolin Style was released that included a special controller in the shape of the Wu Tang signature "W". This controller is a very rare collectors item now. Wu Tang controllers "ain't nothin" to game with.TriviaFeatured as the game that Jeff and Ryan must save from the evil Nuke.com in the first episode of the Time Trotters Animated Series. Because...we all know that it is a masterful, classic game.The game featured a "High Violence Mode" which required you to input a code cleverly hidden in the games manual (At the back of the booklet).</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21282">Thrill Kill</game><game id="2410">Def Jam: Vendetta</game><game id="3744">Def Jam: Fight for NY</game><game id="16690">Def Jam: Icon</game><game id="20100">Power Stone</game><game id="10081">Tekken</game><game id="2895">Battle Arena Toshinden 3</game><game id="22083">Def Jam: Fight for NY: The Takeover</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="20449">Mortal Kombat vs. DC Universe</game><game id="4855">Shaq Fu</game><game id="26346">Relapse: Resistance</game><game id="27591">RAZE</game><game id="10734">Heavy Metal Geomatrix</game><game id="15044">X-Men: Mutant Academy</game><game id="3965">X-Men: Mutant Academy 2</game><game id="17777">Rock 'Em Sock 'Em Robots Arena</game><game id="21313">Seikima II - Akuma no Gyakushuu</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2199438-box_wtss.png</image></root>