<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1096</id><name>Street Fighter II': Champion Edition</name><description>OverviewRyu, one of the twelve playable fighters, in his alternate attire.Street Fighter II': Champion Edition (known in Japan as Street Fighter II') is a fighting game developed and distributed by Capcom for the CP System (CPS-1) arcade hardware on April 1992. The first derivative (hence the "dash" in the title) of Street Fighter II, Street Fighter II': Champion Edition tweaked various gameplay elements (changing the speed, damage, priority, and other characteristics of normal and special moves) while allowing players to pick the same character (each player character sporting a different color scheme) and making the four boss characters ( Balrog, Vega, Sagat, and M. Bison) playable.Special Champion EditionSpecial Champion Edition was the console version of both Champion Edition and Street Fighter II: Hyper Fighting for the Sega Genesis, it had the following features.ArcadeKen Masters beats up a car.Titled simply Game Start in the in-game menu, arcade mode allows the player to choose from one of the 12 available characters to do battle against and AI opponent. The player would face all of the normal characters in random order followed by the boss characters, also in random order save for M. Bison who is always last. At set intervals during the arcade mode the player would be given a specific task to accomplish against the clock. These included destroying a car, a pile of bricks, and falling barrels.V.S. BattleV.S. Battle the player versus player mode of Street Fighter II: Champion Edition where each player chooses a single character to fight with.Group BattleThe Group Battle character select screen.Group battle is also a player versus player mode further broken into two separate variants.Match PlayIn match play both players first choose up to six characters to use. The players then fight with their selected characters in order until one side has been completely wiped out.EliminationElimination is identical to match play save for each player gets to choose how many characters they wish to use.HyperHyper offers all the same modes and options and the standard Champion option except the player gets to choose the hyper level for the game. The hyper level, 0 through 9, increases the speed of the game. Zero hyper being normal speed and nine being somewhere in the vicinity of 5 times speed. Also when in hyper mode the characters default to their alternate color scheme.CharactersNormalRyuKen MastersE. HondaChun-LiBlankaZangiefGuileDhalsimBossBalrogSagatVegaM. BisonCritical ReceptionElectronic Gaming Monthly gave the Genesis version of the game review scores of 8,8,9 and 8 out of ten. Martin Alessi, who gave the higher score wrote, "Every Genesis owner's dream come true is here! SF2 CE is a faithful translation of the arcade smash -- plus more. There are enhancements that aren't even in the Super NES version. Special matches and eliminations make this a great cart to play with a group of friends. The graphics have greatly improved and the speed is even faster too! Problem #1: You need the 6-button controller to enjoy it".</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8161">Street Fighter II Turbo: Hyper Fighting</game><game id="20456">Street Fighter IV</game><game id="1615">Street Fighter III: 3rd Strike</game><game id="14669">Virtua Fighter Animation</game><game id="16793">Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors</game><game id="3744">Def Jam: Fight for NY</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="9542">Night Warriors: Darkstalkers' Revenge</game><game id="2886">WeaponLord</game><game id="22820">Red Earth</game><game id="12125">Capcom Fighting Evolution</game><game id="10574">X-Men: Children of the Atom</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="1235">Street Fighter</game><game id="22953">Ultimate Fighter</game><game id="20678">Soulcalibur IV</game><game id="28437">Super Street Fighter IV</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2374558-genesis_streetfighter2.jpg</image></root>