<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11068</id><name>Kirby's Dream Land 3</name><description>OverviewKirby's Dream Land 3 was the third game in the "Kirby's Dream Land" series and the first to appear on a system other than the original Game Boy.GameplayKirby with some animal friends.Kirby's Dream Land 3 plays much like other Kirby platformers. Kirby travels through different stages and eats enemies to copy their attack abilities. What makes this game unusual in the Kirby series is the inclusion of Kirby's animal helpers. While they were first seen in Kirby's Dream Land 2, Dream Land 3expands on the lineup of friends by adding three new characters: Nago the cat, Pitch the bird, and Chu Chu the octopus. By traveling with one, Kirby can alter what his copy abilities do when he uses them. For example, without a friend Kirby's "Fire" ability transforms him into a fireball that acts as a battering ram. However, when he rides Rick the hamster the fire ability causes Rick to breathe fire at Kirby's enemies.GooeyGooey in action.Kirby's friend Gooey is available as a second character. Normally he is controlled by the computer and fights enemies on his own. However, a second player can take control of him and play along simultaneously with the first player. Gooey has almost all of the same moves as Kirby does, except that he heats things with a long Yoshi-like tongue instead of inhaling them. Gooey can be summoned at any time, but to do so Kirby must surrender a bar of his life meter, which will remain gone until Gooey leaves. Between them, Kirby and Gooey can only ride on one animal helper at a time. Kirby can recover his health at any time by swallowing Gooey.HeartsFancy meeting you here.To truly complete the game Kirby must earn a heart on every stage. To do this he must accomplish a mission that helps a character that hangs out at the end of every level. Looking at the character should normally give the player a hint as to what they should do to complete the mission. Examples of missions include stomping on flowers of a certain color but leaving others alone, or completing a level with a certian animal helper to show off to the character at the end. Some levels even featured cameos by other Nintendo characters; one level's heart character was Samus Aran, who would give Kirby a heart if he destroyed all of the Metroids, which only appear in that level.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15634">Densetsu no Stafy</game><game id="18376">Looney Tunes Back in Action</game><game id="14433">Sonic CD</game><game id="4474">Kirby's Dream Land 2</game><game id="19788">Kirby's Dream Land</game><game id="31732">Donkey Kong Country Returns</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2363906-snes_kirbysdreamland3.jpg</image></root>