<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11083</id><name>Rocky Rodent</name><description>StoryRocky's on the run once again for stealing food when he bumps in to the owner of the restaurant from which he just skipped out on. The owner beseeches Rocky: the mob has kidnapped his daughter and is holding her for ransom. If Rocky can save her and thrash the mafia goons that are tightening their grip on the city, Rocky will be able to eat all he wants at his restaurant for life. Not one to pass up a meal ticket, Rocky agrees and sets off on his quest across the vast metropolis to retrieve the restaurant owner's daughter.   Gameplay Things get hairy!  Rocky Rodent is a pretty standard mascot platformer. By holding down the run button, Rocky picks up a considerable amount of speed - something that comes in handy in later "chase" stages. But what primarily sets Rocky Rodent apart from the pack are his power-ups - there's no     Mushrooms,     Tiki Masks or   breakable TVs to be found in the world of Rocky Rodent. Rocky's power-ups come out of trashcans, and in the form of special hair styles. There are two hair styles in the game, and both have their own unique functions:  Hairspray: Styles Rocky's hair in to a giant pink spike, which can be used like a rhino horn to skewer enemies and break cracked ceiling blocks. By jumping in to certain ceiling types, Rocky can stick in to the ceiling and use it to flip around to the floor above.Electric Shaver: Gives Rocky a literal "Buzz cut" - an axe-like mohawk that can be thrown and returns like a boomerang. Can be used to cut things.In addition to being stylish, Rocky's hairdos also protect him from one additional hit of damage. If Rocky takes damage without a hair style, he will die. </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20205">Bubsy in: Claws Encounters of the Furred Kind</game><game id="17096">Bubsy II</game><game id="23901">Punky Skunk</game><game id="19337">Aero the Acro-Bat</game><game id="11514">Aero the Acro-Bat 2</game><game id="17584">Awesome Possum Kicks Dr. Machino's Butt!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2364641-snes_rockyrodent.jpg</image></root>