<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11120</id><name>LEGO Star Wars: The Complete Saga</name><description>OverviewLego Star Wars: The Complete Saga is a fusion of Lego Star Wars I and II. It is developed by Traveller's Tales and publishedIt's just like Star Wars, only with more Legos.by LucasArts and was released with largely positive reviews. The game has all the features of the first two games, however, there are also some new features added such as co-op, and customisable characters. The Complete Saga edition of the game contains more characters than Lego Star Wars and Lego Star Wars II: The Original Trilogy had, like Indiana Jones. It also included an online co-op mode and new challenges.GameplayThe Lego games franchise is fast becoming famous for it's easy to play, fun for all the family style. The gameplay consists mostly of platforming and action sequences, but it is broken up by puzzle solving sections. None of these areas are particularly challenging as the game is designed for family play. All six episodes in the Star Wars saga are represented in the game and are broken up into six levels each. Death holds no real consequence as your character merely breaks into pieces, only to be reformed instantly, with no loss of life. However, when you die, you lose studs, and this can be a detriment to your progress toward the "True Jedi" status meter filling up.There are also several unlockables to be gained by collecting studs (currency in the Lego Star Wars universe), which can be used to by characters, hints, cheats and many other things. "The Complete Saga" also contains deleted levels from previous Star Wars games and a "duel mode" which were not featured in previous games either.There is also a massive number of 162 playable characters available in the game which can be unlocked by playing through the story mode or purchased. These characters range from all of the 6 Episodes, from Yoda to Jar-Jar Binks, and even Indiana Jones. Any of these characters can be played in Free Mode and you can effortlessly cycle through a limited amount of other characters in-game to reach places that you couldn't in story mode. There is also a character creator function in the game, which lets you create your own character from any mix of the existing characters' parts.Each level has intriguingly-placed doors which can only be opened on a second playthrough on the "free roam" option by characters that you unlock later in the game, so each level must be done at least two or three times. This adds to Lego Star Wars' already large replay value.Co-op PlayA game for young and old alike.A huge part of the gaming experience of Lego Star Wars is its co-op play. At all times throughout the game there will be two characters on screen. If played as a one player game, the second character is AI controlled, but a second player can replace the AI at any moment. The second player simply has to press the start button and can drop out of the game at any time.Whilst the co-op feature isn't needed for the combat sections, many of the platforming and puzzle solving sections require co-operative thought to complete them. "The Complete Saga" introduced an online co-op mode which was not featured in the previous games.Replay ValueOne of the main assets of the Lego Star Wars games are their replay value, and "The Complete Saga" has by far the most. Players are given a lot of reasons to play through the levels again, like hidden areas, red bricks, gold bricks, and minikits. Also when you collect enough studs on the level you fill up a meter and you get "True Jedi" status. The different characters that you unlock throughout the game can be used to overcome specific obstacles in the level when you replay.CollectablesMinikits: There are 10 minikits on every level in the game, when all ten are collected they form a lego version of a specific vehicle from the Star Wars saga. These vehicles are then unlocked as playable in the vehicle missions. Finding all ten also earns the player 50,000 studs and a gold brick.Red Bricks: There is one red brick on every level of the game. Once found they unlock a cheat that can be purchased from the shop in the cantina.Gold Bricks: These are the reward for completing objectives in the game. There are 160 in total. They are gained in a variety of ways; finishing a level, acheiving "true jedi" status, challenges, minikits, and they can also be bought from the shop in the cantina."True Jedi Status": This is earned when the player finds a certain number of studs on a given level. The amount needed to gain the status varies from level to level.Challenge Minkits: Much like the regular minikits, there are 10 hidden challenge minikits on every level. To get these minikits the player must choose "challenge" mode; the aim of this mode is to collect all 10 minikits before 10 minutes has passed. They are hidden in different locations to the regular minikits, are blue in colour, and are not required to get all 160 gold bricks. 50,000 studs is the reward.CharactersThe game features 160 playable characters by being bought at the counter or using cheat codes:These are just a few of the many, many, MANY characters.Qui-Gon JinnObi-Wan KenobiTC-14Jar Jar BinksQueen AmidalaCaptain PanakaPadme (Battle)R2-D2Anakin Skywalker (Boy)Obi-Wan Kenobi (Jedi)R4-P17Anakin Skywalker (Padawan)PadmeC-3P0Mace WinduPadme (Clawed)YodaObi-Wan Kenobi (Episode III)Anakin Skywalker (Jedi)Chancellor PalpatineClone (Episode III)ChewbaccaWookieDarth VaderStormtrooperGonk DroidPK DroidBattle Droid (Security)Battle DroidBattle Droid (Commander)DroidekaRoyal GuardPadme (Casual)Darth MaulCloneGenosianBattle Droid (Geonosis)Super Battle DroidJango FettBoba FettLuminara UnduliKi-Adi MundiKit FistoShaak TiCount Dooku (Darth Tyranus)Grievous BodyguardGeneral GrievousClone Episode III (Sand)Clone Episode III (Pilot)Clone Episode III (Swamp)Clone Episode III (Walker)Mace Windu (Episode III)Disguised CloneDarth SideousRebel TrooperPrincess LeiaLeiaRebel FriendC-3POR2-D2Ben KenobiLuke SkywalkerHan SoloChewbaccaLuke (Stormtrooper)Han (Stormtrooper)Leia (Hoth)Han (Hoth)Luke (Dagobah)YodaLuke (Bespin)Lando CalrissianLeia (Bespin)Leia (Boushh)Luke (Jedi)Han (Skiff)Leia (Slave)Lando (Palace Guard)Leia (Endor)Luke (Endor)Han (Endor)WicketDarth VaderRebel TrooperStormtrooperImperial Shuttle Pilot (Black)Tusken RaiderJawaGonk DroidSandtrooperGreedoImperial SpyBeach TrooperDeath Star TrooperTIE PilotImperial Officer (Gray)Grand Moff TarkinHan (Hood)Rebel Trooper (Hoth)SnowtrooperLuke (Hoth)LobotUgnaughtBespin GuardLeia (Prisoner)Gamorean GuardBib FortunaPalace GuardSkiff GuardBoba Fett4-LOMEwokImperial GuardThe EmperorAdmiral AckbarWattoBoss NassZam WesselLama SuTaun WeR2-Q5Captain TarpalsAaylaa SecuraPlo KoonDexter JettsterPit DroidIndiana JonesXbox 360 Game InstallationLego Star Wars: The Complete Saga requires 5.8GB of space to install on a Xbox 360 HDD.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21818">Docomodake Boing!</game><game id="3438">MediEvil II</game><game id="1563">Spyro 2: Ripto's Rage</game><game id="6134">The Legend of Spyro: The Eternal Night</game><game id="20330">Gex 3: Deep Cover Gecko</game><game id="15991">Chameleon Twist 2</game><game id="7670">Crash of the Titans</game><game id="20258">Spider-Man: Friend or Foe</game><game id="10846">Avatar: The Last Airbender</game><game id="9685">Monster Jam</game><game id="4153">Bomberman Live</game><game id="19552">Pac-Man: Championship Edition</game><game id="8594">Gauntlet</game><game id="18492">Bee Movie Game</game><game id="24430">Bomberman Ultra</game><game id="7184">Trauma Center: Second Opinion</game><game id="25305">G.I. Joe: The Rise of Cobra</game><game id="15212">Ratchet &amp; Clank Future: Tools of Destruction</game><game id="6781">The Simpsons Game</game><game id="24397">Fairytale Fights</game><game id="26390">Star Wars The Clone Wars: Republic Heroes</game><game id="31415">Scooby-Doo! and the Spooky Swamp</game><game id="32196">Marvel Super Hero Squad: The Infinity Gauntlet</game><game id="27295">Up</game><game id="31669">Spare Parts</game><game id="9200">Star Wars: Episode III - Revenge of the Sith</game><game id="36898">LEGO Batman 2: DC Super Heroes</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1967517-box_legoswtcs.png</image></root>