<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11153</id><name>True Crime: Streets of LA</name><description>OverviewTrue Crime: Streets of LA was developed by Luxoflux and published by Activision on the GameCube, Mac, PC, PlayStation 2 and Xbox. It was released on November 3, 2003.True Crime: Streets of LA features hard-boiled cop Nick Kang-Wilson, son of Henry Kang-Wilson. The story involves Nick’s hunt for the top members of several gangs who have taken hold in Los Angeles. These gangs include the Triads and the Russian Mob. Throughout the game Nick is able to track down several men who may have information regarding his father’s mysterious disappearance.LocationTrue Crime takes place in a simulated Los Angeles, California. Although not entirely accurate, the game features a 240 square mile re-creation of the city which features recognizable street names and land marks.Game MechanicsTrue Crime: Streets of LA is an open world sandbox style gameplay that puts the player in the role of an undercover police officer. While completing the story missions the player can also choose to assist other officers with various calls ranging from bar fights to high speed chases or bank robberies. During this process the player may also commandeer vehicles to assist in his or her duties.Upgradable SkillsThe game features upgradable skills that Nick can work on to improve his performance. The player can choose to complete challenges in the following categories: Driving, Shooting and hand to hand combat.After completing a task in either category the player will be rewarded with an upgrade. This might be a better weapon, advanced driving techniques or a skilled grappling move.Shooting UpgradesDual Target AimAim AssistanceFast ReloadFast Aim SpeedLaser SightFlash LightScopeTop AccuracyHollow Point AmmoDriving UpgradesPeel OutRapid StopP.I.T. ManeuverDownshift Boost90 Degree TurnForward SwitchbladeBackward SwitchbladeTwo WheelsNitro BoostFighting UpgradesRunning AttacksBack AttacksGround AttacksTiger Sweep (combo)Tiger Claw (combo)Leaping Tiger (combo)Dragon Kick (combo)Dragon Fist (combo)Flying Dragon (combo)Morales and Branching Story LineTrue Crime features different story lines and endings depending on the way to play the game. Do you kill suspects or arrest them? Do you drive well or hit pedestrians on every curve? All of these things affect your good cop/bad cop rating. Even in situations when you are required to shoot at a suspect, you are judged on whether you inflict a fatal injury (head shot) or an immobilizing injury (arms, legs etc...). The player must also be careful not to accidentally kill civilians in the crossfire or damage city properly. The game features a good, bad and neutral ending, thus adding more replay value to the title.CharactersNick KangThe main protagonist in the game. Suspended from the LAPD for his misconduct, has since been recruited into the E.O.D (Elite Operations Division) to help clean up the streets of Los Angeles.Rosie VelascoRosie is Nick's partner, an ex-gang member recruited to the Elite Operations Division, however an injury lands her behind a desk for the majority of the story.Chief Wanda ParksWanda is the Chief Detective of the LAPD and coordinated the operation of the E.O.D.GeorgeMentor to Nick and a family friend, George also serves as the game's narrator.Snoop DoggSnoop Dogg is a hidden character in the game. He is playable and has his own minigames once the player collects thirty dog bones scattered throughout the city.RikimaruRikimaru from Tenchu is a hidden character in the game. He is playable if the player stealth kills all enemies in mission 6-G2. Ayame is also available.Voice TalentRussel Wong- Nick Kang-WilsonChristopher Walken- GeorgeGary Oldman- Rasputin "Rocky" Kuznetskov / Agent MastersonMichelle Rodriguez- RosieMichael Madsen- RaffertyCCH Pounder- Chief Wanda ParksRon Perlman- MishaMako- Han Yu KimJames Hong- Ancient WuKeone Young- Jimmy Fu / Big ChongRyan Yu- Cary WilsonGrey Delisle- Jill / LolaVernee Watson-Johnson- Police DispatcherSnoop Dogg - HimselfSoundtrackSoundtrack cover1. "Dance Wit Me"- Snoop Dogg2. "Terrorist Threats"- Westside Connection3. "Don't Fight the Pimpin'"- Suga Free4. "What U Wanna Do"- Warren G, RBX5. "True Crime Remix"- Young Dre, Bishop Lamont6. "I'll Do Anything"- Damizza, N.U.N.E.7. "Thug Night"- Jayo Felony8. "Hollywood"- Bizzy Bone9. "Drinks in the Air"- Hollywood10. "Don't Do the Crime"- Kam, Cavie, Above the Law11. "Legends"- Boo-Yaa T.R.I.B.E.12. "They Don't Know"- Dee Dimes, Bigg Swoop13. "Flow"- Sly Boogy14. "This Is How We Live"- Lil' 1/2 Dead, Kon-Troversy, Quicktomac15. "We Don't Stop- Soul Star16. "Can't Fuck With Us"- Tray Deee, Mr. Short Khop, Threat17. "Do Time"- Pomona City Rydaz, Lil 1/2 Dead18. "Roll Wit Me"- Young Billionaires19. "Cali Folks"- Stylistik20. "Lets Get It Crackin'"- Lil Eazy E / Co-Written By P"RizzyBoy"Floyd Jr.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20457">Grand Theft Auto IV</game><game id="17036">Grand Theft Auto: Vice City</game><game id="18163">Just Cause</game><game id="5618">Saints Row</game><game id="4065">Crackdown</game><game id="10593">Grand Theft Auto 2</game><game id="3345">True Crime: New York City</game><game id="20679">Saints Row 2</game><game id="10781">The Godfather: Blackhand Edition</game><game id="22353">The Godfather: The Don's Edition</game><game id="10264">Grand Theft Auto: Vice City Stories</game><game id="6731">Grand Theft Auto: Liberty City Stories</game><game id="9966">Scarface: The World is Yours</game><game id="20698">Wheelman</game><game id="20638">This Is Vegas</game><game id="20454">50 Cent: Blood on the Sand</game><game id="25286">Dead to Rights: Retribution</game><game id="23061">NARC</game><game id="27058">Necessary Force</game><game id="4241">Total Overdose</game><game id="27714">Dead Rush</game><game id="16255">50 Cent: Bulletproof</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2536378-box_tcsola.png</image></root>