<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11174</id><name>LEGO Racers</name><description>SummaryUpon release, Lego Racers was noted for its creation tools which allowed the player to create their own vehicle and driver. At the time the concept was regarded as innovative, and is one which has transcended through many other genres and is a staple in many new releases today. The player could then take their custom vehicle and driver for use in the game's adventure mode. The adventure mode consisted of numerous different worlds, each inhibiting their own end of series boss aswell as track. Upon defeat of the boss, their lego head, torso and legs, aswell as vehicle were them available to the player for use in the creation modes. The game reaches a climax as the player must defeat "Rocket Racer" the fastest racer in the lego universe, in order to claim the final trophy and title the ultimate lego racer  CustomizationLego Racers offers much in the way of customization. The player's car can be customized, using the Lego builder,  by adding Lego Bricks and various accessories onto a variety of unchangable pre-built chassis. Characters can also be customized in a way that , for the time, was quite revolutionary and innovative. The player can customize his/her character by changing headwear, heads, torsos, and legs.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19071">Super Mario Kart</game><game id="7480">LEGO Stunt Rally</game><game id="10084">Mario Kart 64</game><game id="6196">Crash Team Racing</game><game id="5366">Bionicle Heroes</game><game id="20645">Mario Kart Wii</game><game id="6539">Mario Kart DS</game><game id="16769">Mario Kart: Super Circuit</game><game id="22373">Mario Kart Arcade GP</game><game id="14134">Pac-Man World Rally</game><game id="8469">Shrek Smash N' Crash Racing</game><game id="14384">Woody Woodpecker Racing</game><game id="21405">Crash Tag Team Racing</game><game id="5561">Diddy Kong Racing DS</game><game id="15990">Diddy Kong Racing</game><game id="18757">Mario Kart: Double Dash!!</game><game id="310">NASCAR Rumble</game><game id="6272">Bomberman Kart DX</game><game id="12958">Cartoon Network Racing</game><game id="18221">Looney Tunes Racing</game><game id="17291">Atari Karts</game><game id="20906">Cocoto Kart Racer</game><game id="13178">Speed Punks</game><game id="6368">Mickey's Speedway USA</game><game id="26848">ModNation Racers</game><game id="4515">RC Revenge</game><game id="21285">Rollcage Stage II</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1379/277072-lego.jpg</image></root>