<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11221</id><name>Runaway 2: The Dream of the Turtle</name><description>OverviewRunaway 2: The Dream of the Turtle is a standard point and click adventure game that was first released for PC in France, November 17, 2006 and was not released until March the following year in the US.PlotBrian and his girlfriend Gina (who he fell in love with in the previous game) are on vacation in Hawaii and Gina keeps on insisting that they should take a flying trip to see the Tiki Falls and Temple on Mala Island. Brian is however not very keen on going but in spite of that they go. They travel with a travel agency named Platypus Tours in a rickety old plane with a pilot that is so old that he seemingly "kicked the bucket" mid-flight, thus forcing the plane to go down without a pilot and this is where the adventure begins.During his adventure Brian Basco will meet many interesting characters while trying to stay alive and save his girlfriend.GameplayYou manage the character Brian Basco by clicking on certain areas on the screen, picking stuff up and interacting with characters or objects.Often in this game if you find yourself stuck you might want to go back and check out stuff that you already checked out earlier because there might have been something that Brian missed at first when he inspected the item 'cause he did not know at that time why he would want to e g. fuse two objects or take a certain object.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17544">Broken Sword: The Shadow of the Templars</game><game id="4084">Broken Sword II: The Smoking Mirror</game><game id="5729">The Curse of Monkey Island</game><game id="3019">The Secret of Monkey Island</game><game id="9058">Escape from Monkey Island</game><game id="10528">Monkey Island 2:  LeChuck's Revenge</game><game id="30913">The Next Big Thing</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9408/1245264-run2pc0f.jpg</image></root>