<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11228</id><name>Command &amp; Conquer: The Covert Operations</name><description> Overview  Expect to be attacked early  often.     Released in April 1996, Command  Conquer: The Covert Operations is a "mission disk" expansion pack--and the only expansion pack--to             Command  Conquer.   As described in its README file, Covert Operations includes the following:  7 new GDI and 8 new NOD missions. 10 new multiplayer maps. 7 new songs in Redbook Audio format - so you can pop it in your CD player. Automatically patches your copy of Command  Conquer to the newest version available. The 15 new missions are all available immediately to be played from the main menu in any order.  They tend to continue the difficulty curve from the end of the original Command  Conquer, making them notably more difficult, on the whole.  The added cutscenes do not feature FMV with human actors (with one exception noted below); the cutscenes are all entirely CG. The Secret Dinosaur MissionsAfter installing Covert Operations, if Command  Conquer is started with the command line option funpark, beginning a new game as either GDI or Nod will a start a secret 3-mission campaign in which Nod battles against dinosaurs.  The introductory movie to this secret campaign features FMV with Kane instructing the player to investigate "reports of strange animal behavior." System Requirements  Flame tanks, burning bases down since 1995. CPU: 486/66 or higher.RAM: 8MB total, 6MB free XMS or EMS, 560KB conventional RAM.HD space: 30MB.CD: 2xCD-ROM drive.SOUND: Sound Blaster, Sound Blaster Pro, Sound Blaster 16, Sound Blaster AWE32 and 100% Sound Blaster compatibles, Gravis UltraSound, Gravis UltraSound MAX, Ensonic, Soundscape, Roland RAP-10, ESS Audiodrive, Microsoft, Sound System, Gold Sound Standard, Pro Audio Spectrum.DISPLAY: MCGA graphics (256 color, 320x200 pixel resolution).MOUSE: Microsoft Mouse or 100% compatible.DOS: 5.0 or higher.WINDOWS: 3.1 or higher.  For multi-player:    SERIAL: 2 players over minimum 9,600 bps modem, 14,400 bps modem or higher recommended.  2 players over null modem connection.NETWORK: 2-4 players over IPX compliant network.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="33907">APOX</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/11423/632182-115970_front_cover_super.jpg</image></root>