<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11321</id><name>Castlevania: Dawn of Sorrow</name><description>OverviewSoma Cruz returnsCastlevania: Dawn of Sorrow (known in Japan as Akumajō Dracula: Sougetsu no Jūjika, translated to Devil's Castle Dracula: Cross of the Blue Moon) is an action-adventure horror platformer developed by KCE Tokyo and published by Konami for the Nintendo DS on October 4, 2005.The sequel to Castlevania: Aria of Sorrow, Castlevania: Dawn of Sorrow is the first Castlevania game developed for the Nintendo DS and the fifth Castlevania game to use the modern Metroidvania structure of platforming based on free-roaming exploration. It is also one of the few Castlevania games to use an anime-inspired art style.Taking place in the year 2036, one year after the events in Castlevania: Aria of Sorrow, the game follows protagonist Soma Cruz (who is revealed in the last game to be the reincarnation of Dracula), who must investigate an evil cult (headed by shadow priestess Celia Fortner) dedicated to the resurrection of a lord of darkness.GameplayTactical SoulDawn of Sorrow's Magic Seal mechanic in actionFirst featured in Castlevania: Aria of Sorrow, the Tactical Soul mechanic allows Soma to absorb the souls of monsters and creatures he killed throughout the game. Each soul sports a unique power, and there are four categories: Bullet, Guardian, Enchant and Ability. Players can absorb a soul as much they want to except for the Ability souls that are unlocked through specific boss battles and plot points. Each specific soul has a different rarity; the better ones, like the Valkyrie soul, are much harder to get than an ordinary Zombie soul. At Yoko Belnades' shop, you can use absorbed souls to make higher-powered weapons with the penultimate versions requiring the rarest ones to find. If two people have a cartridge for Dawn of Sorrow, an option to trade souls through wireless connectivity became available. Souls relating to the storyline or souls that allow access to later parts of the game are not available through trade.Magic SealThe Magic Seal mechanic first appeared in Castlevania: Dawn of Sorrow with no appearances in the Castlevania series since then. During large boss battles, players received a prompt to draw a predetermined symbol to finish the boss off; there were no other options when defeating bosses. The further into the game the player got, the more elaborate the symbols became.Reception concerning the Magic Seal mechanic was generally negative and deemed as "unnecessary" or "pace-breaking" according to many players and reputable reviewers. This is Dawn of Sorrow's only use of the touch screen other than breaking crystal blocks or controlling familiars. The series has since abandoned extensive use of touch screen capabilities due to negative criticisms.Bosses  Alternate EndingsThere are 16 boss fights in the game:Boss fights are as gruesome as everFlying ArmorBaloreDmitriiMalphasDarioPuppet MasterGergothZephyrRahabBat CompanyParanoiaDario (again)AguniDeathAbaddonMenaceSome boss fights are optional as the game can be completed at three different points during the main story progression. However, to reach the true ending you need to find a way to the final boss room and beat Menace.Game ModesEnemy Set ModeHere, players can select the souls of any they've taken from adventure mode and create their own series of dungeons. The goal is to cut past all enemies on every screen and get to the end as soon as possible with the hero you have in adventure mode. Players can also challenge a friend to fight past their custom dungeons.Boss Rush ModeIn this mode you have to defeat all of the game's bosses in order. You are given a Super Potion, a Mana Prism and a Rusty Food Tin. The objective is to defeat the bosses as fast as possible. Depending on how fast you defeat them, you are given different prizes at the end.Julius ModeIn Julius mode you start off as Julius Belmont, and are later joined by Yoko Belnades and Alucard. You are able to swap between the three characters by pressing the X-button. You fight through the castle as in Normal Mode, except with a different story and a different final boss. The character swap system was later reused in Castlevania: Portrait of Ruin.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11010">Eternal Daughter</game><game id="8292">Super Metroid</game><game id="10323">Metroid Fusion</game><game id="14416">Ninja Gaiden II: The Dark Sword of Chaos</game><game id="17356">Metroid: Zero Mission</game><game id="887">Vampire: Master of Darkness</game><game id="1850">Ninja Gaiden III: The Ancient Ship of Doom</game><game id="6171">Fullmetal Alchemist: Dual Sympathy</game><game id="20435">Mega Man ZX Advent</game><game id="11103">Mega Man ZX</game><game id="2731">Mega Man Zero</game><game id="13623">Mega Man Zero 2</game><game id="9497">Mega Man Zero 3</game><game id="15108">Mega Man Zero 4</game><game id="6630">Aquaria</game><game id="13904">Ninja Five-O</game><game id="25429">Ore ga Omae o Mamoru</game><game id="2664">Phantom 2040</game><game id="1638">Mega Man X6</game><game id="17825">Ninja Gaiden: Shadow</game><game id="26706">Shadow Complex</game><game id="27074">Penguin no Mondai X: Tenkuu no 7 Senshi</game><game id="25307">Penguin no Mondai: Saikyou Penguin Densetsu!</game><game id="4208">Ys III: Wanderers from Ys</game><game id="32008">Soul of Darkness</game><game id="31268">Monster Tale</game><game id="27691">Dust: An Elysian Tail</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1773365-box_cvdos.png</image></root>