<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11346</id><name>4x4 Evo 2</name><description>  Overview      Gettin' Clean Before Gettin' Dirty      4x4 Evo 2 is a 3D offroad racing game set in a wide variety of locales.    Truck Selection4x4 Evo 2 ships with over 120 licensed trucks, though there are fewer base models of trucks; for example, there are 2WD and 4WD versions of most trucks, as well as different trim levels such as XE and SE attached to some models.  The vehicles in 4x4 Evo 2 are from 9 major manufacturers, Dodge, Jeep, Nissan, Infiniti, Lexus, Toyota, Mitsubishi, Chevrolet, and GMC. Truck ListTrim levels in parentheses Dodge Durango (SLT and SLT-Plus, 2WD and 4WD)Dakota (Club and Quad cab, 2WD and 4WD, Young Racing Race)Ram (2WD, 4WD, and Young Racing Race) Chevrolet Blazer  (K5, LS, LT, and Team Death Rally)TrailBlazer (2WD, 4WD, and Team Death Race)Silverado (Ext. Cab and Reg Cab, 2WD and 4WD)Suburban (C1500, C2500, K1500, K2500)Tahoe (2WD and 4WD) JeepGrand Cherokee Limited (2WD, 4WD, and DeGenaro Race)Liberty Sport (2WD, 4WD, DeGenaro Rally)Wrangler Sport (4WD and ARB Rally) NissanFrontier (2WD, 4WD, Desert Runner, and Stillen Race)Xterra (SE and XE, 2WD and 4WD, Stillen Race)) Infiniti QX4 (2WD, 4WD, and AFH Rally Edition) Lexus RX300 (2WD and AWD)LX 470 (AWD and Slim Rally) ToyotaTacoma Xtracab (2WD and 4WD, Ltd and V6, and PreRunner)Tundra (2WD and 4WD, Ltd and SR5, Sakurai Race)Land Cruiser (4WD)RAV4 (2WD and 4WD)4Runner (Ltd and SR5, 2WD and 4WD, Sakurai Rally) MitsubishiMontero (AWD and Vento Rally) GMCSierra (2WD, 4WD, Drehkraft race truck, ARB Sierra Monster Truck)Yukon (2WD and 4WD, XL and SLE)Jimmy (SLT, 2WD and 4WD) CustomizationIn 4x4 Evo 2 there are a wide variety of customization options, from companies such as Stillen, Warn, and ARB.  Upgrades such as winches, snorkels, tires, and lift kits were actually fully functional; i.e. you could use the winch to pull you out of a tough spot, provided your truck wasn't too heavy, snorkels would really prevent your truck from hydro-locking, and tires and lift kits would actually raise your trucks center of gravity. TracksThe game ships with 32 tracks, in a variety of locales and race styles.  There is a south american rally style track, a junkyard circuit, a beach loop, and the list goes on.  The tracks operate on a standard gate based system, though some do have minor branching paths between gates.  Track ListArctic Wasteland Arizona Autumn Leaves Baja Beach Bayou Flats Black Gold Castle Rock Construction Junction Costa Rica Rally Crazy 2001 Deadman's Gulch Desert Run Egypt Farm Road 109 Final Destination Laguna Del Sol Mediterranean Motocross Pikes Peak Quarry Lake Restricted Area Salvage Wasteland Silverton Pass Thailand Rally Tibet Cliffside Treasure Bay Tri Baja 250 Truck Stop 101 Vulture Canyon YukonCareer Mode The career mode in 4x4 Evo 2 is pretty standard, you start out with $30,000 to buy a truck with, and earn money through completing races or challenges.  You will then use these funds to purchase better vehicles or upgrade your existing vehicle. Race mode is relatively standard, though eventually you can attract a "sponsor" and gain access to special trucks and upgrades which differ based on which sponsor is chosen/attracted. Challenge mode has you and your truck dropped into a large open map to undertake a series of more-or-less insane tasks.   These tasks vary  from searching for priceless archaeological discoveries, such as the "ByTheLakeosaurus" (guess where that one is) for a professor at the Tijuana museum of natural history, to searching for a plane wreck on a series of deserted islands, to bringing aid to remote villages along the Alaskan oil pipeline.User Created ContentDue to the ease with which entirely new tracks and trucks could be added into the game, many user created vehicles and stages can be found, some of which far exceed the detail of the "stock" trucks and stages.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7242">1NSANE</game><game id="10826">Test Drive: Off-Road</game><game id="6001">Test Drive: Off-Road: Wide Open</game><game id="19066">Test Drive: Off-Road 2</game><game id="9109">Test Drive: Off-Road 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1795728-box_4x4evo2.png</image></root>