<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11448</id><name>Dance Dance Revolution 4thMIX</name><description>OverviewDance Dance Revolution 4thMIX (usually shortened to DDR 4th Mix) is the fourth game in the Dance Dance Revolution franchise.The game received several releases in the arcades. In December 2000, an upgraded version of the game titled Dance Dance Revolution 4thMIX Plus was released. It features fourteen new songs and altered charts on Maniac difficulty to provide extra challenge for players.SoundtrackThe arcade and home versions have different songs available. In the arcade version, the songs were displayed in different categories with several songs overlapping, which is why some are listed multiple times. Since 4thMIX Plus includes all the songs from the standard version, only the new songs are listed.Arcade (Japan) Cover  ClassicsSong TitleArtistBasicTrickManiacBad GirlsJuliet Roberts245Boom Boom DollarKing Kong  D.Jungle Girls256Eat You UpAngie Gold256El Ritmo TropicalDixies Gang267Flashdance (What a Feeling)Magika478Furuhata's ThemeCJ Crew feat. Sedge479Get Up (Before the Night is Over)Techotronic feat. Ya Kid K467Gotcha (The Theme from Starsky  Hutch)Andy G's Magic Disco Machine257Hero (KCP Discotique Mix)Papaya346HolidayWho's That Girl!456I Believe in MiraclesHi-Rise568It Only Takes a Minute (Extended Remix)Tavares356Kick the CanBus Stop367Kung Fu FightingBus Stop235Let's Get DownJT Playaz345Little BitchThe Specials467My Fire (UKS Remix)X-Treme456One Two (Little Bitch)Bus Stop467Only YouCaptain Jack247Saint Goes Marching (Remix)The Saint469Shake Your BootyKC  The Sunshine Band235SmokeMr. Ed Jumps the Gun346That's the Way (I Like It)KC  The Sunshine Band235The 7 JumpKen D246Upside DownCoo Coo357Vol. 4Ravers Choice468Walkie TalkieKing Kong  D.Jungle Girls357Pops -Side A-Song TitleArtistBasicTrickManiac1,2,3,4,007Ni-Ni13620, November (DDR Version)N.M.R.357BoysSmile.dk347Bu DamBack Ji Young347Bumble BeeBambee357ButterflySmile.dk345Cutie ChaserClub Spice347Dub-I-DubMe  My468Gimme Gimme GimmeE-Rotic346Have You Never Been MellowOlivia Project125HeroPapaya456HigherNM feat. Sunny356If You Can Say GoodbyeKate Project456In the Heat of the NightE-Rotic357LoveSonic Dream357Luv to Me (AMD Mix)DJ Kazu feat. Tiger Yamato478Make a Jam!U1357Mr. WonderfulSmile.dk467My Summer LoveMitsu-O! with Geila369Never Gonna Make (Factory Dance Team Mix)Morgana357OperatorPapaya357Pink DinosaurPapaya457Sung SukSpace A357Tell Me Tell MeS#ARP356XanaduOlivia Project146Young ForeverRebecca357Pops -Side B-Song TitleArtistBasicTrickManiacBa KkwoLee Jung Hyun467Baby Baby Gimme Your LoveDivas136Burnin' the FloorNaoki467ByulTeam136Can't Stop Fallin' in LoveNaoki358Dam DariramJoga468Don't Stop -AMD 2nd Mix-Dr. Vibe feat. JP Miles457Dream a DreamCaptain Jack467FaceN.R.G468Get Me in Your Sight -AMD Cancun Mix-Symphonic Defoggers with 1479368Get Up'N MoveSK357Hypnotic CrisisBlue Destroyers569If You Were HereJennifer567Keep on Movin'N.M.R.456La SenoritaCaptain. T467La Senorita Virtual2MB788Love Again Tonight (For Melissa Mix)Naoki feat. Paula Terry467Oh Nick Please Not So QuickE-Rotic457Rock BeatLoud Force478Silent HillThomas Howard267Stomp to My BeatJS-16567TubthumpingChumbawamba456WaLee Jung Hyun356Wonderland (UKS Mix)X-Treme467Euro  Rave  SpeedSong TitleArtistBasicTrickManiacBoom Boom Dollar (K.O.G G3 Mix)King Kong  D.Jungle Girls578Boys (Euro Mix)Smile.dk468Burnin' the FloorNaoki467Butterfly (Upswing Mix)Smile.dk468Can't Stop Fallin' in LoveNaoki358Captain Jack (Grandale Remix)Captain Jack479Dam Dariram (KCP Mix)Joga467Do It All NightE-Rotic358Dynamite RaveNaoki579Follow the Sun (90 in the Shade Mix)Triple J467Furuhata's ThemeCJ Cew feat. Sedge479Have You Never Been Mellow (MM Groovin Mix)The Olivia Project357Hero (Happy Grandale Mix)Papaya467If You Were Here (B4 Za Beat Mix)Jennifer468In the Navy '99 (XXL Disaster Remix)Captain Jack468Luv to Me (AMD Mix)DJ Kazu feat. Tiger Yamato478MusicHabegale467Night in MotionCubic22367Saint Goes Marching (Remix)The Saint469Shooting StarBang457The RaceCaptain Jack357Turn Me On (Heavenly Mix)E-Rotic467Vol. 4Ravers Choice468Konami Original ASong TitleArtistBasicTrickManiacAfronovaRe-Venge579After the Game of LoveNPD3145Baby Baby Gimme Your LoveDivas136Burnin' the FloorNaoki467Can't Stop Fallin' in LoveNaoki358Don't Stop! -AMD 2nd Mix-Dr. Vibe feat. JP Miles457Drop the BombScotty D.456Dynamite RaveNaoki579HigherNM feat. Sunny356HysteriaNaoki 190468Jam Jam Reggae (AMD Swing Mix)Rice. C feat. Jam Master 73278Keep on Movin'N.M.R.456La SenoritaCaptain. T467La Senorita Virtual2MB788Let the Beat Hit Em!Stone Bros.367Let Them MoveN.M.R.367Let's Talk It OverShin Murayama feat. Argie Phine256Love Again Tonight (For Melissa Mix)Naoki feat. Paula Terry467Luv to Me (AMD Mix)DJ Kazu feat. Tiger Yamato478Make It BetterMitsu-O!457Make It Better (So-Real Mix)Mitsu-O!568Make Your MoveGood-Cool feat. JP Miles467My Summer LoveMitsu-O! with Geila369Never Let You DownGood-Cool feat. JP Mies357Orion.78 (AMeuro-Mix)Re-Venge359Put Your Faith in MeUzi-Lay346Put Your Faith in Me (Jazzy Groove)Uzi-Lay456Silent HillThomas Howard267Think Ya Better DSami345Konami Original BSong TitleArtistBasicTrickManiac.59DJ Taka467AM-3PKTz568B4UNaoki458Brilliant 2UNaoki456Brilliant 2U (Orchestra Groove)Naoki567Dead EndN  S579Drop OutNW260578End of the CenturyNo. 9478Era (Nostalmix)TaQ368Gentle Stress (AMD Sexual Mix)Mr. Dog feat. DJ Swan578Get Me in Your Sight -AMD Cancun Mix-Symphonic Defoggers with 1479368Gradiusic Cyber (AMD G5 Mix)Big-O feat. Taka579HolicTaQ468Hypnotic CrisisBlue Destroyers569Leading CyberDJ Taka579Love This Feelin'Chang Ma678Paranoia180678Paranoia (KCET Clean Mix)2MB678Paranoia Evolution200678Paranoia Max (Dirty Mix)190688Paranoia Rebirth190'679SP-Trip Machine (Jungle Mix)De-Sire678Super StarDJ.Rich feat. Tail Bros.568Trip MachineDe-Sire678Trip Machine (Luv Mix)2MB678Trip Machine ClimaxDe-Sire579Wild RushFactor-X456Special SelectionSong TitleArtistBasicTrickManiacAM-3PKTz568Boom Boom DollarKing Kong  D.Jungle Girls256Brilliant 2U (Orchestra Groove)Naoki567Dream a DreamCaptain Jack467El Ritmo TropicalDixies Gang267Gentle Stress (AMD Sexual Mix)Mr. Dog feat. DJ Swan578Get Up (Before the Night is Over)Technotronic feat. Ya Kid K467Gotcha (The Theme from Starsky  Hutch)Andy G's Magic Disco Machine257HigherNM feat. Sunny356HolidayWho's That Girl!456I Believe in MiraclesHi-Rise568In the Heat of the NightE-Rotic357Kick the CanBus Stop367Let's Get DownJT Playaz345Love Again Tonight (For Melissa Mix)Naoki feat. Paula Terry467Make a Jam!U1357Make It BetterMitsu-O!457MusicHabegale467My Summer LoveMitsu-O! with Geila369Night in MotionCubic22367One Two (Little Bitch)Bus Stop467Only YouCaptain Jack247OperatorPapaya357Put Your Faith in Me (Jazzy Groove)Uzi-Lay456Stomp to My BeatJS-16567The 7 JumpKen D246Walkie TalkieKing Kog  D.Jungle Girls357Young ForeverRebecca357Arcade (Japan, 4thMIX Plus) Cover  ClassicsSong TitleArtistBasicTrickManiacCafeD.D.Sound357Pops -Side A-Song TitleArtistBasicTrickManiacPetit LoveSmile.dk367Pops -Side B-Song TitleArtistBasicTrickManiacNa-NaBus Stop358Euro  Rave  SpeedSong TitleArtistBasicTrickManiacCat's Eye (Ventura Mix)E-Rotic358Conga FeelingVivian358Lupin the 3rd '78Ventura369Rhythm and Police (K.O.G G3 Mix)CJ Crew feat. Christian D469Sky HighLucyfer468Synchronized Love (Red Monster Hype Mix)Joe Rinoie458Woda (Speed K Mix)MM469Konami Original ASong TitleArtistBasicTrickManiacCelebrate NiteN.M.R467Konami Original BSong TitleArtistBasicTrickManiacDo Me -H.I.G.E.O. Mix-Mustache Men369Sexy PlanetCrystal Aliens567Theme from Enter the Dragon -Revival2001 Mix-B3-Project468Special SelectionSong TitleArtistBasicTrickManiacTubthumpingChumbawamba456Playstation (Japan)Song TitleArtistBasicTrickManiac.59DJ Taka4671,2,3,4,007Ni-Ni136B4UNaoki458Baby Baby Gimme Your LoveDivas136Boys (Euro Mix)Smile.dk468Bumble BeeBambee357Burnin' the FloorNaoki467Dam Dariram (KCP Mix)Joga467Dancing All AloneSmile.dk211Don't Stop -AMD 2nd Mix-Dr. Vibe feat. JP Miles457Dream a DreamCaptain Jack467Eat You UpAngie Gold256Era (NostalMix)TaQ368Follow the Sun (90 in the Shade Mix)Triple J467Furuhata's ThemeCJ Crew feat. Sedge479Get Me in Your Sight -AMD Cancun Mix-Symphonic Defoggers with 1479368Gimme Gimme GimmeE-Rotic346Gotcha (The Theme from Starsky  Hutch)Andy G's Magic Disco Machine257GrooveSho-T feat. Brenda468Have You Never Been Mellow (MM Groovin Mix)The Olivia Project357Hero (Happy Grandale Mix)Papaya467Hero (KCP Discotique Mix)Papaya346HigherNM feat. Sunny356HolicTaQ468Hypnotic CrisisBlue Destroyers569If You Were Here (B4 Za Beat Mix)Jennifer468In the Heat of the NightE-Rotic357It Only Takes a Minute (Extended Remix)Tavares356Kick the CanBus Stop367Leading CyberDJ Taka579Let's Talk It OverShin Murayama feat. Argie Phine256Love Again Tonight (For Melissa Mix)Naoki feat. Paula Terry467Make Your MoveGood-Cool feat. JP Miles467Midnite BlazeU1 Jewel Style458MusicHabegale467My Summer LoveMitsu-O! with Geila369Never Gonna Make (Factory Dance Team Mix)Morgana357Never Let You DownGood-Cool feat. JP Miles357Night in MotionCubic22367One Two (Little Bitch)Bus Stop467Only YouCaptain Jack247Orion.78 (Civilization Mix)2MB689Orion.78 (AMeuro-Mix)Re-Venge359Pink DinosaurPapaya457Saint Goes Marching (Remix)The Saint469Shake Your BootyKC  The Sunshine Band347Share My LoveJulie Frost345Shooting StarBang457Synchronized Love (Red Monster Hyper Mix)Joe Rinoie458The 7 JumpKen D246Trip Machine ClimaxDe-Sire579Walkie TalkieKing Kong  D.Jungle Girls357XanaduOlivia Project146Young ForeverRebecca357</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21746">Dance Dance Revolution SuperNOVA 2</game><game id="7010">StepMania</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9261/294107-psx_dancedancerevolution4th.jpg</image></root>