<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1145</id><name>Pokémon Dash</name><description>OverviewPokemon dash is a Nintendo DS racing game based on the Pokémon Franchise.PlotPikachu frolickingPlayers control Pokémon in a race, just one more competition for the psuedo-animals as no real story is implemented.GameplayPlayers rub the DS touch screen to guide their chosen racer around a Pokémon shaped race track, from a top down view. This game was largely considered one of the worst Pokemon spin-off games.What made it what it wasMeowth in a neck on raceEssentially this game was a tech-demo for the (then) newly launched Nintendo DS. It featured touchscreen only controls, adding to the experience that you are racing animals not vehicles, because you had to actually work a bit more than just pushing buttons. It also had GBA slot 2 connectivity with all GBA Pokemon games. Insterting one of these allowed you to ulock new tracks based on which pokemon you had captured on the cartidge.Nintendo knew that the Pokemon name would move the game no matter what, so they used it as a jumping board to aclimate users to DS touch screen. Much in the same way that Nintendo uses Wii-play to "teach" the new controller scheme.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6539">Mario Kart DS</game><game id="31747">Mario Kart 7</game><game id="20645">Mario Kart Wii</game><game id="18757">Mario Kart: Double Dash!!</game><game id="10084">Mario Kart 64</game><game id="19071">Super Mario Kart</game><game id="22373">Mario Kart Arcade GP</game><game id="25285">Mario Kart Arcade GP 2</game><game id="15990">Diddy Kong Racing</game><game id="5561">Diddy Kong Racing DS</game><game id="31769">Chocobo Racing 3D</game><game id="15977">Walt Disney World Quest Magical Racing Tour</game><game id="11831">M&amp;M's Kart Racing</game><game id="25026">MySims Racing</game><game id="21269">Nicktoons Racing</game><game id="8469">Shrek Smash N' Crash Racing</game><game id="18221">Looney Tunes Racing</game><game id="30103">Family Go-Kart Racing</game><game id="18389">Digimon Rumble Arena</game><game id="14870">Digimon Tamers: Digimon Medley</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2098007-box_pdash.png</image></root>