<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11473</id><name>Full Auto</name><description> Overview Never miss a momentFull Auto is a   Vehicular Combat Racing game developed by    Pseudo Interactive and published by   Sega. It was released on February 15th, 2005 exclusively for the Xbox 360. Full Auto combines fast paced racing, guns, and the ability to manipulate time all into one game; with a variety of modes, fast cars, and online multiplayer.Gameplay Full Auto's gameplay is quite different compared to that of traditional console racers, in that it introduces several gameplay elements which add a whole new layer to the racing. The Career mode presents players with a large number of different challenges, such as playing as different classes and different kinds of events which can be extremely challenging by the end of the game.BoostAs the name implies, boost gives you the nitro juice you need to burst ahead of the competition. Boost is earned by performing stunts such as jumps and power slides. The flashier and the more reckless you drive, the more boost you receive. Boost is only available once the boost meter is completely full and flashing.UnwreckShould players make a mistake while driving that results in a crash or that slows them down, unwreck can be triggered. Unwreck lets you turn back time a few seconds to the moment where the mistake was made and replay that event in an attempt to avoid making the mistake. Similar to boost, the unwreck meter builds up by destroying the environment and other cars. This encourages players to fire their weapons as much as possible throughout the race. Unwreck cannot be used in Multiplayer races.Self-DestructShould you find yourself in an inescapable situation or simply want to deprive a competitor of a kill, you can self-destruct your vehicle and re-start at your current position after a brief delay. This feature is usually used when a player finds themselves with an empty unwreck meter.One-Touch Replay Full Auto features One-Touch Replay at all times during offline racing, allowing instant access to cinematic replays of every moment of previous gameplay. This provides players an easy method to replay some of the many ridiculous crashes that occur throughout the game.VehiclesGuns   Speed   Explosions = Full AutoThere are 4 vehicle classes in Full Auto, A B C and S. A cars are fast but weak, B cars are average speed and average strength, C cars are extremely tough but slow, and S cars are extremely fast but weak. Vehicles, vehicle colours, tracks and weapons are unlocked throughout the career mode.EnforcerThis highway patrol cruiser generates a high top speed, but comes up short on handling and durability. It's stable on dry pavement, but its weight makes acceleration sluggish. The Enforcer's armored front grill is good for ramming, but the rest of the car is not durable.Durability: 1 Handling: 5 Speed: 4 PhantomThis vintage sports car is strong on torque if a little weak on handling. While it's on the fragile side, it's plenty fast enough to leave younger cars in the dust.Durability: 2 Handling: 3 Speed: 4 WraithThis high-performance sports car has a low center of gravity and low profile tires. Extremely fast, it's spectacularly suited for drift racing through the corners.Durability: 1 Handling: 3 Speed: 5 StreamlineThe Streamline is a luxury coupe with excellent speed and power acceleration. Its short wheel base and soft suspension give it body roll and a tendency to break loose in corners, and it is not the toughest car on the road.Durability: 1 Handling: 5 Speed: 4 DemonThis hotrod drag racer generates awesome speed but the only thing worse than its handling is its durability. Its short wheelbase makes it maneuverable, but its strong acceleration gives it a tendency to fishtail and oversteer.Durability: 1 Handling: 2 Speed: 4 OutlawThis stock racer has excellent speed and average handling, but it is unrefined with a powerful engine that often outperforms its suspension. Its lack of durability makes the Outlaw a one hit wonder.Durability: 1 Handling: 4 Speed: 5 VulcanThis classic muscle car generates good power with its rear-wheel drive and fat tires. It is very balanced with great handling, decent speed, handling, and acceptable durability.Durability: 2 Handling: 4 Speed: 4 TECA luxury tuner, the TEC S-2 has a good balance of speed, handling, and durability. It's better on paved roads than it is going cross-country.Durability: 2 Handling: 3 Speed: 4 MagnusAn overall good car, this performance SUV is very capable with the handling. Its sticky, all terrain tires are its strongest characteristic.Durability: 3 Handling: 2 Speed: 2 OpulentThis luxury sedan generates excellent speed thanks to its smooth aerodynamics. It also handles well due to its soft but sporty suspension.Durability: 3 Handling: 3 Speed: 3 ArdentA sleek sports coupe, the Ardent's handling is superb in the corners. Its top speed won't blow anyone away, but it's more than acceptable. The Ardent's small size makes it vulnerable to damage.Durability: 2 Handling: 4 Speed: 3 PythonThis classic has been tricked out and lowered for cruising. The Python's soft springs smooth out the bumps, but its low ground clearance and limited suspension travel limit its dampening ability. Its vintage Detroit steel gives it moderate durabilityDurability: 3 Handling: 2 Speed: 4 KodiakThis Baja-style truck is tough, and it's built to soak up every bump in the road, whether on asphalt or dirt. It's handling is best suited for off-road use, however.Durability: 3 Handling: 3 Speed: 3 JupiterThis classic was built before planned obsolescence was the modus operandi of the auto industry. It can take a beating and come through with hardly a scratch. Its weight takes a toll when it comes to acceleration and speed though.Durability: 4 Handling: 2 Speed: 3 HonchoA tricked-out SUV that's more show than anything, the Honcho has excellent durability but poor speed and handling due to its wide girth and massive weight.Durability: 4 Handling: 2 Speed: 2 GuardianIf you fancy a limo ride then the Guardian is for you. It's extremely tough due to its armor-plating and run-flat tires, but its speed and handling are not the best.Durability: 5 Handling: 2 Speed: 2 RoughneckThis 4x4 is hard to damage, and also hard to handle. While it excels against other cars on uneven and slippery surfaces, its short wheelbase and high center of gravity make it skittish when cornering at speed.Durability: 4 Handling: 2 Speed: 2 HitmanVintage luxury, excellent protection, and average handling and speed. Its long wheelbase makes it stable at full speed but also somewhat sluggish.Durability: 4 Handling: 2 Speed: 3 RampartWith its front-mounted plow, the Rampart is great for sweeping aside the competition. If you can catch up to them, that is. It handles well off-road and over bumpy terrain.Durability: 4 Handling: 2 Speed: 2 HookzillaDid someone call a tow-truck? Hookzilla is as indestructible as a lump of iron, and almost as fast. Its wide stance and quad rear tires give it stability and excessive momentum. If you want to bully other cars on the road, Hookzilla is the vehicle for you.Durability: 5 Handling: 2 Speed: 1 WarlordThis low-slung monster would be at home transporting any movie superhero. It's fast, heavily-armed, and literally the only car in its class. Resembles the Batmobile.Durability: 5 Handling: 4 Speed: 5 WeaponsWeapons can decide your outcomeYour Full Auto vehicle can be customized with a wide variety of weapons. Weapons are classified as forward mounting, rear mounting, or variable weapons that can be mounted front or rear. Each weapon is available in three Levels, with 1 being the least powerful and 3 being the most powerful. Players decide which 2 different weapons and their tuning are installed on their vehicle.Twin Machine GunsTwo Forward mounted machine guns spray shots at a very high rate of fire. Shots cause light damage individually, but in a hail they can be deadly.Level 1: .30 cal forward-firing Machine guns are standard. Level 2: .50 cal Machine guns, longer range, and more deadly than Level 1. Level 3: .50 cal High Velocity Ammo. More powerful than Level 2, these guns will chew the back-end off any vehicle. Mini-rocket PodThis weapon fires a salvo of small rockets with each shot. The individual rockets cause only light damage, but as their numbers increase, damage escalates and splash damage is possible. When upgraded, damage potential increases and Blast effects become possible. Rockets become incendiary with Burn effects at Level 3.Level 1: standard; a salvo of four rockets, each only causing light damage. Level 2: same as Level 1, but pod is now Aim-enabled and rockets now cause Blast. Level 3: Hellfire. Same as level 2, but rockets now cause Burn at the point of detonation. MissilesMissiles are larger, more powerful versions of the rocket pods. Even at Level 1, they cause heavy damage and are powerful enough to cause splash damage individually, with a greater radius than rocket pods.Level 1: Standard level missiles. Level 2: same as Level 1, but missiles can now be aimed. Level 3: same as Level 2 but missiles now track targets acquired at point of ignition. Tank CannonThe Cannon is a very powerful single-shot gun. Its ballistic shot fires faster and hits harder than a missile. It is slow to reload, but really packs a punch.Level 1: Sabot, an armor-piercing round that causes heavy damage and Force impact. Level 2: H.E.A.T. (High Explosive Anti-Tank). An explosive shell that has the same punch as a Sabot, but now with Blast. Level 3: Earth-shaker rounds. This cannon upgrade keeps the same effects as Level 2, but increases the radius of the Blast, and increases Force. MinesMines are canisters containing explosive charges that can be dropped behind the vehicle. They are disc-shaped and approximately 45cm in diameter. They are ejected behind a vehicle  and initially detonate only upon contact with an enemy vehicle. An excellent defense against tailgaters, mines have all the ferocity of a missile, with none of the targeting concerns.Level 1: Passive. As described above, passive mines sit awaiting enemy contact to detonate. The mine packs the same blast, splash, and damage of a standard missile. Level 2: Large Blast, same as Level 1, but with an increased radius blast force. Level 3: Proximity, same as Level 2, but upon detonation smaller explosives are released and scattered across the roadway. Smoke ScreenTear gas canisters are mounted with a high-speed fan turbine on the rear of a vehicle, giving this weapon the ability to project clouds of smoke behind it. These clouds of smoke make driving difficult for pursuing drivers as they are blinded while moving through them.Level 1: Standard. This generates a cloud that is approximately 8' high and 10' wide. It continues to project this cloud until the trigger is released or ammunition is exhausted. Level 2: Wide spread. Same as Level 1, but a second smoke nozzle adds to the width of the cloud from 10' to about 15'. Level 3: Darkness. Same as Level 2, but with increased exhaust time and density. ShotgunThe Shotgun fires a single cartridge at a time with great force, but a short range. The cartridge is comprised of many small pellets, making the weapon equally useful in the front or rear since the shotgun's wide range requires minimal aiming. On a substantial hit, the shotgun will inflict force also.Level 1: Double barrel. Same as description, dumb fire front and back. Level 2: Aim-enabled. Same as in Level 1, but if mounted front, the shotgun now has traverse and an aiming reticule. Level 3: Same as Level 2, but much more powerful. Grenade LauncherThe Grenade Launcher fires timed fragmentation explosives. Although less powerful than mines, grenades have a better chance of hitting enemies due to their sheer numbers. A grenade detonates on a delay of roughly 2 seconds, or upon contact with a critical target. As the grenade launcher is a dual weapon, it can be used to good effect mounted either front or rear. In the rear, it is similar in effect to the mine dropper, but with a better area of effect.Level 1: Standard, same as described above, dumb fire front or back. Level 2: Aim-enabled, high explosive. Same as Level 1, but if mounted on front, the launcher now has traverse and an aiming reticule. In addition, the grenades are not more powerful. Level 3: Cluster bombs. Same as Level 2, but now the salvo of grenades increases in number MultiplayerFull Auto features three multiplayer modes, online multiplayer over Xbox Live, splitscreen versus mode, and an arcade mode against NPC's of varying difficulty.Where friends become enemies All three feature three event types;  Circuit, Point to Point, and Down-and-Back. Circuit consists of the basic around the track run with a set number of laps, Point to Point is basically a rally from point A to point B, and Down-and-Back is the same as Point to Point only the player must return to point A after reaching point B. Before each match, the host specifies which car class can be used, the event type, and then the track. Online, players will be awarded a rank throughout their playtime. 10 being the highest and 0 being the lowest. Rank raises and lowers depending on whether they win or lose.Xbox 360 InstallationFull Auto requires 3.4GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16492">Burnout Revenge</game><game id="6836">FlatOut: Ultimate Carnage</game><game id="5648">Burnout Paradise</game><game id="357">Burnout 3: Takedown</game><game id="20484">Burnout</game><game id="12142">Full Auto 2: Battlelines</game><game id="12976">Need for Speed: Most Wanted</game><game id="11055">NASCAR 08</game><game id="859">FlatOut 2</game><game id="20038">NASCAR: Dirt to Daytona</game><game id="6426">Twisted Metal: Black</game><game id="284">NASCAR 2005: Chase for the Cup</game><game id="8438">NASCAR 06: Total Team Control</game><game id="16728">Powerslide</game><game id="25523">Split/Second</game><game id="26054">Cars</game><game id="26055">Cars Supercharged</game><game id="25961">Blur</game><game id="11445">Need for Speed: Most Wanted 5-1-0</game><game id="26566">Crash 'n' Burn</game><game id="43073">Need For Madness 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2543555-box_fullauto.png</image></root>