<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11500</id><name>Windjammers</name><description>ConceptTwo players face off in an arena with a low net in the middle. Points are scored by throwing a disc into the goals behind a player or whenever your opponent is not able to catch the disc in time. The nets behind the players are broken up into three sections consisting of either two 3-point sections with one 5-point section, or two 5-point sections with one 3-point sections. On some stages, the goal sizes will change depending on the score.GameplayThere are two basic moves: a regular throw and a lob. By using quarter-circle and half-circle movements, you can also add effect to the throw such as curves and banks. To catch difficult discs, you can slide to move more quickly. Slides have a recovery time to them, so sliding the wrong way is very risky.Also to add to the game, signature moves are added. To charge these special moves, you must stand where the disc is going to land and power up your throw by mashing or holding the throw button. To know where the disc is going to land you must either pop the disc up by blocking an opponents throw, or get under it quick enough when the opponent lobs it up. These moves can be countered but if received too far back they will knock an opponent into the goal. Slower characters are less prone to being knocked back.There are six characters to choose from, with specific abilities and their own court fit for their skills. A single game consists of short sets of thirty seconds or the first person to score 15 or more points. The games are finished by the first person to get to two wins. If there is a tie at 2-2 via tied set then a sudden death round will be played to find the winner.In the console version two mini-games are included in-between levels: Dog Distance, a platforming fetch game with a dog and Flying Disc Bowling.Other NotesGame also known as "Flying Power Disc" in JapanB. Yoo is rebranded from South Korean to Briton Steve Miller in the Japanese release, complete with new voice acting.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="3">Sports</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="24889">Capcom Sports Club</game><game id="22195">Pong</game><game id="38405">Slap Shot</game><game id="38404">Sanrio World Smash Ball!</game><game id="22270">Battle Flip Shot</game><game id="22295">Bang Bead</game><game id="42748">Lethal League</game><game id="31299">River City Super Sports Challenge</game><game id="3552">Super Dodge Ball</game><game id="40443">BariBariBall</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8072/234421-windjammers_cover.jpg</image></root>