<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11532</id><name>Video Pinball</name><description>OverviewThough a game with the name Video Pinball appeared in arcades in 1979, the best-known Atari game by that name is this, the    Atari 2600 version, programmed by Bob Smith. It features a single table (unlike the dedicated console version) and relies on players moving the control stick to the left or the right to activate the left or right flipper. An inherent problem with this system was that both flippers could not be activated at the same time using these basic controls. Instead, holding up on the joystick activates both flippers at the same time. The ball was launched by pressing down on the joystick button and pulling the joystick downwards while the table could be tilted by holding down the joystick button and moving the joystick in the desired direction. The 2600 version of the game was released on the   Xbox Live Marketplace  Game Room as part of the five releases for the week of 06/02/2010 and like the 2600 version the flippers could not both be activated at the same time by using the left and right flipper buttons, a special button for activating both flippers at the same time must be used to do so.  The table in the Atari 2600/Game Room version of Video Pinball has the ball launching from the right side of the screen and includes elements that will redirect the ball on the left and right sides of the table, three bumpers, two spinners at the top of the table and various collectables which appear around the table. Two holes at the bottom of the table make it relatively easy for players to lose their ball although in the 2600 version at least these holes could be closed to decrease the difficulty of the game. If players could pass their ball over the Atari logo four times they would also receive an extra ball.   </description><genres><genre id="30">Pinball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20885">Pinball</game><game id="12347">Pinball Fantasies</game><game id="14091">Addiction Pinball</game><game id="1557">Full Tilt! Pinball</game><game id="18592">Sonic the Hedgehog: Spinball</game><game id="18314">Pin*Bot</game><game id="33980">Video Pinball</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14206/1096940-vp.jpg</image></root>