<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11576</id><name>Wizkid: The Story of Wizball II</name><description>OverviewWizkid: The Story of Wizball II is an action/adventure game developed by Sensible Software and published by Ocean Software for the PC, Amiga, and Atari ST platforms.GameplayWizkid is split into two modes: Arcade and Adventure.ArcadeIn this mode, Wizkid must use the floating blocks around him to take out enemies. This is possible by ramming Wizkid (currently just a disembodied head, like his predecessor in Wizball) into the blocks to dislodge them, using the direction and speed with which you hit the blocks to send them falling onto the enemies below. Doing so will reward you with colorful musical notes which will eventually fill a little music sheet at the bottom of the screen and allow you to enter the other mode: Adventure. If you beat a stage using nothing but the Arcade mode (usually occurs after a few different screens), you'll almost always end up skipping a stage and messing up the true ending. If you fail to beat a screen (usually by dropping all the blocks while there's still enemies) you'll eventually cycle back to it.In Arcade mode you can collect two power-ups (which often need to be bought in Adventure mode before returning to Arcade): A clown's red nose - used to balance blocks until you're ready to send them at enemies, and a pair of false teeth - used to grip a block so you can directly maneuver it over an enemy.AdventureIn Adventure mode, Wizkid reclaims his full body and is able to explore the level proper, finding secrets, using the store and collecting items to use elsewhere. Solutions to finding the kittens (your true goal) are often obtuse and sometimes requires a guide. If you get stuck in this mode, you can always return to Arcade and continue the game from there.Finding all nine kittens from the nine worlds allows you to race Zark back to his tower in a rowboat and defeat him face-to-face (any fewer kittens and he'll beat you in the race and lock the front door). To beat Zark you have to get the high score on his "Wizeroids" arcade machine (a parody of Asteroids).</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9992/227525-wizkid.jpg</image></root>