<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11683</id><name>Star Wars: The Clone Wars</name><description>SummaryDeveloped by Pandemic Studios and published by LucasArts, Star Wars: The Clone Wars was released on November 28, 2002 for the Nintendo Gamecube and Sony Playstation 2 and April 22, 2003 for Microsoft's Xbox. Starting at the Battle of Geonosis, the game centers around The Dark Reaper project during The Clone Wars. The game focuses on Vehicular combat but also includes on foot combat, similar to Star Wars Rogue Squadron III: Rebel Strike. Players take control of the Grand Army of the Republic and many of the main vehicles the Clone Army uses, however, players can choose to be either The Grand Army of the Republic or Confederacy of Independent Systems in many of the game's various multiplayer modes.PlotOpening CrawlThe galaxy stands on the brink of war. Thousands of star systems, under the leadership of COUNT DOOKU, have seceded from the Republic and formed the Confederacy of Independent Systems. The separatist movement has made it impossible for the JEDI KNIGHTS to maintain peace and order in the Galaxy. In response to the growing conflict, the Galactic Senate has commissioned a CLONE ARMY to aid the Jedi. On the planet Geonosis, OBI-WAN KENOBI, ANAKIN SKYWALKER, and PADMÉ AMIDALA have been captured by Dooku and sentenced to death. The Jedi Council has made plans for a rescue attempt. Master MACE WINDU has enlisted a legion of Jedi to assist him, and is en route to Geonosis....The game opens with The Battle of Geonosis and then takes the player to Rhen Var, where the player escapes only a short time before the Seperatists capture the planet.One month after The Battle of Geonosis, the Republic sends Jedi generals Obi-Wan Kenobi and Anakin Skywalker to Raxus Prime after detecting Seperatist forces in the area. The republic then sends reinforcements and recaptures the planet, however, Anakin is captured by sith lord and Seperatist leader Count Dooku. Dooku sends Anakin to be executed on Alaris Prime, a moon of the wookiee planet Kashyyyk. Skywalker and the other Jedi prisoners are to be killed by the Force Harvester, an old Sith weapon that drains the force from all living things. The Clone Army rescues Skywalker in time and destroys the Seperatist prescence on the moon.After Skywalker returns to the Jedi Temple on Coruscant, Jedi Masters Yoda and Mace Windu tell him of Sith weapon called the Dark Reaper, a weapon so powerful that none can withstand it. They believe that the Seperatists are building a Dark Reaper on the Thule system and using the Force Harvester to power it. All four Jedi travel to Thule to try to stop it from behind built. When they arrive, a huge battle ensues. While the other Jedi fight the droid armies outside the Sith temple, Anakin enters to destroy the Dark Reaper.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15481">Star Wars: Battlefront</game><game id="7094">Star Wars: Battlefront II</game><game id="21023">Star Wars: The Clone Wars - Lightsaber Duels</game><game id="3575">Battalion Wars</game><game id="9051">Psi-Ops: The Mindgate Conspiracy</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2285714-box_swtcw.png</image></root>