<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11721</id><name>Devil's Crush</name><description>OverviewDevil's Crush (Devil Crash in Japan) is the second game in the Crush Pinball series, after Alien Crush and was developed by NAXAT Soft and was released in 1990 for the TurboGrafx-16. It was followed by two sequels, Jaki Crush, and Alien Crush Returns.It was later released on the Wii's Virtual Console on June 19, 2007 in Japan, July 23, 2007 in North America, and on July 27, 2007 in Europe. It was later released for the Sega Mega Drive in 1991, and was renamed Dragon's Fury (Devil Crash MD in Japan), which was developed by the company Technosoft. A PlayStation Network version was released in Japan on July 15, 2009, and is compatible on the PlayStation 3, and PlayStation Portable.GameplayDevil's Crush plays similar to the previous game in the series (Alien Crush), in that it has a free scrolling pinball table that goes three screens high instead of two. You have the flippers coming back, and now you have three flippers, one on each screen. You have to charge up a ball, then release it into the table and begin scoring points. The gameplay in Devil's Crush plays the same as Alien Crush, but with some new features included. Your basic goal is still to gain as much points as you possibly can before losing all of your balls. There are many objects placed throughout the pinball table, requiring you to hit them or get your ball inside of it. The is a pentagram on the top screen, and if you hit all of the Roman Numerals and robed fiends circling around, you will gain a bonus round and gain a lot more points as well. Devil's Crush plays a dark hell oriented theme, and many creatures and objects placed throughout are resembling hell, or the devil in a way. There are also secret holes you can shoot your ball into, thus getting to a different screen which is 1 of 6 different mini boss fights which can be fairly tough, but if successful, you will gain tons of points if doing so.Devil's Crush Pinball board (3 screens long)A new feature to Devil's Crush is the ability to shake or tilt the table to gain leverage, or to get out of a touch, such as being stuck. Tilting the table to much will result in the flippers to stop working, in which causing you a lost ball. Besides the boss type bonus rooms, there are also many other bonus type rooms you can enter, all in which have different setups giving you a chance to score more points. Devil's Crush requires you to have good timing, as well as good aiming with your flippers to gain access to these many bonus rooms, as well as hitting the many targets layed out , or moving on the table. Another feature on the pinball table are features that can help you out, like getting your ball inside the mini castle placed on the table will grant you walls to block under your flippers for a limited time. That will block balls from falling out of the table.Once reaching the one billion point mark will grant you a battle with the final boss battle and a viewing to the end of the game.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="30">Pinball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5941">Crüe Ball</game><game id="19109">Alien Crush</game><game id="18592">Sonic the Hedgehog: Spinball</game><game id="20994">Pinball Hall of Fame: The Williams Collection</game><game id="20875">Dream Pinball 3D</game><game id="25403">Digital Pinball: Necronomicon</game><game id="10645">Digital Pinball: Last Gladiators</game><game id="19853">Dragon's Revenge</game><game id="1939">Devilish</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2365523-tg16_devilscrush_2.jpg</image></root>