<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11740</id><name>Warlocked</name><description>Warlocked is a real-time strategy game for the Game Boy Color developed by Bits Studios and released by Nintendo on 2000. It is notable for being one of the only, if not the only, RTS titles for the handheld.StoryThe story is typical RTS fare, with two groups, Humans and Beasts, trying to destroy each other. The Beasts, led by a being known as Chief Zog, have risen up against the humans, led by Queen Azarel. In desperation, Queen Azarel summons the realm's wizards for help. The game unfolds in typical RTS style, with base-building, resource-management, and hero units with special abilities.GameplayThe game plays like your average RTS. Resource-management and base/unit buildiing is a major part of gameplay, but the real depth lies in mastering the power of the collectable Wizard units. Serving as the game's version of the typical RTS hero unit, each Wizard has their own unique power, ranging from building reinforcement to the ability to turn other units into chickens. Taking a cue from Pokemon, Wizards can be traded from game to game, but instead of using a Game Link cable Warlocked uses the Game Boy Color's infared sensor.In the game's main story mode, players can play as either the Humans or the Beasts, each with their own set of missions. Using a Game Link cable two players can engage in a skirmish mode.The game also features two minigames - a version of Poker and a sliding puzzle.LegacyAlthough released at the height of the RTS craze brought on by the popularity Warlocked remains an obscure title. A sequel, Wizards, was in development for the Game Boy Advance at Bits Studios, but was canceled for unknown reasons before development could be finished.</description><genres><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9719">Warcraft: Orcs &amp; Humans</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/17724/873838-warlocked.jpg</image></root>