<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11758</id><name>Crimsonland</name><description>Overview Crimsonland is a simple    top-down shooter in which, depending on the mode, the player attempts to survive as long as possible or through an entire level.Gameplay Crimsonland starts the player in the middle of the screen, and creatures begin swarming the player soon after the level starts. The player must avoid being completely overrun and killed by running around the screen and shooting the enemies, which may drop   power-ups and weapons that increase your effectiveness.The player aims with the mouse, pointing a reticle in the direction he wants to shoot. Movement is handled with WASD or arrow keys. The control scheme is similar to some PC adaptations of dual-joystick shooters. If the level chosen is a campaign level, the player must survive until the waves of enemies stop. If it is challenge mode, then the player must survive as long as possible. The further a player has reached in the campaign, the more powerful weapons will be available in challenge mode.There is an extra mode that forgoes the normal gameplay to instead use typing to kill enemies in a manner reminiscent of     The Typing of the Dead. The player is stuck in the middle of the screen, unable to move. The incoming creatures have a label with a single word chosen from a random assortment words that must be typed in to kill that assailant. As the player progresses, longer and harder words are given and enemies attack faster and faster. If an enemy reaches the player and they are not shot off before they deplete the player's HP, the player loses.Game Modes QuestsQuest mode consists of 50 levels, split into five chapters, each level getting progressively harder. The player begins each level with only a pistol, but as more and more levels are completed more weapons and power-ups become available. There is also "Hardcore" mode that is unlocked after beating all of the levels in normal, this is the same thing as normal but more enemies come after you. RushRush throws an absurd amount of enemies at you (literally covering the map in moments) and gives you only a assault rifle to fend them off with. There are no  perks or power-ups in this mode, the goal is to survive as long as you can with all of the odds against you. SurvivalThis is a meat of the game. You are placed in a never ending level that get prograssivly harder as you play. The longer you go, the stronger and more plentiful the enemies become. Typ-o-shooterA game mode where you have to type out the monster's word instead of attacking them yourself.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16472">Millennium Soldier: Expendable</game><game id="23125">Babo Violent 2</game><game id="28042">Nation Red</game><game id="29993">Dudebro™ — My Shit Is Fucked Up So I Got to Shoot/Slice You II: It’s Straight-Up Dawg Time</game><game id="27873">I MAED A GAM3 W1TH Z0MBIES!!!1</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5275/1129865-crimsonland_logo.jpg</image></root>