<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11829</id><name>Alundra 2</name><description>StoryThe plot of Alundra 2 takes place in a fantasy world different from its predecessor Alundra known as the Kingdom of Varuna. You play the role of Flint, a young pirate hunter who is wanted by the authority for supposed treason. He takes up his sword and vows to hunt the pirates who killed his parents. Throughout the story Flint uncovers the mystery which plagues the kingdom in how Mephisto, an evil sorcerer is using magical wind-up keys to turn creatures and people into corrupted machines. The games adventure takes you through a variety of different towns and dungeons.GameplayGameplay: Dungeon LevelThe gameplay in Alundra a mix of action and adventure a heavy emphasis on exploration and puzzle solving. Visually the game is presented in full 3d and features a freely manipulative camera system which allows the player to both rotate the camera and select from an array of pre-set angles. The general aim of the game is progressing throughout the kingdom through different towns and dungeons with the ability to backtrack to open new areas with newly acquired spells or skills. The game features boss fights, a variety of mini-games and in game voiced cut scenes.Soundtrack ListThe soundtrack was released on the 18th of December, 1999. It was composed by Kohei Tanaka and its total duration is 01:10:15.Track NumberTitleLength1Carry On Everyday2:062Soldier Boy Frit1:283Demon Doll1:4243 Members of the Zukkoke Pirates1:145Imminent Crisis0:446Shock! A Demon Evolves Before Us1:037Quiet Town3:268Aisha1:549Journey to Vanilla Kingdom0:5210Momomoke Forest2:2411Demon Doll's Airship Crashes1:2912Battle with Demon Doll2:0013Ox Tank Attacks0:3314Villager's Tragedy1:4415Sword Kin Jiken1:3016Bullfighting in Gyuu York1:0517Web Rock1:4818Martini's Trap3:4219Go on the Mine Cart!1:0720Pirates of Puerto Medusa1:5321Who Changed Me into a Jellyfish Like This?1:3722Magic Knight Belgar1:3723I Want to Protect Papa1:2224Count Destoll Nijadoll1:4025Vanilla Capital1:5826Sunken Ship1:5827Ancient Ruins1:5328Ruins of Guardian God2:0229Island of Paradise2:2330Giant Demon Neji Star-Twister0:1931Dragon Volcano1:5632Dragon Island1:5433To the Arion Sky1:0334Fly Over Vanilla Kingdom1:2035Confrontation with Demon Destoll2:2236Ultimate From of Mephisto Machine2:5737Hope for the Future2:4438I'm Home5:26</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2388">StarTropics</game><game id="17335">Zoda's Revenge: Star Tropics II</game><game id="12572">The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time</game><game id="14694">Threads of Fate</game><game id="8698">Tail Concerto</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/97089/2201892-alundra_2.jpg</image></root>