<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11843</id><name>Mortal Kombat: Armageddon</name><description>Overview  Every one of these fighters are playable in Mortal Kombat: Armageddon.     Mortal Kombat: Armageddon is a 3D fighting game developed and published by                                                                                                  Midway on October 2006 for the PlayStation 2 and Xbox. It is the seventh installment in the Mortal Kombat franchise and includes every Mortal Kombat fighter to date, along with a new custom fighter creator and custom                                                                                                 Fatality combos. The game was later released on May 29, 2007 for the                                                                                              Wii, including a bonus character (                                                                                               Khameleon from the Nintendo 64 version of                                                                                               Mortal Kombat Trilogy), an optional motion-based control scheme, and a new Endurance mode at the cost of online multiplayer.  The story takes place in a cataclysmic event in an enormous crater on                                                                                             Edenia, where every warrior in the Mortal Kombat universe clashes in an epic battle royale for the opportunity to defeat                                                                                            Blaze, a giant fire elemental created by the Elder Gods as a final defense against the growing power of the warriors. The main protagonist is                                                                                           Taven, a half-god warrior sent along with his brother (and antagonist),                                                                                          Daegon, to defeat Blaze and save the realms from                                                                                         armageddon.           The Krypt makes a return in the game, where players can use "koins" to unlock alternate costumes, arenas, concept art, music, and other promotional material. However, it is less of a hassle than the two previous games, as there is only one type of "koin" currency instead of several. Collecting 60 Relics in Konquest Mode also unlocks all the content in the Krypt. Gameplay The gameplay for Mortal Kombat: Armageddon remains mostly unchanged from the previous two Mortal Kombat games:                    Mortal Kombat: Deadly Alliance and                   Mortal Kombat: Deception. Players have four attack buttons, a Block button, a Change Fighting Style button, and a Throw button. Fighting StylesEach fighter now has two fighting styles instead of three: one traditional fighting style (based on actual fighting techniques) and one weapon fighting style. Some of the larger bosses, like Onaga and Blaze, have no weapon fighting style. Some characters, like Mokap and Smoke, have another traditional fighting style in place of their weapon fighting style. CombosPre-programmed dial-a-combos and "                 Combo Breakers" remain in the game. One new addition to Mortal Kombat: Armageddon is the concept of "Air Kombat", where the player launches the opponent into the air and then continues their combo in the air.  Fatalities     Fatalities work differently in Mortal Kombat: Armageddon than any other Mortal Kombat game. Instead of a character-specific button combination, which triggers an animated sequence, players input a string of finishing moves (beating up the opponent, ripping out body parts, manuevering the opponent into a more punishing position) with little time in-between and finish with a killing blow (decapitations, spine rips, etc.). After performing a successful fatality (with a killing blow), the Fatality is then ranked on the amount of chains strung together (from Fatality to Ultimate Fatality). Boss characters have their own unique and gruesome killing blows due to their large size. Custom Characters       If over 60 characters is not enough in Mortal Kombat: Armageddon, the game allows players to create their own custom characters through the Kreate-a-Fighter Mode. Players can outfit their character with a wide variety of clothing, including costumes made to resemble the classic      Mortal Kombat ninjas. Players can also customize the fighting style, weapon style, and special moves of their custom characters and take them online against other players.   Konquest Mode       Konquest Mode in Mortal Kombat: Armageddon is an action-adventure/fighter hybrid that borrows elements from            Mortal Kombat: Shaolin Monks. Unlike Mortal Kombat: Deception, the fighting aspect is limited to special fights, as the rest of the game revolves around third-person action-adventure combat. Players control           Taven, an Edenian half-god warrior, as he journeys through the realms of the Mortal Kombat universe to defeat his brother,         Daegon, and stop the impending armageddon by defeating        Blaze. On the way, player can collect "koins" through treasure chests and "Dragon Tokens". Players can also collect special Relics scattered throughout the game, which unlock more content. Collecting all 60 relics unlocks everything in the Krypt. Players can also find content from the Krypt hidden in treasure chests throughout Konquest Mode. Motor Kombat     In a similar vein to Mortal Kombat: Deception's "Puzzle Kombat" mode, Motor Kombat pits eight                super-deformed versions of the game's characters in a brutal version of               kart racing. Up to four players (two in the PS2 version) can play split-screen, while up to eight players can race online. Players race in one of five tracks, each with their own set of "death traps" (in which they respawn back on the course after some time), obstacles, and speed boosts. Racers can pick up items that either temporarily boost their kart's speed, give them the ability to perform their special move, and give them "koins" for use in the Krypt. There are ten total racers to choose from, each with their own unique kart appearance and special move:  Scorpion - Shoots his trademark              spear forward, pulling back any kart that gets caught.Sub-Zero - Shoots a ball of ice forward, temporarily freezing any kart that hits it.Bo' Rai Cho - Pukes behind him, forcing karts that run into it to slip.Jax - Jumps his kart up in the air and does a ground pound, knocking other karts around him.Baraka - Shoots a silver spark ahead of him, temporarily stunning any kart that hits it.Raiden - Surrounds his kart with electricity, zapping anyone that is in its area of effect.Kitana - Creates a shield that protects her kart from other special moves and obstacles.Mileena - Gives her kart a quick boost forward.Cyrax - Drops a bomb behind him, exploding karts that's in its blast radius.Johnny Cage - Shoots a green ball of energy in front of him.Characters   The character select screen with the 58 starting characters.   The game features the most complete Mortal Kombat roster to date, including 62 playable characters (4 of which are unlockable) and the ability to create custom fighters. Every character is from a previous Mortal Kombat game with the exception of Taven and Daegon. Khameleon, previously a secret character in the Nintendo 64 version of                                               Mortal Kombat Trilogy, is playable in the Wii version of this game. Taven, Daegon, Meat, and Blaze can either be unlocked from collecting certain amounts of Relics in Konquest Mode, completing Konquest Mode (for Taven), or entering a special cheat code in the Krypt. Row 1: Ninja Characters                                                                                     Scorpion                                                                                    Sub-Zero                                                                                   Reptile                                                                                  Rain                                                                                 Ermac                                                                                Chameleon                                                                               Noob Saibot  Smoke                                                                             Cyrax                                                                            Sektor Row 2: Male Characters 1                                                                           Stryker                                                                          Kabal                                                                         Dairou                                                                        Jarek                                                                       Darrius                                                                      Reiko                                                                     Fujin                                                                    Bo' Rai Cho                                                                   Mavado                                                                  Hotaru Row 3: Male Characters 2                                                                 Nightwolf                                                                Mokap                                                               Johnny Cage                                                              Kano                                                             Jax                                                            Kai                                                           Kenshi                                                          Shujinko                                                         Hsu Hao                                                        Kobra Row 4: Main Characters Custom Fighter (replaced by                                                        Khameleon in the Wii version)                                                      Taven (unlockable)                                                     Liu Kang                                                    Kung Lao                                                   Shang Tsung                                                  Quan Chi                                                 Shinnok                                                Raiden                                               Daegon (unlockable)Custom Fighter Row 5: Female Characters 1                                              Sonya                                            Kitana                                          Mileena                                         Jade                                        Ashrah                                       Li Mei Row 6: Female Characters 2                                       Tanya                                     Frost                                    Sindel                                   Nitara                                  Kira                                 Sareena Row 7: Monster/Boss Characters 1                                Sheeva                               Baraka                              Motaro                             Havik                            Drahmin                           Moloch Row 8: Monster/Boss Characters 2                           Meat (unlockable)                         Shao Kahn                        Goro                       Kintaro                      Onaga                     Blaze (final boss, unlockable)</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19043">Fighters Megamix</game><game id="2045">Dead or Alive 2</game><game id="22159">Samurai Shodown: Warriors Rage</game><game id="22292">Dead or Alive 2: Hardcore</game><game id="7792">Dead or Alive 4</game><game id="16793">Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors</game><game id="3744">Def Jam: Fight for NY</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="721">Ehrgeiz: God Bless the Ring</game><game id="11065">Shaman King: Power of Spirit</game><game id="13753">Dead or Alive Ultimate</game><game id="22953">Ultimate Fighter</game><game id="20678">Soulcalibur IV</game><game id="10476">War Gods</game><game id="20734">Street Fighter EX</game><game id="20736">Street Fighter EX2</game><game id="20735">Street Fighter EX Plus</game><game id="12518">Street Fighter EX Plus Alpha</game><game id="11370">Street Fighter EX2 Plus</game><game id="10989">Street Fighter EX3</game><game id="20831">Castlevania Judgment</game><game id="866">Kakuto Chojin: Back Alley Brutal</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1881073-box_mka.png</image></root>