<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11852</id><name>Sam &amp; Max Hit the Road</name><description>OverviewThe detective-solving duo, Sam  Max.Sam  Max Hit the Road is one of LucasArts legendary SCUMM adventure games released in 1993 and one of the first to be released on CD and include voice acting. The game is based on a comic book done by Steve Purcell and which later spawned a television show. Unlike previous SCUMM adventure games any action you do is not done by clicking a verb at the bottom of the screen. Instead you selected an action by right clicking and cycling through images which appeared on your cursor. This meant that there was less actions to do in Sam  Max but meant the SCUMM interface was presented in a better fashion. Dialogue was also handled by using symbols instead of lines of text and the inventory screen was also put on a different screen being represented by a box in the lower left corner of the screen.SynopsisGrab your nightstick, squeal like a siren and Hit The Road with Sam  Max, Freelance Police, as they attempt to crack their toughest case. Sam (a canine shamus) and Max (a kinetic rabbity thing) are hot on the trail of a runaway carnival bigfoot across America's quirky underbelly in this crazy animated adventure. Enjoy edgy animation with twisted humor! Stop at tacky tourist traps and intimidate their bizarre denizens!PlotOut on the streets.In Sam  Max, you play as Sam a talking dog who runs a freelance police agency, with his partner Max, whom is a talking rabbit-like animal. At the start of the game Sam  Max are called to rescue a damsel in distress from a mad scientist, they succeed in doing this and return to the office for their next assignment which they pull out of a reluctant cat. Sam  Max get called to the local carnival where they are hired to track down Trixie a giraffe necked singer who has run off with the carnivals other main attraction Bruno the Bigfoot. It seems however that Sam  Max are not the only ones trying to find this Bigfoot. A country western star called Conroy Bumpus is planning to add the Bigfoot to his menagerie.A giant ball of twineThis prompts Sam  Max on a trip around America to track down the Bigfoot, preventing Bumpus from capturing Bruno and Trixie and eventually helping the bigfoot back to their former glory.This trip takes them to many weird places such as a giant ball of twine, bungee jumping out of a former presidents nose, going into a room upside down and many more weird and wonderful places.Additional NotesSam  Max Hit the Road was a success upon its initial release in 1993. A sequel was planned by LucasArts, but this was delayed for unspecified reasons. Finally in 2002, LucasArts announced the sequel, Sam  Max: Freelance Police. Due to the high profile financial failure of LucasArts' previous adventure title, Grim Fandango, the new Sam  Max title was canceled quite far into development. The game would not receive a sequel of sorts until late 2006. In 2005, LucasArts' license with Sam  Max creator Steve Purcell was not renewed. The license was then acquired by Telltale Games who in turn released the new Sam  Max in episodic form. Called Sam  Max: Season One, these games were smaller due to the episodic nature of the release. All up there were six episodes which when played together formed one large adventure. A second and third season have been released so far.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2037">Maniac Mansion</game><game id="3019">The Secret of Monkey Island</game><game id="4372">Maniac Mansion: Day of the Tentacle</game><game id="4084">Broken Sword II: The Smoking Mirror</game><game id="5781">Torin's Passage</game><game id="21174">Full Throttle</game><game id="10528">Monkey Island 2:  LeChuck's Revenge</game><game id="17544">Broken Sword: The Shadow of the Templars</game><game id="7088">Toonstruck</game><game id="10915">Beneath a Steel Sky</game><game id="8178">Freddy Pharkas: Frontier Pharmacist</game><game id="209">Tiny Toon Adventures: The Great Beanstalk</game><game id="8759">The Longest Journey</game><game id="21914">A Vampyre Story</game><game id="9345">Zack &amp; Wiki: Quest for Barbaros' Treasure</game><game id="7947">Lure of the Temptress</game><game id="9527">Flight of the Amazon Queen</game><game id="600">Future Wars</game><game id="15330">Tony Tough and the Night of Roasted Moths</game><game id="3460">Discworld</game><game id="8384">The Adventures of Willy Beamish</game><game id="9058">Escape from Monkey Island</game><game id="11781">Leisure Suit Larry 5: Passionate Patti Does a Little Undercover Work!</game><game id="8430">Pajama Sam: No Need to Hide When It’s Dark Outside</game><game id="14441">Pajama Sam 2: Thunder and Lightning Aren't so Frightening</game><game id="7900">Pajama Sam 3: You Are What You Eat From Your Head To Your Feet</game><game id="14961">Pajama Sam: Life is Rough When You Lose Your Stuff</game><game id="2373">Freddi Fish and the Case of the Missing Kelp Seeds</game><game id="15666">Freddi Fish 2: The Case of the Haunted School House</game><game id="9720">Freddi Fish 3: The Case of the Stolen Conch Shell</game><game id="10911">Freddi Fish 4: The Case of the Hogfish Rustlers of Briny Gulch</game><game id="7662">Freddi Fish 5: The Case of the Creature of Coral Cove</game><game id="14824">Spy Fox in "Dry Cereal"</game><game id="13465">Spy Fox 2: Some Assembly Required</game><game id="5914">Spy Fox: Operation Ozone</game><game id="13134">Putt-Putt Goes to the Moon</game><game id="11177">Putt-Putt Joins the Parade</game><game id="931">Putt-Putt Travels Through Time</game><game id="3785">Putt-Putt Saves the Zoo</game><game id="10431">Putt-Putt Joins the Circus</game><game id="15183">Putt-Putt Enters the Race</game><game id="5729">The Curse of Monkey Island</game><game id="22160">Laura Bow: Colonel's Bequest</game><game id="6351">Discworld II: Mortality Bytes!</game><game id="4203">Discworld Noir</game><game id="21090">A New Beginning</game><game id="23532">Nikopol: Secrets of the Immortals</game><game id="6728">Zak McKracken and the Alien Mindbenders</game><game id="22111">The Whispered World</game><game id="23778">Strong Bad's Cool Game for Attractive People Episode 3: Baddest of the Bands</game><game id="21667">Gray Matter</game><game id="3603">Duckman: The Legend of the Fall</game><game id="1014">Runaway: A Road Adventure</game><game id="21421">Star Trek: 25th Anniversary</game><game id="24452">Life of D. Duck II</game><game id="24962">Full Throttle: Payback</game><game id="17638">Scooby-Doo Mystery</game><game id="15838">Out of Order</game><game id="26494">Life of D. Duck</game><game id="19401">3 Skulls of the Toltecs</game><game id="28084">Ben There, Dan That!</game><game id="27322">Time Gentlemen, Please!</game><game id="19536">Dinotopia</game><game id="29176">Big Brain Wolf</game><game id="35448">Sissy's Magical Ponycorn Adventure</game><game id="32535">Sam &amp; Max Plunge Through Space</game><game id="31979">Edna &amp; Harvey: The Breakout</game><game id="39486">Broken Sword: The Serpent's Curse</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4938/609065-hit_the_road_box_front_6498x8205.jpg</image></root>