<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11870</id><name>The Suffering:  Ties That Bind</name><description>Plot    Be prepared for some gruesome imagery.     When the game begins, the player will play in a mission which happened even before the first game.          Torque is in Eastern        Baltimore Correctional with his friend:       Miles. Blackmore orders his men to teach them that he is now the boss of Eastern.  Before they can start, a riot starts and Torque and Miles tries to      escape from Eastern.  After being separated from Miles and seeing apparition from Copperfield and The Creeper, Torques snaps out of it in present day. After escaping Carnate Island,  Torque arrives in Baltimore, Maryland.  He is greeted by an unidentified group that instruct him to follow them.  Torque then pass out after hallucinating and when he wakes up, he is tied up and he is being transported into one of their building in the harbor.  The group keeps referring him as the Prime Target.  He is transported to     Jordan who then tells Torque that she wants him to help her understand the `Malefactor` which are the creatures seen in both games.  An alarm goes off so Jordan leaves Torque to investigate the problem.  Soon after, the guards are brutally killed for unknown reason and Torque is freed.  He then finds the spirit of Carmen who tells him to go to is old apartment.  When he arrives, she tells him about Blackmore who is indirectly responsible for the her death and their sons death.  Torque has to kill Blackmore because of the Evil he represent and for revenge.Multiple Story Lines Unlike the    previous installment, the player actions do not affect the story.  Instead, it determines the kind of powerup you get when Torque transforms.  The story is determined by the player previous save files which unlocks Good and Evil story to choose at the beginning of the game, neutral being the default.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2414">Max Payne</game><game id="6328">Silent Hill 4: The Room</game><game id="500">The Thing</game><game id="7043">Evil Dead: A Fistful of Boomstick</game><game id="8804">Condemned: Criminal Origins</game><game id="20465">Condemned 2: Bloodshot</game><game id="4800">F.E.A.R.: First Encounter Assault Recon</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2139883-box_tsttb.png</image></root>