<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11891</id><name>Barkley: Shut Up and Jam!</name><description>OverviewBarkley: Shut Up and Jam! is a 2 on 2 street basketball game similar to NBA Jam. Charles Barkley is the only NBA player featured in the game while everyone else is a fictional character. The game is best known for being an awful basketball title and starring Sir Charles (he likes that name, it makes him feel more dignified). It is not unlikely to see a player make a full court shot or see the AI stare at a loose ball and not pick it up. The game also didn't seem to have an out of bounds area or a shot clock. Barkley: Shut Up and Jam! is in a special league with such other crappy games starring NBA players like Shaq Fu. Though at least Sir Charles had enough sense to stick in the basketball genre.Barkley FactorSir Charles brought his likeness (big head not included) to the game as well as his voice. When you started up the game you were greeted with the warm message, "Time for some pain." -- but wait, there's more. He also said: "Time out" and "Play hard or get out".Barkley: Shut Up and Jam: GaidenThe game spawned a spiritual sequel in the form of the popular fan-made freeware RPG Barkley: Shut Up and Jam: Gaiden. Set in the year 2053, the game adopts Japanese-style RPG combat with a story revolving around the demise of basketball. Charles Barkley is the protagonist, and the game features cameos from many celebrities, fictitious characters, and other basketball stars.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="22">Basketball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16928">NBA Jam</game><game id="10512">NBA Hangtime</game><game id="417">NBA Hoopz</game><game id="14792">NBA Jam Tournament Edition</game><game id="7982">NBA Street</game><game id="9938">NBA Ballers</game><game id="125">College Slam</game><game id="12115">Hoops</game><game id="6694">Michael Jordan:  Chaos in the Windy City</game><game id="38745">Super Dunk Star</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3316/299497-barkley.jpg</image></root>