<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11945</id><name>Soulcalibur Legends</name><description>Soul Calibur, the unparalleled weapon based fighting game franchise, reinvents itself as Soulcalibur Legends, a third-person action adventure, exclusively for the Nintendo Wii console.Legends is a spin-off of Namco Bandai's successful Soul fighting game series. It was released on November 20, 2007 in North America and was released in Japan on December 13, 2007. The game is set to come out in Europe in summer 2008. The game features competitive and cooperative multiplayer modes in addition to the single player story mode.StoryThe story of Soulcalibur Legends takes place between Soul Edge and Soul Calibur, and is based around Siegfried Schtauffen's transformation into Nightmare. The game begins as Siegfried finds Soul Edge on a ship. He battles Cervantes on the deck of the ship. Later, Siegfried is tasked by the Masked Emperor of the Holy Roman Empire to find the remaining pieces of Soul Edge in order to use it to win the war against Barbaros of the Ottoman Empire.The game features seven playable characters. Series staples Nightmare and Cervantes make an appearance in the game as non-playable bosses. Assassin, Berserker and Lizardmen from Soulcalibur II also appear in the game as generic enemies.Playable charactersAstaroth (Under the name Astarothα)Heishirō MitsurugiIsabella "Ivy" ValentineLloyd IrvingSophitia AlexandraSiegfried SchtauffenTakiNon-playable charactersAmmon - An Egyptian mummy boss.Barbaros - Usurper Sultan of the Ottoman Empire.Cervantes de Leon - An undead pirate captain and the father of Ivy.Fafnir - A great dragon boss, like the dragon of Norse legends.Geki - A Fu-Ma ninja after Taki, who is transformed by Soul Edge's power into an oni-like monster.Maki - A female Fu-Ma ninja that is Geki's partner, also mutated by Soul Edge's power.Iska Farkas - A refugee Hungarian prince who is the court jester for the Masked Emperor.Masked Emperor/Ilona Farkas - A false human being look-alike of Ilona made by Iska posing as the emperor to trick Siegfried into giving up Soul Edge.Nightmare - Siegfried's demonic alter-ego. Nightmare only appears as a boss fight, emerging from Soul Edge to prevent Siegfried from sealing Soul Edge's power. He (or at least his foot and Soul Edge) is also seen after the credits.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21375">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja 3</game><game id="11958">EOE: Eve of Extinction</game><game id="3744">Def Jam: Fight for NY</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="16842">Street Fighter: Anniversary Collection</game><game id="13753">Dead or Alive Ultimate</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="12411">Soulcalibur</game><game id="20553">Ninja Gaiden II</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1789951-box_scl.png</image></root>