<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12014</id><name>Evil Zone</name><description>OverviewAn anime-themed fantasy/sci-fi futuristic/magic wielding mishmash, Evil Zone is a 3D fighting game with unique characteristics. Combat consists of one button; almost all other actions, movements, grapples, throws, and projectile attacks are focused almost exclusively around the directional pad used in concert with said attack button.PlotIhadulca is a powerful being that can exist in multiple dimensions at once. This dimension witch has temporarily been confined to the "Evil Zone" dimension by the inhabitants of I-Praseru (Happy Island). A multi-dimensional tournament has been held to find the toughest fighter across dimensions, one who can hopefully keep Ihadulca imprisoned in the Evil Zone before she escapes.GameplayCombat is frenetic and fluid for a PS1 title. The story mode for some fighters is told through narrative and static screenshots, which would now be considered archaic but at the time was progressive and gave the game a manga/comic feel. Other characters have in-engine cutscenes for the more dynamic and action packed moments. Voice Acting CreditsDanzavier - Tomokazu Seki (Japanese), Jon St. John (English)Erel Plowse - Houko Kuwashima (Japanese), Susan Wakefield (English)Gally "Vanish" Gregman - Tessho Genda (Japanese), Paul Eiding (English)Linedwell Rainrix - Issei Futamata (Japanese), Rick Calvert (English)Setsuna Saizuki - Kyoko Hikami (Japanese), Moirah Seebold (English)Keiya Tenpouin - Hikaru Midorikawa (Japanese), Chris Wilcox (English)Kakurine - Omi Minami (Japanese), Moirah Seebold (English)Ihadulca - Kikuko Inoue (Japanese), Lani Minella (English)Alty Al Lazel - Akiko Yajima (Japanese), Lani Minella (English)Midori Himeno - Noriko Hidaka (Japanese), Lani Minella (English)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11189">Tekken 3</game><game id="10387">Tekken 2</game><game id="20100">Power Stone</game><game id="6409">Kensei: Sacred Fist</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2199413-box_evilzone.png</image></root>