<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12029</id><name>The Bugs Bunny Crazy Castle</name><description>OverviewThe Bugs Bunny Crazy Castle is an action-platforming puzzle game for the NES in which the player takes control of Bugs Bunny. In each of the sixty or so levels in the Crazy Castle, Bugs must collect all of the carrots in each stage before moving on to the next. Standing in Bugs's way are fellow Looney Tunes characters Yosemite Sam, Sylvester, and Daffy Duck, who wander around the stage and attempt to catch him.The player can defeat enemies by either hitting them with a boxing glove power-up or by dropping a weight, such as a flower pot, onto their head. There is also a power-up that can make Bugs invincible for a short period of time, and he is also invulnerable while being transported through a pipe or moving through a doorway. One thing that Bugs cannot do, however, is jump.In its original Japanese release, the game featured Roger Rabbit, from the Amblin/Disney movie Who Framed Roger Rabbit?. However, when Kemco released the game in the US later the same year, they could not use the Roger Rabbit license in that territory because it had already been purchased by LJN for their Roger Rabbit game, released around the same time. Instead, the game's sprites were reworked to resemble Looney Tunes characters. The two versions are otherwise identical. This would be a common issue for most of Kemco's later Crazy Castle games, as the Japanese versions would invariably feature Disney characters that would be switched out for Looney Tunes characters for their US/EU releases because of licensing issues.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18326">The Bugs Bunny Birthday Blowout</game><game id="1026">Funky Mouse</game><game id="36780">Magical Whip: Wizards of Phantasmal Forest</game><game id="16798">Mickey Mouse</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2361190-nes_bugsbunnyincrazycastle.jpg</image></root>