<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12188</id><name>Theme Hospital</name><description>OverviewThe opening shot.Theme Hospital is a simulation management game developed by Bullfrog in which the player creates and manages the running of a hospital in a number of different scenarios. The player is required to build a hospital from the ground up and hire staff in order to treat patients with comical illnesses ranging from "Bloaty Head Disease" to "Invisibility". To progress to the next level players are required to meet certain criteria e.g. 500 lives saved, 200 deaths. During the course of a level you may deal with; epidemics in which you need to keep under wraps from the health authorities; emergency patients who require immediate attention; impressing the hospital inspector and discovering treatment for a number of different illnesses.The PC version of the game contained a number of funky music trackswhich were left out of the PlayStation version. The PlayStation version of Theme Hospital has also been released on the PlayStation Network to download and play on the PlayStation 3 and the PSP.BuildingBuilding rooms in Theme Hospital is very simple, all you have to do is navigate through a simple menu to find the room you need. The menus allow you to select from a range of different rooms for different needs. More rooms unlock as you progress through the game and will help you cure more illnesses, the rooms have different types of machinery to cure the illnesses. Each room requires a doctor or nurse with a certain qualification to operate it. The player is able to choose the size of the room as well as place doors, windows and various props inside the room to satisfy patients and staff. However, the bigger the room and the more props placed inside it the more expensive it will be and it will come out of your current budget. It is also possible to place staff rooms for employees to rest in and entertain themselves as well as toilets for patients to refresh themselves. Rooms will become dirty and fill with litter unless you employ a handyman to clean up all the mess.Often the player won't have enough space to fit all rooms that they need so they will have to buy more land which contains a separate building to place more rooms in, they will often find they have to buy 2 or 3 more buildings to have the required rooms.Apart from rooms and buildings it is also possible to buy props to make your hospital a more comfortable place to be. Firstly the player can buy a reception desk which is very important and they can also buy plants to make the hospital look nicer, radiators to make sure staff and patients don't get too cold, fire extinguishers to put out possible fires, benches for patients to sit on while they wait to see a doctor and vending machines for patients to buy a snack when they get hungry or thirsty.RoomsDiagnosis RoomsGP's OfficeRequires a doctorMinimum Size is 4x4General DiagnosisRequires a doctorMinimum Size is 5x5CardiogramRequires a doctorMinimum size is 5x4Requires Handyman for repairScannerRequires a doctorMinimum size is 5x5Requires Handyman for repairUltrascanRequires a doctorMinimum size is 5x5Requires a Handyman for repairBlood MachineRequires a doctorMinimum size is 4x4Requires a handyman for repairX-RayRequires a doctorMinimum size is 7x7Requires a handyman for repairPsychiatricRequires a psychiatristMinimum size is 5x5Also a treatment roomWardRequires a nurseMinimum size is 6x6Also a treatment roomMultiple patients may us at same timeTreatment RoomsPharmacyRequires NurseMinimum size is 4x4PsychiatricRequires a psychiatristMinimum size is 5x5Also a diagnosis roomWardRequires a nurseMinimum size is 6x6Also a diagnosis roomMultiple patients may us at same timeOperating TheaterRequires two surgeonsMinimum size is 7x6Requires a handyman to repairRequires a wardClinicsInflationRequires a doctorMinimum size is 5x4Requires a handyman to repairDNA FixerRequires a researcherMinimum size is 6x5Hair RestorationRequires a doctorMinimum size is 4x4Requires a handyman to repairSlack Tongue ClinicRequires a doctorMinimum size is 4x4Requires a handyman to repairFracture ClinicRequires a nurseMinimum size is 4x4Requires a handyman to repairElectrolysisRequires a nurseMinimum size is 5x5Requires a handyman to repairJelly VatRequires a doctorMinimum size is 4x4Requires a handyman to repairDecontaminationRequires a doctorMinimum size is 5x5Requires a handyman to repairFacilitiesStaff RoomMinimum size is 4x4Research DepartmentRequires 1 researcherMinimum size is 5x5One researcher per desk in roomToiletsMinimum size is 4x4TrainingRequires a consultantMinimum size is 4x4One student per desk in roomStaffNurseThe player must employ a variety of staff to keep their hospital running. Different medical rooms require a doctor who has a certain degree. The degrees they have qualify them to be a researcher, surgeon or psychiatrist. Some doctors have all three and some may have none at all meaning they are limited to where they can work. Apart from doctors the player can also employ nurses, cleaners (called Handyman in-game) and a receptionist. Nurses work in pharmacies and wards, handymen clean the hospital as well as repairing broken equipment and receptionists work at the reception desks. More expensive employees will be more friendly to patients and will be more willing to work. However, less expensive employees will become tired more quickly and will be rude to patients.Receptionist System RequirementsMinimum System Requirements:OS: Windows 95Processor: 486/66 MHzMemory: 8 MBHard Drive: 25 MB FreeVideo Memory: 1 MB, SVGASound Card: SoundBlaster CompatibleKeyboard  MouseCD/DVD Rom DriveCheat CodesTo use these cheats you first need to wait for the type writer to show up when you do use the following code 24328Effect Code$2000 (hold for more $)Shift-C+1 patientSHIFT+1All research completedCtrl-CCauses an earthquakeSHIFT+QCauses an emergency.CTRL+EChange the patient's appearanceSHIFT+LDisease of patient changed.SHIFT+IGet an doctor with a special knowledge.CTRL+SHave all itemsSHIFT+CTRL+CLose the gameF11Skip to the end of the monthCtrl-MSkip to the end of the yearCrtl-YWin the current levelF12Open Source VersionsA number of modernized open sourced versions of Theme Hospital have been created over the last few years, as a means for people to keep playing the game on newer versions of Windows, or even Linux or MacOS. The game was reverse engineered by a man named Alexander Gitter, who created a Format Specification Wiki with the intention of allowing the game to be fully recreated in open source.OpenTHThe first of these was known as OpenTH. No longer in active development it attempted to rebuild the original Theme Hospital game in C++ and Lua with the intention of rebuilding it from the ground up with intentions to release it within GNU GPL. As of 2011 there have been no formal updates and no current version of it to Download.CorsixTHAnother open source version of the game, CorsixTH is still currently in active development. However, it requires the original files of the game as a base in order to be played. However it is fully functioning and still in Beta, to accommodate further features. Updates on a bi-monthly basis it is a faithful recreation of the game, using the original visual style and music. The current stable version, 0.01 is available here.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7984">Hospital Tycoon</game><game id="6562">Theme Park</game><game id="21281">Aquarium</game><game id="5860">Theme Park Mystery</game><game id="1471">Pet Vet 3D: Animal Hospital</game><game id="6315">Constructor</game><game id="17620">Dungeon Keeper</game><game id="23725">Prison Tycoon 4: SuperMax</game><game id="21384">The Political Machine 2008</game><game id="3799">The Movies</game><game id="19819">Trailer Park Tycoon</game><game id="19042">Dungeon Keeper: The Deeper Dungeons</game><game id="33312">Game Dev Story 2</game><game id="40093">Cook, Serve, Delicious!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/408/187069-theme_hospital.front_cover.jpg</image></root>