<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12213</id><name>Lethal Enforcers II: Gun Fighters</name><description>Overview   The original arcade cabinet Lethal Enforcers 2 is only a sequal to the orginal in name only. Lethal Enforcers 2 is set in an Old West setting wheras the first Lethal Enforcers has a more modern setting. It was released as arcade game in both North America and Japan. It was later ported to the Sega Genesis and Sega CD, but the ports were never released in Japan. A Super Nintendo port was being worked on, but never saw a release.    Gameplay  You will see common old west environmentsAlthough the setting is different, Gunfighters has the same gameplay as the orginal Lethal Enforcers. The game plays like a typical light gun arcade shooter, where your only objective is shoot all the enemies. There are five stages in Gunfighters: The Bank Robbery, The Stage Hold-Up, Saloon Showdown, The Train Robbery, and The Hide Out. Each level visits environments that are often scene in old western films. The structure of each level takes you through a shooting gallery of enemies, where eventually you will meet a boss. Their are numerous weapons appropriate to the Western theme that can make the player more powerful. The weapons you pick up will make boss encounters much easier to complete.Gunfighters has a score or ranking system based on how many enemies or innocent people you shoot. You are able to obtain a ranking of Posse, Deputy, Sheriff, Deputy Marshal, and U. S. Marshal. Your ranking will always start as sheriff and you will be promoted or demoted based on your scoring after each stage. There are also bonus target stages between levels that will allow the player to boost their rating. </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="35">Light-Gun Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2543">Super Scope 6</game><game id="19246">Vampire Night</game><game id="21276">CarnEvil</game><game id="22002">TinStar</game><game id="13533">X-Zone</game><game id="17486">Mad Dog McCree</game><game id="14268">Crime Patrol</game><game id="1744">Lethal Enforcers</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2370704-genesis_lethalenforcers2_cropped.jpg</image></root>