<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12260</id><name>Simon the Sorcerer</name><description>SimonThe story begins when Simon's dog "Chippy" discovers a chest in the loft of his house. Inside the chest he finds a very old and dirty book, titled " Ye Olde Spellbooke". Not interested in dusty old books, Simon throws it onto the floor. Surprisingly a magical portal appears when the book hits the floor. Being a ordinary teenager, Simon does not know what to do. However, that changes when Chippy decides to enter. Not wanting to lose his faithful dog, Simon decides to follow. After entering the portal, Simon finds himself in another world - more precisely he finds himself in a cauldron. It appears that some goblins see him as their lunch! Regretting the fact that he entered the portal, he manages to escape. Simon finds that a wizard called Calypso has been kidnapped by another wizard who goes by the name of The Evil Sordid. The only person who will send Simon back is Calypso, and so his quest begins, armed with humour, rudeness and sarcasm.Simon is voiced by UK based comedian and actor Chris Barrie who is the star of the popular TV series Red Dwarf.GameplaySimon the Sorcerer is a point-and-click adventure game. The magical world Simon finds himself features parodies of many known fantasy stories: Narnia, Lord of the Rings, Rapunzel and The Three Billy Goats Gruff. Simon can travel around the nearby village, the forest and the mountains at the start of the game.Digital DistributionSimon the Sorcerer was re-released by Good Old Games with compatibility  support for Windows XP, Vista, and 7 for both 32 and 64-bit.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3019">The Secret of Monkey Island</game><game id="6728">Zak McKracken and the Alien Mindbenders</game><game id="11734">Leisure Suit Larry: Love for Sail!</game><game id="17544">Broken Sword: The Shadow of the Templars</game><game id="7947">Lure of the Temptress</game><game id="23561">Fable</game><game id="3603">Duckman: The Legend of the Fall</game><game id="22111">The Whispered World</game><game id="295">The Legend of Kyrandia</game><game id="31451">The Book of Unwritten Tales</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/7/73970/1409362-simonthesorcerer_front.jpg</image></root>