<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12273</id><name>Olympic Summer Games</name><description>OverviewThe Olympic Summer Games was released on the Genesis/Mega Drive, SNES and Gameboy in 1996 to tie in with the centennial Olympic Games being held in Atlanta, USA.  It was the official video game of the '96 Olympics and was the last Olympic Games video game to be released on 16-bit consoles.  The graphics were pretty poor by 1996 standards with most of the action taking place in an isometric view, you could however play to represent any one of 28 nations, each with their own color set.GameplayThe gameplay of Olympic Summer Games is mostly all button mashing in style, with the exception of the Skeet and Archery events.  You have to rapidly press two buttons in order to make your character run faster, usually combined with timed press of the D-pad to either jump a hurdle, throw the javelin or perform the triple jump.The game features an Olympic mode, where you tackle each event one after the other, as well as a practice mode.  There are also options to change the difficulty to one of 3 settings and a list of the then current Olympic and World Record holders for each of the events covered in the game.In the Olympic mode after each event there is a medal ceremony and then a medal table is displayed showing which nations have received Gold, Silver or Bronze so far.  This table is updated after each event and is effectively the scoreboard by which to measure your progress through the game.In practice mode you can choose from the list of 10 events and hone your skills in each before taking on the task of the Olympic mode.EventsThere are 10 events featured in the game, 8 of which focus on the Track and Field portion of the Olympic Games.  They are :-100m Sprint 110m Hurdles Pole Vault High Jump Long Jump Triple Jump Javelin Discus Archery Skeet Shooting </description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="42">Track &amp; Field</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10168">Olympic Gold: Barcelona '92</game><game id="151">Olympic Games: Atlanta 1996</game><game id="13877">Sydney 2000</game><game id="17259">Athens 2004</game><game id="20471">Beijing 2008: The Official Video Game of the Olympic Games</game><game id="18232">Track &amp; Field</game><game id="20619">New International Track &amp; Field</game><game id="15063">The Activision Decathlon</game><game id="31454">Epyx Summer Games</game><game id="40811">Track Meet</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/13/135472/1910231-588542_47137_front.jpg</image></root>