<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12354</id><name>Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Chaos Theory</name><description>OverviewChaos Theory follows many of the stealth gameplay conventions of the first two games in the series. In addition to stunning normal mapped graphics and HDR lighting, a real treat at the time, this entry in the Splinter Cell franchise increased the amount of both lethal and non-lethal options at Sam Fisher's disposal. It also is noteworthy for enemies proclaiming, "Who turned out the lights?" every time the player shoots out, or temporarily disables a light.Plot SummaryThe game starts out with growing tensions between Japan , Korea, and China over Japan's decision to create the Information Self Defense force (I-SDF). This decision goes against the constitution of Japan written after World War II. China and Korea send ships to set up a blockade in the Yellow Sea. To try to calm the situation and push back the Korean ships, the USA sends in the USS Clarence E. Walsh (which in 2007 is the most advanced naval military ship in the world).Sam Fisher is dispatched to a lighthouse in Peru following the disappearance of a genius computer programmer named Bruce Morgenholt. It turns out that Morgenholt was kidnapped by a guerrilla terrorist group known as "The People's Voice". Hugo Lacerda, the leader of this group, took Morgenholt because he was one of few who knew about the Masse algorithms. The Masse Kernels, created by Philip Masse, can be used to launch nuclear attacks anywhere in the world. It is Fisher's job to ensure the safety of these codes. When Fisher arrives at the makeshift camp for The People's Voice, Morgenholt dies after interrogation. The information is released and Lacerda flees via cargo ship (the Maria Narcissa).Fisher interrogating an enemySam is immediately sent on-board the Maria Narcissa to take out Lacerda and to find out who he is dealing with. Sam traces weapons on the boat to a Panamanian bank. Before assassinating Lacerda, he notes the presence of European mercenaries onboard (likely hired from a PMC organization). Fisher then goes to Panama to find more Intel about the deal, and to steal $50,000,000. Here Sam learns about Abrahim Zherkhezi, another genius computer programmer who worked with Bruce Morgenholt. Before leaving the bank, the weapon shipments are revealed to be coming from someone known simply as "Dvorak". Fisher is sent to New York to investigate.Meanwhile, simultaneous blackouts occur in Tokyo and New York, caused by an unknown party. Sam breaks into Zherkhezi's Manhattan apartment to figure out his involvement with the scheme. Fisher sees mercenaries similar to those on the Maria Narcissa guarding Zherkhezi's penthouse apartment. It turns out these mercs are working for Displace International ( Doug Shetland's PMC company). Dvorak ends up being an "infinite state machine" and not a person. Through interrogation, Sam finds out the mercenaries sent to protect Zherkhezi were hired by a man named Milan Nedich. After this mission, Sam is sent to the headquarters of Displace.In the headquarters of Displace, Sam finds out that Displace and Zherkhezi were working together, most likely to secure the Masse Kernels. He also discovers that Milan Nedich is really just a pseudonym for Milos Nowak, a Bosnian war criminal. It turns out that Milan relocated Zherkhezi to a teahouse in Hokkaido where Shetland is also staying. Fisher becomes worried about Doug Shetland's involvement in all of this. Prior to Fisher's infiltration of the teahouse, the USS Clarence E. Walsh is sunk by a missile that originated in North Korea. It is peculiar because the ship's defense system normally protects it from missile attacks and the security is almost impossible to breach. This causes the US to send in troops immediately to invade North Korea and also starts a war between North and South Korea.Sam arrives at Hokkaido to kill Nedich and take in Zherkhezi alive. He is able to kill Nedich and take care of that issue. However, Doug Shetland appears and murders Zherkhezi (Sam witnesses all of this). Now, presumably only Shetland knows about the Masse Kernels. Sam goes to a missile battery in North Korea to figure out if they really launched the missile that sank the Walsh or if there was any other involvement. He confirms Third Echelon's suspicions; Shetland used Masse's algorithms to launch the missile and instigate the war. The military officers in command at the base grow paranoid and launch another missile (intentionally). Fisher immediately disables it. Fisher also goes on a mission to Seoul to find the true origins of the missile launch.Shetland is now in a bath house in Tokyo and Sam soon follows. Douglas is at the bath house to meet with a contact. Shetland's allies surprisingly end up being I-SDF forces (Toshiro Otomo, leader of the I-SDF was allied with Third Echelon to this point). At this point, all speculation is confirmed: Shetland wanted to start the war so he could make profit on the use of Displace as mercenaries. Somehow, a deal between Displace and the I-SDF goes bad which causes the sides to attack each other. Doug tries to get away and rigs the place to blow with bombs. Sam and Doug meet on the roof of the bath house in a dramatic showdown. Here, Sam finally kills Shetland.The conflict is not over, however, as Toshiro Otomo now has a copy of the Masse Kernels. He attempts to make Japan Imperialist again by blackmailing the government. He threatens to launch a missile (using the Masse Kernals) to destroy a Japanese city. Sam heads down to the headquarters of the I-SDF (an underwater facility known as Kokubo Sosho) in Tokyo to confront Otomo. Attempting to die with honor, Otomo tries committing seppuku and fails. Sam saves him and stability is restored in Asia.Third EchelonThe counter terrorism branch Sam Fisher works for is named "Third Echelon." It is a small team of elite members and is comprised of Sam, Lambert, Grim, and Redding. Other field operatives in the same vein as Sam are alluded during the game, but their names and specific roles are never mentioned.Sam FisherSam FisherA field operative for "Third Echelon" and the protagonist of the game. Sam is equipped with the finest equipment available from omni-visual goggles to an internally silenced prototype assault rifle to launchable sticky cameras. An OPSAT built into his headgear and suit gives him constant access to maps, data, and his analyst team back at Third Echelon HQ, who frequently give him hints and objectives during gameplay as well as occasional nearly off-topic conversations. He is not simply a holster for all these items as Sam himself is a very capable stealth artist and combatant, using any number of sneaky tactics and techniques to get the greatest edge out of any situation. Sam, at the time of this game, is 50 years old and he begins to feel his years as the game progresses. Though it has little to no effect on his physical strength or mental acuity in the game, his age is the subject of many dialogues in the game and ties into the plot several times for a point of reference or explanation; in one mission, Fisher breaks into an off-shore bank and has access to very detailed floor-plans because he actually invaded the same place several years ago, providing this information for himself now.Colonel Irving LambertLambertThird Echelon's director of operations. He is only one step below director of the whole shebang but as far as Sam is concerned, Lambert is the top of the food chain. He gives operatives their objectives both in and out of the field (the primary ones at least). If he doesn't like something you do or you go against his orders, Lambert has the authority to pull the plug and consider the mission a failure at any time, so listen to him. He has a serious attitude most of the time but he will occasionally indulge Sam's slightly dark sense of humor if he feels that the pressure is off.Anna GrimsdottirGrimThe information analyst. Grim can do anything pertaining to computer systems and frequently helps Sam out by providing him with programs to use on PC's in the field as well as dispersing generally plot-related information. Because of the nature of the single-player's story, Grim is occasionally deadlocked by program security beyond her prowess, but these occasions are infrequent. She gives Sam bonus objectives every once in a while, generally involving the perusal of on-site computers for information or downloading spybots for surveillance.William ReddingWillWill belongs in the Metal Gear universe as much as he does in Third Echelon. He is a military nerd, his knowledge of guns and tanks and aircraft extending boundlessly. In mission briefings, he gives you the technical details of the environments Sam will be working in--things like the kinds of security a place will be running or potential routes of ingress--as well as your equipment load out. Once in the field, Will lays down a multitude of useful facts and pointer about obstacles in the field, particularly involving technologies Sam might not be familiar with. If Redding gives Sam a bonus objective, it will involve physical reconnaissance or action.GameplayTom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Chaos Theory builds upon the foundations of the first two entries in the series. Mechanically, it is a third person stealth/action game, with a heavy focus on stealth. The player begins each mission at an infiltration point in the level, and must proceed through the level (for the first time, given the option of non-linear progression, and completing mission objectives in any order they wish) completing their primary objectives. Secondary objectives are optional, however if you fail to complete them in one mission, you must complete them on later missions, although usually in a different form. Opportunity objectives, however, are completely optional, and should you not wish to complete them, or are unable for some reason, you are not punished for leaving them uncompleted (save a slightly lower mission rating). In terms of interface, as well as a standard "light meter", a "sound meter" is added to help players monitor both their own noise, and background noise (if your noise  background noise, enemies nearby can hear you).Chaos Theory adds several new gadgets (for example, the "OCP" providing alternate fire for the pistol, allowing players to disable electronic objects from a distance), however the largest addition is the knife. The knife allows for instant, silent kills as long as you are within striking distance of an enemy, allows you to perform various tasks (i.e. cutting a hole in a tent to provide a back entrance), and replaced the pistol when you take an enemy hostage (threatening them with a blade against their throat rather than a gun against their head). Knife kills are performed by pressing the "primary fire" (left click/right shoulder button) button when you are close to an enemy (indicated by Sam reaching for his knife).The game is, in some ways, easier than previous installments. In addition to instant knife-kills, instant non-lethal takedowns may be performed by pressing alternate fire (right click/left shoulder button). No distinction is made between the two other than in your mission rankings, wherein you score higher for non-lethal kills. In addition, for the first time in the series, you can sneak without making noise at a speed greater than most enemy's patrolling speeds, allowing for you to gain ground and eliminate them more swiftly.CombatThe Sniper attachment may be loud, but it works.It is possible to play through most of the game gunning down your opponents, but Chaos Theory deters this behavior in many ways if you do not do so intelligently. Sam Fisher is an absolutely horrible shot when he isn't looking down a scope and holding his breath, making live combat nearly impossible against more than two opponents. The assault rifle will kill in two or three shots to the body or one to the head. Unfortunately, if you don't hit them in the head (or just miss because Sam has such terrible aim) they will automatically yell and start firing, alerting others to your presence at which point you will be overwhelmed or simply die from the first guy's spray of bullets. Shooting also instantly gives away your position to anyone nearby even when using the silencer, so you must relocate immediately to avoid getting aerated with AK-47 rounds when you do. You also get a small penalty for every kill in the mission rating.That said, lethal force should not be ruled out as a viable option during several missions. If there is only one guard in a room and sneaking around him seems like it might cause problems, don't hesitate to shoot him; the silencer on the rifle might not be great but the sound will not travel through walls or doors. Redding also occasionally gives you powerful anti-personnel tools including under-rifle options like a shotgun and even frag grenades. When you are given these, the mission in question will cater to their usage.Missions1. Peruvian LighthousePrimary Objectives:Rescue MorgenholtRecover or destroy information about the Masse KernelsDiscover where the Guerillas got their arms and equipmentEx-filtrate to the primary extraction pointSecondary Objectives:Eliminate Hugo LacerdaOpportunity Objectives:Scan the SSCC bar code of the delivered cratesBonus Objective:Disable the radio in the lighthouse2. Maria NarcissaPrimary Objectives:Eliminate Hugo LacerdaFind out which cabin Lacerda is inRetrieve the ship's last transit ledger for Lacerda's shipmentRetrieve the bill of lading for Lacerda's arms shipmentEx-filtrate to the extraction pointSecondary Objectives:Find the name of Lacerda's Panamanian contactOpportunity Objectives:Place tracking devices on any illegal weapons cratesBonus Objective:Interrogate Lacerda3. Panama BankPrimary Objectives:Steal $50,000,000 in French governmental bearer bondsDetermine who MCA's bank purchased the arms forEnter the bankAuthorize the vault access from the three officer's panelsEx-filtrate to the extraction pointSecondary Objectives:Look for any suspicious transaction recordsOpportunity Objectives:Plant a series of false e-mails to make it look like an inside jobBonus Objective:Delete camera archives in the security room4. Manhattan, New YorkPrimary Objectives:Access Zherkezi's server to determine who Dvorak isGet to Zherkezi's penthouse in the adjacent buildingFind out who the mercenaries work forLocate DvorakRetrieve a hard copy output for a single Dvorak execution cycleEx-filtrate to the primary extraction pointSecondary Objectives:Discover who is in charge of the Zherkezi protection detailOpportunity Objectives:Tap the penthouse video camerasBonus Objective:Obtain the blueprints for the penthouse5. Displace InternationalPrimary Objectives:Don't kill anyoneAccess the central server in the server roomRetrieve the server access algorithmFind information linking Displace and ZherkeziEx-filtrate to the extraction pointSecondary Objectives:Discover the real identity of Milan NedichOpportunity Objectives:Insert tracer programs into Displace's division serversBonus Objectives:none6. Hokkaido, JapanPrimary Objectives:Abduct Abrahim ZherkezhiEliminate Milan NedichEliminate Douglas ShetlandEx-filtrate to the primary extraction pointSecondary Objectives:noneOpportunity Objectives:Retrieve the hidden microphonesBonus Objective:none7. North KoreaPrimary Objectives:Determine if the Koreans intentionally launched the missileTap the launcher bios for a fingerprint of Dvorak algorithm fragmentsAbort the missileAcquire the missile abort codesEx-filtrate to any available extraction pointSecondary Objectives:NoneOpportunity Objectives:Recover the shipping and repair logsBonus Objective:Disable the warhead in the west command center8. Seoul, South Korea Part 1Primary Objectives:Interrogate a special forces agent to determine the location of JongLocate and retrieve data drives from the NDTGet to the rooftop to transfer data to the EA-6BSecondary Objectives:Tap a mobile command centerOpportunity Objectives:Stop the North Korean propaganda broadcastsBonus Objective:noneSeoul, South KoreaPart 2Primary Objectives:Get to the EA-6B crash siteDesignate the wreckage of the EA-6B aerial bombardmentSecondary Objectives:noneOpportunity Objectives:Gain information about NK UAV'SDisable portable radar reconnaissance receiversBonus Objective:Move the pilots to safety before designation of target9. Japan BathhousePrimary Objectives:Discover who Shetland's contact isGain entry to the bathhouseEavesdrop on Shetland's meeting before I-SDF takes him downEliminate ShetlandSecondary Objectives:Find out who gave the I-SDF assault team their ordersOpportunity Objectives:Tap the bathhouse telephone linesBonus Objective:none10. Japanese I-SDFPrimary Objectives:Contact the detained American officersRecord the meeting the war roomGain access to the war roomDo not kill anyoneCripple Otomo's I-SDF serversCapture Otomo aliveSecondary Objectives:noneOpportunity Objectives:noneBonus Objective:noneMultiplayerChaos Theory also adds on the previous game's "spy vs mercenary" multiplayer mode, and for the first time, co-operative play. The Spies vs Mercenary mode is largely similar to the previous game, bar the addition of some new gadgets and cooperative maneuvers for the Shadownet spies, and enhanced close quarter combat moves for the ARGUS mercenaries. Cooperative play consists of seven, self contained cooperative missions that tie into the story of the single-player campaign. Split screen co-operative is supported. In many cases, it was an advantage to be playing splitscreen. There was a feature where the NPC enemies in co-op play would hear your character talking if you, in reality, were speaking loudly into the microphone.SoundtrackThe in-game soundtrack was composed by Amon Tobin. Each "song" serves as an important gameplay element by changing dynamically after how alert the enemy is. For example, the intensity of the music will increase if you are discovered by an enemy. The score featured in the pre-rendered cut scenes are composed by Jesper Kyd.Track ListingChaos Theory Original SoundtrackThe Lighthouse - 5:05Ruthless - 5:15Theme from Battery - 4:26Kobuko Sosho Stealth - 3:25El Cargo - 4:23Displaced - 6:58Ruthless (Reprise) - 4:27Kobuko Sosho Battle - 4:16Hokkaido - 3:01The Clean Up - 7:00None of these tracks can be heard in full in-game. Chaos Theory only uses small samples picked from each track and mixes  matches them to suit the alert state.GameCube VersionThe GameCube version of Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Chaos Theory supports GBA Connectivity. When connecting an empty GBA to the GameCube (using the GC/GBA cable), the GameBoy Advance "will enhance your OPSAT with wireless communication capabilities." These capabilities include using the GBA screen to monitor activity on the Sticky Camera and displaying a map of the current mission area.Xbox OriginalsOn June 2, 2008, Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Chaos Theory became available on the Xbox 360's Xbox Originals service for 1200 Microsoft Points.HD RemakeTom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Chaos Theory was re-released with high definition graphics on the PlayStation 3 as part of the Splinter Cell Trilogy on September 27, 2011. It was also made available as a standalone 4.8 GB download on the PlayStation Network for $14.99.Versus and co-operative multiplayer was removed in this edition however, as well as the option for inverted controls.System RequirementsSupported OS: Microsoft Windows® 2000/XPProcessor: Intel Pentium III or AMD Athlon, 1.4 GHz (Pentium IV or Athlon 2.2 GHz recommended)System Memory: 256 MB of RAM or above (512 MB recommended)Video Card: 64 MB DirectX 9.0c compliant graphics card (128 MB recommended)Sound Card: DirectX 9.0c compliant sound card (EAX 2.0 or higher recommended)DirectX Version: DirectX® version 9.0c or higherHard Disk: 4 GB available hard disk spaceSupported Peripherals: Windows compatible mouse and keyboard, joystick for Solo and Co-op modesMultiplay: Broadband with 64 Kbps data transfer upload rate (128 kbps recommended)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18082">Metal Gear Solid 3: Snake Eater</game><game id="34">Batman Begins</game><game id="21331">Tenchu Z</game><game id="7539">Tenchu: Wrath of Heaven</game><game id="16004">Tenchu: Stealth Assassins</game><game id="7750">Tenchu: Return from Darkness</game><game id="7004">Hitman 2: Silent Assassin</game><game id="6108">Manhunt</game><game id="20573">Velvet Assassin</game><game id="10267">Metal Gear Solid 3: Subsistence</game><game id="21221">StarCraft Ghost</game><game id="14555">Metal Gear Solid: Portable Ops</game><game id="14979">Mission: Impossible - Operation Surma</game><game id="15282">Tenchu: Fatal Shadows</game><game id="11004">Hitman: Blood Money</game><game id="6601">Hitman: Contracts</game><game id="6709">Hitman: Codename 47</game><game id="20669">Metal Gear Solid 4: Guns of the Patriots</game><game id="16140">Metal Gear Solid</game><game id="12388">Metal Gear Solid 2: Sons of Liberty</game><game id="9594">Metal Gear Solid: The Twin Snakes</game><game id="21258">Manhunt 2</game><game id="22960">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six: Lone Wolf</game><game id="3895">Special Forces: Nemesis Strike</game><game id="20488">Robert Ludlum's The Bourne Conspiracy</game><game id="2978">Cold War</game><game id="21965">Cipher Complex</game><game id="24617">Tenchu: Shadow Assassins</game><game id="21654">Metal Gear Solid 2: Substance</game><game id="2077">The Mark of Kri</game><game id="20497">Dark Sector</game><game id="15774">WinBack: Covert Operations</game><game id="31738">Metal Gear Solid: Snake Eater 3D</game><game id="20464">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Conviction</game><game id="37494">Assassin's Creed III</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2215086-box_scellct.png</image></root>