<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12381</id><name>Ghouls 'N Ghosts</name><description>OverviewThree years after                   Knight Arthur rescues his true love,                  Lucifer (                Loki) brings forth an army of macabre                minions and              steals the               souls of his             helpless victims. Among the souls stolen is Knight Arthur's bride. Once again Arthur dons his            armor to fight the                      undead and                     demonic hordes. Ghouls 'n Ghosts game play is identical to its' possessor's with a few exceptions. Arthur is now able to attack straight up and straight down. A few new weapons have been added and a new set of gold armor. The Gold armor allows Arthur to use his weapon's special ability. Each weapon has a unique special ability save for the Psycho Cannon.Weapons: Special Ability (Gold Armor)          Lance:        Lightning         Sword:       Fire      Dragons        Axe:     ExplosionsFire Water: Quadruple    FireballsDiscus: Mirror  Dagger: Phantom ImageArthur must fight through 5 levels, twice, in order to defeat Lucifer (Loki) and free the trapped souls. On the second run through the game you are allowed to get the Psycho Cannon. It is a ball of  magic that Arthur can throw at his enemies. The Psycho Cannon has no special ability. Gold Armor has the singular affect of increasing the Pyscho Cannon's range. Although a message after the first run through of the game claims that Lucifer (Loki) cannot be defeated without the Psycho Cannon, it is not required to actually defeat him.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6949">Wonder Boy in Monster Land</game><game id="10717">Maximo: Ghosts to Glory</game><game id="8040">Maximo vs Army of Zin</game><game id="16098">Black Tiger</game><game id="12176">Ironsword: Wizards &amp; Warriors II</game><game id="11443">Super Castlevania IV</game><game id="6633">Wizards &amp; Warriors</game><game id="11854">Fire and Brimstone</game><game id="18097">Rastan Saga 2</game><game id="12019">Magic Pockets</game><game id="14800">Trojan</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2370583-genesis_ghoulsnghosts.jpg</image></root>