<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12395</id><name>Need for Speed: Hot Pursuit 2</name><description>OverviewNeed for Speed: Hot Pursuit 2 is a racing game developed by Black Box for the PlayStation 2 and by EA Seattle on the Xbox, GameCube and PC. It was published by Electronic Arts for the PlayStation 2, GameCube, Xbox and PC. The game launched first on the GameCube on September 30, 2002, then on the PlayStation 2 and Xbox on October 1, 2002. It later released on the PC on the 21st of October, 2002. The game is the sequel to 1998's Need for Speed III: Hot Pursuit, despite there being 2 games in the franchise in between III and HP:2. Like its predecessor, Hot Pursuit 2 focuses heavily on police chases in exotic cars around picturesque locations around the world.The game features a number of improvements over previous entries in the franchise including event-tree objective modes, a wider variety of cars and a substantial amount of additions to police offensive and defensive abilities.Need for Speed: Hot Pursuit 2 was released to both critical and commercial acclaim, gaining incredibly favorable reviews for the PS2 version and, to this day, is still considered by many to be the franchise's peak. The GameCube, Xbox and PC version suffered with a number technical issues as well as a severe lack of features found in the PS2 version.Game ModesThere are two main modes of play in Need for Speed: Hot Pursuit 2. The first mode is, obviously, Hot Pursuit mode. The second mode is World Racing mode, which is a more traditional, single-player racing mode. Each mode has a number of different event types which are listed below:Hot Pursuit ModeUltimate Racer Event Tree (PC Version)Quick Race : This randomly selects a car, track and game mode and instantly puts you into a race. This mode has cop cars turned on.You're the Cop: This mode lets you take control of a police car as you attempt to intercept and arrest high-speed drivers. Players must turn on their siren as cars speed by to target them and proceed to ram them into submission. Players also have the ability to call in support from the police force to take down the opponent such as roadblocks, helicopters or back-up police cruisers.Challenge: This mode lets you select a car, a track and a game mode to playthrough. Essentially, Quick Race with customizable options. This mode has cop cars turned on.Ultimate Racer: One of NFS: HP2's two main modes. Ultimate Racer is an event tree-based challenge mode that pits the player in a variety of races and challenges. Advancing further into the tree unlocks better cars, harder tracks and other extras. Ultimate Racer has certain "You're the Cop" events, as well.World Racing ModeChampionship Mode Event Tree (PC Version)Quick Race: This randomly selects a car, track and game mode and instantly puts you into a race. This mode has cop cars turned off.Challenge: This mode lets you select a car, a track and a game mode to playthrough. Essentially, Quick Race with customizable options. This mode has cop cars turned off.Championship: The second of two main modes in HP2. Championship Mode is an event-tree based challenge mode that pits the player in a variety of races and challenges. Advancing further into the tree unlocks better cars, harder tracks and other extras.Car ListThe game categorizes cars into five different classes, from E to A. The higher the class, the better the car. Certain cars are also available/unavailable depending on the game mode.* These cars are classified according to the PlayStation 2 version's car categorization. It differs on the PC/Xbox/GC version.E ClassLotus EliseMake: LotusModel: EliseHorsepower: 122 HPTop Speed: 200 km/h0-60 MPH: 5.6 secondsUnlock Condition: Complete Hot Pursuit Event 1NFS Edition Unlock Condition: Accumulate 250,000 NFS pointsOpel SpeedsterMake: OpelModel: SpeedsterHorsepower: 145 HPTop Speed: 220 km/h0-60 MPH: 5.7 secondsUnlock Condition: Available from startNFS Edition Unlock Condition: Complete Hot Pursuit Event 2Mercedes-Benz CL55 AMGMake: Mercedes-BenzModel: CL55 AMGHorsepower: 355 HPTop Speed: 250 km/h0-60 MPH: 5.8 secondsUnlock Condition: Complete Championship Event 2NFS Edition Unlock Condition: Lead all laps in a Single Race with the Normal versionVauxhall VX220Make: VauxhallModel: VX220Horsepower: 145 HPTop Speed: 220 km/h0-60 MPH: 5.6 secondsUnlock Condition: Available from startNFS Edition Unlock Condition: Lead all laps in a Single Race with the Normal versionFord Falcon TS50Make: Ford AustraliaModel: Falcon TS50Horsepower: 335 HPTop Speed: 250 km/h0-60 MPH: 5.9 secondsUnlock Condition: Complete Championship Event 3NFS Edition Unlock Condition: Win a one-player World Racing Knockout with advanced-difficulty opponents.Ford Crown VictoriaMake: FordModel: Crown VictoriaHorsepower: --- HPTop Speed: --- km/h0-60 MPH: --- secondsUnlock Condition: Not available in normal modesPursuit Edition Unlock Condition (Challenge Mode): Complete Hot Pursuit Challenge 5Pursuit Edition Unlock Condition (You're The Cop): Available from startD ClassJaguar XKR CoupeMake: JaguarModel: XKR CoupeHorsepower: 250 HPTop Speed: 370 km/h0-60 MPH: 5.2 secondsUnlock Condition: Available from startNFS Edition Unlock Condition: Accumulate 150,000 NFS pointsHSV GTS CoupéMake: Holden Special VehiclesModel: GTS CoupéHorsepower: 402 HPTop Speed: 275 km/h0-60 MPH: 5.1 secondsUnlock Condition: Accumulate 50,000 NFS pointsNFS Edition Unlock Condition: Drive a clean race in a Single Race with the Normal versionBMW M5 Make: BMWModel: M5Horsepower: 394 HPTop Speed: 250 km/h0-60 MPH: 5.3 secondsUnlock Condition: Available from startNFS Edition Unlock Condition: Not availableC ClassMake: FordModel: Mustang SVT Cobra RHorsepower: 385 HPTop Speed: 282 km/h0-60 MPH: 4.9 secondsUnlock Condition: Available from startNFS Edition Unlock Condition: Accumulate 500,000 NFS pointsPursuit Edition Unlock Condition (Challenge Mode): Complete Hot Pursuit Challenge 18Pursuit Edition Unlock Condition (You're The Cop): Lead all laps in a Single Race with the Normal versionFerrari 550 BarchettaMake: FerrariModel: 550 Barchetta PininfarinaHorsepower: 485 HPTop Speed: 300 km/h0-60 MPH: 4.3 secondsUnlock Condition: Accumulate 200,000 NFS pointsNFS Edition Unlock Condition: Accumulate 1,000,000 NFS pointsFerrari 360 Modena - Challenge EditionMake: FerrariModel: 360 Modena Challenge EditionHorsepower: 400 HPTop Speed: 290 km/h0-60 MPH: 4.5 secondsUnlock Condition: See: 360 SpiderNFS Edition Unlock Condition: Complete Championship Event C32** This car is exclusive to the PlayStation 2 version **Ferrari 360 SpiderMake: FerrariModel: 360 SpiderHorsepower: 400 HPTop Speed: 290 km/h0-60 MPH: 4.4 secondsUnlock Condition: Complete Championship Event 16NFS Edition Unlock Condition: See: 360 ModenaBMW Z8Make: BMWModel: Z8Horsepower: 394 HPTop Speed: 250 km/h0-60 MPH: 4.6 secondsUnlock Condition: Accumulate 100,000 NFS pointsNFS Edition Unlock Condition: Not availableAston Martin V12 VanquishMake: Aston MartinModel: V12 VanquishHorsepower: 450 HPTop Speed: 306 km/h0-60 MPH: 4.5 secondsUnlock Condition: Complete Championship Event 18NFS Edition Unlock Condition: Accumulate 400,000 NFS pointsB ClassPorsche Carrera GT - Concept VersionMake: PorscheModel: Carrera GT - Concept VersionHorsepower: 558 HPTop Speed: 330 km/h0-60 MPH: 3.9 secondsUnlock Condition: Complete Championship Event 26NFS Edition Unlock Condition: Accumulate 3,500,000 NFS pointsPorsche 911 TurboMake: PorscheModel: 911 TurboHorsepower: 414 HPTop Speed: 305 km/h0-60 MPH: 4.1 secondsUnlock Condition: Available from startNFS Edition Unlock Condition: Accumulate 750,000 NFS pointsLamborghini MurciélagoMake: LamborghiniModel: MurciélagoHorsepower: 571 HPTop Speed: 330 km/h0-60 MPH: 3.7 secondsUnlock Condition: Complete Championship Event 21NFS Edition Unlock Condition: Accumulate 3,000,000 NFS pointsPursuit Edition Unlock Condition (Challenge Mode): Complete Hot Pursuit Challenge 27Pursuit Edition Unlock Condition (You're The Cop): Win a Knockout race in the Normal versionLamborghini Diablo 6.0 VTMake: LamborghiniModel: Diablo 6.0 VTHorsepower: 550 HPTop Speed: 330 km/h0-60 MPH: 3.8 secondsUnlock Condition: Complete Hot Pursuit Challenge 22NFS Edition Unlock Condition: Accumulate 2,000,000 NFS pointsFerrari F50Make: FerrariModel: F50Horsepower: 513 HPTop Speed: 325 km/h0-60 MPH: 3.7 secondsUnlock Condition: Accumulate 300,000 NFS pointsNFS Edition Unlock Condition: Lead all laps in a Single Race with the Normal versionDodge Viper GTSMake: DodgeModel: Viper GTSHorsepower: 450 HPTop Speed: 298 km/h0-60 MPH: 4.0 secondsUnlock Condition: Available from startNFS Edition Unlock Condition: Accumulate 1,500,000 NFS pointsChevrolet Corvette Z06Make: ChevroletModel: Corvette Z06Horsepower: 405 HPTop Speed: 275 km/h0-60 MPH: 3.9 secondsUnlock Condition: Complete Hot Pursuit Challenge 24NFS Edition Unlock Condition: Accumulate 2,500,000 NFS pointsPursuit Edition Unlock Condition (Challenge Mode): Complete Hot Pursuit Challenge 13Pursuit Edition Unlock Condition (You're The Cop): Win a Knockout race in the Normal versionA ClassMercedes-Benz CLK-GTRMake: Mercedes-BenzModel: CLK-GTRHorsepower: 450 HPTop Speed: 600 km/h0-60 MPH: 4.0 secondsUnlock Condition: Drive a clean race in a Single RaceNFS Edition Unlock Condition: Accumulate 4,500,000 NFS pointsMcLaren F1 LMMake: McLarenModel: F1 LMHorsepower: 668 HPTop Speed: 333 km/h0-60 MPH: 3.8 secondsUnlock Condition: Complete Championship Paper 30NFS Edition Unlock Condition: Accumulate 4,000,000 NFS pointsMcLaren F1Make: McLarenModel: F1Horsepower: 627 HPTop Speed: 386 km/h0-60 MPH: 3.2 secondsUnlock Condition: Complete Hot Pursuit Event 30NFS Edition Unlock Condition: Accumulate 5,000,000 NFS pointsTrack ListNeed for Speed: Hot Pursuit 2 has 15 tracks spread across 5 different environments. One of these environments (and its 3 tracks) is exclusive to the PlayStation 2 version, which is the Outback environment. Note that the Reverse Unlock conditions apply only to the PS2 version.ParklandParkland is the first environment the player will see. It is set in a forested, back-road area and features many dirt-road shortcuts.Coastal ParklandsNational ForestScenic DriveTrack NameTypeLengthElevationDifficultyWeatherReverse Unlock ConditionCoastal ParklandsCircuit7.387 km15 to 83mBeginnerSunny, OvercastComplete Championship Event 4National ForestCircuit7.435 km57 to 104mBeginnerSunny, OvercastComplete Championship Event 6Scenic DrivePoint-to-point12.472 km15 to 104mAdvancedSunny, OvercastComplete Championship Event 6MediterraneanMediterranean is a coastal, summer environment located in a ruins-filled waterfront resembling Greece.Calypso CoastAncient RuinsMediterranean ParadiseTrack NameTypeLengthElevationDificultyWeatherReverse Unlock ConditionCalypso CoastCircuit8.207 km3 to 87mAdvancedSunny, OvercastComplete Ultimate Racer Event 26Ancient RuinsCircuit10.042 km3 to 219mBeginnerSunny, SunsetComplete Championship Event 12Mediterranean ParadisePoint-to-point15.240 km3 to 247mAdvancedSunny, OvercastComplete Championship Event 14_________The game has 5 different enviroments (outback, forest, tropical, mediterranean and mountain) with 3 tracks each. All of the tracks are on public roads and have a variety of shortcurts.To make the chases and sense of speed more thrilling the game features 24 cars, most of which are supercars (arranged by performance from fastest to slowest) :McLaren F1, McLaren F1 LM, Mercedes CLK-GTR, Ferrari F50, Aston Martin V12 Vanquish, Ferrari 550 Barchetta, Lamborghini Diablo 6.0 VT, Lamborghini Murcielago, Porsche Carrera GT (this car has subtle differences from the real-world production model since at the time that the game was made the car was still only a concept), Chevrolet Corvette Z06, Dodge Viper GTS, Ferrari 360 Spider, Ford SVT Mustang Cobra R, HSV Coupe GTS, Porsche 911 Turbo, BMW M5, BMW Z8, Ford TS50, Jaguar XKR, Mercedes CL55 AMG, Ford Crown Victoria, Lotus Elise, Opel Speedster, Vauxhall VX220.The game has two racing 'trees' where you complete events and unlock more of them: Championship and Hot Pursuit. The difference between them is that Championship does not feature police and Hot Pursuit does.Game ModesSingle RaceSimply pick a car, track, laps, police settings and race.Free RunAllows you to drive around freely on a track with the car of your choice.DeliveryYou have to get from one point to another and don't let the police stop you.SprintThe goal is to get to the other end of the road before your opponent.TournamentA series of races each of which award you points depending on your performance. The person with the most points wins.Be The CopPropably the most interesting mode in the game, your goal is to catch and stop the speeding vechicles. To do this you have a couple of special abilities that the AI controlled police has in other game modes: Spike strip (blows your tires if you drive on it), Helicopter (throws barrels onto the road that explode when hit) and backup (another police car arrives and helps you out).SoundtrackBush - The People That We LoveThe Buzzhorn - OrdinaryCourse of Nature - Wall of ShameHot Action Cop - Fever for the FlavaHot Action Cop - Going Down on ItThe Humble Brothers - Black HoleThe Humble Brothers - Brake StandThe Humble Brothers - SphereMatt Ragan - Bundle of ClangMatt Ragan - Cone of SilenceMatt Ragan - Flam DancePulse Ultra - Build Your CagesRush - One Little VictoryUncle Kracker - Keep It ComingRom di Prisco - CykloidCreditsProgrammer - Andrew ChangProgrammer - Euan ForresterProgrammer - Brian GreenProgrammer - Tristan GrimmerProgrammer - Phil IbisProgrammer - Jeff JohnstonProgrammer - Chris LippmannProgrammer - Colin O'ConnorProgrammer - Leonard PaulProgrammer - Jim RandallProgrammer - Chris RobertsonProgrammer - Martin SikesProgrammer - Amory WongAdditional Programmer - Ryan BedardAdditional Programmer - Steven BrekelmansAdditional Programmer - Jason DorieAdditional Programmer - Keith HentschelArtist - Stephane AlberolaArtist - Brendan CohoeArtist - Darren GoughArtist - Wesley HolderArtist - Greg IppArtist - Martin KonopaArtist - Li LaoArtist - Wayne LeungArtist - Christian McKeeganArtist - Sean MurphyArtist - Rob OliveiraArtist - Mike OlsonArtist - Alden PhippsArtist - Nigel QuarlessArtist - Russell RiceArtist - Craig SchillerArtist - Daniel SeiberlingArtist - Gene ShihAudio - Rashid HilleProducer - David C. HooperProducer - Richard MulProducer - Stefan Q. WesselsGame Designer - William HoProgrammer - Armory WongExecutive Producer - Sam NelsonSenior Producer - Mark MadlandAssociate Producer - Scott ProbinAssociate Producer - Serena WhittlersAssociate Producer - Arlaine WalkerAssociate Producer - Andy AgostoniAudio - Juan JacynaAudio - Robert RidihalghAudio - Martin WasielAudio - Alistair HirstAudio - Omar Al-KhafajiAudio - Matt RaganSenior Art Director - Henry LabountaArtist - Curtis HoinesArtist - Phil ChowArtist - Yvonne Vuu CarinhaProduction Coordinator - Lia SiojoProduction Coordinator - Bryna DabbyProduction Assistance - Brian "Tunaboy" TaneyProduction Assistance - Ragnar LindstromContributing Producer - Hanno LemkePC system requirementsMinimum:Windows XP/ME/2000/98Intel Pentium III 450MHz, or AMD Athlon 500MHz128MB RAM4X CD-ROM/DVD-ROM Drive1.2GB Hard Disk Space16MB Direct3D compatible Video CardDirectX 8.1 compatible Sound CardRecommended:Intel Pentium III, or AMD Athlon 800MHz32MB Direct3D compatible Video Card16X CD-ROM/DVD-ROM drive</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2279">Project Gotham Racing 2</game><game id="20038">NASCAR: Dirt to Daytona</game><game id="941">Project Gotham Racing</game><game id="19809">Project Gotham Racing 3</game><game id="8437">TOCA 2: Touring Car Challenge</game><game id="7019">Ridge Racer V</game><game id="16276">Ford Bold Moves Street Racing</game><game id="20919">Ford Racing: Off Road</game><game id="7431">Ford Racing</game><game id="12950">Gran Turismo 3 A-Spec</game><game id="7777">Juiced</game><game id="10124">Midnight Club: Street Racing</game><game id="284">NASCAR 2005: Chase for the Cup</game><game id="17872">TOCA Race Driver 3 Challenge</game><game id="8438">NASCAR 06: Total Team Control</game><game id="23347">Test Drive</game><game id="1052">Super PickUps</game><game id="5819">Speed Devils</game><game id="20418">Midnight Club II</game><game id="5875">Midnight Club 3: DUB Edition</game><game id="20927">Midnight Club: Los Angeles</game><game id="21114">Midnight Club: Los Angeles Remix</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1897545-box_nfshp2.png</image></root>