<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12414</id><name>Super Bomberman 2</name><description>OverviewSuper Bomberman 2's single player mode focuses on alien invaders, named "The Dastardly Bombers", who kidnap Bomberman from Planet Bomber in their enormous spaceship. Bomberman must take down the five invaders and save Planet Bomber from destruction.Single PlayerWith each section of the spaceship (of which there are five), Bomberman must progress through six normal levels by destroying every enemy, activating all the capsules (which alternate on and off when bomb blasts hit them) and finding the exit. Bomberman must then fight that area's Dastardly Bomber in a one-on-one battle in the seventh level and then in their boss machine - a large personalized mech suit - in the eighth. The single player involve taking out each one of the Dastardly Bombers by entering each of the worlds and taking out each area. Unlike in the previous Bomberman game, the area has changed from a closed square, to an open area with different map layouts.Castle Stage - Magnet BomberMagnet Bomber is the first of the Dastardly Bombers Bomberman faces. He is able to magnetically attract and repel bombs, making it hard to line them up correctly while fighting him.Magnet Bomber's boss machine - Iron Gigue - is a giant robot that can only move laterally, sending out frequent punches. If it rolls over a bomb, the bomb will vanish, so the player will need to lead the slow-moving robot into blasts.Flame Stage - Golem BomberGolem Bomber is a huge red leviathan that tends to use Bomberman's own bombs against him by throwing them around with the Power Glove power-up.Golem Bomber's boss machine - Breast Fire - is a multi-podded machine that moves in straight lines in random directions. It attacks by stopping, firing a quartet of fireballs that slowly fall to the arena and creates bomb blasts before moving again. Though dangerous, it's own fireballs will damage it, making it possible to defeat Breast Fire without the player ever having to lay a single bomb.Amusement Park Stage - Pretty BomberA female bomberman (bomberwoman?), Pretty Bomber uses the "Heart Bombs", which move around on their own chaotically, to ensnare Bomberman.Pretty Bomber's boss machine - Mask Change - is a giant sun-shaped face that moves diagonally around the arena. It doesn't actively engage Bomberman unless he destroys one of its heart-shaped projectiles.Factory Stage - Brain BomberBrain Bomber is, obviously, the brains behind the Dastardly Bombers' operation. He is particularly weak in a one-on-one fight, being able to only drop one bomb at a time with a minimal blast radius. He does, however, have the remote control bomb upgrade.Brain Bomber's boss machine - Robo Bomber - resembles a gigantic white Bomberman like the player. He moves slowly around the arena in a random path. His enormous bombs, when they explode, create unorthodox blast areas that can be hard to gauge.Dark Stage - Plasma BomberThe leader of the Dastardly Bombers, Plasma Bomber, fights with his own special looking bombs. He is able to throw bombs, but doesn't have any other specific advantages - he's just very fast and deadly.Plasma Bomber's boss machine - SkeleGuard - resembles a skeletal version of Iron Gigue and fights similarly, moving laterally across the top of the screen. It has more methods of attack, however.After defeating SkeleGuard, Plasma Bomber appears to surrender, but is shot down by an unseen assailant. The true final boss battle begins against General Ganzu, a floating eyeball enemy. Ganzu is impervious to explosions, so the only way to damage it is by throwing bombs at it with the Power Glove. Because it speeds up the more it is damaged, it becomes harder to accurately aim the thrown bombs (and avoid getting hit).MultiplayerThe multiplayer "Battle Game" allows up to four players (with the Super Multitap peripheral) to compete in twelve different arenas, each with their own specific features and conditions.Super Bomberman 2 introduces the "Golden Bomberman" rule, in which the winning player of the previous tournament plays a roulette game to randomly select between six power-ups (including the Geta - or Clogs - a gag item that makes the player slower). In the new tournament, that player's bomberman turns golden-colored and begins every match with that power-up.Arena 1 - Usual.No special conditions.Arena 2 - Slippery Tunnel.Players will slip across the frictionless ice floors. There are also six warp holes - falling into one randomly teleports the player to one of the five others.Arena 3 - Oshikura Manjuu.Players can no longer pass through each other, instead they push against one another when met. The screen also wraps around vertically, similarly to Pac-Man, so players can go up and appear at the bottom of the screen.Arena 4 - Oil Shock.There's an oil trench that circles around the center of the arena. If any errant bomb blast hits the trench, the entire trench flames up, eliminating anyone standing in it.Arena 5 - Secret Flower Zone.This area has obfuscating awnings that block the player from seeing what's happening underneath. Furthermore, there are spots on the arena which will maximize the strength of the bomb blasts of bombs placed on them.Arena 6 - Chocolate Warp Stage.There are two pairs of warp zones, colored red and blue, which link to each other. Bombers can walk through the warp zones, or they can kick bombs through.Arena 7 - B-1 Circuit.This unusual stage has only one "soft block" - blocks that are destroyed for items - so players must fight over it. The soft block will regenerate each time it is destroyed. Also, there are "Speed Change Panels" which either speed up or slow down any Bombers that pass over them, as well as a "Pause Panel" in the center which stops Bombers dead in their tracks for a few seconds.Arena 8 - Conveyor Belt.This stage has a ring around the center that makes anything placed on them move either clockwise or counter-clockwise around the center. The direction and speed of the conveyor belt can be changed with two buttons in the center of the arena.Arena 9 - Curve Bomb.This arena is littered with arrows which redirect kicked bombs sent towards them. It can be hard to judge where a kicked bomb might end up.Arena 10 - Matango Jump.This forested stage has mushrooms for soft blocks. Players can jump at any time with the Y button, passing over one block. If they land on a mushroom, they will bounce off and jump one more space in that direction.Arena 11 - Gin Gin Deathmatch.One of two "secret arenas", activated by repeatedly pressing the X button for six seconds on the title screen, is an item-less (besides one Skull virus) arena that resembles a wrestling ring.Players are fully powered-up, making this a direct deathmatch. They can also launch themselves off the ropes surrounding the arena for short bursts of invincibility.Arena 12 - Boyoyon Jump.Another secret arena, activated the same way as Gin Gin Deathmatch. The players must be wary of trampolines and "Crystal Blocks", which operate like land-mines.Secret CodesEnter 5656 on the passwords section to enable Sudden Death in multiplayer</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="35226">Super Tekkyuu Fight!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2364811-snes_superbomberman2_ca.jpg</image></root>