<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12411</id><name>Soulcalibur</name><description>OverviewSoulcalibur is the second installment in the "Soul" series with the first being    Soul Edge/Soul Blade which featured originally in arcades and would later be ported to Sony's Playstation 1 console. The game was developed and produced by    Namco who felt that the newer Sega Dreamcast system would better suit a sequel as it offered better graphical power and it very quickly became one of the most popular and best selling Dreamcast games ever. Soulcalibur on the Dreamcast was also the first time the series found fame with fans as the original installment in the series is generally seen as an underground hit rather then a huge success. Seen by many of its fans as one of the greatest fighting games of all time, it is clear to see why this game has found a fond place in fans hearts and continues to be loved today with newer installments of the series. The name of the game itself comes from the weapon created to help defeat the evil Soul Edge Blade which caused so much pain in the first installment. The game itself is also apparently set around the date 1587, except specific timelines have often been taken with a pinch of salt by the fans. Soulcalibur threw the Soul series into the same leagues as competitors such as    Street Fighter,    Tekken and    Dead or Alive.Strangely enough, when Soulcalibur first saw light in arcades it wasn't greatly recieved and wasn't as popular as Namco had first hoped. This is interesting considering how strong the Soulcalibur fanbase is now and could have seen the beat em up classic not appearing on the Dreamcast at all. The game itself was set 3 years after the original Soul Blade/Edge game and continued a story that would later go on to be a surprisingly deep feature for fans of the series as all of the SC Characters featured to date have somewhat deep back stories. Of course Soulcalibur in itself brought a revolution to the Fighter/Beat em Up genre in the form of the now common eight-way run system which allowed the player to use rolls and sidesteps compared to the fixed and limited third axis system which only allowed the player to move from side to side. It was a huge addition in a genre that as rarely seen great advancements in gameplay with many developers sticking to a classic style of fighter that will always please its fan base. It's a feature that would be key to the success of future installments and is still today seen as one of the biggest additions to the fighting/beat em up genre.StoryTakiPirate    Cervantes de Leon of Spain obtained the mythical Sword of Legends also known as the '    Soul Edge'. The sword devoured his soul and turned him insane, slaying his entire crew. For a good 20 years the Dread Pirate stayed silent in the Sea Port Town of Valencia where he would take the souls of those who reached him during their search for the legendary sword. Soon began a reign of terror, violence and pain, yet the joint efforts of the divine warrior Sophitia and the underground Ninja Taki were enough to stop the violent Cervantes in his tracks and in the process breaking one of the twin Soul Blades in half. Another warrior happened upon the remains of Soul Edge, the young knight,    Siegfried. Upon approaching the blades, Cervantes rose, bathed in hellfire, wielding the broken blades. He had become    Inferno, the condensed will of the evil sword. Siegfried swiftly dealt with the weakened monster. After the battle, he picked up the Famous blade. Soul Edge took control of his mind, much as it did Cervantes, using the memory of Siegfried's dead father as a tool, to get the boy to harvest souls for the evil sword. With the evil seed infecting him, Siegfried had turned into a    Nightmare, clad in Azure armor.Three Years later, the Azure Nightmare and it's crazed minions have gathered enough souls to start a ritual to return Soul Edge to it's formal power. Unknown to Nightmare and his followers, a group of young warriors meet on their journeys to stop Soul Edge and with them three sacred weapons are joined once again.FeaturesSoulcalibur has many familiar features that currently exist in the fighting genre. Modes such as Arcade Mode, which consists of choosing one of the sixteen characters found within the game and fighting through 8 rounds with the 7th round opponent being based around the character your playing and the story they tell. The game also feature other classic modes such as Vs Mode, Time Attack, Team Battle, Survival and also Training Mode which allows you to practice with your favorite fighters.The Game also featured a Mission Mode, which allowed the player to move through various levels where fighting and fulfilling tasks earned you special points which could be spent on new costumes, artwork, CG Portraits, fanart and sketches. Another interesting feature not seen in any other fighter was the 'Exhibition Videos' or 'Katas' as they were also known. These videos allowed the player to see various characters performing Katas with the weapon of choice.Strangely, Soulcalibur is the only Soulcalibur game to be without the extra weapons feature. A feature that existed in Soul Blade/Edge,  Soulcalibur II and   Soulcalibur III.5 of the 19 characters available will given an extra 3rd costume to unlock using the Mission Mode. These characters were Maxi, Voldo, Siegfried, Sophitia and Xianghua. Also each character counted with an extra 'transparent' version of their costume in the arcade Version and in the Dreamcast Version counted with a 'Liquid Metal' version of the characters costume.VersionsSEGA DREAMCASTDreamcast version playable characters.Soulcalibur was first released in Japan on the 5th of August 1999 and would be a launch title in North America on the 9th of September 1999. When released it was highly praised and became a fine example of a port being better then its original with much improved graphics, game modes, gameplay changes and new costumes, not to mention the inclusion of a new extra character in    Cervantes De Leon. At the time of release, the    Dreamcast version was cited as being one of the best looking games of all time. It was also a version which saw new modes such as Team Battle, Survival and Training Mode. An 'Artwork' section was also added which included character based artwork, FanArt and general high-res art. A 'Liquid Metal' version of characters costumes was also added along with a Battle Theater which allowed the player to watch battles between two characters played by the A.I. Another interesting note is that in the North American release of Soulcalibur, one of    Voldo's suggestive codpieces which featured a bull was removed, while both the Japanese and European Versions kept it in the game.XBOX LIVE MARKETPLACEApril 2008 saw    Namco Bandai announce that a port of the classic fighter would be released on Microsoft's    Xbox Live Marketplace. It was made available for download on July 2nd 2008, and featured improved HD graphics and LIVE leaderboards. To the dismay of Soulcalibur fans Namco Bandai confirmed that no online mode would be added to the game, this, added to the fact that the Mission Mode found in the original Dreamcast Version is missing, meant that the port got less than impressive reviews from both the gaming media and fans. The game did feature most of the modes available from the original and also saw everything unlocked from the beginning which allowed a player to use characters that were originally locked in the Dreamcast version from the start.This version features the following playable characters:HwangYoshimitsuLizardmanSiegfriedRockSeung MinaCervantesEdge MasterVoldoIvySophitiaMitsurugiKilikXianghuaMaxiNightmareTakiAstarothSuccessSoulcalibur went on to be a huge hit on Sega's Dreamcast system, selling over 1 Million copies in 1999 alone. For the first time the series got its just deserve and was seen as one of the best fighting games out there, for both newbies and experienced players. It is to this day still seen as one of the greatest Beat em up's ever made and is a fine example of the genre done right. At the time of release, it got glowing reviews from all around the world and began what would become a famous series of fighting games still going strong to this day.SoundtrackDisc One1."Light  Darkness"光と闇の闘い（オープニング）2:012."The Stage of History"歴史の舞台へ（キャラクターセレクト）1:073."The New Legend"新たなる伝説 剣聖の石庭（キリク＆エッジマスター）2:374."Bloom and Harvest"花の盛りと実りの時 神宗帝の庭園（シャンファ）2:335."Sail Over the Storm"荒海を越えて インドの港街（マキシ）2:466."Duelists"刃に生き，刃に死す 備中高松城（御剣）2:487."The Cursed Soul"呪われし心臓 方広寺～地下大仏殿（タキ）2:528."Remembrance"懐かしい幻 秘倉マネーピッ（ヴォルド）ト2:389."Wings of Faith"信念の翼 エイリュディケ神殿～神々の回廊（ソフィーティア）2:3710."In Father's Name"父の名の元に オストラインスブルク攻城戦跡（ナイトメア）2:2711."Born From Chaos"狭間より沸き出でし者 バルギア大神殿（アスタロス）～クンペクトー2:4012."Unblessed Soul"祝福されざる者 ヴァレンタイン邸（アイヴィー）2:3413."Beyond the Horizon"地平線の果てに シルクロードの遺跡（黄星京）2:3214."Chasing Downstream"激流の彼方 霊峰富士～地下水脈（吉光）2:4415."Worth Dying For"死に値するもの ヴェネツィアの水路（ジークフリート）2:2916."Gathering: Destiny Beckons"戦士たちの集い：宿命の引力 古代闘技場跡2:5117."Eye to Eye, Blade to Blade"火花散る魂の激闘 トルコの地下迷宮～死者の間（成美那）1:3118."Leaving the World Behind"全てを捨てて エイドリアン号と海岸砦（セルバンデス）2:5119."Immortal Flame"不死の焔 カオス～心象世界（インフェルノ）2:4420."Everlasting Quest"旅果つる先は…（ミッションバトル：マップ画面）1:3321."Going to Where the Wind Blows"風に吹かれるまま（スライドショー）1:5022."Kaleidoscope"揺れ動く未来～戦士たちの偶像（オープニングディレクション）1:2223."Going to Where the Wind Blows: Reprise"風に吹かれるがまま：回想（アートギャラリー）2:2924."The Seal Was Broken"解かれし封印（カードゲットジングル）0:0925."Prepare to Unleash Yourself"白刃の煌めき（乱入ジングル１）0:0826."Prepare to Defend Yourself"黒金の咆哮（乱入ジングル２）0:0727."Apocalypse"黙示の時代（エンディング１）0:4428."Sacrifice"消えゆく魂（エンディング２）0:4329."Forever Onward"終わりなき旅（エンディング３）0:4230."Into the Sunlight"今，光の中へ（エンディング４）0:4431."No Remorse, No Pain"鋼の意志（エンディング５）0:4232."The Legend Will Never Die"伝説は死なず（ネームエントリー）1:4133."Recollection: A Tribute to Those Who Shed Red"魂の記憶：赤き血を流せし者達へ（エンドクレジット）2:10Disc Two1."Under the Star of Destiny (Arcade Version)"宿命の星のもと（AC版アトラクト）0:492."Recollection: A Tribute to Those Who Shed Red (Arcade Version)"AC版エンドクレジット1:573."Light  Darkness (Soul Mix)"光と闇の闘い（SOUL MIX）4:554."Going to Where the Wind Blows (Piano Mix)"風に吹かれるがまま（PIANO MIX)3:14</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10081">Tekken</game><game id="721">Ehrgeiz: God Bless the Ring</game><game id="2045">Dead or Alive 2</game><game id="19766">Virtua Fighter 3</game><game id="18522">Onimusha: Blade Warriors</game><game id="21376">Guilty Gear Dust Strikers</game><game id="20544">Naruto: Clash of Ninja</game><game id="21375">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja 3</game><game id="2895">Battle Arena Toshinden 3</game><game id="3839">Dead or Alive</game><game id="6399">Bushido Blade</game><game id="9603">Star Wars: Masters of Teräs Käsi</game><game id="7564">The Last Blade 2</game><game id="19043">Fighters Megamix</game><game id="1480">Star Gladiator Episode 1: Final Crusade</game><game id="22292">Dead or Alive 2: Hardcore</game><game id="7792">Dead or Alive 4</game><game id="11813">Guilty Gear</game><game id="3744">Def Jam: Fight for NY</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="11065">Shaman King: Power of Spirit</game><game id="16842">Street Fighter: Anniversary Collection</game><game id="13753">Dead or Alive Ultimate</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="11822">Soulcalibur II</game><game id="9855">Soulcalibur III</game><game id="20678">Soulcalibur IV</game><game id="11945">Soulcalibur Legends</game><game id="21195">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai Tenkaichi 3</game><game id="20500">Dragon Ball Z: Burst Limit</game><game id="13129">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai 3</game><game id="1490">Dragon Ball Z: Ultimate Battle 22</game><game id="690">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai Tenkaichi</game><game id="1499">Dragon Ball Z: Shin Budokai - Another Road</game><game id="5206">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai</game><game id="8789">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai Tenkaichi 2</game><game id="15234">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai 2</game><game id="8673">Fighter Destiny 2</game><game id="23223">Mythic Blades</game><game id="23220">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja</game><game id="23007">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja Heroes</game><game id="21582">Naruto Shippuuden: Gekitou Ninja Taisen! EX 2</game><game id="4348">Project Justice</game><game id="18645">Dragon Ball GT: Final Bout</game><game id="9658">Dynasty Warriors</game><game id="10476">War Gods</game><game id="22305">Street Fighter III: 2nd Impact</game><game id="21948">Street Fighter III: New Generation</game><game id="20449">Mortal Kombat vs. DC Universe</game><game id="29790">Deadliest Warrior: The Game</game><game id="26611">Tournament of Legends</game><game id="35844">Deadliest Warrior: Legends</game><game id="5662">Fighting Vipers</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14036/824176-soulcalibur_cover.jpg</image></root>