<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12418</id><name>SSX on Tour</name><description>SSX On Tour is the fourth game in the       SSX Franchise and introduces skiing to the gameplay formula. Both snowboarding and skiing fundamentally control the same with the differentiating factor being the tricks. At the beginning of career mode, you are given the choice between playing a snowboarder or a skier, after which point you may not switch. The only way to switch between them is to make a new character with the specified style.The      GameCube release of the game features     Mario,    Luigi, and   Princess Peach as playable characters outside of career mode. Also featured is a Mario themed level and a remixed  Super Mario Bros. song. Overview  The focus of On Tour remains the same from SSX 3. You earn boost by doing tricks and as you earn boost you unlock the ability to do Monster Tricks, which behave in much the same way as uber tricks from previous SSX games. You can still pick a character from the series, but On Tour features a Create-A-Character mode.  Although this character will start the game with zero stats, while playing through the career mode, opportunities are presented to boost these stats. Completing events earns you "Hype", which serves to measure your progress through the game. There is no online multiplayer as the focus of this game was Single-player.    Although the game was generally well received by critics, claims were made that the series' gameplay was beginning to become stale. Gameplay Events - These events are the main challenges. They range from races to freestyle events. Shreds - These are unofficial challenges in the game that have greater variety than the regular events. Some range from escaping the ski-patrol to only staying on the snow for a set amount of time before reaching the end of the run.Soundtrack Avenged Sevenfold - " Bat Country"* (from the album   City of Evil)  Billy Talent - "Red Flag" (from   Billy Talent II)  Blackalicious - "Rhythm Sticks" (from   The Craft)  Bloc Party - " Banquet (song)" (from   Silent Alarm)  Bonobo - "Pick Up" (from   Dial 'M' For Monkey) Bonobo - "Flutter" (from  Dial 'M' For Monkey)  Chali 2na feat.  Beenie Man - "International" (from   Fish Outta Water)  C-Rayz Walz - "Street Reppin" (from   Year Of The Beast)  Death from Above 1979 - " Romantic Rights" (from   You're a Woman, I'm a Machine)  Def Leppard - " Let It Go" (from   High 'n' Dry)  Dio - "Stand Up and Shout" (from   Holy Diver)  Diplo - "Big Lost" (from   Florida) Diplo feat.  P.E.A.C.E. - "Indian Thick Jawns" (from  Florida)  Diva International - "Nothing to Do" (from   Sold Down The River)  DJ Spooky and  Dave Lombardo feat.  Chuck D - " B-Side Wins Again" (from   Drums of Death)  The Faint - "I Disappear" (from   Wet from Birth)  Fu Manchu - "I Can't Hear You" (from   Start the Machine (album))  Goldfinger - "My Everything" (from   Disconnection Notice)  The Hives - "No Pun Intended" (from   Tyrannosaurus Hives)  The Herbaliser feat.  Roots Manuva - "Lord, Lord" (from   Take London) The Herbaliser - "Gadget Funk" (from  Take London)  Hot Hot Heat - "Pickin' It Up" (from   Elevator)  Iron Maiden - " Run to the Hills" (from   The Number of the Beast)  Jurassic 5 - "Red Hot" (from   Feedback)  LCD Soundsystem - " Daft Punk Is Playing at My House" (from   LCD Soundsystem)  Louis XIV - "God Killed the Queen" (from   The Best Little Secrets Are Kept)  Maxïmo Park - "Apply Some Pressure" (from   A Certain Trigger)  Morningwood - "Nü Rock" (from   Morningwood)  Motörhead - " Overkill" (from   Overkill)  Nine Black Alps - "Shot Down" (from   Everything Is)  OK Go - " Here It Goes Again" (from   Oh No)  Paul Wall feat.  Big Pokey - " Sittin' Sidewayz" (from   The Peoples Champ)  Pennywise - "Competition Song" (from   The Fuse)  The Perceptionists - "People 4 Prez" (from   Black Dialogue)  Queens of the Stone Age - "Medication" (from   Lullabies to Paralyze)  Rock n Roll Soldiers - "Flag Song" (from   The Two EPs)  Scorpions - "Dynamite" (from   Blackout)  Sweatshop Union - "Come Back" (from   United We Fall)  Vatican DC - "Antisocial" (from   We Carnival)  We Are Scientists - "Lousy Reputation" (from   With Love and Squalor)  Z-Trip feat.  Whipper Whip - "All About the Music" (from   Shifting Gears) </description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1932">SSX</game><game id="17149">SSX 3</game><game id="17969">SSX Blur</game><game id="12418">SSX on Tour</game><game id="15979">SSX Out of Bounds</game><game id="18782">SSX Tricky</game><game id="20954">Shaun White Snowboarding</game><game id="15802">Sonic Riders</game><game id="18946">1080° Snowboarding</game><game id="18426">Snowboard Kids 2</game><game id="18062">Snowboard Kids</game><game id="19339">1080° Avalanche</game><game id="1509">Amped: Freestyle Snowboarding</game><game id="5022">Freekstyle</game><game id="5474">BMX XXX</game><game id="14367">Sled Storm</game><game id="9279">Kelly Slater's Pro Surfer</game><game id="23479">Stoked</game><game id="25097">Shaun Palmer's Pro Snowboarder</game><game id="24449">We Ski &amp; Snowboard</game><game id="5510">X-Games: Pro Boarder</game><game id="9806">EyeToy: AntiGrav</game><game id="20957">Pure</game><game id="20880">We Ski</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2139877-box_ssx4.png</image></root>