<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12447</id><name>Mario Party 3</name><description>OverviewThe game's title screen with the Mario Party crew.Mario Party 3 was the last game in the popular series to be released on the Nintendo 64. It was also one of the last games to actually be released on the console. In fact, the game became very rare in Europe and is sold online for very high prices. Mario Party 3 probably made the biggest additions and changes in the history of the series. Because of this, it very much became a love-or-hate game to the fans of the series. Many of the new additions made in this game did not make a return when the series shifted over to the GameCube with Mario Party 4.Battle RoyalDescriptionBattle Royal is the same mode that was used in previous Mario Party games. The objective is to move around the game board and collect as many stars as possible. The person who has the most stars by the end of the predetermined amount of turns wins. Players obtain stars at the Star Space for 20 coins. The Star Space is randomly determined and each time somebody gets a star, the Star Space moves to another location on the board. At the end of each turn, the 4 characters compete in a mini-game. The winner(s) of the mini-game receives 10 coins. To move around the board, players hit a 10-sided dice block, and the number they get determines how far they move.SpacesThere are a total of 8 different spaces players can land on each board:Blue Space: The most frequent space on all of the boards. If you land on this, you will get 3 coins (6 in the last 5 turns) and a blue status for that turn.Red Space: Landing on this will make you lose 3 coins (6 in the last 5 turns) and give you a red status for that turn.Happening Space: A green space with a question mark on top. Landing on one has a variety of actions, depending on the board and the location. It will give you a green status for that turnBowser Space: The worse space to possibly land on. Bowser will bring up a roulette, each option with a horrible consequence, which includes losing stars and coins. This also gives a red status.Chance Time Space: A green space with an exclamation mark on top. This brings up a slot machine with 3 panels. The left and right panel are the playing characters while the middle one is the yield. Players can give a certain amount of coins or stars to the other player, or they could both swap coins or stars. This also gives a green status.Battle Space: All players must give up a certain amount of coins to the pot and play a mini-game. 1st place gets 70% and second place gets 30%.Item Space: One of the best spaces because there is a high reward and no risk. You either play an item mini-game to earn items or you get asked a question by Toad or Baby Bowser and they give you an item if you picked the right answer. This space gives a green status.Koopa Bank Space: Passing by this space will force you to give up 5 coins to the Koopa Bank. Landing on this space will give you all of the coins the Koopa Bank has collected. Landing here gives a green status.Game Guy Space: Landing on this space will force you to surrender all of your coins, and play a Game Guy mini-game. Winning will double your coin total, but if you lose, all your coins will be lost.Mini-Game Types4 Player Mini-Game: This mini-game will take place after the turn is over if all of the characters have a blue status* or if all have a red status*. In these mini-games all 4 players are competing against each other to win the mini-game.1 VS 3 Mini-Game: This mini-game will take place after the turn is over if one character has a blue status* and three have a red status* or if one character has a red status* and three have a blue status*. In these mini-game one person takes on a team of three.2 VS 2 Mini-Game: This mini-game takes place after the turn is over if two characters have a blue status* and the two other characters have a red status*. In these mini-games, a two teams of two compete against eachother for victory.Battle Mini-Game: A battle mini-game will occur if somebody lands on the Battle Space. Every player must give up a certain amount of coins to the pot. 1st place gets 70% and 2nd place gets 30%.Item Mini-Game: One person can play an item mini-game if they land on the Item Space. Obviously, they can earn items by winning.Duel Mini-Game: A player can use an item, The Dueling Glove, to initiate a duel. The person who initiates the duel wagers the amount of coins or stars both players put in the pot. The winner takes all of them. Duels can also be stated if two players land on the same space in the last 5 turns.Game Guy Mini-Game: When somebody lands on a Game Guy space, they must play a Game-Guy mini-game. He/She must wager all of their coins; winning doubles the amount of coins, but losing takes away every coin. These mini-games are completely luck based.* - If you received a green status for that turn, a computer will randomly assign you to a blue or red status.Duel ModeDescriptionDuel mode was a completely new addition to the Mario Party series. In duel mode there are only two combatants instead of the usual 4. The objective here is different than Battle Royal; instead of collecting stars, the mission is to remove the enemy's 5 heart pieces. To do this, you can use a partner that you pay 10 coins for, and they will move in front of you. If you walk into the enemy, they will attack him or her which will result in lost heart pieces, depending on how strong the partner is. You can also have a partner be put behind you so you can use some defense. The partner you get is determined by a roulette. Partners also have a salary that you have to pay on a turn-basis. They will disappear if you cannot pay for their services. If both combatants are still alive by the end of the predetermined amount of turns, then the character with the most heart pieces wins. If they have the same amount of heart pieces, then the character with the most coins wins. If they still somehow have the same amount of heart pieces and coins, then the winner will be determined by who rolls a higher number on 10-sided dice block.SpacesThere are some new spaces exclusively for the Duel Mode and some from Battle Royal. There are also others from Battle Royal that are not present in Duel Mode. The following are the spaces in Duel Mode:Normal Space: A normal, blank space. When you land on one, your characters face will mark it. If you land on the same space again, you will earn 5 coins. If enemy lands on it, you will receive 5 coins from them. You can also land it your enemy's space(s).Mini-Game Space: When this space is landed on, a mini-game begins and the winner receives 5 coins.Power-Up Space: When somebody lands on a Power-Up Space, his or her characters' stats will go up, however, so will their salary.Reverse Space: If landed on, you are forced to roll again and move in the opposite direction.Happening Space: A green space with a question mark on top. Landing on one has a variety of actions, depending on the board and the location.Game Guy Space: Landing on this space will force you to surrender all of your coins, and play a Game Guy mini-game. Winning will double your coin total, but if you lose, all your coins will be lost.Story ModeDescriptionIn story mode, the objective is to collect 7 star-stamps. In order to do this, you must win in Battle Royal and Duel Mode games. For each stamp you must first one a Battle Royal and then win a Duel Mode game. However, for the seventh stamp, you must beat a boss. After doing so, you beat the Story Mode. By beating it, the face of the character that you beat it with will be engraved into Mt. Mariomore, a play on the American monument, Mt. Rushmore. You will also unlock a hidden mini-game and unlock super hard difficulty if you beat Story Mode on hard.Other Notable AdditionsThis was the first Mario Party to add additional characters to the original six. The cast for Mario Party 3 is: Mario, Luigi, Peach, Yoshi, Donkey Kong, Wario, Waluigi (new), and Daisy (new). However, Waluigi and Daisy cannot be used in Story Mode.This was the first entry in the series to allow multiple items to be held. Mario Party 3 allows three items to be held, while Mario Party 2 only allowed one.</description><genres><genre id="14">Trivia/Board Game</genre><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14407">Pac-Man Fever</game><game id="2819">Sonic Shuffle</game><game id="21617">Rayman: Raving Rabbids</game><game id="8753">Bomberman Land Touch!</game><game id="15952">Crash Bash</game><game id="23732">Bomberman Land Touch! 2</game><game id="16650">Fuzion Frenzy</game><game id="404">Disney's Party</game><game id="7669">Cartoon Network Block Party</game><game id="17156">My Street</game><game id="31210">Wii Party</game><game id="33914">Doraemon Wii: Himitsu Douguou Ketteisen!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2129487-box_mparty3.png</image></root>