<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12455</id><name>Creatures 2: Torture Trouble</name><description>Creatures 2: Torture Trouble was released in 1992 for the Commodore 64 and is the sequel to the 1990 game Creatures, or to give it its full title (Clyde Radcliffe Exterminates All The Unfriendly Repulsive Earth-ridden Slime).  The game was developed by Apex Computer Productions and published by Thalamus Ltd.  Unlike the original Creatures which was a side-scrolling platformer, Creatures 2 was mainly a series of torture screens in which you controlled the hero Clyde Radcliffe and had to figure out how to stop the death of your children within each scenario.      Frying tonight!!! Solve the puzzle, save your child.An example of a typical torture scenario is shown on the right where you have to figure out how to put out the fire which is slowly toasting your kid!!After each torture screen has been completed you have to save more of your children who are being thrown off one edge of screen by a monster and you must use a trampoline to guide them to safety and pick up extra lives in the process.Bounce your kid to safety or...When you complete 2 torture screens you end up fighting a demon which increases in size as you battle. Demon battle...seems easy...Oh oh, he seems to be getting mad...Ok this is getting bad...  After you clear an island of all the monsters and save your children you have to swim to the next island using scuba gear and transport your children at the same time.Island hopping.There are 3 islands in the game and each island comprises of 2 torture screens, 2 trampoline interludes, a demon battle and then the island hopping swimming section.The game featured a vibrant art style and very bouncy happy music.  It was a very original game for the Commodore 64 and extremely popular due to its twisted plot and off the wall humour.  Where else would you see small cute creatures chainsawing each other apart!!!</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8671">Gobliiins</game><game id="22552">Gobliiins 4</game><game id="17583">Gobliins 2: The Prince Buffoon</game><game id="18367">Mayhem in Monsterland</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/10026/335414-large_name.jpg</image></root>