<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12476</id><name>Super Mario Strikers</name><description>OverviewWario doing a super strikeSuper Mario Strikers is a football (soccer) game starring Mario characters developed by Next Level Games and published byNintendo for the GameCube. Just like in other Mario sports games such as Mario Golf: Toadstool Tour and Mario Tennis the player can use items such as shells and bananas to attack the opponent. The team consists of five players, a captain, a goalkeeper and three defenders . Captains are able to do super strikes, which are more powerful versions of the normal shots and usually can't be stopped .Captains:MarioLuigiPeachDonkey KongWarioWaluigiDaisyYoshiSuper RobotSidekicks:ToadHammer Bros.BirdoKoopaGame modesGrudge Match - Standard single and multiplayer match, up to four playersCup Battles - Tournament mode, up to four playersSuper Cup Battles - A harder version of the normal cupStrikers 101 - Training ModeCustom Battle - Players can create their own tournamentStadiums:The PalacePipeline CentralThe UndergroundUnlockables:Konga Coliseum (Beat the Mushroom cup)Crater Field (Beat the Flower cup)Battle Dome (Beat the Star cup)Bowser Stadium (Beat the Bowser cup)ControlsB If you are on your side of the field it lobs it down field. If you press it and hold it on your opponents side of the field it makes a charge shot. If you do a charged shot with your team captain it gives an almost certain goal. If you make it, you get 2 points instead of 1A. simple, passJoystick: move around.R: run fasterStart: pauseItemsGreen Shell - Knocks down other players.Red Shell - Homes in on other players and knocks them down.Blue Shell - Freeze other playersSpiked Shell - Rebound off barriers and knocked down opponents.Banana Peel - Places down peels that overturn characters.Bob-omb - Explodes and sends characters flying.Chain-Chomp - Immobilizes all players on enemy team.Mushroom - Raises speed for a set time.Star - Become invincible for a set time.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="40">Soccer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17290">Sega Soccer Slam</game><game id="11496">Mega Man Soccer</game><game id="22201">Disney Sports Basketball</game><game id="15288">FIFA Street</game><game id="20846">Kidz Sports Basketball</game><game id="20913">Sports Party</game><game id="860">Virtua Striker 2002</game><game id="24889">Capcom Sports Club</game><game id="36150">FIFA Street</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2266540-box_sms.png</image></root>