<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12494</id><name>RoboCop Versus the Terminator</name><description>OverviewIn the near future, the worlds of RoboCop and The Terminator merge into a single reality. RoboCop is placed in charge with saving mankind by destroying the Skynet super computer and preventing a possible future where machines reign supreme. By traversing 10 levels of action, fighting against thugs and machines alike, all while utilizing a combination of pistols, laser guns, bazookas and even the deadly ED-209 Gatling gun., the player can destroy Skynet and save the world. The game was released for Sega Genesis, Super Nintendo, Sega Master System, Game Boy, and Game Gear. An NES version was developed but never officially released.Levels (Sega Genesis version)Level 1 - Trainer LevelLevel 2 - Streets of DetroitLevel 3 - Delta City under ConstructionLevel 4 - The Toxic FarmLevel 5 - OCP office ComplexLevel 6 - Terminator OutpostLevel 7 - Underground ComplexLevel 8 - Underground BunkerLevel 9 - The wall to SkynetLevel 10 - SkynetCheats (for the Sega Genesis version)If your version of the game does not have blood, press C, B, A, B, B, C, B, B, C, B, B,C, C, B, C, B, C, A, C, C, A, A, A, B, B, B, A, C, A at the title screen to enable it.To fall through the floor, pause the game and press A, B, C, C, C, B, A. When youunpause the game, you will be able to fall through the floor by holding down and pressingC.To get 54 lives, pause the game and press C, C, A, A, B, B, C, C, A, A, B, B. You'llhear an explosion, and end up in a secret level. If you complete this level, you willreceive 54 lives.If you pause the game and enter C, B, A, B, B, A, B, B, C, B, B, C, C, B, B, C, B, C, A,C, C, A, A, A, B, B, B, A, C, A, there will be new enemies to fight, such asendoskeletons and female terminators. Molotov cocktails and fire traps are now alsoincluded in the game.To jump higher and run faster, pause the game and enter A, B, C, C, B, A, C, B, A, C, B,A, A, A, C, A, C, B, C, A, C, A, C, A, B, C, B. You'll hear a sound effect confirmingyou've entered the code correctly. Once you unpause the game, you'll be able to runfaster and jump higher.To choose any weapon in the game, pause the game and press B, A, C, C, C, A, B, B, A, C,C, C, A, B. You'll hear a machine gun confirming you've entered the code correctly.Unpause the game and press and hold the d-pad down, whilst holding the A, B and Cbuttons down simultaneously. The weapons will display in turn at the top of the screen.Let go of the buttons once you see the weapon you would like to choose.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1503">Aliens Versus Predator 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3715/672010-rvstmg0f.jpg</image></root>