<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12536</id><name>The Adventures of Bayou Billy</name><description>OverviewThe Adventures of Bayou Billy is a platforming game with additional driving and  Zapper based shooting sections. It was developed and published by Konami, and is the English localized version of their Famicom game Mad City. The game play is primarily platforming and brawling, however stages 2 and 7 are shooting levels which can be played with the NES Zapper peripheral, and levels 4 and 5 are driving based. The Adventures of Bayou Billy is well known for being extremely difficult; it's similar in this regard to Battletoads.TriviaThe game features DPCM coded voices of Bayou Billy speaking at the beginning and end of the game, and of the main antagonist, Godfather Gordon, between stages.  The Japanese  version, Mad City, is much less dificult than the English language version.  Archie Comics published a comic book series based on the game, which further developed the characters from the game.  The theme and plot of the game are similar to the film Crocodile Dundee II. The Bayou Billy character art on the Japanese box even looked similar to Crocodile Dundee. Bayou Billy appeared on two episodes of the NES themed cartoon series Captain N: The Game Master. He appears in an episode titled "How's Bayou", where he is the main villain. Joking about the difficulty of the game, Bayou Billy was said to be the one game even Captain N was unable to finish, until he bought a Game Genie in season 4. A LCD handheld  version of the game was also released.  </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7322">Golgo 13: Top Secret Episode</game><game id="15143">Knights of the Round</game><game id="22205">The Lone Ranger</game><game id="4816">Double Dragon II: The Revenge</game><game id="21228">Battletoads</game><game id="9219">The Mafat Conspiracy</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2361120-nes_adventuresofbayoubilly.jpg</image></root>