<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12567</id><name>Warcraft III: Reign of Chaos</name><description>OverviewWarcraft III: Reign of Chaos combined RPG elements with the RTS genre, focusing on hero units that are supported by normal units. This created a new gameplay style for the RTS genre, which, prior to Warcraft III, was largely a purely macro-based gamestyle. This would be Blizzard Entertainment's first 3D game to be released. It had a unique visual style for its time and ran on a broad spectrum of computer setups. Its map editor allowed players to control virtually anything in the game allowing a near limitless amount of customization.Single PlayerThe four races of Warcraft III.The single player portion of the game is viewed through the eyes of the four unique races in the game, each telling part of their own story while still maintaining focus on the whole through four seperate campaigns. The single player campaigns set new standards for the depth RTS games can achieve by having missions and subquests that have yet to be matched in terms of depth and ingenuity. In most RTS games you have to build an army and take out different enemy encampments within alotted timeframes. Warcraft's missions were a mix between these old-school mission styles, and quests much like those you see in World of Warcraft. The game's story unfolds by the characters of the game through both in-game cutscenes and hollywood-level cinematics.The four campaigns and prologue are:Prologue: Exodus of the HordeHuman Campaign: The Scourge of LordaeronUndead Campaign: Path of the DamnedOrcish Campaign: The Invasion of KalimdorNight Elf Campaign: Eternity's EndStoryThe story in Warcraft III: Reign of Chaos is told through all four races in a progressive manner, in a similar way to how StarCraft was told. The order is human, undead, orc, and night elf. Prologue: Exodus of the Horde The young Thrall awakes fom a strange vision, directing him to the prophet Medivh. Medivh tells him to rally the orcs from Lordaeron and travel to Kalimdor, where they shall meet their destiny. He frees the orcs from the remaining internment camps, including Grom Hellscream. The Horde steals the human fleet from Southshore and sail off. Near the Maelstrom, they are forced to land on a small island to repair their ships. There they are joined by the Darkspear Trolls, led by Sen'jin, but are soon ambushed and captured by a group of murlocs worshiping a Naga Sea Witch. Thrall and his people need to escape from their underworld prison together with the trolls and flee from the island before it is destroyed by an erupting volcano. Human Campaign: The Scourge of LordaeronArthas Menethil, PaladinPrince Arthas, a paladin of the Silver Hand, The Captain and Jaina Proudmoore, Arthas' former lover and apprentice-ano.Archmage, are investigating a strange plague that is spreading across the lands of Lordaeron. To their horror, they find that the plague turns unsuspecting people into hideous Undead warriors, and must move to stop the undead's plans. After a string of hollow victories (many towns in the now Plaguelands being destroyed), Arthas decides that the best way to end the game was to destroy Mal'Ganis the (supposed) leader of the scourge. Mal'Ganis travels northward to the icy lands of Northrend, and Arthas follows him. There he aids an old friend, Muradin Bronzebeard, who tells him of a powerful weapon, a sword called Frostmourne. Arthas obtains Frostmourne, at the (supposed) cost of Muradin's life, and uses it to defeat Mal'Ganis. However, as a result, Frostmourne steals Arthas' soul and turns to ally the undead... Undead Campaign: Path of the DamnedArthas Menethil, Death KnightWith their new leader, the undead must move to complete their purpose in Lordaeron, which is to destroy the remnants of the Alliance and pave the way for a new invasion. In a series of quests, Arthas succeeds in reviving a former adversary, Kel'Thuzad, as a Lich, and the two successfully open an inter-dimensional portal for the true masters of the Scourge, the Burning Legion, to enter the realm of Azeroth.Orcish Campaign: The Invasion of KalimdorThrall, Grom and MannorothAfter escaping Human captivity and fleeing to the shores of Kalimdor, orcish warchief Thrall must lead his brethren to safety and ensure their survival in this strange and hostile land. Help comes from the Tauren, a nomadic group of Kalimdor natives, and their leader, Cairne Bloodhoof. Unfortunately, fellow orc Grom Hellscream falls under demonic corruption, and Thrall is forced to ally himself with Jaina Proudmore, now leader of the survivors of Lordearon. He also discovers (courtesy of an oracle) that his fate is to help repel the Burning Legion, and he and Jaina accomplish this goal, and also to save Hellscream. Afterwards, Grom insists upon battling Mannoroth, the demon who cast him into the corruption. Thrall and Grom succeed in vanquishing Mannoroth, but Grom is slain in the process.Night Elf Campaign: Eternity's EndTyrande Whisperwind and the brothers StormrageWith the coming of the undead and Burning Legion as well as the humans and orcs, Tyrande Whisperwind and her night elf Sentinels fight a desperate battle to save their beloved home of Kalimdor. She first reawakens her lover, Malfurion Stormrage, and then the Druids of the Talon and finally the Druids of the Claw. She also decides to free the great betrayer, Illidan Stormrage, and he is eventually instrumental in weakening the Legion. Finally, she and Furion join forces with Proudmoore and Thrall to delay the Legion's advance until a proper end can be arranged for their leader Archimonde (mirroring the final mission of Starcraft, in which the player commands a multi-racial force against a common foe).MultiplayerThe multiplayer aspects of Warcraft III were unlike any other for the time. With four unique races that all played completely different, a focus on microing, creeps, items, shops, and hero units. In addition to the new style of compeititve gameplay, Battle.net has be revamped to reward players with icons depending on the number of wins that player has obtained and levels to show how good that particular player is doing in that ladder season. This added a whole new level of addictiveness to an already fun game.Custom GamesThe most commonly played game types on Warcraft III online. Custom games generally have nothing to do with actual Warcraft, but are standalone games created by users with the map editor. The depth of some of these games has lead to constant rereleases and patches, or in the case of DOTA, it spawned multiple commercial releases. Due to the fact that anyone can go in their map editor, which comes on the disc, and create a map and host it online. There are hundreds of thousands of maps that have been played on the Warcraft III servers. When a player joins a lobby for a game or a map they have never played, they take time to download it. Those maps are stored in the Downloads folder in the Maps folder for Warcraft III. Once you download a map you will never have to load it again on the starting screen.Some of the more popular game types, which have spawned tons of remakes and copy cats:Sheep tagDOTAHero Wars (Which in itself is Dota inspired)Tower DefenseWintermaul (with hundreds of different offshoots: South Park Maul, Simpsons Maul, Techmaulogy, Dynasty Warriors Maul, etc.)Line Tower WarsHero Line Wars (a combination of Hero Wars and Line Tower Wars, Characters use heroes and summon enemies to other team's side to increase their income.)Vampire Hell (Standalone Sheep Tag variant)RiskMurder at the MansionEscape From Titanic/ Polar Escape (Maps where you control a character on a small maze like environment, you need to stay on the road or you die.)CreepsCreeps are the neutral enemy that every player in a competitive match must face and conquer before victory over their adversary. The creeps are design for players to kill so they obtain an advantage over the other player. For every creep killed the player will receive experience to level their hero, items for stats and ability bonues and gold for more items, troops and upgrades. Depending on the level of the creep will determine how the strength and amount of the gold, items, and experience you will obtain. Killing creeps isn't required to win a match but it does help to turn the tables on an enamy you may be tryin to mine more gold or harass a well defended base.HeroesThe basic strategy of all players focuses around their hero unit who can do a variety of tasks that regular units can not. The Hero unit can teleport to town if it is under attack (or needs to retreat), level and become more powerful, aid fellow units, or level armies of enemy units, it can use items and a player can only have 3 hero units at a time. All heroes have a max level of 10 on the Battle.net ladders and 4 skills, 3 of which have 3 levels, and one other spell known as their ultimate; players can also opt to ignore putting points into a skill and increase their heroes' base stats instead; spells/skills can only be upgraded at levels 3 and 5.Heroes and their skills/spells (note: hotkeys for spells are underlined) in Warcraft III are:HumansHeroKey Attributes/Role1st Skill Slot2nd Skill Slot3rd Skill SlotUltimateArchmageIntelligenceSupport HeroSummon Water ElementalSummons a ranged Water Elemental to fight by your side. Water Elementals increase in damage and hit points each level. Useful for creeping and scouting early. Can be dispelled.BlizzardRains down ice over designated area. Is channelled spell, as such, it can be interrupted by stuns. Can only hit up to 5 targets at a time. Damage increase per level. Can hit air units.Brilliance AuraIncreases mana regeneration. Passive.Mass TeleportTeleports you and 24 units to anywhere on the map you already discovered.Mountain KingStrengthMelee HeroStorm BoltSingle target attack that damages and temporarily stuns target. Great for focusing on enemy hero(es). Increase damage and stun time per level. Can hit organic air units as wellThunder ClapArea of Effect spell that slows movement and attack speed of units caught in its effect. Increases slow amount and damage per level. Excellent against fleeing units.BashPassive skill that does increase damage and stuns targets temporarily. Higher proc rate as you level it. Goes great with gloves of haste.AvatarAvatar makes the Mountain King's character size increase temporarily and he turns metallic. His attack strength is increased while under its effect, he can not be harmed by spells and his armor is increased.PaladinStrengthSupportive Melee HeroHoly LightHeals target friendly unit or damages target undead unit. Increases amount healed/damaged per level.Divine ShieldRenders the paladin invulnerable from attacks temporarily. Active spell time is increased per level.Devotion AuraIncreases all friendly units' armor stat so long as they are within range of the paladin. Passive.ResurrectionResurrection revives up to 6 fallen (user owned) units.OrcsHeroAttributes1st Skill Slot2nd Skill Slot3rd Skill SlotUltimateBlade MasterAgilitySolo hero killerWindwalkRenders the Blademaster invisible, increases movement speed and guarentees a critical strike on his first strike. Attacking reveals the Blademaster. Useful for rushing opponents and causing economic damage early game. Excellent for picking off fleeing units and highly effective at killing heroes. Movement speed and duration increase with each level.Mirror ImageCreates a harmless duplicate of the Blademaster. Useful for scouting or causing diversions.Critical StrikeCritical strike causes increased damage to units. At level 1 it deals 2x base damage, at level 2 it deals 3x base damage, and at level 3 it deals 4x base damage. It has a 15% chance to proc. Gloves of haste are perfect compliment to this skill.BladestormBlademaster begins spinning causing damage to all units and buildings caught in his flurry. He cannot be targeted by spells during this time. This is great for taking out armies if you can slow/stun units. Great for taking out weaker buildings such as food support buildings, which most players build near one another.Tauren ChieftainStrengthSupportive TankShock WaveDamages all units and buildings in a line. Effective against ranged units. Has a relatively short cooldown.War StompStuns all units caught in the stomp temporarily. This spell combined with the Chieftan's Endurance Aura can wreak havoc on unsuspecting armies. A good tactic is to send the Chieftan in alone to a group of ranged units to stomp and stun them, while melee units hold the line, the Chieftan is more than capable of taking out a group of ranged units on his own with War Stomp Endurance Aura (not to mention his huge amount of health.) Stun time increases per level.Endurance AuraIncreases Chieftan (and all units within range) attack rate and movement speed (which are also increased per level). Passive.ReincarnationLong and short of it: Extra life. If your Chieftan dies while Reincarnation is active he will respawn where he died with full health and mana and all items before he died.Far SeerIntelligenceSupport HeroFar SightAllows user to reveal any part of the map. Reveals invisible units. At higher levels it reveals gigantic portions of the map. Effective in team games for plotting and mounting an attack.Chain LightningDirect damage spell that bounces from target to target, weakening as it hits each subsequent target. Can hit air units. Hits more units each level as well as causing more damage each level.Feral SpiritSummons 2 spirit wolves. Great for rushing. Excellent support in battles to increase the Horde's melee supremecy. At level 3 they become invisible and are fantastic for invading an enemy's base and taking out their economy.EarthquakeCauses damage to buildings on designated area. Disorients units caught in the spell, causing them to move and attack extremely slow. Great for leveling enemy bases.Night ElvesHeroAttributes1st Skill Slot2nd Skill Slot3rd Skill SlotUltimateDemon HunterAgilitySolo hero killerMana BurnTurns enemy caster/hero's mana against them. Takes 50/100/150 mana from enemy (based on level of spell) and causes equal amount of damage to target unit and removes the same amount of mana. Great way to keep heroes in check.ImmolationCreates a firery ring around the Demon Hunter that causes damage to any units that come in range of him.EvasionCauses enemy attacks to miss the Demon Hunter occasionally. Increases evasion percentage per level.MetamorphosisCauses the Demon Hunter to transform into a Demon himself temporarily, giving him a range attack, increased health regeneration and chaos damage.Keeper of the GroveIntelligenceSupport CasterEntangling RootsCauses target unit to be immobilized. Causes damage over time. Great for picking off fleeing units, disabling late game units, and for focusing on enemy heroes.Thorns AuraEffects all friendly units within range. Any melee damage dealt to units under this effect causes damage to the attacker(s). Passive.Force of NatureSummons Treants to aid army. Can only be cast on trees. Can be used to breach through enemy's treeline to catch them off-guard and undefended.TranquilityChannelled spell that quickly heals all friendly units within range of the Keeper of the Grove.Priestess of the MoonAgilityRanged SupportScoutSummons an invulnerable owl that... well... scouts. Can reveal hidden enemies. Lasts longer each level.Searing ArrowsSearing Arrows can be autocast, which will make them be used every shot the Priestess uses. This will drain mana fast, however, it will increase the damage of her attacks substantially. Increases damage per level.Trueshot AuraIncreases range damage to all ranged units within range. Passive.StarfallCauses stars to fall from the sky and hit enemies and buildings for big damage. Is channelled and can be interrupted. Great base cleaner.UndeadHeroAttributes1st Skill Slot2nd Skill Slot3rd Skill SlotUltimateDeath KnightStrengthDeath CoilCan be used to heal friendly undead units, or damage any non-undead units. Works much like Paladin's Holy Light but in reverse.Death PactKills player owned unit and transfers health to Death Knight. Great against players whose tactic is largely based around focusing on your hero units.Unholy AuraIncreases health regeneration and movement speed of all units within range of the Death Knight. Passive.Animate DeadTemporarily revives any 6 dead units, player, friendly or enemy owned. Once timer expires, the units explode.Dread LordStrengthCarrion SwarmDamages units within a line.Vampiric AuraAny melee damage caused by units under this aura's effect will gain health back from their attacks. Passive.SleepCauses the targeted unit to fall asleep. Great for surrounding enemy units.InfernoSummons an Infernal from the sky. He comes in as a comet, causing damage and stunning units in the designated area. He then turns into a commandable, melee unit that has a weaker version of Demon Hunter's immolation, does chaos damage, has a high number of hit points, and is a temporary unit that expires upon his timer's completion.LichIntelligenceFrost NovaDirect damage attack with splash mixed in. Slows units temporarily. Increases damage and slow time per level.Frost ArmorAutocast. It shrouds units in frozen armor causing any melee attackers to move and attack slower. Increases armor of target.Dark RitualSacrafices friendly unit and converts its health into the Lich's mana. Effective for keeping those Novas coming.Death and DecayArea of Effect targeted spell that does 4% of units' base health as damage per second. Also affects buildings.Custom MapsFootmen WarsFootmen wars is a very popular custom map game that was created in Warcraft: 3 Reign of Chaos and has become even more popular with Warcraft 3: The Frozen Throne with more updated versions. Footmen wars is a game that puts 4 teams of three or in some versions 2 teams of six againt one another. The goal is to destroy the other oppoents base or command center before he/she destroyes yours. Every players gets 1 hero and Tier 1 footmen soldiers, as the game progresses players will recieve more exp and gold for stronger heros and troops. Depending on the version, the heroes and troops will differ but the main idea is still the same.Defense of The AncientsDefense of the Ancients in progress.Defense of the Ancients (or DotA) is a free downloadable custom game mode for Warcraft 3 and its expansion pack Warcraft 3: The Frozen Throne. Initially released in 2003, the goal of DotA is to destroy the enemy's heavily guarded base before they destroy yours. Each player controls one hero, while the other units are computer controlled. Waves of units will constantly assault the other team automatically. Defensive structures are along the lanes to the other team's base. Each hero is vastly different from the others, including varied abilities. As you kill the AI-controlled units you receive gold and experience to level up and learn new abilities. Gold is used to purchase other units, upgrades, and items to benefit your hero and team. Defense of the Ancients is Warcraft 3's most popular custom map and is played across the world. It has sparked many games directly inspired by the Defense of the Ancients mod, like Demigod and League of Legends.SoundtrackWarcraft III: Reign of Chaos features an original soundtrack composed by Glenn Stafford, Derek Duke, Jason Hayes, and Tracy Bush.Warcraft III SoundtrackTrack Listings:Arcane Echoes (Duke)Arrival at Kalimdor (Bush)Awakening (Bush)Blackrock  Roll (Stafford)Blight (Duke)Bloodlust (Duke)Carrion Waves (Duke)Cinematic Suite (Hayes)Doomhammer's Legacy (Bush)Frostmourne (Stafford)Lordaeron Fall (Stafford)Reign Of Chaos (Duke)Rise of the Ancients (Bush)Temporary Alliances (Bush)The Calm (Bush)System RequirementsWindows速 98/ME/2000/XP:400 MHz Pentium II or equivalent128 MB of RAM8 MB 3D video card (TNT, i810, Voodoo 3, Rage 128 equivalent or better) with DirectX速 8.1 support700 MB HD space4X CD-ROM driveMacintosh速 OS 9.0 or higher/ Mac OS X 10.1.3. or higher:400 MHz G3 processor128 MB of RAM16 MB ATI Technologies or nVidia chipset 3D video card700 MB HD space4X CD-ROM driveRecommended:600 MHz processor256 MB of RAM32 MB 3D video cardDirectX速 8.1 compatible sound cardMultiplayer:Low-latency, active Internet connection rated at 28.8 Kbps or faster. LAN play requires TCP/IP connection.</description><genres><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14440/1375153-warcraftiii.jpg</image></root>