<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12628</id><name>Double Switch</name><description>StoryEddie (  Corey Haim) is trapped in the basement of his own house. He got you in through the phone lines to trap  burglars, and to find a code to set him free. There are a few tenants living in the house, like a mobster that just got out of jail, a female wannabe reporter looking for a story, two young female students, a rock band, and a weird handyman that Eddie doesn't seem to like too much. What's their story, and why is Eddie really trapped in the basement?GameplayThe gameplay is basically the same as in  Night Trap, only this time it has evolved, so you don't need to endlessly switch rooms just to see if something is happening. Instead, on the left side of the screen you have a  heads up display that shows you a map of the house with all the rooms laid out. When someone breaks into a room, an alarm goes off, and the room on your HUD starts flashing. When a person enters a room, an icon appears. A green icon is a tenant, a yellow one is for unknowns, and red icons are bad guys.There are two traps in every room, each with a spring. Choose which trap you want to set off, tighten the spring, and once the person you want to trap steps on a certain mark on the floor, you'll hear a sound indicating that he or she is in place. Spring the trap and watch the bad guy go away. Be careful that you don't trap any of the tenants though, or Eddie will disconnect you.As the story progresses, and you do your job trapping bad guys, you will also need to find a code to get Eddie out of the basement. The code appears in different power boxes around the house, so pay attention when someone opens one up. Also, be extra careful that someone doesn't get their hands on the power box in the basement. If the power goes out, everyone is cut off, and it's  game over.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7427">Sewer Shark</game><game id="18648">Night Trap</game><game id="18020">Fahrenheit</game><game id="5705">Wirehead</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14206/1079173-ds.jpg</image></root>