<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12691</id><name>Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 2x</name><description>OverviewTony Hawk's Pro Skater 2x is a launch title for the Xbox - it's a director's cut version of Tony Hawk's Pro Skaters 2 that appear on the PlayStation, Dreamcast, and Nintendo 64. The game features more levels, better graphics, and an improved version of the create-a-skater mode.GameplayGrinding it up in France.The game features several single player modes and multi-player modes, single-player has a career mode, single session, park editor, create a skater, and free skate. The career has the player picking a skater and a level to complete various goals for cash. Money in the game is use to purchase stats, skateboard decks, and more tricks. Free Skate is mainly viewed as a practice mode, which means you can't fail because there is no time limit. Single Session works like the career mode only there are no goals, just the time limit. Multiplayer has modes that can go up to four or eight (via system link) players.Other single player modes contains park editor and create a skater. In the Park Editor mode, the player can create his or her very own skate park - using various tools like quarter pipes, rails, stair cases, etc. In create-a-skater, the player can create a skater by customizing the skater's clothing, hair style, and tricks. New to this version of Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 2, is the ability to create a female skater.Multi-player modes in the game consist of regular "trick attack" session - two to eight players can compete to see who can get the high score in a set time limit. "Graffiti mode" is were the player can take over certain parts of a level by tricking off them - the objective is to take over as much of the environment before the time runs out. Other players can take over their opponents' controlled areas by performing higher scores. "Tag mode" is what the title says - the player who is "it" has to make contact with another opponent in the game. "HORSE" is were the player performs a trick and his or her opponent has to follow what the player has done with a better trick. If the opponent fails to do so, he or she will get a letter - if a player gets enough letters to spell out "HORSE," the player will lose the game. The game also contains a free skate mode for the multi-player for two to eight players can use to skate around a level as much as they want.StatsHang time!Stats are purchase with cash that is earned from the career mode. Stats increase a skater's performances. There are ten stats for each skater.Air - Affects the boost you get when you air on a quarter pipe.Hang Time - Affects the length of time you stay in the air.Ollie - Affects your ground jump height.Speed - Affects your flat ground speed.Spin - Affects the speed at which your character rotates. Max it out if you want to spin 720s or 900s.Landing - Affects how easy it is for you to nail big drops.Switch - Determines how well you skate when you are skating switch. When maxed out to ten, the skater should be equally skilled regular and switch.Rail Balance - Affects your ability to balance on rails.Lip Balance - Balance for lip tricks. The higher the stat, the longer you can tweak lip tricks and the more points you can score.Manual Balance - The higher the value, the longer you will be able to balance manuals.Playable CharactersTony HawkBob BurnqustSteve CaballeroKareem CampbellRune GlifbergEric KostonBucky LasekRodney MullenChad MuskaAndrew ReynoldsGeoff RowleyElissa SteamerJamie ThomasOfficer Dick (Unlockable)Spider Man (Unlockable)LevelsThe game features twenty-four levels, the most out of any Tony Hawk game. All the levels from the original Tony Hawk game are included with five new levels added as well. The remake, like the original, have special cases where some of the levels (like Marseille) have a hidden section unlocked through specific things - like breaking a supporting wooden stick holding up a tree by skating on it will make the tree fall down and open up a hidden skatebowl downstairs.THPS2 LevelsThe Hanger Mullet Falls MTSchool II Southern CaliforniaMarseille FranceNY City New YorkVenice Beach CaliforniaSkatestreet VenturaPhiladelphia PennsylvaniaThe Bullring MexicoChopper Drop HawaliSkate HeavenTHPS LevelsWarehouse Woodland Hills CASchool Miami FLMall New YorkSkate Park ChicagoDowntown MinneapolisDownhill Jam Phoenix AZBurnside Portland ORStreets San FranciscoRoswell New MexicoTHPS2X LevelsOne of the five new levels in the game.Club LondonConstruction Site Dallas TXSkate Park Tampa FLSubway New YorkSky Lines Detroit MISoundtrackBlood Brothers - Papa RoachBring The Noise - AnthraxGuerilla Radio - Rage Against The MachinePin The Tail On The Donkey - Naughty By NatureYou - Bad ReligionWhen Worlds Collide - Powerman 5000No Cigar - MillencolinB-Boy Document 99 - The High And MIghtyCyclone - Dub PistolsMay 16 - LagwagonSubculture - Styles Of BeyondHeavy Metal Winner - ConsumedEvil Eye - Fu ManchuOut With The Old - Alley LifeFive Lessons Learned - Swingin' UttersCity Stars - Born Allah</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="23">Skateboarding</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2570">Aggressive Inline</game><game id="21758">ESPN X-Games Skateboarding</game><game id="21495">Skate It</game><game id="9279">Kelly Slater's Pro Surfer</game><game id="30195">Shaun White Skateboarding</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2106407-box_thps2x.png</image></root>