<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12780</id><name>Darkwatch</name><description>Overview Darkwatch is a horror and western-themed first person  shooter developed by         High Moon  Studios and published by                  Capcom. Story The  player takes on the role of         Jericho Cross, a Wild West outlaw who is  turned into a vampire by the evil Lazarus. Through the course of the  game, Jericho and his friend and partner           Cassidy, who was killed early  on but doles out ghostly advice, join forces with the Darkwatch vampire hunting organization and  attempt to take down Lazarus. Jericho is also aided by his new partner, the Native American Darkwatch agent     Tala.Gameplay  Darkwatch steampunk combat vehicle     The gameplay is very fast-paced, with enemies often coming from numerous directions at an alarming rate. Many of the game's gothic-styled weapons have blades of some sort attached to the butt, which means Jericho is able to mutilate enemies and leads to some fairly extreme violence against the undead hordes.   On top of this, the game contains some half-baked moral decisions that allow the player to gain points towards up to eight total Good and Evil abilities, such as Silver Bullet, which increases weapons' firepower, or Blood Frenzy, which deals out more damage from melee attacks.    There are also some "rail shooter" horseback sections and  vehicle-driving section during the course of the game. Playboy  Playboy picture of Tala (censored)     Both            Cassidy and             Tala were used in  Playboy's pictorial featuring nude female videogame characters. Tala was first used in the October 2004 spread while both Cassidy and Tala were used in the October 2005 issue.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15476">Vampire Hunter D</game><game id="9085">Vampire Rain</game><game id="7337">Van Helsing</game><game id="20905">Damnation</game><game id="2600">Halo: Combat Evolved</game><game id="22150">Gun: Showdown</game><game id="25249">Red Dead Redemption</game><game id="22361">Red Steel 2</game><game id="9201">The Darkness</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/30036/1336054-darkwatchgb.jpg</image></root>