<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12805</id><name>Initial D: Special Stage</name><description>OverviewInitial D: Street Stage is a port of Initial D Arcade Stage 2 with new additions exclusive to the console version. These exclusives include the addition of five new tracks, new background music and a Story mode where you are able reenact races and events from the Initial D manga. The game is controlled with the D-Pad or analog stick, though it also supposedly works with with Logitech steering wheels. There have been complaints about the transmission stick not working in game however. GameplayRaces involve one on one races against rivals through mountain passes that the player selects. As the tracks become more difficult, so do the rivals. Skillful use of gear shifting and braking techniques allow cars to drift around corners. The game's physics are arcade like, but they do involve some realism as well. Cars can oversteer and understeer depending on the car type. ModesArcadeJust like in the arcades, your goal is to defeat all the Initial D characters in the many different tracks in the game. As you win (or lose) battles, you gain points in which to spend vs. Keisuke on upgrading your car that you choose or to personalize it. StoryTake control of Takumi Fujiwara as he rises to fame from his first race with Keisuke Takahashi on Akina to the climatic mountain battle against Tachi on Happogahara. All the races are based on the manga events, so those that watch the anime may not remember specific events exclusive the manga. The story is told through manga panels as well as illustrations where the characters' mouths move with their respective voice acting. Majority of the unlockable features and items in the game can be unlocked by playing through this mode. Unlockable range from new background music to car explanations in the car showcase mode.Manga CutsceneTime TrialCars that have been saved in Arcade mode can be used here. When the player completes a time trial, they are able to earn points depending on how fast they were.Car ShowcaseThe car showcase allows players to view a replay of a selected car in action as well as an explanation of the car from Iketani.CarsCars are divided up into three different types of drivetrain styles:MR - Mid Rear DriveFR - Rear Wheel Drive4WD - Four Wheel DriveFF - Front Wheel DriveMR and FR cars tend to be driftier than the other counterparts. 4WD cars tend to have superior traction in any weather condition, but tend to understeer. These are the cars that are present in this version of Initial D as well as their drivetrain type:Toyota:Trueno GT-APEX (AE-86) FRLevin GT-APEX (AE-86) FRLevin SR (AE-85) FRMR2 G-Limited (SW-20) MRMR-S S Edition (ZZW30) MRAltezza RS200 (AKA: Lexus IS) (SXE10) FRCelica GT-4 (ST205) 4WDNissanSkyline GTR V-Spec II (BNR32)  4WDSkyline GTR V-Spec II (BNR34)  4WDSkyline GT 25 Turbo (ER34) FRSilvia K's (S14) FRSilvia Q's (S14) FRSilvia K's Aero (S14) FRSilvia Spec-R (S15) FR180SX Type X (RPS13) FRSileighty (RPS13) FRMitsubishiLancer GSR Evolution III (CE9A)  4WDLancer RS Evolution IV (CN9A)  4WDLancer GSR Evolution VII (CT9A)  4WDHondaCivic SIR II (EG6) FFCivic Type R (EK9) FFIntegra Type R (DC2) FFS2000 (AP1) FFMazdaRX7 Infiniti III (FC3S) FRRX-7 Type R (FD3S) FRRX-7 Spirit R Type A (FD3S) FRRoadster S Special (NA6C) FRRoadster RS (AKA: Miata MX-5) (NB8C) FRSubaruImpreza WRX Type R STi Version V (GC8V)  4WDImpreza WRX-STi Version VI (GC8)  4WDImpreza WRX-STi (GDB)  4WDSuzukiCappuccino (EA11R) FRTracksAll of these tracks are unlocked from the start.Original TracksMyogiUsuiAkagiAkinaHappogaharaIrohazakaConsole Exclusive TracksShin Myogi (This is later featured on Initial D: Arcade Stage 4)Shin Usui Shomaru (This is later featured on Initial D: Arcade Stage 3)MomijiEnnaMusic ListOut of all the home versions of Initial D, Initial D Special Stage has the most background music choices. Most of them, however are not exclusive as many of them are eventually used in the future versions of this game.Space BoyNight of FireDon't Stop the MusicLove is in DangerKilling My LoveRunning in the 90'sGrand PrixBeat of the Rising SunHeartbeatRock Me to the TopStation to StationSpeedy Speed BoyNo One Sleeps in TokyoRemember MeBack on the RocksDon't Stand So CloseWhite LightSave MeBurning DesireGet Me PowerMikadoCrazy for LoveStay100Don't You (Forget About My Love)West End GuyCrazy For Your LoveI Need Your LoveBig in JapanCrazy NightExpress LoveArcade ModeThese are the characters you face in Arcade Mode as well as the cars they drive:MyogiItsuki Takeuichi - Levin SR (AE-85)Takumi Fujiwara - Levin SR (AE-85)Shingo Shoji - Civic SIR II (EG6)Takeshi Nakazato - Skyline GTR V-Spec II (BNR32)  UsuiTwo Guys from Tokyo - Silvia Spec-R (S15)Nobuhiko Akiyama - Altezza RS200 (AKA: Lexus IS) (SXE10)Mako Sato and Sayuki - Sileighty (RPS13)Sakamoto - Cappuccino (EA11R)AkagiKyoko Iwase - RX-7 Type R (FD3S)Kenta Nakamura - Silvia Q's (S14)Keisuke Takahashi - RX-7 Type R (FD3S)Ryosuke Takahashi - RX7 Infiniti III (FC3S)AkinaKenji - 180SX Type X (RPS13)Iketani Kouichiro - Silvia K's (S13)Wataru Akiyama - Levin GT-APEX (AE-86)Takumi Fujiwara - Trueno GT-APEX (AE-86)HappogaharaToru Suetsugu - Roadster RS (NB8C)Daiki Ninomiya - Civic Type R (EK9)Smiley Sakai - Integra Type R (DC2)Tomoyuki Tachi - Civic Type R (EK9)IrohazakaSeiji Iwaki - Lancer GSR Evolution III (CE9A)Kyouichi Sudou - Lancer RS Evolution IV (CN9A)Kai Kogashiwa - MR2 G-Limited (SW-20)Keisuke Takahashi - RX-7 Type R (FD3S)Takumi Fujiwara - Trueno GT-APEX (AE-86)Shin MyogiShingo Shoji - Civic SIR II (EG6) Takeshi Nakazato - Skyline GTR V-Spec II (BNR32)  Shin UsuiMako Sato and Sayuki - Sileighty (RPS13)ShomaruWataru Akiyama - Levin GT-APEX (AE-86)MomijiToru Suetsugu - Roadster RS (NB8C)Atsurou Kawai - Skyline GT 25 Turbo (ER34)EnnaDaiki Ninomiya - Civic Type R (EK9)Smiley Sakai - Integra Type R (DC2)AkinaBunta Fujiwara - Impreza WRX Type R STi Version V (GC8V)</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14975">Import Tuner Challenge</game><game id="1101">Ridge Racer 7</game><game id="21689">Wangan Midnight</game><game id="26956">Wangan Midnight Maximum Tune</game><game id="26958">Wangan Midnight Maximum Tune 3</game><game id="26957">Wangan Midnight Maximum Tune 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/10468/610837-idspecials.jpg</image></root>