<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12814</id><name>Glider: Collect'n Kill</name><description>StoryAllianceIn the years of the beginning discovery of space by man, when state and private organisations fought for the dominating position, one came to the conclusion that an amalgamation of man, the new federates and the freed species would be necessary. The smartest heads came together and made the foundation stone, the foundation manifest of the Alliance: the Alliance is the main anchor of all interstellar incidents. Luckily, the Alliance’s influence has been expanded on the global administrations, so meanwhile an almost frictionless flow between the members of the growing family of the Allience became possible. Victory for the Alliance, by the Alliance!OGLTo offer the possibility of fair, athletic competitions to the different planets of the Alliance, in the year 2259 the Official Glider League was founded. We wish you, a new member of the proud round of the league’s pilotes, good luck, courage and bravery. Victory for the Alliance, by the Alliance! AvatarsJohn 'Painkiller' HarveyJohn Harvey was born in the mining colony on alpha 246, where he used to live until he went 15. Thereafter he served honestly for the troops of the Alliance for 21 years, 14 of them in a deadly-flight-squadron, where he received his nickname. He left the army because of personal reasons and now is an OGL-pilot for rising up for his honour in the name of the Alliance!Gloria 'Black Widow' JamesonGloria Jameson was born on earth, and lived here for 17 years.. she learned the basics of aviation on her grandfather’s farm, a quondam combat pilot. With 18 she applied for a job at the OGL for the first time, with 20 she was taken over after all. Since then she has improved to a great pilot and has no handicap with her male colleagues, therefore her nickname. She fights for her grandfather’s memory in the name of the Alliance!Jin 'Freaky' JinnzJin jinzz home planet is gamma 315. Because his species was liberated successfully by the Alliance shortly before jins birth, as one of his quadrants best flight-learners he had the great chance to choose the way of an OGL-pilot instead of the military. He flies for his family in the name of the Alliance!ALF 'Steelbite' #109ALF-artificial life form # 109. the 109th specimen of its production series has been modified to check this androids independent airworthiness. That experiment turned out so positive, that one decided to apply it to the OGL as an ambassador for the Alliances technical improvement. ALF#109 is on the way in the name of the Alliance! Volt 'Vultor' Joe'Vultor' - substantia cornutus, his real name is inexpressible for humans - has been worker in a security camp on Gamma 7D quite recently. Now, as a refined member of his meanwhile freed race he took the chance to become an ambitious pilot of the Glider League. He flies for the continuity of peace and in the name of the alliance!</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/30196/1822292-glider.jpg</image></root>