<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12842</id><name>Disney's Toy Story</name><description>Plot    Use your whip to stun enemies It's Andy's birthday and he recieves a gift in the form of Buzz Lightyear, and Andy's other toys get jealous. Woody the cowboy has long been Andy's favorite toy, and Woody fears he is being replaced by Buzz. This pushes Woody get rid of Buzz by knocking him out a window. This makes the conflict between Woody and Buzz all the worse. Eventually the two a stranded far away from home, and they need to work together to get back to Andy. They will fight many through many different situations and obstacles before getting home, and this journey makes them friends.  Gameplay   Plays very much like Outrun Toy Story is largly a side scrolling platformer with the occassional gameplay twist. You control Woody as travel through many different scenes and environments from the movie. Woody can run, jump, and use his pull string as a whip. The pull string has a variety of uses, you will use it for attacking enemies and as a grappling hook. Levels either have you traveling from point A to point B or beating an objective to open the exit. The objectives may include tasks such as cleaning up the toys in Andy's room. Another type of level that you will play twice are vehicular stages. You will ride on top of an R/C car trying to make it to the goal as fas as possible. These R/C levels will play from a top down, side scrolling, or behind the back perspective depending where you are in a level. When the perspective is behind that back it plays similarly to Outrun There are a few other levels such as a level where you search through a maze in a first person perspective. Controls: Controls will very level to level because of variety of gameplay typesA: WhipB: JumpX: WhipY: JumpStart: Skip/Pause Hints  Cheats:To change the amount of lives you start with, go into Options and push the down button. This allows you to see and change how many lives you start with.  Max Coins Inside The Claw - Genesis Version.At the start of the game, enter A,B,Right,A,C,A,Down,A,B,Right,A at the start screen. When you have to put all the aliens back into the bin, in the level inside the claw, press Start to pause, Then A. Partial Invincibility   - Genesis Version.To avoid being hurt by airplanes, trains, and other enemies, simply keep hitting B as the enemy hits you. This code even works Buzz's laser. However, it does not save you from time limits and falling. Invincibility   - Genesis Version.Make your way to the second stage, then put all toys away and get 7 stars. Finally, jump into the toybox and press Down for 7 seconds. Level Skip   - Genesis Version.At the "Press Start" screen, press A,B,Right,A,C,A,Down,A,B,Right,A quickly. If you have done this correctly you should hear a laugh. Begin a game on the normal difficulty, but whenever you want to skip a level, press Start,A.  Genesis Level Passwords  1- 312 41 2- 34152 3- 34255 4- 51324   SNES Level Passwords Level 2- 251324 Level 3- 421553 Level 4- 343435 Level 5- 151423 </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="8">Educational</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12842">Disney's Toy Story</game><game id="21476">Disney/Pixar Toy Story 2: Operation Rescue Woody</game><game id="9621">Disney/Pixar Toy Story Racer</game><game id="26805">Toy Story Mania!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8272/1124915-586557_46808_front.jpg</image></root>