<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12847</id><name>Mario Tennis: Power Tour</name><description>Mario Tennis: Power Tour (Mario Power Tennis in PAL regions) is an arcade tennis game for the Game Boy Advance. It is a sequel to the Game Boy Color version of Mario Tennis, and like its predicessor, and unlike it's home console counterparts, features an RPG-like story mode, in which players take control of a boy or girl enrolled in a tennis academy.PlotThe main character, Clay or Ace, dependent on the selected gender (or Max or Tina in PAL regions) wakes up in unfamiliar surroundings. After a visit from their counterpart of the opposite gender, he/she realizes they have recently enrolled at the Royal Tennis Academy. They soon learn that recently, the six academy champions have been beaten by a team of masked tennis players, and thus the masked players are the new champions. Clay and Ace set out to rise the ranks of the tennis academy to enter the Island Open to discover the identities of the masked players.After winning the Island Open, Clay and Ace are still in the dark about the masked players. However, the next day they are approached by one of them, and it is revealed that the masked players are Mario and several of Mario's Mushroom Kingdom friends. Clay and Ace are then invited to The Mushroom Kingdom to take part in another tournament, the Peach Tournament. After winning this, they return to the Academy, and are the hero's of the Academy.CharactersThere are many playable characters in the game, including characters from the Mario Universe, the main characters in the Story Mode, and many other characters from the Story Mode.Main CharactersClay (Max in PAL regions)Ace (Tina in PAL regions)Mario CharactersMarioLuigiPrincess PeachDonkey KongWaluigiBowserTennis Academy CharactersSophiaMegMasonChadSashaSylviaChrisKyleLindaShawnGarryJetKyokoMickiRoyEmiPaulaWhiskerToriElroyFlitSkipperBarbSassChasMelDweezilMinzWillySheri</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="25">Tennis</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20578">Sega Superstars Tennis</game><game id="3038">Tennis Critters</game><game id="31796">Hot Shots Tennis: Get a Grip</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2160630-box_mtpt.png</image></root>