<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12863</id><name>Postal 2</name><description>Postal 2 was the PC (and later, Mac) follow up to Running With Scissors' title Postal. Due to the violent and offensive nature of the game it was very much a dividing title for gamers with a love or hate reaction and little room between.PlotPeeing on people can cause them to vomit - An example of the "low" humor in Postal 2The basic premise is to get through the game completing a daily list of mundane tasks along the lines of picking up your paycheck from work, where you subsequently get fired and berated by your boss (Running With Scissors founder Vince Desi), then trying to cash the check at the local bank where masked men storm in with guns preventing you from getting your money.Each day grants you new tasks, and the day ends when you both complete all tasks and return home.Monday: Pick up Check, Cash Paycheck, and Get Milk.Tuesday: Return Book, Get Garry's Autograph, Confess Sins, and Get Signatures.Wednesday: Piss on Dad, Get Laundry, Get Xmas Tree, and Vote.Thursday: Get Napalm, Pay Ticket, Get Steaks, and Get Krotchy.Friday: Go to the Clinic, Get Alternator, Pick up Package, and Uncle Dave's Birthday. The game features many aspects which were seemingly included simply to be offensive; Very coarse language is used throughout the game, the game features many stereotypes including gay rapist southerners, idiotic police officers and suicide bomber Afghans, constant references to puerile jokes concerning bodily fluids and solids, the ability to urinate on NPCs and everything else, the ability to upgrade urine to special flammable urine, the WMD biological weapon retrieved from the Tora Bora level and frequent reference to narcotics, especially the use of a "crack pipe" as an in-game stimulant.It is possible to get through the game without killing anyone and the game itself boast that it is "Only as violent as you are". The developers have used this mantra to defend the game from critics. However, it's been pointed out that doing this is incredibly hard and not very rewarding.Widely panned by critics and gamers alike, as well as being banned in many countries, it has remained a niche game with a fairly hard-core cult following. Whether the game is enjoyable or not comes down primarily to the players appreciation for over the top crude humor.The game takes place in Paradise, Arizona which is base on the actual town of Bisbee, Arizona.TechnologyOne of the earlier games based on Unreal Engine 2 and making use of Karma rag-doll physics, the game could support up to 50 on screen AI NPC's who were intended to provoke you and occasionally set off on their own rampages whereupon the local police would have slightly more interest in them than your potentially law breaking activities.When the game shipped it was crippled by frequent loading times of up to 90 seconds which many reviewers found unacceptably long. This problem was patched soon after the release, although loading times were still a problem thanks to the game’s use of a simulated "sandbox" world. Just as Grand Theft Auto III loaded each of its three islands individually so too did Postal 2 with its maps; however, the game’s town was made up of many small levels ‘stitched together’ with load times to simulate one constant area. This led to loading areas often being right next to one another and at certain times a player may get out of one loading area just to step into another to get where they are going.Expansion PacksTwo expansion packs have been released for Postal 2: Share the Pain, which added a rudimentary online multiplayer mode consisting of deathmatch and variants of the capture the flag and last man standing game rules, and Apocalypse Weekend, a single player addition which gives the player new maps to explore and weapons with which to destroy things.MoviePostal the MovieThe film adaptation of Postal was released in May 2008 and is directed by legendary auteur and long-time video-game-to-film visionary, Uwe Boll. It currently holds a score of 22/100 on metacritic.com and 3.8/10 on imdb.com.PC System RequirementsMinimum:OS:Windows XP/Vista/7Processor:Pentium 3 1133MHz or AMD Athlon 733MHz ProcessorMemory:128 MB RAMGraphics:32MB GeForce 2 or Radeon Video CardDirectX®:8.0Hard Drive:1200 MB HD spaceOther Requirements:Broadband Internet connectionRecommended:OS:Windows XP/Vista/7Processor:1.2GHzMemory:384 MB RAMGraphics:64MB GeForce 3 or Radeon 8500 Video CardDirectX®:8.0Hard Drive:1200 MB HD spaceOther Requirements:Broadband Internet connection</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4745">Soldier of Fortune II: Double Helix</game><game id="6108">Manhunt</game><game id="17036">Grand Theft Auto: Vice City</game><game id="20457">Grand Theft Auto IV</game><game id="6731">Grand Theft Auto: Liberty City Stories</game><game id="10264">Grand Theft Auto: Vice City Stories</game><game id="3018">Meat Puppet</game><game id="44063">Jazzpunk</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/386/221246-front_cover.jpg</image></root>