<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12906</id><name>Superhero League of Hoboken</name><description>SummarySuperhero League of Hoboken is set in a post-apocalyptic United States, where freelance superhero leagues have formed to inspire hope, combat evil, and give superheroes a place to hang out on Friday nights. The game is very similar in structure to a console RPG such as Dragon Quest, with turn based random encounters against groups of enemies, top-down exploration, and inventory based puzzles. Its humor is largely based around the ridiculous nature of the characters' superpowers, such as the ability to create organizational charts, or to see inside pizza boxes without opening them. Enemies consist of mutated humans, animals, machines, and objects, ranging from bloodthirsty packs of wild lawyers, to sentient Tupperware.Character ListThe following are some of the playable characters in the game, along with a brief description of their abilities:The Crimson Tape: Able to create organizational charts at incredible speedsThe Iron Tummy: Can eat spicy foods without distressRobomop: Able to clean any messMademoiselle Pepperoni: She can see the contents of a pizza box without opening the lidKing Midas: His Midas Touch can turn anything he touches into a mufflerPrincess Glovebox: Able to successfully re-fold road mapsTreader Man: Is really good at treading waterTropical Oil Man: Can raise an opponent's cholesterol</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14917">Spellcasting 101: Sorcerers get all the Girls</game><game id="7509">Spellcasting 201: The Sorcerer's Appliance</game><game id="221">Spellcasting 301: Spring Break</game><game id="11797">The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy</game><game id="15067">Eric the Unready</game><game id="10332">The Adventures of Fatman: Toxic Revenge</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/13/136461/2434021-hobokenbox.jpg</image></root>