<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12914</id><name>Flicky</name><description>OverviewFlicky is a action platformer developed by Sega. The title was first released for arcade in 1984 and Sega Genesis in 1991.The game has been re released In the Sonic Mega Collection for the GameCube (2002), the Sonic Mega Collection Plus for th e Xbox and the PlayStation 2 (2005), Sega Genesis Collection for PSP and PlayStation 2 (2006) and Sonic's Ultimate Genesis Collection for Xbox 360 and Playstation 3 (2009).GameplayThe player controls a bird named Flicky and the object of the game is to guide your chicks to safety whilst avoiding a cat (Tiger) and a lizard (Iggy). You can throw certain objects at Tiger and Iggy to kill them. There are 48 proper levels in the game and they are broken up with a mini-game in which Flicky must catch her chicks in a net as they are flung in the air by Tiger. Each main level is wrap around meaning if you go to far you'll end up on the opposite end, however unlike Pac Man the screen is scrolling giving the impression that the space each level takes place in is infinite.TriviaFlickies are a species of bird that have appeared in a number of Sonic games most notably Sonic 3D Blast and Tails Adventure .After you finish the 48 levels the game it is possible to replay the game at a higher difficulty setting.The game was designed by Yoji Shii before he went on to found Artoon.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11874">Ghostbusters</game><game id="6782">Sonic 3D Blast</game><game id="22900">Mort the Chicken</game><game id="29027">Arkedo Series - 01 JUMP!</game><game id="16859">Mappy</game><game id="19573">Fairy</game><game id="1026">Funky Mouse</game><game id="21456">Super Rub 'a' Dub</game><game id="10038">From the Legend of Balubalouk: Aigiina no Yogen</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2370563-genesis_flicky_ca_cropped.jpg</image></root>