<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12954</id><name>Batman: Dark Tomorrow</name><description>OverviewBatman takes on a group of thugs.Batman: Dark Tomorrow is a 3D action-adventure game developed by HotGen and published by Kemco for the Xbox (on March 18, 2003) and GameCube (on March 25, 2003). Unlike most games in the Batman franchise (prior to LEGO Batman: The Videogame), which are based on adaptations of the caped crusader in movies and animated TV shows, Batman: Dark Tomorrow is solely based on the franchise's source material (the various comic book series, specifically those in the "Modern Age" of comic books).The plot of the game (written by veteran comic book writer Scott Peterson and famed Final Fantasy writer Kenji Terada) involves Batman (with assistance from Oracle) breaking up a turf war between Scarface (with The Ventriloquist) and Black Mask, rescuing Commissioner James Gordon (who was kidnapped by The Joker) from the overrun Arkham Asylum (forcing Batman to fight The Ratcatcher, Killer Croc, Poison Ivy, Mr. Freeze, and Mr. Zsasz), and stopping Ra's al Ghul from world domination.GameplayThe gameplay is a cross between third-person, first-person, and fixed camera angle (much like Resident Evil). Despite being a stealthy Dark Knight who relies on his shadow and sneaky approach, the game encourages the player to run towards the enemies and battle them without any tactics whatsoever. Every time Batman defeats an enemy, he has to handcuff each thug or they will wake up and continue fighting. There are also hidden documents and discs scattered throughout the game that consist of extra intel and unlockable items.Bat WeaponsBatcuffs: The most important item in Batman's arsenal. Since Batman doesn't kill, he uses it to handcuff his opponents.Fingerlight: A small torchlight to illuminate dark places.Nightvision: Enables Batman to see in poorly lit or cramped areas. It's also useful to reveal hidden laser beams and other traps.Universal Tool: A special lock-picking device that opens some locked doors encountered in the game.Batgrapple: A grappling hook.Batarang: Batman's signature throwing device to knock enemies down and inanimate, non-living objects (such as an explosive barrel or a switch).Bat Cable: A strong cable to jump from rooftop to rooftop.Smoke Capsule: Capsules that release a cloud of diluted nerve gas to obscure vision and to knock an enemy unconscious.Medical Kit: A healing item.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16327">Justice League Heroes</game><game id="8423">Superman: Shadow of Apokolips</game><game id="30399">Spider-Man: Shattered Dimensions</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2116195-box_batmandt.png</image></root>