<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13052</id><name>Phraze Daze: Famous Quotes Word Game</name><description>Overview Phaze Daze was developed by LatticeWorks Software and was released on 08 November, 2004. The game is shareware and costs $19.95. The game is only available from third party download websites, because LatticeWork Software's site, "www.latticeworksw.com", is an empty page.Gameplay In Phraze Daze players must rearrange a set of scrambled letters to spell a famous quote. The only clues each puzzle gives are appropriate spacing and punctuation and the name of the quoted person. Also, the letters in the letter bank are vertically aligned with the spaces they belong to. There are three difficulty settings: Novice (quotes with 2-3 lines), Mage (quotes with 4-5 lines) and Wizard (quotes with 6-7 lines).    A game of Phraze Daze.   There is also only one game mode, so no variations such as a       time limit or a versus game can be made. However, the game does allow players to add their own quotes to the game and to create "phrase packs" containing up to 50 player made quotes per level, which can be played and shared. The game does not  include any online support or software, however, for sharing these.    The game does not include any in-game hints or even solutions to puzzles players cannot complete. The game description points to "www.dexterity.com" for help and solutions, but this website redirects users to the developer's, unrelated, website. The  game comes with three different themes to change the appearance of the program.  RequirementsWindows XP, 2000, 98, Me, NT   Credits  Steve Pavlina - Developer/CEO LatticeWork Software Cyber Theme game board - Mark Stupak </description><genres><genre id="14">Trivia/Board Game</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16265">Jumble: That Scrambled Word Game</game><game id="26151">Jumble Madness</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/86090/1306176-phrazelogo.jpg</image></root>