<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13105</id><name>Baroque</name><description>OverviewBaroque is a roguelike style role playing game release for the Sega Saturn, Playstation 2, and Nintendo Wii video game systems. Unlike other roguelike titles, Baroque is played in full 3D, and the players move in real time. Traditional roguelikes had turn based movement. In Baroque, dying aids in pushing forward the story. When the player dies, they can choose to restart the game, uncovering new pieces on the plot. Unfortunately, the player's entire inventory is also lost, and they must begin at level 1. Some see this as tedious, but it is a traditional feature of modern roguelike games, such as Breath of Fire: Dragon Quarter. One other aspect of roguelikes present in Baroque are the randomly generated dungeons. Each floor of Neuro Tower will be new upon re-entry.The ArchangelThe main protagonist of the game, whom the player controls, is a mute amnesiac.The game has one primary location, Neuro tower, which the player must ascend to advance in the game. Inside neuro tower, the player can find an assortment of items. However, as is standard in roguelike titles, if the player dies, all within their inventory is lost. The only chance the player has to hold parts of their inventory are consciousness orbs, which can be used to store up to five items outside of the tower.The player is shown two gauges, the health and vitality gauge. The vitality gauge will constantly drain throughout gameplay, and when epmptied, the health gauge will begin to slowly drain as well. both gauges can be refilled using various items the player can find within the tower.In the original Sega Saturn title, the player was limited to a first-person view, though in the Wii and PS2 versions, the player could swap between first and third person perspectives.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20541">Mystery Dungeon: Shiren the Wanderer</game><game id="20911">Final Fantasy Fables: Chocobo's Dungeon</game><game id="4464">Izuna: Legend of the Unemployed Ninja</game><game id="21034">Izuna 2: The Unemployed Ninja Returns</game><game id="13974">Pokémon Mystery Dungeon: Blue/Red Rescue Team</game><game id="21294">Pokémon Mystery Dungeon: Explorers of Darkness/Time</game><game id="5276">World of Dragon Warrior: Torneko: The Last Hope</game><game id="13019">Dragon Quest Characters: Torneko no Daibouken 3 - Fushigi no Dungeon</game><game id="6411">Torneko no Daibouken - Fushigi no Dungeon</game><game id="23107">Dragon Quest: Shounen Yangus to Fushigi no Dungeon</game><game id="21782">Chocobo no Fushigina Dungeon</game><game id="7679">Chocobo's Dungeon 2</game><game id="21881">Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles: The Crystal Bearers</game><game id="25769">Tales of Graces</game><game id="24050">Monster Hunter Tri</game><game id="4202">Evolution: The World of Sacred Device</game><game id="29300">Summon Night Granthese: Horobi no Tsurugi to Yakusoku no Kishi</game><game id="26831">Shiren the Wanderer</game><game id="30580">Monster Hunter Portable 3rd</game><game id="35423">Dungeons of Dredmor</game><game id="14159">Grandia Xtreme</game><game id="32906">Rune Factory: Tides of Destiny</game><game id="37153">Dark Delve</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2199397-box_baroque.png</image></root>