<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13177</id><name>FlatOut</name><description>FlatOut is developed by Finnish Bugbear Entertainment and published by Empire Interactive and Vivendi Universal Games in 2004 and 2005. The main racing mode in FlatOut is standard lap races. The tracks are set in destructible environments, which allows the player to find short-cuts by driving through fences and other obstacles. But the player must still drive carefully though, as cars will be realistically damaged. Meaning that the driveability and appearance of the car will be affect by collisions.FlatOut also features ragdoll physics. The driver will be tossed out through the windshield when the car crashes. This feature is used in Ragdoll sports where the task is to propel the driver as far, as high, or as accurately as possible.An alternative mode to standard racing in FlatOut is demolition derby deathmatches, in which the driver of the sole-surviving vehicle declared the winner.The car crashes in this game are amazing to see, you'll see car parts flying through the air with dirty all over the place. The environments are also well designed, with trees and other obstacles littered across the track you're drving on. But FlatOut will really impress you when it comes to the level of detail that is shown on the cars for damage. PC Requirements Minimum Processor: 1.5 GHz Pentium 4 or AMD Equivalent Memory: 256 MB RAM Video: 64 MB Graphics Card Sound: DirectX Compatible Sound Card HDD: 1.1 GB of free Hard Drive Space OS: Win 98/ME/2000/XP/Vista/7, DirectX9.0c RecommendedProcessor: 2.0 GHz Pentium 4 or AMD 2000  Memory: 512 MB RAM Video: 128 MB GraphicsCard Sound: DirectX Compatible Sound Card Controllers: Gamepad or Steering Wheel OS: Windows XP SP2/ Vista / 7</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18059">PAIN</game><game id="20484">Burnout</game><game id="13776">Destruction Derby 2</game><game id="786">Destruction Derby</game><game id="13514">Burnout 2: Point of Impact</game><game id="357">Burnout 3: Takedown</game><game id="16492">Burnout Revenge</game><game id="4970">Burnout Legends</game><game id="8459">Burnout Dominator</game><game id="5648">Burnout Paradise</game><game id="13576">Demolition Racer</game><game id="11909">Demolition Racer: No Exit</game><game id="18394">Carmageddon</game><game id="10553">Carmageddon II: Carpocalypse Now</game><game id="20029">The Incredible Crash Dummies</game><game id="9813">Crashday</game><game id="23527">Hardware 2</game><game id="16728">Powerslide</game><game id="689">Jak X: Combat Racing</game><game id="12967">Rumble Racing</game><game id="25512">Clutch</game><game id="37034">Dirt Showdown</game><game id="35125">Ignite</game><game id="43835">Next Car Game (working title)</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2525181-box_fout.png</image></root>