<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13210</id><name>Kendo Rage</name><description>The player controls Josephine, an schoolgirl who recently came to live with his grandfather in rural Japan, at his Kendo Dojo. After her summer vacation, she leaves for her first day at school. However, her kendo skills will tested as she faces all sorts of bizarre enemies on the way. The game has an anime art style, complete with characters engaging in melodramatic posturing, and the main character becoming briefly super-deformed when hit. The game has a persistent timer that runs while going through the game. If the player doesn't beat the final boss by the time the clock in the upper left hand corner reads 9:00, they will get the bad ending. The game has seven stages, each with different environmental themes. Stage 1 – Cliff Hanger Josephine must get from her house to her bus stop and catch her bus. At the bus stop she must defeat a robotic Super-Deformed duplicate of herself. Stage 2 – Ice Queen Josephine must navigate a snow-covered mountain pass to reach her next bus connection, and defeat a crazed karaoke singer who unleashes ice attacks. Stage 3 – The Pond Josephine must get through various underwater caves and defeat 3 vicious fish to continue along her way. Stage 4 – Technodyne Josephine now must get through a construction site and fight a transforming giant robot in order to catch the cable car from the mountain to the city. Stage 5 – Commute Josephine must fend off attackers as she rides the cable car down to the bottom of the mountain, and then while taking the train. Stage 6 – Triathlon Once she's reached her stop, Josephine must fend off three groups of athletes bent on stopping her from making it to school on time, including a dark magical girl with tennis themed attacks. Stage 7 – School Daze As she races to school, Josephine faces a final boss rush, and one last demonic opponent hell-bent on keeping her from getting to school on time.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="810">Parodius</game><game id="2561">Prince of Persia</game><game id="6510">Valis: The Fantasm Soldier</game><game id="40698">Makeruna! Makendou 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4430/476848-box.png</image></root>