<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13216</id><name>Yu-Gi-Oh! Dark Duel Stories</name><description>OverviewYu-Gi-Oh! Dark Duel Stories is a card battling game developed and published by Konami for the Game Boy Color platform.GameplayThe rules for Yu-Gi-Oh! Dark Duel Stories follow the real life card game counterpart (Although an outdated ruleset).Game ModesWhen the game is first started there are seven different options to choose from:Campaign - The campaign is the main mode of the game. The game consists of multiple stages, represented by locations from the Yu-Gi-Oh! franchise.Construction - The construction section is where a player can go to construct a custom deck to use in battles.Versus - Versus mode is where two players can link their Game Boy Colors together to duel one another.Trade - Trade mode, like versus mode is used when two players link Game Boy Colors. Players can only trade cards if there is extra cards not being used in a deck available in the trunk.Records - The records section tells the player various stats collected from duels.Change Name - The change name area is where to go to change the name of the in game player.Password - The passwords in this game are used to instantly add cards to the players collection.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="13">Card Game</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10489">Pokémon Trading Card Game</game><game id="19085">Dragon Ball Z: Collectible Card Game</game><game id="3210">Marvel Trading Card Game</game><game id="2532">Magic: The Gathering - Duels of the Planeswalkers</game><game id="9558">Magic: The Gathering Online</game><game id="2789">Duel Masters: Limited Edition</game><game id="9324">Duel Masters Sempai Legends</game><game id="10219">Duel Masters Shadow of the Code</game><game id="13159">Duel Masters Kaijudo Showdown</game><game id="23426">Dragon Ball Z: Legendary Super Warriors</game><game id="23867">Fullmetal Alchemist Trading Card Game</game><game id="22912">Magi Nation</game><game id="27976">Koto Battle: Tengai no Moribito</game><game id="36372">Pokémon Card Game: How To Play DS</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2210228-box_ygodds.png</image></root>