<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13281</id><name>Chase H.Q.</name><description>OverviewThe game was originally brought to the arcades in 1988 by         Taito and later ported onto home console and computers, including the critically acclaimed        ZX Spectrum version, by       Ocean Software. Playing as a member of the Special Chase Investigation Department players were tasked with chasing down the A.I controlled car before finally taking them down. The arcade version of the game included 5 levels for the player to play through. The game spawned two arcade based sequels called      Special Criminal Investigation in 1988 and Super Chase: Criminal Termination in 1992.GameplayViewed from a similar behind the car perspective as     Outrun there was an initial 60 second time limit for the player to reach the fleeing vehicle. This was often made more difficult by having more cars on the road and also by providing the player with a choice of two branching roads to take; with one being a slower route than the other to the enemy car.  Once the enemy car was caught up with another 60 seconds was given to the player within which they had to bump into the car a certain amount of times forcing it pull over to the side of the road. The game had 5 different criminals, one for each level.1. Ralph, the Idaho Slasher 2. Carlos, the New York armed robber 3. Chicago pushers 4. L.A kidnapper 5. Eastern Bloc SpyVirtual Console ReleaseThe    Turbografx-16 version of the game was released onto the  Nintendo Wii   Virtual Console in July 2008 costing 600 Wii points.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="407">Battle Out Run</game><game id="17224">Chase H.Q. II: Special Criminal Investigation</game><game id="19714">Fire and Forget</game><game id="13251">Crazy Cars 2</game><game id="18496">MegaRace</game><game id="7347">Highway Patrol II</game><game id="205">Pursuit Force</game><game id="31698">Need for Speed: Hot Pursuit</game><game id="9554">Black Viper</game><game id="12975">Super Chase H.Q.</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1987/815351-chase_hq_front.jpg</image></root>