<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13286</id><name>Unreal Tournament 2004</name><description>OverviewUnreal Tournament 2004 is a futuristic arena-based shooter developed by Epic Games and Digital Extremes and published by Atari for the PC on March 16, 2004. An enhanced version of Unreal Tournament 2003, Unreal Tournament 2004 uses the Unreal Engine 2.5 game engine to include a variety of new content, including vehicular combat (ranging from tanks and aircraft to full-blown space combat), new weapons and characters, brand new maps (bringing the total number of maps to over 100), a new single-player campaign experience, and three brand new game modes (including the return of the mission-based Assault game mode from the original Unreal Tournament).Game modesDeathmatchClassic free-for-all gameplay. Reach a target number of frags to win.Team DeathmatchSimilar to deathmatch but with teams. The first team to reach target number of frags wins.Last Man StandingSimilar to deathmatch but with a limited number of lives. Last player alive wins.Capture the FlagTeams compete to capture the opponent's flag and return it to their base. First team to reach target number of flag captures wins.Vehicle Capture the FlagCapture the Flag with vehicles. First team to reach target number of flag captures wins.Double DominationSimilar to the well known "King of the Hill" mode in other games, domination contains two control points that must be captured and held in unison by teams in order to gain points. First team to reach target number of points wins. This mode was cut out of the game's sequel, Unreal Tournament III.AssaultThe closest thing UT2004 has to missions, assault mode tasks each team with a set number of objectives. One team is attacking while the other is defending and trying to prevent the attacking team from completing their objectives. If the objectives are completed within a time limit, the attacking team wins, but if the time runs out without the objectives being completed the defending team takes the win. After every round, attacking and defending teams switch sides.Bombing RunIntroduced in UT2003, the objective in Bombing Run is to take the bomb that spawns in the middle of the map and carry it into the enemy base and through the hoop located there. First team to reach target score wins. To do this you are given a "Bomb Launcher" whenever you are carrying the bomb. By left clicking the gun will, as the name suggests, launch the bomb out for anyone to pick up. But if you right click first when aiming at one of your teammates, the gun will "lock on" and home in on that person when you fire it making it easier to pass the bomb. As stated earlier the aim is to take the bomb to the enemy hoop. There are two ways you can do this, one is fire it into the hoop nabbing your team three points. Or you can try and jump through the hoop with the bomb scoring you seven points but usually giving your player an environmental death.InvasionInvasion is a simple survival mode. The players are forced to work together to try and survive endless waves of monsters that get increasingly difficult with each wave. Once a player dies they cannot re-spawn until the round is over. Rounds can either end after a time limit (victory), or when all players are dead (failure).MutantMutant is a deathmatch-type game mode where every player starts out with all weapons, and the first player to get a kill becomes the “Mutant”. This player has unlimited ammo as well as the berserk, speed, and invisibility power-ups. They are also constantly losing health and cannot pick up health packs, but they gain health with every kill they make. The person with the lowest score is given the title of “Bottom Feeder” and only the Mutant and Bottom Feeder can kill players without those titles.OnslaughtOnslaught is a vehicle-based game mode in which the objective is to capture a series of power nodes connecting your and your opponents’ bases and destroy the power core located within their base. First team to destroy opponents’ power core wins. This mode was combined with Assault mode to form Warfare mode in Unreal Tournament III.WeaponsTranslocatorMain Article: TranslocatorClassification: Personal Teleportation DevicePrimary Fire: Launches the destination module. Throws the module to the location you would like to teleport to.Secondary Fire: Activates the Translocator and teleports the user to the destination module.Techniques: Throw your destination module at another player and activate the secondary fire and you will teleport to your opponent's exact position, killing them instantly.TranslocatorShield GunClassification: Energy ShieldPrimary Fire: Charges up to smash opponents for massive damage.Secondary Fire: Creates a shield that can protect user from incoming bullets.Techniques: Pointing the shield down while falling will reduce the damage taken on impact.Shield GunAssault RifleMain Article: EnforcerClassification: Assault RiflePrimary Fire: A series of inaccurate shots with a high rate of fire.Secondary Fire: A grenade projectile that bounces around and then detonates.Techniques: Collect two for twice the damage.Assault RifleBio RifleMain Article: Bio RifleClassification: Toxic RiflePrimary Fire: Wads of Tarydium byproduct are lobbed at a medium rate.Secondary Fire: When trigger is held down the Bio Rifle will create a much larger was of byproduct that will burst into smaller wads which will adhere to any surfaces.Techniques: Byproducts will adhere to walls, floors, or ceilings. Chain reactions can be caused by covering entryways with this lethal green waste.Bio RifleShock RifleMain Article: ASMD Shock RifleClassification: Energy RiflePrimary Fire: Instant hit laser beam.Secondary Fire: Large, slow moving plasma core.Shock Combo: Shooting the secondary fire's core with a primary beam will cause a massive explosion, killing most opponents instantly.Shock RifleMine LayerClassification: Remote ExplosivePrimary Fire: Launches remote control “Spider Mines” onto the ground.Secondary Fire: A laser that allows you to guide the Spider Mines to where you want them to go.Techniques: Shoot eight Spider Mines at once to maximize explosive potential!Mine LayerLink GunMain Article: Pulse GunClassification: Plasma RiflePrimary Fire: Fires fast-moving green orbs of plasma.Secondary Fire: A bolt of green plasma lightning is expelled with limited length.Techniques: “Link” together with team mates to increase the Link Gun’s power.Link GunMinigunMain Article: Gatling GunClassification: Gatling GunPrimary Fire: Bullets are sprayed forth at a fast rate of fire and good accuracy.Secondary Fire: Minigun fires twice as fast and half as accurate.Techniques: Secondary Fire is much more useful at close range but can waste a lot of ammo.MinigunFlak CannonMain Article: Flak CannonClassification: Heavy ShrapnelPrimary Fire: White hot chunks of scrap metal spray out in a wide spread.Secondary Fire: A flak grenade is launched out of the gun with a high arc, exploding on impact.Techniques: The Flak Cannon is most useful in close quarters combat.Flak CannonGrenade LauncherMain Article: Grenade LauncherClassification: ExplosivePrimary Fire: Fires bouncing grenades that will stick to enemies or vehicles.Secondary Fire: Detonates grenades.Techniques: Turn friendly fire off and cover a team mate in grenades. Then have them run into the enemy base and detonate. Your team mate will be unharmed but the same cannot be said for the enemies nearby.Grenade LauncherRocket LauncherMain Article: Rocket LauncherClassification: Heavy BallisticPrimary Fire: A slow moving but deadly rocket is fired at opponents.Secondary Fire: Loads up to three rockets into the barrel which can then be fired in either a flat, horizontal pattern or a tight spiral.Techniques: Keeping this weapon aimed at an opponent will cause it to lock on. If you opponent keeps moving just before you can lock on however, it is best to just shoot at their feet.Rocket LauncherAVRiLMain Article: AVRiLClassification: Heavy BallisticPrimary Fire: A deadly anti-vehicular rocket is fired.Secondary Fire: Player’s view holds and zooms on locked target.Techniques: Keeping this weapon aimed at an enemy vehicle will cause it to lock on and become a seeking missile capable of pulling two ninety degree turns in one hundred feet.AVRiLSniper RifleMain Article: Sniper RifleClassification: Long Range BallisticPrimary Fire: Fires a high powered bullet.Secondary Fire: Zooms the rifle in, up to ten times normal vision.Techniques: Great for long distance headshots.Sniper RifleLightning GunMain Article: Lightning GunClassification: Long Range Energy RiflePrimary Fire: Fires an instant-hit lightning bolt with perfect accuracy.Secondary Fire: Zooms the rifle in, up to eight times normal vision.Techniques: Headshots do double damage, enough to kill an un-shielded opponent.Lightning GunRedeemerMain Article: RedeemerClassification: Thermonuclear DevicePrimary Fire: Fires a huge slow moving missile that will explode on impact, sending out a gigantic shock wave, instantly pulverizing anyone and anything within its colossal radius.Secondary Fire: Guide the missile using an onboard camera.Techniques: Shoot down a redeemer missile in midair to cause it to explode harmlessly.Redeemer (Swallow This)Ion PainterMain Article: Ion CannonClassification: Remote Targeting DevicePrimary Fire: Ion Painter delivers a delayed but extremely powerful blast which appears to come out of the sky.Secondary Fire: Same as primary fire.Techniques: Use the Ion Painter to take out enemy nodes in Onslaught mode.Ion PainterTarget PainterClassification: Remote Targeting DevicePrimary Fire: Fires a laser to mark a location. After a short delay, a Phoenix bomber is called in to drop bombs on target position.Secondary Fire: Zooms in.Techniques: The Phoenix bomber can be shot down before it delivers all or any of its explosive payload.Target PainterVehiclesMantaScorpionHellbenderRaptorGoliathLeviathanCicadaPaladinSPMAHuman Space FighterSkaarj Space FighterIon Plasma TankPhoenixTC-1200TeamsBlack LegionBlood FistFire StormGoliathHellionsIron GuardIron SkullJuggernautsSun BladeSuper NovaThe CorruptThunder CrashSoundtrackDisc OneNo.TitleWriter(s)Length1."Intro"Kevin Riepl3:122."Menu UT2K3"Kevin Riepl1:313."Menu UT2K4"Kevin Riepl4:144."Menu UT2K4 Version 2"Kevin Riepl1:365."Intro UT2K4 Version 2"Kevin Riepl2:056."Menu"Kevin Riepl1:557."Mercs Entrance"Kevin Riepl1:168."Jugs Entrance"Kevin Riepl1:009."Level 2"Starsky Partridge5:4810."Level 3"Starsky Partridge3:0911."Level 5"Starsky Partridge5:4712."Level 6"Starsky Partridge5:3113."Level 7"Starsky Partridge4:4814."Level 8"Starsky Partridge3:3815."Level 9"Starsky Partridge4:2116."Level 11"Starsky Partridge3:3517."Level 13"Starsky Partridge4:3418."Level 15"Starsky Partridge3:4019."Level 16"Starsky Partridge4:1620."Stage"Kevin Riepl0:53Disc TwoNo.TitleWriter(s)Length1."Absolute Zero"Kevin Riepl2:592."Action 1"Kevin Riepl3:083."Action 2 Version 2"Kevin Riepl3:344."Action 3"Kevin Riepl2:595."Assault"Kevin Riepl2:006."Atlantis"Kevin Riepl3:037."Chemical Burn"Kevin Riepl2:008."City"Kevin Riepl4:039."Collision Course"Kevin Riepl2:0010."Conduit"Kevin Riepl3:0011."Convoy"Kevin Riepl4:0512."Corrugation Rise"Kevin Riepl3:0713."DM1"Kevin Riepl2:0014."From Below Version 2"Kevin Riepl1:5915."Ghosts of Anubis"Kevin Riepl2:0216."Glacier"Kevin Riepl3:0017."Hell"Kevin Riepl2:0018."HyperBlast Redux"Kevin Riepl3:1319."Infernal Realm"Kevin Riepl2:0020."Infiltrate"Kevin Riepl2:0021."Junkyard"Kevin Riepl4:0122."Metallurgy"Kevin Riepl3:0523."Morpheus 3"Kevin Riepl3:02Disc ThreeNo.TitleWriter(s)Length1."Pharao's Revenge"Kevin Riepl2:002."Rankin"Kevin Riepl3:123."Robot Factory"Kevin Riepl4:014."Roughinery"Kevin Riepl3:025."Serenity"Kevin Riepl3:006."Skaarj Assault"Kevin Riepl3:007."Sky Scraper"Kevin Riepl2:018."Slaughter"Kevin Riepl2:209."Sniper Time"Kevin Riepl2:0010."Sulphur"Kevin Riepl2:5811."Tomb of Horus"Kevin Riepl2:0112."WasteLand"Kevin Riepl1:5813."Onslaught 1"Will Nevins3:4814."Onslaught 2"Will Nevins3:5715."Onslaught 3"Will Nevins6:1216."Onslaught 4"Will Nevins3:2117."Onslaught 5"Will Nevins4:0918."Onslaught 6"Will Nevins4:2519."Onslaught 7"Will Nevins3:2420."Ending Sequence"Kevin Riepl1:33System RequirementsWindows 98/Me/2000/XP128MB RAM (256MB RAM or greater recommended)Pentium III or AMD Athlon 1.0 GHz processor (Pentium® or AMD 1.System Requirements2GHz or greater recommended)8X CD-ROM or DVD5.5GB HDD spaceDirectX® version 9.0b32 MB video card required (64 MB NVIDIA or ATI hardware TL card recommended)Useful linksOfficial website</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21471">Warsow</game><game id="21388">Quake Live</game><game id="3874">Quake III Arena</game><game id="18883">Enemy Territory: Quake Wars</game><game id="7076">Battlefield 2142: Booster Pack - Northern Strike</game><game id="19358">Quake III: Team Arena</game><game id="15481">Star Wars: Battlefront</game><game id="7094">Star Wars: Battlefront II</game><game id="21218">Black Powder | Red Earth</game><game id="7747">John Romero's Daikatana</game><game id="22609">Soldier Front</game><game id="22129">Legions: Overdrive</game><game id="22807">Quake Arena Arcade</game><game id="21912">Planetside: Core Combat</game><game id="4389">Red Orchestra: Ostfront 41-45</game><game id="13683">Quake 4</game><game id="14714">Half-Life 2: Deathmatch</game><game id="26786">Halo: Reach</game><game id="17179">Starsiege: Tribes</game><game id="2832">Tribes 2</game><game id="10603">Tribes: Aerial Assault</game><game id="909">Tribes: Vengeance</game><game id="2078">Mobile Forces</game><game id="30389">Nexuiz</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1837522-box_ut2k4.png</image></root>