<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1329</id><name>Pocket Fighter</name><description>OverviewPocket Fighter (Also known as Super Gem Fighter: Mini Mix in North America) is an arcade game released by Capcom for it's CPS-2 arcade system, and was later ported to the WonderSwan,  PlayStation, Sega Saturn, as well as to the PlayStation 2 in Street Fighter Alpha's Anthology Collection. Pocket Fighter is a "super deformed" or "chibi" take on Capcom's fighting series, by offering a new animesque graphical style, where all the characters are dramatically shrunken in size. The game could be considered a parody or homage from Capcom to it's fighting series, due to the fact that it has a large variety of cameos/playable characters from all it's different fighting series, such as; Chun Li, Ryu and Zangief who are from Street Fighter II, Ibuki from Street Fighter 3, Morrigan and Felicia, from the Darkstalkers series and Tessa from Red Earth. GameplayUnlike many other fighters, Pocket Fighter has a relatively simple control scheme. In Pocket Fighter, only a punch, kick and "special" button is used, which in turn makes the game much easier and accessible to beginners. Another feature that is not included in other fighters, is the use of gems to control what special moves your character can do. These gems are dropped when you hit an opponent or a treasure chest.  The more gems you collect of one color, the more powerful the special move is that relates to that color. In relation to other series that Capcom produced, each character keeps his/her own special move. Another unique feature of Pocket fighter, is the addition of power-ups - you can collect food to decrease damage on the health bar, as well as collect "orbs" that have some special function, such as a bomb that can be thrown, or turn the player into ice. CameosAmazon Boardwalk                                                                     Elena is eating some ice cream.                                                                      Blanka is inside the ice shop.                                                                       Rikuo is inside the snakes mouth while his son Alba cheers him on.                                                                        Dhalsim washes the elephants back with his long arms while his wife sits ontop of it.Two                                                                            Sasquatch are reaching for the                                                                           banana's while                                                                          Mai-Ling is in their way.The snake in the background is possibly a reference to Blanka's                                                                             Street Fighter II stage that also shares a photographer like this one. Some say the Snake maybe akin to the one from the first                                                                              Resident Evil game.Chinatown Restaurant                                                                    Guy is hiding on the very left.                                                                   Jon Talbain is ontop of the giant plate of food while                                                                   Gen is in front of it.At the first table                                                                 Birdie,                                                                M.Bison and Sodom eat while                                                               Fei-long sits above them and                                                                  Rolento is seen crawling on the ground.The second table has                                                             Victor and                                                              Bishamon.Under the sign near the dragon is                                                            Adon.All alone in the right hand corner sits                                                           Charlie.A panda riding ontop of a ball will roll on by. This is the same panda and ball that                                                         Hsien-Ko turns into when hit by                                                          Anakaris' Pharoahs Curse. Maximum BarIn the balcony is                                                     Guy,                                                    Rolento and                                                   rose.In front of the toilet door is                                                  Birdie. In                                                 Street Fighter Alpha 2, Birdie's stage is inside a male restroom.Sitting together at the table is                                                       Guile and                                                      Charlie.At the bar,                                                Cammy jumps up and down on her chair.                                              Dee Jay is behind the bar dancing.                                             E.Honda is watching Cammy.                                            Huitzil is holding a drum with flowers in it. This is reference to his win pose in                                            Darkstalkers were he pulls out a drum and tuba.                                          June is on the cashier.Above June,                                          Sagat,                                         M.Bison and                                        Adon watch the flight below. Demitri's Moving Castle                                     Jedah is laying on the red rug. This form of Jedah is the one he transforms into during                                     Demitri's Midnight Bliss. Demitri teleports and slides across the floor.The portrait above is also seen in Demitri's Darkstalkers stage as well as in one of                                   Anita's attacks in                                    Marvel Super Heroes; only in Pocket Fighter the man is shown cross dressing from the waist down.Ghouls are seen lugging in Demitri's throne. The girls on this stage appear in various versions of Demitri's other stages.The iron maiden on the far right belongs to                                  Donovan.Dhalsims ToyshopBlodia from                                Cyberbots: Full Metal Madness is seen in the background. Blodia is piloted by                               Jin Saotome.                             M.Bison and                             Cammy are looking into the toy shop while                            Donovan is above on the balcony searching for a lost                           Anita who, is only around the corner, in front of the toy shop.                         Balrog is seen looking at a giant                       Chun-li toy or doll with                         B.B.Hood and                        Jon Talbain are to his right.The shop windows has many references to                      Plasma Sword including in the top right window, Rimgal (the Dinosaur), the face of                     Bistein in the left bottom window and a hologram of                    June.The windows also feature Darkstalkers refrences, a small bat in the top left window, a Hsien-Ko toy in a sled being pulled by pandas, the snowmen seen in various                   Sasquatch moves and poses as well as his Pharoahs Curse form.                  Rikuo is also seen in his Pharoah's curse form as a frog latched onto the window.La Menkoi Ski Resort      Vega is seen wearing no shirt in the cold.     M.Bison is seen sitting on a sled, laughing.The two girls outside of the              igloo are from                 Bishamon's                Darkstalkers: Night Warriors stage while Bishamon and               Sodom are inside of the igloo. The dog, Taro, outside and the statue are also references to Bishamon's stage.Above the stage,            Oro is latched to the the ski lift sleeping, a           Sasquatch is holding onto a line nearby while             Balrog is trying not to fall off a broken chair.In the background        Yun   and         Yang will appear flying through the air one on skis and one on a snowboard.Moonlight Dark Castle   Jon Talbain is seen howling at the moon.In the carriage sits one of   Morrigan's servants. This stage is also a reference to Morrigan's Darkstalkers stage as the fountains are from the game.Tessa's Den Lilith appears sitting above the chest, on the window as long as Morrigan isn't fighting on the stage.Leo is seen polishing his sword while sitting in the chair in front of the fireplace.Felicia, as long as she's not fighting, will appear on the floor napping. The ghost in the bed is from one of Tessa's attacks while a portrait of her appears on the wall.</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5845">Super Puzzle Fighter II Turbo HD Remix</game><game id="1167">Virtua Fighter Kids</game><game id="4762">Street Fighter Alpha Anthology</game><game id="2755">Super Puzzle Fighter II Turbo</game><game id="34011">Super Cosplay Wars Ultra</game><game id="36652">Fight 'N' Jokes</game><game id="25850">Battle Arena Nitoshinden</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1791300-box_pocketf.png</image></root>