<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13338</id><name>Andretti Racing</name><description>Published by EA Sports, Andretti Racing, gives the player the ability to race both Indy and Stock cars.  The player will race against a mix of 15 authentic and fictional drivers at a time, on 16 different race courses.  The majority of the courses in the game are road and street courses, all fictitious with exception to the Calder Park Thunderdome, which shares a name likeness with an Australian race track.Andretti Racing is seen as a precursor to the NASCAR Franchise that EA launched a year after Andretti Racing was released, under direction by Scott Orr.  The Andretti family involved themselves in the development of the game, Jeff Andretti specifically contributed to the design of the game.  Derek Daly Commentary In-game commentary was recorded by Derek Daly, Bob Jenkins and James Brown.  James Brown was the studio anchor for the game, giving updates between races as you progress through your career.  Derek Daly provided the pre-race commentary before every career race, while Bob Jenkins was the commentator for the race itself.Authentic DriversAll the drivers listed only appear in the Indy Car series, with the exception to Geoff Bodine, the only authentic driver in the Stock Car Series.  The remainder of the drivers have real pictures although are either fictional or unknown in proffessional racing.Jeff Andretti Mario Andretti Michael Andretti Gil de Ferran Christian Fittipaldi Robby Gordon Scott Pruett Danny Sullivan Geoff Bodine  Race TracksThe fictional race courses are mostly road and street circuits, set in real world locations.  Bridgeport - Tri-oval Meibashi - Road Course Vancouver - Street Circuit Toronto - Street Circuit Thunderdome - Tri-oval Australia - Street Circuit Vallejo - Road Course Kings Beach - Road Course Cincinnati - Street Circuit  Grand Rapids - Road CourseBinghampton Speedway  Longhorn - Road Course Oceanside - Road Course Glacier Fields - Road Course Binghampton - Street Circuit Oasis - Road Course Phalanx - Road Course </description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7432">Formula One World Championship: Beyond the Limit</game><game id="6473">Newman Haas Racing</game><game id="2416">Gran Turismo</game><game id="8100">Gran Turismo 2</game><game id="2162">Sega Rally Championship</game><game id="22135">Daytona USA</game><game id="2158">Ridge Racer</game><game id="18400">NASCAR 98</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/11423/714832-andretti_racing_pal_front.jpg</image></root>