<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1334</id><name>Super Mario World</name><description>OverviewSuper Mario World Intro ScreenSuper Mario World, or Super Mario Bros. 4 in Japan is a platformer developed and published by Nintendo launched as a bundle title for the SNES/Super Famicom. It was developed by Nintendo EAD, led by Shigeru Miyamoto and Takashi Tezuka. The game depicts Mario and Luigi trying to save Dinosaur Land from Bowser, the series' main antagonist. It introduced new power ups, and also Yoshi, the riding mount and loyal sidekick/pet of Mario's, who would continue to appear in the later games of the series.The game was a commercial succes, selling more that 20 million copies globally. It was re-released multiple times, first as a part of Super Mario All-Stars in 1994, then it was ported to the GBA and then again for the Wii Virtual Console in 2007.GameplayYoshi's first appearanceThe game follows Mario as he traverses several differently themed worlds, fighting against the minions of Bowser to once again rescue Princess Peach. Super Mario World first introduced Yoshi the dinosaur, who has since become a favorite among fans and went on to star in his own games, such as Yoshi's Story, Yoshi Topsy-Turvy, and Yoshi Touch  Go.Mario can ride Yoshi in all stages of the game except for castles and fortresses, and can make Yoshi shoot out his long tongue to snare and eat enemies. Super Mario World also introduced the cape power-up, which allows Mario to fly and glide in a slightly different manner than he did in the previous game, Super Mario Bros. 3.Super Mario World was the first game to give the player a reward for completing Star Road (all of the starting 5 and subsequently-unlocked 8 bonus levels). Once this is accomplished, the player may replay the game in EXTRA mode, in which several enemies' sprites are changed and the over world's color scheme changes. For instance, once-brown "Chocolate Island" turns green, while the green grass in other areas changes to brown, as does the green forest.Development  ReceptionCreator Shigeru Miyamoto has said conflicting things about Super Mario World, ranging from a feeling that the game's development (said to take 29,000 man hours to program) was rushed in order to more immediately compete with Sega's Sonic the Hedgehog to a 2010 interview with USA Today where the legendary creator cited SMW as his favorite in the series.Super Mario World was a North American launch game for Nintendo's 16-bit SNES in August 1991. The game launched alongside other SNES launch titles that included F-Zero and Pilotwings. The original version was released in 1990, alongside the Super Famicom launch. The game was well-received at release and would eventually go on to sell over 20 million copies, worldwide.WorldsThe game is laid out in an island overworld.World 1: Yoshi's IslandWorld 2: Donut PlainsWorld 3: Vanilla DomeWorld 4: Forest of IllusionWorld 5: Chocolate IslandWorld 6: Bowser's ValleyBonus World: Star World/Star RoadBonus World: Special WorldPower-UpsBoth Mario and Yoshi had power-ups in the game.Super MushroomFire FlowerStarmanFeather CapeYoshi also had his share of power-ups, which he got via eating colored shells which gave him special abilities such as flying, spitting out fireballs, and more.Super Mario World: Super Mario Advance 2Mario finds a secret passage.This game is an almost identical port of Super Mario World for the Super Nintendo, but there are some changes. Some of the minor differences that were made for this version on the Game Boy Advance were the ability to slightly move the camera and additional noises that Mario and Luigi make.Yoshi coins were also included in every level, while Yoshi coins previously appeared only in certain levels in the original version. In addition to that, you can save your progress after each level, making it more convenient to play a little here and there on the GBA, you can also check how much of the game you have completed. The Life counter was increased to 1000 lives.TV seriesThe TV series based on the game with the same name.In addition to the video game, there was also a TV show based on the game with the same name in 1991 and It was also the third and final Mario cartoon in the series (The other two are The Super Mario Bros. Super Show and The Adventures of Super Mario Bros. 3). The show was produced by Nintendo in association with DiC Entertainment. The series span only thirteen episodes and it took place in Dome City in the TV series. The cast of characters include Oogtar, Yoshi, and the Mario Bros. This was also the second show to feature the Koopalings in the series. Each one of the 13 episodes has a song that corresponds to the troubles that they cause during the episode. For example: If Mario and Yoshi were playing football against the Koopalings, then the song that corresponds to "The Yoshi Shuffle" is called "Fight to the Finish". This chart shows the episode and the song that plays in the episode. Speed Running Super Mario World has taken it's place among speed runners, the streamlined levels allowing players to keep moving or find a way to keep moving with out ever stopping for anything.without using any glitches or bugs in the game. Timers are started when the player presses start on the main game screen and ends when a player has made his last hit on Bowser.RecordsFastest Minimalist Completion - 11:00s Rodrigo Lopes 2008-04-04Fastest Total Completion (getting all 96 exit gates) 1h 31m 44s Jason Baum 2005-03-22These records were verified through Twin Galaxies though many speed runners continue to run this game with increasingly faster times on streaming service around the internet.Song ChartEpisodeSongGopher BashCheatsy's LifeFire SaleKootie Pie RapThe Yoshi ShuffleFight to the FinishMama LuigiLooking for YouThe Wheel ThingMotor City, Here We ComeRock TVReady To GoSend in the ClownThe Greatest Show in the WorldGhosts 'R' UsThere's a Wizard, Here TonightKing Scoopa KoopaKeep on RunningThe Night Before Cave ChristmasRockin' With the SleighbellsParty LineListen to the GrapevineBorn to RideTime to Get WildA Little LearningRockin' the High SchoolEnemiesAmazing Flying Hammer BroA flying enemy, throws hammers. Can be killed by hitting the bottom of his platform.Amazing Flying Hammer Bro.Banzai BillA large Bullet Bill, shoots out of nowhere and can be avoided by ducking or killed by stomping on its head.Banzai BillBlarrgA lava monster that jumps out of the lava at Mario. There is a glitch that actually allows Yoshi to eat them.BlarrgBlurpA fish that endlessly swims in one direction.BlurpBob-OmbA walking bomb that blows up after a set amount of time or when jumped on.Bob-OmbBony BeetleA mummy incarnation of the Buzzy Beetle.Bony BeetlesBooA ghost that shies away when looked at. When looked away from, the boo chases Mario.Three BoosChargin' ChuckA football playing koopa. They are known to throw footballs and baseballs. They also charge towards Mario.Chargin' ChuckBuzzy BeetleA koopa that is immune to fire balls.Yoshi can swallow them whole unlike koopas.Buzzy BeetleBullet BillA missile shot out of a cannon that aim for Mario.Bullet BillCheep-CheepA fish that swims in a set pattern.Dino RhinoA rhino that shoots fire and can only be killed while running around.Dino RhinoDry bonesA skeletal Koopa that pops back up after being jumped on.Dry BoneEerieA "Ghost Yoshi" that floats towards Mario.EeriesFishBoneA fish that swims after Mario when seen.FishBoneFishin' BooA boo that bobs down attempting to hit Mario with fire.Fishing BooFishing LakituA Lakitu that lures Mario with a 1-UP. When the 1-UP is collected, Fishing Lakitu acts like a normal Lakitu and throws Spinys.FIshing LakituFuzzyA black ball of fuzz that spin in a circle and can only be killed by a Starman.FuzziesGold Bowser StatueA hopping statue of Bowser.Gold Bowser StatueGoombaA popular enemy. In this game, they can be picked up and thrown after being jumped on.Mario holding a Goomba.LakituA flying koopa that throws Spinys.LakituMagiKoopaA wizard koopa that shoots blasts. Whenever those blasts hit blocks, the blocks turn into enemies, such as Koopas and Thwimps.MagiKoopaMecha KoopasRobotic Koopas that can be thrown when hit.Mecha-koopaMonty MoleMoles that pop up out of the ground and chase Mario.Monty Mole ArtworkMega MoleLarger monty moles that chase Mario. They can be ridden across spikes.Mega MoleNinjiCreatures that hop up and down in an attempt to hit Mario.Ninji comparison from SMB 2, Super Mario World, and Paper Mario.Pipe LakituLakitus in a pipe that pop up and throw Spinys.Pipe LakituPiranha PlantPlants that come up from pipes and try to hit Mario.Piranha PlantPodobooBalls of fire that hop up from lava trying to hit Mario.PodoboosPokeyWalking cacti that move towards Mario and can be eaten by Yoshi.PokeysPorcu-PufferFish that are covered in spikes and chase Mario.Porcu-PufferRexDinosaurs that walk randomly and have to be jumped on twice unless they are spin-jumped onto.RexRip Van FishA sleeping fish that chases Mario when passed by.Rip Van FishSpinySpike covered Koopas thrown by Lakitus.Mario avoiding Spinys.Sumo Bro.Giant Koopa that stand on overhead blocks and attack by stomping their feet. This sends lightening bolts toward the ground that will catch the ground on fire when they hit.Sumo Bros. attacking MarioSuper KoopaFlying Koopas. The ones with flashing capes will drop a Cape Feather when hit.Super KoopaSwooperBats that hang on the ceiling of caves and swoop down at Mario.SwooperThwompGiant blocks that drop down at Mario.ThwimpSmaller blocks that hop in patterns.A Thwimp (left) compared to a Thwomp (right)Torpedo TedBullet Bills of the water. Drop down from boxes and swim towards Mario.Torpedo TedUrchinSea Urchins that swim around in patterns.UrchinVolcano LotusPlants that spit several fireballs.A Volcano Lotus from the Super Mario World T.V. show.WigglerCaterpillars that get angry when Mario jumps on them.Wiggler</description><genres><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5834">Bubsy In: Fractured Furry Tales</game><game id="20205">Bubsy in: Claws Encounters of the Furred Kind</game><game id="16875">Mickey Mania</game><game id="9233">Kirby Super Star</game><game id="10384">Jak II</game><game id="16337">Sly 3: Honor Among Thieves</game><game id="7804">Rocket: Robot on Wheels</game><game id="20330">Gex 3: Deep Cover Gecko</game><game id="15991">Chameleon Twist 2</game><game id="962">Clockwork Knight</game><game id="18376">Looney Tunes Back in Action</game><game id="4547">Donkey Kong Country 3: Dixie Kong's Double Trouble!</game><game id="11514">Aero the Acro-Bat 2</game><game id="5694">James Pond 3: Operation Starfish</game><game id="6657">Blue's Journey</game><game id="12900">M.C. Kids</game><game id="21622">The Ren &amp; Stimpy Show: Veediots!</game><game id="14433">Sonic CD</game><game id="4182">Plok</game><game id="1683">Porky Pig's Haunted Holiday</game><game id="23656">Hook</game><game id="20963">Wario Land: Shake It!</game><game id="17034">Super Adventure Island II</game><game id="15738">Donkey Kong Country</game><game id="16889">Donkey Kong Country 2: Diddy's Kong Quest</game><game id="8627">Super Star Wars: The Empire Strikes Back</game><game id="27050">Frantic Flea</game><game id="4628">Sonic the Hedgehog 3</game><game id="18115">Sonic &amp; Knuckles</game><game id="24993">Prehistorik Man</game><game id="18090">Psycho Fox</game><game id="31732">Donkey Kong Country Returns</game><game id="33044">Flip-iT &amp; Magnose</game><game id="25220">All Night Nippon Super Mario Bros.</game><game id="7423">Keio Flying Squadron 2</game><game id="39484">Giana Sisters: Twisted Dreams</game><game id="41550">Super Ubie Land</game><game id="6763">Skyblazer</game><game id="44033">Giana Sisters: Twisted Dreams - Rise of the Owlverlord</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2364833-snes_supermarioworld.jpg</image></root>