<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13351</id><name>Phoenix Wright: Ace Attorney - Justice For All</name><description>OverviewANGRY CLOWNS!A year after the events of Phoenix Wright: Ace Attorney, Phoenix Wright is now a semi-famous defense attorney. With the return of his friend and assistant, Maya Fey, and the introduction of a new rival, follow Phoenix through four brand-new cases with the help of his friends, as well as a new way of gaining information during his investigations. Justice For All also has a heavier focus on the supernatural elements of the series than the first game did, with psychic abilities playing a major role in almost every case, and the psyche-lock system being entirely based around a supernatural concept, where Phoenix uses a Magatama given to him by Pearl.CharactersPhoenix Wright - The title character, a spiky-haired lawyer with a deep trust in his clients' innocence.Maya Fey - The sister of Phoenix's former boss and mentor, Mia Fey. She is a spirit medium in training.Pearl Fey - A cousin of Maya and a member of the Fey Branch Family, she possesses strong spiritual powers for her age.Mia Fey - After being murdered in the previous game, she returns as a spirit (after being channeled by either Maya or Pearl) to offer Phoenix advice and guidance during his investigations and trials.Franziska von Karma - The daughter of Manfred von Karma. She is a gifted prosecutor, beginning her career in Germany at the age of 13. Carries a whip and uses it frequently.Dick Gumshoe - A detective. Has the habit of addressing nearly everyone as 'pal'. Constantly having his salary lowered due to multiple screw ups.Miles Edgeworth - Phoenix's friend and rival who is missing for most of the game.Case SummariesThe Lost TurnaboutPhoenix is asked to defend police officer Maggey Byrde in the murder of her boyfriend, Dustin Prince (get it?!) who had plummeted to his death. However, there's a problem: he can't remember who she--or even HE--is, as at the beginning of the case, Phoenix is knocked over the head with a fire extinguisher. This case then becomes a sort of "tutorial case", where Maggey tries to help you do everything in the place of Mia (who shows up partway through the case to drop off some evidence) by reminding about everything you can do- present evidence, the cross examination, etcetera.It is revealed that the murderer was actually tied to a smuggling ring in town. The murderer, Duke Wellington, had lost his phone and, when he saw Dustin walking with Maggey, he thought that she had called the cops about the phone and, to protect himself, he pushed Dustin off a wall in the park. He then wrote Maggey's name in the ground with Dustin's finger (spelled incorrectly as Maggie) to frame her, and then phoned in his crime.His undoing came from the fact that his glasses were found under Dustin's body, along with the large gap of time between his 'discovery' of the body and the time he called the police. In the end, Phoenix remembered that he still had Wellington's phone and then called his own. It rang in Wellington's pocket, proving it was him who hit Phoenix so that he could try to steal his phone back.Reunion, and TurnaboutThis case takes place before The Lost Turnabout. Phoenix meets Maya in her village, but is forced to defend her after the shooting of a doctor in the middle of a spirit channeling. And this time, he has to take on another member of the von Karma family--Franziska.Turnabout Big TopA world-famous magician, Max Galactica, is accused of murdering the ringmaster of the circus he works for. Things may not be as they first appear, as the grudges of an accident six months ago come to light.Farewell, My TurnaboutIn the middle of the Hero of Heroes Grand Prix, the winner (Matt Engarde) is accused of killing his rival, Juan Corrida. An old foe returns as the fate of Matt, as well as that of Maya, is put in Phoenix's hands in this thrilling final case.SoundtrackThe soundtrack for the game was composed by Masakazu Sugimori and Akemi Kimura on March 31, 2004 in a two disc format in Japan.Disc OneGyakuten Saiban 1+2 Original SoundtrackGyakuten Saiban - PrologueCourtroom Lounge ~ Beginning of the PreludeGyakuten Saiban - TrialExamination ~ Moderate 2001Logic and TrickRyuuichi Naruhodou ~ Objection! 2001Examination ~ Allegro 2001Investigation ~ OvertakedInform the Truth 2001SuspenseInvestigation ~ Overtaked (Variation)Jingle ~ It Doesn't End HereSearch ~ Opening 2001Shinshuu Ryouri ~ Gyakuten Sisters' Theme 2001Police Cell ~ Jailers' ElegyKeisuke Itonoko ~ Itonoko GeijissuReminiscence ~ True Evening of GriefSoranosuke Hoshikage ~ Old, Regret, RewardCongratulations EverybodyReminiscence ~ Light and Shadow of the Film StudioOo-edo Soldier TonosamanReminiscence ~ DL6 CaseSearch ~ Core 2001Reminiscence ~ Classroom TrialWon the Lawsuit! ~ The First SuccessGyakuten Saiban - EndGyakuten Sisters' BalladeDisc TwoGyakuten Saiban 2 - Prologue ~ From J.S. Bach 'Toccatta and Fuga in D- BWV565'Arrival Melody (Takamasa Moroheiya)Courtroom Lounge ~ Overture AgainGyakuten Saiban 2 - TrialExamination ~ Moderate 2002Trick and MagicRyuuichi Naruhodou ~ Objection! 2002Examination ~ Allegro 2002Investigation ~ Cross-examiningInform the Truth 2002Arrival Melody (Ryuuichi Naruhodou)Investigation ~ Cross-examining (Variation)Jingle ~ It Didn't Sleep In That NightPsycho LockSearch ~ Opening 2002Shinshuu Ryouri ~ Gyakuten Sisters' Theme 2002Police Cell ~ Elegy of Surveillance CamerasSouin VillageReminiscence ~ The fire carves scarsEccentricGorgeous!Tachimi - CircusCongratulations Everybody, AgainReminiscece ~ True PainSasayuuemon Kuroushike ~ Murderous Gentleman of PleasureHarumi Ryouri ~ Hamichan QuestioningSearch ~ In the Midst 2002Great Revival ~ Reiji MitsurugiHotline of FateSearch ~ Core 2002Reminiscence ~ Tonosaman's BalladeGreat Revival ~ Myou ShumaWon the Lawsuit! ~ Success AgainGyakuten Saiban 2 - EndProsecutors' Murmur ~ Expecting the Next Meeting</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1159">Hotel Dusk: Room 215</game><game id="21826">Defenders of Law Inc: Crime in Willburg</game><game id="20145">Sprung</game><game id="20522">Harvey Birdman: Attorney at Law</game><game id="17990">Trace Memory</game><game id="11177">Putt-Putt Joins the Parade</game><game id="12998">Sherlock Holmes: Consulting Detective</game><game id="18297">Where in Space is Carmen Sandiego? (Deluxe Edition)</game><game id="1182">Sherlock Holmes Consulting Detective: Volume II</game><game id="23075">Ikatan: Ikamono Tantei</game><game id="20529">Insecticide</game><game id="22330">Jake Hunter: Detective Chronicles</game><game id="21807">Unsolved Crimes</game><game id="24237">Again</game><game id="21845">Death Note: Kira Game</game><game id="25340">Tokyo Twilight Busters</game><game id="25446">Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kizuna: Daisankan Rasen</game><game id="25583">Yuzai x Muzai</game><game id="21777">LifeSigns:  Surgical Unit</game><game id="17544">Broken Sword: The Shadow of the Templars</game><game id="25156">Lux-Pain</game><game id="25654">Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kizuna: Daiichikan Tatari</game><game id="25655">Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kizuna: Dainikan Sou</game><game id="21411">Theresia</game><game id="25685">Miami Law</game><game id="26447">Hayarigami: Toshi Densetsu Kaii Jiken</game><game id="24071">So Blonde</game><game id="28435">Agatha Christie: The ABC Murders</game><game id="29344">Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kizuna: Daiyonkan Kizuna</game><game id="26608">Case Closed: The Mirapolis Investigation</game><game id="29533">Last Window: The Secret of Cape West</game><game id="30111">Disney Guilty Party</game><game id="40045">Devil's Attorney</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1836593-box_pwaa2.png</image></root>