<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13393</id><name>WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW</name><description>OverviewWWE Smackdown vs. Raw is the sixth game in the WWE Smackdown series of games and the first to use the "vs. Raw" suffix. Later games would adopt this suffix as well as a year (Smackdown vs. Raw 2006), similar to most traditional sports games. The "vs. Raw" suffix was used up until Smackdown vs. Raw 2011, and now the games are named "WWE" with the year.New FeaturesSmackdown vs. Raw improves over previous games in a few areas. The first is with its graphics. SvR features an increased polygon count over previous Smackdown games. Voiceovers from many WWE Superstars were also added into the Season mode. Mini-games were added for the first time for both pre-match and in-game situations. The Clean/Dirty that would be expanded on in later games was first instituted in SvR. A reformatted PPV mode and a Create-A-Championship mode were also added.RosterAs with every WWE Smackdown game, Smackdown vs. Raw features an updated roster, including wresters from Raw, Smackdown, and a separate roster of Legends.Raw SuperstarsA-TrainBatistaChris BenoitChris JerichoChristianChuck PalumboEdgeGarrison CadeKaneMatt HardyMolly HollyRandy OrtonRhynoRic FlairShawn MichaelsShelton BenjaminStacy KeiblerTajiriTriple HTrish StratusVictoriaSmackdown SuperstarsBig ShowBooker TBubba-Ray DudleyCharlie HaasChavo GuerreroD-Von DudleyEddie GuerreroHardcore HollyJBLJohn CenaKurt AngleMark JindrakPaul HeymanRene DupreeRey MysterioRicoRob Van DamSableScotty 2 HottyTorrie WilsonUndertakerLegendsAndre the GiantAnimalBret HartBrutus BeefcakeHawkJimmy SnukaUndertaker (Legend)MankindKane (Masked)The RockRoddy PiperTriviaHidden on the disk are unusued announce files, which indicate that the roster was once planned to include Goldberg, Ultimo Dragon, Brock Lesnar, Steve Austin, and several others.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="10">Wrestling</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10775">WWF Royal Rumble</game><game id="10158">M.U.S.C.L.E.</game><game id="22464">Wrestling Encore</game><game id="20723">WWE Legends of WrestleMania</game><game id="30637">Lucha Libre AAA Heroes del Ring</game><game id="13440">Backyard Wrestling: Don't Try This at Home</game><game id="18333">Backyard Wrestling 2: There Goes the Neighborhood</game><game id="28430">WWF Royal Rumble</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2139897-box_wwesdraw.png</image></root>