<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13440</id><name>Backyard Wrestling: Don't Try This at Home</name><description> Backyard Wrestling: Don't Try This At Home was developed by     Paradox Development and published by     Eidos Interactive in 2003 for the     Xbox and     PlayStation 2. The goal of Backyard Wrestling is to use the environment and the weapons in it to defeat the enemy is the bloodiest way possible.  The game consists of decently large roster of wrestlers, including     Violent J and     Shaggy 2 Dope, Mad Man Pondo, Tylene Buck, Kitana Baker, Sabu and Monoxide Child to name a few. The game received lukewarm to bad reviews, with critics criticizing the poor graphics, terrible gameplay, repetitiveness and sloppy presentation. However, critics have complimented the game's soundtrack, with it standing out against the poorly put together game, and that the game at least tried something different than the normal. Despite the reviews, the game went on to sell nearly half a million copies worldwide, enough for the company to justify the development of a sequel, Backyard Wrestling 2: There Goes the Neighborhood.  Roster    Violent J   Shaggy 2 Dope Mad Man Pondo The Rudeboy Josh Prohibition M-Dogg 20 JCW's Evil Dead Jamie Madrox Monoxide Child  Sabu Tom Dub Masked Horn Dog El Drunko El Chicharron Karnage Gupta masked mike jackson Sonny D. Chopper Atrocity XXX Commissioner Dameon Redd Da Bone Doctor Ross Lover Josh Asbill Tylene Buck Kitana Baker Sally Jezebel Rosie Adrianna Paine Hernia</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="10">Wrestling</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12592">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2008</game><game id="20469">TNA iMPACT!</game><game id="18320">WCW/nWo Revenge</game><game id="10286">WCW Backstage Assault</game><game id="14786">WCW vs. nWo: World Tour</game><game id="22273">WCW Superbrawl Wrestling</game><game id="557">WCW vs. the World</game><game id="775">WCW: World Championship Wrestling</game><game id="1873">WCW/nWo Thunder</game><game id="30637">Lucha Libre AAA Heroes del Ring</game><game id="26888">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2010</game><game id="20680">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2009</game><game id="20723">WWE Legends of WrestleMania</game><game id="15815">WWE SmackDown! Here Comes the Pain</game><game id="7552">WWE SmackDown! Shut Your Mouth</game><game id="13393">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW</game><game id="11394">WWF No Mercy</game><game id="1696">WWF Smackdown! Just Bring It</game><game id="17814">WWF SmackDown! 2: Know Your Role</game><game id="3213">WWF Wrestlemania</game><game id="3826">WWF Super Wrestlemania</game><game id="3667">WWF Wrestlemania 2000</game><game id="8027">WWF WrestleMania: The Arcade Game</game><game id="6945">ECW Anarchy Rulz</game><game id="8647">ECW Hardcore Revolution</game><game id="29222">TNA iMPACT: Cross the Line</game><game id="25903">TNA Wrestling</game><game id="31640">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2011</game><game id="31641">WWE All Stars</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2314056-box_bwrestl.png</image></root>