<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13502</id><name>Brothers in Arms DS</name><description>One of the first World War II shooter on DS, Brothers in Arms is a third-person shooter set in WWII, you battle through various mission but the game doesn't last long and you'll soon be wishing for some multiplayer or another game mode. despite this brothers in arms is full of hollywood movie sequences, like when a panzer tanks busts through the wall of a church your hiing out in."Brothers in Arms DS" is a third person shooter set, like the other "Brothers in Arms" titles, in World War 2.  Locations in the game include Normandy, Tunisia and the Ardennes, and these span a total of 16 missions. The controls are a combination of button and stylus, which have received mixed reviews due to their tendency to create sore hands after an extended period of time.  To make up for the sometimes hard to deal with controls, an auto-aim system was added, although this also had mixed reviews.  Unlike other Brothers in Arms titles, the DS version does not have squad based combat, but centeres around a lone character wading through an army of nazis.  Missions in Brothers in Arms DS include many of the same types seen in previous WW2 shooters, such as setting charges on tanks, take on waves of enemies upon a large machine gun, or pilot a jeep or a tank to get to objectives on the map.  All objectives are conveyed through textbox messages clearly telling you what to do next, although the game is quite linear and pretty easy to figure out.  The missions, however simplistic, are varied in all three campaigns.  In Normandy you will find yourself driving jeeps and tanks through French villages, in Tunisia you will set charges and raid bunkers, and in the Ardennes you will hold the line against waves of enemy troops and chase down nazi soldiers.  Brothers in Arms DS is an impressive technical achievement for the DS due to its varied and detailed environments, where the small screen fits in a surprising amount of action and movement at one time.  That said, alot of the textures and characters can be rather grainy and muddled up close, a problem that is often noticed since your character is almost always under cover.  Brothers in Arms recieved mixed reviews, and 6.0 from Gamespot, an 8.0 on IGN, and a 72 at Metacritic.  It is widely known as being a game for someone who just really wants a third person shooter on their DS.captioncaptioncaption</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2347">Call of Duty 2</game><game id="19230">Medal of Honor</game><game id="7524">Call of Duty 3</game><game id="5484">Medal of Honor: Heroes</game><game id="10228">Medal of Honor: European Assault</game><game id="17429">Vietcong: Purple Haze</game><game id="27664">Call of Duty: Modern Warfare: Mobilized</game><game id="7827">Call of Duty: Roads to Victory</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1801417-box_biads.png</image></root>