<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1353</id><name>The Beast Within: A Gabriel Knight Mystery</name><description>Jump back into the shoes of private investigator and novelist Gabriel Knight and his sidekick Grace Nakimura as they investigate the killing of a little girl by a supposed werewolf. The game is a point and click adventure and was published by Sierra. The Beast Within uses full motion video throughout the game, as a result the game was released on 6 CDs each of which contained a different chapter in the story. Unlike many other full motion video games however, the game's interface is a typical point and click affair which mostly resembles earlier Sierra and Lucasarts titles. Characters are represented by animated sprites with which the player character can interact, resulting in video sequences.The Beast Within takes place one year after the events of the first Gabriel Knight game. Knight has inherited a castle in a small German village and the title of Schattenjäger . The local villagers show up at his door late one night and ask him to investigate the mysterious death of a little girl which they believe was caused by a werewolf. Knight's duties as a Schattenjäger require him to look around the town and see what he can discover about the girl's death.Each chapter alternates between the player controlling Gabriel Knight as he investigates the killing and the disappearance of two zoo wolves near Munich, and Grace Nakimura as she researches past werewolf sightings. The story is eventually tied to the mysterious death of King Ludwig II of Bavaria and his encounter with a man known as the Black Wolf. In the climax, Gabriel himself is turned into a wolf through a secret tied to a lost Richard Wagner opera discovered by Grace. The final showdown features wolf-Gabriel traversing a maze-like subbasement of an opera house with the Black Wolf in pursuit. The player is tasked with leading the Black Wolf through the maze to the boiler room where Gabriel lunges forth knocking the Black Wolf into the furnace.Additional NotesThe Gabriel Knight series is known for weaving historical figures, real-world locations and landmarks into its plots. The Beast Within features several German landmarks, possibly the most famous of which is the castle Neuschwanstein, built by King Ludwig II in the 19th Century.The fact that Gabriel Knight doesn't speak German is an important part of the plot. In the german localization all native people speak in a strong Bavarian accent - thus Gabriel Knight (now speaking German fluently) still isn't able to understand the local town's folk.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16298">The 7th Guest</game><game id="1724">The 11th Hour</game><game id="4327">Roberta Williams' Phantasmagoria</game><game id="3181">Burn: Cycle</game><game id="10169">Phantasmagoria: A Puzzle of Flesh</game><game id="2845">Gabriel Knight 3: Blood of the Sacred, Blood of the Damned</game><game id="828">Harvester</game><game id="18648">Night Trap</game><game id="224">Star Trek: Klingon</game><game id="13504">MTV's Club Dead</game><game id="2614">The Dig</game><game id="1555">Codename: ICEMAN</game><game id="3633">Indiana Jones and the Fate of Atlantis</game><game id="21667">Gray Matter</game><game id="2619">The Pandora Directive</game><game id="20056">9: The Last Resort</game><game id="37416">Yesterday</game><game id="38144">Leisure Suit Larry in the Land of Lounge Lizards RELOADED</game><game id="38172">Moebius</game><game id="19852">The Blackwell Legacy</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3863/307608-gk2box.jpg</image></root>