<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13568</id><name>Batman &amp; Robin</name><description>OverviewBatman  Robin is a third-person action-adventure game developed by Probe and published by Acclaim for the PlayStation on August 7, 1998. Loosely based on the 1997 film of the same name, players explore the open-world Gotham City as Batman, Robin, or Batgirl, as they fight thugs and analyze clues to foil the villanous trio of Mr. Freeze, Poison Ivy, and Bane.A handheld version was developed by Tiger and published for the Game.Com as a simpler 2D action platformer.GameplayThe game is a third-person action-adventure title, operating in an open-world environment. Players can take the Batmobile, or any one of five other vehicles, out onto the streets of Gotham, and explore the city. Civilians and thugs roam the streets, and Batman can jump out of his vehicle at any time to roam the city on foot.Gameplay consists of fighting and driving sequences, and some platforming elements. But the main focus was on detective work, encouraging the player to use the various functions of the Batcomputer to analyse clues and evidence, calculating The World's Greatest Detective's next move.The game also moves in real-time, in a similar style to the more modern franchise Dead Rising, where events will occur at preset times during the day or night, and Batman must uncover plots and track locations, arriving at the scene of the crime in a timely fashion in order to prevent disaster. Should the player be unable to make sense of the clues and fail to arrive at set locations on time, the game will be over. Most of the crimes throughout the game are directly taken from the movie, and the game follows the film's plot for the most part, but some missions were specifically created for the game.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10593">Grand Theft Auto 2</game><game id="1238">Batman Beyond: Return of the Joker</game><game id="17295">Mortal Kombat Mythologies: Sub-Zero</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2116192-box_batmanar.png</image></root>