<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13592</id><name>Ever17: The Out of Infinity</name><description>OverviewEver17: The Out of Infinity is a sci-fi mystery visual novel that was developed by the now defunct KID Corp, who was known for creating the popular Memories Off series and even the cult classic Pepsiman. The North American release of Ever17 was distributed by Hirameki International Group who have since bowed out of publishing visual novels. The US release was a port of the Japanese "Premium Edition" of Ever 17, which contained various extras that can be unlocked or are available from the outset. These include system sound files, wallpapers, and screensavers.StoryDanger looms just outside the walls of LeMUAs the player you take the role of one of two characters as determined by an early-game choice. One is a Japanese teenager named Takeshi Kuranari and the other is a young amnesiac boy that the group simply call "the Kid." As one of these two you watch as the undersea theme park known as LeMU floods, trapping six people inside. However, with water pressure continuing to press in on the depressurized walls of LeMU, time is short. The choices you make will build relationships, change events, and ultimately determine the fate of the survivors within LeMU.Ever 17 consists of five separate scenarios, two of which are exclusive to each of the main characters, and the final scenario which can be accessed with either after completing the other four. Each of the five scenarios are themed around a different female character in the game while offering more clues, hints, and mysteries for the player.In total Ever 17 has 11 endings, 126 scenes, and an estimated 100 hours of gameplay.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="36">Text Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21525">Hourglass of Summer</game><game id="23483">Tea Society of a Witch</game><game id="23485">Day of Love</game><game id="23486">Amusement Park</game><game id="21560">Phantom of Inferno</game><game id="27266">999: 9 Hours, 9 Persons, 9 Doors</game><game id="28224">Steins;Gate</game><game id="2885">Remember 11: The Age of Infinity</game><game id="38614">Root Double: Before Crime * After Days</game><game id="38910">I/O</game><game id="1705">Yu-No: Kono Yo no Hate de Koi o Utau Shoujo</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/97089/2567290-b.png</image></root>