<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13712</id><name>Blazing Angels: Squadrons of WWII</name><description>OverviewIn Blazing Angels: Squadrons of WWII, the player takes control of two pilots ( Tom or Frank), to recreate and fight in several battle of  World War II.  The game features several aspects of flying such as lift off, in flight maneuvers such as loops and back flips, as well as landings. The game also offers a dynamic two player mode, enabling to fight side by side.    The gameplay has you controlling a fighter airplane in many missions and battles that take place during pivotal points during WWII. You go on bombing runs, recon missions, and dogfights with other squadrons. Your squad consists of a excellent airplane mechanic named Joe, if your plane in on the verge of failing, you can summon Joe, and he prompts you with a sequence of buttons that can be used once and if hit sequentially, repairs your plane. Your other teamate, Tom who can be used to draw enemies toward him, and away from the player. The last squad members name is Frank. Frank can be used to eliminate enemy fighters. The last mission of the game has you pitted against a squad of elite german aces flying experimental jet planes. You fight the squad and when the battle ends, they shoot down Joe, killing him, and shoot down Tom which nearly kills him.   An interesting PS3 exclusive feature, is that the sixaxis controller can be used to pilot the planes using the motion senstive feature.BattlesOperation Dynamo One of the largest evacuation missions in World War II. As the forces of Germany were invading France, they cut off British, French and Belgian Forces, basically trapping them against the Atlantic coast, forcing them to a small strip of land in Dunkirk. With over 900 ships more than 340,00 troops were evacuated. Interestingly enough, part of those 900 ships were not war ships, but private ones such as fishing boats. The whole operation was completed under heavy attack from the German Luftwaffe. In this battle the Royal Air Force lost 177 planes, while the Luftwaffe lost 132 . The Battle of BritainFor Germany to invade Britain, they needed to get air superiority over the British Channel and the southeast coast. For this to be accomplished the RAF needed to be destroyed, which is what Germany tried to do with the Battle of Britain. In this battle, Germany had three times as much planes as Britain (ca. 2,600 to 700). The battle started by by the attacking of shipping convoys , and later on by planning to destroy the aircraft of Fighter Command. Later on Germany used what is referred to as "the Blitz". In total, the RAF lost around 1,600 vs. 1,900 planes lost by the Luftwaffe. Pearl HarborJapanese Planes attack the Pacific Fleet of the US Navy in Peaarl Harbor in Hawaii. The result of the attack cost more than 2400 people their lives. This attack was which largely shifted public opinion against Japan. It is important to note that the attack was not as successful as planned, since some of the targets were not present at the time. Battle of MidwayHappened about six months after Pearl Harbor. It was a Japanese Plan to surprise a US base in Midway on attack, to then later set up a Japanese air base. The US intervened this though, and set up a trap. Even though the US was inferior in numbers, they won the battle against the Japanese, making them lose four full carriers, while only losing one themselves. RabaulLiberation of ParisThe End of the War in Berlin  System Requirements Supported OS: Windows® XP (only)Processor: 1 GHz Pentium® IV or AMD Athlon™ processor (3 GHz Pentium IV or AMD Athlon or better recommended)Memory: 256 MB (1 GB recommended)Graphics: 64 MB DirectX® 9.0c compliant (256 MB recommended) (see supported list*)DirectX Version: DirectX 9.0cSound: Direct X 9.0c compliant sound cardHard Drive: 6 GBMultiplayer: 64 Kbps upstream broadband internet connection or fasterPeripherals: Windows-compliant mouse, keyboard, joysticks, gamepad*Video cards supported at time of release: ATI® Radeon® 8000/9000/X series, NVIDIA® GeForce® 3/4/FX/6/7 Series (GeForce 4 MX NOT supported)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="24">Flight Simulator</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13712">Blazing Angels: Squadrons of WWII</game><game id="384">Aces of the Pacific</game><game id="12047">IL-2 Sturmovik</game><game id="12911">Crimson Skies: High Road to Revenge</game><game id="8847">Red Baron II</game><game id="19216">Blazing Angels 2: Secret Missions of WWII</game><game id="9503">Project Sylpheed: Arc of Deception</game><game id="24417">Snoopy Flying Ace</game><game id="20968">Heroes Over Europe</game><game id="24983">Stormbirds</game><game id="24986">Propeller Arena</game><game id="11171">Secret Weapons Over Normandy</game><game id="20722">Il-2 Sturmovik: Birds of Prey</game><game id="4075">Wing Arms</game><game id="32089">Apache: Air Assault</game><game id="31188">Tom Clancy's H.A.W.X. 2</game><game id="38609">Dogfight 1942</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1795420-box_blazangl.png</image></root>