<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13745</id><name>R-Type</name><description>Overview R-Type is a classic side scrolling shoot-em up game produced by Irem Corp. The game was first released to Japanese arcades in July 1987.  The player controls a spacecraft and is tasked with defending humanity against the alien life forms known as Bydo.  R-Type is infamously known for its extreme difficulty.  Description for the game from the Irem Corp. official website:  Enter the Bydo Empire; a world where hatred and slaughter are the norm. Here, grotesque creatures that strike fear into the center of our souls, subsist and wait. Now, a very transcendental battle is about to begin as we seek to mercilessly destroy these monsters. GameplaySet in the 22nd century, the game takes place in the Bydo Empire.  The player must make their way through the 8 merciless levels and defend mankind from the evil attackers.   Bydo The Bydo are biologically engineered weapons created by mankind to be used against their enemies in their quest for universal domination.  This plan backfired however and the Bydo began to attack their creators.      Dobkeratops - Boss of the first level   The Ship  The player pilots a ship called the R-9a "Arrowhead".  The ship is named for its distinctive shape and is the 9th model of the R series of star fighter.      The Force The R-9a "Arrowhead" can be  equipped with an indestructible living weapon called "The Force".  The force, a spherical pod that can be attached to the ship, is made of Bydo flesh and can absorb energy in order to increase in power.  To obtain the force, the player must obtain a weapon power up.   The force will appear behind the players ship and they can obtain the force by flying into it.  The force acts as the ships weapon system and will fire in the whatever direction it is facing.  The force also acts as a shield and can be used to block incoming enemy attacks.   The force has three levels of power. Collecting weapon power ups increases the power level of the force. The forces visual appearance changes as it increases in power. Red - A powerful counter-air laser beam that fires horizontally.Blue - Three thin laser beams. One forward firing and two that fire at a 45 degree angle from the front of the ship     These beams rebound off walls.Yellow - Two flame beams that fire above and below the ship.  These flames can travel along the ground or   walls to destroy enemies.  The force can be controlled by the user by using the force button.   By pressing the force button, the user can attach the force to the front or the rear of the ship.  They can also propel the force forward to execute an attack called the "force ram".  Wave Cannon   The R9-a is equipped with a beam weapon called the wave cannon.  Holding the fire button will charge up the wave cannon and increase its power.  Wave Cannon         </description><genres><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16253">Raptor: Call of the Shadows</game><game id="13960">Life Force</game><game id="15508">Gradius</game><game id="16495">Einhänder</game><game id="119">Söldner-X: Himmelsstürmer</game><game id="21799">Blazing Star</game><game id="11627">Lightening Force: Quest for the Darkstar</game><game id="4709">Hyper Dyne: Side Arms</game><game id="12069">Ikaruga</game><game id="4900">Gaiares</game><game id="12266">Arrow Flash</game><game id="3623">Gradius II</game><game id="2685">Sol-Feace</game><game id="810">Parodius</game><game id="7865">Wings of Wor</game><game id="12192">Axelay</game><game id="3205">Project-X</game><game id="11556">Andro Dunos</game><game id="16079">Stinger</game><game id="13714">Last Resort</game><game id="5273">The Last Starfighter</game><game id="18465">Zombie Nation</game><game id="4252">Last Hope</game><game id="17782">Xenon 2: Megablast</game><game id="14539">Astro Warrior</game><game id="20869">Blast Works: Build, Trade, Destroy</game><game id="3838">Space Megaforce</game><game id="22600">Homura</game><game id="15077">Z-Out</game><game id="4106">Slayer</game><game id="23462">Gradius Gaiden</game><game id="11071">X-Out</game><game id="20364">Zero Wing</game><game id="12471">Thunder Force II</game><game id="4459">Armalyte</game><game id="6010">Hellfire</game><game id="3802">Blood Money</game><game id="13861">Whip Rush</game><game id="18464">Dragon Breed</game><game id="25183">Escape</game><game id="4394">Zanac</game><game id="18519">Phalanx</game><game id="25326">Underwater Attack</game><game id="25402">RayXanbeR</game><game id="2763">Frenetic</game><game id="23658">Gradius ReBirth</game><game id="27999">Apidya</game><game id="7778">Pulstar</game><game id="22347">Thunder Force VI</game><game id="28016">Nemesis</game><game id="29870">zeit²</game><game id="309">Sqoon</game><game id="30594">Aldynes</game><game id="30856">Dorapan</game><game id="7102">Operation Spacehog</game><game id="15881">Jets'n'Guns</game><game id="28233">Progear</game><game id="31302">Gigablast</game><game id="3512">Zybex</game><game id="6085">Laser Hawk</game><game id="31573">DOVEZ</game><game id="28120">Söldner-X 2: Final Prototype</game><game id="31643">Hydorah</game><game id="19398">Katakis</game><game id="30183">Shoot 1UP</game><game id="32664">Star Crisis</game><game id="32798">A Shooter</game><game id="20222">Soldier Blade</game><game id="6909">Gates of Zendocon</game><game id="17225">Ziriax</game><game id="32392">Who's That Flying?!</game><game id="14706">Sinistron</game><game id="35567">PixelJunk SideScroller</game><game id="21828">Shooter: Space Shot</game><game id="37433">Sirius 7</game><game id="5164">Advanced Busterhawk Gleylancer</game><game id="39433">Star Beast</game><game id="8092">Starship Hector</game><game id="34857">StreetPass Mii Plaza</game><game id="18246">Firewind</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/7/73970/1253970-rtype_amiga_front.jpg</image></root>