<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1374</id><name>R.C. Pro-Am</name><description>R.C. Pro-Am in a 1988 racing game developed by Rare and published by Nintendo. In the game the player is not driving cars, but rather controlling radio-controlled vehicles. The game is played from an isometric perspective, giving the game a pseudo 3Dlook. The player can only see a small section of the track around them. There is also a minimap at the bottom of the screen showing the entire course and locations of all of the cars. The player can also use weapons to temporarily disable the other cars so that the player can pass them. R.C. Pro-Am was actually the first racing game to have sections of track that give the player a speed boost, rather than speed power ups that are collected. There are also numerous hazards scattered through out the tracks that can slow the player down.The game was followed by Super R.C. Pro-Am for the Game Boy in 1991.HazardsOil Slick - When driven over, these make the cars spin out and lose control. Water Puddle - When driven over, these make the cars slow down. Rain Cloud - Follows a set path across the track and slows down the cars that drive through it. Pop-Up Wall - Pops up from the road and causes the player to crash.  Weapons and ItemsMissiles -Used to shoot opponents ahead of the player. Bombs - Used to blow up opponents behind the player. Roll Cage - This can be used as both a shield and a weapon. Skulls  -These decrease the player's ammunition stockpile by 1 unit. Stars - These increase the player's ammunition stockpile by 1 unit.  </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18026">Rock 'n Roll Racing</game><game id="11631">Galaxy 5000</game><game id="6017">Super Cars</game><game id="5037">Re-Volt</game><game id="22893">Team Losi RC Racer</game><game id="9017">Mad Max</game><game id="18963">Thrash Rally</game><game id="25627">Smash Cars</game><game id="9303">Moto Roader</game><game id="28346">Mini Yonku Let's &amp; Go!!: Power WGP 2</game><game id="35953">Battle Grand Prix</game><game id="36378">Armada F/X Racers</game><game id="36938">MotorStorm RC</game><game id="40565">Motocross Champion</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/7465/783217-587546_46971_front.jpg</image></root>