<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13753</id><name>Dead or Alive Ultimate</name><description>OverviewDead or Alive: Ultimate is a 3D fighting game compilation developed by Team Ninja released in October 2004 for the Xbox. It contains the Sega Saturn version of Dead or Alive under the name "Dead or Alive 1 Ultimate." It added online support added but lacked the vast additions that the Playstation version of Dead or Alive contained. In addition, it also came with a visually remastered version of Dead or Alive 2 under the name "Dead or Alive 2 Ultimate." Along with a visual upgrade, it added a significant amount of unlockable costumes, new stages, the addition of Hitomi as a playable character and online support for up to 8 players.GameplayDead or Alive is a 3D fighting game where players can participate in 1v1 fights, or engage in tag team fights up to four players. Players can move their characters in a 3D-axis As per usual in a fighting game, the goal is to drain the vitality (life) bar of your opponent, resulting in a knockout. Alternately, the fighter with the most vitality upon a time out will be declared the winner.Dead or Alive 1 UltimateDead or Alive uses a four button control scheme, consisting of a punch button, kick button, grab button and hold button. The vast majority of moves assigned to each character can be performed simply by pressing the punch and/or kick buttons along with a direction on the directional pad or analog stick.A mechanic exclusive to the Dead or Alive series is the unique counter system. Using the hold button, players can counter attacks from their opponents not only to take no damage, but to punish their opponents with devastating counter-attacks.Hold + Back will counter a medium punchHold + Forward will counter a medium kickHold + Down Forward will counter a low strikeHold + Up Forward will counter a high strikeDead or Alive 1 Ultimate remains unchanged from its original form. A defining feature of the original Dead or Alive is the Danger Zone. When an opponent is hit into the Danger Zone, the ground explodes upon impact, resulting in a larger bounce and additional damage.Additions  ChangesWhile Dead or Alive 1 Ultimate remains unchanged, Dead or Alive 2 Ultimate contains many significant changes from its previous iterations. These changes include:Dead or Alive 2 Ultimate sported a visual upgradeDead or Alive 2 Ultimate sported a visual overhaulA significant visual upgrade, utilizing the engine used to power Dead or Alive Xtreme Beach Volleyball. DOAU2 resembles Dead or Alive 3 more than it does previous DOA2 iterations.Online support over Xbox Live. Up to 8 players can battle in lobbies in varied game modes including Winner Stays and Tournament modes.A new opening CG movie, expanding the story between Ayane, Kasumi and Hayate.More costumes for each characters, with an emphasis on the female roster.Changes to the counter system. The parry system is now more complex, as there are now separate inputs to counter medium kicks and medium punches.New stages, in addition to remastered stages from Dead or Alive 2.New grabs for each character. There are now specific grabs when a player grabs their opponent near a slope or staircase.The addition of Hitomi from Dead or Alive 3 as a playable character.Other changes include an increase in damage for counters and environmental hazards not resulting in knockouts.Character RosterAyaneStyle: NinjutsuOccupation: NinjaAge: 16Bass ArmstrongStyle: WrestlingOccupation: Pro WrestlerAge: 46BaymanStyle: SamboOccupation: AssassinAge: 31EinStyle: KarateOccupation: Karate InstructorAge: 23Gen FuStyle: Xinyi Liuhe QuanOccupation: Book Store OwnerAge: 65Helena DouglasStyle: Pi Qua QuanOccupation: Opera SingerAge: 21HitomiStyle: KarateOccupation: College StudentAge: 19Jann LeeStyle: Jeet Kune DoOccupation: BouncerAge: 20KasumiStyle: NinjutsuOccupation: Runaway ShinobiAge: 17Lei FangStyle: Tai Chi QuanOccupation: College StudentAge: 19Ryu HayabusaStyle: NinjutsuOccupation: Curio Shop OwnerAge: 23Tina ArmstrongStyle: Pro WrestlingOccupation: Pro WrestlerAge: 22ZackStyle: Muay ThaiOccupation: DJAge: 25</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21375">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja 3</game><game id="20678">Soulcalibur IV</game><game id="3744">Def Jam: Fight for NY</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="11065">Shaman King: Power of Spirit</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="16842">Street Fighter: Anniversary Collection</game><game id="10989">Street Fighter EX3</game><game id="20736">Street Fighter EX2</game><game id="20734">Street Fighter EX</game><game id="11370">Street Fighter EX2 Plus</game><game id="12518">Street Fighter EX Plus Alpha</game><game id="20735">Street Fighter EX Plus</game><game id="20456">Street Fighter IV</game><game id="8161">Street Fighter II Turbo: Hyper Fighting</game><game id="8680">Street Fighter Alpha 3 MAX</game><game id="1328">Street Fighter Alpha 3</game><game id="1615">Street Fighter III: 3rd Strike</game><game id="22305">Street Fighter III: 2nd Impact</game><game id="9309">Marvel Super Heroes Vs. Street Fighter</game><game id="21948">Street Fighter III: New Generation</game><game id="11156">X-Men vs. Street Fighter</game><game id="1235">Street Fighter</game><game id="243">Street Fighter II: The World Warrior</game><game id="20689">Tekken 6</game><game id="18753">Tekken 5</game><game id="11606">Tekken: Dark Resurrection</game><game id="11189">Tekken 3</game><game id="10081">Tekken</game><game id="10162">Tekken Tag Tournament</game><game id="14684">Tekken 4</game><game id="10387">Tekken 2</game><game id="12411">Soulcalibur</game><game id="9855">Soulcalibur III</game><game id="11822">Soulcalibur II</game><game id="11945">Soulcalibur Legends</game><game id="707">Virtua Fighter 5</game><game id="41">Virtua Fighter 2</game><game id="19766">Virtua Fighter 3</game><game id="15584">Virtua Fighter</game><game id="4313">Virtua Fighter 4</game><game id="4891">Virtua Fighter 4: Evolution</game><game id="20449">Mortal Kombat vs. DC Universe</game><game id="2178">Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3</game><game id="1434">Mortal Kombat 3</game><game id="11843">Mortal Kombat: Armageddon</game><game id="8279">Mortal Kombat Trilogy</game><game id="6588">Mortal Kombat: Deadly Alliance</game><game id="383">Mortal Kombat: Deception</game><game id="4652">Mortal Kombat Gold</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="23833">Tekken 6: Bloodline Rebellion</game><game id="21277">Ultimate Mortal Kombat</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1894015-box_doau.png</image></root>