<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13787</id><name>Jet Moto 2</name><description>OverviewPlayers ride through hellfire in NebulousThe sequel to the original hit     Jet Moto was as much of an improvement as its fans had hoped it would be.  A reduction in the amount of team riders was not a big loss and was compensated with 10 completely new and imaginative courses as well as the entire track lineup from the first game.  The new tracks were longer, harder, and much more of a spectacle than those in the original, and as a result the game was received well by fans and critics alike.CoursesA flowing river pushes players downstream in HotshotThe original Jet Moto seemed like a relatively low budget game due to the fact that the developers had re-used the same assets to create the different courses, meaning players would see the same tree sprites and snow textures and freeway debris in as many as three courses each.  For the sequel, each course was made to feel unique by having a dedicated theme that made each course stand out from the rest and make it memorable.  Assets seemed to be recycled much less frequently which helped to make the game feel like a more complete package.The difficulty was also ramped up considerably in some of the later courses, and many would argue that this was an unnecessary improvement over the original game (which was very difficult in its own right).      Suicide Tracks also made an appearance in the sequel and, making it a franchise tradition, a truly hellish final course was also included.The new courses, in order of ascending difficulty, are as follows:Slickrock GorgeSlickrock Gorge course layoutMeltdownMeltdown course layoutAftershockAftershock course layoutArctic BlastArctic Blast course layoutHot ShotHot Shot course layoutThe ShaftThe Shaft course layoutRollercideRollercide course layoutKa-Ma-TeKa-Ma-Te course layoutMach SchnellMach Schnell course layoutNebulous Nebulous course layout   Teams and RidersOne of the only features to be scaled back from the original game is the number of team riders.  Some characters make a return and some new ones make an appearance for the first time, making a total of 11 riders for players to choose from (one of which being an   unlockable).  In addition, players could no longer filter their choices by selecting a team and then deciding on a rider within that team, rather the new selection process was a simple linear jumble of all the available riders in no apparent order.Some examples of the riders from each of the five teams:Team Atlantic Technology Li'l Dave   Team AxiomTechnician Team DragonVampeera Team Jet Ski Wild Ride Team Mountain DewBomber        PlayStation Network The game is available on the American PlayStation Store for $5.99 </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10145">Rocket Jockey</game><game id="20451">MotorStorm: Pacific Rift</game><game id="8949">S.T.U.N. Runner</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/13158/959068-gb.png</image></root>