<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1386</id><name>Pro Evolution Soccer</name><description>OverviewPro Evolution Soccer is a soccer simulation developed by Konami Computer Entertainment Tokyo and published by Konami. It is the first game in the popular Pro Evolution Soccer franchise. The game is seen as a spiritual successor to the International Superstar Soccer series of soccer games, and in fact it was made by the same team of developers headed by Shingo "Seabass" Takatsuka. The game attempts to authentically recreate the sport of soccer in video game format, and offers several different gameplay modes to the player. The game was originally released in 2001 and received a number of positive reviews, holding an average rating of 93 on Metacritic. The game is known as Winning Eleven 5 in Japan and World Soccer Winning Eleven 5 in the United States.Licensing The Pro Evolution Soccer franchise is renowned for lacking complete team, player and stadium licensing when compared to EA Sports' FIFA series. The first game is no exception, lacking licensed teams and stadia, instead opting for sound-alike alternatives in many cases. The game does, however, feature FIFpro licensing, resulting in a significant proportion of player names (although by no means all) being correctly portrayed in-game.List of teams in Pro Evolution SoccerPro Evolution Soccer features fifty-three international teams and thirty-two club teams, all of which are playable in most of the game's modes (it may be noted that international squads cannot be used in the game's Master League mode). What follows is a comprehensive list of all teams in the game.International TeamsEuropeIrelandNorthern IrelandScotlandWalesEnglandPortugalSpainFranceBelgiumNetherlandsSwitzerlandItalyCzechGermanyDenmarkNorwaySwedenFinlandPolandSlovakiaAustriaHungarySloveniaCroatiaYugoslaviaRomaniaBulgariaGreeceTurkeyUkraineRussiaAfricaMoroccoTunisiaEgyptNigeriaCameroonSouth AfricaThe AmericasUnited StatesMexicoJamaicaColombiaBrazilPeruChileParaguayUruguayArgentinaAsia and OceaniaJapanKoreaChinaIranSaudi ArabiaAustraliaClub TeamsEnglandManchester (Manchester United)London (Arsenal)Chelsea (Chelsea)Liverpool (Liverpool)Leeds (Leeds United)Westham (West Ham United)Newcastle (Newcastle United)SpainBarcelonaMadridValenciaLa CorunaFranceMonacoMarseilleParisBordeauxNetherlandsAmsterdamRotterdamEindhovenItalyInternationalPiemonteMilanoLazioParmaFirenzeRomaGermanyDortmundMunchenLeverkusenBrazilRio De JaneiroPalestoraArgentinaLa PlataBuenos Aires</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="40">Soccer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19086">Total Club Manager 2004</game><game id="1586">Total Club Manager 2003</game><game id="15714">Total Club Manager 2005</game><game id="14647">FIFA 2001</game><game id="21030">FIFA Soccer 09</game><game id="19350">FIFA Soccer 08</game><game id="9171">FIFA Soccer 06</game><game id="9983">Club Football</game><game id="9188">Club Football 2005</game><game id="2629">UEFA Euro 2000</game><game id="33257">ESPN MLS ExtraTime</game><game id="34856">FIFA 12</game><game id="38858">Virtua Pro Football</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/19490/745831-pro_evolution_soccer.jpg</image></root>