<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13964</id><name>Ys: Book I &amp; II</name><description>OverviewYs Book I and II is a compilation of the games Ys: Ancient Ys Vanished and Ys II: Ancient Ys Vanished - The Final Chapter. It was one of the first video games to use CD-ROM, which was utilized to provide enhancements such as improved graphics, a longer quest, a CD-quality Redbook audio soundtrack, cinematic anime cutscenes, and extensive voice acting throughout the game. The game's English localization was also one of the first to use voice dubbing. When it released in 1989, the game was regarded as a technical marvel, showcasing the possibilities of the CD-ROM format.StoryYs Book IYs Book IIGameplayThe gameplay was very simple. There was no "attack' button. The player would simply run into the enemies to slash them with his sword. The armor you wore, the level of your character, and the angle at which you attacked determined the success of your attack or not. Also, some enemies had a higher defense verses certain attacks and could only be defeated with certain items or magic.Differences From Prior ReleasesThe music in the TG16-CD release of the game is by far the biggest difference from prior releases. The rich sound of CD quality music was far and away better than anything the franchise had seen before. Of course, the graphics were updated a little and there was voice acting as well.Legacy</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10276">The Legend of Zelda: A Link to the Past</game><game id="12945">Lagoon</game><game id="19383">Legend of Xanadu II</game><game id="9970">Legend of Xanadu</game><game id="35873">The Lost Angelic Chronicles of Frane: Dragon's Odyssey</game><game id="37956">Xak I &amp; II</game><game id="9086">Cosmic Fantasy Stories</game><game id="39939">No-Ri-Ko</game><game id="2411">Sorcerian</game><game id="19597">Dragon Slayer: The Legend of Heroes</game><game id="23450">Tengai Makyou: Ziria</game><game id="42651">The Legend of Heroes I &amp; II: Eiyuu Densetsu</game><game id="39255">Gheldia</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2365594-tg16_ys1and2.jpg</image></root>