<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13986</id><name>Soul Blazer</name><description>OverviewSoul Blazer (Soul Blader in Japan) is an action adventure RPG developed by Quintet and published by Enix (which is now known as Square Enix). In PAL territories, it was published by Ubisoft. Soul Blazer was developed for the Super Nintendo Entertainment System and was released in Japan, America and in Europe. The player takes the role of an angel, who is sent by "The Master" to destroy the world's monsters and release the people from the captivity of Dark Gaia.There are eight levels to the game that follow various themes, such as Haunted House, Underwater and Forests.CharactersThe Hero (a.k.a. "Blazer") : The protagonist of the game who seeks to restore the world that was locked away by Deathtoll.The Master (a.k.a. "Gaia") :Guides the protagonist through the world via the Shrine, instructing him on occurring conflicts.Lisa :Dr. Leo's daughter, who gives the player her fathers old paint brush which allows entrance into Leo's Painting. She is later seen during Magrid Castle as a prisoner.Doctor Leo :The creator of the many inventions in the game, along with being Lisa's father. He was captured at the beginning of the game by King Magridd's soldiers to build a machine to contact Deathtoll. Afterward, he sacrifices to stop the Queen from killing his daughter.Village Chief :The chief of Grass Valley who was sealed in Leo's painting by Metal Mantis to prevent the collection of the brown stone.Guardian of the Forest :The overseer of Green Wood, imprisoned by Deathtoll sealing the green stone within the roots.Mermaid Queen :Ruler of the underwater city of Oceania - she guards over all aquatic forms in the sea.GEM Fairy :Helpful fairies that guide the player throughout the game. They are imprisoned in jewels, but if players get near one, they will appear and talk to them, providing helpful information and allowing the hero to teleport back to towns.Death Toll : The demon who imprisoned everyone in the world. Not much else is know about him other then the fact his intentions are evil.Critical ReceptionWhen released Electronic Gaming Monthly issued the following scores, 8,9,8,8 adding, "A great action/adventure cart that's loaded with great graphics and sounds and a long quest. The game is fast and the pace is just right if you need a little action with your role-playing. The quest is a little easier than I expected and can be solved in a few hours. Great music and visuals keep you coming back for more".</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1861">Dark Cloud</game><game id="9032">Star Ocean</game><game id="1296">Seiken Densetsu 3</game><game id="255">Tales of Phantasia</game><game id="16959">Alcahest</game><game id="394">Robotrek</game><game id="12945">Lagoon</game><game id="32085">Bastion</game><game id="14381">Ultima IV: Quest of the Avatar</game><game id="14722">Miracle Warriors: Seal of the Dark Lord</game><game id="18007">Spiritual Warfare</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2364764-snes_soulblazer.jpg</image></root>