<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14029</id><name>Homeworld: Cataclysm</name><description>OverviewDeveloped by Barking Dog Studios and published by Sierra on June 30, 2000, Homeworld: Cataclysm is the stand-alone expansion for Homeworld, Relic Entertainment's acclaimed 1999 deep-space real-time strategy game for the PC. Using the same graphics engine as its forebear, Cataclysm features two entirely new playable factions, a number of changes to gameplay mechanics, and a full seventeen-mission single-player campaign. This campaign centers on a conflict waged between the Kiith Somtaaw, a subset of the original game's Hiigarans, and the Beast, a bio-mechanical virus, some fifteen years after the events of the previous game. The new factions can both be used in multiplayer, which, like the previous game, features support for up to eight players as well as a skirmish mode that allows a human player to combat up to seven A.I. opponents. Much like Homeworld itself, Cataclysm was very well-received by critics.PlotThe plot of Cataclysm focuses on the actions of the Kiith Somtaaw, a somewhat disenfranchised group within the Hiigaran people. It is set roughly fifteen years after the Hiigarans retook their homeworld of Hiigara from the Taiidan Empire, a tumultuous journey that was depicted in the original game. As the campaign begins, the Kuun-Lan, a Somtaaw mining vessel, is called back to Hiigara to defend against an attack by Taiidani Imperialists. They are successful in helping their brethren repel the invaders, and shortly thereafter the Somtaaw are ordered to travel to the edge of Hiigaran space to assist the disabled Bushan-Re. Upon arriving within the ship's vicinity, the Kuun-Lan discovers Turanic Raiders, who now possess the secrets of mimicking technology. Despite the Turanic Raider's unexpected technological edge, the Somtaaw are able to successfully defend the Bushan-Re until its hyperdrive is repaired, gaining access to the Raiders' new mimic technology in the process.After retaking the Homeworld, the Kushan Mothership is converted into a stationary shipyard.With the Bushan-Re gone, the Kuun-Lan prepares to leave the system. Before it can, however, Fleet Intelligence informs it of a weak signal beacon being transmitted by something in the area. Despite the Turanic Raider's significant interest in the artifact, the Somtaaw are able to recover the derelict responsible for transmitting the signal before jumping out of the system intact. Though the Kuun-Lan finds that it is unable to properly examine the derelict, Somtaaw Command ultimately rejects the proposal to seek outside help, instead opting to rendezvous with the Somtaaw research ship Clee-San. Unfortunately, they arrive to find the Clee-San being held captive by Turanic Raiders, who hope to use it as a means to acquire Somtaaw technology. Using the Raiders' own mimic technology against them, the Somtaaw are able to rescue the Clee-San and jump to a safe distance before the arrival of a larger Turanic Fleet.The Kuun-Lan is forced to prematurely end its hyperspace jump, however, as the situation within the mining vessel turns unexpectedly dire. Parts of the ship begins to show signs of infection by an unknown virus, forcing the Kuun-Lan to detach its hangar and its science module to prevent its spread. As the Somtaaw begin to rebuild the Kuun-Lan, the Clee-San and a small escort detachment are sent out to examine the ejected modules, which are now covered with the same mysterious organic matter found on the recovered derelict. The Clee-San and its defenders are then attacked and infected as well, and the apparently sentient virus then turns these ships against the Kuun-Lan. The pursuing Turanic Raiders catch up to the Kuun-Lan at about this time hoping to recover the Clee-San, but, not believing the Somtaaw's warnings regarding the ship, they are infected as well, and the crew of the Kuun-Lan finds itself under even greater duress.Quickly gathering whatever information they can on this new threat, the Somtaaw retreat, and while in transit they decide to refer to this new bio-mechanical virus, which seems to turn flesh into sentient circuitry, as "the Beast." Now recognizing that they need help, the Somtaaw seek out the Bentusi, but find that they are already under attack by the Beast. The Kuun-Lan helps to defend the Bentusi tradeship until another party, the Manaani, arrives in response to the Bentusi's distress call. The tradeship eventually self-destructs rather than face assimilation, though the Somtaaw are able to save the Manaani carrier Caal-Shto. The Kuun-Lan and the Caal-Shto then attempt to escape the Beast through the Kadiir Nebula, though this brings with it additional complications, as the area is occupied by Taiidani Imperialists. Nonetheless, their make it through the nebula successfully, and the Caal-Shto promises to bring the matter of the Beast before the rest of Hiigara.Shortly thereafter, the crew of the Kuun-Lan becomes aware of a Cruise Missile weapon that inflicts an infection similar to the one seen on Beast ships. The Somtaaw are informed by Taiidani Republicans that this weapon was developed by Imperialists, which prompts the Kuun-Lan to look further into the matter. After setting up a meeting with a spy inside Imperial territory, further information comes to light indicating that the Cruise Missile was developed at Gozan IV. Before they can approach the planet, though, they are informed that the planet is protected by a planetary defense system, and that bypassing this system requires Imperial codes. The Somtaaw successfully capture a number of Imperial vessels and use them to gain access to Gozan IV. They learn that the Imperialist's attempts to weaponize the Beast virus were ultimately unsuccessful, though they are able to recover a means to halt the spread of the Beast virus before leaving for Koreth's Rift.Over the course of its journey, the Kuun-Lan incorporates a number of potent upgrades.Within Koreth's Rift the Somtaaw find an ancient Siege Cannon which they attempt to incorporate into the Kuun-Lan. They are beset by Impirialist forces and Turanic Raiders, but the battle is interrupted by the arrival of the Caal-Shto, now infected by the Beast, and the Beast's Mothership, fashioned from the Kuun-Lan's discarded modules and other unknown parts. The Kuun-Lan fires its Seige Cannon at the Mothership, but to no avail. Retreating, the Somtaaw next seek out the Faal-Corum, whose crew promises to complete the Caal-Shto's original mission. Around this time it is discovered that the source of the derelict recovered by the Kuun-Lan is an alien ship called the Naggarok. Believing that the Naggarok may hold the key to defeating the Beast, the Somtaaw decide seek it out. This search leads them again into conflict with the Turanic Raiders and the Taiidani Imperialists, though this time they are saved by the Faal-Corum, whose crew has succeeded in warning the rest of Hiigara.Upon finding the Naggarok, the Somtaaw are alarmed to find that the Imperialists are repairing the infected vessel in hopes of reactivating it. After performing some quick reconnaissance on the Naggarok, the Kuun-Lan escapes to seek out the Bentusi, hoping once again that they might receive aid from them. They arrive in Bentusi space to find them fleeing in fear of the Beast, but after a brief skirmish the Somtaaw are able to convince them of the error of their ways. With the Bentusi's help, the Kuun-Lan's Siege Cannon is upgraded in order to cause damage to Beast ships. Using this weapon, the Kuun-Lan is able to destroy both the infected Clee-San and the Beast Mothership. Afterwards, the Somtaaw heads to a rendezvous point where Taiidani Republicans are building a weapon which they hope will be able to destroy both the Beast and the Taiidani Imperialists in one blow.When the Kuun-Lan arrives, however, they find the Taiidani Republicans nearly defeated, and the weapon known as the Nomad Moon already infected by the Beast. The Somtaaw manage to disable the Nomad Moon, which is in truth an immense repulsor field generator, but soon Imperialist and Beast reinforcements arrive along with the fully active Naggarok, which is capable of tearing ships apart with an extremely powerful Phased Disassembler Array. The Somtaaw are able to hold their ground until the Bentusi arrive, who grant them the means to construct Super Acolytes. Upon seeing the Bentusi, the Imperialists turn on the Beast, as it had apparently promised to destroy them. Without the aid of the Taiidani Imperialists, the remaining Beast forces and the Naggarok are soon destroyed by the Kuun-Lan and its new weaponry. When word of their accomplishmenst reaches the Hiigaran system, the once-marginalized Somtaaw are quickly heralded as the "Beast Slayer" clan.GameplaySee also: HomeworldWhile the basic mechanics of Homeworld are unaltered, Cataclysm makes a number of subtle and noticeable changes that, cumulatively, have a significant impact on gameplay. Among the most prominent of these changes is the introduction of two entirely new factions, the Kiith Somtaaw and the Beast, who entirely replace the Kushan and Taiidan player factions of the first game. Though the number of units possessed by these factions is in fact smaller than the number featured in the original game, in some cases the utility of multiple units has simply been assigned to a single ship. The Worker, for instance, can harvest, repair, and salvage, roles that in Homeworld were assigned to three different ships, and the Research Ships of the past are incorporated into the new Motherships as expansion modules. In fact, almost all ships in Cataclysm can be upgraded or combined with other ships in some way to give them even greater usefulness.The Sensors Manager and other interface elements receive refinements with the release of Cataclysm.Mechanically, the biggest change in Cataclysm is the introduction of Support Units. Whereas in Homeworld players were only limited to producing as many units as their resource reserves would allow, Cataclysm also requires the player to have enough Support Units to sustain the ship and its crew. The player can upgrade their Mothership and produce Carriers if they wish to increase the total number of Support Units they have, for if at any time the player reaches their current Support Units cap, further ships cannot be constructed. In general, sizable attack vessels like Super Capital class ships require an extremely large number of Support Units in order to be constructed, especially when compared to the requirements of smaller ships, which effectively limits the total number of heavy-hitting units that can be feasibly commissioned. The overall effect of this change is that fleets in Cataclysm tend to be considerably smaller than those found in Homeworld.Other more minor changes include the addition of a waypoint system and the implementation of a fog of war system that does not allow ships to see past their own sensor range (indicated by a blue sphere on the Sensors Manager). The option to issue attack orders from the Sensors Manager is also included, and a number of features are introduced seemingly for the express purpose of speeding up gameplay, including slipgates that allow instantaneous travel between two points and a time acceleration option during single-player. Cataclysm also offers detailed statistics on player ships by pressing the Tab key and displays any enemy's health bar when they are focused on, a feature that was absent from the first game. The campaign also features several difficulty settings, and a number of graphical enhancements and minor interface tweaks are introduced as well.Kiith Somtaaw ShipsThe Kiith Somtaaw are a faction of Hiigarans who eke out an existence as interstellar miners, and thus their equivalent of the Homeworld Mothership is the Kuun-Lan, an immense and self-sufficient mining vessel. They are the only selectable player faction during the single-player campaign, and one of two factions available during multiplayer. All of the various ship classes laid out in Homeworld are represented within the Somtaaw faction (and the Beast, for that matter), though Cataclysm also introduces the Microship class, which is reserved for only the smallest of vessels. Though their people are a subset of the original Kushan faction, none of the Somtaaw's ships are borrowed from them.Fighter ClassKiith Somtaaw ReconReconMass: 41 tonsCost: 40 RUs, 2 SUsBuild Time: 15 secondsFirepower: 40Armor: 25Coverage: 4%Maneuverability: Very HighMax. Velocity: 1,050 m/sSpecial Function: NoneRequired Tech: NoneUpgrade Tech: Advanced Sensors, Advanced Fighter Drive, Energy Cannon, Armor Level 2With its impressive speed and extremely large detection radius, the Recon is a natural reconnaissance unit that can scout out enemy locations and resource deposits or simply keep vigil around the player's Mothership. It is a crucial unit for remaining informed about one's surroundings both in single-player and in multiplayer. Though it does have a weapon, it is not usually a good idea to engage enemies with a Recon unit, as its hull integrity and overall firepower are both extremely slight when compared to other vessels.Kiith Somtaaw AcolyteAcolyteMass: 90 tonsCost: 75 RUs, 2 SUsBuild Time: 12 secondsFirepower: 85Armor: 70Coverage: 6%Maneuverability: Very HighMax. Velocity: 825 m/sSpecial Function: Link, MissilesRequired Tech: Fighter DriveUpgrade Tech: Energy Cannon, Missile Tech, Linking Tech, Advanced Fighter Drive, Armor Level 2The Acolyte is a very well-rounded Fighter class ship, with good speed and exceptional firepower for its size. Its offensive capability can be bolstered even further by research into Missile Technology, which gives it greater utility against Frigate and Capital class vessels. Like all ships in its category, the Acolyte is frail, and therefore can't sustain many hits before being destroyed, however large groups of them can be effective against a wide variety of units, and once Linking Technology is researched, they can be combined into ACVs.Kiith Somtaaw MimicMimicMass: 55 tonsCost: 70 RUs, 2 SUsBuild Time: 15 secondsFirepower: NoneArmor: 20Coverage: NoneManeuverability: Very HighMax. Velocity: 750 m/sSpecial Function: Mimic, LinkRequired Tech: Fighter Drive, Mimic TechUpgrade Tech: Energy Cannon, Linking Tech, Quantum Explosive Charge, Advanced Fighter Drive, Armor Level 2Though it is an inexpensive scouting ship in the same vein as the Recon, the Mimic achieves its ends in a markedly different fashion. The technology behind the Mimic allows it to masquerade under the guise of small ships or objects such as Fighters, Corvettes, or even space debris. This enables it to be able to avoid immediate detection in a way that the Recon cannot, although, once spotted, the Mimic has no offensive option other than ramming into its opponent. The damage caused by this kamikaze attack can also be upgraded.Corvette ClassKiith Somtaaw ACVACVMass: 180 tonsCost: 150 RUs, 4 SUsBuild Time: 20 secondsFirepower: 170Armor: 140Coverage: 6%Maneuverability: HighMax. Velocity: 600 m/sSpecial Function: Unlink, EMPRequired Tech: Fighter Drive, Linking TechUpgrade Tech: Energy Cannon, EMP Weapon, Advanced Fighter Drive, Armor Level 2The ACV, or Acolyte Composite Vehicle, is one of the immediate results of research into Linking Technology. It is, in essence, two Acolytes fused into one, which grants it twice the armor and twice the firepower of a single of its constituent units. It can also gains the ability to deliver EMP blasts that disable the drive systems of nearby enemy ships. They can be created by combining two existing Acolytes or being commissioned specifically from a construction ship. In either case, ACVs can also be detached in order to form two Acolytes.Kiith Somtaaw MCVMCVMass: 110 tonsCost: 140 RUs, 4 SUsBuild Time: 26 secondsFirepower: NoneArmor: 40Coverage: NoneManeuverability: HighMax. Velocity: 550 m/sSpecial Function: Unlink, MimicRequired Tech: Fighter Drive, Holographic Emitter, Linking TechUpgrade Tech: Energy Cannon, Quantum Explosive Charge, Advanced Fighter Drive, Armor Level 2The Mimic Composite Vehicle (MCV) is to the Mimic what the ACV is to the Acolyte. Two linked Mimics are capable of impersonating much larger ships and objects, including Frigates and large space debris. In addition, by combining themselves the suicide attack of the Mimic becomes far more potent, making it possible to cripple and destroy larger ships with it. The attacking ships will naturally be lost, but if used well the damage caused can often more than compensate for the loss of the MCV itself.Frigate ClassKiith Somtaaw Ramming FrigateRamming FrigateMass: 12,900 tonsCost: 650 RUs, 10 SUsBuild Time: 1 minuteFirepower: 2,500Armor: 4,700Coverage: 6%Maneuverability: MediumMax. Velocity: 398 m/sSpecial Function: RamRequired Tech: AfterburnerUpgrade Tech: Advanced Ion Cannon, Repair Bots, Infection Vaccine, Armor Level 2, Armor Level 3While somewhat unimpressive from the perspective of raw firepower, the Ramming Frigate serves a special purpose in battle that sets it apart from other vessels. When directed, it is able to ram into other ships, immobilizing them and even pushing them in a different direction. This can be useful in a number of ways, not least of which is its ability to give smaller craft greater freedom in how they attack. The Ramming Frigate is capable of pushing a target for thirty seconds at a time, with a ten second downtime required between uses.Kiith Somtaaw Multi-Beam FrigateMulti-Beam FrigateMass: 10,200 tonsCost: 700 RUs, 12 RUsBuild Time: 1 minuteFirepower: 3,900Armor: 4,000Coverage: 90%Maneuverability: MediumMax. Velocity: 370 m/sSpecial Function: NoneRequired Tech: Frigate Drive, Advanced Ion CannonUpgrade Tech: Energy Cannon, Repair Bots, Advanced Frigate Drive, Armor Level 2, Armor Level 3The Multi-Beam Frigate is akin to the Ion Cannon Frigates of the original game, albeit with a much larger coverage area. Whereas the Ion Cannon Frigates of the past were hard-pressed to hit anything outside of the small cone directly in front of them, the Multi-Beam Frigate is able to target enemies much more freely, making it significantly more useful against smaller Fighter and Corvette ships than its predecessor while still retaining the inherent strengths against Frigates and Capital ships that its Ion Cannons are known for.Kiith Somtaaw Hive FrigateHive FrigateMass: 9,900 tonsCost: 575 RUs, 20 SUsBuild Time: 1 minutesFirepower: 1,400Armor: 3,800Coverage: 12%Maneuverability: MediumMax. Velocity: 390 m/sSpecial Function: SwarmRequired Tech: Frigate Drive, Microship ConstructionUpgrade Tech: Energy Cannon, Repair Bots, Advanced Frigate Drive, Armor Level 2, Armor Level 3The Hive Frigate is most comparable to the Kushan Drone Frigate of Homeworld, as its primary feature is a full complement of automated drone fighters that can be released at any time. Unlike the Kushan's earlier design, the Hive Frigate's Swarmers are fully self-sufficient insofar as they are not controlled by technology housed on the frigate itself. This allows the drones a far greater degree of flexibility in their deployment, as they can move and attack freely rather than being restricted to operating within a fixed distance of the ship.Super Capital ClassKiith Somtaaw DestroyerDestroyerMass: 28,000 tonsCost: 3,000 RUs, 38 SUsBuild Time: 1 minute, 50 secondsFirepower: 8,500Armor: 16,000Coverage: 30%Maneuverability: LowMax. Velocity: 325 m/sSpecial Function: NoneRequired Tech: Destroyer Drive, Missile Launcher, Advanced Ion CannonUpgrade Tech: Energy Cannon, Advanced Destroyer Drive, Repair Bots, Armor Level 2, Armor Level 3The second-largest attack craft available to the Kiith Somtaaw, the Destroyer is an immense Capital ship equipped to handle most any type of resistance that comes its way. This includes massive turret-mounted guns, Ion Cannons, and even anti-Strike missile launchers. Its only real weakness is the fact that all of these weapons are designed to fire toward the ship's front side. Enemies that are able to maneuver around to the backside of the Destroyer will find that it is surprisingly vulnerable to attacks from this direction.Kiith Somtaaw DreadnoughtDreadnoughtMass: 152,000 tonsCost: 6,800 RUs, 80 SUsBuild Time: 5 minutesFirepower: 24,000Armor: 85,000Coverage: 80%Maneuverability: Very LowMax. Velocity: 390 m/sSpecial Function: RepulseRequired Tech: Advanced Destroyer Drive, Missile Launcher, Energy Cannon, Advanced Ion CannonUpgrade Tech: Repulsor Weapon, Repair Bots, Armor Level 2, Armor Level 3Though a colossal expenditure to be certain, the Dreadnought is easily the deadliest Capital class ship in the game, with near-unfathomable firepower and no glaring weaknesses to speak of. It seemingly has a gun for every occasion, and can make short work of Strike ships, Frigates, and Capital class vessels alike. It also has immunity to Beast infection just like all ships in its category. In the unlikely even that it is truly threatened, it can activate a special repulsor weapon that repels and damages all ships smaller than itself.Kiith Somtaaw CarrierCarrierMass: 129,000 tonsCost: 3,400 RUs, 0 SUsBuild Time: 4 minutes, 40 secondsFirepower: 4,200Armor: 65,000Coverage: 80%Maneuverability: Very LowMax. Velocity: 300 m/sSpecial Function: NoneRequired Tech: Destroyer Drive, Support SystemsUpgrade Tech: Energy Cannon, Crystal Harvesting Ability, Repair Bots, Advanced Destroyer Drive, Armor Level 2, Armor Level 3The Kiith Somtaaw's version of the Carrier, like those featured in Homeworld, operates as a miniature version of the Mothership. It requires no Support Units in order to build, and in fact it can be upgraded in a number of respects just like the Kuun-Lan. Any ship type up to and including Frigate class can be built from a Carrier, and it can also act as a drop point for Workers and a dock for Strike ships. It has very little in the way of offense though, so it is best kept away from the front lines whenever possible.Microship ClassKiith Somtaaw LeechLeechMass: 26 tonsCost: 40 RUs, 2 SUsBuild Time: 10 secondsFirepower: NoneArmor: 30Coverage: NoneManeuverability: Very HighMax. Velocity: 1,250 m/sSpecial Function: LeechRequired Tech: Microship Construction, Phased TelemetryUpgrade Tech: Armor Level 2The Leech is a small automated drone ship that is designed to attach itself to an enemy vessel without being noticed. Once there, it can perform a number of beneficial functions for its creator. First and foremost, the Leech can cause damage to the ship over time, weakening it without the commitment of major resources. It can also be used to continuously broadcast the location of the ship it is attached to. Lastly, it can convert the damage it has done into resources if it docks with a a resource-collection vessel afterwards.Kiith Somtaaw SentinelSentinelMass: 21 tonsCost: 70 RUs, 3 SUsBuild Time: 20 secondsFirepower: 290Armor: 350Coverage: 15%Maneuverability: HighMax. Velocity: 250 m/sSpecial Function: ShieldRequired Tech: Microship ConstructionUpgrade Tech: Energy Cannon, Force Field Level 1, Force Field Level 2, Force Field Level 3, Advanced Sensors, Armor Level 2, Armor Level 3The diminutive Sentinel is the smallest manned vessel in the Somtaaw fleet, and has the somewhat unspectacular role of being a protective escort for other, larger ships. When activated, the Sentinel can project an energy shield capable of deflecting enemy fire, and this effect can be further strengthened by the presence of additional Sentinels. The applications of this technology should be readily apparent, as high-value targets such as resource gatherers and the Mothership can be given an extra barrier against attack.Mothership ClassKiith Somtaaw Mining VesselMining VesselMass: 613,000 tonsCost: 8,000 RUs, 0 SUsBuild Time: 16 minutes, 40 secondsFirepower: 5,400Armor: 98,000Coverage: 70%Maneuverability: Very LowMax. Velocity: 110 m/sSpecial Function: Siege CannonRequired Tech: NoneUpgrade Tech: Energy Cannon, Crystal Harvesting Ability, Repair Bots, Siege Cannon Weapon, Support Systems, Armor Level 2, Armor Level 3The Kiith Somtaaw's Mothership equivalent, the Mining Vessel Kuun-Lan is a large, modular Capital class ship that can accommodate a large number of expansions and addenda. It is the primary construction vessel available to Somtaaw players, capable of producing any other ship whose research requirements have been met, and it can also be fearsome in combat once the Siege Cannon has been researched. It serves many other duties as well, including housing Strike ships, repairing allied units, and receiving resources from Workers.Non-Combat ClassKiith Somtaaw WorkerWorkerMass: 5,200 tonsCost: 500 RUs, 4 SUsBuild Time: 45 secondsFirepower: NoneArmor: 1,500Coverage: NoneManeuverability: MediumMax. Velocity: 425 m/sSpecial Function: Harvest, Repair, SalvageRequired Tech: NoneUpgrade Tech: Infection Vaccine, Repair Systems, Salvaging Ability, Repair Bots, Armor Level 2While it may appear at first a simple cosmetic replacement for Homeworld's Resource Collector, the Worker is in fact a far more versatile unit. Though its primary duty is still to gather and deliver resources that exist within its immediate surroundings, with the right upgrades it is capable of carrying out other tasks as well. This includes the ability to salvage enemy ships and repair allies that have sustained damage. In multiplayer, it can also be used to reverse the infection process inflicted by Beast players and return units to the player.Kiith Somtaaw ProcessorProcessorMass: 89,000 tonsCost: 1,100 RUs, 13 SUsBuild Time: 1 minute, 50 secondsFirepower: 2,500Armor: 45,000Coverage: 80%Maneuverability: LowMax. Velocity: 250 m/sSpecial Function: NoneRequired Tech: Hangar ModuleUpgrade Tech: Crystal Harvesting Ability, Energy Cannon, Repair Systems, Repair Bots, Armor Level 2Cataclysm's incarnation of the Resource Controller, the Processor is a mobile drop-off point that facilitates faster resource gathering by reducing the distance that Workers must travel to deliver their payload. Sending a Processor to a distant resource field is almost always preferable to having Workers trek back and forth to the Mothership. As a secondary role, it can also repair ships once it has been fully upgraded to do so. It is able to defend itself against small Strike ships, though not much else, so an escort is at times necessary.Beast ShipsAs the main antagonists throughout Cataclysm's campaign mode, the Beast faction is only playable during multiplayer matches. With only a couple exceptions, all of their units are assimilated forms of preexisting Taiidani, Hiigaran, or Turanic ships. In most cases the utility of these units is unaltered, though Beast units are generally tougher, slower, and more expensive than the units they are based on. All Beast units also have the ability to regenerate health, albeit slowly. Perhaps the most striking attribute of the Beast faction is its ability to infect enemy ships and take control of them. Several Beast vessels incorporate weaponry specifically meant to convert hostile ships to their side, and the Beast also has the option to consume and repurpose enemy technology for its own ends.Fighter ClassBeast ReconReconMass: 41 tonsCost: 50 RUs, 2 SUsBuild Time: 18 secondsFirepower: 40Armor: 30Coverage: 4%Maneuverability: Very HighMax. Velocity: 1,000 m/sSpecial Function: NoneRequired Tech: NoneUpgrade Tech: Energy Cannon, Advanced Sensors, Advanced Fighter Drive, Armor Level 2The Beast Recon does not differ overmuch from the Somtaaw's version of the unit. It is somewhat slower, though still fast enough to outpace almost every other unit in the game. It is also ever so slightly sturdier, a difference which is somewhat hard to notice in practice. Despite the slight statistical differences between it and its Somtaaw counterpart, its purpose remains the same. It is a unit intended for non-confrontational reconnaissance duty.Beast InterceptorInterceptorMass: 90 tonsCost: 65 RUs, 2 SUsBuild Time: 14 secondsFirepower: 65Armor: 85Coverage: 5%Maneuverability: Very HighMax. Velocity: 810 m/sSpecial Function: NoneRequired Tech: Fighter DriveUpgrade Tech: Energy Cannon, Advanced Fighter Drive, Armor Level 2As an assimilation of the Turanic Raider's Interceptor, the Beast Interceptor is undoubtedly a step above the Recon in terms of offensive potential, though a small step below the Somtaaw's workhorse Fighter unit, the Acolyte. Due to their position as perhaps the weakest offensive unit in the game, Interceptors are best produced en masse if they are to be produced at all, since smaller numbers of them aren't very threatening, and can be dispatched without much trouble by many larger Strike craft and Capital ships.Beast Cloaked FighterCloaked FighterMass: 90 tonsCost: 95 RUs, 2 SUsBuild Time: 22 SecondsFirepower: 75Armor: 80Coverage: 5%Maneuverability: Very HighMax. Velocity: 750 m/sSpecial Function: CloakRequired Tech: Fighter Drive, Cloaking AbilityUpgrade Tech: Advanced Fighter Drive, Energy Cannon, Armor Level 2The Beast's Cloaked Fighter is clearly a derivation of a similar model developed by the Kushan, and its application is exactly the same. In terms of firepower, speed, and durability, it is a respectable Fighter ship, though it differentiates itself from other ships through its ability to render itself undetectable to enemy sensors. This results in a number of deployment options that are unique to the Cloaked Fighter. It can, for instance, attack weak targets without being detected by escorts, or surround an attacking force without their knowledge.Beast Attack BomberAttack BomberMass: 60 tonsCost: 120 RUs, 3 RUsBuild Time: 25 secondsFirepower: 86Armor: 90Coverage: 5%Maneuverability: MediumMax. Velocity: 640 m/sSpecial Function: NoneRequired Tech: Fighter Drive, Plasma Bomb LauncherUpgrade Tech: Advanced Fighter Drive, Armor Level 2The Beast Attack Bomber (a subversion of the Taiidani Attack Bomber) is a unique Fighter ship that is not really intended for use against other ships in its class. Rather, it comes standard with slow-moving Plasma Bombs that are ideally suited for use against Frigates and other Capital ships. These bombs become something of a liability when used against Strike ships, though, as they do not move quickly enough to adequately track most Fighters and Corvettes.Beast AcolyteAcolyteMass: 90 tonsCost: 90 RUs, 2 SUsBuild Time: 13 secondsFirepower: 85Armor: 80Coverage: 6%Maneuverability: Very HighMax. Velocity: 800 m/sSpecial Function: Link, MissilesRequired Tech: Fighter DriveUpgrade Tech: Linking Tech, Advanced Fighter Drive, Armor Level 2The Beast has the capability to infect, capture, and produce Somtaaw Acolytes, and they represent a significant boon to their Fighter arsenal. They are possessed of the same strengths that their non-infected counterparts enjoy, though they are also more durable. Beast Acolytes are more expensive to produce and somewhat slower than their normal versions, though they also gain armor regeneration and retain the ability to link with one another into ACVs.Corvette ClassBeast Multi-Gun CorvetteMulti-Gun CorvetteMass: 750 tonsCost: 275 RUs, 5 SUsBuild Time: 35 secondsFirepower: 380Armor: 730Coverage: 78%Maneuverability: MediumMax. Velocity: 570 m/sSpecial Function: NoneRequired Tech: Fighter Drive, Fast Tracking TurretsUpgrade Tech: Advanced Fighter Drive, Energy Cannon, Armor Level 2The Beast's Multi-Gun Corvette is a ship design stolen from the Taiidani, and its purpose after assimilation remains the same. It is similar to the Attack Bomber insofar as it is designed specifically to handle a certain class of ships. With its six-gun setup capable of tracking and damaging up to six different targets at once, the Multi-Gun Corvette is at its best when attacking fast-moving groups of Fighter ships. Against larger targets, the Multi-Gun loses much of its appeal, as it lacks the concentrated firepower of other ships.Beast Heavy CorvetteHeavy CorvetteMass: 750 tonsCost: 250 RUs, 4 SUsBuild Time: 35 secondsFirepower: 200Armor: 1,700Coverage: 50%Maneuverability: MediumMax. Velocity: 550 m/sSpecial Function: NoneRequired Tech: Fighter Drive, Heavy Corvette UpgradeUpgrade Tech: Advanced Fighter Drive, Energy Cannon, Armor Level 2Like its non-infected Kushan counterpart, the Beast Heavy Corvette is a benchmark for other Corvette models. It is quite durable, reasonably fast, and able to inflict a fair amount of damage as well. Unlike many of the Beast's other Corvettes, the Heavy Corvette is not really specialized to any particular task, and is neither weak nor overwhelmingly strong against any ship type, so it can be used with a fair amount of effectiveness in most situations. When grouped, they can also be very helpful during Capital ship assaults.Beast Missile CorvetteMissile CorvetteMass: 775 tonsCost: 320 RUs, 4 SUsBuild Time: 25 secondsFirepower: 320Armor: 1,400Coverage: 60%Maneuverability: HighMax. Velocity: 490 m/sSpecial Function: NoneRequired Tech: Fighter Drive, Missile LauncherUpgrade Tech: Advanced Fighter Drive, Armor Level 2Another Turanic Raider design that was consumed and recreated by the Beast, the Missile Corvette is an anti-Strike vessel that uses fast-tracking missiles to seek out and destroy Fighter and Corvette ships. Like other highly specialized craft, it does not fare quite as well against ships outside of its intended target class. However, even large groups of Fighters will sustain heavy casualties when attacking Missile Corvettes, and certain Corvette classes must be wary of them as well.Beast Cruise MissileCruise MissileMass: 490 tonsCost: 250 RUs, 4 SUsBuild Time: 18 secondsFirepower: NoneArmor: 68Coverage: NoneManeuverability: HighMax. Velocity: 650 m/sSpecial Function: NoneRequired Tech: Fighter Drive, Missile Launcher, Bio-Warhead, Beast Infect WeaponUpgrade Tech: Advanced Fighter Drive, Armor Level 2, Armor Level 3The Cruise Missile is one of only two Beast ship designs that does not overtly appear to have been stolen from another race. Indeed, its unique application in battle is something that no other faction would find useful. Once built, they are sent careening into enemy ships in order to infect them and allow the Beast to take control. Larger ships require a greater number of Cruise Missiles to be successfully subverted, though the largest ships are immune to this effect. Cruise Missiles are very fragile, and therefore must be deployed carefully.Beast ACVACVMass: 180 tonsCost: 180 RUs, 4 SUsBuild Time: 22 secondsFirepower: 170Armor: 160Coverage: 6%Maneuverability: HighMax. Velocity: 580 m/sSpecial Function: Unlink, EMPRequired Tech: Fighter Drive, Linking TechUpgrade Tech: Energy Cannon, Advanced Fighter Drive, EMP Weapon, Armor Level 2The Beast variant of the Acolyte Composite Vehicle is almost statistically identical to the Somtaaw ACV. It is slower, tougher, and more expensive than the ship it is based on, and can also regenerate its armor over time. It is worth noting that, unlike the Kiith Somtaaw, who must rely on linked Fighter ships to build their squadrons of Corvettes, the Beast has several other options within this category, many of which are more deadly and much more heavily armored than the ACV.Frigate ClassBeast Ion Array FrigateIon Array FrigateMass: 13,550 tonsCost: 700 RUs, 15 SUsBuild Time: 1 minuteFirepower: 3,500Armor: 5,100Coverage: 6%Maneuverability: LowMax. Velocity: 230 m/sSpecial Function: CloakRequired Tech: Frigate Drive, Advanced Ion CannonUpgrade Tech: Cloaking Drive, Advanced Frigate Drive, Armor Level 3The Ion Array Frigate is a Turanic vessel that the Beast has seen fit to mass produce. It is equipped with a single Ion Cannon that is incredibly effective against ships within and above its weight class, though it has the same weakness that Ion Cannon Frigates in the original game had, namely an inability to target anything that is not directly in front of it. This fact makes it all but useless against fast-moving Fighter and Corvette ships. It has the ability to cloak itself, though, giving it more leeway to position itself strategically before attacking.Beast Defense Field FrigateDefense Field FrigateMass: 13,000 tonsCost: 900 RUs, 10 SUsBuild Time: 1 minute, 30 secondsFirepower: NoneArmor: 4,650Coverage: 100%Maneuverability: LowMax. Velocity: 310 m/sSpecial Function: NoneRequired Tech: Frigate Drive, Defense FieldUpgrade Tech: Advanced Frigate Drive, Armor Level 3As its name indicates, the Defense Field Frigate is a purely defensive vessel. It emits a constant defense field that suppresses incoming fire, thereby protecting itself and any units nearby. This field is strong enough to deflect all but the most powerful of attacks. The downside is that the the Defense Field Frigate has no means of damaging an opponent in and of itself. It can significantly improve the longevity of an attacking or defending force, though deploying it requires some forethought, as enemies will usually be keen to eliminate it quickly.Beast Ramming FrigateRamming FrigateMass: 12,900 tonsCost: 750 RUs, 10 SUsBuild Time: 1 minute, 15 secondsFirepower: 2,500Armor: 5,100Coverage: 6%Maneuverability: MediumMax. Velocity: 378 m/sSpecial Function: RamRequired Tech: AfterburnerUpgrade Tech: Repair Bots, Armor Level 3The Beast's Ramming Frigate is slightly slower and more difficult to destroy than the Somtaaw Ramming Frigate, and slightly more expensive as well. Despite this, there is no major change to its role in battle. It is a support ship that is meant to collide with and move enemy ships, forcing said vessels into a more vulnerable state while also allowing allied vessels the opportunity to do their work more easily. It can self-repair over time, as Beast ships are wont to do.Beast Multi-Beam FrigateMulti-Beam FrigateMass: 10,200 tonsCost: 800 RUs, 12 SUsBuild Time: 1 minute, 10 secondsFirepower: 3,900Armor: 4,200Coverage: 90%Maneuverability: MediumMax. Velocity: 330 m/sSpecial Function: NoneRequired Tech: Frigate Drive, Advanced Ion CannonUpgrade Tech: Advanced Frigate Drive, Armor Level 3With Ion Cannons that take full advantage of advancements in turret technology, the Multi-Beam Frigate offers an attractive alternative to the Ion Array Frigate. Like the Somtaaw's version, the Beast Multi-Beam Frigate's main advantage over traditional Ion Cannon Frigates is the ability to target small, fast-moving Strike ships. It is more expensive and more lightly armored than the Ion Array Frigate, however, and has no cloaking ability, so there are still circumstances in which the latter might be desirable.Beast Hive FrigateHive FrigateMass: 9,900 tonsCost: 625 RUs, 20 SUsBuild Time: 1 minute, 10 secondsFirepower: 1,400Armor: 4,000Coverage: 12%Maneuverability: MediumMax. Velocity: 345 m/sSpecial Function: SwarmRequired Tech: Frigate DriveUpgrade Tech: Microship Construction, Advanced Frigate Drive, Armor Level 3The Beast Hive Frigate incorporates minor survivability improvements over its Somtaaw progenitor vessel, but otherwise remains the same. Its Swarm Fighters are housed and launched in groups of six, and like its parent ship it also possesses a pair of Mass Drivers that allow it to cause damage to ships directly as well. Its drones can be sent a considerable distance from itself without adverse effects, though if the main ship is destroyed, all drones will subsequently self-destruct.Super Capital ClassBeast CarrierCarrierMass: 121,000 tonsCost: 3,400 RUs, 0 SUsBuild Time: 4 minutes, 40 secondsFirepower: 4,000Armor: 65,000Coverage: 75%Maneuverability: LowMax. Velocity: 290 m/sSpecial Function: InfectRequired Tech: Destroyer DriveUpgrade Tech: Crystal Harvesting Ability, Advanced Destroyer Drive, Energy Cannon, Beast Infect Weapon, Armor Level 3Based on the Taiidani version of the Carrier, the Beast Carrier is one of the few subverted Beast ships that actually differs greatly from its non-infected variant. Most noticeably, it has eight Infection Beams attached to its hull which allow it to subvert other ships that get too close. In addition, the Carrier is able to assume all of the normal duties associated with it, including constructing Strike and Frigate class ships, docking Fighters and Corvettes, and accepting resources from Workers.Beast Heavy CruiserHeavy CruiserMass: 131,000 tonsCost: 6,500 RUs, 70 SUsBuild Time: 4 minutes, 50 secondsFirepower: 20,000Armor: 77,000Coverage: 30%Maneuverability: Very LowMax. Velocity: 245 m/sSpecial Function: InfectRequired Tech: Destroyer Drive, Heavy Guns, Advanced Ion CannonUpgrade Tech: Energy Cannon, Advanced Destroyer Drive, Beast Infect Weapon, Armor Level 3A design formerly exclusive to the Taiidan, the Beast's Heavy Cruiser is their most formidable attack ship, with twin Ion Cannon turrets and six Mass Driver emplacements. These weapons are complemented by several Infection Beams capable of converting Frigate and Strike ships into allies, making it an even greater danger. Only the largest vessels are able to attack the Heavy Carrier without fear of infection. It is not as powerful nor as durable as the Somtaaw Dreadnought, though its subversion weaponry requires special consideration.Microship ClassBeast SentinelSentinelMass: 21 tonsCost: 80 RUs, 2 SUsBuild Time: 22 secondsFirepower: 290Armor: 400Coverage: 15%Maneuverability: HighMax. Velocity: 225 m/sSpecial Function: ShieldRequired Tech: Microship ConstructionUpgrade Tech: Force Field Level 1, Force Field Level 2, Force Field Level 3, Advanced Sensors, Armor Level 3Like most assimilated units, the Beast Sentinel is more similar than dissimilar to the unit it is derived from, with only minor differences in armor values, cost, and maximum speed. It is a small protection ship that can project an energy shield in order to deflect or nullify incoming fire. As with the Somtaaw's Sentinel, greater numbers of ships are generally more effective at damage mitigation, especially when larger Capital class ships need to be protected.Mothership ClassBeast MothershipMothershipMass: 565,000 tonsCost: 8,000 RUs, 0 SUsBuild Time: 16 minutes, 40 secondsFirepower: 4,600Armor: 94,000Coverage: 80%Maneuverability: Very LowMax. Velocity: 110 m/sSpecial Function: InfectRequired Tech: NoneUpgrade Tech: Beast Infect Weapon, Crystal Harvesting Ability, Support Systems, Armor Level 3The second of two Beast ships not directly analogous to any other known vessel, the Mothership acts as the focal point for Beast unit production. It can be upgraded over time, enabling more Support Units and higher offensive capability, among other things, and it can also store large numbers of Strike ships and receive resources from Workers. It has the option to boost unit production at the expense of health, and also boasts the single largest Infection Beam in the fleet, which can absorb enemy ships and assimilate their technology.Non-Combat ClassBeast WorkerWorkerMass: 5,200 tonsCost: 650 RUs, 4 SUsBuild Time: 55 secondsFirepower: NoneArmor: 1,800Coverage: NoneManeuverability: MediumMax. Velocity: 365 m/sSpecial Function: Harvest, Salvage, RepairRequired Tech: NoneUpgrade Tech: Repair Systems, Salvaging Ability, Armor Level 2The Beast Worker retains all of the normal attributes associated with standard Workers. It is first and foremost a resource gathering unit meant to break down and transport various forms of useful materials, depositing them at a Mothership, Carrier, or Processor. Additional technology allows it to fill other roles as well. With the salvage upgrade, for instance, it is able tow other ships and large objects, and with the repair upgrade it can act as a repair ship for other vessels in the fleet.Beast ProcessorProcessorMass: 89,000 tonsCost: 1,200 RUs, 13 SUsBuild Time: 2 minutesFirepower: 2,500Armor: 45,100Coverage: 80%Maneuverability: LowMax. Velocity: 235 m/sSpecial Function: NoneRequired Tech: Hangar ModuleUpgrade Tech: Crystal Harvesting Ability, Energy Cannon, Repair Systems, Armor Level 2The Beast Processor is a large non-offensive ship that, like the Somtaaw's Ore Processor, exists primarily to make the resource gathering process easier. It has four docking points for Worker units to drop off resource loads and four Mass Driver turrets to offer moderate protection against attack. When coupled with the repair upgrade, the Processor can be used to set up relatively self-sufficient mining operations at remote locations, as defending units can be repaired without requiring a trip back to the Mothership.ReceptionThe critical response to Homeworld: Cataclysm was extremely positive, mirroring the enthusiastic response its predecessor received. Review scores frequently fell within or near the ninetieth percentile, and were in some instances accompanied by an "Editors' Choice" award, as was the case with PC Gamer and IGN's reviews. Most critics came to the conclusion that the high points of the previous game, including its graphical presentation, streamlined interface, and story-focused campaign, were still in evidence with Cataclysm, and that the new units and the alterations made to the underlying game mechanics were welcome ones. Common criticisms of the game included its difficulty, which some players felt was too steep, while a number of reviewers also mentioned that the quality of the campaign was not quite on par with that of the original game.Original PC System SpecificationsMinimum:System:PII 233 or equivalentRAM:32 MBVideo Memory:4 MbHard Drive Space:150 MBRecommended:System:PII 350 or equivalentRAM:64 MBVideo Memory:12 MbHard Drive Space:400 MB</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5244">Far Gate</game><game id="29556">Sins of a Solar Empire: Diplomacy</game><game id="36300">Nexus 2</game><game id="42153">Homeworld: Shipbreakers</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/24362/917458-catc.jpg</image></root>