<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14096</id><name>Nagano Winter Olympics '98</name><description> Overview The official mascots for the 1998 Winter Olympic Games.          Konami's Olympics video game recreates some of the events and locales seen at the 1998 Nagano Olympic games.  The player has nine different sports to choose from and compete in, and may compete as one of sixteen different nations to choose from.    Gameplay The gameplay for Nagano '98 consists of the player taking control of an Olympic team, and using that Olympic team through twelve events based from the Winter Olympic Games. Nagano '98 represents the Winter Olympic Games that were held in Nagano. In Nagano '98 t he player has to either press different buttons, or simultaneously press two buttons back and forth, much like previously released Track  Field games, and play very similar to those, but winter sports. For the skiing, luge, and bobsledding all have similar control, with you taking control over your character or sleigh team, and skiing having you maneuver around colored flags. In ski jumping you'll have to press certain buttons at correct times, or hold them at tight timing while moving the d-pad to perfect yo ur landing. In curling you'll have to pick what curve and how much to sweep and so forth.  Also, in skating you'll have to repeatedly tap two face buttons simultaneously as fast as you can without breaking formula to gain and keep speed throughout the event.  There are also a few other events which can play similar in controls, or may tweak them a bit. Through the single player you'll have to qualify in seven events to advance, and the game will save high score progress, and will keep you trying to get the high score, with four player multiplayer as well.  Multiplayer is also played similar to single player, as two -four players can challenge each other in random or chosen events for Gold, Silver, or Bronze, and fourth recieves nothing. At the end of all of the events the total medals will be added, and each medal counting for a different point tally, and whoever has the highest total point value at the end is victorious.   High score can also be achieved by anyone and will be saved for that specific event.  Olympic TeamsRussiaNorwayGermanyItalyUnited States of AmericaKoreaCanadaSwitzerlandNorwaySwedenJapanFranceChinaUnited Kingdom Heard and McDonald IslandsSpainEventsAlpine SkiingDownhill Super-G Giant Slalom  SnowboardGiant Slalom  Speed Skating500M 1500M  Short Track500M 1000M  BobsleighLugeSki JumpingLarge Hill  Freestyle AerialsCurling</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="33">Snowboarding/Skiing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7309">Stadium Events</game><game id="17969">SSX Blur</game><game id="24402">Biathlon 2008</game><game id="25318">Mario &amp; Sonic at the Olympic Winter Games</game><game id="27099">Winter Challenge</game><game id="25572">Vancouver 2010</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5822/380819-nwo9864.jpg</image></root>