<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14113</id><name>Sonic Gems Collection</name><description>Sonic Gems is a collection of Sonic games that were not included in the Sonic Mega Collection. Most of these are Master System/Game Gear games, Sonic CD, Sonic R, Sonic the Fighters, Sonic 2, Sonic Spinball, Sonic the Hedgehog Triple Trouble, Sonic Drifit 2, Tails Skypatrol and Tails Adventures are all playable, their are also a few unlockable games. Only the Gamecube version was released in the US whereas Europe had an additional PS2 version.Sonic CD (PC port) 1 playerMain Article: Sonic CDThis was the only Sonic game for the Sega/Mega CD. The collection uses an emulation of the PC port rather than the original. It was created during the development of Sonic 2. The game included a time-travelling gimmick. Depending on what you do in the past, you can change the enemies in the level.Sonic R (PC port) 1-4 playersMain Article: Sonic RA Sonic Racing game. Most characters are on foot on this except for Amy and Robotnik. The playable characters are Sonic, Tails, Knuckles, Amy, Robotnik, Metal Sonic, Eggrobo, Metal Knuckles, Tails Doll, and Super Sonic. There was only 5 stages available in the game. These were Resort Island, Radical City, Regal Ruin, Reactive Factory, and Radiant Emerald. Only the Gamecube version is four player as there is no multitap support.Sonic The Fighters (Arcade port) 1-2 playersMain Article: Sonic The FightersA Sonic fighting game based on the Virtua Fighter engine. The playable characters are Sonic, Tails, Knuckles, Amy, Espio, Fang, Bean, and Bark. Super Sonic is playable if you play as Sonic and don't lose a round. Interestingly, this is was the first ever home release of the 1996 game.Vectorman 1 and 2 (Mega Drive ports) 1 playerMain Article: Vectorman (franchise)Bonanza Bros 1-2 playersMain Article: Bonanza BrosThis was the 3D version made as part of the Sega Ages series in Japan.Streets of Rage 1,2 and 3 (Mega Drive ports) 1-2 playersMain Article: Streets of Rage (franchise)The Japanese version of Gems also included the Streets of Rage trilogy. They were removed from the Western version in order to maintain a low rating.</description><genres><genre id="15">Compilation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14433">Sonic CD</game><game id="21013">Sonic the Fighters</game><game id="2260">Sonic R</game><game id="18592">Sonic the Hedgehog: Spinball</game><game id="13900">Sonic the Hedgehog: Triple Trouble</game><game id="21821">Sonic Drift 2</game><game id="31361">Tails' Skypatrol</game><game id="25043">Tails Adventure</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1803661-box_sonicgc.png</image></root>