<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14123</id><name>GoldenEye: Rogue Agent</name><description>OverviewGoldenEye: Rogue Agent is a video game developed and published by Electronic Arts in 2004. The player takes the role of Jonathan Hunter, later to be known as "GoldenEye", an ex-MI6 agent who is recruited by Auric Goldfinger to assassinate his rival Dr. Julius No. Throughout the game, many legendary allies and enemies that appeared in previous Bond movies, which you will fight alongside and against such as Pussy Galore, Oddjob, Xenia Onatopp and Francisco Scaramanga, will help develop the story as your main mission is vengeance and demolition. Despite Electronic Arts' attempt to recreate the success of the best-selling Bond game entitled GoldenEye 007 in 1997, GoldenEye: Rogue Agent received mediocre reviews due to its lack of innovation, personality and mediocre gameplay.Gameplay" Why save the world when you can rule it?"This game is a typical first person shooter with some extra twists. Several gameplay mechanics will come in handy as you will encounter tougher enemies and several boss battles. Firstly, you can use cover to your advantage. Since this game is in first-person view, you can either crouch or stand behind anything in your environment to avoid enemy attack. Secondly, your health replenishes when you take cover. You can pick up armor that are placed throughout the maps or dropped by enemies when they die to quicken the healing process. Thirdly, the game lets you dual-wield weapons to create devastating weapon combination as you can shoot them separately or together by using the right and left triggers on your controller. In addition, you can subdue an enemy in close combat by using hand-to-hand attacks. After a couple of strikes, your opponent will be stunned and you can either hit him again to knock him out, or use him as a human shield. Using an enemy as a hostage is a great way to replenish your health and ammunition when cover is scarce. Furthermore, there are many machine traps located throughout the game in the environment that can be used to defeat opponents. These deathtraps can eliminate quite a few enemies once mastered.The infamous Moonraker deathtrapFinally, with the help of Francisco Scaramanga, your eye is replaced with an upgradeable synthetic eye which lets you see enemies through cover using MRI vision, manipulate electronics and weapons using the EM Hack, deflect damage with the EM Shield and send enemies flying across the room with the Magnetic Field.MultiplayerAlong with the fully integrated single-player, this game offers 4-player split-screen and online gameplay for the Playstation 2 and Xbox. However, on November 26 2006, the servers for both versions were shut down due to inactivity online. Furthermore, Activision had acquired non-exclusive rights to develop and publish James Bond games later that year.Different game modes were present in the game such as:Multiplayer frenzy in Scaramanga's FunhouseShowdown (Every man for himself)Team Showdown (Eliminate the other team)Domination (Capture domination points to keep your counter high)Tug-O-War (Teams compete to transport a bomb to their goal)These modes could also be modified by changing the rules by playing them on:Normal (Play the match with not special rules)Golden Gun (Place Scaramanga's legendary Golden Gun in the map)You Only Live Twice (Each player receives only two lives)License to Kill (All weapons are one hit eliminations)WeaponsSpec-9- standard pistolType-s Frag GrenadeJackal .357- Powerful pistolMamba 12 GA. - Shotgun that can be dual wieldedHS-90 - Submachine gunAR4 CommandoLongbow SR (campaign only) - SniperHarpoon RL- rocket launcherPredator MGVenom 200ML- paralyzes targetsMK2 Detonnater - shoots an explosive chargeMag-RailTesla EM (campagin only)OMEN XR- Vaporizes enemiesGoblin mine (multiplayer only)Golden Gun (multiplayer only)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9491">Cold Winter</game><game id="16559">007: Agent Under Fire</game><game id="18168">007: The World is Not Enough</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1841796-box_geyera.png</image></root>