<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14131</id><name>RollerCoaster Tycoon: Loopy Landscapes</name><description>OverviewFollowing the success of the preceding expansion, Loopy Landscapes is the second expansion to the popular theme park simulator RollerCoaster Tycoon. Like Corkscrew Follies before it, Loopy Landscapes piles on new rides, scenery, and other options among an entire new list of scenarios to the original game's selection. Additionally, every scenario and object from Corkscrew Follies is included. GameplayScenariosPacked with 30 new scenarios, the objectives in Loopy Landscapes are noted to be more inventive and varied than the original game and its first expansion.ScenarioObjectiveDescriptionIceberg Islands1,250 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3A collection of icebergs make a cold setting for this ambitious theme park.VolcaniaComplete the 5 roller coasters with an excitement rating of 6.70A dormant volcano is the setting of this coaster-building challenge.Arid Heights2,000 guests, park rating must be kept over 700Free of any financial limits, your challenge is to develop this desert park while keeping guests happy.Razor RocksBuild 10 different roller coasters with an excitement rating of 6.00Your task is to build a massive coaster-filled park in amongst Razor Rocks.Crater Lake1,300 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3A large lake in an ancient crater is the setting for this park.Vertigo Views$8,000 monthly income from ride ticketsThis large park already has an excellent hyper-coaster, but your task is to massively increase its profit.Big Pier 21,200 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 2Big Pier has expanded its network of walkways over the sea, and your task is to expand the park to use the extra space.Dragon's CoveComplete the 5 roller coasters with an excitement rating of 6.60This sea-side cove is the setting for this coaster-building challenge.Good Knight Park1,200 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3A castle with a pair of roller coasters needs developing into a larger theme park.Wacky Warren$9,000 monthly income from ride ticketsA park which has much of its footpaths and coasters underground.Grand Glacier1,500 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3A glacier-filled valley is yours to develop into a theme park.Crazy Crates2,000 guests, park rating must be kept over 700In a far-off world where money is not needed, you must build an entertainment center to keep the people happy.Dusty DesertComplete the 5 roller coasters with an excitement rating of 7.00Five coasters require completing in this desert park.Woodworm Park1,600 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3This historical park is only allowed to build older-styled rides.Icarus Park$10,000 monthly income from ride ricketsDevelop this alien park to maximize its profit.Sunny Swamps1,600 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3This well-themed amusement park already has several rides, but has plenty of space for expansion.Frightmare Hills1,500 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3A scary park with a giant centerpiece coaster.Thunder Rocks1,500 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3Two large hunks of rock stick out of the sand, upon which the beginnings of a theme park are constructed.Octagon ParkBuild 10 different roller coasters with a length 1,200 m (3,937 ft) an an excitement rating of 7.00In this large park you must design and build ten large coasters.Pleasure IslandBuild 10 different roller coasters with an excitement rating of 6.00A long thin island makes a challenging setting to build a selection of coasters.Icicle Worlds2,500 guests, park rating must be kept over 700An icy landscape needs turning into a thriving theme park.Southern Sands2,300 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 4A desert park with some cleverly designed coasters is yours to expand.Tiny TowersComplete the 5 roller coasters with an excitement rating of 6.40In this tiny park you must finish building the five existing coasters.Nevermore ParkBuild 10 different roller coasters with a length of 1,400 m (4,593 ft) and an excitement rating of 7.00A large park with a novel transportation system around its edge.Pacifica$8,000 monthly income from ride ticketsThis large island is all yours to develop as an amusement park.Urban Jungle1,200 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3A giant abandoned skyscraper is a unique opportunity for a theme park develop.Terror TownBuild 10 different roller coasters with an excitement rating of 6.00This urban area is all yours to develop into as an amusement park.Megaworld Park3,500 guests, park rating must be kept over 700A giant park already packed full of rides needs improving.Venus Ponds1,600 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 4On a far-away planet this area of land needs turning into a theme park.Micro Park$10,000 park value by October 31, Year 3Try to create the world's smallest profitable park. Real ParksAlso included in Loopy Landscapes are the recreations of three real world parks accompanied with their own objectives.ScenarioObjectiveDescriptionAlton Towers2,500 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3Based on the real park in Alton, Staffordshire, England, it is your job to expand its ride selection and attract more guests.Heide-Park2,500 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3Based on the real park in Soltau, Lower Saxony, Germany, it is your job to expand its ride selection and attract more guests.Blackpool Pleasure Beach3,500 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3Based on the real park in Blackpool, Lancashire, England, it is your job to expand its ride selection and attract more guests. Extra ScenariosTwo extra, previously-released scenarios are also included. Prior to the Loopy Landscapes release, Fort Anachronism was available for download from the Atari website, and Mega Park is the final scenario in the original RollerCoaster Tycoon.ScenarioObjectiveDescriptionFort Anachronism1,250 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3This park has a landmark - a fort in the center. Build the park into a thriving theme park.Mega ParkHave fun!Just for fun! Everything is unlocked and there is no objective, however you still have a budget. The closest the game has to a true sandbox mode. Other AdditionsMuch like Corkscrew Follies, Loopy Landscapes received mild criticism for lack of gameplay changes to the series. Notable new additions are more options for painting and decorating the rides, new music selections, a large collection of new terrain and scenery theming. Attraction ListsThe following attractions are added with Loopy Landscapes.Roller CoastersRideDescriptionAir Powered Vertical CoasterTrack consists of steel girders. Trains run on rubber tires to give a smooth ride, with up-stop wheels below.Inverted Wild Mouse Roller CoasterTrack consists of tubular steel rails. Supports are large tubular steel posts. Cars hang under the track, held on by wheels above, below, and outside the running rails.Suspended Looping CoasterTrack has a tubular steel spine, connected to the outside edges of tubular steel running rails. Supports are large tubular steel posts. Trains hang underneath the track, held in position by wheels above, below, and inside the running rails. Thrill RidesRideDescriptionEnterprisePassenger-carrying pods hang around the edge of the wheel, which first starts spinning and is then tilted up by a support arm. Water RidesRideDescriptionJet SkisBoat dock consists of wooden platforms built on a lake.Raft RideWater channel is supported by steel lattice supports. The raft boats are guided along the water channel by guide-wheels under the hull.Water CoasterTrack is made up of two steel beams with cross sections in the middle. The supports are poles made out of steel. The water sections have steel lattice supports. Shops/StallsShop/StallDescriptionCoffee ShopSells coffee.Doughnut ShopSells doughnuts.Fried Chicken StallSells fried chicken.Lemonade ShopSells lemonade.T-Shirt StallSells t-shirts that guests will wear in the park. Player can designate the color of shirt sold at each individual stall. Scenery ListAlso included in Loopy Landscapes are several new scenery themes.Category/ThemeDescriptionCreepy ThemingCreepily-themed decor.Medieval ThemingMedieval-themed decor.Pagoda ThemingPagoda-themed decor.Snow/Ice ThemingSnow-themed decor.Space ThemingSpace-themed decor.Urban ThemingCity-themed decor. System RequirementsMinimumPentium 90 MHzWindows 95/9816 MB RAM50 MB hard drive space4x CD-ROM1 MB SVGA video cardWindows 95/98 compatible sound cardDirectX 5.0 (included)MouseRecommendedPentium 200Windows 9532 MB RAM180 MB hard drive space8x CD-ROM4 MB SVGA video cardWindows 95/98 compatible sound cardDirectX 5.0 (included)MouseKeyboard</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18956">Thrillville</game><game id="18407">Thrillville: Off the Rails</game><game id="6562">Theme Park</game><game id="10999">Chris Sawyer's Locomotion</game><game id="19003">SimCoaster</game><game id="17736">Mall Tycoon 2</game><game id="17948">Mall Tycoon</game><game id="33263">Hyper Rails</game><game id="1153">NoLimits Roller Coaster Simulation</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/46/1212496-looplandscapes.jpg</image></root>