<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14300</id><name>Dragon Ball Z: Sagas</name><description>OverviewDragon Ball Z: Sagas is an action Beat em’ up based on the popular anime released in March 2005 for the Gamecube, PS2 and Xbox, it was developed by Avalanche Studios and published by Atari. It’s the first action game in the series and also the first and only Dragon Ball Z game released for the Xbox.Gameplay The concept of the game is to kill all enemies in a level in order to reach the boss using several techniques such as Vegeta’s Galick Gun and Goku’s Kame-Hameha, after finishing a level players gain access to the next one. The game takes the players from the beginning of the Saiyan saga up to the Cell games and takes place in several locations from the series such as Planet Namek and the Earth.It also includes a Co-op mode for up to two players and a special mode mode called “Pendulum room” unlocked after completing the game. Playable characters include: Goku, Vegeta, Gohan, Yamcha, Tien, Piccolo, Trunks and Krillin.Game CreditsDevelopment - Aaron Walker Development - Adam Ford Development - Al Mecklenburg Development - Alex Olmos Development - Barry Zundel Development - Benson Yee Development - Brent Critchfield Development - Bryan Lefler Development - Chefi Hawley Development - Dallin Haws Development - Dave McClellan Development - Del Campbel Development - Gabe Avila Development - Jeff Oxburrow Development - Jim Henns Development - Joe Barnnes Development - Jon Bray Development - Jon Warner Development - Justin Kunz Development - Kristen Yee Development - Lauriann Development - Marcus Fisher Development - Matt Parrish Development - Mike Olmos Development - Nate Robbins Development - Rodney Olmos Development - Scott Stoddard Development - Scott Yoho Development - Todd Blackburn Development - Tyler Colburt Voice of: Piccolo and Vegeta - Chris Sabat Voice of Bulma - Tiffany Vollmer Voice of Henchman/Guldo - Bill Townsley Voice of Ginyu - Brice Armstrong Voice of Android 17 - Chuck Huber Voice of Cell - Dameon Clarke Voice of Red Ribbon army - Duncan Brannan Voice of Trunks - Eric Vale Voice of Tien/Saibamen - John Burgmeier Voice of Cell Jr. - Justin Cook Voice of Dr. Gero - Kent Williams Voice of Narrator/Gohan - Kyle Hebert Voice of Dende - Laura Bailey Voice of Frieza - Linda Young Voice of Android 18 - Meredith McCoy Voice of Master Roshi - Mike McFarland Voice of Nappa - Phil Parsons Voice of Android 19 - Phillip Wilburn Voice of Goku/King Kai - Sean Schemmel Voice of Krillin/Bardock - Sonny Strait Voice of Gohan - Stephanie Nadolny Voice of Broly - Vic Mignogna </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15106">Fullmetal Alchemist 2: Curse of the Crimson Elixir</game><game id="21425">Naruto: The Broken Bond</game><game id="20546">Naruto: Ninja Council 3</game><game id="6939">Naruto: Ninja Council 2</game><game id="15928">Naruto: Rise of a Ninja</game><game id="4214">Naruto: Uzumaki Chronicles</game><game id="22519">Naruto: Uzumaki Chronicles 2</game><game id="5554">The Matrix: Path of Neo</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2352258-box_dbzs.png</image></root>