<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14449</id><name>Cadaver</name><description>Story"Legend has it that Castle Wulf is filled with treasure so you decided to raid it. Unfortunately the legend didn't say anything about the castle also being filled with deadly traps, riddles and monsters. It's not all about surviving though, proving your with collecting objects, putting the objects to the right use, mastering spells and solving tasks posed by the gods is also necessary. Quick reflexes and jumping skills are also needed."GameplayPlayers are expected to explore the castle, avoiding enemies if possible and discovering how to collect the treasures around the castle without setting off the devious traps.The player controls Karadoc, a dwarven thief, who is able to grab, move and throw objects. Some of the items can be interacted with in different ways: Clicking on them brings up commands like "pick up", "drink", "open" or "insert". Most of the puzzles in the game are solved with these commands.Several items are needed to progress further, such as keys for unlocking doors, rocks for hitting switches or pickaxes for breaking down walls. It is, in effect, a lot like a graphic adventure game, where success hinges on the correct use of items to solve puzzles.Cadaver also has a sequel: The Payoff. There's also additional stages that were given away as cover-disc demos.</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3308">Cadaver: The Payoff</game><game id="2064">Back to Stone</game><game id="6498">Heimdall</game><game id="3935">Mystic Towers</game><game id="16860">Darkmere: The Nightmare's Begun</game><game id="18183">Monster Max</game><game id="13849">Equinox</game><game id="13220">Solstice: The Quest for the Staff of Demnos</game><game id="7068">Head Over Heels</game><game id="2300">Knight Lore</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9408/723402-cadavercover.jpg</image></root>