<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14547</id><name>Mega Man II</name><description>Not to be confused with  Mega Man 2,  Mega Man II is its own unique title on the       Nintendo Gameboy.  DUDE     The differences from                    Mega Man 2 are the bosses of the games. Some of the bosses from the   NES version made it to the Game Boy version, such as                        Air Man and                       Wood Man; but bosses from                 Mega Man 3 appear here too, such as                      Magnet Man and      Hard Man. Also, the music is not even remotely similar to the music of      Mega Man 2 and      Mega Man 3, and is, in fact, notorious for its extremely grating quality.Characters           Mega Man.                   Mega ManThe hero of the series, Mega Man. Dr. Willy is up to no good and it's up to Mega Man to put a stop to Dr. Willy's evil plain. Rush. RushMega Man's loyal companion, Rush. Rush has the ability to transform; which is an aid for Mega Man to use to aid him in his quest to stop Dr. Willy. Rush's abilities are earned by defeating bosses in the game.Rush's AbilitiesRush Jet: Rush can transform into a hover board to guide Mega Man around in the air.Rush Coil: A jumping pad that allows Mega Man to jump really high.Rush Marine: Rush can transform into a submarine to help Mega an get through a underwater area in one of the later levels in the game.BossesName:                   Air ManWeapon: Air ShooterName:                  Crash ManWeapon: Crash BombName:                 Metal ManWeapon: Metal BladeName:                Wood ManWeapon: Leaf Sheld Name:               Magnet ManWeapon: Magnet Missile Name:              Hard ManWeapon: Hard KnuckleName:             Needle ManWeapon: Needle CanonName:            QuintWeapon: Sakugarine, whatever that means</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1257">Blaster Master</game><game id="4350">Contra</game><game id="6673">Castlevania</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1806087-box_mmgb2.png</image></root>