<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14623</id><name>Jak and Daxter: The Precursor Legacy</name><description>OverviewJak and Daxter: The Precursor Legacy is the first game in the Jak and Daxter franchise. It is also the first game to ever feature a fully seamless 3D world.SettingJak and DaxterJak's (and Daxter's) adventures take place on a completely open continent similar in tone and visual style to Naughty Dog's previous work on the Crash Bandicoot series. The continent is geographically diverse to the extreme, full of both lava pits and icy mountains, thick forests and sprawling beaches. Curiously, the locations themselves are named, but the continent itself isn't, but that's the least of the mysteries surrounding this universe as it is littered with the remnants of a once great race of beings known only as the Precursors.GameplayWhile primarily an open world 3D platformer, Jak and Daxter has some limited combat, which is again almost identical to that of the Crash Bandicoot games. Jak is capable of various attacks and moves, including a long punch, spinning kick, jump uppercut, downward smash, roll, double jump, long jump and high jump, which can be used to defeat enemies, activate secrets and speedily traverse terrain. Damage can be taken from enemies, falling long distances or touching dangerous surfaces, each event taking a bar of life or potentially vaporizing Jak entirely.The main objective to proceed in Jak and Daxter is to collect Power cells, which are used to power vehicles and technology which provide (relatively) safe passage to the next major area. These can be found scattered across the landscape (usually as rewards for challenging platforming or combat situations), bought from various people Jak encounters on his journeys or acquired by completing quests(sometimes including minigames) for these same people. The main currency in Jak and Daxter are Precursor Orbs, which litter the landscape. In every area, there are 7 strong boxes which Jak can break to release scout flies, the last of which yields a power cell.Jak riding the ZoomerA major game mechanic comes in the form of colored energy, called Eco. In total, there are six types of Eco in the game: Green, which replenishes life; Blue, which enhances speed, attracts nearby collectibles and activates Precursor technology; Red, which enhances melee combat power; Yellow, which gives a ranged burst of energy attack; Dark, which deals damage to or kills Jak instantly; and White, which is only encountered at the end of the game as the combination of the first four Eco types. The effects of blue, red and yellow Eco dissipate at a steady rate, which adds a timed element to many challenges that feature or require their use. Eco can be collected in hovering globules of small or large size, but only Eco vents give constant and complete filling of the Eco meter as long as you stand on them. Jak can only use a single type of Eco at a time, so collecting a different type will overwrite the current one.Vehicle sections separate major sections of the game world, usually involving a timed mechanic (including overheating from lava and chasing down demolition-minded enemys), and there are a few major boss battles.Comic ReliefBesides many comedic interactions and commentary, Jak and Daxter has a couple fairly unique methods of comic relief:Whenever the duo acquires a new power cell, it is accompanied by a success dance or tableau cutscene and accordingly triumphant music. Also, whenever Jak keels over from losing all his life (and it makes sense that Daxter might not be out of commission as well), there is a short randomly chosen cutscene. These are viewed from Jak's incapacitated perspective of Daxter standing on his chest and making wisecracks at the expense of his buddy (and the player), including insulting his breath, requesting his change and, as long as he's down there, a foot massage.PlotJak and Daxter, two young elfin rascals, secretly sail off to Misty Island against the wishes of Samos the Sage and discover a sinister gathering of evil Lurkers creatures addressed a pair of floating villains. The protagonists attempt to sneak away, but they are soon discovered by a lone Lurker who attacks them. Jak hurls a barrel of Eco at the Lurker which destroys it and sends Daxter flying into a vat of Dark Eco. He is spat out again as a loudmouthed ottsel (otter weasel). When they return to Samos for help returning Daxter to his original form he chides them harshly and explains that they must travel far, far north to Gol Acheron, who might be able to help them. A firey canyon stands in the way, which can only be traversed by Keira's Zoomer with a heat shield upgrade made possible with power cells.After successfully passing through the canyon, Jak and Daxter find the next town, Rock Village, under siege by a giant cyborg lurker named Klaww and the Blue Sage, the patron sage of the town, mysteriously missing, his laboratory a mess. After gathering more power cells, a flaming boulder blocking the path to the monster can be dislodged with an anti-gravity device, and the duo proceed via Zoomer through a mountain pass to reach the Volcanic Crater.Here, they find the Red Sage missing and his laboratory in similarly terrible shape. Gol Akuron and his sister, Maia Acheron, (whom we remember from the Lurker gathering) appear and explain how they have captured all the sages but Samos, and, in an effort to shape the world to their liking, plan to flood the world with the Dark Eco contained in the massive Percursor silos to the north. More power cells and another heat shield upgrade allow Keira's Zoomer to brave the Lava Tube, which leads to the Yellow Sage's lab.When they arrive, Keira explains that her father has also been kidnapped. Jak and Daxter then venture into Gol and Maia's Citadel, where they learn the sages were being used to power the Percursor robot, which is powerful enough to open the silo. After freeing the sages, the two encounter Gol and Maia with a reworked Percursor robot atop the Dark Eco silo. Jak battles the robot, as its strikes open the silo further and further, and only with the help of all four sages combining their powers to create the fabled White Eco does he defeat it. Although Daxter realizes it would probably reverse his transformation, he decides saving the world is more important.The Percursor robot containing Gol and Maia is disabled and crashes into the silo, which then seals itself again. Although this might kill them both, Samos is uncertain this is the case. The group's attention is directed toward a massive Percursor door, which requires 100 power cells before it opens, revealing some thing large shrouded in blinding light. This is not explained until the sequel.Soundtrack#Song TitleTimeArtist1Naughty Dog0:18Mutato Muzika2Title Screen4:59Mutato Muzika3Intro6:08Mutato Muzika, Max Casella, Warren Burton, Anna Garduno, Dee Snider, Lisa Hagood4Geyser Rock4:53Mutato Muzika5Sandover Village4:53Mutato Muzika6Sandover Village (Keira Mix)4:54Mutato Muzika7Sandover Village (Fisherman Mix)4:54Mutato Muzika8Sandover Village (Mayor Mix)4:54Mutato Muzika9Sandover Village (Uncle Mix)4:54Mutato Muzika10Sandover Village (Sculptor Mix)4:53Mutato Muzika11Sandover Village (Farmer Mix)4:54Mutato Muzika12Sandover Village (Bird Watcher Mix)4:54Mutato Muzika13Forbidden Jungle4:19Mutato Muzika14Forbidden Jungle (Fisherman's Theme)4:19Mutato Muzika15Forbidden Jungle (Machine Mix)4:19Mutato Muzika16Forbidden Jungle (Precusor Area Mix)4:19Mutato Muzika17Forbidden Jungle (Outside the Temple Mix)4:19Mutato Muzika18Forbidden Jungle Temple5:10Mutato Muzika19Forbidden Jungle Temple (Blue Eco Vent Mix)5:11Mutato Muzika20Forbidden Jungle Temple (Vs. Dark Eco Plant)2:22Mutato Muzika21Sentinel Beach4:41Mutato Muzika22Sentinel Beach (Windmill Mix)4:36Mutato Muzika23Sentinel Beach (Bird Watcher Mix)4:36Mutato Muzika24Misty Island4:08Mutato Muzika25Misty Island (On the Ship)4:08Mutato Muzika26Fire Canyon3:36Mutato Muzika27Rock Village4:22Mutato Muzika28Rock Village (Samos Mix)4:22Mutato Muzika29Rock Village (Warrior Mix)4:22Mutato Muzika30Rock Village (Gambler Mix)4:22Mutato Muzika31Rock Village (Geologist Mix)4:22Mutato Muzika32Rock Village (Levitation Cannon  Keira Mix)4:22Mutato Muzika33Lost Precursor City4:10Mutato Muzika34Precursor Basin3:49Mutato Muzika35Boggy Swamp4:36Mutato Muzika36Boggy Swamp (Flut Flut Mix)4:36Mutato Muzika37Mountain Pass4:08Mutato Muzika38Mountain Pass (vs. Klaww)3:52Mutato Muzika39Volcanic Crater4:00Mutato Muzika40Volcanic Crater (Samos And Keira Mix)3:58Mutato Muzika41Volcanic Crater (Miners Mix)4:00Mutato Muzika42Volcanic Crater (Train Track Mix)3:59Mutato Muzika43Spider Caves4:42Mutato Muzika44Spider Caves (Blackout)4:39Mutato Muzika45Spider Caves (Robot Mix)4:39Mutato Muzika46Spider Caves (Top of the Robot Mix)4:47Mutato Muzika47Snowy Mountain4:53Mutato Muzika48Snowy Mountain (Snow Boulder Mix)4:53Mutato Muzika49Snowy Mountain (Yellow Eco Vent Mix)4:54Mutato Muzika50Snowy Mountain (Flut Flut Mix)4:54Mutato Muzika51Snowy Mountain (Lurker Fort Mix)4:53Mutato Muzika52Lava Tube (Part 1)2:54Mutato Muzika53Lava Tube (Part 2)2:53Mutato Muzika54Lava Tube (Part 3)2:49Mutato Muzika55Gol and Maia Citadel4:19Mutato Muzika56Gol and Maia Citadel (Red Sage Mix)4:19Mutato Muzika57Gol and Maia Citadel (Blue Sage Mix)4:19Mutato Muzika58Gol and Maia Citadel (Yellow Sage Mix)4:19Mutato Muzika59Gol and Maia Citadel (Before Final Battle Mix)4:19Mutato Muzika60Final Battle (Part 1)3:22Mutato Muzika61Final Battle (Part 2)3:40Mutato Muzika62Final Battle (Part 3)3:40Mutato Muzika63Final Battle (Part 4)3:40Mutato Muzika64Ending Dialogue1:12Mutato Muzika, Max Casella, Warren Burton, Anna Garduno, John Di Crosta, Sherman Howard65Credits  Mountain Pass (vs. Klaww) [long version]6:43Mutato Muzika66Need 100 Power Cells Ending ~ Dialogue0:19Mutato Muzika, Max Casella, Warren Burton, Anna Garduno67Got 100 Power Cells Ending ~ Dialogue1:01Mutato Muzika, Max Casella, Warren Burton, Anna Garduno68A Power Cell!0:05Mutato Muzika69Hiemlich (Daxter) (Bonus)0:04Mutato Muzika70Good Night (Daxter) (Bonus)0:05Max Casella71Good Night (Daxter) (Bonus)0:01Max Casella72Well, Uh... (Daxter) (Bonus)0:03Max Casella73Hey Jak (Daxter) (Bonus)0:04Max Casella74Down There (Daxter) (Bonus)0:03Max Casella75Don't Step Into the Light (Daxter) (Bonus)0:03Max Casella76Step One and Two (Daxter) (Bonus)0:05Max Casella77I Was Right Behind You (Daxter) (Bonus)0:03Max Casella78That looks like (Daxter) (Bonus)0:02Max Casella</description><genres><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7380">Crash Bandicoot</game><game id="18309">Ratchet &amp; Clank</game><game id="19026">Star Fox Adventures</game><game id="21115">Ratchet &amp; Clank Future: Quest for Booty</game><game id="1753">Spyro: Year of the Dragon</game><game id="20908">The Legend of Spyro: Dawn of the Dragon</game><game id="7836">Spyro the Dragon</game><game id="15835">Beyond Good &amp; Evil</game><game id="609">Rayman 2: The Great Escape</game><game id="15353">Sly Cooper and the Thievius Raccoonus</game><game id="6649">Super Mario Sunshine</game><game id="8660">Crash Bandicoot 2: Cortex Strikes Back</game><game id="12909">Crash Bandicoot: Warped</game><game id="15000">Donkey Kong 64</game><game id="8420">Spyro: Enter the Dragonfly</game><game id="15212">Ratchet &amp; Clank Future: Tools of Destruction</game><game id="20351">Kya: Dark Lineage</game><game id="13992">Uncharted: Drake's Fortune</game><game id="3438">MediEvil II</game><game id="4228">Haven: Call of the King</game><game id="11407">Vexx</game><game id="16337">Sly 3: Honor Among Thieves</game><game id="15573">Sly 2: Band of Thieves</game><game id="1563">Spyro 2: Ripto's Rage</game><game id="6134">The Legend of Spyro: The Eternal Night</game><game id="3457">MediEvil</game><game id="7804">Rocket: Robot on Wheels</game><game id="20330">Gex 3: Deep Cover Gecko</game><game id="15991">Chameleon Twist 2</game><game id="4618">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Going Commando</game><game id="4966">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Up Your Arsenal</game><game id="18745">Ratchet: Deadlocked</game><game id="10920">Banjo-Kazooie</game><game id="18376">Looney Tunes Back in Action</game><game id="1653">Ninja Gaiden</game><game id="1850">Ninja Gaiden III: The Ancient Ship of Doom</game><game id="7212">Klonoa 2: Lunatea's Veil</game><game id="16094">Super Mario Galaxy</game><game id="20584">Sonic the Hedgehog</game><game id="18926">Malice</game><game id="11470">Scaler</game><game id="2931">Super Mario 64</game><game id="68">Crash Bandicoot: The Wrath of Cortex</game><game id="10983">Kingdom Hearts</game><game id="24969">Tokobot Plus: Mysteries of the Karakuri</game><game id="25673">Ratchet &amp; Clank Future: A Crack in Time</game><game id="21772">Dawn of Mana</game><game id="96">Kao the Kangaroo</game><game id="26496">Agent Hugo: Lemoon Twist</game><game id="30746">Ruff Trigger: The Vanocore Conspiracy</game><game id="12611">Robots</game><game id="35559">Sly Cooper: Thieves in Time</game><game id="14790">Crash Twinsanity</game><game id="22800">Whiplash</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1897524-box_jad.png</image></root>