<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14662</id><name>Scramble</name><description>OverviewScramble is a  side-scrolling shooter originally developed by  Konami for the arcade. The game predates  Gradius, and shares many qualities with that classic franchise.GameplayScramble's second stageScramble is a hrorizontal shooter played using a four-way joystick and two buttons that control the forward guns and bombs. The game has six stages, and in each stage the player must navigate a gauntlet of enemies. The environment is also a considerable hazard as the terrain can be difficult to navigate with the slow ship. Additionally, the ship is constantly running out of fuel, and must refuel on the fly by destroying fuel tanks that litter the stages. The final stage requires the player to finish a tricky bombing run, which if they fail, they must repeat the stage. After finishing the last level, the game loops back to the first stage and plays again at a higher difficulty level where the ship runs out of fuel more quickly.LegacyArcade flyerScramble was ported to many different home game systems and computers, both legally and as illegal clones. It was the subject of an important  intellectual property case (Stern Electronics, Inc. v. Kaufman, 669 F.2d 852) where it was ruled that  Stern Electronics Inc. (the game's publisher in North America) could copyright the images and sounds in a game and not just the game's source code.Sequels and Relation To GradiusThe arcade game  Super Cobra could be called a sequel to Scramble, as it shares basically the same game mechanic as the original. Scramble is also cited as a predecessor to Gradius in both the introduction to  Gradius Galaxies on the  Game Boy Advance and the Gradius Breakdown bonus DVD included with  Gradius V; however, Konami disputed the relation in their guide for the  Gradius Portable collection on  PSP. Although Scramble may now not be part of the official Gradius continuum, it's easy to see how some of the features of Scramble, such as independently-fired weapons and hazardous terrain, were further developed for Gradius.</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10519">Super Cobra</game><game id="15273">Aegis Wing</game><game id="17011">Cosmic Avenger</game><game id="11640">Vanguard</game><game id="16929">Plasmania</game><game id="18053">Fire Galaxy</game><game id="18558">Penetrator</game><game id="9355">Caverns of Mars</game><game id="15508">Gradius</game><game id="7617">Gradius III</game><game id="3623">Gradius II</game><game id="10201">Gradius V</game><game id="676">Gradius III and IV</game><game id="23660">Gradius IV Fukkatsu</game><game id="16456">Fortress Underground</game><game id="32798">A Shooter</game><game id="34395">Asteroids Do Concern Me</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1364/459274-scramble.gif</image></root>