<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14748</id><name>Indiana Jones and The Last Crusade: The Graphic Adventure</name><description>OverviewIndiana Jones and The Last Crusade is a point and click adventure game based on the movie of the same name. While it follows the plot of the film in broad terms, it also adds to existing sequences for the film, or creates new ones altogether, presumably to flesh out the experience. Unlike later LucasArts titles, it is possible for the protagonist to die.The game also features music from John Williams' score to the film. If you didn't have a soundcard this would be limited to short bursts of PC speaker jingles. It was re-released via Steam on July 8th, 2009.FeaturesGame manual in the form of Dr. Jones Sr.'s Grail diaryDifferent styles of gameplay: puzzles, boxing, and flyingIndy Quotient (IQ) scorning system, rewarding different solutions to puzzles, and adding replay value</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9058">Escape from Monkey Island</game><game id="10927">Loom</game><game id="17544">Broken Sword: The Shadow of the Templars</game><game id="9527">Flight of the Amazon Queen</game><game id="3019">The Secret of Monkey Island</game><game id="5729">The Curse of Monkey Island</game><game id="14441">Pajama Sam 2: Thunder and Lightning Aren't so Frightening</game><game id="8430">Pajama Sam: No Need to Hide When It’s Dark Outside</game><game id="21090">A New Beginning</game><game id="23532">Nikopol: Secrets of the Immortals</game><game id="6728">Zak McKracken and the Alien Mindbenders</game><game id="23778">Strong Bad's Cool Game for Attractive People Episode 3: Baddest of the Bands</game><game id="21667">Gray Matter</game><game id="19493">Silent Hill: Play Novel</game><game id="24962">Full Throttle: Payback</game><game id="29490">Lost Horizon</game><game id="11064">The Adventures of Maddog Williams in the Dungeons of Duridian</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4938/609329-last_crusade_box_front_6390x8118.jpg</image></root>