<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14769</id><name>Twisted Metal Small Brawl</name><description>Overview A smaller take on the popular        Twisted Metal franchise and developed by the     original team, Twisted Metal: Small Brawl has remote-controlled cars with weapons attached taking the place of the normal sized vehicular combat. The story revolves around a young Billy       Calypso bullying kids around the neighborhood into his RC car competition. Characters/Vehicles Crimson Fury - A British child who pretends to be a secret agent. Agent Stone wishes to thwart Calypso's evil plans and bring an end to his misdeeds. Hammerhead - A punk rock-loving teen who wants to become the world's greatest rock star. Mr. Grimm - A Halloween-obsessed child who wishes to find the mythical Halloween Land where it's Halloween everyday. Slam - The tallest and oldest kid in the competition, Slam wants revenge for Calypso destroying his beloved treehouse. Outlaw - The son of a police officer, driver Officer Roberts intends to bring Calypso to justice. Shadow - A bit of a science nerd, Mortimer wants to get his pet frog back which was stolen by Calypso. Spectre - A shy, withdrawn child who only wishes to find his long, lost father. Sweet Tooth - The youngest of the competitors,      Sweet Tooth enters Twisted Metal simply to satisfy his sweet tooth. Thumper - Two "cool kids" who enter the competition hoping to get the ultimate sound system. Twister - A thrill-seeking lass, Twister hopes to find the fastest, most adrenaline-inducing ride. Warthog - A chubby kid with an interest for all things militant,   Warthog hopes to get revenge on Calypso for being picked on for so long. Unlockable Characters/Vehicles Note: These characters do not have an ending.  Axel - A two-wheeled RC car held by an action figure attached in the middle.  Axel enters Twisted Metal simply to show-off his two-wheeled RC car held by an action figure attached in the middle. Darkside - Entering the competition for unknown reasons, driver    Jimmy Ash's toy semi truck holds the strongest defense in the game. Mime - An actress who mimics her competitors' special abilities to get on their nerves.  Trapper - An RC car that resembles a jeep normally used for jungle expeditions. Serves as the game's mid-boss. A smaller version can be unlocked. Piecemeal - A large RC car that is built from the parts of the other RC cars in the competition. Serves as the game's final boss. A smaller version can be unlocked.  Trivia Was originally going to be called Twisted Metal Kids.Was originally planned to be developed for the PS2. Dropped for unknown reasons.Axel was intended to be unlocked from the start and had an ending movie already made for him, but was removed due to possible offense to paraplegics and African Americans.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9259">Twisted Metal: Head-On</game><game id="4315">WWE Crush Hour</game><game id="23930">Wild Metal</game><game id="5917">Cyber Sled</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2011585-box_tmetalsb.png</image></root>