<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14819</id><name>Tron 2.0</name><description>OverviewTron 2.0 is a first person shooter sequel to the 1982 Disney original movie "Tron". The protagonist of the game, Jet, is the son of the original Baxter from the film. Tron 2.0 is notable for its use of bloom; many objects in the game glow, even the surfaces. It was originally released in 2003 for the PC platform and a release on the Xbox, with additional emphasis on the multi-player component, followed the subsequent year as Tron 2.0 Killer App.StoryIn the computer world beyond your screen, programs live out their mundane lives doing the tasks assigned to them by "The Users" (humans, programmers in particular) This glowing world of neon and electricity was once threatened by the Master Control program, but now, a new threat arises.In the wake of the planned 2010 release of Tron: Legacy and Tron: Evolution, the events of Tron 2.0 and its related media have been deemed to be an alternate universe, and not part of the main Tron canon.CharactersBruce Boxleitner reprises his role as Alan Bradley, father of the protagonist Jet. During the course of the game, Alan is digitized and gets to experience the computer word for the first time.Cindy Morgan, who played the lead female roles of Lora and Yori in the original Tron, voices Ma3a, the guiding A.I. program that helps Jet traverse the computer world and rescue his father.Rebecca Romjin (Stamos) plays the new digital character Mercury, a lightcycle champion who aids Jet in certain levels.Wide-screen  ModsTron 2.0 does not support wide-screen displays. You can force the resolution on to the game, this can break some of the graphics. Some mods like " killer-app"have emerged to fix this issue and add few other features.System RequirementsPC Minimum System RequirementsProcessor: Intel Pentium III or AMD Athlon 500MhzRAM Memory: 256 MBGPU: 32MB Direct 3D-Compatible video card with Hardware TL, 32-bit color, DirectX 9-Compatable DriverOperating System: Windows 98/ME/2000/XPMisc: Mouse, Keyboard, Internet Connection for multi-play, LAN Connection for lightcycle multi-play</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8870">System Shock 2</game><game id="8093">Ricochet</game><game id="23357">Tank Universal: Challenger Eight</game><game id="14523">Star Wars: Jedi Knight II - Jedi Outcast</game><game id="16922">Star Wars: Jedi Knight - Jedi Academy</game><game id="4170">Command &amp; Conquer: Renegade</game><game id="621">Doom II: Hell on Earth</game><game id="7570">Enter the Matrix</game><game id="15509">Star Trek: Elite Force II</game><game id="11187">Star Trek: Voyager - Elite Force</game><game id="2832">Tribes 2</game><game id="7574">Battle Engine Aquila</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/15/155745/2173605-51wd7cswxvl._ss400_.jpg</image></root>