<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14858</id><name>GTR 2: FIA GT Racing Game</name><description>GTR 2 is based on the GMotor 2 Engine by ISI and includes a similar physics engine, but with different multiplayer code. GTR 2 also included and extensive driving school feature that explained the basics and many in depth driving techniques, and driving coaching for each stock track. Tracks included are Zhuhai International Circuit,Hockenheim (GP, National, International),Imola,Barcelona (GP, National),Oschersleben (2003, 2004, b course),Brno (2003, 2004),Donington Park (2003, 2004, National),Valencia (GP, National, Long),Estoril,Dubai (GP, Club, National, International),Enna Pergusa,Anderstorp (GP, South),Spa-Francorchamps (2003, 2004),Monza (2003, 2004, Junior),Magny Cours (2003, 2004, National).All of the real life cars of the FIA GT series 2003 and 2004 season are included. These are BMW M3 GTRBMW Z3 MChevrolet Corvette C5-RChrysler Viper CCChrysler Viper GTS-RFerrari 360 GTCFerrari 360 ModenaFerrari 550 MaranelloFerrari 575 GTCGillet VertigoLamborghini Murcielago R-GTLister StormLotus EliseMaserati MC12Morgan Aero 8Mosler MT900RNissan 350ZPorsche 911 BiturboPorsche 993 GT2Porsche 996 GT3 CupPorsche 996 GT3-RSPorsche 996 GT3-RSRSaleen S7-RSEAT Toledo GTTVR T400R Addittionally many user created mods have been released for GTR2, some of these include F1 2009: All Cars from the 2009 Formula One Season.F1 2008: All Cars from the 2008 Formula One Season.Power and Glory: features authentic GT racing from the 1960s and 1970s. (Converted from GT Legends)V8 Supercars 2006: features V8 Supercars championship in Australia.World Super GT: features 7 GT cars - Aston Martin DBR9, Aston Martin DBRS9, Ferrari F50 GT, Ferrari FXX, Maserati Trofeo Light, McLaren F1 GTR Longtail and Ultima GTR. Completed in high quality.SCC Prototype mod v2.41: Features Le Mans Prototypes such as the Zytek 045, the MG Lola EX257, and the Audi R8R. and the (LMP1 and LMP2) from 1998-2008Champcar 2005/2006: Features all the cars off the Champcar 2005 and 2006 season, converted from rFactor by RMiF1 1979: Features all the cars and some tracks of the 1979 formula 1 season, converted from rFactor by RMi, a beta has been released, featuring 4 cars.System RequirementsMinimumOS: Microsoft Windows XP/Vista/SevenProcessor: 1.3 GHz Intel Pentium III or AMDMemory: 512 MB RAMGraphics: DX8.1 comp. video card/64 MBDirectX®: 8.1Hard Drive: 3 GB HD spaceSound: DX8.1 comp. sound cardRecommendedProcessor: 2 GHz Intel Pentium IV or AMDMemory: 1 GB RAMGraphics: DX9.0c comp. video card/256 MBDirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 3 GB HD spaceSound: DX9.0 comp. sound card</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7723">Grand Prix 4</game><game id="6347">Grand Prix Legends</game><game id="275">GT Legends</game><game id="20130">rFactor</game><game id="327">Race 07: The Official WTCC Game</game><game id="19522">Live for Speed</game><game id="5881">Forza Motorsport 2</game><game id="22693">RACE Pro</game><game id="25225">Need for Speed: SHIFT</game><game id="24995">Forza Motorsport 3</game><game id="23517">GTR Evolution</game><game id="27298">rFactor 2</game><game id="19563">Sports Car GT</game><game id="32253">SHIFT 2: Unleashed</game><game id="32037">STCC - The Game</game><game id="36993">Project CARS</game><game id="34542">F1 2011</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3699/649015-pc_gtr_2.jpg</image></root>