<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1496</id><name>Shade: Wrath of Angels</name><description>  Overview Shade: Wrath of Angels is a 2004                   Microsoft Windows and                   Xbox game produced by                                 Black Element Software and published by                     Cenega.  The original name was Nefandus, but later was changed to Shade: Wrath  of Angels before its release. The history revolves around an ancient war  between                             angels and                            gods.   GameplayShade: Wrath of Angels is a third-person adventure game where players play as a                                   nameless protagonist who must fight off various creatures while looking for his brother. The player must travel across different dimensions with 4 different chapters to complete. It has many action/adventure elements seen in some games like                                Tomb Raider and                               Prince of Persia etc, players can ledge grab and jump across a gap. Players can use variety of weapons like a                              pistol, a                             crossbow and a                            magic sword. Players can also use magic to kill several enemies like, Medieval England                           knights,                          demons,                         zombies and Egyptian warriors.  Plot Get away from me, you bastards!The game starts with a                tutorial  to explain various aspects of the game. The tutorial goes on as the  player sleeps, and he plays the tutorial in his dream. After the  completion of the tutorial, the player goes to a town on receiving an  invitation from his brother 'B'.  On his latter 'B' has claimed to have  discovered an important archaeological site, which appears to be a very  primitive one. But on reaching the town, the player is amazed to find  out that nobody is anywhere.  He reaches the Hotel where his brother has  written to be boarded. But on reaching the Hotel, he finds nothing but a  pistol left by his brother for him. He decides to check the Church but  on his way downstairs, he is stunned to see a zombie, in the lobby.  He  however shoots the zombie and goes to the              Church, only to encounter two  more walking dead therein. After dealing with them, he finds a secret  passage and moves into it to descend down and finds an orb. After the  player comes out of the room with the orb, a misty figure appears and  reveals to him a fearful secret.  The figure reveals to the player that  he is the angel of Faith, and the orb he is carrying is the heart of the  angel.  The Angel of Faith asks the player to release the other three  angels to bring his brother back. When the player agrees, the Angel  gives him the her loyal servant, a single-eyed red demon to help him on  his quest.  The player is teleported by the angel to each of the three  worlds where the pieces of the hearts of the other three angels are  kept, the first being in the world of undead knights (themed on a  medieval period with walking dead, the zombies and undead knights), the  second being in the Pyramid of Egyptian God Seth (themed on pyramids,  with living statues, mummies and undead worshippers of mighty Seth) and  the third being in the world of eternal darkness, the 'Shadowland'  (themed on a shadowy plain with creatures of darkness everywhere).  But  on collecting the three hearts of the angels and reunifying them, the  angel of Faith reappears and reveals herself to be the dark angel, who  opposed the Gods and set the war between the four worlds. The player  vows to stop the evil by breaking all the hearts of the angels, but the  other three good angels appear and ask the player to destroy the demon,  who helped him on his quests.  The player kills the demon with his magic  sword, and the good angels trap the angel of Faith. The angels then  reveal to him that his brother's soul is sealed and can not be made to  live again. The angels then transform the player to an immensely  powerful guardian, to protect all the four hearts of the angels with his  magic sword till the end of time.  LevelsIntro / TutorialRailway StationHotelChurchUndergroundDeserted Town IDeserted Town IICastle Ruins ICastle Ruins IIBurning TownNecropolisNecropolis TempleSpiders' NestThe TowerAncient CryptTemple of SethTemple of Seth IIThe Host of SerqetThe House of OsirisThe Hypostyle HallThe Scales of MaatThe Fields of PeaceThe Descent to DarknessThe Descent to Darkness IIThe PortalThe First EncounterThe GateThe BridgeThe SwampThe MachineGrand Finale  Soundtrack Album Cover Artwork            The         original score for Shade: Wrath of Angels was composed by     Jaroslav Kasny and is available for download at the        game's official website. Track No.Song TitleRunning Time 01 Main Theme 02.52 02 Reality 03.20 03 Dark Ages Explorations 02.06 04 Lord of the Undead Knights 02.47 05 The Town 01.32 06 The Tower 01.25 07 Leaving the Medieval 02.01 08 The Egypt Journey, pt. 1 03.06 09 Boss and Spiders 01.03 10 The Egypt Journey, pt. 2 01.11 11 The Second Pylon 03.48 12 The Shadowland 00.43 13 Betrayal 01.25 14 Chasm of Eternity 04.22 15 Final Fight 02.56 16 Credits 03.20 17 Bonus Track 1 01.51 18 Bonus Track 2 02.25 19 Bonus Track 3 - from trailer 01.54  PC System RequirementsMinimum Requirements Operating System: Win 98SE, ME  Processor: Intel PIII - 700 MHz  Memory: 128 MB RAM  Video Card: 32 MB GeForce2  Sound Card: SoundBlaster compatible sound card  Hard Disc: 2 GB free space on HDD Recommended System RequirementsOperating System: Win 2000, XP Processor: Intel P4 - 2 GHz Memory: 512 MB RAM Video Card: 256 MB GeForce4 Sound Card: EAX compatible sound card Hard Disc: 4 GB free space on HDD   </description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3023">Tomb Raider</game><game id="8554">Lara Croft Tomb Raider: Legend</game><game id="10863">Prince of Persia 3D</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5258/324918-shade.jpg</image></root>