<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1497</id><name>WarTech: Senko no Ronde</name><description>Overview WarTech: Senko no Ronde (known in Japan as Senko no Ronde Rev. X) is a hybrid arcade shoot-em-up/fighter developed by                        G.rev for the                       Xbox 360. It is a port of the Japanese arcade game Senko no Ronde, adding improved features, a more defined control scheme, and online multiplayer via                      Xbox Live. The port was originally published on July 27, 2006 in Japan by G.rev, then brought over to North America and Europe almost a year later by                     Ubisoft. The game takes place in the far future, where the player takes control of one of eight pilots (each piloting their                   mech, called Rounders) as they become involved in a mastermind's scheme to take control of a                  superweapon. Gameplay The bulk of the game revolves around three buttons: Main Weapon (the X button), Sub-Weapon (the Y button), and Dash/Act (the A button). Players move around an enclosed arena, attempting to win against their opponents by using weapons and melee attacks.  Armor Gauge Each player has an Armor Gauge, which essentially acts as a    life bar. As the player is attacked, it depletes. When it is fully depleted, the Rounder enters a Vanish Mode, by which the next hit would be the killing blow. Taking too much damage at one time triggers a Large Down, in which the Rounder activates an Anti-Field (a large shield that destroys all incoming attacks and pushes the opponent out of its range). Charge GaugeIn addition to their Armor Gauge, players have a Charge Gauge (essentially a         super meter), which increases when you hit your opponent, get hit by a ranged attack, shoot down your opponent's attacks, and when you're not firing (slowly over time). However, the Charge Gauge decreases when you are either hit with a closed-ranged attack or use certain moves. Each rounder in-game has two circles surrounding it, one for the Main Weapon and one for the Sub-Weapon. Not only do they represent the current reloading time of each weapon, but the Sub-Weapon circle also represents the range at which your Rounder can be engaged in melee combat.  Advanced ControlsPressing both the Main Weapon and Sub-Weapon buttons together (or the B button) activates the Barrage attack, which serve as special weapons (some offensive, some defensive) at the cost of some of the Charge Gauge. Players can use certain combinations of joystick and attack buttons to perform powerful attacks.  Pressing the Right Trigger (or pressing the A button while the joystick is neutral and the A button is set to "Act" in the Options menu) activates the Barrier, which allows your Rounder to target freely and reduce damage taken at the cost of some of the Charge Gauge. Pressing the Left Bumper activates Overdrive, which you can only do once per round. Overdrive mode increases your Rounder's attack and defense, at the cost of slowly depleting the Armor Gauge.  B.O.S.S. Mode       Each Rounder has its own unique B.O.S.S. formation, which serve as powerful shoot-em-up      bosses with complex     bullet hell patterns, insane armor, and the ability to damage an opponent just by touching. Players have a limited amount of chances to activate B.O.S.S. mode, after which pressing the button(s) to activate it causes an Anti-Field (at the cost of half the Charge Gauge) instead. Pressing the Dash/Act, Main Weapon, and Sub-Weapon buttons simultaneously (or pressing the Left Trigger, or the Dash/Act and Barrage buttons) triggers B.O.S.S. mode. The Charge Gauge determines how much armor the B.O.S.S. formation starts with and how long the player lasts in B.O.S.S. mode. The Charge Gauge depletes as the mode is in effect. Opponents can destroy the formation to end the mode early. When the player's Armor Gauge is depleted and the Rounder is in Vanish Mode, triggering B.O.S.S. mode activates FINAL B.O.S.S. mode, which puts the Rounder in a more powerful B.O.S.S. formation (with new abilities and more complex bullet patterns). However, destroying this formation also destroys the Rounder and ending the mode leaves the player open for a quick finish.Characters There are eight playable characters in WarTech: Senko no Ronde, each with a unique Rounder. Each Rounder has it's own unique speed, health, attacks, B.O.S.S. forms, and melee ranges. Players can also choose between two "cartridges" of Rounders, each with three color schemes, which contain differences in bullet patterns and slightly modified stats.                 Mika Mikli (Ventuno II)               Baek Changpo (Citronette)              Cuilan (Orangette)             Sakurako Sanjo (Triad)            Lili Levinas (Brinsta)           Ernula (Castrato)          Karel Werfel (Azureus) Xbox 360 InstallationThe amount of memory it takes to install this game is 1.2 GB.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15508">Gradius</game><game id="4819">Cyber Troopers Virtual-On: Oratorio Tangram</game><game id="11350">Zone of the Enders</game><game id="10225">Zone of the Enders: The 2nd Runner</game><game id="24285">Battle Rage: The Robot Wars</game><game id="34428">Strania: The Stella Machina</game><game id="38615">Ginga Force</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2314087-box_wartech.png</image></root>