<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15035</id><name>SimCity</name><description>OverviewAn example of a city.SimCity is a city-building simulation game released in 1989 and designed by eventual Sims creator Will Wright. SimCity, being Maxis' first game and originally based on the Commodore 64, has been adapted to several different personal computers and game consoles and has gone on to become one of the most successful and popular games of all time.Until the release of The Sims in 2000, the entire SimCity franchise was the most successful gaming franchise Maxis had created. Due to the immense popularity of SimCity, Maxis went on to create a multitude of other, similar simulation games, including SimTown and SimAnt., though none of these franchises has ever met the success of SimCity.GameplaySandbox vs. ScenarioAs would later to go on to define games of the SimCity franchise, the game first opens with the option of either building a city from the ground up (Sandbox) or running a city that is currently facing some issue or crisis (Scenario). In Sandbox mode, players choose a city site by choosing from a large list of premade maps and then giving a name to their city. Additionally, the Sandbox mode has no predefined goal or metric for "winning" the game, so players are free to run their cities as they see fit. Conversely, Scenarios have clearly defined metrics for winning (ex. double population in X years) and can be "lost".VersionsSimCity was developed for a wide range of platforms and has seen multiple re-releases, each with their own changes and additions.iPhoneAn iPhone version of SimCity is available now, but it isn't this version of the game. The iPhone version is a remake of Simcity 3000, with some added features (such as better advisers).SNESThe Super Nintendo version exhibited changes made by Nintendo, such as the addition of Bowser, and the character "Dr. Wright" who guides the player.SimCity EnhancedWhile the game play remained identical to the original PC release the CD-Rom enhanced edition featured Live Actors, Digitized Voice and Sound, and  Full Motion Video.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18915">Populous: The Beginning: Undiscovered Worlds</game><game id="14139">Spore</game><game id="6210">Populous</game><game id="2168">Viva Piñata</game><game id="4187">Romance of the Three Kingdoms II</game><game id="18748">Gemfire</game><game id="13760">SimCity 2000</game><game id="2447">SimTower: The Vertical Empire</game><game id="22003">A Kingdom for Keflings</game><game id="995">1701 A.D.</game><game id="11466">CivCity: Rome</game><game id="8760">1503 A.D.: The New World</game><game id="6724">1602 A.D.</game><game id="1643">Utopia</game><game id="8592">Caesar</game><game id="5652">Caesar II</game><game id="12757">Tropico</game><game id="7965">Tropico 2: Pirate Cove</game><game id="186">Stronghold</game><game id="15674">Overlord</game><game id="22300">Big Biz Tycoon</game><game id="7274">ActRaiser</game><game id="9515">Transport Tycoon</game><game id="6802">SimTown</game><game id="15262">Imperium Romanum</game><game id="21729">Cities XL</game><game id="21149">Populous DS</game><game id="24980">Grand Ages: Rome</game><game id="13657">City Life</game><game id="24951">City Life 2008</game><game id="21631">Little King's Story</game><game id="27594">Constructor 2</game><game id="15588">Klomanager - Spül mir das Lied vom Kot</game><game id="29384">City Rain</game><game id="30789">Coconut Queen</game><game id="30965">Lord of Ultima</game><game id="34620">Outer-Rim Pod Digger</game><game id="738">Black &amp; White 2: Battle of the Gods</game><game id="1128">The Settlers II: 10th Anniversary</game><game id="3642">The Settlers II: 10th Anniversary - Vikings</game><game id="16757">Tropico: Paradise Island</game><game id="32326">Tropico 4</game><game id="24458">Tropico 3</game><game id="1489">8th Wonder of the World</game><game id="6645">Caesar III</game><game id="30573">Tropico 3: Absolute Power</game><game id="4102">Emperor: Rise of the Middle Kingdom</game><game id="18721">Cultures</game><game id="19132">Cultures 2: The Gates of Asgard</game><game id="5457">Cultures: Die Abenteuerbox</game><game id="3009">Immortal Cities: Children of the Nile</game><game id="36949">Majesty 2: Battles of Ardania</game><game id="17680">Pharaoh</game><game id="10562">Populous II: Trials of the Olympian Gods</game><game id="5211">Zeus Official Expansion: Poseidon</game><game id="3769">Zeus: Master of Olympus</game><game id="9828">The Settlers: Rise of an Empire – The Eastern Realm</game><game id="2815">The Settlers: Rise of an Empire</game><game id="22372">The Settlers IV: The Trojans and the Elixir of Power</game><game id="22371">The Settlers IV: Mission CD</game><game id="16829">The Settlers II: Veni, Vidi, Vici</game><game id="3449">The Settlers II Mission CD</game><game id="15294">The Settlers III: Quest of the Amazons</game><game id="10978">The Settlers III</game><game id="2081">The Settlers II</game><game id="6946">The Settlers: Fourth Edition</game><game id="28310">The Settlers 7: Paths to a Kingdom</game><game id="12922">The Settlers</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/7622/643387-simcity.jpg</image></root>