<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15059</id><name>The Fool's Errand</name><description>OverviewTitle ScreenThe fool's errand is often referred to as a "meta-puzzle", because while there are several distinct puzzles in the game, solutions to one puzzle unlock clues and pieces in other puzzles. The central puzzle in the game is the Sun's Map, which is a large map presented in several pieces that must be reassembled. Along with the map, there is a story that describes the fool's journey through the world that contains several clues as to the map's layout. It is also the key to most of the puzzles in the game, and players will have to switch between the map, story, and one or more puzzles several times in order to complete the game.The game is available for Amiga, Mac, or PC as a free download.StoryThe Sun's MapThe following is a sample of some of the in-game story:One sunny day, a lighthearted Fool strolled along a hilly path, whistling a merry tune. A long wooden pole was slung over his shoulder and attached to it was a cloth bundle which carried his life’s possessions.“What a marvelous afternoon!” he exclaimed to no one in particular, pausing to appreciate the lovely countryside.Soon the trees parted and the path led to a small clearing, ending abruptly at the edge of a treacherous cliff. But the Fool was undaunted and kept at his swift pace, steadily approaching the sheer drop.Additional pieces of the story become unlocked as more puzzles are solved. Once every puzzle is completed, the entire story can then be read from beginning to end.SequelOne of Many PuzzlesOn October 26th, 2012, Cliff Johnson (creator of The Fool's Errand) self-published The Fool and his Money, the direct sequel to The Fool's Errand, for Mac and PC.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5786">3 In Three</game><game id="14311">At the Carnival</game><game id="40808">The Fool and his Money</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15568/610403-box2front.jpg</image></root>