<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1509</id><name>Amped: Freestyle Snowboarding</name><description>Lets Hit The Slopes Amped: Freestyle Snowboarding was developed by Access Software Inc. and published by Microsoft Studios. Amped was released during the launch of the Original Xbox as an exclusive title. The game hit the shelves on the 20th of November 2001  The launch of the game saw it given free in many of the bundle deals in some countries. Later this was lifted and people were charged for the game. Amped: Freestyle Snowboarding kick started the Amped Franchise.Gameplay Unlike snowboarding games before it, Amped focused more on the technical aspects of the game rather than racing down a mountain. With over 1000 tricks avaliable and mountains that are based on existing mountains, Amped offers large replay value with many different ways to descend the mountain. Characters are customizable with a choice of coats, hats, boots and so on. By completing challenges in the career mode you gain points enabling you to improve your skills. Amped offers a choice of 12 pro snowboarders.Career The career mode of the game required you to gain exposure by finding a sponsor and getting media coverage. Eventually you would reach start status and achieve a shop sponsor. From there the path involved beating more high scores to become a sponsored pro snowboarder and compete in the Jib-Fest, a world renowned snowboarding competition.Multiplayer allows up to four players to battle it out in various game modes. The soundtrack for Amped features over 150 track with the option for playing your own music straight from the built in HDD.Amped: Freestyle Snowboarding was followed by Amped 2 for the Original Xbox and Amped 3 on the Xbox 360. Both Amped 2 and Amped 3 feature online play that was not seen in Amped: Freestyle Snowboarding. </description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="33">Snowboarding/Skiing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17149">SSX 3</game><game id="20954">Shaun White Snowboarding</game><game id="19339">1080° Avalanche</game><game id="17969">SSX Blur</game><game id="18946">1080° Snowboarding</game><game id="12418">SSX on Tour</game><game id="15277">TransWorld Snowboarding</game><game id="23479">Stoked</game><game id="25097">Shaun Palmer's Pro Snowboarder</game><game id="24449">We Ski &amp; Snowboard</game><game id="21727">MTV Sports: Snowboarding</game><game id="20880">We Ski</game><game id="1932">SSX</game><game id="42370">R: Rock'n Riders</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2136536-box_amped.png</image></root>