<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15090</id><name>Policenauts</name><description>OverviewThe PolicenautsPolicenauts is the spiritual successor to Snatcher, both of which have been designed by Hideo Kojima. It takes place in the year 2040 on Earth and within the space colony orbiting high above it, Beyond Coast. It is similar to a point-and-click adventure game and even features mouse support (this is even suggested within the manual as a better means of control). It also features action sequences where the player must shoot targets onscreen in a gallery-format reminiscent of the approach taken by titles such as Virtua Cop and even its predecessor, Snatcher.It was first relesaed on the NEC-PC9821, a Japanese microcomputer, on July 29, 1994, with both a CD-ROM and an installation floppy disk The cut scenes were rendered with hand-drawn pixels than as compressed animation in the anime-style.Policenauts: Pilot Disk was also released for the 3DO on April 21, 1995, containing a playable demo, an interviews with the voice actors behind what would become the standard edition of the game along with the developers, and an extensive encyclopedia describing the concepts within the title's detailed backstory.The first console version version was released on September 29, 1995, for the 3DO and featured extensive enhancements. CG effects were added in, most notably with the mechs that were used within the game, and hand-drawn animation sequences augmented the cut scenes. This would be considered the standard edition of the game that would later be enhanced for its debut on the PlayStation.When the PlayStation version arrived on January 19, 1996, it would feature further cleanup on both the graphics and the movie footage created for the 3DO release. It would also come on two discs. The Saturn would receive the last version of the game on September 13, 1996. It would arrive on three disks and feature support for the Virtua Gun peripheral.On February 9, 1996, Policenauts: Private Collection was released for the PlayStation with the material from Policenauts: Pilot Disk along with a copy of an earlier script of the game included as a bonus. Everything that had been a part of the Pilot Disk release was made available in this release.Policenauts was re-released under the "Konami the Best" label on September 18, 1997, and then again under the "PSone Books" series on August 7, 2003. It was added to the PlayStation Store's Japanese Game Archives on May 15, 2008, making it available as a downloadable title for the PSP and the PS3.English LocalizationThe Saturn version was expected to be released for American audiences, however it was never released. Hideo Kojima had cited that work had begun on it, but the developers were unable to synchronize the English dialogue with the FMV cut-scenes.However, a fan translation of the game was pursued. Marc Laidlaw and Artemio Urbina worked on a translation of the game during 2007, but could not find a programmer capable of inserting the material. In August, 2008, Something Awful forum member Michael Sawyer began experimenting with different approaches to inserting the text and on August 24, 2009, the patch was released coinciding with Hideo Kojima's 46th birthday.StoryIn the year 2013, Jonathan Ingram is a 'Policenaut' - an astronaut with police training - whose duty is to protect Beyond Coast, man's first space colony.While testing a prototype spacesuit, it malfunctions and sends him into deep space where he is presumed dead. Twenty-five years later, Jonathan is discovered alive (thanks to the emergency cryo-sleep module in the space suit which also explains why he also has not aged). With everything that he has known having changed in the last two and a half decades, he attempts to eke out a living by returning to Earth and work as a private detective in Los Angeles.He is visited by his ex-wife (Lorraine) who had believed him to be dead and whom he had never thought to visit on Beyond Coast ever since he was found a few years earlier. The meeting for her is just as awkward, but she has no one else to turn to when her husband (Kenzo Hojyo) disappears. She asks him to investigate the matter and although Jonathan refuses to accept the case at first and Lorraine quietly leaves.However, looking outside of his window, he spies someone suspicious near her car and realizing that something might be wrong, he runs out to the street below his office only to watch as Lorraine's car explodes, killing her. Giving chase to the mysterious saboteur, he manages to shoot him several times but ultimately loses him when he escapes on a motorcycle.Determined to learn the truth behind Lorraine's death, the only clue he has is the fact that she was a citizen on Beyond Coast. Having vowed not to go back into space after his incident, he forces himself to take a flight there to crack the case and confront his past.GameplayMuch of the game is played very much like a point-and-click adventure game as the player moves from scene to scene. Everything is seen from first-person with scenes represented as stills allowing the player to move the cursor over them in search of items, clues, or interactive hot-spots such as being able to use a computer or a television to catch up on the latest news.The game uses a mix of mediums from still-images to animated CG effects. Anime-styled FMV is used as a storytelling device for dramatic sequences.The game also incorporates shooting sequences with the player controlling a targeting cursor onscreen. Puzzles, such as uncovering a hidden bomb and then defusing it in a step-by-step process, were only two of the challenges that players were confronted with in the game. Speaking to different characters, hearing their views on different topics, and exploring the environment were every bit as important and added to the entertainment value of the title as well as capturing many of the personalities within it.As is typical of most of Hideo Kojima's work, Policenauts also features a well-developed lexicon of terms, cultural nuances, and philosophical themes that help distinguish its cyberpunk-like world. It also features Meryl Silverburgh who would go on to have a role in Metal Gear Solid and the hero is also notable for his smoking habit.CharactersPolicenauts features a wide variety of characters to interact with, each with their own distinctive personalities, hang-ups, andJonathan Ingram - He's one of the five "Original Cops" that formed the first Policenauts on Beyond Coast. He was performing a spacewalk with an experimental EVA suit when things went wrong, sending him into deep space where his emergency cryo-capsule saved his life while stopping him from aging. Although 25 years had passed, he still resembles someone in his twenties as a result. It is through his eyes that the player will unravel the mystery. Voiced by Hideyuki Tanaka.Lorraine Hojo - Jonathan's ex-wife who comes to him on Earth from Beyond Coast hoping that he will help her find her missing husband. She hasn't seen Jonathan since he had disappeared twenty-five years earlier, although she had always known where he was on Earth. She is murdered at the start of the game in front of Jonathan's eyes which spurs him into his quest. Voiced by Chiyoko Kawashima.Ed Brown - The chief of Beyond Coast's Vice Unit, he was Jonathan's partner during their days in the LAPD and was one of the Original Cops. The Vice Unit is considered a dead end career path and Ed is simply trying to make it to retirement until Jonathan arrives. He and his duo of investigators eventually partner up with his old friend to help uncover the mystery surrounding Lorraine's death, albeit unofficially. Voiced by Shozo Iizuka.Anna Brown - Ed's young, teenaged daughter attending college is also a gymnastics prodigy. She takes care of the house when her father is away, along with her adopted little brother, Marc, her mother having died some years earlier. Voiced by Yumi Toma.Marc Brown - Ed's adopted son. His real father was driven violently mad by drugs and the police had been called onto the scene. With Marc at risk, Ed was forced to shoot his father to defend him and had adopted him afterwards. Since that time, Marc hasn't spoken.Karen Hojo - A popular anchorwoman at Beyond Coast, she is Lorraine's daughter and bears a strong resemblance to her mother when Jonathan and her were married. Voiced by Kikuko Inoue.Tony Redwood - He is a Frozener, the slang term for an artificially-conceived human who have been genetically enhanced to operate in extraterrestrial environments. He's a member of the Advance Police, Beyond Coast's version of a SWAT team, and an ace mecha pilot. Voiced by Kaneto Shiozawa.Salvatore Toscanini - One of the "Original Cops", he had quit the force to work in the private sector. He is now the Chief of Security at Tokugawa's Moon Plant. Voiced by Masaharu Sato.Joseph Sadaoki Tokugawa - One of the "Original Cops", he had left the force to inherit his family's business, the Tokugawa Group. As one of the key corporations responsible for the construction of Beyond Coast, Tokugawa wields considerable influence and power within the colony. Voiced by Iemasa Kayumi.Gates Becker - One of the "Original Cops", he had remained with the force and is now the Chief of the BCP and the commander of the Advance Police. He is a no-nonsense personality who sticks to the rules no matter what the situation might be. He allows Jonathan to work with Ed on his investigation so long as it doesn't interfere with regular police business. Voiced by Osamu Saka.Dave Forrest - A member of the BCP's Vice Unit, he has a penchant for hamburgers and wears an orange vest and goggles. He has a secret crush on his partner, Meryl, but he is also a top investigator who helps Jonathan and Ed. He also has a thing for plastic dinosaurs. Voiced by Bin Shimada.Meryl Silverburgh - A member of the BCP's Vice Unit, she was a former member of a military unit named FOXHOUND and is usually seen at the office in a black tank top and military issue camo. She is portrayed as a rough and tumble character who won't go on a date with a person until they can beat her score in the simulator (similar to the challenge given by Red Sonja in to Schwarzenegger's character in the film of the same name). Voiced by Megumi Terase.Chris Goldwin - A former model, she now runs the Beyond Coast Central Hospital. She knows Jonathan as one of the Original Cops having done a photo shoot with them twenty-five years earlier. Voiced by Chiyoko Kawashima.Kenzo Hojo - The missing husband of Lorraine, he was a scientist working as the head of one of Tokugawa's manufacturing and research departments. It is his disappearance that spurs Lorraine to travel to Earth in seeking Jonathan's help.Michael Saito - A security guard at the front desk of Tokugawa Pharmaceuticals. Voiced by Nobutoshi Canna.Victor Jurgens - He works at the BCP as a forensic pathologist aided by an AI named Gorby who runs the Auto-analysis Identification Device (AID). He has seen nearly everything there is to see in his field. Voiced by Kohei Miyauchi.Jun Ishida - A pharmacist working for the Beyond Coast Central Hospital. Voiced by Naoki Tatsuta.SoundtrackPolicenauts Original SoundtrackThe soundtrack for Policenauts was primarily composed by Konami veterans Motoaki Furukawa and Tappy Iwase, who would later compose the main themes for the Metal Gear Solid franchise. It was first released in Japan on February 3rd, 1995. The soundtrack features music reminiscent of detective and 'buddy cop' films of the 1980s.PolicenautsTotal Length: 1:08:18"Legendary Faces" - 1:13"Opening Title "Old L.A. 2040"" - 7:17"Criminal Investigation Part 1" - 1:17"L'amour Impossible" - 1:06"Embarrasment ~Murder~ Shoot For Angels" - 2:24"Capturing" - 0:55"The End of Beyond" - 0:53"The Zone" - 0:58"28 Years" - 1:33"Call Your Name" - 2:17"First Triangle" - 1:12"Theme from "News Order" - 0:52"Girls" - 1:36"Landfall" - 1:20"BCP H.Q." - 1:08"Magic Subway" - 1:11"Dear My Friend" - 1:38"Lavender" - 5:00"Innocence White" - 1:08"No, No, No!" - 1:15"Mission 307" - 2:01"Sweet Home" - 0:53"Ana's Theme" - 2:11"Owl-Cat" - 1:00"Investigate" - 0:48"My Love" - 2:15"Domestic Moon" - 1:19"Abandoned Launcher" - 1:14"Atmosphere In Gray" - 0:59"Living in the Real World" - 2:14"Icy Offence of Clouds" - 1:40"Stouthearted" - 1:14"Past Year At Sunset Beach" - 1:10"End of the Dark" - 2:04"Karen" - 2:46""Policenauts" End Title" - 2:09</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12552">Snatcher</game><game id="991">Psy-O-Blade</game><game id="31637">Marine Philt</game><game id="5758">Famicom Tantei Club Part II: Ushiro ni Tatsu Shoujo</game><game id="34672">Shadowrun</game><game id="28342">Metal Slader Glory: Director's Cut</game><game id="28224">Steins;Gate</game><game id="1705">Yu-No: Kono Yo no Hate de Koi o Utau Shoujo</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5150/1681772-tumblr_lewrfh47sb1qzurbto1_500.jpg</image></root>