<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15143</id><name>Knights of the Round</name><description>Knights of the Round is a     side-scrolling brawler - in the same genre as   games like         Final Fight  -  developed by    Capcom in the early 1990s. The game is very loosely  based  on Arthurian legend. It follows the exploits the legendary   King  Arthur  and two of his Knights of the Round Table, Percival and  Lancelot, as  they attempt to overthrow king Garibaldi and take his  throne.  Knights  of the Round plays virtually identically to its contemporary  games. All three characters have an attack button and jump button.   Pressing  the attack button several times performs powerful combination  attacks,  while pressing back attack allows the knights to block most  incoming  attacks.  By pressing both attack and jump at the same time,  the knights  will perform a powerful spinning attack which will knock  back nearby  enemies, at the expense of some of the hero's lifebar;  however, the life in the lifebar could be replenished by eating a hearty  helping of turkey which could be found in crates and other smashable  objects.  Additionally,  the knights can mount  horses, which vastly  increases their combat  prowess.  Though the characters play very similarly, each knight  has strengths  and weaknesses.   Arthur  is the balanced character, with decent  speed and strength.Lancelot is a speedy  character, with great  maneuverability but less strength.Percival  is  a large, slow character, who has very powerful attacks.   Knights  of the Round did have a feature rarely seen in brawlers. As  the  knights dispatched enemies, they gained experience which increased  their  stats and made them more effective in combat. As each character   leveled up, their appearance changed as well.  For instance, Percival   starts the game with blond hair and a bare chest. As he levels up, he   becomes bald, with much bulkier armor. </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14351">Golden Axe</game><game id="5402">Golden Axe II</game><game id="20436">Streets of Rage</game><game id="6722">Final Fight</game><game id="5996">Kung-Fu Master</game><game id="4146">Vigilante</game><game id="18293">Renegade</game><game id="20752">Double Dragon</game><game id="2536">Altered Beast</game><game id="1618">The Ninja Warriors</game><game id="10696">Captain America and the Avengers</game><game id="20733">Castle Crashers</game><game id="905">Gekido</game><game id="8112">Viewtiful Joe 2</game><game id="922">Final Fight: Streetwise</game><game id="18034">Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles IV: Turtles in Time</game><game id="12536">The Adventures of Bayou Billy</game><game id="2838">Bujingai: The Forsaken City</game><game id="21334">The Lord of the Rings: The Two Towers</game><game id="13072">Devil May Cry</game><game id="6510">Valis: The Fantasm Soldier</game><game id="4325">Magic Sword</game><game id="22857">Battletoads</game><game id="22872">Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Shadow Over Mystara</game><game id="22870">Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Tower of Doom</game><game id="11762">Battle Master</game><game id="25800">Warrior Blade - Rastan III</game><game id="3796">The King of Dragons</game><game id="28126">Dungeon Fighter Online</game><game id="32643">Dungeon Magic</game><game id="28897">Samurai Deeper Kyo</game><game id="37267">Hook</game><game id="7950">The Peace Keepers</game><game id="30494">Charlie Murder</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2363908-snes_knightsoftheround.jpg</image></root>