<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15203</id><name>Turtles</name><description>InstructionsThe following is taken from the game's instruction booklet: 		TO BEGIN: Insert the cartridge into the slot of the Odyssey console or into The Voice of Odyssey with the label side of the cartridge facing the alpha-numeric keyboard.Turn on the power by pressing the power button of the console. The TURTLES game title will appear on your TV screen. If it does not, press the RESET key on the alpha-numeric keyboard. 			The Voice enhances this game with authentic arcade music. 		TURTLES! 		(1 or more players) 		To start the game, move the joystick of either hand control.The screen will display the first floor of the "Turtle Towers Hotel." Use the same joystick to control your turtle who you will always find in the lower right corner of the screen. It will move in the same direction that you move the joystick. 			Bottom of game screen is broken into five sections:  							3    							03    							000000    							00    							1    							Turtles    							 Bug Bombs     							 Current Score     							 Turtles rescued     							 Game level   Each room in the "Turtle Towers Hotel" contains a question mark. When your turtle touches a question mark, it will turn into a baby turtlet or a beetle.A baby turtlet will climb on your turtle's back and a house will appear somewhere around the edge of the screen. Your objective is to carry the baby turtlet home without being bugged by the beetles.Beetles always start off blue and "blind." They move randomly on the screen. BUT - beetles grow up quick! When blue beetles turn yellow they can see your turtle along straight line. AND - when the beetles turn red they can actually see around corners. The longer it takes you to bring all the baby turtlets home, the more dangerous the beetles become.A turtle touched by a beetle is zapped on contact - but you do have three extra turtles per game.BUG BOMBS!!!!!! Your turtle can temporarily de-bug a beetle by putting a bug bomb in its path. Your turtle starts each game with three of them. These bug bombs are so powerful that your turtle can travel through a de-bugged beetle without worry. A bug bomb will also make even a dangerous red beetle turn blue and "blind" when it recovers.To drop a bug bomb, press the action button of your hand control. It will momentarily halt any beetle crossing its path. Pick up additional bug bombs by sending your turtle over the "x" at the center of the screen whenever it's flashing. A turtle can carry up to 99 bug bombs at a time.A bug bomb alarm will sound when your turtle has run out of them.Only one bug bomb can be on screen at any one time.When you have rescued all the baby turtlets on one floor, your turtle will climb up the next floor - where you will find more beetles and fewer bug bombs. The higher the floor, the harder the game.You get three turtles per game plus a bonus turtle after scoring 5000 points.A game ends when you run out of turtles. If you want to start a new game immediately, move the joystick. If you want to check the high score, wait a moment. The screen will automatically change to the outside of the"Turtle Towers Hotel." The high score is a series of games will appear on top.To play again, move the joystick of either hand control.SCORING:Discovering a baby turtlet   							100 points  Carrying a baby turtlet to a house     							150 points  Discovering a bug   							80 points  Stunning bug with Bug Bomb   							50 points  The winner is the player scoring the highest number of points over a predetermined number of games or after a predetermined length of time.To start a completely new scoring cycle, press RESET and move the joystick of either hand control. 		</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1306/240173-587854_39936_front.jpg</image></root>