<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15254</id><name>Game &amp; Watch Collection</name><description>Overview Game  Watch collection was originally only available through Club Nintendo in Japan; featured on the cartridge are three multi-screen Game  Watch games, Oil Panic, Donkey Kong and Green House.  The three games are direct ports of the original and the player may choose between Game A or the harder Game B when selecting a game.  Game  Watch Collection also has the alarm clock, which was a feature  present on the old Game  Watch systems.Oil Panic On the upper screen, use the D-pad to catch the falling drops of oil in a bucket that Mr. Game  Watch is holding.  The bucket can hold up to three drops at a time before they must be dumped out the window to a computer controlled character who is down below.  However, you must dump the oil into the computer controlled characters bucket or else it will land on the pedestrians on street.  If the player fails to catch the falling oil drops, they will land on a hot kettle, a burner or a hot plate, starting a fire.  If three drops of oil fall onto the burners or if three buckets get dumped on a pedestrian then the game ends.Donkey Kong A variation on the classic Arcade game, maneuver Mr. Game  Watch up the steel girders in order to make it to the top.  Once on top the player must pull a lever which will activate a crane, have Mr. Game  Watch jump on the crane to take out a link that is supporting the platform Donkey Kong is on.  Remove the four supports on the platform to knock Donkey Kong off.  Each time you successfully knock him off, more obstacles will appear in your way, making it more challenging.  Green House Use Mr. Game  Watch's bug spray to attack an oncoming pest invasion in a green house.  There are four flowers to protect, two in the top corners of the upper screen and two in the bottom corners of the lower screen.  The player must then move Mr. Game  Watch between the two screens spraying the bugs who wish to eat the plants.  On the top screen, worms appear, moving to one of the two flowers, spray them to kill them.  On the bottom screen, spiders will appear from one of two cob webs, spray them when they're directly over the plant to kill them, or use multiple sprays to push them back up the screen and into the web. If three flowers get eaten then the game ends.</description><genres><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10965">EA Replay</game><game id="33488">Super Meat Boy HANDHELD!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2549839-box_gawc.png</image></root>