<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15262</id><name>Imperium Romanum</name><description>OverviewSet in the time-honoured Roman Empire players will marvel at the incredible attention to detail, as they construct fortifications, build towers, gates and bridges, and pay for them with the new currency which has been implemented into the game for a challenging, enjoyable, and authentic quest to rule the World.  "Imperium Romanum" boasts a variety of new features to enhance the game-play and complete the historical strategy gaming experience. These include a sophisticated graphics engine, a mass of authentic historical buildings such as the world famous Circus Maximus and Gladiator schools, an improved battle system where the player commands their armies and an interactive mission mode which allows the player to control the activation of goals.  Features   History mode with timeline, where missions are based on real events and locations   Interactive mission mode: the players activate the goals when they choose   Improved battle system where players commands their own armies   Player-constructable bridges, fortifications, walls, towers and gates   Introduction of currency, crime, historically accurate buildings, natural disasters, and siege machines   New interface design, and improved economy and overview dialogues  System Requirements  Minimum    Windows 2000, XP or Vista    Pentium / AMD Processor with at least 1,7 GHz    DirectX 9 compatible Graphic Card    (Geforce 3 / Radeon 9550 or better)    512 mb Ram    DVD-ROM Drive    1,5 gb free disk space    DirectX 9.0c  RecommendedWindows 2000, XP or Vista    Pentium / AMD Processor with at least 2 GHz    DirectX 9 compatible Graphic Card    GeForce 6600GT or better    1 gb Ram    8 x DVD-ROM Drive    1,5 gb free disk space    DirectX 9.0c </description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20660">Command &amp; Conquer: Red Alert 3</game><game id="20674">StarCraft II: Wings of Liberty</game><game id="17551">Command &amp; Conquer 3: Tiberium Wars</game><game id="16457">Sid Meier's Civilization IV</game><game id="1594">Sid Meier's Civilization III</game><game id="10733">SimCity 3000</game><game id="13760">SimCity 2000</game><game id="15035">SimCity</game><game id="24980">Grand Ages: Rome</game><game id="23783">SimAnimals</game><game id="13844">Glory of the Roman Empire</game><game id="24079">StarCraft II: Legacy of the Void</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14014/565427-boxcover.jpg</image></root>