<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15398</id><name>Mario Power Tennis</name><description>OverviewMario Power Tennis is a tennis game for the Nintendo Gamecube where Mario and friends duke it out on various themed tennis courts. The game came out on November 8, 2004, and was re-released for the Nintendo Wii on March 9, 2009 with new motion controls.GameplayA match on Luigi's Gimmick Court, where ghosts can slow down characters.The basic format of Mario Power Tennis is similar to other tennis video games. There are a variety of characters, each with different styles like, "Speed," "Technique," or "All-Around," which the player can use as a guide to how that character moves or how they handle the ball. Generally, the basic rules of tennis apply, and you can play with singles or doubles. A shot which bounces within court limits and out without a player returning the ball is considered a point. However, a number of Nintendo-themed touches alter the sport's basic rules.Rallying the ball back and forth builds up your Special Shot, which you can then release at any time. These are over-the-top moves designed to bring one player or team back from what may have been a defeat. There are two types of special shots, offensive and defensive. For example, using Boo's offensive special will cause a more powerful curve shot that is surrounded by small ghosts, obscuring the opposing team's view of the ball. His defensive shot will cause him to split up into a dozen or more Boos, allowing him to return the ball even if he is nowhere near it. These special abilities can be turned off if the player wants a more traditional experience.Mario's offensive special, where he whacks an incoming ball with a giant hammer.Gimmick Courts also add in more Nintendo flavor. A number of courts borrow imagery from Super Mario Sunshine, Donkey Kong, Luigi's Mansion, and so on. These courts have special features that may alter the flow of the game. For example, on the Donkey Kong court, Klaptraps walk across the net. If the ball hits a Klaptrap, it will run into the opposing team's court and latch onto them, making them slower and putting them at a disadvantage.The game can be played with friends via local multiplayer that supports up to 4 players.Challenge ModesA number of challenge modes complement the game's Tournament and Exhibition (quick action) modes. These are akin to minigames but still use the game's basic controls. These challenges usually require you to maintain control of the ball and where it is landing. You may need to get balls through rings floating above the court, or use colored balls to paint a picture. Completing Tournaments with different characters as well as completing challenges will unlock hidden characters and other extras.New Play Control - Wii VersionMario Power Tennis was re-released on Nintendo Wii as part of the company's New Play Control line. This version has some small graphical improvements (mostly in the form of increased sharpness) as well as a Nunchuck and Remote control scheme. Diagonal swipes of the remote do regular shots, horizontal swipes do slices, upward swipes do lobs, and smashing downward when a star is painted on the court will do a power shot. Special moves can be activated by using A or B plus a swinging motion.Critics have vocalized their opinions that the motion controls, while functional, are no substitute for the Gamecube's traditional, pad-based controls.On June 10th, 2012, Mario Power Tennis joined the Nintendo Selects line for the Wii.Starting Characters:Mario:Mario Power Tennis - Character ArtAn "all around" type character that has no particular strengths nor weaknesses. His offensive power shot is Iron Hammer and his defensive power shot is Spin Jump Return.Luigi:Mario Power Tennis - Character ArtAlso an "all around" character, his offensive power shot is Squeaky Mallet and his defensive power shot is Poltergust Return.Peach:Mario Power Tennis - Character ArtHas an offensive power shot called Super Peach Spin and a defensive power shot called Sweet Kiss Return. Peach is a "technique" type player focusing more consistent and somewhat high level play.Daisy:Mario Power Tennis - Character ArtJust like Peach, Daisy is another "technique" player. Her offensive power shot is Wonder Flower and her defensive power shot is Flowerbed Return.Wario:Mario Power Tennis - Character ArtA "power" player who relies on strong shots to overwhelm his opponent. Wario's offensive power shot is Thunder Cast Shot and his defensive power shot is Ultra-Hand Return.Waluigi:Mario Power Tennis - Character ArtThe only "defensive" staring character relying on consistent volleys and returns in order to beat his opponents. His offensive power shot is Whirluigi and his defensive power shot is Swimming Return.Bowser:Mario Power Tennis - Character ArtOf course Bowser is a "power" player with an offensive power shot called Fire Breath and a defensive shot called Spinner Shell Dash.Donkey Kong:Mario Power Tennis - Character ArtAnother "power" player who has an offensive power shot of Barrel Cannon Blast and a defensive power shot Boomerang Banana Return.Diddy Kong:Mario Power Tennis - Character ArtA "speedy" character who banks on being able to cover most of the court easily and return any trick shot thrown his way. Diddy has an offensive power shot called Acrobatic Banana and a defensive power shot called Barrel Jet.Yoshi:Mario Power Tennis - Character ArtA "speedy" character who can travel the court easily. Yoshi's offensive power shot is Rainbow Flutter and his defensive power shot is Rolling Egg Return.Boswer Jr.:Mario Power Tennis - Character ArtA "tricky" character who relies on faking the opponent out in order to score points and win games. Bowser Jr.'s offensive power shot is Magic Paint and his defensive power shot is Rolling Brush Return.Koopa Trooper:Mario Power Tennis - Character ArtThe final starting "speedy" character with an offensive power shot of Water Bomb and a defensive power shot of Water Shell Dash.Boo:Mario Power Tennis - Character ArtThe final starting "tricky" character with an offensive power shot of Boo Blast and a defensive power shot of Boo Brigade Return.Shy Guy:Mario Power Tennis - Character ArtThe final starting character and the final "technique" starting character. Shy Guy has Lightning Spear as an offensive power shot and Spear Dance Return as a defensive power shot.Unlockable Characters:Fly Guy:Fly Guy in Mario Power TennisA "tricky" character that's similar to the Shy Guy but with a propeller on his head which enables flight. You can unlock the Fly Guy by beating singles Mushroom, Flower, and Star cups. His shots are the offensive Tornado Twist and the defensive Tornado Return.Paratrooper:Paratrooper in Mario Power TennisA koopa with wings the Paratrooper is a "technique" that is unlocked by winning 3 of the normal tournament cups. His offensive power shot is Energy Ball and his defensive power shot Sky Dive.Wiggler:Wiggler in Mario Power TennisUnlocked by winning the Flower cup doubles this "defensive" character has an offensive power shot called Anger Management and a defensive power shot called Flutter Return.Petey Piranha:Petey Piranha in Mario Power TennisWinning the Fire and Thunder special tournaments will unlock Petey for play. A "power" character Petey has Sludge Racket as his offensive power shot and Piranha Swingback as a defensive power shot.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="25">Tennis</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20578">Sega Superstars Tennis</game><game id="814">Mario Superstar Baseball</game><game id="16770">Rockstar Games presents Table Tennis</game><game id="3038">Tennis Critters</game><game id="24286">Cocoto Tennis Master</game><game id="24759">The Tennnis</game><game id="22168">Hot Shots Tennis</game><game id="24396">Grand Slam Tennis</game><game id="30171">VT Tennis</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2160626-box_mpt.png</image></root>