<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15413</id><name>Dynasty Warriors 2</name><description>Overview Dynasty Warriors 2 is the second installment of Koei's popular fighting game franchise, and the first game to move from the original's one-on-one fighting structure. The game is heavily influenced by the Romance of the Three Kingdoms novel written by Luo Guanzhong in the 14th century, which is one of the Four Great Classical Novels of Chinese Literature.      The game has you control one of 28 characters as you fight through China's turbulent Three Kingdoms era in a bid to unite the land under one rule, starting with the Yellow Turban Rebellion in 184AD, and ending with either the Battle of Yi Ling in 222AD or the Battle of Wu Zhang Plains in 234AD, depending on the allegiance of your chosen character. The series is most known for the large scale of the battles depicted, offering hundreds of combatants on the field with a KO count of over a thousand being easily attainable by the player. Characters The game initially allows for the selection of 9 characters, with an additional 20 that become available after being unlocked. This title sees an additional 14 characters added to the original's roster, with the exclusion of Oda Nobunaga and Toukichi (both likely removed as they are part of Japan's Sengoku era). Characters that have no allegiance to Shu, Wei or Wu are only usable in Free Mode.   Stages There are a total of eight stages in the game that can be accessed either by playing through the Musou/Story mode, or by selecting them individually in Free Mode. Each of the stages are based on actual battles that took place in history.  The Yellow Turban Rebellion (184AD, Imperial Forces vs. Yellow Turbans)  Battle of Hu Lao Gate (191AD, Allied Forces vs. Dong Zhou Forces) Battle of Guan Du (200AD, Cao Cao's Forces vs. Yuan Shao's Forces) Battle of Chang Ban (208AD, Liu Bei's Forces vs. Cao Cao's Forces) Battle of Chi Bi (208AD, Liu Bei and Sun Quan's Forces vs. Cao Cao's Forces) Battle of He Fei (215AD, Sun Quan's Forces vs. Cao Cao's Forces) Battle of Yi Ling (222AD, Sun Quan's Forces vs. Liu Bei's Forces) Battle of Wu Zhang Plains (234AD, Liu Bei's Forces vs. Cao Cao's Forces) Trivia  Dynasty Warriors 2 was a launch title for the Playstation 2 in North America. The game was not marketed as a direct sequel in Japan and was instead given the name Shin Sangokumusou, which has lead to a discrepancy in title numbers for international releases as Shin Sangokumusou 2 in Japan is Dynasty Warriors 3 in English territories. The song that plays during the credit sequence is Can't Quit This!!! ～KNOCK'EM OUT～, performed  by Japanese electronica/dance group m.o.v.e. Despite the ESRB rating of Teen for only "Animated Violence", the word "fuck" can be heard among the lyrics.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10139">Samurai Warriors</game><game id="20871">Samurai Warriors 2: Xtreme Legends</game><game id="21972">Samurai Warriors 2: Empires</game><game id="22123">Mystic Heroes</game><game id="8556">Drakengard</game><game id="24042">Ninety-Nine Nights II</game><game id="23839">Devil Kings</game><game id="5552">Warriors Orochi</game><game id="20792">Warriors Orochi 2</game><game id="23886">Sengoku Basara 2</game><game id="23885">Sengoku Basara 2 Heroes</game><game id="22555">Demon Chaos</game><game id="29036">Fist of the North Star:  Ken's Rage</game><game id="38563">Fist of the North Star: Ken's Rage 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2126434-box_dw2.png</image></root>