<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1541</id><name>Darkstalkers 3</name><description>OverviewVampire Savior: The Lord of Vampire is a 2D Gothic horror-themed fighting game developed and released by Capcom for arcades (using the CPS-2 hardware) on May 1997. The third installment of the Darkstalkers franchise (and the sequel to Night Warriors: Darkstalkers' Revenge), Vampire Savior further modifies the roster (replacing Donovan Baine, Huitzil, and Pyron with four new characters: young succubus Lilith, bee/human hybrid Q-Bee, schizophrenic psychopath B.B. Hood, and dark vampire savior Jedah Dohma) while adding two new gameplay enhancements: Damage Gauge System (which replaces the traditional round-based system, in which both player's lifebars are restored between rounds, with a multi-lifebar system, and allows players to slowly regain a portion of their lifebar by avoiding further damage) and Dark Force System (a manuever, activated by pressing a Punch and Kick button of the same strength simultaneously, that temporarily grants the player character special properties unique to that character). The game also includes two secret character variations ("dark" versions of Jon Talbain and Bishamon) and a special secret character (Shadow) who changes characters between matches to the last defeated opponent.The story involves the resurrected dark messiah Jedah Dohma, who is displeased with the state of the Demon World and decides to recreate it.Two minor updates were released to Japanese arcades simultaenously on September 1997, titled Vampire Hunter 2: Darkstalkers' Revenge and Vampire Savior 2: The Lord of Vampire. Both games feature minor gameplay adjustments (such as tweaking the power of the Dark Force mechanic, removing character-specific boss fights and endings, and recoloring stages and CPU opponents), and only differ from each other by their character roster (Vampire Hunter 2 including the roster from Night Warriors: Darkstalkers' Revenge). Both updates also adds another special secret character (Marionette), who changes characters between matches to the current opponent (creating mirror matches).An port of the original Vampire Savior was ported to the Saturn (in Japan only) on April 16, 1998, adding back in Donovan Baine, Huitzil, and Pyron. An enhanced port was released for the PlayStation (titled Darkstalkers 3 in the U.S. and Vampire Savior: EX Edition in Japan) on November 30, 1998, adding all characters and gameplay mechanics from all three versions (each character now has two modes: Dark Force Change for the original version and Dark Force Power for the updated versions) while adding new secrets (including new secret character variations and custom gameplay changes) and a custom character option (allowing players to re-color any character and build up their stats by earning experience points).The game will be remastered in HD as part of Darkstalkers Resurrection for XBLA and PSN (alongside Night Warriors: Darkstalkers' Revenge).CharactersJedahFour new characters were introduced in Darkstalkers 3. Unlike in previous titles, some characters have to fight different characters for their final battle. Most characters do however have to fight against Jedah as their final battle. Also, if certain conditions are met, a character with extra dialog will challenge the player on the fourth round. Similar to Akuma in Super Street Fighter 2 Turbo, a more powerful version of Bishamon can be faced after the final boss if certain conditions are met. This powered up Bishamon is playable in the console via an input code in the character select screen. While not actual fighting game characters, Shadow and Marionette can also be selected to play as the last character defeated and the current character you are fighting against respectively.New CharactersB.B. HoodJedahLilithQ-BeeReturning CharactersAnakarisBishamonDemitriDonovanFeliciaHsien-KoHuitzilJ. TalbainLord RaptorMorriganPyronRikuoSasquatchVictorHidden CharactersBishamon (Oboro)ShadowMarionetteGame ModesDarkstalkers 3 has most of the standard fighting game modes that one would expect. Arcade, Versus, Training and Options are all present. Darkstalkers 3 also throws in an Original Character mode were the play can edit the name and colors of any Darkstalker. There is a Collection mode of game art and extra options that can be unlocked by playing and leveling up in the Original Character mode.ArcadeFight through eight CPU controlled opponents with a player chosen difficulty between one and eight. When certain conditions are met the player may also fight against Oboro Bishamon or a special mid-boss.VersusTwo human controlled players can fight head to head. Players may also choose their handicap and stage they wish to play.TrainingThe Training mode in Darkstalkers 3 gives several options to players when they pause the game and press select.Original CharacterOriginal character allows players to rename and recolor any Darkstalker and battle with them to level up and unlock game art and extra options. The player must win battles, perform special moves in order to collect enough experience. Three parts of the character can be leveled up, Health Stock (the number of bats a player has), Damage caused by attacks and how full the players Super Meter (SS Guage) is at the start of the battle.When certain levels are reached the player receives a small reward.Level 1: Page 2 of art in Collections is unlocked .Level 2: EX Options are unlocked.Level 3: Page 3 of art in Collections is unlocked.Level 4: Page 4 of art in Collections is unlocked.Level 5: DX Options are unlocked in the Options Menu.CollectionCollection is a basic art gallery. Page 1 is unlocked at the start of the game and the rest of the pages must be unlocked in the Original Character mode by leveling up a character.OptionsSome options directly effect gameplay, such as the difficulty level, which can be changed from 1 to 8; 8 being the hardest. Players may also choose what speed the game is in turbo mode, how many health stocks will be given during the match as well as how much damage the characters deal. Things like the timer, shortcut and dual shock vibrations can be toggled on or off. Other things can be adjusted such as screen position and controller layout.EX OptionsEx Options must be unlocked by playing an original character and leveling them up to level 2. Once unlocked, EX Options can be found in the options menu by press L2.DX OptionsDX Options must be unlocked by playing an original character and leveling them up to level 5. Once unlocked, DX Options can be found in the options menu by pressing L1.CheatsShadowTo play Shadow Mode, highlight the "?" on the character selection screen and press Select five times and any punch or kick button. To select a character you'd like to play as first, select them and press select on them three times before pressing select five times on the "?."MarionetteTo play Marionette mode, highlight the "?" on the character selection screen and press select seven times.Lilith with Morrigan's VoiceTo play as Lilith with Morrigan's voice you must first go into options and set "short cut" to on. Then go into the game and highlight Lilith then hold down the select button and press any punch or kick. Remember you must have "short cut" on.Play as Oboro BishamonTo play as Oboro Bishamon, highlight Bishamon on the character select screen. Hold down the select button and press any two punch or kick buttons at the same time (i.e. light punch and medium punch or medium kick and hard kick). It should be noted Oboro has slightly different animations and transformations along with moves.Play as "Image" Jon TalbainTo play as "Image" Jon Talbain, highlight Talbain on the character selection screen. Hold select and press all three punches at the same time.Alternate Version of RikuoTo play a different version of Rikuo, highlight Rikuo on the character selection screen. Then hold the select and press any attack button.Alternate Version of DonovanTo play as a different version of Donovan, highlight Donovan on the character selection screen then press and hold select then press any attack buttonAlternate Version of VictorHighlight Victor on the character selection screen. Hold down select and press any attack button.Alternate Version of Jon TalbainHighlight Jon Talbain on the character selection screen. Hold down select and press any attack button.SecretsTo view all the images in the image gallery, simply place the Darkstalkers 3 disc into your computer and open the folder.During Lord Raptor's Dark Force, he appears for a moment in a leather Jacket with his hair in a mohawk. There is a one in sixteenth chance he'll appear with an afro instead.Sound TrackVampire Savior Official Sound TrackBackFrontRed Side (Disc One)Black Side (Disc Two)Opening TitleRanking DisplayPlayer Select 1Player Select 2Versus ScreenFeast of the DamnedDemitri Victory ThemeDemitri Ending 1Demitri Ending 2Vanity ParadiseLei-Lei Victory ThemeLei-Lei Ending Theme 1Lei-Lei Ending Theme 2Story Demo 1Green ScreamAulbath Victory ThemeAulbath Ending Theme 1Aulbath Ending Theme 2Sasquatch Victory ThemeSasquatch Ending Theme 1Sasquatch Ending Theme 2Tower of ArroganceFelicia Victory ThemeFelicia Ending Theme 1Felicia Ending Theme 2Abaraya 1Story Demo 2Abaraya 2Bishamon Victory ThemeBishamon Ending Theme 1Bishamon Ending Theme 2War AgonyLilith Victory ThemeLilith Ending Theme 1Lilith Ending Theme 2Bulleta Victory ThemeBulleta Ending Theme 1Bulleta Ending Theme 2Feast of the Damned MixAnnouncer and Stage FXRed Side Voice  Effects 1Red Side Voice  Effects 2Deserted ChateauMorrigan Victory ThemeMorrigan Ending Theme 1Morrigan Ending Theme 2Concrete CaveGallon Victory Theme 1Gallon Victory Theme 2Gallon Ending Theme 1Gallon Ending Theme 2New ChallengerForever TormentZable Victory ThemeZable Ending Theme 1Zable Ending Theme 2Victor Victory ThemeVictor Ending Theme 1Victor Ending Theme 2Red ThirstAnakaris Victory ThemeAnakaris Ending Theme 1Anakaris Ending Theme 2Iron Horse, Iron TerrorQ-bee Victory ThemeQ-bee Ending Theme 1Q-Bee Ending Theme 2Story Demo 3Fetus of GodJedah Victory ThemeJedah Ending Theme 1Jedah Ending Theme 2Shadow Victory ThemeShadow Ending ThemeContinueGame OverCreditsSpecial Ending 1Special Ending 2Deserted Chateau RemixBlack Side Voice  Effects 1Black Side Voice  Effects 2OmakeVersus JedahVampire Another Selection: The Unreleased TakesThis disc contains some of the addition tracks added to Vampire Savior when it was ported as Darkstalkers 3.Disc OneDirty Beret LogoOpeningPlayer SelectRevenge RoostStory DemoPhobos Winning ThemePyron Winning ThemeDonovan Winning ThemeOboro Winning ThemeLimit Winning ThemeEnding 1Ending 2Phobos Ending Theme 1Phobos Ending Theme 2Pyron Ending Theme 1Donovan Ending Theme 1Donovan Ending Theme 2Donovan Ending Theme 3Oboro Ending Theme 1Oboro Ending Theme 2Staff RollVoice  Effects Collection</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16793">Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors</game><game id="1328">Street Fighter Alpha 3</game><game id="11156">X-Men vs. Street Fighter</game><game id="8680">Street Fighter Alpha 3 MAX</game><game id="8605">Marvel vs. Capcom: Clash of Super Heroes</game><game id="22820">Red Earth</game><game id="10574">X-Men: Children of the Atom</game><game id="379">Waku Waku 7</game><game id="18647">JoJo's Bizarre Adventure</game><game id="23535">Samurai Shodown VI</game><game id="28446">Street Fighter III: Double Impact</game><game id="20292">Astra Superstars</game><game id="30944">Marvel vs. Capcom 3: Fate of Two Worlds</game><game id="27857">Touhou Hisoutensoku - Choudokyuu Ginyoru no Nazo o Oe</game><game id="17631">Groove on Fight: Gouketsuji Ichizoku 3</game><game id="34082">Skullgirls</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2340613-box_ds3.png</image></root>