<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15431</id><name>BioForge</name><description>OverviewBioForge is an adventure game developed by Origin Systems and published by Electronic Arts for DOS. The player takes control of a prisoner who has been abducted by a group of religious extremists, the Mondites, and subject to involuntary bionic implants. The player wakes up in a devastated Mondite facility and must escape, all the while discovering the events that led to the disappearance of its occupants. Expansions and SequelsOrigin spent ten weeks developing an expansion or sequel to BioForge, tentatively titled BioForge Plus, to continue directly from where the original game ends. BioForge Plus was to have new weapons, improved combat, and other ameliorations, as well as a new Gauntlet Mode, with sequential combat scenarios in an arena environment.The source code for BioForge Plus is believed to be in the possession of Mythic Entertainment, along with several other former Origin Systems source materials. CharactersAP-127The main character, a cyborg whose past identity is a mystery. Captured by the evil Dr. Mastaba, his/her body has been augmented with the traits of an ancient alien race known as the Phyxx.   Dr. MastabaA Mondite zealot whose only goal is "progression". He is devoid of all sympathy or compassion recognizing neither good or evil, the advancement of technology and evolution are all that matters. He commands an army of Mondite followers on the planet Daedalus, where he performs horrible experiments on any he finds fit.Dr. EscherAn archaeologist who unwittingly began work under Dr. Mastaba to uncover the secrets of Mount Sion. Her desire to learn more of the ancient Phyxx race blinded her to the Mondites true nature. Signs of distress and resistance have not gone silent as she believes her very life is in danger.CaynanFormally Chief of Security, Caynan began to question the Mondite methods concerning prisoners. Secret meetings with Dr.Escher has inspired him to become more bold. An encounter with an Reticulum officer Dan laid bare his sympathies. He was caught scheming escape for himself and prisoners. Dr. Mastaba ordered he receive highly damaging experiments that caused discoloration of the skin, limb replacement and psychosis.    Master Learner GenAn Phyxx alien concerned with the survival of his race. The Learner class of Phyxx has neglected physical attributes in favor of intelligence. One of many to enter stasis on a gravity ring station created long ago on the planet Daedalus. Recent activity has disturbed a single Phyxx soldier that damages the base reactor, threatening the planet. He needs AP-127 to finish the physical tasks needed to insure his race's escape.DroggDr. Eschers excavation team uncovered an Phyxx sarcophagus with a sleeping Soldier in it. This class of Phyxx is purely physical in nature, bred for war in harsh worlds. Nearly invincible it began a wave of destruction that eventually damaged a reactor prompting the evacuation of the planet, mortally wounding Dr. Escher in the process. Captain Tumult and Space MarinesResponding to Dr. Mastaba's call for reinforcements Captain Tumult and his Elite Special Force Space Marines attempt to land on Daedalus. AP-127 intervenes however shooting down his transport ship. Having lost nearly all of his crew, his space suit damaged and leaking, Tumult proceeds with what is surely a suicide battle with AP-127.  Roland and Mondite GuardsThe bread and butter of the Mondite forces on Daedalus. They are used as pawns by Dr. Mastaba, he gives their lives no more respect than a fly on the wall. Roland is one guard in particular that will be essential to AP-127. Not only is his assistance required, his fate will directly affect the main characters story.      SecurityBots, MechBots and NurseBotsMany robotic entities patrol the Mondite facilities guarding passages, caring for prisoners or patrolling for intruders. Nurse bots are nearly invincible however many have been disrupted by the common energy door guarding most prisoners cells. Mechbots wield heavy fire power and are immune to physical attacks. Energy weapons have proven useful in piercing its hull. Security bots are weak and stationary, but they come in groups. They can fire fast and often have cross fire from each other. Many energy projectiles are known to ricochet off walls however,making them sitting ducks for a skilled marksman.Acid BeastThe primary excavation site and the Mondite base are connected with an acid pool. Dr. Eschers team lost many personnel to the acid beast attempting to reach the site. The area became off limits as the beast seems impervious to all small arms fire, and alternate routes were explored.CybeRaptorThe CybeRaptor can best be described as a failed experiment. With nearly the same augments as AP-127, its infused with fast repairing nano-tech and alien genes. It's regenerative properties are so great it cannot be killed. Dr. Mastaba permantly retired it into stasis until it could be controlled.FloaterAn alien with a metallic outer shell that makes in impervious to all damage while curled into a ball. The reflective shell also makes it resistant to energy weapons. Hand-to-hand combat is the most effective method of dealing with this troublesome enemy however close range is where its most deadly.     ItemsFlutePerhaps the most mysterious item in the game, the player will find themselves obtaining it quite early. Ironically one of the very first log books acquired explains its purpose, however a careful interpretation of this could lead someone to believe it may have use later. When Doctor Mastaba experiments on his subjects, he imprints a subliminal urge to play a flute as well as his choice of the melody. His victims are never aware of this and believe they choose this themselves. If a subject plays the flute it's reaffirmation that mental controls he has put in place are working properly. It is the final stage of mental conditioning.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20800">Dead Space</game><game id="18074">Cyberia</game><game id="3102">Alone in the Dark</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2305293-bioforge_cover.jpg</image></root>