<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15449</id><name>Backyard Baseball 2001</name><description>Backyard Baseball 2001 broke ground by being the first game in the beloved series to feature major league baseball players. A streamlined batting and pitching system combined with an easy learning curve made this game accessible for all ages.Team SelectionAll 30 Major League Baseball teams are available for use. There is also a selection of the classic backyard baseball teams such as the Watermelon Heads, and the Wombats. Customizable team colors and nicknames are available for the custom teams.MLB Players30 MLB players were playable in this game, all in the animation form of kids. Some of them beingManager ScreenMark McGwireIvan RodriquezMo VaugnRandy JohnsonTony GwynnKen Griffey JR.Curt SchillingAlex RodriguezSammy SosaJason GiambiCal Ripken Jr.Fictional PlayersIncluded alongside the 30 MLB players were the original 30 characters whom were all included in the first installment of Backyard Baseball.Jocinda SmithRonny DobbsMario LunaAchmed KhanTony DelvecchioDimitri PetrovichGretchen HasselhoffLueane LuiKimmy EckmanRicky JohnsonAnnie FrazierMikey ThomasLisa CrocketAmir KhanSally DobbsPete WheelerDante RobinsonVicki KawaguchiReese WorthingtonKenny KawaguchiStephanie MorganSidney WeberAshely WeberAngela DelvecchioMarky DuboisPablo SanchezBilly Jean BlackwoodJorge GarciaErnie Steele30. Kiesha PhillipsCreate a PlayerThis game featured Create a Player feature, letting you decide the GenderBirthdayRight or Left handedRaceHairstyleNicknameStats of playerCreate a PlayerGame TypesSingle Game Able to select your difficulty level, team, and players. You pick in a dodgeball type format, back and forth.Season Mode Play a full 14 game season. Pick your team and whatever players you want. Also pick your home-field and difficulty level.Online Play The first backyard game to feature online play. Played on a closed network provided by Humongous Entertainment.Batting Practice Robotic pitching machine Mr. Clankey throws you fastballs, slow balls, and curve-balls. You hit them all around the field.Club HousePower-upsDuring the game you are rewarded both batting power-ups and pitching power-ups. To get a batting power-up you need to make a double or triple play. To get a pitching power-up you must get a strikeout with you pitcher.Pitching Power-upsFire BallBig Freeze- Right when the ball gets above the strikezone, it freezes into an iceball, throwing off the batters timing.Corkscrew- Does a circular spiral across to the plate. Hard to control.Crazyball- As the name suggests it goes in all different directions.Elevator- A pitch that on the way to the plate rides the ground, but once it reaches the plate it quickly rises to the strikezone.Fireball- An extremely fast thrown pitch.Slo-mo Ball- An extremely slow thrown pitch.ZigZag- Does movements up and down or side to side.Extra Juice- Refreshes pitches stamina.Batting Power-upsAluminum Power- Your wood bat changes to an aluminum bat. Gives your batter unbelievable Crazy Bunt power.Crazy Bunt- A bunt that goes in all different directions. The only way it can be stopped is if a player touches it, or if it hits the fence.Screaming Line Drive- A lighting fast line drive that screams while in the air.Undergrounder- A ball hit straight into the ground, often resulting in a ground role double. </description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="34">Baseball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20686">MLB Power Pros</game><game id="814">Mario Superstar Baseball</game><game id="20687">MLB Power Pros 2008</game><game id="22848">MLB '98</game><game id="1899">Backyard Hockey 2005</game><game id="21765">Backyard Baseball '10</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1516/701908-513mg4ae8ql.jpg</image></root>