<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15481</id><name>Star Wars: Battlefront</name><description>OverviewStar Wars: Battlefront mimics the classic Battlefield series in that it puts players in large scale battles that combine infantry with vehicle combat. Like the Battlefield series, it uses a rigid class system for the infantry classes and employs a number of vehicles in every map. On the PC, over 64 players can play on a single map with 32 players on xbox live and 16 players on the PS2.Historical CampaignPlayers fight in battles from the Star Wars movies.Galactic ConquestA strategic mode in which players select planets to dominate. Each planet has two maps that the player must win on in order to control the planet. Once they do, they unlock the bonus from the planet, which can be anything from increased health for the team to a Jedi Hero. The next time the player selects a planet to attack, they can choose one of the bonuses to activate for the battle. Should they lose a fight, the enemy chooses the next planet.Instant ActionThe player selects maps to play on. They can either select one single map to play on or build a "playlist" of maps that can either be played in order or in random order.ClassesEach faction shares relatively the same classes, although they do have different weapons.RebelsRebel SoldierRebel VanguardRebel PilotRebel MarksmenWookie Smuggler (exclusive for Rebels).RepublicClone TroopersArc TroopersClone PilotClone SharpshooterJet Trooper (exclusive for Republic)CISSuper battle DroidAssault DroidPilot DroidDroid SniperDroideka (exclusive for CIS)Galactic EmpireStorm TroopersShock TroopersImperial PilotsScout TroopersDark troopers (exclusive for Galactic Empire)MapsBespin: PlatformsBespin: Cloud CityEndor: BunkerGeonosis: SpireKamino: Tipaco CityKashyyk: IslandsKashyyk: DocksNaboo: PlainsNaboo: TheedRhen Var: HarborRhen Var: CitadelTatooine: Dune SeaTatooine: Mos EisleyTatooine: Jabba's Palace (DLC)Yavin 4: HarborYavin 4: ArenaHothMultiplayerBattlefront used to have online connectivity with the ability to support up to 50 players on PC over LAN. The Mac version only could play up to 32 unless on LAN (back up to 50). The Playstation 2 version could play up to 16 players with 2 offline and the Xbox version could play 32 players over Xbox Live. This game can no longer be played online over Xbox Live but still can be used for LAN and single player games.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17828">Battlefield 2142</game><game id="20965">The Lord of the Rings: Conquest</game><game id="20458">Warhawk</game><game id="13286">Unreal Tournament 2004</game><game id="20333">Geist</game><game id="21220">Battlefield Heroes</game><game id="12716">Battlefield 1942</game><game id="7094">Star Wars: Battlefront II</game><game id="26549">Star Wars Battlefront: Elite Squadron</game><game id="10853">Freedom Fighters</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2525269-box_swbf.png</image></root>