<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15504</id><name>Top Hunter: Roddy &amp; Cathy</name><description>A typical Klapton soldier.Taking place in the galaxy of Andromeda, Roddy and Cathy (two top Space Bounty Hunters) are attempting to capture the leaders of "Force Klapton", a group of space pirates who have taken over the various planets in the system. There are four basic planets to start from (Forest, Fire, Ice, and Wind); the player can pick any stage where they choose to start, although the Forest world is the easiest. Each planet is controlled by a different leader of Force Klapton. Forest World: SlyIce World: MistyWind World: BigmanFire World: BurnCaptain Klapton... obviously. (Note: It's a toupee!)After the initial four stages are completed, the players advance to Captain Klapton's battleship. Each of the previous bosses is fought again (albeit in new vehicles). At the end, Captain Klapton himself challenges the players. Each stage contains a bonus round where the player rides collects items and time.ItemsCoin: Increases your score.Special Coin: Increases your score by a larger margin.Crystal: Increases your score by an even larger margin.Time: Adds 5 seconds to the clock.Super Time: Adds 20 seconds to the clock.Food: Restores lost energy.Rifle: Pick up to shoot enemies!Power Up: Powers up Roddy or Cathy's special attacks.Robo Vehicle: A mech that the player can jump in and pilot.The Protagonists:RoddyRoddy's father is from the planet Asta, and his mother is a human.  Because of his Asta heritage, his limbs are capable of stretching. Height: 160cmWeight: 52kgPlace of Origin: Planet AstaLikes: HamburgersHates: The KlaptonsCathyRoddy's partner from Earth. She uses a "chain saucer" as a weapon.Height: 159cmWeight: 4?kgFrom: EarthLikes: MoneyDislikes: SpidersBoth Roddy and Cathy have a number of fighting-game style special moves they can perform (I.E., qcf   attack  results in a projectile)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10261">Bad Dudes</game><game id="20752">Double Dragon</game><game id="6722">Final Fight</game><game id="20436">Streets of Rage</game><game id="13297">Two Crude Dudes</game><game id="563">Wrath of the Black Manta</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/4/44493/1058269-tophuntercover.jpg</image></root>