<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1552</id><name>Dune 2000</name><description>OverviewDune 2000 is a real-time strategy game that was developed by Intelligent Games; while initially being a PC game, it was later ported to the Sony Playstation. The game makes use of the Command  Conquer: Red Alert engine, and is based in Frank Herbert's Dune universe. The game itself is a remake of the real-time strategy game, Dune II.The game was not a critical nor a commercial success, with poor production standards cited as being a key reason for the lacklustre reception. StoryThe game is set on the desert planet of Arrakis. Spice, a valuable commodity, has attracted three Houses aiming to fulfill the challenge issued by Emperor Corrino of gathering the largest amount of spice. You must command the military of one of these Houses and claim ownership of the valuable spice.   FactionsThe game features three playable factions:  House Atreides This faction originally came from Caladan, a water-planet. Ruled by the Duke, this faction has a wealth of strong units that ensure its air superiority.   House HarkonnenOriginating from the barren wasteland of Giedi Prime, the Harkonnen are a race who have many human characteristics, at least genetically. Ruled with the iron grip of the evil Baron; the Harkonnen are a brutal and malicious race. House OrdosThe Ordos come from the icy world of Sigma Draconis IV. They rely heavily on importing goods, as they have few natural resources. The wealth gained from merchanting is used to construct units and develop infrastructure, but has had the effect of making the Ordos very paranoid.Also included in the game are four non-playable subfactions. These include the Mercenaries, the Smugglers, the Fremen, and House Corrino. FeaturesThe game had a number of significant features;  Three playable factions available to play across 30 missions A number of different gameplay modes including head-to-head, solo, or Skirmish Mode against up to 3 AI opponents Cinematic full motion video segments accompany the gameplay     System Requirements (minimum) Pentium 90 16MB RAM 2MB Video Memory 60MB Hard Drive Space</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13062">StarCraft</game><game id="1901">Supreme Commander</game><game id="18930">Company of Heroes</game><game id="4384">Command &amp; Conquer</game><game id="249">Command &amp; Conquer: Red Alert</game><game id="18072">Command &amp; Conquer: Red Alert 2</game><game id="20660">Command &amp; Conquer: Red Alert 3</game><game id="16365">Command &amp; Conquer: Red Alert - The Aftermath</game><game id="5550">Command &amp; Conquer: Yuri's Revenge</game><game id="17551">Command &amp; Conquer 3: Tiberium Wars</game><game id="20494">Command &amp; Conquer 3: Kane's Wrath</game><game id="22012">Command &amp; Conquer: Tiberian Sun Firestorm</game><game id="9719">Warcraft: Orcs &amp; Humans</game><game id="20103">Warcraft II: Tides of Darkness</game><game id="14073">Warcraft III: The Frozen Throne</game><game id="23161">Desert Law</game><game id="6948">Dark Colony</game><game id="25481">Officers</game><game id="5415">StarCraft: Brood War</game><game id="20674">StarCraft II: Wings of Liberty</game><game id="25034">Command &amp; Conquer Red Alert 3: Uprising</game><game id="2068">Command &amp; Conquer: Tiberian Sun</game><game id="11328">Command &amp; Conquer: Red Alert - Counterstrike</game><game id="24079">StarCraft II: Legacy of the Void</game><game id="12651">Ground Control</game><game id="33907">APOX</game><game id="24078">StarCraft II: Heart of the Swarm</game><game id="5205">Dark Reign: Rise of the Shadowhand</game><game id="40429">Echelon: Explore, Discover and Eliminate</game><game id="5921">M.A.X.: Mechanized Assault and Exploration</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14912/809553-dune_2000_pc.jpg</image></root>