<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1565</id><name>Empire Earth II</name><description>InformationEmpire Earth II was originally developed by Mad Doc Software, which later became Rockstar New England, and published by Sierra Entertainment. The game has three campaigns (American, Korean, and German), 14 playable civilizations, as well as online muliplayer with up to 10 players in any one map with 9 customizable victory conditions.GameplayLike many in the genre before it, each of the playable civilizations have specific areas in which they excel. However, most of the innovations in Empire Earth II have to do with citizen management and battlefield management. The PIP(Picture-in-Picture) allows the player to view two areas at any given time, also allowing several queued PIP locations that can be switched on the fly. The PIP can be assigned to look at a specific location or unit. Another addition is the war planner, which is essentially a top down view of the battlefield showing known locations of allies, enemies, and movement plans. This allows players to easily coordinate attacks on a common enemy, which is especially useful in multiplayer game. EpochsStone AgeCopper AgeBronze AgeIron AgeDark AgesMiddle AgesRenaissanceImperial AgeEnlightenment AgeIndustrial AgeModern AgeAtomic AgeDigital AgeGenetic AgeSynthetic AgeCivilizationsWestern:AmericanBritishGermansGreeksRomansMiddle Eastern:BabyloniansEgyptiansTurksFar Eastern:ChinaJapanKoreaMeso-American:AztecsIncansMayans</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14073">Warcraft III: The Frozen Throne</game><game id="10485">Age of Empires</game><game id="11610">Empires: Dawn of the Modern World</game><game id="11993">Rise of Nations</game><game id="1370">Age of Mythology: The Titans</game><game id="8897">Stronghold 2</game><game id="8546">Age of Empires III</game><game id="19887">Rome: Total War</game><game id="16130">Imperial Glory</game><game id="11360">Warrior Kings: Battles</game><game id="8421">Outlive</game><game id="7701">The Lord of the Rings: The Battle for Middle-earth</game><game id="13732">Rise &amp; Fall: Civilizations at War</game><game id="4686">Waterloo: Napoleon's Last Battle</game><game id="32355">Age of Empires Online</game><game id="38672">Command &amp; Conquer: The First Decade</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5076/873718-empire_earth_ii_box.png</image></root>