<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15689</id><name>Armored Core: Project Phantasma</name><description>BackgroundThe game folows the first Armored Core game in that all the corporations and weapons of the previous games carry over. It is in a sense a direct sequel to the first game.Amber CrownA mid-sized subterranean complex, large parts of which have been abandoned. Rumors that a research group known as "The Doomsday Organization" is using these empty sections of the city for their own testing and operational facilities.Doomsday OrganizationAn organization surrounded by mystery. In addition to the many rumors that surround their Amber Crown activities, they are rumored to the beneficiary of financial backing contributed by one of the conglomeration of companies. They are the masterminds behind the shady "Project Phanstasma."Project PhantasmaThe codename for an experiment that somehow molds human life and machine together, with the result being a much more efficient AC. However this experiment is so extreme that its side effects can be drastic.StorylineThe player is a Raven from Isaac City who receives an unknown transmission to destroy a materials dump in three minutes. Afterwards, the Raven is given his first assignment from the mysterious employer: infiltrate the underground city Amber Crown. Shortly afterwards the Raven is introduced to two Ravens. Stinger, and irregular who is working against the player and his employer, and Sumika, a prisoner of the Doomsday Organization and the one who gave the Raven the assignments. After the rescue operation, the Raven and Sumika work together to take down the Doomsday Organization and their secret weapon "Project Phantasma."The two partake in acts of sabotage against the Doomsday Organization, and run into Stinger on multiple occasions. Even after destroying the base of operations for Doomsday, the group continues to operate and work on Project Phantasma, with Stinger backing them. The Raven encounters Stinger piloting the prototype Phantasma in the North Highlands, and chases down the final version of the weapon in the subways of Amber Crown. Unfortunately, Stinger escapes with the finished weapon, and challenges the Raven to a dual in the building known as Abyss. The Raven is successful in destroying Project Phantasma along with Stinger, and Sumika is greatful for his assistance. A carrier arrives to pick up the Raven and leave the area, taking the Raven home.GameplayProject Phantasma is a direct sequel to Armored Core, and the core gameplay remains the same. When starting, the player can choose to either start a new game with a starter AC and zero credits, or transfer a save file from Armored Core into Project Phantasma, bringing over all parts and credits acquired. Human PLUS and Overweight modes can be transferred as well if they have been unlocked.Aside from the mission mode and mech customization, a new mode is introduced to Project Phantasma. The Arena is a mode where the player fights against 49 ranked ACs for credits and extra parts.PartsAll parts from the original Armored Core can be transferred to Project Phantasma, along with over 20 new parts. Some can be found in the shop right at the beginning or are earned by completing matches in the game's Arena mode.HD-G780Part Type: HeadPrice: 82500Weight: 393Energy Drain: 723Armor Points: 905Def Shell: 186Def Energy: 448Provides good protection against energy based weaponsComputer Type: RoughMap Type: Area  Place NameNoise Canceler: ProvidedBio Sensor: ProvidedRadar Function: ProvidedRadar Range: 7600Radar type: StandardXXA-S0Part Type: CorePrice: 122000Weight: 784Energy Drain: 1273Armor Points: 2050Def Shell: 600Test Model. Lightweight, but with low APDef Energy: 580Maximum Weight: 2820Anti-Missile-Response: 50Anti-Missile-Angle: 50Extension Slots: 17AW-DC/2Part Type: ArmsType: Dual CannonPrice: 188500Weight: 1805Energy Drain: 220Armor Points: 892Def Shell: 0Def Energy: 0Dual grenade launcherWeapon Lock: SpecialAttack Power: 3822Number of Ammo: 20Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 1800Range: 15300Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 60LN-2KZ-SPPart Type: LegsType: Humanoid LegsPrice: 118000Weight: 1820Energy Drain: 3034Armor Points: 2210Able to carry heavier loads, but AP is sacrificedDef Shell: 648Def Energy: 820Maximum Weight: 4420Speed: 383Stability: 3025Jump Function: ProvidedGBX-TLPart Type: GeneratorPrice: 38000Weight: 1582Large output and capacity, offset by its heavy weightEnergy Output: 9055Maximum Charge: 50000Redzone: 22000GBX-XLPart Type: GeneratorPrice: 139000Weight: 975Modified GRD-RX6. Above average efficiencyEnergy Output: 8500Maximum Charge: 52000Redzone: 33000FBMB-18XPart Type: FCSPrice: 108000Weight: 21Maximum of 6 quick, wide area lock-onsEnergy Drain: 65Maximum Lock: 6Lock Type: Wide  ShallowRATORPart Type: FCSPrice: 129000Weight: 18Max lock-on 2, suitable for long distance missilesEnergy Drain: 75Maximum Lock: 2Lock Type: Narrow  DeepB-HP25Part Type: BoostersPrice: 52500Weight: 186Small lightweight model. Low acceleration, but efficientEnergy Drain: 35Boost Power: 8500Charge Drain: 2520WM-ATType: Large MissilePrice: 256800Weight: 910Energy Drain: 382Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: StandardAttack Power: 9830Most powerful missile in AC's inventoryNumber of Ammo: 10Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 3510Range: 20000Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 35WM-T0100Type: Small MissilePrice: 862000Weight: 725Energy Drain: 290Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: StandardAttack Power: 230Lots of ammo, but low attack powerNumber of Ammo: 120Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 150Range: 9000Maximum Lock: 6Reload Time: 5WM-SMSS24Type: MissilePrice: 118300Weight: 655Energy Drain: 308Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: StandardAttack Power: 1630Mortar Shell. Launches verticallyNumber of Ammo: 40Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 420Range: 9000Maximum Lock: 4Reload Time: 10M118-TDType: MagazinePrice: 96300Additional ammo. Increases a weapon's ammo capacityWeight: 455Energy Drain: 0WC-SPGUNType: Slug GunPrice: 89500Weight: 912Energy Drain: 11Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: SpecialAttack Power: 208Fires a seven shell spreadNumber of Ammo: 50Ammo Type: EnergyAmmo Price: 0Range: 9200Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 8WC-IR24Type: Laser CannonPrice: 159500Weight: 528Energy Drain: 806Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: Narrow  DeepAttack Power: 3025Triple barrel energy weaponNumber of Ammo: 20Ammo Type: EnergyAmmo Price: 0Range: 15000Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 40RZ-Fw2Type: RadarPrice: 82100Weight: 352Energy Drain: 826Wide forward search areaRadar Function: ProvidedRadar Range: 213000Radar Type: OctagonWG-RFM118Type: RiflePrice: 95000Weight: 512Energy Drain: 10Weapon Lock: Wide  ShallowAttack Power: 340Improved fire speedNumber of Ammo: 200Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 45Range: 11000Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 5WG-XFwPPkType: Laser RiflePrice: 132000Weight: 893Energy Drain: 395Weapon Lock: SpecialAttack Power: 1120Rapid fire energy weaponNumber of Ammo: 100Ammo Type: EnergyAmmo Price: 0Range: 14000Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 10WG-HG1Type: Hand GunPrice: 72000Weight: 283Energy Drain: 52Weapon Lock: Wide  ShallowAttack Power: 280Upgraded hand gunNumber of Ammo: 100Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 56Range: 6300Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 8WG-PC26Type: Grenade LauncherPrice: 113000Weight: 681Energy Drain: 34Weapon Lock: Wide  ShallowAttack Power: 2200Grenade launcher, powerful but has limited ammo supplyNumber of Ammo: 15Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 1015Range: 9000Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 10WA-FINGERType: Machine GunPrice: 275000Weight: 150Energy Drain: 120Weapon Lock: SpecialAttack Power: 250Very powerful for close-in combatNumber of Ammo: 3000Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 8Range: 3700Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 1SP-DEhfPart Type: Optional PartType: Energy ReducePrice: 245000Reduced energy weapon consumption by halfSlot Spend: 5Function: Cuts weapon energy needed by halfNexus RemakesArmored Core: Nexus Disc two features remakes of specific missions from ACPP. Ariake and Vixen's parts are completely unlock-able in Armored Core: Nexus and can be used in the game's conventional single player.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9122">Front Mission Online</game><game id="15264">Krazy Ivan</game><game id="22133">Armored Core: for Answer</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1810912-box_acpp.png</image></root>