<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15703</id><name>Multimedia Celebrity Poker</name><description>OverviewMultimedia Celebrity Poker, released in 1995 by New World Computing, is a CD-ROM-based poker game that allows players to test their poker skills against three B-level Hollywood celebrities. Headlining the game are Jonathan Frakes (Star Trek: The Next Generation, North  South miniseries), Morgan Fairchild (Falcon's Crest, Hotel) and Joe Piscopo (Saturday Night Live, Wise Guys).GameplayDO NOT turn down the video qualityMultimedia Celebrity Poker features eight styles of poker to play. Each player can select a new style when it is their turn to deal. These are:7 Card Stud7 Card Stud Low5 Card Stud5 Card Stud, Deuces Wild5 Card Draw, No Openers5 Card Draw, Jacks or Better5 Card Draw, Low5 Card Draw, Deuces WildPlayers begin with chips worth $250. Betting is done by clicking on stacks of chips - white chips count as one, red chips count as two, blue chips count as four. The guest celebrities will refer to bets, raises, and antes by numbers of chips, not by their value; presumably to make putting the game together easier technically.The player can disable any of the three celebrities, but they will not leave the table; they simply are not dealt cards. However, at least one of the celebrities must remain active at all times. Players can switch between Classical, Pop, and Rock background music, toggle a voice for themselves (when requesting cards), or command Joe Piscopo to tell a joke through use of a drop-down menu. He will still tell jokes even when he has been disabled as a participant.OuttakesThe game includes a blooper reel of botched and unused video outtakes of the actors as a separate executable file. This video also hasn't been keyed, showing the green screen set and an idea of how video for the game was shot.System RequirementsThe following system requirements are listed as they appear in the game manual:2x CD-ROM486DXWin 3.1x4MB of RAM MemorySome hard drive space (the exact amount is not specified in the system requirements documentation)</description><genres><genre id="13">Card Game</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="32551">Poker Night at the Inventory</game><game id="7290">Telltale Texas Hold'em</game><game id="38792">Poker for Dummies</game><game id="42089">Poker Night 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/11/117445/1653914-1076852870_00.jpg</image></root>