<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15711</id><name>AMBER: Journeys Beyond</name><description>OverviewAmber: Journeys Beyond is an adventure game that begins when the protagonist visits a fellow scientist named Roxy. The game was released in 1996 for both PC and Mac.StoryAn avid paranormal researcher, Roxy has chosen her new home because she believes it is haunted. Using a host of unreliable detection devices, she plans to use this house as a laboratory. Her goal: proving the existence of psychic phenomena. Driving out to the house in a thunderstorm, you are run off the road by a shimmering apparition and are sent crashing into a lake. In short order, you discover other things have gone wrong - Roxy is in the garage, apparently dead. It's up to you to save yourself and the overzealous scientist from the forces lurking in the house. Patience and close attention to detail are musts for playing Amber: Journeys Beyond. Critical items are sometimes hard to spot, and one or two of the scenes take place in very dark locales. When you can see, the graphics are crisp and drawn with a faint gothic sensibility, surrounding the player in a milieu of creepy sounds and ghost-catching gadgets. The game is especially suited to beginning or younger gamers, as the problem-solving challenges are on the simple side. Even so, Amber: Journeys Beyond is spooky and engaging, a worthy electronic heir to campfire stories everywhere.CharactersRoxy Westbridgewas a former run of the mill scientist who became obsessed with paranormal activity. She created a machine called AMBER to track paranormal activity.She contacts the protagonist to help her with her paranormal research. She is so obsessed with the paranormal that she bought a home that was said to be haunted.MargaretA housewife of 1943. Her story is activated through the mirror. She has committed suicide but why?Brice Brice is extremely obsessed with Mandy. He send her notes and gifts but she does not want them. Now they are both dead but why?Edwin Edwin has fallen into a frozen lake. Suffice to say he did not make it. Solve his story and let his ghost live in peace.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3970">Myst</game><game id="16230">Riven: The Sequel to Myst</game><game id="18742">Myst III: Exile</game><game id="7863">Myst IV: Revelation</game><game id="1961">Myst V: End of Ages</game><game id="20146">Shivers</game><game id="10546">Shivers 2: Harvest of Souls</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3948/1083124-amber.jpg</image></root>