<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15774</id><name>WinBack: Covert Operations</name><description>StoryA terrorist group know as The Crying Lions takes control of the GULF complex, a military command center that controls a weapon of mass destruction. The Secretary of Defense responds to the threat by tasking the unfortunately named Special Covert Action Team (S.C.A.T.) to reclaim it. Winback was released as Operation: Winback in Australia and Europe.Multiple EndingsThe ending of the game depends entirely on the time it took the player to complete the game. A good and a bad ending result in either the success or failure of 'operation winback' and the survival of the main characters.CharactersS.C.A.T.Jean-Luc CougarLisa RobertsDaniel StewartLaw BrufordJake HudsonMichael HawkinsThomas SmithSteven LegalKeith BirdyMatthew BrownThe Crying LionsKenneth Coleman (leader)Bad Luck LilaLeonRyanSergeant ThunderDukeGuntBanderasJinDeathmaskCecile NewcastleThe Traitor (a.k.a Daniel Stewart)InfluenceWinback was the first game to incorporate the cover mechanic in a 3rd-person shooter and influenced games like Kill.Switch, Metal Gear Solid 2: Sons of Liberty and Gears of War.As an homage to the game, Jean-Luc Cougar's dog tags can be collected while playing through the Plant level of MGS2:SoL on Easy. They are only available in the original version of the game, not MGS2: Substance.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1152">kill.switch</game><game id="16140">Metal Gear Solid</game><game id="15691">Syphon Filter 3</game><game id="21866">WinBack 2: Project Poseidon</game><game id="21632">Trigger Man</game><game id="20497">Dark Sector</game><game id="21654">Metal Gear Solid 2: Substance</game><game id="20669">Metal Gear Solid 4: Guns of the Patriots</game><game id="18082">Metal Gear Solid 3: Snake Eater</game><game id="10267">Metal Gear Solid 3: Subsistence</game><game id="5961">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell</game><game id="1248">Syphon Filter</game><game id="18599">Syphon Filter 2</game><game id="12388">Metal Gear Solid 2: Sons of Liberty</game><game id="12231">Gears of War</game><game id="20662">Gears of War 2</game><game id="15549">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Pandora Tomorrow</game><game id="12354">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Chaos Theory</game><game id="33396">Splinter Cell Trilogy</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2323888-box_winback.png</image></root>