<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1578</id><name>Resident Evil 4</name><description>OverviewLeon Kennedy, in trouble.Resident Evil 4 was first announced in 2001. It went through a long development period, during which various versions of the game were scrapped; with one, a radical departure from previous installments, being kept and retooled into Devil May Cry. An early version bore a greater resemblance to the previous Resident Evil video games than the final product: while the beta video displays a move away from the traditional survival-horror camera angles, the focus on exploration and puzzles is clear. The beta video also suggested a potential move away from the traditional zombie slaying by implementing ghosts and other supernatural concepts.The game was released for the GameCube on January 11th, 2005. Later that year in October, it was ported, despite threats of self-decapitation by Shinji Mikami, to the PlayStation 2. (Mikami has yet to follow through). Nintendo Wii and PC ports of the game followed in 2007. The Wii version does utilize the Wiimote's unique control system. In 2011, an HD version was released on the PlayStation Network and Xbox Live services.Resident Evil 4 received widespread critical acclaim, selling, worldwide, three million copies. It was praised for its immersive and novel style, which drew many new fans, despite annoying a vocal minority of the franchise's players.PlotAfter the events of the T-Virus outbreak in Raccoon City, the Umbrella Corporation is dissolved; Leon S. Kennedy, a protagonist of Resident Evil 2, is recruited by the Secret Service's Adam Benford. Leon is sent to an isolated village in Spain. He is tasked with the rescue of President Graham's kidnapped daughter, Ashley.Leon is accompanied by two policemen on his mission. The three are being watched. Their car stops at a footbridge. Leon crosses it. He makes his way through the woods, and he stumbles across a small house. He meets the man inside it. Upon asking him if he's seen Ashley, the man responds hostilely, throwing an axe. After disposing the hostile and dodging traps in the forest, Leon makes it to the village. From the outskirts, Leon observes that both of the policemen have been murdered by the villagers, who see him and begin attacking en masse. Leon barricades himself in a house. The crazed villagers, including one with a chainsaw, try to get him. After holding down the fort for a period of time, the church bell rings; the villagers eerily walk away, completely ignoring Leon. Leon continues on his quest, killing more villagers, dodging boulders, and meeting a merchant of arms.Leon eventually comes face to face with Bitores Mendez, a giant who knocks him out. Leon wakes up tied to another man, Luis Sera, an ex-Madrid cop, who used to do research for a cult known as Los Illuminados. Leon looks through Sera's notes. He discovers that the cult is controlled by Osmund Saddler. Saddler controls the villagers, thanks to a parasitical creature called Las Plagas, which transforms the people it infests into mindless slaves, called Los Ganados. Saddler plans on injecting the Plagas into Ashley. He plans to have her, then, infiltrate the United States, allowing Los Illuminados to take over. Leon, while knocked out, was injected with the said parasite. As Leon comes to, however, he resumes looking for the president's daughter. He meets a big lake, where he sees some Ganados disposing of a body. Its the second man's, who'd escorted him on the mission. A giant fish called Del Lago eats the corpse. Kennedy, in order to cross the lake, faces the creature. He collapses in a lakeside cabin. He has nightmares, due to complications from his infestation. He discovers where Ashley is being held (in the village's church) and finds a key to open the church.On his way back to the village, he faces El Gigante. He makes it to the church and saves Ashley. Saddler tells them that the parasite is growing inside their bodies, and that they'll soon be his puppets. The two escape and head for the extraction point. They find themselves, yet, barricaded with Luis in a cabin. They defend the premises against a large number of Ganados. Luis decides to part ways with Leon. The helicopter that was supposed to retrieve the two survivors is shot down. HQ tells them that a second one should be on the way. Leon sees a nearby castle, and decides that it would be a good place to hide. To access the castle, they must get Mendez' eye. Leon confronts Mendez in a barn. Mendez transforms into a monster; however, Leon gets the best of him and gets the eye. Ashley and Leon enter the castle, hoping they can find refuge.They discover that the castle is replete with Los Illuminados. Monks, who use catapults and other medieval weapons, try to kill Leon and capture Ashley. One of Saddler's top men and the castle's king, Ramon Salazar, jams all of Leon's communications. As the two fight through the castle, Ashley starts coughing up blood; in her panic, she runs off. Ashley is captured. Leon must once again save her. He meets ex-colleague Ada Wong, who'd already saved him from Mendez. Ada has her own private agenda (she's working for "the Organization"), and she remains very enigmatic with Leon. Before Leon can wrestle any concrete information out of Ada, she escapes. Leon spots Ashley. She is, a story level below Leon in a complex castle, out of reach. Luis arrives, flashing two antidotes to the parasite and the Master Plaga, a form of the parasite which allows the infested person to keep their mind and control others infested. Just as Luis is about to give these things to Leon, Saddler has snuck upon the scene. He stabs Luis with a giant tentacle, which comes out of his tunic. Ashley is captured again; Leon swears to avenge the deceased Luis.Leon makes his way to Salazar, who informs him that Ashley has been taken to a research facility on a nearby island. Salazar, then, turns into a giant mutated flower. A boss fight commences. Leon goes to the island (transported by Ada), and fights heavily armed Ganados. He finds Ashley, finally, along with the Master Plaga and the two antidotes. They cleanse themselves of the plagas within. After an epic fight, with the help of Ada, Leon manages to kill Saddler. Ada does, however, steal the Master Plaga. The island is set to blow.Leon and Ashley manage to escape on a jet-ski, just seconds before the island blows. From the impact, Ashley is flung from the vehicle; Leon briefly searches for her, and then picks her up. As Leon does so, he says, "Lets go home". In agreement, Ashley responds: "mission accomplished". A scene is shown of the two traveling into the open ocean, Ashley says to Leon: "After you take me back to my place, how about we do some overtime?". Leon politely refuses the offer.GameplayThe gameplay in Resident Evil 4 is significantly more accessible to players than previous Resident Evil games, featuring much faster-paced action and an over-the-shoulder camera perspective. This perspective, along with the addition of laser sights, affords improved weapon aiming. The game also includes a dedicated knife button, allowing players to engage in more effective close-quarters combat without have to switch to the inventory screen to change the equipped weapon. Context-sensitive controls and quick-time events have been included, which add to the game's cinematic feel.InventoryLeon's Attache Case.Resident Evil 4 utilizes a new grid-based inventory system. The player is given an attache case with a limited number of grid squares to carry items collected in the game. Each item occupies a certain number of the available squares, leaving the player responsible for arranging items to best utilize the limited space. When an acquired item requires more inventory space than what's currently available, the player is required to free up space by using, combining, discarding, or selling items. The player is able to buy larger attache cases from the weapons dealer throughout the game in order to increase item carrying capacity. Key items and sellable Treasures are not limited by the space of the inventory, and instead are housed in a separate menu.Mini Game: Shooting GalleryAt four points during the main story you gain access to areas known as Shooting Galleries. Within these Galleries you are challenged to shoot enemy cardboard cut-outs while avoiding Ashley shaped targets. Finding a new gallery area unlocks a new course in the Shooting Gallery. Points are awarded for hitting enemy targets, more for getting headshots. Each gallery features a row of six Bottle Caps to be won. One Bottle Cap can be earned by obtaining 4000 points or hitting all the enemy targets, while the other five are earned by obtaining 3000 points multiple times. Each course will actually change the layout of the enemies once after successfully obtaining a certain number of Bottle Caps from it. The Bottle Caps can be viewed on their stand in the Key Item Inventory screen. Each Bottle Cap also comes with a sound clip that can be played when viewing it, somewhat reminiscent in quality to actual sound-playing toys.The MerchantThroughout Resident Evil 4 the player will come across a traveling Merchant, who will offer new weapons and items for the player to purchase. The player can also sell anything that isn’t a key item (apart from the knife) to the Merchant and upgrade weapons via interacting with him. At first, the Merchant’s weapons and upgrades will become available at set times throughout the game; however, on a second game, everything will be available from the start.Below is a complete breakdown of all the weapons, their upgrade costs (in parenthesis) and statistics: firepower, firing speed (rounds fired per second), reload speed, and capacity (the number of rounds in a full magazine). Exclusive upgrades are also detailed.PistolsHandgunLevelFirepowerFiring SpeedReload SpeedCapacity11.00.471.731021.2 (7,000)0.40 (5,000)1.47 (5,000)13 (4,000)31.4 (10,000)0.33 (12,000)0.87 (12,000)16 (6,000)41.6 (15,000)19 (8,000)51.8 (18,000)22 (10,000)62.0 (20,000)25 (12,000)Notes: The Handgun's exclusive upgrade increases the likelihood of one a one-hit kill by fivefold.PunisherLevelFirepowerFiring SpeedReload SpeedCapacity10.90.471.701021.1 (10,000)0.40 (10,000)1.47 (8,000)13 (8,000)31.3 (15,000)0.33 (20,000)0.83 (18,000)16 (10,000)41.5 (20,000)20 (15,000)51.7 (25,000)24 (18,000)61.9 (35,000)28 (24,000)Notes: The Punisher's exclusive upgrade will allow the penetration of up to five enemies at once.Red9LevelFirepowerFiring SpeedReload SpeedCapacity11.60.532.73821.8 (15,000)0.47 (10,000)2.20 (6,000)10 (6,000)32.0 (20,000)0.40 (15,000)1.67 (10,000)12 (8,000)42.4 (24,000)15 (12,000)52.8 (28,000)18 (16,000)63.7 (45,000)22 (22,000)Notes: The Red9's exclusive upgrade will raise its firepower to 5.0 on the GameCube and to 6.0 in other versions. The weapon resembles a Mauser C96.BlacktailLevelFirepowerFiring SpeedReload SpeedCapacity11.60.471.701521.8 (10,000)0.40 (10,000)1.47 (8,000)18 (8,000)32.0 (15,000)0.27 (20,000)0.83 (15,000)21 (10,000)42.3 (20,000)25 (15,000)52.7 (25,000)30 (20,000)63.0 (35,000)35 (25,00)Notes: The Blacktail's exclusive upgrade will raise its firepower to 3.4.MatildaLevelFirepowerFiring SpeedReload SpeedCapacity11.00.471.731521.2 (15,000)1.47 (6,000)18 (7,000)31.4 (17,000)0.87 (15,000)21 (10,000)41.6 (20,000)24 (12,000)51.8 (25,000)27 (16,000)62.0 (35,000)30 (20,000)Notes: The Matilda is an unlockable weapon, available after beating the game. Its exclusive upgrade will increase its capacity to 100.ShotgunsShotgunLevelFirepowerFiring SpeedReload SpeedCapacity14.01.533.03624.5 (15,000)2.43 (7,000)8 (8,000)35.0 (20,000)1.50 (15,000)10 (10,000)46.0 (25,000)12 (12,000)57.0 (30,000)15 (15,000)68.0 (45,000)18 (20,000)Notes: The Shotgun's exclusive upgrade allows full firepower at all ranges.Riot GunLevelFirepowerFiring SpeedReload SpeedCapacity15.01.533.03725.5 (20,000)2.43 (7,000)9 (10,000)36.0 (24,000)1.50 (20,000)11 (12,000)46.5 (28,000)13 (15,000)57.0 (32,000)15 (20,000)68.0 (50,000)17 (25,000)Notes: The Riot Gun's exclusive upgrade raises its firepower to 10.0. The weapon resembles an M1014.StrikerLevelFirepowerFiring SpeedReload SpeedCapacity16.00.733.001227.0 (25,000)2.40 (8,000)14 (10,000)38.0 (28,000)1.50 (15,000)16 (12,000)49.0 (32,000)20 (16,000)510.0 (40,000)24 (18,000)612.0 (60,000)28 (25,000)Notes: The Striker's exlusive upgrade increases its capacity to 100.MagnumsBroken ButterflyLevelFirepowerFiring SpeedReload SpeedCapacity113.00.703.676215.0 (25,000)3.00 (15,000)8 (15,000)317.0 (30,000)2.33 (20,000)10 (20,000)420.0 (35,000)12 (25,000)524.0 (50,000)628.0 (70,000)Notes: The Broken Butterfly's exclusive upgrade raises its firepower to 50. The weapon resembles a Schofield Model 3.Killer7LevelFirepowerFiring SpeedReload SpeedCapacity125.00.701.837230.0 (62,000)1.53 (20,000)10 (30,000)335.0 (78,000)0.93 (30,000)14 (40,000)Notes: The namesake of this weapon is the game Killer7.HandcannonLevelFirepowerFiring SpeedReload SpeedCapacity130.01.173.673235.0 (40,000)2.87 (25,000)4 (15,000)340.0 (50,000)1.83 (50,000)5 (20,000)445.0 (70,000)6 (25,000)550.0 (90,000)8 (35,000)660.0 (120,000)10 (50,000)Notes: The Handcannon is an unlockable weapon; it becomes available after the Mercenaries minigame is beaten with all characters, with five stars on each level. The Handcannon's exclusive upgrade is unlimited ammo and an increase of firepower to 99.9.RiflesBolt-action rifleLevelFirepowerFiring SpeedReload SpeedCapacity14.02.734.00525.0 (10,000)3.23 (8,000)7 (6,000)36.0 (12,000)2.33 (18,000)9 (8,000)48.0 (20,000)12 (12,000)510.0 (25,000)15 (18,000)612.0 (35,000)18 (25,000)Notes: The Rifle's exclusive upgrade raises its firepower to 18.0Semi-automatic rifleLevelFirepowerFiring SpeedReload SpeedCapacity17.01.832.331028.0 (15,000)1.90 (9,000)12 (10,000)39.0 (18,000)1.33 (18,000)14 (12,000)411.0 (24,000)17 (15,000)513.0 (30,000)20 (20,000)615.0 (40,000)24 (25,000)Notes: The Semi-autmoatic rifle's upgrade decreases its firing speed to 0.40 on the GameCube, and to 0.80 in all other versions. This weapon resembles a PSG1.Misc. WeaponsTMPLevelFirepowerFiring SpeedReload SpeedCapacity10.40.102.373020.5 (7,000)1.93 (5,000)50 (7,000)30.6 (14,000)1.17 (15,000)100 (15,000)40.8 (18,000)150 (20,000)51.0 (24,000)200 (25,000)61.2 (35,000)250 (35,000)Notes: The TMP's exclusive upgrade raises its firepower to 1.8.Chicago TypewriterLevelFirepowerFiring SpeedReload SpeedCapacity110.00.101.63InfiniteNotes: The Chicago Typewriter is an unlockable weapon; it becomes available after the completion of Assignment Ada on the GC; after Separate Ways on the PS2 and Wii; or after both minigames of the PC.Mine ThrowerLevelFirepowerFiring SpeedReload SpeedCapacity12.01.333.43524.0 (25,000)2.53 (18,000)7 (25,000)36.0 (45,000)10 (40,000)Notes: The Mine Thrower's exclusive upgrade enables heatseeking and increases its blast radius.Extra ContentUpon completion of the game, the player is awarded with the modes described hereunder.Assignment AdaAssignment Ada is an additional non-canonical single player chapter where the player takes control of Ada Wong, assaulting the final island's base in search of five Las Plagas virus vials. There are no save points; the enemy count is increased; this chapter turn, then, into a mad-dash battle royale, ending in a confrontation with Krauser.The MercenariesThis minigame stations the player in an area wherein he must survive before a chopper pick-up. The goal is to rack up as many points as possible, by taking out enemies quickly, before time expires. There are five characters and four areas to choose from. Each character starts with different weapons; while each stage is equipped with ammo boxes, bonus timers, and time extenders. These stages are sourced and slightly altered from the main game.ScoringUpon starting Mercenaries, Leon will be the only selectable character. To earn additional characters, the player must earn four stars on each individual stage. The village stage unlocks Ada Wong; the castle stage unlocks Krauser; the military base unlocks Hunk; and the water-world unlocks Wesker.An unlockable weapon, the Handcannon, may be earned thus: four stars on every level with all five characters. (To earn a five star rating, the player must earn 60,000 points on a stage. He must survive until the time reaches zero; even if he hits 60,000 points, dying will cause the score to not count).Below is a complete list of characters and their starting weapons, grenades, ammo, and health. Hand to hand moves are also detailed, in addition to each stage's boss.Leon S. KennedyWeapons:Blacktail – Power = 2.7 / Reload Speed = 1.47 / Firing Speed = 0.40 / Capacity = 21Riot Gun – Power = 7.0 / Reload Speed = 1.67 / Firing Speed = 1.53 / Capacity = 13Ammo – 30 Pistol Rounds / 10 Shotgun RoundsGrenades – NoneHealth – 1 First Aid SprayHand to Hand:Headshot – Roundhouse kickKnee shot – Thrust kick to villages, suplex on soldier types and monksAda WongWeapons:Punisher – Power = 1.9 (exclusive, rounds go through 5 enemies) / Reload Speed = 1.47 / Firing Speed = 0.33 / Capacity = 20Semi Auto Rifle (scoped) - Power = 15 / Reload Speed = 1.90 / Firing Speed = 0.80 / Capacity = 12TMP – Power = 1.0 / Reload Speed = 1.93 / Reload Speed = 1.93 / Firing Speed = 0.10 / Capacity = 100Ammo – 30 Pistol Rounds / 100 TMP Rounds / 5 Rifle RoundsGrenades – 3 Incendiary GrenadesHealth – 1 First Aid SprayHand to Hand:Headshot – Fan kickKnee shot – Heel kickJack KrauserWeapons:Bow – Power = N/A / Reload Speed = N/A / Firing Speed = N/A / Capacity = N/AAmmo – 30 ArrowsGrenades – 3 FlashHealth – 1 First Aid SprayHand to Hand:Headshot – Double heel kickKnee shot – Knee to faceMutilated arm – RB to activate, X to attack, B to cancel (X360)HUNKWeapons:Custom TMP – Power = 1.0 / Reload Speed = 1.17 / Firing Speed = 0.10 / Capacity = 100Ammo – 50 TMP RoundsGrenades – 3 Hand GrenadesHealth – 1 First Aid SprayHand to Hand:Headshot – NeckbreakerKnee shoot – Rugby kickAlbert WeskerWeapons:Handgun – Power = 2.0 (exclusive, headshots are five times more likely) / Reload Speed = 0.87 / Firing Speed = 0.33 / Capacity = 25Semi Auto Rifle – Power = 15.0 / Reload Speed = 1.90 / Firing Speed = 0.80 / Capacity = 24Killer7 – Power = 30.0 / Reload Speed = 1.53 / Firing Speed = 0.70 / Capacity = 10Ammo – NoneGrenades – 4 Hand Grenade / 1 Incendiary / 3 FlashHealth – 1 First Aid SprayHand to Hand:Headshot – Thrust punchKnee shot – Chikyo Chagi (downward kick similar to Kazuya’s Tsunami kick from Tekken)Stages and BossesVillageCastleMilitary BaseWater WorldBella SistersGarradorsChaingun GeneralSuper Dr. SalvadorSeparate WaysIncluded in the PlayStation 2 and Nintendo Wii versions, Separate Ways is an additional 3-5 hour campaign. Separate Ways follows Ada through the whole game and consists of 5 chapters, each taking place in a different section and time of the game. Players are given a small stash of weapons and ammo and can purchase (but not upgrade) weapons from the merchant. All the treasures from Leon's campaign also exist in Ada's, and in some cases are key items in her quest. Each chapter is preceded by a cutscene and ends with Ada giving a short audio report on a character vital to that chapter.In Chapter 1, Ada has been tasked by Wesker to retrieve the Las Plagas sample. She arrives in the village at around the same time as Leon. Ada observes Leon in trouble during his skirmish with the villagers; in order to stop them from attacking Leon, she must quickly get to the church and ring its bell.In Chapter 2, Ada has learned that Luis is in possession of the sample, but has gone missing. Ada needs to find him ASAP. She starts in Bitores Mendez' (the village chief's) house and must work her way back to the cabin, where Leon finds Luis. When she reaches the cabin, she finds that Leon and Luis have just been captured by Mendez. She backtracks to Mendez' house, just as Mendez and Leon meet in the hallway. Ada saves Leon from being killed by Mendez. Mendez gives chase to Ada, and tranquilizes her. Ada wakes up on the bloody altar found near the lift area, where she is about to be sacrificed by the villagers. She escapes, takes the lifts back and fights an El Gigante. She runs into Luis, finally, who was exiting the cabin where he and Leon had their late night hold-off from the villagers.In Chapter 3, Ada is still in search of the sample held by Luis. The chapter starts at Leon and Ada first meeting, which was in the room overlooking the castle's garden maze. Ada flees Leon into the maze, and resolves to find Luis and the sample. Wesker orders Ada to kill Leon on sight, so Ada makes a pact to not run into him, as she does not want to hurt her former acquaintance. Ada does end up in the room of the castle where Leon finds Ashley in the shackles; she hides behind a column, as Luis is murderer by Saddler, in front of Leon. Saddler takes the sample from the corpse of Luis and escapes. Wesker tells Ada that there will be another time to retrieve the sample.Ada unleashing fire at the docks.In Chapter 4, the game jumps ahead to the Island, where Ada and Krauser have become distrustful of each other. Krauser is ordered to do the job Ada couldn't do: kill Leon. Ada has to hurry to the room where Krauser and Leon fight, in order to stop Krauser. This chapter is the first to take place in an new section of the game: a ship dock littered with turrets and cannons. Ada hurries through the locale, and after a small scare on one of the ships, she stops the fight and saves Leon.In Chapter 5, the final chapter, the mission is simple: retrieve the sample. Taking place at the very end of the game, Ada is making her way through the camp Leon had fought through with the help of his helicopter buddy, Mike. After she kills the straggler soldiers, she's confronted by Krauser again. This time, however, he wants to fight Ada. This fight takes place after Leon had "killed" Krauser; however, he is just as tough as he was in the Leon fight. Ada dispatches him. She makes her way towards the room where Leon and Ashley ran into Saddler. Ada interrupts their confrontation and makes the two run away. Ada faces Saddler, who is in a more human form than Leon is later exposed to. After the battle seems over, Ada grabs the sample; yet, she is captured, this time by Saddler. She wakes up just prior to Leon and Saddler's final fight. Leon releases her. Ada stands back as they fight, noticing a rocket launcher. Ada hurries to the launcher, and throws it to Leon, who uses it to destroy Saddler once and for all. Ada takes the sample from Leon, sets the island to self-destruct, and escapes on a helicopter. She returns the Plagas sample to Wesker, single-handedly making his mad scheme to destroy the world in Resident Evil 5 possible.Differences between Regional Versions (JAP, U.S. and PAL)Other than the game being called BioHazard 4 in Japan, there is a more subtle difference between versions which one would only notice if he were to put two screenshots of Ashley Graham next to one another. Her cup size was "embiggened", from an A, perhaps a small B, to a C, for the game's US release. The Japanese version, in addition, cuts some scenes featuring Dr. Salavador, the chainsaw zombie, because of gore and violence.The differences in the PAL version are found in mercenaries mode. Throughout each stage, the enemy counts and triggers are lowered, and rifle ammo will only appear in quantities of two and three, instead of three and five.ReceptionResident Evil 4 was a large departure from the past Resident Evil games. News of the over-the-shoulder perspective (vs. third person) and more action oriented gameplay (vs. survival-horror) had worried the most niche Resident Evil fans; but, at the least, the masses were pleased. Capcom did state that Resident Evil sales had been declining for some time, and that gamers - and even the producers themselves - were tiring of the old Resident Evil formula. Capcom, then, took the risks involved with making changes. The game was a blockbuster hit. It sold millions of copies, more than any other Resident Evil game. While the hardcore fans missed the old style, they still did, generally, like the game. Resident Evil 4 became one of the highest rated games ever, from both professional critics as well as consumers. It sold so well that Capcom decided to port the game to the PS2, which ended the "GameCube Only Deal". It was, moreover, ported to the PC and then again to the Nintendo Wii. The PC port, while receiving positive reviews, was criticized for its sub-par keyboard controls, lack of mouse support and low quality cut-scenes. Because of Resident Evil 4's reception, its controls would be kept and improved upon in the next installment, Resident Evil 5, which pushed the action even further and added co-operative play for the first time in the franchise.PortsDespite Mikami's intention of making Resident Evil 4 a Gamecube exclusive, the game ended up receiving more ports than other games in the series. Many fans consider the Wii version to be the best port.PublicationGameCubePlayStation 2PCWiiPS3Xbox 360Metacritic96/10096/10076/10091/10084/10084/100GameRankings95.83%95.85%74.24%91.45%84.64%86.00%PlayStation 2Released on October 25, 2005 in North America, the PlayStation 2 features a brand new scenario called "Separate Ways", an exclusive campaign for Ada Wong. While nothing much was changed in translation, the PS2 version was criticized for its inferior graphics.PCThe first PC port of Resident Evil 4 was developed by SourceNext in Hong Kong and published by Typhoon Games. It was released in Japan on May 15, 2007, with March releases in Europe, North America and Australia, all of where it was published by Ubisoft. This port contains the bonus features from the PS2 version, such as "Separate Ways", the P.R.L. 412 laser cannon, and a second set of unlockable costumes for Leon and Ashley, as well as an easy difficulty level. It also supports multiple widescreen resolutions. The shadow and lighting issues were fixed in the first and only patch for the game, Version 1.10.Surprisingly, the PC port does not support the mouse, making the controls in the game feel outdated.System RequirementsMinimumRecommendedOS: Windows 2000CPU: Pentium 4 or AMD Athlon 1.4 GHz (single core)RAM Memory: 256MBHard Drive Space: 7GBGraphics Card: DirectX 9.0c compatible card with 128MB RAM with Pixel Shader 2.0 supportSound Card: DirectX 9.0c compatibleOS: Windows 2000CPU: Pentium 4 or AMD Athlon 2.4 GHz (single core)RAM Memory: 512MBHard Drive Space: 7GBGraphics Card: DirectX 9.0c compatible card with 256MB RAM with Pixel Shader 2.0 supportSound Card: DirectX 9.0c compatibleNintendo WiiIn May 2007, a re-release version of BioHazard 4 made its way to Japan. This version did not include any new features except a trailer for Resident Evil: Umbrella Chronicles, but it did retain extras from the PlayStation 2's version while also featuring visual from the GameCube's original release and widescreen display. It also allowed for aiming with the Wii's IR functionality.The game is compatible with multi-controller scheme including the following.Wiimote/NunchuckClassic ControllerGameCube ControlleriOSIn July 2009, an iPhone version of Resident Evil 4 was released on the Japanese iTunes App Store. It came to the US store as well, and plays as a drastically inferior boiled-down level-based version of the real game, much more arena shooting than adventuring. Capcom later created an iPad version.Xbox 360 and PS3On March 23, 2011, Capcom confirmed that Resident Evil 4 HD and Resident Evil: Code Veronica X HD would come to Xbox Live Arcade and the PlayStation Network as two separate downloads, on September 20, 2011 and September 27, 2011. This, of course, is in contrast to the compilation disc, entitled BioHazard Revival Selection, which would be a Japanese only release.The HD collection features all the extras from the previous releases, including the minigame Separate Ways.</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20800">Dead Space</game><game id="19631">Cold Fear</game><game id="20510">Escape From Bug Island</game><game id="20982">Alan Wake</game><game id="22561">Colors</game><game id="32684">Shadows of the Damned</game><game id="39750">The Evil Within</game><game id="29212">Deadly Premonition</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/82063/2566479-re4.jpg</image></root>