<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15820</id><name>Tecmo Super NBA Basketball</name><description>Tecmo Super NBA Basketball is a 5-on-5 basketball game, published by Tecmo and developed by Acclaim for the SNES and Sega Genesis. The game includes a season mode, with three season lengths (Short, Reduced, and Regular), as well as the option to play a pre-season game and an all-star game. The game includes a battery, allowing the player to save his or her game. Rosters The following are the teams in the game and their rosters. Atlanta Hawks  Starters  Guards: Rumeal Robinson, Stacey Augmon     Forwards: Dominique Wilkins, Kevin Willis Center: Blair Rasmussen    Reserves  Guards: Morlon Wiley, Rodney Monroe, Maurice Cheeks     Forwards: Duane Ferrell, Paul Graham, Alexander Volkov Center: John Koncak   Boston Celtics  Starters  Guards: John Bagley, Dee Brown Forwards: Reggie Lewis, Larry Bird Center: Robert Parish  Reserves  Guards: Rickey Green, Kevin Gamble Forwards: Rick Fox, Kevin Mchale, Ed Pinckney Center: Joe Kleine, Stojko Vrrankovic   Charlotte Hornets  Starters  Guards: Tyrone (Muggsy) Bogues, Rex Chapman Forwards: Kenny Gattison, Larry Johnson Center: Mike Gminski  Reserves  Guards: Kevin Lynch, Kendall Gill, Dell Curry Forwards: Anthony Frederick, Johnny Newman, J.R. Reid Center: Eric Leckner   Chicago Bulls  Starters Guards: John Paxson, Michael Jordan Forwards: Scottie Pippen, Horace Grant Center: Bill Cartwright Reserves Guards: B.J. Armstrong, Bobby Hansen, Craig Hodges Forwards: Stacey King, Cliff Levingston Center: Scott Williams, Will Perdue  Cleveland Cavaliers  Starters Guards: Mark Price, Craig Ehlo Forwards: John (Hot Rod) Williams, Larry Nance Center: Brad Daugherty Reserves Guards: Terrell Brandon, John Battle, Steve Kerr, Jimmy  Oliver              Forwards: Winston Bennett, Henry James Center: Danny Ferry  Dallas Mavericks  Starters Guards: Lafayette Lever, Derek Harper    Forwards: Rolando Blackman, Randy White Center: Doug Smith Reserves Guards: Mike Iuzzolino, Brad Davis Forwards: Terry Davis, Rodney McCray, Herb Williams Center: James Donaldson, Donald Hodge  Denver Nuggets  Starters Guards: Chris Jackson, Winston Garland Forwards: Reggie Williams, Marcus Liberty Center: Dikembe Mutombo Reserves Guards: Mark Macon, Todd Lichti Forwards: Anthony Cook, Kevin Brooks, Greg Anderson Center: Joe Wolf, Scott Hastings  Detroit Pistons  Starters Guards: Isiah Thomas, Joe Dumars Forwards: Dennis Rodman (No special hair colors), Orlando  Woolridge        Center: Bill Laimbeer Reserves Guards: Lance Blanks, Darrell Walker Forwards: Mark Aguirre, Bob McCann, John Salley, Charles  Thomas Center: Brad Sellers  Golden State Warriors  Starters Guards: Tim Hardaway, Mario Elie Forwards: Chris Mullin, Tyrone Hill Center: Billy Owens Reserves Guards: Vincent Askew, Sarunas Marciulionis Forwards: Rod Higgins, Chris Gatling, Victor Alexander, Tom  Tolbert Center: Alton Lister  Houston Rockets  Starters Guards: Kenny Smith, Vernon Maxwell Forwards: John Turner, Otis Thorpe Center: Hakeem Olajuwon    Reserves Guards: Eric Floyd, Dave Jamerson    Forwards: Buck Johnson, Carl Herrera, Larry Smith, Matt  Bullard           Center: Wayne Rollins     Indiana Pacers  Starters Guards: Micheal Williams, Reggie Miller    Forwards: Chuck Person, Detlef Shrempf    Center: Rik Smits    Reserves Guards: Vern Fleming, George McCloud, Sean Green, Jerome Lane           Forwards: Kenny Williams, LaSalle Thompson    Center: Greg Dreiling  Los Angeles Clippers  Starters Guards: Gary Grant, Ron Harper    Forwards: Loy Vaught, Danny Manning    Center: Charles Smith Reserves Guards: Glenn Rivers, Bo Kimble, Danny Young    Forwards: Ken Norman    Center: Leron Ellis, James Edwards, Olden Ploynice     Los Angeles Lakers  Starters Guards: Byron Scott, "Magic" Johnson    Forwards: James Worthy, Sam Perkins    Center: Vlade Divac    Reserves Guards: Sedale Threatt, Tony Smith    Forwards: Terry Teagle, Keith Owens, A.C. Green, Jack Haley    Center: Elden Campbell     Miami Heat  Starters Guards: Brian Shaw, Steve Smith    Forwards: Glen Rice, Alec Kessler    Center: Rony Seikaly    Reserves Guards: Jon Sundvold, Vernell Coles, Kevin Edwards    Forwards: Keith Askins, Willie Burton, Grant Long    Center: Alan Ogg     Milwaukee Bucks  Starters  Guards: Jay Humphries, Alvin Robertson     Forwards: Dale Ellis, Fred Roberts     Center: Frank Brickowski      Reserves  Guards: Lester Conner, Jeff Grayer, Steve Henson     Forwards: Larry Krystkowiak, Brad Lohaus     Center: Moses Malone, Danny Schayes       Minnesota Timberwolves  Starters  Guards: Jerome Richardson, Doug West     Forwards: Tony Campbell, Thurl Bailey     Center: Felton Spencer      Reserves  Guards: Scott Brooks, Gerald Glass     Forwards: Mark Randall, Sam Mitchell, Tod Murphy     Center: Luc Longley, Randy Breuer       New Jersey Nets  Starters  Guards: Kenny Anderson, Drazen Petrovic     Forwards: Chris Morris, Derrick Coleman     Center: Sam Bowie      Reserves  Guards: Mookie Blaylock, Tate George, Doug Lee     Forwards: Roy Hinson, Terry Mills     Center: Chris Dudley, Dave Feitl       New York Knicks  Starters  Guards: Mark Jackson, John Starks     Forwards: Xavier McDaniel, Charles Oakley     Center: Patrick Ewing      Reserves  Guards: Greg Anthony, Gerald Wilkins, Kennard Winchester     Forwards: Kiki Vandeweghe, Anthony Mason, Brian Quinnett     Center: Tim McCormick       Orlando Magic  Starters  Guards: Scott Skiles, Nick Anderson     Forwards: Sean Higgins, Jeff Turner     Center: Stanley Roberts       Reserves  Guards: Sam Vincent, Chris Corchiani, Anthony Bowie     Forwards: Mark Acres, Terry Cateledge, Brian Williams     Center: Greg Kite       Philadelphia 76ers  Starters  Guards: Johnny Dawkins, Hersey Hawkins     Forwards: Ron Anderson, Charles Barkley     Center: Charles Shackleford      Reserves  Guards: Brian Oliver, Greg Grant     Forwards: Jayson Williams, Kenny Payne, Armon Gilliam     Center: Jeff Ruland, Manute Bol   Phoenix Suns  Starters  Guards: Kevin Johnson, Jeff Hornacek     Forwards: Tim Perry, Tom Chambers     Center: Andrew Lang      Reserves  Guards: Negele Knight, Dan Majerle     Forwards: Cedric Ceballos, Ed Nealy, Jerrod Mustaf, Kurt   Rambis     Center: Mark West       Portland Trail Blazers  Starters  Guards: Terry Porter, Clyde Drexler     Forwards: Jerome Kersey, Buck Williams     Center: Kevin Duckworth      Reserves  Guards: Robert Pack, Danny Ainge, Ennis Whatley     Forwards: Cliff Robinson, Mark Bryant     Center: Alaa Andelnaby, Wayne Cooper       Sacramento Kings  Starters  Guards: Spud Webb, Mitch Richmond     Forwards: Anthony Bonner, Pete Chilcutt     Center: Les Jepsen      Reserves  Guards: Jim Les, Randy Brown, Dennis Hopson     Forwards: Lionel Simmons, Wayman Tisdale     Center: Duane Causwell, Dwayne Schintzius       San Antonio Spurs  Starters  Guards: Rod Strickland, Paul Pressey     Forwards: Sean Elliott, Terry Cummings     Center: David Robinson      Reserves  Guards: Greg Sutton, Vinnie Johnson     Forwards: Willie Anderson, Donald Royal, Antoine Carr,   Sidney Green     Center: Tom Copa       Seattle Supersonics  Starters  Guards: Gary Payton, Ricky Pierce     Forwards: Eddie Johnson, Shawn Kemp     Center: Michael Cage  Reserves  Guards: Dana Barros, Nate McMillan, Bart Kofoed     Forwards: Tony Brown, Marty Conlon     Center: Benoit Benjamin, Rich King       Utah Jazz  Starters  Guards: John Stockton, Jeff Malone     Forwards: Theodore Edwards, Karl Malone     Center: Mark Eaton      Reserves  Guards: Eric Murdock, Delaney Rudd, Corey Crowder     Forwards: David Benoit, Tyrone Corbin     Center: Mike Brown, Isaac Austin       Washington Bullets  Starters  Guards: Michael Adams, A.J. English     Forwards: Bernard King, Harvey Grant     Center: Pervis Ellison      Reserves  Guards: La. Bradford Smith, David Wingate, Andre Turner     Forwards: Ledell Eackles, Larry Stewart, Charles Jones     Center: Greg Foster   All-Star East  Starters  Guards: Isiah Thomas, Michael Jordan Forwards: Scottie Pippen, Charles Barkley     Center: Patrick Ewing      Reserves  Guards: Mark Price, Michael Adams, Joe Dumars     Forwards: Dennis Rodman, Reggie Lewis, Kevin Willis     Center: Brad Daugherty       All-Star West  Starters  Guards: Magic Johnson, Clyde Drexler     Forwards: Chris Mullin, Karl Malone     Center: David Robinson  Reserves  Guards: John Stockton, Tim Hardaway, Jeff Hornacek, Dan   Majerle         Forwards: James Worthy     Center: Hakeem Olajuwon, Dikembe Mutombo       </description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="22">Basketball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2778">Bulls vs. Lakers and the NBA Playoffs</game><game id="22046">David Robinson's Supreme Court</game><game id="18984">NBA Courtside 2: Featuring Kobe Bryant</game><game id="27293">Tecmo NBA Basketball</game><game id="11202">NBA Give 'n Go</game><game id="38745">Super Dunk Star</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2389497-genesis_tecmosupernbabasketball.jpg</image></root>