<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1601</id><name>Lumines II</name><description>Overview   Lumines II is a PSP game developed by Q Entertainment and published by Disney Interactive Studios (Buena Vista Games at the time of release.) Returning from the first game are the Challenge, VS CPU, Time Attack, and Puzzle Modes. New with Lumines II is the Mission Mode, Sequencer, and the ability to create custom playlists of skins. Songs created in the Sequencer can be sent to other PSPs via local Wi-Fi, along with custom playlists and replay data. Ad-Hoc is also used for two player VS Mode and sharing a demo of the game. A trial of  Every Extend Extra is included on the disc.  Music   All music is composed by  Takayuki Nakamura unless otherwise noted.  Challenge Class B Skins 1. Circles 2. Stroll Around the World - Star Casino 3. My Generation 4. Block the Sky 5. Pump It - Black Eyed Peas 6. Get Up and Go 7. Mysterious Travels to Asia 8. Kabuki 9. Bean Jam? 10. Born to Lead - Hoobastank 11. Morning Beats 12. Round About 13. 4x4 Bricks - Techriders 14. T.S.L 15. Talk 2 You 16. Star Guitar - The Chemical Brothers 17. Take a Coffee for a Moment? 18. Kawaii 19. Let It All Ride - Ken Ishii 20. Strangers 21. Fly Into Yhe Sky 22. Girls - Takagi Masakatsu  Challenge Class A Skins 23. Sparks!! 24. Bottle Rocket - The Go! Team 25. The Mission to the Moon 26. Bad Boy Century 27. Hollaback Girl - Gwen Stefani 28. Cuckoo Clock 29. Sister Walk 30. Heavenly Star - Yusuke Tanaka 31. Urbanization 32. Meguro 33. Lose Control - Missy Eliot 34. You Are Not Here. 35. Square Dance 36. House 66 - Sugiurumn 37. Da-Di-Do 38. So That Someone May Visit You. 39. Tiny Piano 40. Take My Time - Junior Senior 41. Holiday in Summer 42. Flashback 43. Hikaru Frame Work 44. El Viento - Takagi Masakatsu  Challenge Class S Skins 45. Spirits 46. Black Tambourine - Beck 47. Just... 48. Regret - New Order 49. Day Dream 50. Breezer - Junkie XL 51. Aoi 52. Bloomy Girls - Takagi Masakatsu 53. Darkside Beside the River 54. Shadow of the Grand Father 55. Gangster Trippin' - Fatboy Slim 56. Butterfly Stroke 57. Aback 58. Hometown 59. Cosmic Humming - Muku 60. Take a Dog Out a Walk 61. Dao 62. Be Bop Acid - Toby  Q'hey 63. Working in the Hole 64. Big Things 65. Big Elpaso 66. Reality Check - Stigmato Inc.  VS CPU Skins 67. That Savanna Calls. 68. Auto Mobile Industry 69. Naha!! 70. The Bird Singing in the Night 71. The Speed of Light 72. Japanese Form 73. Go to a Toy Town. 74. Whoop-De-Do 75. Papa's Ukelele 76. Moon Beam  Sequencer Skins 77. Song #1 78. Song #2 79. Song #3 80. Song #4  Unlockable Skins 81. TinToy 82. Fanatic 83. 45 Degrees 84. Neodimium 85. Rodent 86. Slipping 87. Please Return My CD 88. Prime Factor 89. Mekong 90. Water, Flower  Lights 91. The Spy Loves Me 92. Brash 93. Chinese Restaurant 94. Xop 95. Manager Class 96. Machine Interface 97. Elect.M.G.R.</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17578">Rez</game><game id="20320">Synaesthete</game><game id="8887">Every Extend Extra</game><game id="13414">Gunpey</game><game id="22034">Rez HD</game><game id="1896">Tetris</game><game id="5487">Columns</game><game id="8669">Exit</game><game id="1710">Mercury Meltdown</game><game id="20589">Bomberman</game><game id="6382">Archer Maclean's Mercury</game><game id="20566">PQ: Practical Intelligence Quotient 2</game><game id="6190">Super Collapse! II</game><game id="10673">PQ: Practical Intelligence Quotient</game><game id="25808">Blokus Portable: Steambot Championship</game><game id="7037">Osu! Tatakae! Ouendan</game><game id="254">Moero! Nekketsu Rhythm Damashii Osu! Tatakae! Ouendan 2</game><game id="11982">Elite Beat Agents</game><game id="22383">Otocky</game><game id="23234">Tetris Party</game><game id="29186">Chime</game><game id="27236">Numblast</game><game id="29417">Kurulin Fusion</game><game id="31232">Fractal: Make Blooms Not War</game><game id="34287">Chime Super Deluxe</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4647/837327-932702_75091_front.jpg</image></root>