<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16121</id><name>Day of Defeat: Source</name><description>OverviewDay of Defeat: Source is the sequel to the Half-Life mod Day of Defeat, a multiplayer first-person shooter set in World War II. Like Counter Strike: Source, the game offers a Source engine update to the original's visuals, sound and gameplay, with minor tweaks to its formula.Players assume the role of US Army (Allies) or Axis (Wehrmacht) troops and choose between six classes, each with unique weapons. Teams are tasked with either holding strategic points or detonating those of the enemy.It is also the first Valve release other than the free Lost Coast level for Half-Life 2 to incorporate High Dynamic Range lighting.ClassesRiflemanU.S. ArmyU.S. Army RiflemanPrimary Weapon:M1 GarandClip Capacity: 8 rounds, with 10 additional clipsSecondary Fire: " Iron sight" zoomEquipment:2 Rifle GrenadesCombat KnifeWehrmachtWehrmacht RiflemanPrimary Weapon:Mauser Kar 98Clip Capacity: 5 rounds, with 12 extra clips.Secondary Fire: "Iron sight" zoomEquipment:2 Rifle GrenadesEntrenching ShovelAssaultU.S. ArmyU.S. Army AssaultPrimary Weapon:M-1928 ThompsonMagazine Capacity: 30 rounds, with 6 extra mags.Secondary Fire: PunchEquipment:M-1911 Colt .451 Fragmentation Grenade1 Smoke GrenadeWehrmachtWehrmacht AssaultPrimary Weapon:MP-40 Submachine GunMagazine Capacity: 30 rounds, with 6 extra mags.Secondary Fire: PunchEquipment:Walther P381 Fragmentation Grenade1 Smoke GrenadeSupportU.S. ArmyU.S. Army SupportPrimary Weapon:M-1918A2 BAR (Browning Automatic Rifle)Magazine Capacity: 20 rounds, with 10 extra mags.Secondary Fire: Semi-Auto toggleEquipment:2 Fragmentation GrenadesCombat KnifeWehrmachtWehrmacht SupportPrimary Weapon:MP-44 (Sturmgewehr-44)Magazine Capacity: 30 rounds, with 6 extra mags.Secondary Fire: Semi-Auto toggleEquipment:2 Fragmentation GrenadesEntrenching ShovelSniperU.S. ArmyU.S. Army SniperPrimary Weapon:M-1903A4 Springfield w/ ScopeClip Capacity: 5 rounds, with 12 extra clipsSecondary Fire: Scope ZoomEquipment:M-1911 Colt .4Combat KnifeWehrmachtWehrmacht Sn iperPrimary WeaponMauser Kar 98 w/ ScopeClip Capacity: 5 rounds, with 12 extra clips.Secondary Fire: Scope ZoomEquipmentWalther P38Entrenching ShovelMachine GunnerU.S. ArmyU.S. Army Machine GunnerPrimary Weapon:.30 Caliber Light Machine Gun w/ bipod150-round belt, with 2 additional beltsSecondary Fire: Deploy/Retract bipodEquipment:M-1911 Colt .45Combat KnifeWehrmachtWehrmacht Machine GunnerPrimary Weapon:MG-42 w/ bipod250-round belt, with 1 additional belt.Secondary Fire: Deploy/Retract BipodEquipment:Walther P38Entrenching ShovelRocketU.S. ArmyUS RocketPrimary Weapons:M1A1 BazookaAmmunition:5 rocketsSecondary Fire: Shoulder BazookaM1 CarbineMagazine Capacity: 15 rounds, w/ 2 extra mags.Secondary Fire: NoneEquipmentCombat KnifeWehrmachtWehrmacht RocketPrimary WeaponsPanzerschreck Raketen-Panzerbüchse 54Ammunition: 5 rocketsSecondary Fire: Shoulder PanzerschreckMauser C96 w/ M712 attachmentMagazine Capacity: 20, w/ 2 extra mags.Secondary Fire: NoneEquipmentEntrenching ShovelOfficial MapsArea Capturedod_anziodod_argentandod_avalanchedod_donnerdod_flashdod_kaltdod_palermDetonationdod_colmardod_jagdThe Palermo UpdateIn June 2008, the game received a major update consisting of a new map, dod_palermo, and Steamworks integration, including achievements, stat-tracking, and user icons. The game was also updated to a newer version of the Source engine used in The Orange Box, allowing for new visual effects. As a result, the game no longer supports DirectX 7 graphics cards.PC System RequirementsMinimum: 1.7 GHz Processor, 512MB RAM, DirectX® 8.1 level Graphics Card (Requires support for SSE), Windows® 7 (32/64-bit)/Vista/XP/2000, Mouse, Keyboard, Internet ConnectionRecommended: Pentium 4 processor (3.0GHz, or better), 1GB RAM, DirectX® 9 level Graphics Card, Windows® 7 (32/64-bit)/Vista/XP/2000, Mouse, Keyboard, Internet ConnectionMac System RequirementsMinimum: OS X version Leopard 10.5.8, Snow Leopard 10.6.3, 1GB RAM, NVIDIA GeForce 8 or higher, or ATI X1600 or higher, Mouse, Keyboard, Internet Connection</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2347">Call of Duty 2</game><game id="12633">Call of Duty: United Offensive</game><game id="20777">Call of Duty: World at War</game><game id="4389">Red Orchestra: Ostfront 41-45</game><game id="33357">Darkest Hour: Europe 44-45</game><game id="29886">Dino D-Day</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5480/609079-dod_boxart.jpg</image></root>