<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16176</id><name>Black Belt</name><description>OverviewThe cover of Hokuto no KenBlack Belt is a brawler developed and published by Sega for the Sega Master System platform.Black Belt is the American version of a Japenese game called Hokuto no Ken, better known as Fist of the North Star. The characters, story and setting were all changed in the American version because it lacked the license. Even though much was changed in the American version the gameplay stayed the same.PlotOne of the many boss encountersWang has kidnapped Kyoko who is the girlfriend of Riki. The kidnapper also happens to be Riki's rival, and he sets out to rescue Kyoko from Wang. Riki will fight his way through various cities and towns defeating enemies in order to fight against Wang. In the Japanese version, it plays the story of Hokuto No Ken facing familiar enemies up to the final boss, Raoh.GameplayTraverse Japan inspired locationsBlack Belt is a side scrolling brawler where you control Riki, a martial artist. Riki will travel through six stages, walking left to right, using his fighting skills to defeat Wang's henchman. Riki is able punch and kick enemies, and upon defeating them the enemies will explode. As you travel you will come across various enemies and mid bosses, which will eventually lead Riki to confront Wang. In the boss battles the fighting mechanics do not change, and you simply punch and kick to be victorious. The only difference is that the player is always facing the boss.Name changesBecause of the licencing issue, the names of the characters had to have been changed from the Hokuto No Ken characters to generic characters.Black Belt CharactersHokuto no Ken CharactersRikiKenshiroKyokoYuriaRyuShinHawkColonelGontaDevil RebirthOniTokiRitaSoutherWangRaohAppearances from other charactersThe Four Jacks (Club, Spade, Diamond and Mr Heart)Mad SargeFoxUighur</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9710">Batman Returns</game><game id="18122">Streets of Rage 2</game><game id="20436">Streets of Rage</game><game id="15924">Streets of Rage 3</game><game id="14763">The Karate Kid</game><game id="1653">Ninja Gaiden</game><game id="9602">My Hero</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2453/1538146-bbus2_front.jpg</image></root>