<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16179</id><name>Skies of Arcadia: Legends</name><description>PlotSkies of Arcadia: Legends starts you as a young ambitious Blue Rogue pirate named Vyse. Your father, Captain Dyne, is the captain of the Albatross a mighty pirate airship that is feared by the Valuan Empire. You, the crew, and your father, travel the skies in search of other pirates as well as Valuan battleships to take any valuables that can be found. While on such a mission you run into a Valuan captive, a young, shy girl named Fina, and this is where your adventure really begins. Fina will tell you little but her name, and revealed nothing about her secret mission, only that you trust her, and help her complete her important agenda.As everyone gets some rest, you and your best friend Aika notice a moon stone fall from the sky and land on a distant island. As the young adventurous pirates that you are, you and Aika make your way to the distant island to claim the magnificent moon stone. As you embark on your journey the Valuan Empire decides to ambush your home, Pirate Isle, and take Fina, your father and other loved ones. As soon as you learn this you make the only decision you can, to save your father and friends. Soon, you embark on your own, meeting many interesting people and traveling to majestic cities and villages. As you rescue Fina you learn about the Valuan Empire's plan to gather and control an ancient evil and use that evil to control the world. It is Fina's mission and destiny to stop this evil, and with you, Aika and a eclectic cast of others, nothing can stop you.Blue Rogues vs. The Black Pirates.Vyse and his father are Pirates, however, there are two types of Pirates and their incentives are very different. Blue Rogues fly under a blue-skulled flag and do not attack unarmed ships such as merchant vessels. Blue Rogues take pride in their actions and only attack ships that are armed and bigger then their own ship. Black Pirates fly under a black-skulled flag and attack anyone in their sights. Unarmed merchant ships and battleships alike are not safe, they attack them for pure pleasure, killing, and treasure hunting.Battle SystemThe game features a turn-based battle system as seen in many other JRPG's. Characters can use their turn to attack or use an item or special ability. Battles take place in three dimensions with characters moving around the battlefield automatically to attack their designated targets. A tactical element is introduced by changing the weapon's element, which also changes the colour. This doesn't take a turn and is useful when you know an enemy's weakness. The party shares a pool of SP, used for special moves. Characters can use a turn to charge more SP so you can unleash a devastating super move.The game also features aerial ship-to-ship combat, likewise turn-based. These battles are more tactical in nature as you have to choose what types of weapons to use, when to heal and whether to use evasive action all in advance.CharactersVyse--The main character of Skies of Arcadia: Legends. A young boy part of the Blue Rogues who has great hopes and ambitions of sailing to the end of the skies.Aika--Part of the crew of the Albatross and childhood friend of Vyse. She may speak her mind, but she's strong and reliable.Dyne--Captain of the Albatross, a feared pirate ship, and father to Vyse. He is a trusted leader and respected among his crew.Fina and Cupil--Fina is a mysterious, quiet girl that through curious events teams up with Vyse to take on the Valuan Empire. By her side is her trusted pet Cupil who can change shapes and helps Fina during combat.Drachma--An old sailor that Vyse meets early in his adventure. Drachma has a heavy conscience and helps Vyse throughout his adventure in hopes that he will also get a chance to settle his past.Gilder--Another Pirate that captains the Claudia. He's free spirited and travels wherever the skies take him in search of treasure and women.Empress Teodora--The Empress of the Valuan Empire. She is obsessed with conquest and power, no one dares challenge her reign.Prince Enrique--The son of Empress Teodora and the Prince of the Valuan Empire. Enrique does not agree with his mother, however, he is powerless to stop her.Lord Galcian--The commander of the entire Valuan Empire Armada, and he head of the master plan to control the ancient evil. He has 5 subordinates as well as one Vice-Captain.Ramirez--Lord Galcian's Vice-Captain. Ramirez is a close conspirator with Lord Galcian and carries out many of Lord Galcian's dirty work, he is seems very mysterious and coy, however, looks can be deceiving.ShipsAlbatross--Captain Dyne's ship. It was destroyed by the Valuans when he, his crew, and Fina were captured and taken to the Grand Fortress. He later rebuilt the Albatross II, a ship that looks very similar, to replace it.Little Jack--This is the name of the old ship that Drachma captains. Although the ship is an old fishing ship, do not underestimate it's fighting capabilities as it has been fortified to fight against heavily armed Valuan Battleships.Claudia--A classy ship that Gilder owns. Gilder mainly uses it as a means to escape from Clara, but it is also a ship that can hold its own in an air ship battle.Delphinus--A prototype Valuan battleship owned by Enrique. As the story progresses, Enrique gives the ship to Vyse in order to escape the Valuan Grand Fortress a second time on the condition that Vyse takes Enrique with him to stop Valua's conquest for ruling over everyone.The Valuan Empire Armada--Lord Galcian controls five Captains who make up the Royal Armada and are the last line of defense between Vyse and the Empire. Alfonso, Gregorio, Vigoro, Belleza, and De Loco all have their own unique way of battling Vyse, but it is not enough.Differences from Dreamcast versionWhile the port still features random enemy encounters, which was a main complaint about the original, the chance of such encounters are decreased.Two new side quests have been added; the first involving the collection of "Moon Fish" in order to allow a small girl to open her heart and speak again, receive rare items (including ones unlocked from Pinta's Quest, which utilized the Dreamcast's VMU card) and learn more about the backstory of General Ramirez. The second quest, involves encounters with a Air Pirate hunter named Piastol, who blames Vyse for the death of her father. This side quest also ties in with the "Moon Fish" side quest.Finally, addtional 'discoveries' have been added, a few crew members like Domingo can join up sooner, and new battles with enemies on the new "Wanted List" can be fought.Other Info1 playerMemory Blocks needed: 3</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13053">Final Fantasy VII</game><game id="11252">Suikoden III</game><game id="18991">Suikoden IV</game><game id="19152">Suikoden V</game><game id="12099">Star Ocean: Till the End of Time</game><game id="10129">Grandia II</game><game id="18762">Evolution Worlds</game><game id="23987">Nostalgia</game><game id="3692">Panzer Dragoon Saga</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2141565-box_soal.png</image></root>