<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16223</id><name>Pinball Quest</name><description>GeneralPinball Quest is a pinball/RPG game released in 1990 for the NES by Jaleco. It is probably the only hybrid of pinball and RPG gameplay ever made.GameplayThere are four gameplay options available to you in pinball quest:Pop! Pop! - a pinball table with a 1950's themeViva Golf! - a golf themed pinball tableCircus - a circus theme pinball table.RPG - The meat of the game where you are tasked with saving the pinball kings wife who was kidnapped by orange demons in the opening scene of the game. You move upwards through several "tables" each with its own theme and boss, instead of dying you fall down into the previous table should you "lose" your ball. If this happens on the first table you are asked if you would like to try again.After each level you have the ability to visit the store and buy upgrades, sell items, and also risk stealing.TablesTable 1Table 1 is a cemetary where you will begin your quest, in order to progress you must defeat the 3 skeletons and then the giant skeleton that they form.Table 2Table 2 starts you off with a lot of forward momentum bringing you right to the boss which is a witch, should she hit you with her power sapping spell you will be sent back down into the store below and forced into the field again in order to progress. She can also heal by using her table in the corner, which can be destroyed .Table 3 Table 3 is set in what looks like a mine,  the boss here is protected by several guards that must be defeated before you can attempt to hurt him. Also goblin enemies are found on this table who will throw your ball back to you should they catch you.Table 4Table 4 involves using a roulette wheel to get a boat ride across the river and defeat 3 ghost knights to move on. The ghost knights have the ability to attack your flippers with their swords.Table 5Just when you thought you finally found the princess she will turn into a vampire and attack. After defeating her destroy her fake throne to access the final tableTable 6Finally at the last level defeat the Devil who is holding the princess. He has the ability to freeze your bumpers when the image of his head's eyes glow white.EndingAfter beating the Devil you are treated to a humorous cutscene in which your pinball encounters and defeats the master a giant magnet. Since pinballs are made of metal it makes perfect sense!</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="30">Pinball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20885">Pinball</game><game id="18314">Pin*Bot</game><game id="22540">Powershot Pinball Constructor</game><game id="14881">Balls of Steel</game><game id="18592">Sonic the Hedgehog: Spinball</game><game id="4287">Mario Pinball Land</game><game id="5436">Metroid Prime Pinball</game><game id="6410">Mendel Palace</game><game id="40114">Goindol</game><game id="35666">Wizorb</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2362117-nes_pinballquest.jpg</image></root>