<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16235</id><name>Star Trek: Bridge Commander</name><description>OverviewIn Star Trek: Bridge Commander, players take control a Federation Starship as its newly minted Captain. Bridge Commander is best known for its unusual gameplay systems, most notably the ability to control the ship by giving orders to bridge officers.GameplayBridge Commander gave the player the ability to manually control a starship in 3D space and battle other ships. The player could also view the ship from the perspective of the captain and simply issue orders to officers instead of directly controlling the ship. Bridge Commander gave the player the ability to target subsystems on other enemy ships, giving the player a variety of strategies to use against enemy ships. The game has two main modes, campaign and free play mode. The campaign follows a captain who is awarded command of gradually stronger ships as the story progresses, until finally the player is captain of a Sovereign class ship. The free play mode allowed players to go online and battle other players or battle AI and create custom scenarios involving starbases, starships, asteroids, etc. Federation, Borg, Romulan, Klingon, Kessok, Ferengi, and Cardassian ships appear throughout the game. System RequirementsMinimum SpecificationsRecommended SpecificationsOS: Microsoft Windows 95 OSR2/98/ME/2000/XPOS: Microsoft Windows 95 OSR2/98/ME/2000/XPProcessor: Pentium II 300Mhz processorOS: Pentium II 450Mhz processorGraphics Card: 3D Hardware Accelerator (with 16MB VRAM)Graphics Card: 3D Hardware Accelerator (with 16MB VRAM)RAM: 64MB RAMRAM: 64MB RAMDirectX: DirectX 8.0a or higherDirectX: DirectX 8.0a or higherHard Drive: 175 MB of HDD SpaceHard Drive: 175 MB of HDD Space</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17383">Star Trek: Starfleet Academy</game><game id="38199">Star Command</game><game id="37304">Artemis: Spaceship Bridge Simulator</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2423343-bc_pc.jpg</image></root>