<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16255</id><name>50 Cent: Bulletproof</name><description>From the back of the box:After getting shot nine times and left for dead, 50 climbs from the jaws of death to exact revenge on his enemies. Working with his G-Unit soldiers - Lloyd Banks, Young Buck, and Tony Yayo - 50 takes on the most powerful gangs and crime syndicates in the city, uncovering a criminal conspiracy with international implications. This gritty urban action game, written by Terry Winter, Emmy Award-winning Executive Producer of The Sopranos, also stars Eminem as Detective McVicar and Dr. Dre as street-wise war veteran, Grizz.Take down enemies with over 25 dramatic counter-kill movesClip up with a massive stash of weapons, from heaters to launchersGrab enemies as shields, extract information and steal their valuablesUse strategic tactics, evasive rolls and mobile cover to stay alive while the bullets flyEnemy AI that hunts, covers, flanks, works in teams and strategically navigates the environment4 CDs worth of 50 Cent and G-Unit music including NEW EXCLUSIVE TRACKS AND REMIXES FROM 50Over a dozen 50 Cent and G-Unit music videosCreate custom music playlists, watch music videos, and rock the exclusive soundtrack from Sha Money XLPSP VersionThe PSP version of Bulletproof swaps the third-person shooting of the consoles versions for isometric, corridor crawl-style gameplay.Soundtrack50 Cent - Maybe We Crazy50 Cent - When You Hear That50 Cent - I'm A Rider50 Cent - Simply The Best50 Cent - Pimpin (Part 2)50 Cent - Why They Look Like That50 Cent - Come And Get You50 Cent - I Warned You50 Cent Feat Tony Yayo - I Run NY50 Cent - Grew Up50 Cent - Southside50 Cent Feat Lloyd Banks and Tony Yayo - Hit You Up50 Cent Feat DJ Whoo Kid - G-Unit RadioDifficulty LevelsPlaya (Very Easy)Hustler (Easy)Thug (Normal)Gangsta (Hard)G-Unit Soldier (Very Hard)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3345">True Crime: New York City</game><game id="11153">True Crime: Streets of LA</game><game id="20679">Saints Row 2</game><game id="5618">Saints Row</game><game id="1375">Crime Life: Gang Wars</game><game id="9966">Scarface: The World is Yours</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2285610-box_50cbp.png</image></root>