<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16268</id><name>The Black Cauldron</name><description>The Black Cauldron was a graphical adventure game released in 1986 by Sierra Entertainment for the PC and equivalents (such as the Amiga and the Apple II). The game was designed by Al Lowe, a veteran adventure game designer who was also responsible for the Leisure Suit Larry series, Freddy Pharkas: Frontier Pharmacist, and Torin's Passage.StoryUnlike many other Sierra adventure games of the era, The Black Cauldron was based on a licensed property: a 1985 Disney animated film directed by Ted Berman and Richard Rich. The film itself, and to some degree the game, is based on The Chronicles of Prydain books, written by Lloyd Alexander. The Black Cauldron game's story revolves around pig herder Taran. When Taran's magical pig Hen Wen is kidnapped by the evil Horned King, Taran sets off to win his magic pig back.GameplayThe Black Cauldron is notable for several reasons. First, the game features a dynamic storyline, with branching plots and multiple endings. Second, in order to make the game more accessible and easier to control, the designers eschewed the traditional text parser system in the favour of a function key system which mapped specific actions (Inventory, Look, Use, etc.) to a respective F-Key.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9648">King's Quest</game><game id="20243">Quest for Glory I: So You Want To Be A Hero</game><game id="3019">The Secret of Monkey Island</game><game id="6715">The Dark Crystal</game><game id="14212">Mickey's Space Adventure</game><game id="8806">Gold Rush!</game><game id="1917">Hugo's House of Horrors</game><game id="4990">Leisure Suit Larry 1:  In the Land of the Lounge Lizards</game><game id="295">The Legend of Kyrandia</game><game id="14732">The Legend of Kyrandia: Hand of Fate</game><game id="14164">The Legend of Kyrandia: Malcolm's Revenge</game><game id="14195">King's Quest II: Romancing the Throne</game><game id="1256">King's Quest III: To Heir is Human</game><game id="15565">Armaeth: The Lost Kingdom</game><game id="7947">Lure of the Temptress</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1987/629342-black_cauldron__the___front.jpg</image></root>