<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16275</id><name>Extreme Paintbrawl</name><description>Overview Extreme Paintbrawl is a first-person shooter based on the sport of      paintball. It was developed by     Creative Carnage and released by    HeadGames Publishing in its line of video games under the Extreme name. The developer was given only two weeks to work on the game using the   Build engine, resulting in slapdash presentation and artificial intelligence. The game received poor reviews and is considered one of the worst first-person shooters of all time.  The interface used for the game ran on Windows 95 and higher, yet the game itself ran on DOS. This causes compatibility issues on later versions of Windows.  Gameplay Extreme Paintbrawl features five different arenas (ranging from the desert to outer space) that can only be played in one mode: 8-on-8  Capture the Flag. The player wins the game if he eliminates all the enemy A.I. or touches the enemy flag. If the player is "tagged", he immediately controls an ally A.I. and continues the game. If all eight of the player's team is eliminated, the player loses the game. The player can switch between different A.I. manually at any time. (To access different weapons and gear)  Because Creative Carnage did not have time to implement actual A.I., the bots included in the game were very poor. You could not issue orders to ally bots, who often get stuck behind obstacles. Depending on the difficulty of the enemy team, they can sometimes act like aimbots, shooting the player from across the map with deadly range and accuracy.   The Windows interface features everything needed to set up a single-player campaign. Players can create/load campaigns, which consisted of a pre-determined "tournament" against pre-determined teams. The interface also includes a "shop" where players must buy new guns, ammo, and CO2 canisters with money won by previous battles. You can also swap A.I. players for new players with different stats, though its effect is minimal due to the incomplete A.I. coding.  Multiplayer through online or LAN were also available, though limited to standard deathmatch.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="3">Sports</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2828">Extreme Paintbrawl 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1378127-pbrawl_box.png</image></root>