<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16305</id><name>Dragon Warrior</name><description>OverviewDragon Warrior (known as Dragon Quest in Japan) is a turn-based RPG, designed by Yuji Horii, developed by Chunsoft, and published by Enix. It was first released in 1986 for the Famicom, then ported to the MSX and PC-98 the same year, and has since gone on to appear on a variety of other platforms. It was later released in the United States in August 1989 for the NES. The game was the first to combine turn-based combat, random encounters and dynamic character leveling. Groundbreaking for its time, the game established the conventions that define traditional Japanese Role-Playing Games which are still in use today.In 1992 it was re-released along with Dragon Warrior II as Dragon Warrior I  II for the SNES and later released in 2000 on Game Boy Color.StoryIn old times, Erdrick fought demons with a mystical Ball of Light. In recent times, the Dragonlord has hidden the mystical Ball of Light, kidnapped the Princess Gwaelin, destroyed the town of Hawkness, and taken over the city of Alefgard. The Dragon Warrior hero has two distinct quests for him: first he must rescue Princess Gwaelin and then he must track down the legendary weapon and armor to defeat the DragonlordGameplayA monster initiates combat in the overworldDragon Warrior uses a menu oriented turn-based combat system. It inquires for your commands and verbosely displays the result of every action taken by both the protagonist and the monster being fought in a combat log on the lower half of the screen. After each battle experience points and gold are earned, and when the protagonist achieves a certain number of experience points he will level up, and gain stats such as additional HP (Hit Points) and useful magic skills like HEAL. Only a single monster can be fought at a time, and monsters appear at random outside of towns.There are three different types of areas. Towns where you can talk with towns folk, search for hidden items, and buy and sell weapons, armor, and items. The overworld, which is basically a map of the world that can be traveled that's populated with random monstrous encounters of all kinds, from slimes to golden golems. Lastly, dungeons populate the world, and require torches or magic spells to see through the darkness, and much like the overworld they are populated with monsters, except far more dangerous ones and great rewards are hidden in them.LocalizationDragon Warrior is known as Dragon Quest in Japan. Occasionally shortened to Dorakue much like Pocket Monsters is shortened to Pokemon. Akira Toriyama of Dragon Ball fame drew the original box and cartridge artwork for Dragon Quest, but the artwork for Dragon Warrior was replaced with something meant to appeal more to a North American audience. The graphics for the North American release' maps and characters were enhanced, adding multi-direction facing for characters. Dialog was also changed to reflect an olde English style, and many locations renamed to moreso fit Arthurian legend.Nintendo Power PromotionIn 1989-1990, Nintendo Power offer a free copy of Dragon Warrior to new magazine subscribers. This was done as a means to boost magazine sales and interest in the game.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8403">Final Fantasy</game><game id="7400">Phantasy Star</game><game id="7447">Blue Dragon</game><game id="4638">Knights of Legend</game><game id="1624">Destiny of an Emperor</game><game id="5551">Ultima</game><game id="15861">Pokémon Crystal</game><game id="3966">Pokémon Red/Blue</game><game id="2363">Hydlide</game><game id="6336">Final Fantasy VI</game><game id="23409">Gamera: The Guardian of the Universe</game><game id="2094">Final Fantasy II</game><game id="3755">Persona 2: Innocent Sin</game><game id="267">Golden Sun</game><game id="640">Emerald Dragon</game><game id="23450">Tengai Makyou: Ziria</game><game id="31023">Breath of Death VII</game><game id="33862">War of the Dead</game><game id="37095">SD Gundam Gaiden: Knight Gundam Monogatari</game><game id="1973">Heracles no Eikou: Toujin Makyou Den</game><game id="39590">Zoids: Chuuou Tairiku no Tatakai</game><game id="39606">Kalin no Tsurugi</game><game id="39610">Indora no Hikari</game><game id="39616">Minelvaton Saga</game><game id="14543">Momotarou Densetsu</game><game id="13383">Artelius</game><game id="39779">Outlanders</game><game id="39833">GeGeGe no Kitarou 2: Youkai Gundan no Chousen</game><game id="40027">Elysion</game><game id="40055">Sanada Juu Yuushi</game><game id="40367">Genpei Touma Den: Computer Boardgame</game><game id="40383">Kaijuu Monogatari</game><game id="40561">Satomi Hakkenden</game><game id="40637">Jajamaru Ninpou Chou</game><game id="37131">La Salle Ishii no Childs Quest</game><game id="1754">Faria: A World of Mystery and Danger!</game><game id="20174">Valkyrie no Bouken: Toki no Kagi Densetsu</game><game id="37992">Dragon Fantasy</game><game id="19597">Dragon Slayer: The Legend of Heroes</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2361686-nes_dragonwarriror.jpg</image></root>