<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16367</id><name>Armored Core: Master of Arena</name><description>BackgroundPROGTECHA research company rising in power and influence, they are responsible for breakthroughs in AC development, and also serve as sponsors for the Ravens' Nest Arena. The company eventually becomes the player's sponsor in the Arena. Within PROGTECH is the head of RD, Elan Cubis, a brilliant scientist, and contacts the player via mail in later portions of the game.StoryThe main character is a Raven seeking revenge against the number one ranked Raven Hustler One and his AC Nine-Ball. Prior to the game, the Raven's family along with many other civilians were killed in a violent skirmish between Chrome and Murakumo Millenium in Isaac City, with Nine-Ball at the center of the conflict. After encountering Nine-Ball again during the Raven's first mission, his contact Lana Nielsen tells him about the Arena, and that if he wants to defeat Nine-Ball, he must climb to the top of the Arena, but challenging him may result in death.After completing more missions, the Raven is contacted by PROGTECH offering to be his sponsor in the sub arena, and eventually the main Arena. During points in the story, the Raven's Arena licensed is revoked temporarily in order to aid PROGTECH in a critical mission. However, these are mission requests being sent directly to the Raven, rather than through the Nest's channels to the Raven's operator. The Raven receives his first warning from Lana after completing one of these direct mission requests, and after doing it a second time, Lana Nielsen ceases to be his operator, leaving him in the dark without new contracts to accept. The Raven has no choice but to continue fighting in the Arena until he can face Hustler One.PROGTECH continues to face attacks from unknown forces, this time at their head of RD Elan Cubis. The Raven comes to his aid, and Elan agrees to assist the Raven in anyway he can for information regarding Hustler One and Nine-Ball. Cubis discovers that all important files pertaining to Hustler One and Nine-Ball have been deleted, and sources claim that no one has ever seen Hustler One in person. After reaching 2nd place in the main arena, Elan Cubis goes into hiding for fear of Nine-Ball coming to assassinate him, and Lana Nielsen returns to give one final mission to the Raven. In an abandoned factory in Isaac City, the Raven faces against Nine-Ball, and then two more Nine-Balls at once, all with Lana Nielsen's voice, albeit distorted. Lana Nielsen is revealed to be Hustler One, and that Nine-Ball is controlled by an AI, similar to the first Nine-Ball and "R" from the original Armored Core. After destroying the three copies, the Raven descends further into the complex and discovers the ultimate form of Nine-Ball. Nine-Ball Seraph, a more powerful and deadlier version of the red and black AC. The Raven defeats Nine-Ball Seraph, and with the destruction of Hustler-One, the Ravens' Nest functions ceased to operate.GameplayGameplay is identical to Armored Core and Armored Core Project Phantasma. With new parts introduced, previous parts were adjusted to better balance the game. Like in Project Phantasma, the player can transfer data from either the original Armored Core or Project Phantasma. Secret parts in the original Armored Core could not be obtained in Project Phantasma, but in Master of Arena, they are available in the shop from the beginning.The Arena concept from Project Phantasma has been expanded, and is now integral to progressing through the main game. The player cannot enter the Arena proper until the player's AC is backed by a sponsor. At points in the game to progress the story, the ability to compete in the Arena will be revoked in order to focus on critical missions for the Raven.Armored Core Master of Arena came with two discs. The first disc contains the mission mode, sub arena, and main arena. On disc 2 was the Ex Arena and Ranker Mk. Ex Arena provided 8 additional Arenas for the players to compete in, and Ranker Mk could let the player create their own custom Arena mode, including AI for the ACs.PartsIn Armored Core Master of Arena, 27 new parts are introduced, bringing the final total of the PS1 Armored Core parts to 187. All previous parts in the series can be accessed in the shop, and some items have had stat changes along with the new parts in order to keep the game balanced.HD-12-RADARPart Type: HeadPrice: 72600Weight: 180Energy Drain: 511Armor Points: 831Def Shell: 104Def Energy: 159A specialized unit equipped with a wide variety of radar functionsComputer Type: StandardMap Type: Area  Place NameNoise Canceler: ProvidedBio Sensor: ProvidedRadar Functions: ProvidedRadar Range: 8720Radar Type: StandardHD-HELMPart Type: HeadPrice: 63200Weight: 134Energy Drain: 793Armor Points: 850Def Shell: 172Def Energy: 185Well-balanced unit with improvements made to all existing functionsComputer Type: DetailedMap Type: Area  Place NameNoise Canceler: NoneBio Sensor: NoneRadar Function: ProvidedRadar Range: 7300Radar Type: StandardHD-H10Part Type: HeadPrice: 81000Weight: 261Energy Drain: 332Armor Points: 956Def Shell: 204Heavily armored unit designed with defensive strength in mindDef Energy: 210Computer Type: RoughMap Type: Area MemoryNoise Canceler: NoneBio Sensor: NoneRadar Function: NoneHD-4004Part Type: HeadPrice: 44100Weight: 139Energy Drain: 628Armor Point: 820Def Shell: 146Def Energy: 138A design-oriented model with low basic functionalityComputer Type: DetailedMap Type: Area MemoryNoise Canceler: ProvidedBio Sensor: NoneRadar Function: ProvidedRadar Range: 6200Radar Type: StandardXXL-D0Part Type: CorePrice: 115000Weight: 910Energy Drain: 1120Armor Points: 2960Def Shell: 608Test model that represents the next generation standardDef Energy: 610Maximum Weight: 3320Anti-Missile-Response: 32Anti-Missile-Angle: 20Extension Slots: 5AN-891-SPart Type: ArmsPrice: 54200Weight: 1790Energy Drain: 1290High defense model equipped with armor shieldingArmor Points: 1920Def Shell: 480Def Energy: 509AW-R/4Part Type: ArmsType: CannonPrice: 126300Weight: 1650Energy Drain: 187Armor Points: 1600Def Shell: 0Def Energy: 0Multi-cannon firing capabilityWeapon Lock: StandardAttack Power: 1024Number of Ammo: 180Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 150Range: 8000Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 15LN-S3Part Type: LegsType: Humanoid LegsPrice: 75000Weight: 2300Energy Drain: 2050Armor Points: 3426Lightweight model, but without sacrificing defense or load capacityDef Shell: 752Def Energy: 680Maximum Weight: 5630Speed: 106Stability: 1480Jump Function: ProvidedLB-H230Part Type: LegsType: Reverse JointPrice: 56000Weight: 2593Energy Drain: 1848Armor Points: 3880New reverse joint model featuring enhanced load capacityDef Shell: 695Def Energy: 430Maximum Weight: 5124Speed: 275Stability: 2954Jump Function: ProvidedLF-TR-0Part Type: LegsType: Four Legs TypePrice: 92000Weight: 2593Energy Drain: 3358Armor Points: 2546Enhanced speed while retaining defensive propertiesDef Shell: 589Def Energy: 669Maximum Weight: 4360Speed: 504Stability: 542Jump Function: ProvidedLC-HTP-H5Part Type: LegsType: CaterpillarPrice: 64000Weight: 3056Energy Drain: 3140Armor Points: 3884Enhanced hover tank with increased speed and maneuverabilityDef Shell: 687Def Energy: 645Maximum Weight: 5630Speed: 284Stability: 731Jump Function: NoneP/CVPart Type: FCSPrice: 96000Weight: 24Wide area model well suited for close to mid range encountersEnergy Drain: 55Maximum Lock: 1Lock Type: StandardB-PT000Part Type: BoostersPrice: 62500Weight: 301Power on demand. For rapid approaches and retreatsEnergy Drain: 52Boost Power: 23400Charge Drain: 7450WM-MVG812Type: Small MissilePrice: 54000Weight: 1016Energy Drain: 300Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: StandardAttack Power: 830A heat-seeking missile that tracks its targetNumber of Ammo: 40Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 300Range: 10000Maximum Lock: 4Reload Time: 30WM-X15-EXType: Plasma DispenserPrice: 86000Weight: 580Energy Drain: 330Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: NoneAttack Power: 1560Plasma mortarNumber of Ammo: 60Ammo Type: EnergyAmmo Price: 0Range: 0Maximum Lock: 0Reload Time: 15WR-RS7Type: Special RocketPrice: 176000Weight: 759Energy Drain: 31Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: NoneAttack Power: 200Launches special rockets that disable their target's functionsNumber of Ammo: 12Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 2046Range: 15500Maximum Lock: 0Reload Time: 40WRR-10Type: Mine DispenserPrice: 143000Weight: 351Energy Drain: 24Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: NoneAttack Power: 2240Floating proximity mineNumber of Ammo: 100Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 436Range: 0Maximum Lock: 0Reload Time: 8WX-ED2Type: Plasma CannonPrice: 74000Weight: 1350Energy Drain: 750Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: StandardAttack Power: 572Simultaneously fires two plasma burstsNumber of Ammo: 160Ammo Type: EnergyAmmo Price: 0Range: 12000Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 6WX-C/4Type: Laser CannonPrice: 138000Weight: 1670Energy Drain: 905Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: StandardAttack Power: 1259Laser cannon that can simultaneously fire four linked laser cannonsNumber of Ammo: 60Ammo Type: EnergyAmmo Price: 0Range: 7600Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 32P77-STType: StealthPrice: 230000Special equipment that gives the AC stealth capabilityWeight: 1780Energy Drain: 998WG-HG770Type: Hand GunPrice: 59000Weight: 210Energy Drain: 64Weapon Lock: Wide  ShallowAttack Power: 540A scattershot handgun with improved target accuracyNumber of Ammo: 100Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 147Range: 7300Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 7WG-XW11Type: Laser RiflePrice: 61000Weight: 547Energy Drain: 451Weapon Lock: SpecialAttack Power: 549Laser rifle that is capable of firing two simultaneous shotsNumber of Ammo: 70Ammo Type: EnergyAmmo Price: 0Range: 10500Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 6WG-FGI-00Type: Flame ShellPrice: 62300Weight: 815Energy Drain: 18Weapon Lock: Wide  ShallowAttack Power: 200Napalm. Burns the area surrounding the point of detonationNumber of Ammo: 60Ammo type: SolidAmmo Price: 104Range: 8600Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 15WG-RF/EType: Sniper RiflePrice: 71000Weight: 412Energy Drain: 156Weapon Lock: SpecialAttack Power: 3800Sniper rifle with significantly increased bullet velocityNumber of Ammo: 10Ammo Type: EnergyAmmo Price: 0Range: 22000Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 48WG-MG500/EType: Machine GunPrice: 56100Weight: 415Energy Drain: 10Weapon Lock: SpecialAttack Power: 185A new machine gun that fires energy roundsNumber of Ammo: 500Ammo Type: EnergyAmmo Price: 0Range: 6800Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 2LS-1000WPart Type: Laser BladePrice: 67500Weight: 212An irregular blade that emits an energy waveEnergy Drain: 71Charge Drain: 2430Attack Power: 1849SP-ABS/RePart Type: Optional PartType: Balancer OptionPrice: 68000Enhanced SP-ABS modelSlot Spend: 2Function: New SP-ABS</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22675">Mobile Suit Gundam: Journey to Jaburo</game><game id="15264">Krazy Ivan</game><game id="15641">Tex Atomic's Big Bot Battles</game><game id="25684">Murakumo: Renegade Mech Pursuit</game><game id="29057">Frame Gride</game><game id="22133">Armored Core: for Answer</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1810139-box_acmoa.png</image></root>