<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1638</id><name>Mega Man X6</name><description>OverviewMega Man X6 was the sixth main entry in the Mega Man X series. X6 is a direct sequel to X5, the story kicks off three weeks after the ending of that game. The gameplay and graphics are almost entirely the same as in X5. X6 did featured voice acting, something omitted from X5, but it was only in Japanese. X6 was also well known as being one of the most challenging X series games. It is also known for it's spotty English translation.GameplayThe game starts off with X, but you later get to play as Zero, after you unlock him. The game features a "Nightmare" system, which makes it so that when you defeat a Maverick, their icon on the level select screen will become red, which means that certain environmental hazards will be added to the level to increase difficulty. This is important because this game has many more hidden secrets to find than the other games in the X series.Ranking SystemMega Man X6 offers a leveling system, and the way a character can level up is by obtaining souls from certain Mavericks. Once the player collects enough, the character's ranking will go up, which allows the characters to have access others special parts that are obtained from missing Reploids, found in various locations throughout the game's eight Maverick stages.Reploids/PartsThe game has over a hundreds missing reploids in the game's levels - some of the Reploids offer specials parts that X or Zero can use. The special parts can help X  Zero in certain ways. For example, one of the parts can allow X or Zero jump higher, or some can increase the power of the X-Buster or the Z Saber.ArmorsX has a total of four armors in the game, and each armor has certain abilities.The Falcon Armor.Falcon Armor: Available from the start of game, the Falcon Armor gives X the ability to perform a dash in mid-air that will also damage enemies, perform the Giga Attack that damages all enemies on screen, and use special charged versions of the weapons obtained by the Maverick bosses.The Shadow Armor.Shadow Armor: The Shadow Armor has the ability to touch spiked areas with no consequence, take less damage, dash vertically by pressing up and jump, shoot Shurikens that shoot in random directions, and perform a special charged slash with the Z Saber. The one downside to this armor is that you can not air dash and you can not use weapons obtained from defeated Mavericks.The Blade Armor.Blade Armor: The Blade Armor has the ability to perform a powerful slash attack by pressing up and the attack button with a full weapon charge, and the ability to dash in any direction and stop in mid-air before you do so. While dashing, X will be invincible to all attacks.Ultimate Armor.Ultimate Armor: Only accessible via a cheat code entered at the title screen, this incredibly powerful armor has the ability to use a special move called Nova Strike at any time, which rockets X forward and does a great deal to normal enemies and bosses. It also has a conventional air dash and the same charged shot that you get with the Ultimate Armor in X4 and X5.BossesName: Blizzard WolfangLevel: NorthPole AreaWeapon: Ice Burst (X) Hydroga (Zero)Weakness: Magma Blade (X) Shoenzan (Zero)Name: Commander YammackLevel: Amazon AreaWeapon: Yammar OptionWeakness: Ray ArrowName: Infinity MijinionLevel: Weapon CenterWeapon: Ray ArrowWeakness: Guard ShellName: Ground ScaravichLevel: Central MuseumWeapon: Ground Dash (X) Sentsuizan (Zero)Weakness: Yammar OptionName: Rainy TurtloidLevel: Inami TempleWeapon: Meteor Rain (X) Ensuizan (Zero)Weakness: Ice Burst (X) Hydroga (Zero)Name: Metal Shark PlayerLevel: Recycle LabWeapon: Metal Anchor (X) Rakukojini (Zero)Weakness: Meteor Rain (X) Ensuizan (Zero)Name: Blaze HeatnixLevel: Magma AreaWeapon: Magma Blade (X) Shoenzan (Zero)Weakness: Ground Dash (X) Sentsuizan (Zero)Name: Shield SheldonLevel: Laser InstituteWeapon: Guard ShellWeakness: Metal Anchor (X) Rakukojini (Zero)ControversyMega Man X5 was intended to be the last game in the X series by creator Keiji Inafune. Capcom quickly developed X6 without his consent. Many fans consider this to be the root of this game's many problems. The most commonly named issues for the game were: poorly translated script, lack of localized voice acting, poor story and unfairly difficult level design. Because of these issues, many fans consider this to be one of their least favorite X games, along with Mega Man X7.SoundtrackCover ArtIn 2005 Capcom released a 5-disc box set called Capcom Music Generation Rockman X1~6. It contains the original music of Mega Man X through Mega Man X6 as well as some unused tracks. Mega Man X6 tracks span most of the fifth disc with the last few tracks on the disc being opening and ending themes from X3 through X5. The track listing is as follows:Track #Song TitleLength1.OPENING STAGE2:462.D-10001:083.STAGE SELECT1:414.STAGE START0:115.COMMANDER YAMMARK STAGE2:476.RAINY TURTLOID STAGE2:367.SHIELDNER SHELDON STAGE2:368.BLIZZARD WOLFANG STAGE2:259.BLAZE HEATNIX STAGE2:1210.INFINITY MIJINION STAGE2:2311.METAL SHARK PLAYER STAGE2:2012.GROUND SCARAVICH STAGE1:5913.BOSS1:4014.STAGE CLEAR X0:0815.MISSION REPORT0:4716.GATE'S LABORATORY STAGE2:0517.Hi-MAX1:1518.GATE1:3519.STAGE CLEAR ZERO0:0820.SIGMA 1st2:2221.SIGMA 2nd1:4822.Dr.RIGHT0:5123.ALIA GATE1:3924.ZERO1:3425.ENDING THEME2:32</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1257">Blaster Master</game><game id="20627">Castlevania: Order of Ecclesia</game><game id="20975">Mega Man 9</game><game id="20256">Mega Man X4</game><game id="14357">Castlevania: Portrait of Ruin</game><game id="6673">Castlevania</game><game id="11321">Castlevania: Dawn of Sorrow</game><game id="4350">Contra</game><game id="4237">Contra 4</game><game id="3016">Contra III: The Alien Wars</game><game id="11684">Contra: Shattered Soldier</game><game id="10374">Blaster Master: Enemy Below</game><game id="16758">Blaster Master: Blasting Again</game><game id="1018">Blaster Master Boy</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1806102-box_mmx6.png</image></root>