<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16437</id><name>BloodRayne</name><description>StorylineIn this grisly game, you star as the sexy, vivacious, deadly character,  Agent  BloodRayne. Rayne is a half-human/half-vampire hybrid known as a dhampir. The story  takes place throughout the time period in and around World War II. Rayne is recruited by the Brimstone Society to help eradicate all vampires in the world. An additional plot point sees Rayne and the Brimstone Society hunting for information regarding the whereabouts of Rayne's father, Kagan, a powerful vampire lord. The game opens with the player controlling Rayne during her first mission with the Brimstone Society, in Morton, Louisiana. Following this mission, the story jumps ahead several years to a Nazi base in Argentina. The remainder of the game sees Rayne hunting down Nazi soldiers, officers, and powerful supernatural beings.Combat WeaponsRayne possesses multiple weapons for use in dispatching her enemies. Her blades, harpoon, and weapons her victims drop. The most commonly associated weapon with Rayne are the two forearm mounted blades that she uses to slice and dice enemies into gooey, messy pieces. Being blades, they are always available for use and do not run out of ammo.Another neat weapon at Rayne's disposal is the wrist mounted harpoon.  The weapon flies out in a given direction and will impale enemies in its way. Rayne then uses her vampiric strength to haul the unfortunate victim into melee combat range. The harpoon is also useful for getting enemies into range so that Rayne may jump onto them to feed. Feeding is a necessary game mechanic as it replenishes Rayne's health supply. In addition, the way in which Rayne mounts enemies that she is a feeding upon allows her to use them as shields to incoming fire.Rayne's final weapon is that she can pick up weapons that enemies drop such as pistols, shotguns, machine guns, and rocket launchers.Vampiric PowersAura VisionSimilar to heat sensing, IR vision, this view mode allows Rayne to see enemies behind walls and other forms of cover. It can also help Rayne navigate an area.Blood RageRayne temporarily moves faster, hits for more damage and increased gratuitous dismemberment, and performs different, more violent attacks.Dilated PerceptionRayne has the ability to slow down time. This allows her to have better control for hitting targets, evading attacks and dodging bullets</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10037">Bullet Witch</game><game id="17504">Nocturne</game><game id="19261">Drake of the 99 Dragons</game><game id="21984">WET</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2116204-box_brayne.png</image></root>