<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16475</id><name>Mega Man 6</name><description>OverviewMega Man 6 was released on the Nintendo Entertainment System in October of 1993, very late into the console's life. It is the sixth and final Mega Man game released for the NES, though not the last one to sport 8-bit graphics and music, as Mega Man 9 returned to the NES style game in late 2008. Mega Man 6 is the only Mega Man game published by Nintendo rather than Capcom (at least in the U.S), as Capcom opted out of publishing in America the game due to the popularity of the Super Nintendo at the time. The game was never released in Europe.Mega Man 6 was ported to the Playstation 2, Xbox, and Gamecube in 2004 in the Mega Man Anniversary Collection.StoryDr. Wily Be Riine Un!!Mega Man 6 begins differently than other Mega Man games. Once again taking place in 20XX, Mega Man 6 enters players into the first ever Robot Masters Tournament, a contest to test the abilities of the most high tech robots in the entire world, built by the greatest engineers mankind has ever known. People from all over the world have gathered to spectate this monumental event, being hosted by the mysterious Mr.X, a man whom is only to be very rich, and very intelligent.Though Dr. Light, a pacifist, does not enter Mega Man, he sends his greatest creation to make sure nothing goes wrong at the tournament. Dr. Light knows all too well that Robot Masters tend to cause mayhem when gathered in groups of eight, the number of champions in the tournament.Once the eight are victorious, Mr. X appears, revealing that he reprogrammed the champions to do his bidding, and that everyone in the audience fell for his trap. He will use the eight robot masters to command his robot army, and take over the world. Luckily, Mega Man is around, and Dr. Light orders him to stop this villainy once and for all.Mega Man gets down to business, murdering each of the eight robot masters. He then searches for and defeats the mysterious Mr. X, revealing that his true identity is none other than the maniacal Dr. Wily (who saw that coming?). Wily flees to his new, more high tech, anatomy inspired castle, and Mega Man makes pursuit. After an intense battle, Wily is finally placed into prison, where he belongs.GameplayBlizzard ManMega Man 6 carries over much of what has made the series special, great action and platforming, with a few new elements. Mega Man has a few new forms, such as Jet Mega Man, which allows him to hover, although he cannot use charge shots in this form. Another is Power Mega Man, who can punch through massive blocks to demolish them with very limited attack range. Neither adapter allows him to use the slide move.As is the series norm, Mega Man will travel through 8 stages freely, collecting the special weapons of each robot master, discovering their weakness, and punishing them.BossesBlizzard ManBlizzard ManWeapon: Blizzard AttackWeakness: Flame BlastCentaur ManCentaur ManWeapon: Centaur FlashWeakness: Knight CrushFlame ManFlame ManWeapon: Flame BlastWeakness: Wind StormKnight ManKnight ManWeapon: Knight CrushWeakness: Yamato SpearPlant ManPlant ManWeapon: Plant BarrierWeakness: Blizzard AttackTomahawk ManTomahawk ManWeapon: Silver TomahawkWeakness: Plant BarrierWind ManWind ManWeapon: Wind StormWeakness: Centaur FlashYamato ManYamato ManWeapon: Yamato SpearWeakness: Silver Tomahawk</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10152">Bucky O'Hare</game><game id="16783">The Krion Conquest</game><game id="16188">Clash at Demonhead</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2269415-box_mm6.png</image></root>