<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16507</id><name>Lands of Lore: The Throne of Chaos</name><description>PlotScotiaEvil sorceress Scotia and her dark army are on the move again, and their goal is to destroy Gladstone Keep and its King Richard. King Richard LeGrey (voiced by Patrick Stewart on the CD version) is the 40th heir to the throne of Gladstone Keep and to the White Army. The White Army has for generations been defending Gladstone Keep which is the base of operations for all of the civilized areas.However the tide is turning, Scotia has recently gotten a hold of “The Mask” and her powers have grown stronger giving her the ability to take any shape that she wishes. With this new-found power, she infiltrates Gladstone Keep and poisons the King. It is up a band of heroes to find a cure before it is too late, and get rid of Scotia once and for all.GameplayLands of Lore: The Throne of Chaos is a Real-Time 1st Person Perspective, Dungeon Crawler Role Playing Game. At the start of the game the players have the option to choose between four selectable hero classes: Warrior, Rogue, Mage and a “Little bit of everything” hero. Each of these heroes have strength and weaknesses, but their abilities can be upgraded in the game.The game has an automatic stats distributions system. This means that if the player chooses to fight one hero with only melee skills, then this hero’s melee skill will increase and the rest of the stats will not. Throughout the game, players will also have the opportunity to outfit their heroes (up to three heroes in a party) with new weapons and armor.AvailabilityThis game is available for download at gog.com, which made it playable on modern windows versions.PC System RequirementsMinimum system requirements:Windows XP or Windows Vista (Windows7 - GOG version)1.8 GHz Processor512MB RAM (1 GB recommended)3D graphics card compatible with DirectX 7 (compatible with DirectX 9 recommended)2GB HDDMouseKeyboard</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3239">Might and Magic VIII: Day of the Destroyer</game><game id="8121">The Elder Scrolls III: Bloodmoon</game><game id="14535">Might and Magic: Book I</game><game id="4398">Might and Magic VII: For Blood and Honor</game><game id="12559">Might and Magic III: Isles of Terra</game><game id="17886">Might and Magic VI: The Mandate of Heaven</game><game id="20238">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion</game><game id="17367">The Elder Scrolls III: Morrowind</game><game id="1129">The Elder Scrolls II: Daggerfall</game><game id="17949">The Elder Scrolls III: Tribunal</game><game id="10740">The Elder Scrolls IV: Shivering Isles</game><game id="7513">The Elder Scrolls: Arena</game><game id="17285">Anvil of Dawn</game><game id="12917">Dragon Lore: The Legend Begins</game><game id="21505">Project Offset</game><game id="1295">Wizardry: Llylgamyn Saga</game><game id="11906">Wizardry 8</game><game id="12013">Wizardry: Crusaders of the Dark Savant</game><game id="6633">Wizards &amp; Warriors</game><game id="11234">Eye of the Beholder</game><game id="1500">Eye of the Beholder II: The Legend of Darkmoon</game><game id="14326">Eye of the Beholder III: Assault on Myth Drannor</game><game id="26463">Mines of Titan</game><game id="36425">Frayed Knights: The Skull of S'makh-Daon</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9408/738474-6943_boxshot_lands_of_lore.jpg</image></root>