<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16561</id><name>A Bug's Life</name><description>OverviewA Bug's Life is a video game adaptation of the hit Pixar movie by the same name. It tries to appeal to a very young audience with its extremely simplistic gameplay and bright, colorful graphics. It was released on the PlayStation, Nintendo 64, PC, and Game Boy Color.Gameplay (PSX, N64, PC)The ever-unlucky ant Flik is the main playable character in the gameEach game level begins with either a still or clip from the movie depending on what version of the game you were playing and then the player was given control over the main character ' Flik' and began the level, the general purpose of which was to collect items, avoid or fight enemies, and use the seeds and plants around you to navigate your way to the end. The game featured a unique seed mechanic where players were able to move around seeds and change their color, effectively influencing what grows from the seed, allowing access to hidden items and previously unreachable areas. The items collected were not needed for the player to continue to the next level, however they usually granted the player benefits such as extra lives if the player found all four of the letters that make up Flik's name. Flik has two main attacks in the game. While jumping in the air, he could stomp the ground similar to the attack in Mario 64. As well as that, he had a limitless supply of berries that could be upgraded and changed throughout the level. Some enemies, however, could simply not be harmed and had to be avoided, an example would be the bird which, in one level, as in the movie, chases Flik through a labyrinthine series of cracks in the dirt.Differences in VersionsA memorable sequence in the game featured Flik using dandelions to glide across a levelAll versions of the game except for the Game Boy Color version were the same game apart from some cosmetic differences. No version featured in game cut scenes instead using clips from the movie to set up the premise for each level. The Nintendo 64 version did not feature these however due to its cartridge based format. Instead they relied on a still from the movie before each level with a short sentence describing what was happening. The Game Boy Color version was a simple 2D platform game that offered a little more challenge to the older audience than its 3D counterparts did.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2284662-box_abl.png</image></root>