<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>166</id><name>Command &amp; Conquer: Red Alert - Retaliation</name><description>Command  Conquer: Red Alert – October 1996  Hell March.Main Article:            Command  Conquer: Red AlertSomeone helps                  Albert Einstein alter history by killing                 Adolf Hitler, and someone plants the idea to invade                Europe into Joseph Stalin's head. Instead of preventing               World War II they simply change it as              Russia invades Europe. Spies lurk, land mines wait, and strange new technologies aid both sides in their struggle for ultimate control.   Many new technologies are used by Russia and the Allies including Tesla, the Chronosphere's             teleport, Iron Curtain's invulnerability and the Gap Generator's satellite surveillance blocking system. Ore, the most abundant and valuable resource on the planet, is the primary resource that funds the military might of the Soviets  Allies.  The War over land and the resources it brings has gotten deadly in this alternate universe as the Soviet Union deploys Mammoth Tanks  Tesla Coils to crush the allies. Not only does the war rage on land, but also in the air and on the oceans. The allies deploy devastating Destroyers  Cruisers while the soviets deploy Submarines to counter the allies' massive navy. In the air the Allies deploy deadly Apache Helicopters while the Soviets deploy Yak  MiG aircraft and helicopters of their own. It's up to the player to decide who will win Soviet Union or the Allied Forces. Command  Conquer Red Alert gives you the opportunity to be more devious, cunning and ruthless than ever before. Easy to play and highly addictive, Command  Conquer Red Alert puts the fate of the world in your hands  .  Command  Conquer: Red Alert – Counterstrike – March 1997 Just add fire.Main Article:  Command  Conquer: Red Alert - Counterstrike  The expansion to CC Red Alert is full of clandestine activity, new experimental technologies and disavowed tactics. Includes 16 extremely hard single player missions and many new multiplayer maps from the original designersof CC: Red Alert.  World War 2 really heats up as both sides deploy their strongest weapons against each other in this expansion to Red Alert. Many new units await those who play this expansion including, Tesla Tanks, super soldiers  dangerous new nuclear technologies.  Do you have what it takes to beat these missions which are all harder then the last mission in the Red Alert? Last but not least, experience the hidden Giant Ant missions included in this expansion. Command  Conquer: Red Alert – The Aftermath – Sept 1997Nuclear Winter.Main Article:  Command  Conquer: Red Alert - The Aftermath This expansion to CC Red Alert will test your mettle. Prepare for guerrilla tactics, insidious strategies and forbidden weapons.   Includes 18 extremely hard single player missions and many new multiplayer maps from the original designers of CC: Red Alert. Red Alert's  World War 2 climaxes as both sides deploy their new strong weapons against each other in this expansion to Red Alert. Seven new units await those who play this expansion including, Chrono Tanks, Sea-to-land Submarines, Shock Troopers,  M.A.D. Tank.  Do you have what it takes to beat these missions which are all harder then the last mission in the Red Alert? Last but not least, experience 8 new songs from Frank Klepacki while you dominate the world.</description><genres /><similar_games><game id="33907">APOX</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/13692/1353904-command___conquer___red_alert_retaliation__soviets_disc___u___slus_00667__front.jpg</image></root>