<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16647</id><name>Amped 3</name><description>OverviewBig AirAmped 3 is a snowboarding game, developed by Indie Built and published by 2K Sports. It has improved from previous games through larger levels, customizable terrain, a hefty 300 song soundtrack, and the introduction of snowmobiles and sleds, along with new Xbox Live features. The simple controls are easy to pick up and anyone can pull off huge tricks on their first play.There are now seven real resorts which are three times larger than previous games allowing for greater exploration and a wide variety of ramps and rails. The introduction of snowmobiles also allow players to travel uphill or downhill allowing you to do that combo run again and again. In addition to this, there is a hill-editor mode that allows the player to place objects on the hill to tailor the experience more to his or her preference. There are unlockable parts that are earned by simply playing the game.The game also features more online features than ever before such as online leaderboards allowing the player to compare their best scores against their friends or the rest of the world.Story ModeGrindingAmped 3 was the first game in the Amped franchise to feature a story-driven experience. The player creates a character, and is thrust into the game. A quick, and strange cutscene plays involving a mysterious character watching over you and your friends, and another female character that seems to be narrating your story. After this, another cutscene plays involving you in a pink bunny costume, and suddenly you are snowboarding down the mountain (tutorial level anyone?). After this quick tutorial, we come across this strange female narrator, only to find out about how much she loves scrap booking!From here on out, it is very self explanatory. The game's main focal point is snowboarding, but there is plenty of fun to be had with its other features. Following a big red star, you are whisked through the game's storyline, and you find yourself not only snowboarding, but doing a bit of sledding, and snowmobiling as well.Throughout the game's story, you make friends and lose friends, discover new enemies, go on a full blown adventure, and the game's way of presenting this is top-notch. The cutscenes are straight out of a pop-art display, with strange sock puppets, arcade-style snippets, action figures, and paper cut-outs pulling the story along. It has plenty of quirky oddities that you rarely see in games. In addition to great storytelling, the dialogue and voice acting is also unique. The game features musical segments, 90's style commercial pieces, and much more to keep the player laughing throughout.SoundtrackTitles are listed as they appear in the game's menu. (Some titles were shortened by the game)Abacus RecordsThe Goodwill – Your Friendly GhostsThe Goodwill – Live And Die On Li…AlternativeCellphone Masses – RealThe Kite-Eating… – Like ButterscotchThe Kite-Eating… – Hope Is A PassengerGreen Olive Tree – DagobahThe Kite-Eating… – Sighs Of The CuratorGreen Olive Tree – Fake (false)The Kite-Eating… – All Sweedish, No Fin…The Kite-Eating… – Softer Seems The P…Green Olive Tree – PullArc The Finger RecordsCollective Efforts – DefineCollective Efforts – No WorriesMinamina Goodsong – SallyCollective Efforts – VersabilityPsyche Origami – Wherever You AreAsylum Ent.Eddie Meeks  Jax – Change EverythingBabygrand RecordsSharkey – Here We AreCentury MediaNightrage - ReleaseDoghouse RecordsCruiserweight – Goodbye Daily Sadn…Cruiserweight – PossibleCruiserweight – To Be Quite HonestDrive-Thru RecordsI Am The Avalanche – AlwaysHellogoodbye – Jesse Buy NothingHidden In Plain View – Ashes, AshesAllister – A Study In EconomicsHalifax – Because Pillows Ar…Hellogoodbye – Call N’ ReturnHidden In Plain View – American ClassicElectronicaKristin Mainheart – Cary GrantKristin Mainheart – Stranger ThingsRob Simonsen – BreatheKristin Mainheart – ChompingKristin Mainheart – Gonna Make ItChilldren Ov Par… - ThrillseekerTrystero – Him And Her And HimMinimum Sountr… - Big City At NightMount Sims – No Yellow LinesTrystero – BirthdayKristin Mainheart – Same Name In GoldMount Sims – RestlessKristin Mainheart – Tramp (remix)Demogorgon – Freezing TreeAmanaska – Distant WorldsEmoThis Is Exploding – StopTime To Fly – I Went Out To Color…Long Since Forg… - What She SaidThis Providence – Catching My BreatheWoke Up Falling – 21 Miles Into KansasNational Fire Th… - Too Young To DieThis Providence – Our Flag Is WhiteTime To Fly – BirthThis Is Exploding – MourningTime To Fly – Seemingly GreyDigen – From The OutsideFerret RecordsBoys Night Out - HealingBoys Night Out - PurgingHip HopFashion Expo – The New SongLojique – Instramentalude Pt 1Acts 29 – When The Smoke Cl…Phatheads – Rock OnKhromozomes – SushiKhromozomes – StudioMg! – Bumpiddy BumpActs 29 – Deja VuKhromozomes – PotatoKhromozomes – KickFashion Expo – You Dont Know The Half…Lojique – Case LogicFashion Expo – Lolly PopsKhromozomes – TomatoMg! – LatinosB. Dastardly – Its OverFashino Expo – ClayDa Diggler – Supa PowaRed Clouds – Ridiculous JunkDa Diggler- Hands 2 Tha PumpMan Of War – Verbal JunkThe Crow – MonkeyRaging Family … - The Ill TrackSackcloth Fashion – Strange ChemistryKhromozomes – SausageActs 29 – See ClearInvisible RecordsTub Ring – The Promise KeeperTub Ring – We Are The RighteousTub Ring – HabitatJade Tree RecordsPaint It Black – The New BrutalityPaint It Black - GhostsThe Loved Ones – Candy CaneLife Sentence RecordsTears From The… - Power SymbolTears From The… - Nailed DownLobster RecordsA Small Victory – Limousines And Che…Lorene Drive – Change Of OccupancyDays Like These – Preparation: AnxietyDays Like These – The Sergeant’s SonA Small Victory – Random CelebrationDays Like These – BruisesLorene Drive – Lip ServiceMiscellaneousDouble-O-Steven – Satellite TransmissionBryan Ingram – IgnitePluto RecordsPlease Mr. Grave… - The Nine To FivePlease Mr. Grave… - Rocket SciencePunkO’doyle Rules – The ListNational Fire Th… - Sick The AlarmPuny Human – Witches Chasing CabsGatsby’s American Dream – CastawayWhole Wheat Bread – No FutureHome Team – Place And TimeWhole Wheat Bread – OverratedVia Caramel – Friday NightRazor And Tie RecordsThe Chemistry – From WithinHeiruspecs – Something For Noth…The Giraffes – Haunted HeavenThe Giraffes – Wage EarnerRockMiss Lonely Heart – The Note That Mat…Ponticello – Wondering BluesThe Glasspack - HydroplanePuny Human – The ToosDe La Vega – Let It BurnDaydreams  Cur… GoldTime To Fly – You Will Not Commu…Tummer – Shooting BlanksDe La Vega – Buffalo BatterThe Glasspack – The Glasspack SongMiss Lonely Heart – TransitThrottlerod – MarigoldCasey Maxwell – The QuitsThe Glasspack – Bridge BurnerMiss Lonely Heart – WestRushmore RecordsSelf Against City – Take It How You Want ItThe Track Record – Winters RunDay At The Fair – CodaHouston Calls – High RiseHouston Calls – A Bottle Of Red, A…Self Against City – All This TimeHouston Calls – Elephant And CastleSuburban Noize RecordsThe Dirtball – This OneThe Dirtball – Bulldoggin’The Militia GroupCartel – Settle DownAnadivine – Dangerous Mixed WithCopeland – No One Really WinsBrandtson – Throwing Rocks Ton…Cartel – Burn This CityLovedrug – RocknrollThe Rocket Summ… - Around The ClockBrandtson – Just BreatheBrandtson – Who Are You NowThe Rocket Summ… - Brat PackThorp GroupThe Ducky Boys – FightBrain Failure – Hang Out TonightThe Ducky Boys – Break MeBrain Failure – PlayedThe Ducky Boys – Pass You ByTooth And Nail RecordsAnberlin – Neven Take Friend…Emery – So Cold I Could See…Anberlin – Paperthin HymnUnderoath – It’s Dangerous Business…Anberlin – The RunawaysMewithoutyou – January 1979Underoath – A Boy Brushed Red…Mewithoutyou – Disaster TourismWaking Ashland – I Am For YouUnderoath – Young And AspiringEmery – Studying PoliticsUnsignedAudio Assassins – ElbowsAudio Assassins - BuckdownAfter The Tradegy – The Soul Burns The…Audio Assassins – DarknessAudio Assassins – Make Some NoiseAfter The Tradegy – The Beautiful BrandBone Worship - WormVictory RecordsThe Forecast – Late Night ConversationThe Junior Varsity – I’m Home HoorayThe Junior Varsity – Get ComfortableGiles – Desk Seeking SpadesJune – I’ve Got The Time If…June – The CityThe Forecast – These NightsThe Forecast – Seating Subject To ChangeThe Junior Varsity – Mad For MedusaGiles – AttackinSnow TraxThe Track Record – Letters To SummerO’doyle Rules – MexicoMiss Lonely Heart – On A Train Up A TreeGatsby’s American Dream – Golden TicketAction Figures – Jamacian ManMount Sims – Good ServiceBrain Failure – Stay FreeThese Arms Are… - Darlings Of New Mid…Hellogoodbye- Shimmy Shimmy Quarter…Allister – A Lot Of NerveGravy MixAfter The Tradegy – Choking On ShoelacesBrandtson – C’mon FascistaSecret Society D… - HeyTears From The… - The Next Few DaysFashion Expo – Dues For CashewsDanko Jones – I Want YouDaydreams  Cur... – The ChaseDay At The Fair – Who Are You Guna Belie…Hidden In Plain View – A Minor DetailViva Caramel – Option 3Songs Not N...Coleon – Relax Ya SoulThe Ducky Boys – Boston, UsaCasey Maxwell – Far Too LongMewithoutyou – Torches TogetherFashion Expo – Journey Through M…Halifax – Anthem For TonightHoneyroot – State Of MindUnderoath – Reinventing You ExitKhromozomes – Track 13Minimum Soundtrack – Swat TeamMuzik 4 YouNightrage – PhantasmaTrystero – Come And Get ItMorsel - NeedleCruiserweight – VermontLovedrug – PandamorandoCellphone Masses – BelieveDj Sonix – Needle DropB Dastardly – Got It GoodHouston Calls – Exit EmergencyThrottlerod – In The FloodSounds About V…The Chemisty – Still AliveCartel – Say Anything (else)1 Up 2 Down – CrawlingCollective Efforts – Doin AlrightThe Dirtball – Not AfraidFashion Expo – How We DoFashion Expo – TravelingFashion Expo – Tight With LassoMg! – UnderstandingThe Kite Eating… - Hollywood Hates YouSick Sick SixCowboys And Mon… - Race Car FireThe Goodwill – Live From The Red…Lucien Nicolet – K-DanceAudio Assassins – Shake ItO’doyle Rules – Dies Smiling And A…Sharkey – If It FitsMiss Lonely Heart – Digital ImageryDays Like These – One In One ThousandThe Loved Ones – MassiveAnberlin – Audrey Start The…Anadivine – Adding Insult To In…Beat NoirTime To Fly – Locked In And Hope…A Small Victory – Amy Never MissesGiles – BeaneHalfway To Gone – Black NightAnadivine – Yes Sir Mr MachineThe Giraffes – Million $ ManThe Volumes – So LongThrottlerod – Tomorrow And A Lo…Dj Sonix – Full StretchGreenleaf – 10,000 Years To Re…Your Brain On…Heiruspecs – A Tiger DancingThis Providence – EverydayDignen – BlueBrain Failure – Summer AfternoonLong Since Forg… - Some Sort Of MeaningO’doyle Rules – Lesson LearnedDj Sonix – Booty KlubThis Is Exploding – Without A FightMassive Power S… - Hard DriveHome Team – False AlarmA Non-Concept…Trystero – Faster NowVeloce – RegardlessSecret Society B… - Kaboom BabyDetroit Escalato… - Inline 6Cex – The Marriage (instr…Micropworld – Bc StyleIncendio – DeliriumEmery – Miss BehavingJune – Ok CorralCellphone Masses – Another WorldInsanity In S…Halifax – SydneyI Am The Avalanche – Dead And GoneHypnos – SlipstreamPaint It Black – Atheists In FoxholesPugwash  Bizzy B – Tutti FruttiNightrage – Reality Vs. TruthSecret Society D… - OkO’brien Parker… - Is It Real?Pete Miser – Table ScrapsNakoi Kenji – Extra MileTime To Fly – Give Me Some Morp…Love  OtherCex – Brer Rjyan Instrum…This Providence – Any Romantic Fairy…Tub Ring – Sharpening The Stic…Time To Fly – Things You Don’t Ne…Helix – GutsuckerGatsby’s American Dream – Game OverHome Team – I’ll Take My ChancesHelix – A-KlimatizeHoneyroot – Sweet As HoneyPlease Mr. Graves… - WalesBlink Blank B…Mg! – Re-GlittaRed Cloud – When Kenpo Stikes44 Long – FreeWaking Ashalnd – MedicationFashion Expo – PerceptionsDaydreams  Cur – Faceless ShadowActs 29 – Blank MindsOmega Watts – 422 BurnsideThe Forecast – Fade In FadeoutPerfume Tree – Blink (black And Wh…Xbox 360 Game InstallationAmped 3 requires 6.0 GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="33">Snowboarding/Skiing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20954">Shaun White Snowboarding</game><game id="18782">SSX Tricky</game><game id="17149">SSX 3</game><game id="18946">1080° Snowboarding</game><game id="19339">1080° Avalanche</game><game id="18062">Snowboard Kids</game><game id="18426">Snowboard Kids 2</game><game id="9202">Disney Sports Snowboarding</game><game id="17969">SSX Blur</game><game id="834">Jonny Moseley Mad Trix</game><game id="23479">Stoked</game><game id="15277">TransWorld Snowboarding</game><game id="25097">Shaun Palmer's Pro Snowboarder</game><game id="24449">We Ski &amp; Snowboard</game><game id="21727">MTV Sports: Snowboarding</game><game id="28475">Stoked: Big Air Edition</game><game id="20880">We Ski</game><game id="1932">SSX</game><game id="42370">R: Rock'n Riders</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2136538-box_amped3.png</image></root>