<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16650</id><name>Fuzion Frenzy</name><description>GameplayThis is a 4 player party game with a total 45 mini games. There are two different game modes the players can compete in, they are 'Tournament' and 'Mini Game Frenzy'. Mini Game Frenzy allows the players to pick any mini game they like and a score sheet is recorded of who wins each mini game that is played. Tournament mode is set up differently in that the player wants to record the highest number of points after playing mini games in two different zones. There are six different zones:  Coliseum - Rolling Ball and Ice Car mini-games.Downtown - Fireworks and Music mini-games.Outlands - Demolition and Tail mini-games.Military Base - Pod and Tank mini-games.Power Station - Hopper and Splat mini-games.Waterfront - Jetboat and Orb mini-games.  The number of zones in tournament mode can be chosen to be as few as 2 or as many as all 6. The zones are chosen randomly if the player decides not to play all 6 zones. In each of the zones the players will play 3 random mini games specified to that zone. The mini-games sometimes require a partner so your partner will be chosen randomly. Some of the mini-games are timed, while others are not.  Depending on how you place in the mini-game you will receive a certain amount of orbs.  6 orbs4 orbs2 orbs0 orbs Though if there is a tie the orbs are split evenly.  Once the third mini-game is finished for a zone their is a special event called 'Fuzion Frenzy'. This requires the player to decide how many of the orbs they won in the 3 mini-games they want in play for 'Fuzion Frenzy'. The more you bet the greater the reward, but also the greater the risk. When 'Fuzion Frenzy' begins colored orbs and colorless orbs begin to appear on the playing field. The colored orbs can only be picked up by the corresponding player, but the colorless orbs can be picked up by any player. Once the player has picked up the orbs they need to deliver them to a glowing circle where they will cash in their points. Though if the player is carrying several orbs they will gain a bonus. Also the players need to be wary of the other players on the field because you can attack one another and steal each others orbs. When the 80 seconds of madness ends the scores are tallied up to the orbs that weren't bet and the winner of the zone is determined. If there is a tie a tie-breaker is performed. On the final zone the overall winner is declared and they get to stand on the amazing first place podium while everyone else shakes their heads in shame.Characters The players can select between six different characters, though the character that is chosen is purely cosmetic and does not affect gameplay what so ever.  The different characters are as follows.  ZakSamsonJetDubNaomiGeena CPUIf there is not 4 human players CPU will take the open slots.  The difficultly of the CPU can then be chosen, but be warned if you choose the hardest difficulty prepare to be smashed into a pulp!  Especially in the 'Fuzion Frenzy' stages since they really seem to like to steal your orbs. Xbox Originals   On December 4, 2007, Fuzion Frenzy became available on the       Xbox 360's      Xbox Originals download service for   1200 Microsoft Points. </description><genres><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21617">Rayman: Raving Rabbids</game><game id="6424">Mario Party</game><game id="8362">Mario Party 8</game><game id="12447">Mario Party 3</game><game id="4660">Mario Party 4</game><game id="12162">Mario Party 2</game><game id="5995">Mario Party Advance</game><game id="3410">Mario Party 5</game><game id="8380">Mario Party 6</game><game id="21186">Mario Party DS</game><game id="7669">Cartoon Network Block Party</game><game id="24844">Every Party</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2275990-box_ff.png</image></root>