<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16835</id><name>Ultima Online: The Second Age</name><description>New land mass with cities and dungeons.CreaturesBullfrog - A small amphibian which is found in swamps and jungles.Frost Spider - Large spiders which tend to attack in numbers.Giant Ice Serpent - Large snakes that have strong melee attacks.Giant Toad - A larger version of the Bullfrog.Ice Snake - Simply a snake found in cold climates.Lava Lizard - Fire-breathing alligators.Nightmare - Evil black horses that can shoot fireballs.Forest Ostard - A forest dwelling creature which is peacefull and can be tamed and ridden.Destert Ostard - Similar to the Ostard, but is found in the desert.Frenzied Ostard - An evil version of the above two which has a very fast melee attack. MonstersCyclopian Warrior - Incredibly strong one-eyed monsters.Frost Troll - Slightly stronger than a normal troll.Ice Elemental - Radiates extreme cold which damages even at a distance.Ice Fiend - Strong Daemon-like creatures which radiate cold.Imp - A spellcasting version of the mongbat.Mummy - Yet another medium strength undead creature.Ophidian Apprentice Mage - Low level lizard mages.Ophidian Avenger - The strongest of the Ophidian fighters.Ophidian Enforcer - A medium strength Ophidian fighter.Ophidian Justicar -Ophidian Knight-Errant - Second only to the Ophidian Avenger in melee attacks.Ophidian Matriarch - The Queen of the Opidians. She has a dangerous melee attack an extremely potent mage to boot.Ophidian Shaman - A high level Ophidian mage.Ophidian Warrior - The most basic of the Ophidian fighters.Ophidian Zealot -Snow Elemental - Radiates the same damaging cold as the Ice Elemental, but it also has a medium level magical attack.Stone Gargoyle - A gargoyle which has traded brawn for brains. Strong melee, no magic.Stone Harpy - A beefed up Harpy.Swamp Tentacle - A corpser that can move.Terathan Avenger - A strong Terathan warrior which can also cast spells.Terathan Drone - The easiest of the Terathans. Not much to worry about.Terathan Matriarch - The counterpart to the Ophidian Matriarch, only slightly less dangerous.Terathan Warrior - The bulk of the Terathan forces. Warriors are competent melee fighters.Titan - A spellcasting Cyclops.Wyvern - A weak Dragon which relies on melee attacks.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="545">Asheron's Call</game><game id="13869">Istaria: Chronicles of the Gifted</game><game id="24336">Fiesta</game><game id="27896">World of Warcraft: Cataclysm</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/10356/274879-uo2a.jpg</image></root>