<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16851</id><name>Castlevania: The Dracula X Chronicles</name><description>Released in Japan as Akumajo Dracula X Chronicle, this game compiles remakes of two of the most popular games in the Castlevania line, Akumajo Dracula X: Chi no Rondo and Castlevania: Symphony of the Night. This marks the first time that Chi no Rondo has been released outside of Japan.Akumajo Dracula X: Chi no Rondo, which was originally released as a CD game for the PC Engine, has been translated into English and retitled Castlevania: Rondo of Blood. A handful of additional changes have been inserted into the remake. The game also contains the original version of of Chi no Rondo, though players can still opt for the new English soundtrack.The version of Symphony of the Night has been updated with newly-recorded voice acting. Maria, who was playable in the Saturn version of the game, is playable in this version, as well.Game 1: CASTLEVANIA RONDO OF BLOODRichter Belmont, protagonist of "Castlevania Rondo of blood"The main change in this game is that it was remade as a 3d game in a 2d plane, so it continues to be a sidescroller like most Castlevania games are, but unlike most of the new 2d Castlevania games that came out in recent years, this one doesnt have the exploration or RPG elements of those recent games.It resembles more the original gameplay style of the series, go from point A to point B getting rid of everything in your way.Multiple paths allow you to reach the end of the level and eventually your confrontation with Dracula. In each level you can find hidden rewards that give new tracks for the soundtrack or even 2 new games to play.Game 2: CASTLEVANIA SYMPHONY OF THE NIGHTThis game is a sequel to the main game. It takes place a few years after the first one and puts you in control of a new character: Alucard, son of Dracula.Alucard, son of DraculaThe game was released in 1997 for the Sony PlayStation and the Sega Saturn. First Castlevania game to use the "explore the castle - lvl up formula" of the recent games. It became a success.The formula has been emulated and used in handheld Castlevania games for a number of years now. It seems to be a staple of the series.The game allows you to explore Dracula's castle in any order you please. Different areas are restricted untill you get a special ability that allows you to reach the new area or bypass the obastacle blocking your way. You can lvl up your character gaining experience from monster you kill and you can do away with them using many diferent weapons and spells found in the game. Different weapons can mean different abilities or different aproaches to the many enemies found in the game.Game 3: CASTLEVANIA RONDO OF BLOOD (original)This is the original game as it was released on the PC-Engine Super CD-Rom2 in Japan in 1993.PS Vita CompatibilityDespite not being in the official compatibility list, Castlevania: The Dracula X Chronicles can be played on the PS Vita. To do this, the user must first download the game to the PS3. From there, go to Content Transfer on the PS Vita and select the game for transfer. Once complete, the game will show up on the Vita's menu.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20483">Bionic Commando Rearmed</game><game id="887">Vampire: Master of Darkness</game><game id="14416">Ninja Gaiden II: The Dark Sword of Chaos</game><game id="1850">Ninja Gaiden III: The Ancient Ship of Doom</game><game id="16948">Mega Man X3</game><game id="20435">Mega Man ZX Advent</game><game id="17825">Ninja Gaiden: Shadow</game><game id="14147">Patapon</game><game id="20773">N+</game><game id="11913">Mega Man Maverick Hunter X</game><game id="23616">Winx Club: Join the Club</game><game id="15893">Rainbow Islands Revolution</game><game id="23692">Prinny: Can I Really Be the Hero?</game><game id="26706">Shadow Complex</game><game id="28250">Rusty</game><game id="28918">Metal Slug XX</game><game id="14148">Princess Crown</game><game id="31372">Jikandia: The Timeless Land</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1773366-box_cvdxc.png</image></root>