<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16856</id><name>Batman</name><description>OverviewIntro screenBatman is a 3D isometric perspective Action/ Arcade/ Adventure game which is a comic, superhero and light puzzle- solving influenced game based on the TV-show and comic license ( DC Comics Inc.).It was written by Bernie Drummond and programmed by Jon Ritman and released under the Batman license by Ocean software.The first version was one of their more successful games and was well received by critics and called a classic which made Batman a popular name in the videogame industry.GameplayOverview of the 3D map.The game sports a monochrome style for 8-bit gaming. Batman’s sidekick Robin has been kidnapped by the Joker and the Riddler while he was repairing Batman’s Car. You as Batman must save the Boy Wonder. But before Batman can save Robin, he must find seven missing parts of the bat-hovercraft that Robin left scattered throughout the Batcave and Bruce’s mansion. Batman also has to start off without his equipment that he must find, as you traverse in the games 150 different screens of monochrome rooms filled with nasty creatures, spiked traps, conveyer belts, lifts and sinking floors.ItemsThe slightly chubby Batman is on the left and the little Batman on the right is, in fact, a Bat-pill.The Bat-bag allows you to pick up and drop objects, the Bat-boots let you jump, the Thruster allows movement when falling but no control of speed and the Bat-belt is a low gravity belt that halves the speed of descent. Four extra powers and a fifth neutralizing power are also available. They fall from the ceiling at certain points along the way.You can become invincible, have extra energy and improved speed for a short time by acquiring Bat-pills. Extra lives can also be found strewn throughout the game. The jump power enables you to jump twice as high as normal jumps. The neutralizer will cancel all of Batman’s extra powers and should be avoided.OptionsBatman was the first game to have a checkpoint system built in as an option for players to restart from a point in the game. Batman collects a Bat signal to achieve this. It costs of one of a possible eight lives and returns you with your previous health and equipment intact.TriviaA freeware / payware remake was made and produced by Kakarot, The GGG, Russell Hoy and System Halted for PC in 2001 as a DOS game and was called Watman. There was also another remake by the same developers for Game Boy Advance released in 2002 under the name Gwatman</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7068">Head Over Heels</game><game id="13220">Solstice: The Quest for the Staff of Demnos</game><game id="13849">Equinox</game><game id="12187">Last Battle</game><game id="30399">Spider-Man: Shattered Dimensions</game><game id="34997">The Amazing Spider-Man: Lethal Foes</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/10831/896668-940198_89941_front.jpg</image></root>