<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16875</id><name>Mickey Mania</name><description>BackgroundMickey Mania ( Mickey's Wild Adventure on the  PlayStation) has players guide  Mickey through various levels, all of which are based on classic Mickey Mouse Cartoons dating from 1928 to 1990. The game is basically the same across all platforms, however there are some minor differences. The  Sega CD version for example adds CD-quality audio and an  extra boss battle, whilst the  SNES version excludes the tower sections.Mickey's Wild Adventure (The PlayStation release), only available in  Europe and  Australia, also featured CD-quality audio and had improved graphics over the original releases.The game was originally intended as a celebration of Mickey Mouse's 65th Birthday Celebration, but was pushed back in order to allow more time for development. This also led to the game's premise as released in which Mickey travels back to his previous cartoons.GameplayMickey Mania is a fairly typical  side-scrolling platform game. Players guide Mickey from left to right through levels, passing obstacles through  jumping or  solving puzzles. Enemies can be defeated either by jumping on them or by  throwing marbles at them. The game is famously difficult, some say feel much too difficult for its intended audience. A lot of this difficulty is because some of the game requires a lot of precise timing and many of the enemies are hard to defeat without taking damage.At the top left hand corner of your screen, you will see Mickey's Glove. The number under the glove symbolizes the number of lives you have remaining and the fingers of the glove show how many hits you can take before you lose a life.ItemsIn Mickey Mania there are three types of items at your disposal, each with a different purpose:Stars: These give you 1 health (finger) back per star. If you have full health and get the stars, they will disappear and you will NOT get an extra life.Marbles: The main way of getting past most levels in this game. Marbles are everywhere to collect and the serve as your means of hitting enemies and bosses. They are transferable from level to level though you have a holding limit of 99 marbles.Mouse Ears: Mickey's Mouse Ears can come in very handy and are in secretive locations throughout the game. They replenish 1 full life, regardless if you have not previously lost a life.Cartoons Featured as LevelsThere are a total of 7 levels to play through in Mickey Mania.Steamboat Willie (1928)The level starts you out on the steamboat from the famous 1928 animated short, and after a short time on the boat the level continues on land. You are faced with challenging platforming elements already on the first stage, and you also meet  Pete as a  mini boss in this stage. At the end of the level you can actually find to branching paths; one that leads to a crane boss battle, and another, which leads you to a secret area with tons of marbles and  1-ups.In the level you will find small details from the animated short, like the "musical goat" and the iconic boat-horns.The Mad Doctor (1933)This level starts up with a little homage to  Dragons Lair by basically copying the start of the game. You continue through The Mad Doctors  castle and you are faced with classic enemies like  skeletons and  bats, you are even met with a  elevator and an on-rail jumping section. At the end you fight The Mad Doctor and save  Pluto before he gets experimented with.The Band Concert (1935)This is a secret bonus level in which players must navigate to the top of a  tornado. This is basically one of the tower sections and as such is not featured in the SNES version.Moose Hunters (1937)Players follow Pluto (In the cartoon,  Goofy and  Donald were alongside Mickey, not Pluto) through this level. Enemies including a  moose who charges at Mickey and environmental hazards too such as falling branches and boulders.Lonesome Ghosts (1937)This level features the titular lonesome  ghosts who attempt to halt Mickey's progress with all sorts of tricks and jokes. This level has some tricky sections and a memorable section where water levels rise and fall.Mickey and the Beanstalk (1947)This level forces Mickey to "do some gardening" and has him contend with not just a giant (Additionally, an escape section featuring the giant is in CD versions, though not others) but also a giant spider. This level features the only friendly  NPC in the game apart from various Mickeys and Pluto - a  ladybug who helps Mickey escape the spider.The Prince and the Pauper (1990)The game makes a large jump in time to feature The Prince and the Pauper (43 years). This level features the most difficult combat in the game, including a boss battle against a very powerful Pete which has two forms.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1334">Super Mario World</game><game id="9331">Pitfall: The Mayan Adventure</game><game id="6833">Rayman: Hoodlum's Revenge</game><game id="14279">Land of Illusion starring Mickey Mouse</game><game id="23656">Hook</game><game id="18350">The Adventures of Lomax</game><game id="6368">Mickey's Speedway USA</game><game id="9551">Disney's Donald Duck: Goin' Quackers</game><game id="9412">QuackShot starring Donald Duck</game><game id="27050">Frantic Flea</game><game id="29084">Mickey Mouse Magic Wands!</game><game id="16604">Ardy Lightfoot</game><game id="14055">Disney's PK: Out of the Shadows</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2543318-box_mmania.png</image></root>