<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16885</id><name>Hogs of War</name><description>OverviewHogs of War is a turn-based strategy game that was released on both the PC and Sony Playstation in 2000. The gameplay bears a significant resemblance to other turn based strategy games such as Worms. There are both single and multiplayer modes, where players can choose to take control of any one of seven different teams, across a variety of levels.Characters in the game (as well as the narration), are voiced by Rik Mayall, the renowned British comedian. PlotThe game's setting is the fictional area of Saustralasia, an island in the Pigsific Ocean.  The object of the game is to acquire all of the territory on Saustralasia (it is split up into sections such as Hogshead and Arstria) in order to gain access to swill, a seemingly valuable commodity in the world at which the game is set. The game is inspired by the events and nations that were part of the First World War.TeamsUncle Ham's HogsBased upon the army of the United States of America, Uncle Ham's Hogs wear a light blue uniform.PiggystroikaA Russian-inspired team, dressed in uniforms of dark red. The name Piggystroika comes from the Russian word perestroika, which was used to describe the economic reforms undertaken in Russia under Gorbachev.Sow-A-KrautsClearly intended to be the German army, the name is derived from a pun on the German word sauerkraut, the Sow-A-Krauts team wear uniforms of grey.Garlic GruntsBased upon a stereotypically French army, the Garlic Grunts wear a dark blue uniform.Sushi SwineA team based upon the army of the Japanese, wearing bright yellow uniforms.Tommy's TrottersWearing dark green uniforms, Tommy's Trotters are a team that is based upon the British Expeditionary Force (BEF), that was active during World War I.Team LardA team, clad in dark purple, that feature in the final level of the single player campaign. They represent the developers of the game and can be unlocked by completing the final level, as a 'survival bonus', if all of the pigs in your team are alive at the end. In the Playstation version, Team Lard could be unlocked by entering the cheat code 'MARDY PIGS' as your team name.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17255">Worms Armageddon</game><game id="522">Worms 3D</game><game id="20815">Worms</game><game id="13355">Worms 4: Mayhem</game><game id="18822">Worms World Party</game><game id="22008">Raze's Hell</game><game id="27139">Worms 2: Armageddon</game><game id="2007">Worms</game><game id="32738">Delve Deeper</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2437071-box_how.png</image></root>