<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16928</id><name>NBA Jam</name><description>OverviewNBA Jam is a basketball arcade game developed and released by Midway in 1993. It is the first entry in the NBA Jam series and became exceptionally popular in arcades, generating over $1 billion dollars in revenue for the company. Mark Turmell was the game's main programmer and designer, and its gameplay is based on the game Arch Rivals which Midway released in 1989.Due to the success of NBA Jam, an updated version of the game called NBA Jam Tournament Edition was released a year and a half later, and it features updated rosters and adds a number of new features to the series. Midway also used the success of NBA Jam to apply the over-the-top nature of the game to other sports. For example, Midway went on to create NFL Blitz, an over-the-top version of American football, in 1997.GameplayNBA Jam is a 2-on-2 arcade-style basketball game that features over-the-top gameplay. The exaggerated nature of the gameplay means that players can perform gravity defying dunks with ease and shove opposing players down without penalty. Each game consists of four 3 minute long quarters, and the team with the most points at the end of the fourth quarter wins the game. When starting a match players have the option to enter their initials in order to keep track of their win-loss record and teams that they have beaten.The only fouls a player can commit in NBA Jam are goal tending and shot clock violations. This means that the player can shove the other opposing players (and even his own teammate) down in order to get the ball and not commit a foul. A shot clock is present in order to keep the game moving at a fast pace and goal tending is used to prevent players from hoarding the basket while on defense.A trademark of the NBA Jam series is the ability for players to catch on fire. This occurs when a player makes three consecutive shots, and their opponent makes none. While on fire the player is nearly unstoppable; the player is granted unlimited turbo, increased accuracy, and can't be called for goal tending. A player's fire goes out when the opposing team makes a basket.Teams*Note: The arcade version features teams from the 92-93 NBA season, while the home version include players from the 93-94 season. Shaq only appears in the arcade version of the game, he does not appear in the home versions of the game because the cost to renew the right to license him was deemed too high.Eastern Conference TeamsTeamArcadeSNES/GenesisSega CDGame BoyGame GearAtlanta HawksDominique Wilkins and Stacey AugmonDominique Wilkins and Stacey AugmonStacey Augmon and Mookie BlaylockStacey Augmon and Mookie BlaylockDominique Wilkins and Stacey AugmonBoston CelticsReggie Lewis and Kevin McHaleDee Brown and Robert ParishDee Brown and Dominique WilkinsDee Brown and Dominique WilkinsDee Brown and Robert ParishCharlotte HornetsLarry Johnson and Kendall GillLarry Johnson and Alonzo MourningLarry Johnson and Alonzo MourningLarry Johnson and Alonzo MourningLarry Johnson and Alonzo MourningChicago BullsScottie Pippen and Horace GrantScottie Pippen and Horace GrantScottie Pippen and B.J. ArmstrongScottie Pippen and Horace GrantScottie Pippen and Horace GrantCleveland CavaliersMark Price and Brad DaughertyMark Price and Brad DaughertyMark Price and Brad DaughertyMark Price and Brad DaughertyMark Price and Brad DaughertyDetroit PistonsIsiah Thomas and Bill LaimbeerIsiah Thomas and Bill LaimbeerTerry Mills and Joe DumarsTerry Mills and Joe DumarsIsiah Thomas and Bill LaimbeerIndiana PacersReggie Miller and Detlef SchrempfReggie Miller and Derrick MckeyReggie Miller and Derrick MckeyReggie Miller and Rik SmitsReggie Miller and Derrick MckeyMilwaukee BucksBrad Lohaus and Blue EdwardsBrad Lohaus and Blue EdwardsVin Baker and Eric MurdockVin Baker and Eric MurdockBrad Lohaus and Blue EdwardsMiami HeatRony Seikaly and Glen RiceRony Seikaly and Harold MinerRony Seikaly and Glen RiceRony Seikaly and Glen RiceRony Seikaly and Harold MinerNew Jersey NetsDerrick Coleman andDražen PetrovićDerrick Coleman and Kenny AndersonDerrick Coleman and Kenny AndersonDerrick Coleman and Kenny AndersonDerrick Coleman and Kenny AndersonNew York KnicksPatrick Ewing and Charles OakleyPatrick Ewing and John StarksPatrick Ewing and John StarksPatrick Ewing and John StarksPatrick Ewing and John StarksOrlando MagicShaquille O’Neal and Scott SkilesNick Anderson and Scott SkilesNick Anderson and Penny HardawayNick Anderson and Penny HardawayNick Anderson and Scott SkilesPhiladelphia 76ersHersey Hawkins and Jeff HornacekClarence Weatherspoon and Jeff HornacekClarence Weatherspoon and Jeff HornacekClarence Weatherspoon and Jeff HornacekClarence Weatherspoon and Jeff HornacekWashington BulletsTom Gugliotta and Harvey GrantTom Gugliotta and Harvey GrantTom Gugliotta and Calbert CheaneyTom Gugliotta and Calbert CheaneyTom Gugliotta and Harvey GrantWestern Conference TeamsTeamArcadeSNES/GenesisSega CDGame BoyGame GearDallas MavericksDerek Harper and Mike IuzzolinoDerek Harper and Jim JacksonDerek Harper and Jamal MashburnDerek Harper and Jamal MashburnDerek Harper and Jim JacksonDenver NuggetsDikembe Mutombo and LaPhonso EllisDikembe Mutombo and LaPhonso EllisDikembe Mutombo and Mahmoud Abdul-RaufDikembe Mutombo and Mahmoud Abdul-RaufDikembe Mutombo and LaPhonso EllisGolden State WarriorsTim Hardaway and Chris MullinTim Hardaway and Chris MullinChris Webber and Latrell SprewellChris Webber and Latrell SprewellTim Hardaway and Chris MullinHouston RocketsHakeem Olajuwon and Kenny SmithHakeem Olajuwon and Vernon MaxwellHakeem Olajuwon and Vernon MaxwellHakeem Olajuwon and Vernon MaxwellHakeem Olajuwon and Vernon MaxwellLos Angeles ClippersDanny Manning and Ron HarperDanny Manning and Ron HarperPooh Richardson and Ron HarperPooh Richardson and Ron HarperDanny Manning and Ron HarperLos Angeles LakersVlade Divac and James WorthyVlade Divac and James WorthyVlade Divac and Nick Van ExelVlade Divac and Nick Van ExelVlade Divac and James WorthyMinnesota TimberwolvesChristian Laettner and Chuck PersonChristian Laettner and Chuck PersonChristian Laettner and Isaiah RiderChristian Laettner and Isaiah RiderChristian Laettner and Chuck PersonPhoenix SunsCharles Barkley and Dan MajerleCharles Barkley and Kevin JohnsonDan Majerle and Kevin JohnsonDan Majerle and Kevin JohnsonDan Majerle and Kevin JohnsonPortland Trail BlazersClyde Drexler and Terry PorterClyde Drexler and Terry PorterClyde Drexler and Cliff RobinsonClyde Drexler and Cliff RobinsonClyde Drexler and Terry PorterSacramento KingsWayman Tisdale and Spud WebbWayman Tisdale and Mitch RichmondWayman Tisdale and Mitch RichmondWayman Tisdale and Mitch RichmondWayman Tisdale and Mitch RichmondSan Antonio SpursDavid Robinson and Sean ElliotDavid Robinson and Sean ElliotDavid Robinson and Chuck PersonDavid Robinson and Dale EllisDavid Robinson and Dale EllisSeattle Super SonicsShawn Kemp and Benoit BenjaminShawn Kemp and Detlef SchrempfShawn Kemp and Detlef SchrempfShawn Kemp and Detlef SchrempfShawn Kemp and Detlef SchrempfUtah JazzKarl Malone and John StocktonKarl Malone and John StocktonKarl Malone and John StocktonKarl Malone and John StocktonKarl Malone and John StocktonEaster EggsDražen Petrović haunts the arcade version of NBA Jam, allegedly.Dražen Petrović died in a car accident between the game's home version port. It is believed that he haunts the arcade version of the game by causing the announcer to call his name out at random.NBA Jam is well known for featuring many odd hidden characters that can be unlocked via the game's initial entry. Unlockable players include:Bill ClintonAl GoreSal DivitaMark TurmellNBA Jam also includes cheats that enhance a players stats, these include: always on fire, infinite turbo and super dunks.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="22">Basketball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="946">Rap Jam: Volume One</game><game id="10302">NBA Street Homecourt</game><game id="17290">Sega Soccer Slam</game><game id="125">College Slam</game><game id="61">NBA Street V3</game><game id="7982">NBA Street</game><game id="11891">Barkley: Shut Up and Jam!</game><game id="8857">Arch Rivals</game><game id="19644">RedCard 20-03</game><game id="9866">NBA Street Vol. 2</game><game id="1533">Double Dribble</game><game id="26912">NBA Unrivaled</game><game id="5958">White Men Can't Jump</game><game id="4632">NBA Showtime: NBA on NBC</game><game id="11202">NBA Give 'n Go</game><game id="30483">Run and Gun</game><game id="17850">Looney Tunes B-Ball</game><game id="17238">Harlem Globetrotters: World Tour</game><game id="22752">Fox Sports College Hoops '99</game><game id="24889">Capcom Sports Club</game><game id="8577">Jammit</game><game id="38745">Super Dunk Star</game><game id="18865">Great Basketball</game><game id="40805">Basketball Nightmare</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1535202-nbajam_box.png</image></root>