<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16922</id><name>Star Wars: Jedi Knight - Jedi Academy</name><description>OverviewJedi Academy is a spin-off of the Jedi Knight series, and the first game to feature Kyle Katarn as an NPC, instead eschewing him in favor of a customizable lead, Jaden Korr. Jedi Academy was designed with the idea of giving the player more customization and more control, instead of funneling them down a story corridor like Jedi Outcast did. Kyle Katarn was already a powerful Jedi at this point, and Raven realized that Kyle would not work as a main character plot-wise, because there would be no character evolution, so they decided to create Jaden Korr, and make Kyle his Jedi Master. The game was developed in tandem by Raven, Vicarious Visions, and Lucasarts, with Threewave software designing multi-player maps.Opening CrawlTen years after theBattle of Endor,the IMPERIAL REMNANTcontinues to be drivenback by the NEW REPUBLIC,forcing the Imperials to adoptincreasingly desperatetactics in the ongoingstruggle.Meanwhile, Jedi MasterLUKE SKYWALKERmoves to restore theJEDI to their formal placeas peacekeepers of thegalaxy at his JEDI ACADEMYon Yavin 4.JADEN KORR, apromising student fromCoruscant, is en route tothe Academy afterachieving the impossible:creating a lightsaberwithout any formal Jedi training…StoryThe story of Jedi Academy deals with the Disciples of Ragnos, led by returning series character Tavion Axmis. The game starts out with Tavion's apprentice, Alora, infiltrating the Jedi Academy on Yavin 4 and stealing a list of areas infused with force energies. New Jedi Jaden Korr sees Alora with some sort of scepter channeling force energy, but is immediately knocked out, and the Dark Jedi flee. Shortly after, Luke Skywalker addresses the new students, assigning them masters, but noting that because there are so few Jedi, multiple padawans will be assigned to each master.Jaden is assigned to Kyle Katarn, along with another student, Rosh Penin. Jaden and Rosh both go through some basic training at the academy, where Rosh sets a training droid on Jaden so that Rosh can finish the course first. Jaden defeats it however, and arrives at about the same time as Rosh. After they complete their basic training, both Jedi begin taking on missions with Kyle, although they never work together. After the Jedi have undertaken 4 or 5 missions, Luke Skywalker calls the Jedi back to the academy. He has concluded that the Disciples of Ragnos are somehow funneling the force energy from the places he mentioned in his stolen records. However, he believes there are a few places that may not have been found yet, and dispatches the Jedi to protect them. Jaden is sent to Hoth alone to investigate, while the other Jedi head off to investigate other areas.Jaden on HothJaden lands on Hoth in his Z-95 Headhunter, and initially thinks nothing is out of place, until he spots a path marker through the snow. He hops on a Tauntaun and heads off, following the markers. Shortly, he encounters a picket force of Stormtroopers from the Imperial Remnant, which leads him to believe that the Disciples of Ragnos are on Hoth as well. After fighting his way through the ice plains, and a cave containing a wampa, Jaden reaches the outer fortifications of Echo base, which he infiltrates, successfully avoiding an AT-ST walker.Inside Echo base, Jaden encounters both Stormtroopers and cultists, all of whom attempt to stop him. However, after fighting his way through to the command center, Jaden finds a Dark Jedi attempting to slice into the records. Jaden kills him, but seeks out the other cultist in the base who was communicating with the one he just killed. Entering the Echo base hangar, Jaden encounters Alora, a red Twilek, and the Dark Jedi Jaden saw at the Academy. The two engage in a furious lightsaber duel, and when Jaden starts to gain the advantage, Alora uses the force to flee through a hole in the ceiling, telling Jaden that they'll meet again.Jaden returns to the academy and passes this information onto Kyle Katarn and Luke Skywalker, who inform Jaden that Rosh never returned from his mission to the planet of Byss. Kyle says he is going to investigate, while Luke leaves the academy to investigate the Disciples of Ragnos further, leaving Jaden to complete his missions on his own. Jaden takes on four or five missions in the meantime, these all much more difficult, as the Disciples of Ragnos are growing more aggressive, and the Jedi are being mobilized to stop them.Shortly after this, Master Skywalker called all the Jedi back to the academy, and sent them on missions to investigate places strong in the force that hadn't been mentioned in the stolen records. Due to the loss of Rosh, the Jedi were to work in pairs on these missions. Jaden and Kyle were selected to investigate Vader's Bast Castle on the planet Vjun.Upon arriving on Vjun, the pair encountered a hostile environment, with acid rain falling from the sky and heavy, suited environment troopers armed with Concussion Rifles. The two Jedi fought their way through the canyons surrounding the perimeter of Bast Castle, facing Imperial troops along the way. However, they were stopped from entering the actual castle by a pair of TIE Bombers carpet-bombing the entrance, keeping them from entering. Jaden and Kyle entered a nearby structure, where Jaden fought a Reborn, before entering a mounted turret which he used to shoot down the TIE Bombers. With the pathway clear, the duo made their way to the entrance of Bast Castle, and infiltrated the lower levels by jumping into a garbage chute.Jaden and Kyle split up in order to infiltrate the castle, working their way from the lower levels occupied only by weak Imperial forces, to the upper echelons where the Disciples of Ragnos are. When Jaden overloaded a machine by feeding the energy it was producing back into it, part of the ceiling collapsed, knocking Kyle down a long pit. He managed to survive the fall, but Jaden was forced to go on alone while Kyle worked his way back up again.Fighting through the upper levels of Bast Castle, Jaden encountered many Reborn and Dark Jedi. After fighting through to the top level of the Castle, Jaden encountered old friend Rosh Penin, who had succumbed to the lure of the Dark Side and was working alongside Tavion to siphon the force energies of the castle. Jaden battles with Rosh and the Kothos Twins, eventually dispatching the Twins and disarming Rosh. Shortly after, Kyle arrived on the scene. However, Tavion disabled Jaden and Kyle with Force Lightning, used the Scepter of Ragnos along with Jaden's lightsaber to bring down the entire room around them and escaped with Rosh in tow. Thanks to Kyle's quick reaction, Jaden and Kyle were able to escape safely as well.Upon returning to the Jedi Academy, Jaden was promoted to the rank of Jedi Knight in light of his actions on Vjun. After building a new lightsaber to replace the one that was lost on Vjun, Jaden then set out to accomplish more missions.Jaden was then called back to the Academy and informed by Luke that he was to be part of a Jedi Strike team to prevent the Disciples of Ragnos from resurrecting Marka Ragnos on Korriban. Before Jaden could set out however, Kyle informed him that he had received a transmission from Rosh stating that he wished to return to the Jedi Order. Thus the two of them went to Taspir III in order to rescue Rosh from the cult.After fighting through the cult members that were in the base, Jaden finally reached Rosh and discovered him to be unharmed and walking freely. Jaden immediately assumed that it was a trap and his anger flared, readying his lightsaber for combat. Before he struck Rosh, Kyle sensed Jaden's situation and mentally warned him not to let his anger get the better of him.(At this point the story diverges according to the player's choice of action. Star Wars canon states that Jaden let Rosh live)Jaden eventually let go of his anger and forgave Rosh, deactivating his lightsaber. Upon seeing this, Alora, who had been observing from above, leaped down and struck Rosh, dismembering his left arm. Jaden then proceeded to engage Alora in combat and emerged victorious after a grueling battle. After Kyle arrived on the scene to tend to Rosh's safety, Jaden went on ahead to Korriban to join with the other Jedi.He fought his way through the legions of Disciples alongside his fellow Jedi and finally reached the tomb of Marka Ragnos where he confronted Tavion before she had revived Ragnos. Tavion fought with all the power of the Dark Side, even using the Scepter of Ragnos to feed off of its energies. Eventually however she was bested by Jaden, at which point she attempted to resurrect the spirit of Marka Ragnos who then possessed Tavion's body. After another prolonged duel, Jaden managed to destroy the Scepter, thus forcing Ragnos to leave Tavion's body. Tavion died shortly after due to her body not being able to withstand the corruption caused my Ragnos. Jaden then left the tomb and sealed it, meeting Luke and Kyle on the steps to the tomb, where Luke proclaimed Jaden to be a true Jedi Knight.MultiplayerJedi Academy built on the work done in Jedi Outcast, and included an online multiplayer component with five modes, including two completely new gametypes. All of Jedi Academy's multiplayer modes can be played in a bot match except for siege, which can only be played over a network with other humans.Multiplayer GametypesAll of these modes (with the exception of the Siege mode) are playable with bots.Multiplayer lets you play as fat Rodians with lightsabers. Awesome.Team FFA: The standard Team Deathmatch, exactly the same as standard FFA, but with teams.Duel: A one-on-one mode where two players would duel with only lightsabers and Force powers, no guns. If multiple people were in a room, whoever wins the duel continues playing, while the loser has to wait again for another turn.Power Duel: A variant of the duel mode, Power Duel saw a 2v1 setup, where two lesser powered players would attempt to take on one player with more Force and saber skills, attempting to eliminate him.Siege: A unique mode to Jedi Academy, siege is a class-based objective mode, effectively making it an independent beast from the rest of Jedi Academy's multiplayer modes which all use the same basic template. Siege allows you to choose from a variety of classes, each of which have unique weaponry and abilities, and only one of which can use a lightsaber. Your team must work to either complete or prevent the completion of a set of objectives throughout the map. When the attacking team achieves an objective, the defending team is pushed back to a new location, where they have a new objective to protect, meaning the game will generally change scenery over the course of the game.Capture the flag: A standard CTF variant. Flags touch return and your flag must be at your home base before you can score the enemie's flag.Multiplayer CharactersThe game included a large list of multiplayer character models, including the ability for you to import your single-player Jaden model. The full list is as follows:Jaden (customizable)Alora (two models)Bespin Wing GuardBoba FettChewbaccaChissCultistDesannGalak FyyarGranLannik RactoImperial OfficerImperial WorkerJan OrsJediJedi TrainerKyle KatarnLando CalrissianLuke SkywalkerMon MothmaMorgan KatarnNoghriPrisonerRax JorisRebel TrooperRebornNew RebornReborn MasterReeloRodianRosh PeninImperial SaboteurShadow TrooperSnowtrooperTIE PilotStormtrooperSwamptrooperTavion Axmis (two separate models, Jedi Outcast Outfit and Jedi Academy model)TrandoshanTusken RaiderUgnaughtWeequayMercenaryReborn TwinSystem RequirementsPC System RequirementsOS: Windows 2000, XP or VistaProcessor: Pentium II or Athlon 450 MHzMemory: 128 MBGraphics: 32 MB OpenGL compatibleDirectX®: 9.0aHard Drive: 1.3 GBSound: 16 bit Direct x 9.0aMultiplayer Requirements: Pentium II or Athlon 450MHzMac System RequirementsOS: 10.7.5 (Lion), 10.8.2 (Mountain Lion)Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo (Dual-Core), 2.2 GHzMemory: 4 GBGraphics: 256 MB, (NVidia): Geforce 8800, (ATI): Radeon HD 2600Hard Drive: 2 GBSupported Video cardsNVIDIA GeForce® 8800, 9400, 9600, GT 120, 320M, 330M, 640M, 650M, 660MX, 675MX, 680MXATI Radeon HD 2600, HD 3870, HD 4670, HD 4850, HD 5670, HD 5750, HD 5770, HD 5870, HD 6490, HD 6630, HD 6750, HD 6770, HD 6970Intel HD Graphics 3000,4000Unsupported Video cardsIntel Integrated GMA 950Intel Integrated x3100ATI RADEON HD 2400</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7574">Battle Engine Aquila</game><game id="4170">Command &amp; Conquer: Renegade</game><game id="7570">Enter the Matrix</game><game id="621">Doom II: Hell on Earth</game><game id="14819">Tron 2.0</game><game id="15509">Star Trek: Elite Force II</game><game id="2832">Tribes 2</game><game id="11187">Star Trek: Voyager - Elite Force</game><game id="12306">Star Trek: Voyager - Elite Force Expansion Pack</game><game id="13683">Quake 4</game><game id="27152">Serious Sam: The First Encounter</game><game id="41473">Blade Symphony</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2525271-box_swjkja.png</image></root>