<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16937</id><name>ESPN NBA Basketball 2004</name><description>OverviewESPN NBA Basketball (also known as NBA 2K4) is a realistic basketball game developed by Visual Concepts and published by Sega for the Xbox and PlayStation 2 on October 21, 2003. The fifth installment of the NBA 2K franchise, ESPN NBA Basketball covers a customizable 2003/2004 NBA season while continuing co-branding with the ESPN (Entertainment and Sports Programming Network).The two main additions to the franchise in this game is the IsoMotion control system, where players can make their characters perform special manuevers (such as spins and fakes) by moving the right analog stick, and 24/7 Mode, which builds upon the traditional player creation mode by requiring players to win special street matches (ranging from matches with unique rules to 1-on-1 matches against legendary players) to build upon their character's default stats (earning new cosmetic items along the way).The cover athlete of ESPN NBA Basketball is Allen Iverson of the Philadelphia 76ers. Despite being the cover athlete for the previous games of the series, this is the last game to feature him as the cover athlete.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="22">Basketball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13378">NBA Live 2003</game><game id="20819">NBA Live 09</game><game id="21687">NBA Live 08</game><game id="7437">NBA Live 07</game><game id="7206">NBA Live 06</game><game id="15029">NBA Live 2005</game><game id="9237">NBA Live 2004</game><game id="11411">NBA Live 2002</game><game id="8383">NBA Live 2001</game><game id="3771">NBA Live 2000</game><game id="2861">NBA Live 99</game><game id="15170">NBA Live 98</game><game id="1356">NBA Live 97</game><game id="20257">NBA Live 96</game><game id="3091">NBA Live 95</game><game id="3917">NBA Shootout '97</game><game id="21762">NBA ShootOut 2000</game><game id="12346">NBA Shootout 2004</game><game id="21744">NBA ShootOut 98</game><game id="21747">NBA ShootOut</game><game id="21770">NBA ShootOut 2001</game><game id="21773">NBA ShootOut 2003</game><game id="21774">NBA ShootOut 2002</game><game id="18984">NBA Courtside 2: Featuring Kobe Bryant</game><game id="20917">NBA 2K9</game><game id="23864">NBA '08</game><game id="10302">NBA Street Homecourt</game><game id="30719">ESPN College Hoops</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2222523-box_nba2k4.png</image></root>