<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17021</id><name>DJMAX Portable</name><description>DJ MAX Portable is a music/rhythm game from Korean developer Pentavision. It's the first entry in the now-popular Portable franchise, laying the foundation for some of the series' reoccurring artists, songs and bonuses. DJ MAX Portable was released in South Korea on January 16th, 2008 with the International version releasing in October of 2008.Game ModesDJ MAX Portable plays akin to games like Beatmania, Pop'n Music or Rock Band. Rectangular shaped (with the default Note effector) notes scroll down from the top of the screen onto a red line across the note field where the player must hit each corresponding note in time to the beat. DJ MAX Portable is comprised of 3 different control schemes, represented as follows.Rookie DJingRookie DJ Mode ControlsRookie DJing is essentially the 'beginner mode'. Uses only 4 inputs (Left, Up, Triangle and Circle) and consists of a 3-song set.Pro DJ Mode ControlsPro DJingPro DJing is the normal difficulty. Uses 6 inputs (Left, Up, Right, Square, Triangle and Circle) and consists of a 3-song set. Master DJingMaster DJ Mode ControlsMaster DJing is the advanced difficulty. Uses 8 inputs (Left, Up, Right, Square, Triangle, Circle and both triggers) and consists of a 3-song set. Master DJing is locked from the get-go, requiring several hours of playtime before unlocking.Freestyle DJingFreestyle Mode can be played at any of the 3 available difficulties and does not have a set song list. All the songs unlocked are available to play and combo points carry over from song to song. Certain unlockables, such as songs and UI skins, are unlocked after reaching a specific combo (ex.: 8000).Club ModeClub Mode is played at all 3 difficulty levels. Club mode consists of different 'clubs' that each have multiple set lists dedicated to one music genre or style. Difficulty varies from each set list, going from the easiest to the hardest. GalleryThe Gallery is the area in which you can view all the images, movies and Discs you've unlocked throughout playing the game. Ranking ChartRanking Chart is the area where you can view your high scores obtained in each mode. Main Menu optionsThe game opens on a Main Menu, the first option being "Portable". This is the main game. Here are the two other options: OSTThis is, essentially, a music player that allows you to listen to the game's soundtrack. Full version of songs can be unlocked within the game by achieving certain challenges. M/V ClipsThis allows you to watch the background animation/videos for each song in the game.GameplayEffectors, Notes and GearsDJ MAX Portable has an Effector Setting screen, available during song selection by pressing either trigger. Gears are the note track and Notes are the notes themselves. As you play through the game, hitting certain score targets or going past a certain combo score, you'll unlock new Gears and Notes which each have separate effects, like HP 20 or MAX 20%, for example. Effectors can also be added on top, throwing in changes like the scrolling speed, note fader, mirroring tracks, etc. CombosCombos have been a large part of DJ MAX games, going to lengths of having new tracks, images, music videos or OST tracks unlock as you hit a certain combo number. Combos carry over from song to song in regular gameplay modes that, in modes like Free Mode, can allow players to reach combos of 10,000, 80,000, 100,000 notes. Song List Song TitleComposerGenreVisualizer바람에게 부탁해 (Ask the Wind)Forte EscapeFantasy PopTako AshinEnd of the MoonlightForte EscapeTechno PopUSEnemy StormCrooveHardcoreJayExtreme Z4Forte EscapeBreak BeatKinysLight HousexxdbxxHappycoreECOLuv Flow3rd CoastRnB MediumAyamyNever SayND LeeJungle PopEyeheadOut LawCrooveNu SkoolDRay of IlluminatiESTiEuro DanceEter, Tari, ECOSave My DreamForte EscapeAcid DanceNapaSunny SideCrooveBright RnBTivOne The LovexxdbxxBeer HouseEyeheadLong VacationESTiSchool HouseTariCan We TalkForte EscapeAcid JazzAqualixJBGCrooveYellow HiphopEyeheadEternal Memory ~소녀의 꿈~M2UFantasy PopNGMasaiCrooveNew WaveECONB RangerM2UScream PunkNG, ECO, TariSINESTiDrum n BassRessFunky ChupsForte EscapeFunky ElectroEyeheadFever GJxxdbxxNu HnSEyeheadFuturismForte EscapeElectro FusionNG아침형 인간ND Lee80's 8bitD-myoAstro FightForte EscapeFunky StompECOFTR슈퍼꼬마 SupbabyElectro HouseTari  EterONND Lee2step SlowRBLet's go Baby3rd CoastHiphopMiyuJupiter DrivingxxdbxxTechno StockEyeheadElastic StarForte EscapeAcid HouseEyeheadKUDAGonZoTechno CoreNGBright DreamM2UAnime HouseTariCatch MeForte EscapeAlternative RockArmsRedCrooveRnBTari  Eter복수혈전 RevengeND LeeHardcoreECOPara-QForte EscapeDrum n BassECOTemptationS-TRO2step GarageEyeheadOblivionESTiDramatic TranceD-myoRock or DieNienHardcoreBS차이코프스키 피아노협주곡 1번(Tchaikovsky Piano Concerto No. 1)Wavfactory (Remix)ClassicECOTriple ZOEForte EscapeProgressive RockECOYa! Party!Forte EscapeCandy PopTari  EterMinimal LifeEarbreakerTechnoECO  TinaRoad of DeathNienHardcoreNecobusA.I.Forte EscapeTechnoKinysFear슈퍼꼬마 SupbabyDrum n BassTina레모네이드 (Lemonade)M2ULounge DnBTariChrono BreakersNienAni PopRessMemory of BeachM2UDance PopAppleDreadnoughtEarbreakerBig BeatECORiver FlowPlanetboomGroovy PopAyamyHamsinmakouTranceAcheSunny Side ~deepn'soul mix~Croove, Mixed by makouSoulTivOblivion ~Rockin' Night Style~ESTi, Mixed by NienFusion RockD-MyoSIN ~The Last Scene~ESTiDrum n BassRessBlytheM2USynth DnBDCnPCrooFEElectro FunkNone DJ MAX Portable International VersionLater after the game's original release, an Internation Version was released including a host of changes. The biggest change was the inclusion of Japanese and English language options, making the International Version of the game an incredibly import-friendly title. Some songs were also removed due to content deemed unfit for international audiences, biggest on in particular being the song "Dreadnought" due to it's video depiction of President George W. Bush.</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2951">beatmania</game><game id="8631">GuitarFreaks 3rdMIX &amp; DrumMania 2ndMIX</game><game id="254">Moero! Nekketsu Rhythm Damashii Osu! Tatakae! Ouendan 2</game><game id="20635">Rock Revolution</game><game id="22342">beatmania IIDX 13 DistorteD</game><game id="22343">beatmania IIDX 14 GOLD</game><game id="25421">Rock Band Unplugged</game><game id="30355">Hatsune Miku: Project DIVA 2nd</game><game id="23769">Hatsune Miku: Project DIVA</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8124/1287472-djmp1.jpg</image></root>