<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17043</id><name>Agatha Christie: And Then There Were None</name><description>OverviewAgatha Christie: And Then There Were None is a point and click adventure game based on the novel of the same name. It was developed by AWE Productions, Inc. It first was released on the PC, but later was released on the Wii.The North American version of the game came with the original Novel.The only major differences between the game and the novel are the inclusion on a new character, Patrick Narracott and multiple endings different then the novel's conclusion.The alternate ending of the game can be accessed after the main game has been completed.PlotThe game starts with 8 people travelling to the town of Sticklehaven. Each of them have been invited to stay at a mansion on Shipwreck Island. Upon arrival all 8 people meet up with the games playable character and the brother of the boatman, Patrick Narracott. Patrick's brother has been framed for murder and he thinks that by talking to the guests he will be able to clear his brothers name. But when they arrive a voice starts accusing everybody, except Patrick Narracott of murder. The boat is then discovered to have been sabotaged, so they are stuck on the island.Tensions build as the guests' shadowy pasts and hidden motives begin to unwind, leaving you, as Patrick Narracott to unravel the mystery, while staying alive, trapped on an island with a murderer.The player has no control of plot development until nearing the end of the game.GameplayAgatha Christie: And Then There Were None is a point and click adventure game that is played from a third-person perspective. It is divided into chapters, which are then divided into acts. The play will play through each act, and after triggering a certain event the game will move onto the next act. The developers have said nothing essential can be missed during the players progression throughout the game, although sections of the game can be skipped, and the player may avoid doing side quests if they wish.Most of the interactive parts of Agatha Christie: And Then There Were None are asking other guests questions, finding items, and combining items. The inventory system can hold up to 12 items.And Then There Were None features a journal system for helping keep track of side quests, and the main quests clues. It also lets you piece together the clues you have found. the journal will record everything needed to complete the game, including every conversation you have with the other people. The reason for putting in the journal system was so that the player didn't have to use resources outside of the game to solve the puzzles, such as a pen and paper, it could be done right in the game.Another vital feature of And Then There Were None is the suspicion meter, this meter measures the relationship with you and the other characters of the game. The meter was made to counteract the problem with other adventure games at the time where the player could go through another characters belongings in-front of them and that character would not care. The system adds negative consequences when the player does things the other characters see as inappropriate. When the meter beings it is at neutral for each character. Depending on where the meter is at for a character it will affect dialogue choices. If the suspicion meter falls on a character, the player can do certain tasks for the other character to redeem themselves.On the Wii, the remote controller is used to point and select objects, manipulate your inventory and is twisted to open doors.Voice CastNolan North (Uncharted Franchise, every other game in 2009) - Patrick NarracottGreg Ellis (Dragon Age Origins Awakening - Phillip LombardIan Ambercrombie (The Star Wars movie franchise) - Rogers / General MackenzieReceptionAnd Then There Were None has received massively varying reviews since it was released, reviews were from 2/10, up to 9/10 representing a very wide range of opinions on the game.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16965">Syberia</game><game id="2845">Gabriel Knight 3: Blood of the Sacred, Blood of the Damned</game><game id="8441">Sherlock Holmes: The Awakened</game><game id="22199">Laura Bow 2: The Dagger of Amon-Ra</game><game id="2539">Nancy Drew: Legend of the Crystal Skull</game><game id="4925">Murder!</game><game id="16710">Suspect</game><game id="7276">Pathologic</game><game id="22160">Laura Bow: Colonel's Bequest</game><game id="3942">Cruise for a Corpse</game><game id="17237">Crime Stories: From the Files of Martin Mystère</game><game id="6870">Sherlock Holmes: Secret of the Silver Earring</game><game id="29805">Nancy Drew: Warnings at Waverly Academy</game><game id="27449">Nancy Drew: Ransom of the Seven Ships</game><game id="35988">Nancy Drew: Trail of the Twister</game><game id="22610">Nancy Drew: The Haunting of Castle Malloy</game><game id="22388">Nancy Drew: The Phantom of Venice</game><game id="895">Nancy Drew: The White Wolf of Icicle Creek</game><game id="12583">Nancy Drew: The Creature of Kapu Cave</game><game id="7911">Nancy Drew: Danger by Design</game><game id="16040">Nancy Drew: Last Train to Blue Moon Canyon</game><game id="15904">Nancy Drew: Secret of the Old Clock</game><game id="17878">Nancy Drew: Curse of Blackmoor Manor</game><game id="3336">Nancy Drew: The Secret of Shadow Ranch</game><game id="19004">Nancy Drew: Danger on Deception Island</game><game id="8516">Nancy Drew: The Haunted Carousel</game><game id="18960">Nancy Drew: Ghost Dogs of Moon Lake</game><game id="19601">Nancy Drew: The Secret of the Scarlet Hand</game><game id="60">Nancy Drew: The Final Scene</game><game id="19223">Nancy Drew: Treasure in the Royal Tower</game><game id="2438">Nancy Drew: Message in a Haunted Mansion</game><game id="20280">Nancy Drew: Secrets Can Kill</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2757/206868-agatha_christie_and_then_there_where_none___front_cover.jpg</image></root>