<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17280</id><name>BioShock</name><description>OverviewNo Gods or Kings. Only Man.Bioshock is inspired by themes in Ayn Rand's novel Atlas Shrugged. At the time of it's release, Bioshock was lauded by critics for its peerless storytelling and fascinating story. To enhance the story beyond what is directly experienced by the player, Bioshock uses audio diaries. These diaries follow different characters through the rise and fall of the city of Rapture. At times, ghosts will also appear in the city showing very brief fragments of the actions of certain citizens of Rapture. Bioshock is also well known for not taking player control away during scripted events, allowing the player to experience literally everything through the eyes of the protagonist.The player does not directly see any of the coup of Rapture in BioShock, instead arriving sometime afterward in the year 1960, discovering a desolate city filled with insane, drug-addled citizens. The player hears about Rapture's golden era--and the events that led to its demise--through a series of audio logs that serve as diary entries for the past inhabitants of the city. Touted by 2K as an "FPS-RPG" and a " spiritual sequel" to Irrational's highly revered System Shock 2, it has gameplay similarities to both System Shock games as well as Deus Ex. It is possibly an indictment of the current gaming generation that BioShock has been lauded as such an original game, when in fact it copies so many structural elements from said predecessors' gameplay (such as non-linear player-character development, moral choice in plot progression, immersive setting and story).To its credit, however, BioShock is more of an exploration-focused first-person shooter that makes streamlined, simplified use of some of its predecessors' mechanics, such as the use of audio logs as a storytelling device, a hacking minigame (reminiscent of the classic puzzler Pipe Dream), and special abilities. While being primarily built on Unreal Engine 2.5, BioShock is also one of the first games to be produced using features from Epic's Unreal Engine 3 and appeared on both the Xbox 360 and the PC. On October 17, 2008 Bioshock was released for the PlayStation 3. This version of the game features a new 'Survivor' difficulty mode as well as other in-game add-on content. Downloadable "challenge rooms" are also available; these put the player in a race against the clock while working through brief, puzzle-oriented levels. The Playstation 3 version ships with Trophy Support, just as the Xbox 360 version, of course, contains Achievements.PlotWelcome to Rapture.Set in 1960, BioShock begins with a plane crash, with the player character, named Jack, being the only survivor. The player takes refuge in a lone lighthouse in the middle of the ocean. A bathysphere leads down into the bowels of the underwater city of Rapture. A message from the city's creator, Andrew Ryan, talks of his vision for Rapture, a utopia without ethical or moral barriers. However, from the looks of things, Ryan has failed in realizing his vision.A man named Atlas contacts Jack in the bathysphere and helps to lead him through the city, which is filled with genetically modified Splicers, Little Sisters, and their guardians, the Big Daddies. Atlas also tells Jack about ADAM, stem cells harvested to enhance the abilities of the human body. The abuse of ADAM has driven the Splicers mad and the material is what the Little Sisters constantly search for throughout Rapture.Atlas instructs Jack to kill the Little Sisters and take the ADAM from them in order to use special abilities called Plasmids. However, another ally in Rapture, Dr. Tenenbaum, tells Jack to save the Little Sisters and promises to reward him if he obeys.Atlas soon tells Jack of his wife and child, who are hiding from Splicers in a submarine. When Jack reaches them, however, Andrew Ryan destroys it, supposedly killing Atlas' family. Atlas, enraged, asks Jack to kill Andrew Ryan.Jack reaches Andrew Ryan, who reveals that Jack is actually his son and was born in Rapture two years prior. Genetic modification allowed for him to age rapidly. One of Rapture's pioneers, Frank Fontaine, "programmed" Jack to obey any order uttered with the phrase "Would you kindly", a phrase that Atlas has repeated many times. Jack was the one who crashed the plane and was brought to Rapture on purpose, with the goal of killing Andrew Ryan.Ryan orders Jack to kill him, using the phrase "Would you kindly." Forced to obey, Jack kills Ryan with a golf club. Shortly after, Atlas reveals himself to be Frank Fontaine and leaves Jack to die in the city. Dr. Tenenbaum saves him, though, and deactivates the "Would you kindly" trigger phrase control Fontaine has over him. Jack then proceeds to Olympus Heights and finds Lot 192 which reverses a heart stopping mental control Fontaine was attempting to kill Jack with. Tenenbaum then instructs Jack to don a Big Daddy suit so the Little Sisters can lead him to Fontaine. When he reaches him, Fontaine, pumped up by massive quantities of ADAM, has acquired almost superhuman abilities.Upon defeating Fontaine, three endings are possible. If the player rescues all the Little Sisters, the game ends with Jack and the Little Sisters leaving Rapture and the girls growing up to live their lives. If the player harvested two or more, but not all the Little Sisters, Jack kills the Little Sisters and takes their ADAM. If the player harvests all of the Little Sisters, the same ending is shown but with Tenenbaum's narration being angrier.WeaponsGunning it with a Big Daddy.The game features an array of traditional weapons that can be acquired throughout the game. The player carries all of the weapons at once, so all of the weapons are available at any time. Each weapon can be upgraded twice, using special kiosks called " Power to the People" machines. Each weapon can also carry three types of ammunition. The weapons in the game are as follows:Wrench: A simple melee weapon acquired at the beginning of the game.Pistol: A standard six-shooter, it is the first firearm acquired.Machine Gun: An automatic weapon that holds a large number of bullets.Shotgun: A close-range weapon that packs quite a punch.Grenade Launcher: A large weapon that can be upgraded to fire different kinds of explosives such as heat seeking rpgs.Chemical Thrower: A device that fires various substances like napalm, liquid nitrogen, and electrical gel.Crossbow: A long-range weapon best used against single opponents.Research Camera: This "weapon" allows the player to research various enemies and gain bonuses on damage and acquire various tonics.Weapon UpgradesWeapons are upgraded at Power To The People machines. The machine shuts down after one upgrade has been applied. The upgrades do not cost anything and also cause cosmetic changes to the weapons in addition to the listed effects. The wrench is the only weapon that cannot be upgraded at a Power To The People machine.PistolsIncreased DamageIncreased Clip SizeMachine GunIncreased DamageDecreased RecoilShotgunIncreased DamageIncreased Rate of FireGrenade LauncherIncreased DamageImmune to Damage self-fired GrenadesCrossbowBolt Breakage Chance ReducedIncreased DamageChemical ThrowerDecreased Chemical ConsumptionIncreased RangeKey CharactersThis is a list of the characters who either have major roles in Bioshock or encounter the player at some point in the story.Jack: The silent protagonist of Bioshock. He survives a plane crash and stumbles upon Rapture. Early on, Jack gains the ability to use Plasmids (his first one being the Electro Bolt).Andrew Ryan: The founder of Rapture. Andrew Ryan is an antagonist in Bioshock and he taunts Jack throughout the game.Atlas: Jack's mentor and guide in Rapture. Atlas gives Jack instructions and helps for a majority of the game.Tenenbaum: A German scientist who helped develop ADAM. She wishes to protect the Little Sisters and urges the player to do so.Doctor Steinman: A doctor who's gone insane with his obsession with perfection. He performs surgery on people to make them physically perfect, yet his insane obsession with his job drives him crazy and causes him to often perform unwanted surgeries on people to correct their "imperfections"; often these people die from being horribly mutilated.Peach Wilkins: A member of Frank Fontaine's smuggling business. He encounters Jack in Fontaine fisheries.Julie Langford: The scientist responsible for creating Arcadia, which is where she encounters Jack.Sander Cohen: An artist who runs Fort Frolic in Rapture. He also produces theatrical performances for the city. When he encounters Jack, he makes him take pictures of his four disciples after they've been killed and mounts them as part of a masterpiece.HackingHacking in BioShockPerforming hacks on various machines in the game can make things a lot easier. Everything from security bots to safes can be hacked. Hacking machines can help you evade security systems, supply you with hidden items, and give you discounts on items at vending machines.Hacking is done with the hacking mini-game, which is highly reminiscent of the classic computer game Pipe Mania (Pipe Dream in the United States). The goal is to successfully move fluid through a tube set on a grid of tiles from a starting location to and ending location, both of which are just outside the grid and, thus, not modifiable by the player. The player reveals pieces of the tube one at a time and may swaps tiles to continue the tube and keep the fluid moving. If the fluid is hindered in its progress either due to player error or by hitting certain tiles such as overload tiles and security tiles, the mini-game is failed and, depending on the gravity of the failure, security bots may be deployed to eliminate the player. An auto-hack tool can allow for a hack without using the mini-game. Hacking ability is greatly enhanced and simplified through the strategic equipment of certain engineering tonics. Also, the Winter Blast plasmid used on a machine just before hacking will slow the progress of the fluid considerably.Vending Machines / KiosksVarious vending machines and kiosks are found throughout the game. The different types are as follows:Circus of Value: A place to purchase a variety of items. Ammo, first aid kits, and EVE Hypos are all available here.Ammo Bandito: A vending machine that supplies ammunition.Gatherer's Garden: This vending machine allows you to use collected ADAM to purchase Plasmids and Tonics.Gene Bank: This machine allows you to customize your character, switching Plasmids and Tonics.Power to the People: This machine allows you customize weapons. Each individual machine can only be used once.U-Invent: This machine allows you to combine different items to create more helpful ones.Vita-ChambersVita-ChamberWhenever the player's HP reaches zero, they "respawn" at the nearest vita-chamber, large man-sized tubes scattered throughout Rapture. This only works with the main character Jack and the explanation to why it doesn't work for splicers is that it was in its testing phase when Rapture fell. Vita-Chambers serve as a checkpoint of sorts, even though the game can also be saved at any time through the start menu. Unlike traditional checkpoints, enemies injured or killed since reaching the Vita-Chamber will remain so when the player is respawned. However, weapon ammunition will remain at the same level as when the player was killed and the player is also given only a fraction of his maximum health. Since there is seemingly no penalty for using Vita-Chambers many players have bemoaned this design decision for making the game too easy — given enough time and patience, a player wielding only the wrench can slog his or her way through even the toughest battles.Moral ChoiceLittle SisterNear the beginning of the game, the player is given the choice of either harvesting the Little Sisters (effectively killing them) to gain a large amount of ADAM, or rescuing the Little Sisters for a significantly smaller amount of ADAM. Rescuing Little Sisters will, however, allow the player to access certain plasmids and Xbox 360 achievements unavailable through the "evil" method of play, and for each 3 that you rescue you will receive a gift from Dr. Tenenbaum. Depending on exactly how many Little Sisters you harvest or rescue, the game's ending is affected. If you save all the Little Sisters you get a one hundred point achievement.SecurityA hostile security camera. Hacked cameras have a green light instead of redJack has to deal with the security of Rapture throughout Bioshock. The security force includes cameras, turrets, and flying bots called Security Bots. All three of these can either be destroyed or hacked by Jack to get them on his side. Hacked turrets and bots will automatically fire on enemies, and hacked cameras will target enemies and trigger the alarm against them (which causes a wave of bots to come flying in and attack them). In addition, there is a Plasmid called "Security Bullseye" that, when thrown onto an enemy, will cause cameras and turrets to target said enemy.All three types of security forces can be temporarily disabled by zapping them with the Electro Bolt or Winter Blast plasmid. Turrets and bots must be hit with the Electro Bolt or Winter Blast before being hacked; security cameras do not.DevelopmentThe original story for Bioshock was drastically different. It centered around a deprogrammer, someone who forces a person to abandon religious or social group allegiances. The main character's mission was to rescue someone from a cult and adjust them mentally to a regular life. However, the plot underwent significant changes by the time development on the game was announced in 2004. At that time, the game's setting was changed to a World War II-era underground laboratory. When the laboratory was uncovered by scientists in the 21st century, they discovered an ecosystem formed by the experiments in the lab.The developers used a heavily modified version of the Unreal Engine 2.5. They also hired a water programmer and water artist to create the stunning water effects seen in the game. Bioshock also uses the Havok physics engine for more lifelike ragdoll effects.PlasmidsOpen bottle for PlasmidPlasmids change your character's genetic information and provide him with specific abilities. A substance called EVE is needed to use these abilities. EVE is found in hypodermic needles, called Hypos in the game. It is carried by the character and can be acquired from enemies and purchased from Circus of Value vending machines. Plasmids are both found throughout the game and bought from the Gatherer's Garden Kiosk. The Plasmids in the game are as follows:DescriptionADAM CostEVE CostDamageCyclone TrapPlaces a cyclone on the floor; used as a trap for enemiesUpgradeable to level 2level 1- 60level 2- 80level 1- 95level 2- 120variesElectro BoltShoots electricity at enemiesCan also be used to disable security cameras, turrets and botsUpgradeable to level 31- N/A2- 1103- 1201- 952- 1103- 1201- 4002- 16003- 8000EnrageTurns a Splicer near you against other Splicers6030N/AHipnotize Big DaddyTurns a Big Daddy into an allyN/AN/AN/AIncinerate!Shoots fire at enemies and sets them on flamesUpgradeable to level 31- N/A2- 1003- 1501- 482- 603- 721- 12 per sec2- 24 per sec3- 48 per secInsect SwarmLaunches a swarm of bees at enemiesUpgradeable to level 31- 602- 803- 1201- 482- 603- 721- 6 per sec2- 12 per sec3- 24 per secSecurity BullseyeAlerts security to the presence of your enemiesN/A30N/ATarget DummyCreates a decoy for your enemies to attack6048N/ATelekinesisAllows you to use moveable objects as weapons by flinging them through the airN/A15N/AWinter BlastShoots a blast of ice that freezes enemiesCan also be used on turrets, cameras and bots to slow down the water for better hackingUpgradeable to level 31- 602- 1003- 1501- 802- 903- 108N/ASonic BoomAllows the player to shoot a large blast of wind at enemiesOnly available with DLC or game patch 1.111- 902- 120variesNOTE: N/A means the item is either given to you by a Little Sisters or found somewhere on Rapture.TonicsCombat Tonics have a Green glowTonics upgrade your character and his abilities. There are three types of Tonics (Combat, Engineering and Physical) and they can either be found scattered throughout the Rapture or bought at Vending Machines.The Gene Bank machine is used to place tonics into whatever available slots you may have at the moment.Combat TonicsThese Tonics work on the player's offensive and defensive capabilities.TonicADAM CostArmored ShellMore 15% piercing and bludgeoning resistance20Armored Shell 2More 25% piercing and bludgeoning resistanceN/ADamage ResearchAdds 30% to research damage bonuses20Damage Research 2Adds 60% to research damage bonusesN/AElectric FleshMore 75% electric resistanceAdds 30% to electric damage20Electric Flesh 2More 100% electric resistanceAdds 60% to electric damage60Frozen FieldMore 15% cold resistanceAdds 10 points of cold damage to the Wrench and gives a 10% chance of freezing an enemy upon successful hitN/AFrozen Field 2More 30% cold resistanceAdds 20 points of cold damage to the Wrench and gives a 20% chance of freezing an enemy upon successful hit50Human InfernoMore 20% heat resistanceAdds 30% heat damage and causes enemies to take burning damage at a 30% higher rate20Human Inferno 2More 40% heat resistanceAdds 50% heat damage and causes enemies to take burning damage at a 50% higher rate50Photographer's EyeAdds 10% to all research photo scores20Photographer's Eye 2Adds 15% to all research photo scoresN/AStatic DischargeThe player emits an electric burst whenever struck by a melee attack, causing 50 points of electric damage and giving a 15% chance of shocking the enemyN/AStatic Discharge 2The player emits an electric burst whenever struck by a melee attack, causing 30 points of electric damage and giving a 25% chance of shocking the enemyN/AWrench JockeyAdds 350% to Wrench damage20Wrench Jockey 2Adds 550% to Wrench damageStacks with Wrench Jockey 1N/AWrench LurkerAdds 150% to Wrench damage on unware or electrical shocked enemiesQuiets the player's footsteps20Wrench Lurker 2Adds 200% to Wrench damage on unware or electrical shocked enemiesQuiets the player's footsteps50Machine BusterSlightly increases damage against security devicesOnly available with DLC or patch 1.11Machine Buster 2Significantly increases damage against security devicesOnly available with DLC or patch 1.11NOTE: N/A means the item is either given to you by a Little Sister, found somewhere on Rapture or gained through researching the Splicers with your Camera.Engineering TonicsEngineering Tonics have a Yellow glowThese Tonics improve the player's hacking ability and also his/her overall interaction with machines such as bots or turrets.TonicADAM CostAlarm ExpertMinus 2 alarm tiles when hacking20Alarm Expert 2Minus 4 alarm tiles when hackingN/AClever InventorInventing items requires 1 less of each component50Focused HackerMinus 2 overload tiles when hacking20Focused HackerMinus 4 overload tiles when hacking50Hacking ExpertMinus 1 alarm and 1 overload tile when hackingN/AHacking Expert 2Minus 2 alarm and 2 overload tiles when hacking50Prolific InventorGives 2x the items produced at a U-Invent machineN/ASafecrackerMinus 1 acceleration, 2 alarm and 2 overload tiles when hacking safes and combination locksPlus 3 resistor tiles when hacking safes and combination locksFlow speed reduced by 1/2 second per tileN/ASafecracker 2Minus 2 acceleration, 4 alarm and 4 overload tiles when hacking safes and combination locksPlus 6 resistor tiles when hacking safes and combination locksFlow speed reduced by 1 second per tileN/ASecurity ExpertMinus 1 acceleration, 2 alarm and 2 overload tiles when hacking security devicesPlus 1 resistor tile when hacking security devicesFlow speed reduced by 1/2 second per tile20Security Expert 2Minus 2 acceleration, 4 alarm and 4 overload tiles when hacking security devicesPlus 3 resistor tile when hacking security devicesFlow speed reduced by 1 second per tileN/AShorten AlarmsMinus 20 seconds on hostile security alarms' duration20Shorten Alarms 2Minus 40 seconds on hostile security alarms' duration50Speedy HackerFlow speed reduced by 1.5 seconds per tile when hacking20Speedy Hacker 2Flow speed reduced by 3 seconds per tile when hacking50Vending ExpertSlight reduction of prices on vending machinesOnly available with DLC or patch 1.11Vending Expert 2Significant reduction of prices on vending machinesOnly available with DLC or patch 1.11NOTE: N/A means the item is either given to you by a Little Sister, found somewhere on Rapture or gained through researching the Splicers with your camera.Physical TonicsPhysical Tonics have a Blue glowThese Tonics will interact with the player's physical and physiological properties, namely with his/her Health and EVE, making the player a tougher, harder enemy to kill.TonicADAM CostBloodlustPlayer gains small amounts of health with every successful blow to enemies with the WrenchN/ABooze HoundAlcohol restores a small amount of EVE, instead of draining itN/AEVE LinkFirst Aid kits give small amounts of EVE20EVE Link 2First Aid kits give significant amounts of EVE50Extra NutritionBandages, drinks and food give a little more health than usual20Extra Nutrition 2Bandages, drinks and food give significantly more health than usual40Extra Nutrition 3Bandages, drinks and food give a lot more health than usualN/AHacker's DelightEach successful hack gives small amounts of health and EVE20Hacker's Delight 2Each successful hack gives medium amounts of health and EVEN/AHacker's Delight 3Each successful hack gives large amounts of health and EVEN/AMedical ExpertFirst Aid kits give 20% more health20Medical Expert 2First Aid kits give 40% more health40Medical Expert 3First Aid kits give 60% more health60Natural CamouflageThe player becomes invisible after standing still for a period of timeMoving, using weapons and/or Plasmids nullify the effectN/AScroungerAllows the player to search both corpses and containers a second time, finding different loot this time aroundN/ASecurity EvasionTurrets and security cameras take 2 seconds longer to successfully track the player20Security Evasion 2Turrets and security cameras take 4 seconds longer to successfully track the player50Sport BoostSpeed increased by 10%Wrench swing speed increased by 25%N/ASport Boost 2Speed increased by 20%Wrench swing speed increased by 50%N/AEVE SaverAll Plasmids consume less EVE when activatedOnly available with DLC or patch 1.120NOTE: N/A means the item is either given to you by a Little Sister, found somewhere on Rapture or gained through researching the Splicers with your camera.SoundtrackThe original soundtrack for Bioshock was composed by Garry Schyman, and is comprised of 23 themes.12 of these themes can be downloaded for free at the 2K Games website.Here are the tracklists for both "editions".Downloadable VersionTrack No.Song TitleRunning Time01Bioshock Main Theme (the Ocean On His Shoulders)01.5602Welcome to Rapture01.5203Dr. Steinman01.0004The Docks00.5305The Dash00.3506Step Into My Gardens01.1007Dancers On a String01.2808Cohen's Masterpiece02.5309The Engine City01.0710Empty Houses01.4311This Is Where I Sleep01.2112All Spliced Up01.03Complete VersionTrack No.Song Title01Bioshock Main Theme (The Ocean On His Shoulders)02Andrew Ryan -- Tauchfahrt03Welcome to Rapture04Andrew Ryan -- Hahn05Dr. Steinman06Dr. Steinman -- Schönheit, Skalpell!07The Docks08Geist -- Schönheit Versprochen09The Dash10Atlas -- Little Sisters11Step Into My Gardens12Dr. Suchong -- Zorn-Versuch13Dancers On a String14Atlas -- Die Ganze Stadt Geht zum Teufel15Cohen's Masterpiece16Martin Finnegan -- der Eismann Kommt17The Engine City18Geist -- Total Verspliced19Empty Houses20Dr. Suchong -- Bewusstseinskontrolle21This Is Where They Sleep22Andrew Ryan -- Natur der Dinge23All Spliced Up"The Rapture EP"Back Cover for the Bioshock EPIncluded in the Bioshock limited edition version is an EP comprising of 3 tracks with song remixes by Moby and Oscar the Punk. Although the EP's official name is Bioshock EP, it quickly became known as "The Rapture EP".Track No.Song TitleRunning Time01Beyond the Sea03.1302God Bless the Child03.5503Wild Little Sisters03.56Downloadable content:Xbox 360:On Dec 4th, 2K games released a patch as well as Downloadable content for Xbox 360 fixing some known bugs and adding some features:Patch/title update:Challenge room DLCAdded widescreen option: Horizontal FOVFix for rare case where a partial cache is not clearedIncreased Atlas’ volume in GermanFix for GUI sounds not playing during heavy actionFix for not being able to take picture of Cobb in RecPossible fix for pauses or hangs when opening flash Bink moviesFix for switching difficulty breaking achievementFix for small texture streaming bugFix for rare hang when a lot of things are going on at onceDownloadable content:Added Disable Vita Chamber optionPlasmid Pack is included in this DLC (Machine Buster 1  2, Vending Expert 1  2, Sonic Boom 1  2, EVE Saver)100 point achievement called "Brass Balls". A player will gain it after beating the game on Hard without using any Vita Chambers . The player can always roll back to an earlier save if a Vita Chamber was used. The Vita Chamber Disabled option can be on or off as long as the player doesn't resurrect. (Note:this is currently untrue if a vita chamber is used with vita chambers turned on then it corrupts all saves in that play through, vita chambers must be turned off to get the achievement or you must make sure never to die.)PlayStation 3:The PlayStation 3 contains all the updates of the Xbox 360 version.20th November 2008 patch:Enables Add On Content functionality for the Challenge Rooms and New Game Plus (Add-On Content required to use this functionality)Fix for an issue where large blocky pixels would show up whenever viewing the Bouncer and Elite Bouncer variants of the Big Daddy. Also fixes various other texture pixelation including weapons.A battle in the challenge roomFix for an issue where white/discolored bars would show up at the right and bottom sides of the screen during the plane crash / water scene at the beginning of the game.Fix for an issue where Big Daddy would occasionally turn black after the player dies and is then resurrected.Fix for an issue where some fire particles would shrink every time they were retriggered.Fix for an issue where Big Daddies would gush abnormal amounts of blood after being killed by a critical hit while having more than 10% health (i.e., from another Big Daddy’s gun).Fix for an issue where the game would crash when PS button hit during hacking when vsync turned to offFix for a rare issue where the game would hang caused by a deadlock between the renderer, Havok, and the main game threads.Fix for an issue where reflective water would sometimes be rendered with incorrect fog colors.Fix for an issue where audio subtitles would occasionally not go away, even after the audio finished playing.Fix for an issue where menu sounds were too loud.Fix for an issue where the autosave message wasn’t localized.Fix for several issues where localized strings were too long. This includes the ‘Cannot Carry:’ message, ammo name lengths, weapon name lengths, and the Location in Fisheries ‘Upper Freezer’.Fix for an issue where the game would hang if the player dies while using a combination lock with the Vita-Chamber option off.The patch was released by accident on 13th of November 2008, but was quickly pulled off.Downloadable content - Challenge Rooms:The Challenge Rooms are three levels intended to test the knowledge and skills players have learned while playing through the main game.A Shocking Turn of Events – A Little Sister is trapped atop a Ferris wheel in an undisclosed location in Rapture. Using only the tools and environment around them, players must use their wits to create electricity to power the Ferris wheel and bring the Little Sister to safety.The I in Team – Using limited resources, and an even more limited arsenal, players must negotiate traps and find a way to defeat a Big Daddy using their wits instead of raw firepower.Worlds of Hurt – Step up and take on the most grueling challenge offered in the world of Rapture. Players must battle through eight rooms of Big Daddies, Splicers and the worst that Rapture has to offer. Accumulate Adam, build an arsenal of Plasmids, Tonics and Weaponry, and fight through to rescue the Little Sister.In addition to these three Challenge Rooms, two other additions are included in the package.The Official Premium BioShock Theme.A new feature, New Game Plus. This feature will give players who have beaten the main game the ability to start a new game with the character data (weapons, inventory, research, etc.) carried over from the end of the game (if you beat the game after the patch was installed) or from a saved game of your choosing (if you beat the game before the patch was installed). When you install the Add-On Content, a "New Game Plus" option will appear on the menu screen allowing you to use this feature.System RequirementsSystem Requirements As displayed on the back cover of the box.Minimum RequirementsCPU (Processor): Pentium 4 2.4GHz Single Core processorSystem RAM: 1GBGPU (Video Card): Direct X 9.0c compliant video card with 128MB RAM (NVIDIA 6600 or better/ATI X1300 or better, excluding ATI X1550).Sound Card: 100% direct X 9.0c compatible sound cardHDD (Hard Disc) space: 8GB free spaceRecommended RequirementsCPU (Processor): Intel Core 2 Duo processorSystem RAM: 2GBGPU (Video Card): DX9 - Direct X 9.0c compliant video card with 512MB RAM (NVIDIA GeForce 7900 GT or better) / DX10 - NVIDIA GeForce 8600 or betterSound Card: Sound Blaster X-Fi series (Optimized for use with Creative Labs EAX ADVANCED HD 4.0 or EAX ADVANCED HD 5.0 compatible sound cards)Xbox 360 Game InstallationWhen installed on an Xbox 360 console running the current versions of the NXE, Bioshock requires only 4.7 GB of HDD space. However, if the game was installed under the preliminary (first release) version of the NXE, Bioshock takes up 6.1 GB of space. This is true even if the user has since updated their Xbox 360's dashboard to a newer version. The only way to take advantage of the smaller size is to delete the old installation and re-install the game.ArtbookOn March 16, 2009 the Cult of Rapture website announced that a limited edition artbook for Bioshock called Breaking the Mold: Developer's Edition was available for pre-order on the 2K online store. The standard version can be found on the Cult of Rapture website for download as a PDF file.TriviaOriginally 2K Designed a Teleportation Plasmid that teleported the player out of danger, by marking a location that the player would teleport to when they used the plasmid, the plasmid was ultimately removed due to the fact that it could be used to break story events. A same sort of teleport plasmid did appear in Bioshock 2 as an Easter Egg, presumably based on the plasmid scrapped from Bioshock 1.Xbox 360 Games on DemandOn August 6, 2009, BioShock became available on the Xbox 360's Games on Demand service. It costs $19.99 or 1600 Microsoft Points.</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8870">System Shock 2</game><game id="17533">Deus Ex</game><game id="12098">Turning Point: Fall of Liberty</game><game id="21478">Cryostasis</game><game id="11725">S.T.A.L.K.E.R.: Shadow of Chernobyl</game><game id="7747">John Romero's Daikatana</game><game id="21256">Perfect Dark</game><game id="16508">Half-Life: Opposing Force</game><game id="21144">Singularity</game><game id="8105">OverBlood</game><game id="10157">Clive Barker's Undying</game><game id="4725">Metroid Prime 3: Corruption</game><game id="20333">Geist</game><game id="14782">Far Cry</game><game id="20465">Condemned 2: Bloodshot</game><game id="24898">Under Pressure</game><game id="20964">Metro 2033</game><game id="18678">Call of Cthulhu: Dark Corners of the Earth</game><game id="7276">Pathologic</game><game id="21151">Hydrophobia</game><game id="21119">Wolfenstein</game><game id="16372">Prey</game><game id="33394">The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim</game><game id="35888">Hard Reset</game><game id="14180">Project Firestart</game><game id="35850">Dishonored</game><game id="28006">Okamiden</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/6899/401569-bioshock_cover_edited.jpg</image></root>