<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17293</id><name>Alien Shooter</name><description>OverviewAlien Shooter is an isometric shooter which was developed and published by Sigma Team for the PC platform.DLCThere were two expansion packs created for Alien Shooter.Alien Shooter - Fight For LifeFight For LifeAlien Shooter - Fight for Life takes place one year after the aliens landed on Earth. The aliens are trying to destroy a facility in which a virus was developed to help the human race survive. The virus must be saved in order to also save the human race.Alien Shooter - Fight for Life new features:Five new missionsNew storylineLarger amounts of enemiesAlien Shooter - The ExperimentThe ExperimentIn Alien Shooter - The Experiment the alien race has not only attacked Earth, but taken half of it over. The people of Earth must hide in fortified living quarters. The top scientists of Earth have created a new race of monsters to attack the invading aliens.Alien Shooter - The Experiment new features:Five new missionsNew monster typesA new boss type monsterNew musicNew in-game objectsSelectable difficulty levelsOther VersionsAlien Shooter: RevisitedAlien Shooter: RevisitedOn April 15, 2009 a remake of the Alien Shooter was created called Alien Shooter: Revisited. The game features new levels, new weapons, enhanced graphics and more. Alien Shooter: Revisited was also released on the Steam platform on May 27, 2009.Digital DistributionAlien Shooter and its expansions was re-released by Good Old Games as "Alien Shooter Expansions". It contains the main game (Alien Shooter) and its two expansions (Fight for Life and The Experiment) for $4.00 (at normal non/sales price) with compatibility  support for Windows XP, Vista, and 7 for both 32 and 64-bit.It can also be purchased on Steam for $5 (normal non/sales price) without the expansions (which are not available as of this writing. Revisited and Alien Shooter 2 are available on Steam however).PC System RequirementsAlien Shooter/fight For Life/the ExperimentPentium II 400 MHz processor or betterDirect3D compatible 3D graphics W/ 16 MB or more64 MB RAM or higherDirectSound compatible sound cardAlien shooter: Revisited1.7 GHz CPU or betternVidia GeForce2 / ATI Radeon 8500 video card with 64MB video memory or better512 MB RAMDirectSound compatible sound card</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9203">Shadowgrounds</game><game id="29464">Dysnomia</game><game id="32098">Alien Swarm</game><game id="17722">Shadowgrounds Survivor</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/13692/1245405-udklip.png</image></root>