<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>173</id><name>Far Cry: Instincts - Predator</name><description>OverviewFar Cry Instincts Predator is a slightly upgraded port of the Xbox Game "Far Cry Instincts" and "Far Cry Instincts: Evolution". It includes both single player campaigns and all the multiplayer and map editing improvements from Evolution. While the "Far Cry" name may indicate that it is a console version of the hit PC game "Far Cry", the console games are more of a re-interpretation and have a much different design and feel than the original PC game. In general, the graphics and textures are more Xbox than 360 since its pretty much a straight port of the Xbox game. The graphics will look smoother and the draw distance and pop-in are certainly better but it won't compare to other 360 shooters in terms of graphics.GameplayUnlike a typical shooter Far Cry Instincts focuses more on a variety of combat, melee and super human "feral" abilities that you gain along the way. These feral abilities require adrenaline to use though, which are gained in several ways including taking pain, resting using a ration or by remaining close to an enemy.However, despite being a focus on melee and super abilities, there is still gun play, with the ability to dual wield some guns, such as sub machine guns. Additionally, the player can set traps for the enemies. Also, Jack can drive a wide variety of vehicles, in which he can shoot from while driving.WeaponsButterfly Knife9mm Auto (pistol)9mm (pistol)HandgunShotgunMP5P90CarbineAssault RifleMachine GunRecon RifleSniper RifleRocket LauncherHand GrenadeMortar Stationary WeaponFC Stationary WeaponBlowgunPipe BombMolotov CocktailTrapsTree branch with a wooden stick, which can be pulled back and then releasedClaymore minesFeral AbilitiesFeral Attack- slashing attack that will instantly kill an enemyFeral Sense (smell and vision)- enemies are highlighted, and blood and fear leave odor trailsFeral Speed- greatly increases Jack's speed, and allows for long distance jumpsFeral Strength- Jack's strength is highly increasedFeral Climb- allows Jack to perceive climbable paths on cliffs or trees that would be otherwise inaccessibleVehiclesRMV (Recon Medium Vehicle)Patrol BoatInflatable BoatGliderATV (all-terrain vehicle)Hovercraft (allows for travel over any surface)Water ScooterPirate BoatMilitary Transport TruckLevelsTrainingBeachNativeRiverRain ForestMinesCliffsSub-Aquatic FacilityDead MarshesWastelandBlack ForestPirate Enclave: Part 1Pirate Enclave: Part 2Pirate Enclave: Part 3Shanty TownShanty Town EscapeRefinery AssaultCanopy ForestRebel Fortress</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7747">John Romero's Daikatana</game><game id="11757">Crysis</game><game id="21912">Planetside: Core Combat</game><game id="21549">White Gold: War in Paradise</game><game id="13290">Far Cry: Instincts</game><game id="21524">Warhound</game><game id="8197">Boiling Point: Road to Hell</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2179477-box_fcip.png</image></root>