<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17438</id><name>MechAssault</name><description>OverviewWith an extensive single player campaign set in the Battletech universe and a robust multiplayer component, MechAssault established itself as one of the first hit releases of the original Xbox console. MechAssault was one of the Xbox's most successful online games, as well as one of its first, allowing players to go toe-to-toe in large scale, fast-paced mech combat.GameplayA Mad Cat is madcatting it up by this ship.Unlike previous MechWarrior games, MechAssault puts the camera behind the player's mech instead of within the cockpit, allowing for a wider field of view while simplifying gameplay, which represented a fairly significant departure. Most mechs have three offensive weapons and a single, unique defensive weapon (some smaller mechs only have two offensive weapons, and various mechs do not have a defensive weapon at all). Offensive weapons come in three flavors: energy, ballistic, and missile. Defensive weapons range from jump jets to cloaking to a flare which guides incoming missiles away from your mech. Since no two mechs are alike, MechAssault allows plenty of different gameplay styles due to the unique weapon loadouts of each mech.CampaignIn Campaign, the player takes on the role of a nameless MechWarrior whose objective is to stop the Word of Blake from destroying the planet of Helios. The player will "unlock" various mechs throughout campaign, allowing the option to choose different mechs with different playstyles to complete each mission. Once campaign mode is completed, the Ragnarok and Ymir mechs are unlocked for multiplayer.MultiplayerWhile mech customization is somewhat limited, MechAssault provides players with 21 different mechs in total, many of which have the same chassis but unique weapon load outs. The variety of different vehicles, as well as five separate multiplayer game types, gave MechAssault the hardiness to stay as one of the most popular Xbox Live-enabled games in the platform's history.Multiplayer Maps:River CityColiseumIcepackArea 51FrostyThe JunkyardSmug robot.Hell's Kitchen (downloadable content)Stone Cold (downloadable content)Desert Storm (downloadable content)Midtown Mayhem (downloadable content)Jotenheim (downloadable content)Secret Outpost (downloadable content)Magma Fields (downloadable content)City Under Siege (downloadable content)Multiplayer Game Modes:Grinder: a mode that unleashes continuous waves of enemy AI mechs that increase in strength and number with each cycle. Can be played co-operatively or competitively on a single Xbox only.Destruction: typical deathmatch or team deathmatch modes -- the player or team with the highest score at the end of the match wins. Can be played online or locally.Capture the Flag: typical CTF mode found in numerous other games. Get the enemy flag, bring it back to base. Can be played online or locally.Last Man Standing: has the same rules as Destruction except each player only has one life. Can be played with or without teams, online or locally.Not It!: a game mode in which players take turns being "it" by killing the current player that is "it." Free-for-all only game mode that can be played online of off.Giant Killers: (downloadable content) a unique gametype in which numerous Elementals are pitted against a single giant mech. The player who brings down the giant is the giant for the next round.Scout Match: (downloadable content) similar to deathmatch except players are limited to light class mechs. Can be played with or without teams.Skirmish: (downloadable content) similar to deathmatch except players are limited to light and medium class mechs. Can be played with or without teams.Check It: (downloadable content) team compete to capture the most outposts scattered around the map. The team with the most outposts at the end of the match wins.Take It: (downloadable content) teams compete for the other's data core. Attempt to take the other's team's core while defending your own.MechsULLERUller / Kit FoxThe Uller is extremely versatile and touts a potent arsenal of weapons that provide striking power at all ranges. It is fast, very well armored, and makes a great reconnaissance Mech.Class: Light BattleMechTonnage: 30Speed: 40 mphOffensive Weapons: Pulse Laser, Crossbow MissilesDefensive/Special: Jump Jets, ChaffAlternate Chassis: Kit FoxCORVUSCorvus / RavenTied for the fastest Mech in the game, the Corvus sacrifices armor and firepower for pure speed and maneuverability.Class: Light BattleMechTonnage: 35Speed: 45 mphOffensive Weapons: Pulse Laser, AutocannonDefensive/Special: Jump Jets, Target JammingAlternate Chassis: RavenOWENSOwens / HackmanThe Owens has become a staple for front-line regiments. It’s lightly armored, but fast, and can carry all, Inner Sphere electronic components. It rarely engages an enemy directly but uses its superior electronics and LRMs to provide support for heavier Mechs.Class: Light BattleMechTonnage: 35Speed: 45 mphOffensive Weapons: Machine Gun, Crossbow MissilesDefensive/Special: Null SignatureAlternate Chassis: HackmanCOUGARCougar / PumaTon for ton, the Cougar is probably the best Mech out there. With its low profile and high speed, it’s very hard to hit and has a powerful weapons package for its sizeClass: Light BattleMechTonnage: 35Speed: 40 mphOffensive Weapons: Pulse Laser, Autocannon, Javelin MissilesDefensive/Special: Jump JetsAlternate Chassis: PumaUZIELUziel / BelialThe Uziel combine maneuverability with firepower and decent armor; it is a good performer in any role. With its speed and jump jets, it’s ideal for hit-and-hide tactics.Class: MediumBattleMechTonnage: 50Speed: 35 mphOffensive Weapons: PPC, Machine Gun, Crossbow MissilesDefensive/Special: Jump Jets, Target JammingAlternate Chassis: BelialVULTUREVulture / Mad DogThe Vulture is aptly named for its hunched shoulders, protruding head, and bird-like legs Its lower-torso Omni slot add to its versatility, and its huge twin missile racks can carry more missiles than any other Mech. It is very good in a fire support role.Class: Medium BattleMechTonnage: 60Speed: 30 mphOffensive Weapons: Laser, Machine Gun, Javelin MissilesDefensive/Special: ChaffAlternate Chassis: Mad DogCATAPULTCatapult / BowmanSlow but extremely rugged, the Catapult is best used as a standoff thread where it can use it long-range missile racks. It is designed for second-line defense but with strong offensive capabilities.Class: Medium BattleMechTonnage: 65Speed: 25 mphOffensive Weapons: Pulse Laser, Javelin MissilesDefensive/Special: Jump Jets, Target JammingAlternate Chassis: BowmanTHORThor / SummonerThe Thor offers mobility and short- to medium-range capability. It successfully blends firepower and maneuverability, and it can dish out a lot of damage in any terrain.Class: Heavy BattleMechTonnage: 70Speed: 30 mphOffensive Weapons: Laser, Machine Gun, Crossbow MissilesDefensive/Special: Jump JetsAlternate Chassis: SummonerHELLBRINGERHellbringer / LokiSimilar in tonnage, maneuverability, and profile to the Thor, the Hellbringer has a dirty little trick that allows it to overheat enemy Mechs with its flamethrower while still packing enough firepower to take out enemies from long-range.Class: Heavy BattleMechTonnage: 70Speed: 30 mphOffensive Weapons: Flamethrower, Autocannon, Javelin MissilesDefensive/Special: Jump JetsAlternate Chassis: LokiMAD CATMad Cat / TimberwolfThe Mad Cat was the first Clan 'Mech to appear in the Inner Sphere. It also has been the most used. It offers an array of weapons but is particularly lethal with its missile packs.Class: Assault BattleMechTonnage: 75Speed: 20 mphOffensive Weapons: PPC, Machine Gun, Javelin MissilesDefensive/Special: Target JammingAlternate Chassis: TimberwolfATLASAtlas / PrometheusThe sight of an Atlas still makes even the most experienced MechWarrior break out in hives. The head, torso, and weaponry create a perfect combination of function and fear factor. It is built to inflict a lot of damage on its enemies.Class: Assault BattleMechTonnage: 100Speed: 20 mphOffensive Weapons: Pulse Laser, Autocannon, Javelin MissilesDefensive/Special: ChaffAlternate Chassis: PrometheusRAGNAROKRagnarok / YmirThe ultimate combination of armor and firepower, the Ragnarok’s unstoppable Lava Cannon and quickly-recharging damage shield allow this massive Mech to burn through enemies like butter.Class: Assault BattleMechTonnage: 100Speed: 20 mphOffensive Weapons: PPC, Javelin Missiles, Lava CannonDefensive/Special: Damage ShieldAlternate Chassis: YmirELEMENTALElemental PowerArmorMore a suit of PowerArmor than a Mech, the Elemental is extremely weak by itself, but in numbers can take down even the largest of enemy behemoths.Class: PowerArmorTonnage: 5Speed: 15 mphOffensive Weapons: Pulse Laser, Crossbow MissilesDefensive/Special: Jump JetsAlternate Chassis: NoneOther Info1-8 playersSystem Link compatibleXbox Live features- Online Multiplayer, Friends support, Downloadable Content, Voice ChatDolby Digital</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17041">MechWarrior 2: Mercenaries</game><game id="19719">Chromehounds</game><game id="11350">Zone of the Enders</game><game id="17302">War World: Tactical Combat</game><game id="14084">TransFormers</game><game id="13461">Ultrabots</game><game id="9122">Front Mission Online</game><game id="13569">Heavy Gear II</game><game id="4602">10six Online</game><game id="25296">Lore: Aftermath</game><game id="25684">Murakumo: Renegade Mech Pursuit</game><game id="26008">Front Mission Evolved</game><game id="772">Outwars</game><game id="6186">Gungriffon Blaze</game><game id="34304">Iron Brigade</game><game id="34412">Hawken</game><game id="7531">Shattered Steel</game><game id="21238">Metal Wolf Chaos</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2276011-box_mecha.png</image></root>