<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17491</id><name>Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six 3: Black Arrow</name><description>Multiplayer Black Arrow's online multiplayer was very popular during its time in the spotlight. Fans of the original                                    Rainbow Six 3 did not need to worry about the sequel changing the simple and satisfying formula. It is because of this that the                                expansion Black Arrow was not critically acclaimed as its predecessor. However, that did not deter new gamers from flocking to the series. Clan match functionality and new multiplayer modes were thought of icing on the cake by true fans of the series. Others viewed these add-ons as too simple and rushed. Black Arrow's core fanbase was more than pleased and newcomers were introduced to a great modern military shooter. The most popular multiplayer game mode was Team Survival.  This mode pitted the Red team against the Green team, giving each player only one life and no respawns. The game supported the standard 16 players, however a full 16 player server made the action a bit too frenetic for some. In Black Arrow, a 12 player server was the sweet spot for most maps and game modes. The most popular maps included Cafe, Airport, Back Alleys, Garage, Killhouse, Office Complex, Presidio, and Subway. Some hosts preferred to cycle through these maps occasionally to switch up the gameplay experience. The beauty of Black Arrow was the                              re-playability of the maps. Game rounds were very satisfying and the maps stayed fresh when playing with skilled friends and opponents.                               Voice chat aided in communication and teamwork, and hosts would often kick players without                             microphones. The two main strategies on many maps were rushing straight to the opponent's base, or finding a good defensive position to                                     camp in. Thankfully the maps were generally small to medium in size and hosts refrained from setting long round times. A good host who booted disruptive players and disabled game options that complicated gameplay added to the experience.Note:The original Rainbow Six 3 had a glitch called "Open Leaning." This created an invisible wall in front of the player every time he / she                            leaned. Thankfully, Black Arrow did not have this glitch, but there were still ways to escape the                           geometry of a map and shoot players from long distances.       The most popular gun of choice was the                                  G3A3 or other guns with similar attributes. Experienced players would journey off and use new weapons but a majority of players will usually stick with their favorite automatic rifle. Asking players what the best gun to use, they would generally respond with these,                          AK47,                         M16,                        FAMAS, G3A3, and                       MP5.Popular secondary weapons included                      grenades or                     remote mines. Grenades are vital for both offensive and defensive tactics, while a  more experienced player could use a remote mine to create a tactical advantage. Grenades in Black Arrow can be cooked forever, until release. This adds another layer of control to the game. Recently, the                                   Rainbow Six series has drastically changed its presentation by adding new gameplay mechanics. While these changes have drawn in many new gamers to the series, many would prefer a return to the roots of previous games in the franchise.Multiplayer Maps Garage Cafe Presidio Moroccan Kesba Ferry Boat Nuclear Reactor Old Ruins  Subway Station Village (Free) Lockdown Boot Camp (Free) Killhouse Petroleum Winter Lodge Office Complex Pumping Station Winter Base Harbour Warehouse Prison Agora Airport Back Alleys Castle Hotel Military Base Observatory Peaks Rocket Facility Streets of Milan Winter LodgeWeapons and Equipment                    MAC 11/9 MP5A4 MP5SD5                   P90                  SR-2                 TMP                UMP AK-47               AUG FAMAS G2              G36C G3A3 GALIL ARM L85A1 M16A2             M4            TAR-21           M249 M60E4          M1         USAS-12 AW COVERT        DRAGUNOV       PSG-1 92FS D.EAGLE MAC 11/9 (Secondary: shorter clip)      MK23 SR-2 (Secondary: shorter scope) USP     M203 Grenade Launcher M203 CS (teargas grenade launcher) M203 Smoke Grenade Launcher    Flashbang Grenade Frag Grenade M34WP Grenade   Smoke Grenade Tear Gas Grenade Breaching Charge Claymore Mine Remote Mine  Gas Mask</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11339">Counter-Strike: Source</game><game id="12934">Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon 2 - 2007: First Contact</game><game id="18162">Team Fortress 2</game><game id="4561">Team Fortress Classic</game><game id="20777">Call of Duty: World at War</game><game id="2347">Call of Duty 2</game><game id="7524">Call of Duty 3</game><game id="20676">SOCOM: U.S. Navy SEALs - Confrontation</game><game id="7747">John Romero's Daikatana</game><game id="20655">Battlefield: Bad Company</game><game id="9993">Halo 3</game><game id="8732">Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon</game><game id="21527">Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon 2: Summit Strike</game><game id="1576">Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon: Jungle Storm</game><game id="8017">Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon: Island Thunder</game><game id="22948">Specnaz: Project Wolf</game><game id="7334">Crossfire</game><game id="24713">Modern Warfare 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2360879-box_rs3ba.png</image></root>