<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>175</id><name>The Journeyman Project: Pegasus Prime</name><description>StoryThe game's story is almost precisely a remake of the original Journeyman Project, and its later edition The Journeyman Project: TURBO!.Full-Motion VideoThe gameplay added extensive use of full-motion video with live action, which was sparsely used in the first game, it became the series defining point in the second game, The Journeyman Protect 2: Buried In Time. The successively higher quality acting and voice work would become the source of the relative success of the final game in the series, The Journeyman Project 3: Legacy of Time.CollectibilityPoor marketing and limited platform availability ( Playstation and Pippin in Japan, and only Power Macintosh in the USA) would doom the game to obscurity and relegate it to diamond-in-the-rough territory. Any copy is highly valued by collectors and fans, and a sealed copy on eBay can gain upwards of $35. Extremely limited numbers of the Japanese PSX edition were ever made, which make those along with the DVD version of The Journeyman Project 3: Legacy of Time and the box set of The Journeyman Project Trilogy fetch a high price on internet auction sites. Presto Studios made plans to port the game to the PlayStation (with publisher Acclaim Entertainment) and Sega Saturn in the U.S., but these versions were never released.Due to rights and compatibility issues, the first game in the series, along with plus Pegasus Prime, were not released digitally, but a trailer in 2013 hinted at upcoming ports for Windows and Mac OS X. Support had also been added in ScummVM for the old PowerPC CD-ROM.SoundtrackIn December 2012, over 15 years after the original release, The Original Soundtrack album by Geno Andrews, Jack Harris, and Bob Stewart was released.No.Track TitleLength (31:46)1.Through the Roof1:052.The Year 23181:403.Anticipation0:294.Good Morning, Caldoria0:335.4D Warmup0:116.Phantom Blue Orchestra1:027.Acoustic Clouds0:568.Power Tower Funk0:409.Scrapyard Gearhythms0:3910.Industrial Nuage1:1111.Elevator Ride0:3312.Back to the Grind0:2413.Temporal Quartet0:4914.Alert Status Alpha0:2215.Into the Time Stream1:0216.Historical Log0:4817.Another World1:0418.Mining Colony0:3819."Out of my way, human"0:2220.Lost Below0:3921.Race Against Time2:5322.All Clear for Takeoff0:5423.Coprates Minor0:5224."I've been expecting you"0:0825.Poisoned0:3126.Organic Walls0:2627.The Other Side / Creature Feature1:1528."You are no match for me"0:1629.Plasma Rock1:2330.Resolution0:2631.Caldoria Heights0:4032.Mission Accomplished0:4933.The Journeyman Fanfare2:1734.Ripples on the Horizon0:2935.Pegasus Forever3:20</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18742">Myst III: Exile</game><game id="6125">Return to Zork</game><game id="3970">Myst</game><game id="16230">Riven: The Sequel to Myst</game><game id="7863">Myst IV: Revelation</game><game id="1961">Myst V: End of Ages</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/19013/706784-pegasusprime.jpg</image></root>