<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17533</id><name>Deus Ex</name><description>OverviewJ.C. Denton, Deus ExDeveloped by Ion Storm Austin, and released in 2000 by Eidos Interactive, Deus Ex is a first-person shooter role-playing hybrid. In Deus Ex, players take on the role of JC Denton, a nano-augmented agent of UNATCO (the United Nations Anti-Terrorist Coalition). JC is charged with investigating a terrorist group known as the NSF (National Secessionist Force). Though, throughout the course of the story, JC finds himself dropped into a larger ideological war involving the Illuminati, Majestic-12, and other secret organizations. The future path of humanity is at stake and the game culminates with the player making the ultimate determination of mankind's future by choosing one of three possible scenarios.GameplayDeus Ex plays as a hybrid between a shooter and an RPG. As JC Denton, players can make choices that ultimately alter the course of the main story, both in dialogue and through game actions. The RPG/shooter gameplay supports many different play styles; from run-and-gun, to stealth, to subterfuge. For example, a building might be guarded by robots. Players can choose to sneak past the robots as they patrol in circuit, lock-pick a nearby door to bypass the area the robots patrol, or, of course, go in guns blazing. The same set up might even include an opportunity for both stealth and action-based tactics. Again, for example, the player could stealthily hack gun turrets in order to enter a gun fight with added backup.As in many RPGs, players can kill almost any non-critical character in the game. Some major characters may live or die based entirely on the player's decisions. Both of these major RPG features can lead to unique dialogue options, or change future mission objectives.Improving Your CharacterA large part of Deus Ex revolves around the ability to improve JC's abilities. There are three notable ways to do this: Augmentation Canisters, Upgrade Canisters, and Skill Points.Augmentation and Upgrade CanistersAugmentation selection screenThe player can improve Denton's abilities via bio-mechanical augmentation. This is done by collecting canisters and interacting with a medical bot. Denton's body contains a set number of augmentation slots. Each slot may only hold a single canister--containing 2 pre-determined augmentations--and only one of the augmentations can be activated at a time, forcing the player to decide between the two bonuses.The augmentation slots are as follows:Head AugmentationsEye AugmentationsSubdermal AugmentationsTorso AugmentationsArm AugmentationsLeg AugmentationsSkill PointsSkill Upgrade ScreenAt the start of each game, the player is allotted a set number of points to be spent on various skills. By completing mission objectives (including sub-goals or specific game actions) as well as through exploration, the player gains additional skill points to spend later.Every skill has 4 levels of progression: Untrained, Trained, Advanced, and Master. The trainable skills are as follows:Computer - Allows hacking and manipulation of security consoles and computers.Electronics - Reduces the number of multi-tools required for any non-computer hack.Deus Ex Limb based health system in the PC version of the gameEnvironmental Training - Allows the player to better survive environmental hazards and make better use of certain equipment such as re-breathers, hazard suits and body armor.Lock-picking - Reduces the number of lock picks required when lock-picking.Medicine - Increases the amount of health regained when using health kits.Swimming - Increases the player's swimming speed and the time they can spend underwater.Weapons: Demolition (various grenade types.) - Increases damage and accuracy of small explosives. Also makes grenades placed as mines easier to disarm.Weapons: Heavy (Rocket launchers, etc.) - Increases damage and accuracy with heavy weapons. Also shortens reload time and movement penalty when wielding a heavy weapon.Weapons: Low-Tech (Swords, knives, etc.) - Increases damage and accuracy with melee weapons.Weapons: Pistol (Hand guns, etc) - Increases damage and accuracy, while shortening reload times.Weapons: Rifle (Sniper rifles, machine guns, etc.) - Reduces reload time while increasing accuracy and damage. A master-level sniper shot can destroy a camera in a single hit.Weapons ListWeapon / Icon / Inventory spaceDescription / Stats / Possible upgradesFlamethrowerA portable flamethrower which utilizes napalm to incinerate enemies.Weapon type: HeavyBase damage: 3 (fires bursts of 7 units of napalm additional burning damage)Accuracy: 55%ROF: very fastClip size: 100Max ammo: 400Upgrades acceptedRange, Reload speedGuided explosive Projectile (GEP) gunA rocket launcher that can fire powerful unguided / heat seeking rockets.Weapon type: HeavyBase damage: 300Accuracy: 75%ROF: very slowClip size: 1Max ammo: 20HE rockets are effective against anything destructible. It has a small splash damage area.WP rockets have a wide splash damage area and sets anything flammable on fire.Upgrades acceptedRange, Reload speedScopeLight Antitank Weapon (LAW)A disposable, anti-armor rocket launcher with a large splash damage area.Weapon type: HeavyBase damage: 100Accuracy: 70%Clip size: Single UsePlasma RifleA devastating experimental weapon that fires three plasma projectiles at once.Effective against slow moving targets.Weapon type: HeavyBase damage: 105 (3 projectiles with 35 damage each)Accuracy: 70%ROF: mediumClip size: 12Max ammo: 84Upgrades acceptedAccuracy, Range, Recoil, Clip, Reload speedLaser sight, ScopePistolA standard government issue 10mm pistol.Weapon type: PistolBase damage: 14Accuracy: 65%ROF: mediumClip size: 6Max ammo: 150Upgrades acceptedAccuracy, Range Recoil, Reload speed, ClipLaser sight, ScopeStealth PistolA pistol with a larger clip and an integrated silencer, designed for stealth combat.Weapon type: PistolBase damage: 8Accuracy: 60%ROF: fastClip size: 10Max ammo: 150Upgrades acceptedAccuracy, Range, Reload speed, ClipLaser sight, ScopeMini CrossbowA wrist-mounted stealth-oriented weapon, which uses three types of ammo.Weapon type: PistolBase damage: 25Accuracy: 60%ROF: mediumClip size: 4Max ammo: 60Tranquilizer darts: ( Nonlethal ) Tranquilizes the target slowly and knocks it out.(Does additional poison damage)Darts: Lethal and powerful dart.Flare darts: Useful to light up certain surfaces, otherwise it does damage as a normal dart.Upgrades acceptedRange, Reload speed, AccuracyLaser sight ScopeSpecial: (Tranquilizer darts stun enemies instead of killing them)PS 20A disposable prototype plasma stealth weapon.Weapon type: PistolBase damage: 25Accuracy: 100%Clip size: Single useAssault rifleA 7.62 x 51mm bullpup assault rifle intended for close-quarters combat.Weapon type: RifleBase damage: 3 (fires bursts of 5 rounds)Accuracy: 65%ROF: very fastClip size: 30Max Ammo: 300 7.62 x 51 / 32 20mm HE grenades7.62 x 51 ammo: Effective against organic targets and some destructible objects.20 mm HE: Effective against everything with a wide splash damage area.Upgrades acceptedAccuracy, Range, Recoil, Clip, Reload speedLaser sight, SilencerAssault shotgunKnown unofficially as the "Street Sweeper," it is a fully automatic shotgun which can quickly clear a room.Weapon type: RifleBase damage: 20 (5 pellets with 4 damage)Accuracy 60%ROF: fastClip size: 12Max Ammo: 96 Both types00 Buckshot: Effective against organic tissues.Sabot slug: Effective against armored targets. (In the game this is a pellet round that does more damage)Upgrades acceptedClip, Reload, RecoilSawed Off ShotgunA compact pump-action, close range shotgun.Weapon type: RifleBase damage: 25 (5 pellets with 5 damage)Accuracy 70%ROF: slowClip size: 4Max ammo: 9600 Buckshot: Effective against organic tissues.Sabot slug: Effective against armored targets. (In the game this is a pellet round that does more damage)Upgrades acceptedClip, Reload, RecoilSniper RifleA 30.06 based sniper rifle.Weapon type: RifleBase damage: 25Accuracy 75%ROF: slowClip size: 6Max ammo: 96Upgrades acceptedAccuracy, Range, Recoil, Clip, Reload speedLaser sight, SilencerBatonA standard police/military baton.Weapon type: Low TechBase damage: 7Accuracy: 50%ROF: fastSpecial: (Stuns enemies instead of killing them)Riot ProdA weapon which causes a seizure-like reaction when the target is hit by the end of the prod.Weapon type: Low TechBase damage: 15Accuracy: 75%ROF: mediumClip size: 4Special: (Stuns enemies instead of killing them)Combat knifeA standard combat knife.Weapon type: Low TechBase damage: 5Accuracy: 50%ROF: fastThrowing knivesKnives to throw at targets.Weapon type: Low TechBase damage: 15Accuracy: 55%ROF: fastMax ammo: 25Pepper gunA riot control weapon which causes temporary blindness and great pain for the victim.Weapon type: Low TechBase damage: 0Accuracy: 65%ROF: very fastClip size: 100Max ammo: 400Special: (Immobilizes enemies and causes minor damage to JC when fired by an enemy)CrowbarA crowbar.Weapon type: Low TechBase damage: 6Accuracy: 50%ROF: mediumSwordA typical sword.Weapon type: Low TechBase damage: 10Accuracy: 50%ROF: mediumDragon's tooth swordAn indestructible and very damaging sword, which was forged with nanotechnology.Weapon type: Low TechBase damage: 100 (5x20)Accuracy: 50%ROF mediumEMP grenadeEffective against all electronics and can be used as a proximity mine.Weapon type: DemolitionBase damage: 0Accuracy: 50%ROF: mediumMax ammo: 10Gas grenadeA tear gas grenade which effects humans and can be used as a proximity mine.Weapon type: DemolitionBase damage: 0Accuracy : 50%ROF: mediumMax ammo: 10Special: (Immobilizes enemies who are in the gas area and causes damage to JC)LAM (Lightweight Attack Munitions)A highly explosive grenade. Doubles as a proximity grenade.Weapon type: DemolitionBase damage: 50Accuracy: 50%ROF: mediumMax ammo: 10Scramble grenadeA grenade which causes security bots to attack each other and ignore security breaches. Also doubles as proximity mine.Weapon type: DemolitionBase damage: 0Accuracy: 50%ROF: mediumMax ammo: 10Items ListSuitsHazmat suitProtects against acid, radiations, toxic substances, and electric / EMP fields.Thermoptic CamoGrants invisibility for a short period of time, useful to bypass some hard security.Ballistic ArmorProtcts against most physical and explosive damage.UtilityRebreatherAllow for extended time underwaterFire extinguisherExtinguishes fires.Creates a cloud to disable enemies similar to pepper sprayNight Vision GogglesEnabled vision in low light settings.FlareGenerates light within a small radius.Short durability but useful for saving other resources.GogglesActivates a zoomLockpickUseful for unlocking mechanical doors, chests, vents, doors, etc.MultitoolUseful for disabling electronic devices through panels, such as laser fences, alarm panels, security cameras, turrets, keypad locks, etc.Weapon upgradesAccuracy upgradeUpgrades a weapon's accuracy and reduces aiming timeLaser sightAdds laser sight to a weapon.Pressing the laser button will toggle its visibility.Range upgradeUpgrades a weapon's range.ScopeAdds scope to a weapon.Pressing the scope button enables a zoom function.Every weapon has a set zoom power.Recoil upgradeDiminishes weapon's recoil.SilencerAdds a silencer to a weapon.Reload SpeedDecreases reload time.Clip upgradeUpgrade the amount of ammo per magazine.Add 1 ammo in the magazine if the mag is under 20 ammo and adds 10% if the mag =20 or aboveConsumablesMedkitHeals 30 HP or more depending on medical skill level.Can carry a maximum of 15 at a time.Zyme vialHardcore drugCauses vision blur and sway.Can be sold to some dealers to gain money or other useful things.Soy FoodHeals 5 HP.Cigarette packPoisonous.Removes 10 HP from the torso.Soda canHeals 2 HP.Beer bottleThe beer gives 2 HP and adds some vision blur.Candy barHeals 2 HP.Wine bottleRarer then beer, but does the same thing, gives 2 HP and vision blur.LiquorThe liquor is very rare and found mostly in bars. Has the same effect as wine and beer, 2 HP and vision blur.Augmentations ListThe player is given 1 head slot, 1 eye slot, 3 torso slots, 1 arm slot, 2 sub-dermal slots, and 1 leg slot in addition to the default augmentations. The player must choose the augmentations they wish to equip in those slots. The available augmentations are listed below:DefaultInfolinkAllows player to receive communications from characters in the game.IFFColors crosshairs to identify friend/foe.The lightAllows player to see in the dark. Enemies can spot the light.HeadAggressive Defense SystemAllows player to detonate explosives such as rockets / grenades before they reach the player. Upgraded: Detonate planted LAMs, more range.Spy DroneRemote flying camera. Upgraded: Flies faster, has EMP bomb. It needs one minute to be recreated after use.EyeTargetingScope Vision.Upgraded: Can indicate enemy health and status.Vision EnhancementNight Vision.Upgraded: Can see through walls within a certain range, and at great range when fully upgraded .TorsoAqualungAllows player to breathe longer, reduces oxygen consumption underwater.Environmental ResistanceAllows player to resist against radiation and toxins.RegenerationAllows player to cure wounds in exchange of bio electric energy.Energy ShieldAllows player to resist "energy" and "fire" weapons.Power RecirculatorReduces energy consumption of other augmentations, while consuming some energy as well.Sythetic HeartIncreases efficiency of augmentations. Increases energy use slightly while adding one more level to active augmentations.(Cannot be upgraded)ArmsCombat StrengthIncreases the damage dealt by melee weapons and allows some weapons to break certain objects.Microfibral MuscleIncreases player's strength to lift/push heavy objects.SubdermalBallistic ProtectionResist against physical damage such as bullets, projectiles, and melee weaponsCloakMakes player invisible to organic creatures. The upgrade reduces its energy consumption.EMP ShieldResists against EMP damage and prevents the BE to be drained by EMP.Radar TransparencyMakes player invisible to robots/cameras. The upgrade reduces its energy consumption.LegsSpeed EnhancementAllows player to run faster, jump higher, and reduces falling damage.Run silentMakes the player run silently. Great when combined with the cloak.MusicThe music in Deus Ex was composed by Alexander Brandon and consists of jazz, techno, and ambient sounds. These tracks are implemented dynamically, much like the iMUSE system developed by LucasArts. Thus the music changes based on what is happening around the player.Deus Ex Track List:Main Title - 02:24Intro Sequence - 02:23Liberty Island - 05:26UNATCO - 05:12Battery Park - 04:42NYC Streets - 04:15Lebedev's Airfield - 03:14Airfield Action - 01:10Enemy Within - 01:48Desolation (Hong Kong Canal) - 02:26The Synapse (Hong Kong Streets) - 04:37Hong Kong Action - 00:59Majestic 12 Labs - 01:50Versalife - 03:48Naval Base - 04:59Paris Streets - 01:18DuClare Château - 06:42Paris Action - 01:24Return to NYC - 01:34Ocean Lab - 01:35Ocean Action - 01:24Ocean Lab Complex - 01:48Vandenberg - 03:46Begin the End (Bunker) - 01:41Area 51 - 02:22Ending 1 - 01:15Ending 2 - 01:18Ending 3 - 01:50The Illuminati - 02:38DX Club Mix - 03:00Training Room - 02:03NYC Bar - 05:10Hong Kong Helipad - 03:30Hong Kong Club 1 - 04:56Hong Kong Club 2 - 02:57The Nothing - 03:17Paris Club 1 - 02:49Paris Club 2 - 04:31Paris Cathedral - 03:36Conspiravision - 05:38Paris Cathedral Conversation - 00:54ReceptionDeus Ex was well received by critics, who praised it for its interesting story and immersive gameplay, as well as the game's cyberpunk setting. The game scored solid to exceptional reviews from some notable gaming outlets, such as an 8.2 from GameSpot, a 9.4 from IGN, a 5/5 from GamePro, and a 88/100 from GameSpy. Overall the game averaged scores of 90 and 91 as tracked by review aggregate sites Metacritic and Game Rankings. It was nominated for over 40 Game of the Year and Best in Class awards by numerous gaming outlets, including IGN, GameSpot, and PC Gamer, and is arguably one of the most influential CRPG/shooter hybrids in gaming history.Many reviewers repeatedly mentioned a few negative aspects, such as the underwhelming graphics. The voice acting was also criticized, GamePro's Chris Patterson calling it "truly cheesy."PC RequirementsOperating System: Windows 95/98/Me/XPProcessor: Pentium 300 (Min.), Pentium 450 (Rec.)Memory: 64 MB RAM (Min.), 128 MB (Rec.)Video Card: 8MB DirectX 7.0a compatible 3D graphics card (Min.)Sound Card: DirectX 7.0a compatible sound cardHard Drive Space: 150 MB (minimum)TriviaThere's an Easter Egg in the Hell's Kitchen map in Deus Ex. There's a neighborhood basketball park where a bum is getting roughed up by some NSF toughs. If you miss hitting the basket enough times with the basketball, you'll see a message that says: "Sign him up for the Nicks!!!!"Useful LinksThrough the Looking GlassDirectX 10 for Unreal 1 engineDeus Ex: New Vision</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8870">System Shock 2</game><game id="17280">BioShock</game><game id="16426">Vampire: The Masquerade - Bloodlines</game><game id="9258">Neocron 2: Beyond Dome of York</game><game id="11187">Star Trek: Voyager - Elite Force</game><game id="14328">Half-Life 2: Episode One</game><game id="13948">System Shock</game><game id="3857">Project: Snowblind</game><game id="21302">S.T.A.L.K.E.R.: Clear Sky</game><game id="5559">Fallout 2</game><game id="11725">S.T.A.L.K.E.R.: Shadow of Chernobyl</game><game id="10565">Strife</game><game id="7747">John Romero's Daikatana</game><game id="9480">Half-Life 2: Episode Two</game><game id="7814">Half-Life: Blue Shift</game><game id="21912">Planetside: Core Combat</game><game id="4505">Vampire: The Masquerade - Redemption</game><game id="4523">Thief: The Dark Project</game><game id="11085">The Chronicles of Riddick: Escape from Butcher Bay</game><game id="3183">Neocron</game><game id="17350">Unreal II: The Awakening</game><game id="21710">Shadowrun</game><game id="12134">Wasteland</game><game id="20987">The Chronicles of Riddick: Assault on Dark Athena</game><game id="4301">Area-51</game><game id="11704">Fallout</game><game id="7787">Thief II: The Metal Age</game><game id="21590">Mass Effect 2</game><game id="20984">Alpha Protocol</game><game id="20504">Fallout 3</game><game id="8580">Jade Empire</game><game id="29935">Mass Effect 3</game><game id="23471">Prey 2</game><game id="29717">E.Y.E: Divine Cybermancy</game><game id="35888">Hard Reset</game><game id="35850">Dishonored</game><game id="3651">Auto Racing</game><game id="8858">Kingpin: Life of Crime</game><game id="36497">Star Cruiser</game><game id="15444">Chrome</game><game id="38456">Cyberpunk 2077</game><game id="3428">Anachronox</game><game id="36610">Psychic City</game><game id="16140">Metal Gear Solid</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5480/608405-dxcover_1.jpg</image></root>