<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17543</id><name>Destroy All Humans!</name><description>Basic Game InfoDestroy All Humans! is an open world sci-fi game that puts you in the shoes of Crypto, an alien out to destroy all humans in order to discover his previous clone's fate and replenish his race's DNA. It was developed by Pandemic Studios' Brisbane office, previously responsible for Army Men RTS. Destroy All Humans! was orignally released for the Playstation 2 and Xbox and was recently released as an Xbox Original on the Xbox LIVE Marketplace.Plot (Spoilers)In 1959, Cryptosporidium-137 arrives on Earth to investigate the planet and the disappearance of his missing clone, Cryptosporidium-136. Orthopox-13 (also known as Pox, and voiced by Richard Horvitz) is the one who sends him to Earth.While on Earth, Pox sends Crypto on a mission to harvest human brain stems in order to propogate the genital-free Furon race. To keep on trying to accomplish his mission, he must contend with the Majestic, a shady government organization led by Silhouette who is aware of alien life. After defeating the organization, Crypto takes over the Presidency of the United States and convinces everybody that nothing is wrong.GameplayCrypto possesses a lot of weapons in line with our view of aliens.For instance, he has a ray gun, which is the first weapon you can use, which shoots a beam of electricity into your target, or targets after upgrading it. Furthermore, he has an anal probe which allows for a quicker but much less subtle approach to harvesting brain stems. He also has a basic gun that basically seems to destroy humans when fired.While shooting you can move around the world pretty easily with the use of a jet pack (which needs regular stops to recharge). In keeping with the alien concept, Crypto also has the power of Telekinesis which can be used to throw cows, and eventually, cars and trucks. An important part of gameplay is the ability to put up a holobob which makes humans think that you are one of them. This is used both to sneak around and to convince the populace that the recent activity is nothing but the action of the Communits (a.k.a. The Red Menace).Another fun, but sometimes not essential component of the game is the ability to read people's minds which in some missions gives you important information.Another important gameplay component that is essential for traveling large distances and taking on larger foes is your UFO, which is equipped with a laser beam, an Abducto-Beam, a sonic explosion gun and one for quantum explosions for taking out stronger structures.LevelsTurnispeed FarmRockwellSanta ModestaRockwellSanta ModestaArea 42Santa ModestaUnion TownCapitol CityUnion TownCapitol CitySide MissionsTurnispeed FarmRockwellSanta ModestaArea 42Union TownCapitol CityReleasesDestroy All Humans was released on June 21, 2005, and has since sold over 2 million units on all platforms combined. The IP was sold to FOX television in order to make an animated series, however the show has been stuck in development hell indefinitely.On October 6, 2008, Destroy All Humans! became available on the Xbox 360's Xbox Originals download service for 1200 Microsoft Points.</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9185">Destroy All Humans! 2</game><game id="13381">Redneck Rampage</game><game id="20820">Destroy All Humans! Path of the Furon</game><game id="21004">Destroy All Humans! Big Willy Unleashed</game><game id="16238">Alien Shooter 2</game><game id="20697">Mercenaries 2: World in Flames</game><game id="17350">Unreal II: The Awakening</game><game id="6948">Dark Colony</game><game id="261">Stubbs the Zombie in Rebel Without a Pulse</game><game id="22070">Global Defence Force</game><game id="36473">Demolition Inc.</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2136541-box_dah.png</image></root>