<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17551</id><name>Command &amp; Conquer 3: Tiberium Wars</name><description>OverviewCommand  Conquer 3: Tiberium Wars tells the third chapter of Earth's Tiberium-laden history, of the transcendence of the seemingly ageless Kane, the supposed final victory of the GDI over the Brotherhood of NOD, and the invasion of the Scrin, an alien race of incredible destructive power with technology that's built from Tiberium itself. For this game and its expansions, EALA has brought together an eclectic cast of character actors to comprise the roles of GDI and NOD forces, as well as Joseph D. Kucan to reprise the role of the enigmatic and immortal Kane.Gdi rolling in their attack force!Viewed in a default isometric point of view, Command  Conquer 3 puts you in the role of a field commander of whichever faction you choose. You're given complete strategic command over the battlefield, and are tasked with the job of destroying the enemy through the collection of resources, which are used to increase the number of forces you have at your disposal and the size and capabilities of your base, which unlocks special abilities, advanced units, and super weapons. Built around the SAGE engine, CC3 plays much like it's predecessor, CC: Generals, and features a robust construction menu system, allowing the user to queue up a large number of buildings and units to quickly create a powerful attack force. Additionally, you'll need to protect your base with a range of defensive structures, such as turrets and missile launchers..Commander  Conquer 3 is unique among the CC games for introducing a third faction, the Scrin. Between the three races to choose from, the game offers a wide range of tactical gameplay choices in the game's skirmish and multiplayer modes. The GDI is a juggernaut, with powerful ballistic units but limited mobility. NOD's technology is highly advanced but focused on stealth, featuring fantastically powerful defensive structures but relatively weak offensive units. The Scrin is a mixture of both, with incredibly powerful air units, weak ground units, and a single, powerful defensive structure. This inclusion of the third race represents the greatest change to the CC franchise since the days of CC2, and was generally well received by fans.VillainsKaneKane, as he appears in Command  Conquer: Tiberian Sun.The part of Kane has been played by Joe Kucan for 14 years. This makes him the longest running actor in a video game role according to Guinness World Records. The character of Kane is the charismatic leader of the terrorist organization known as the Brotherhood of Nod in the Command  Conquer games. He was believed to have died on multiple occasions, but apparently survived every time. In the original teaser trailer for Command  Conquer 3: Tiberium Wars, he claims: "You can't kill the messiah."Biblical referencesKane, as he appears in Command  Conquer 3.Some theorists believe that Kane could be, or at least reference "Cain" from the Bible. In the Christian and Jewish beliefs, Cain killed his brother, Abel, and was doomed to wander the earth (Presumably forever). He settled the land of "Nod". Adam  Eve's third son, born after Abel's death, was named "Seth". Kane's second-in-command in the original Command  Conquer was also named Seth. Kane never appears to age throughout the entire Command  Conquer series, which spans over 50 years, leading some to believe that Kane could possibly be the biblical "Cain", still wandering the earth. Of course, this is entirely speculation, and none of it has been confirmed by the game's creators.System RequirementsOS: Windows XP/VistaProcessor: 2GHz AMD Athlon™ processor or equivalentMemory: 512MB RAMGraphics: ATI Radeon 8500 or Nvidia GeForce 4 or higher video cardHard Drive: 8GBSound: DirectX 9.0c-compatible sound cardOther Requirements: Internet service required to access online features, Broadband modem required for 3 to 8 players and voice supportXbox 360 Game InstallationCommand  Conquer: Tiberium Wars requires 6.6GB to install to an Xbox 360 HDD.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6164">World in Conflict</game><game id="9326">Universe at War: Earth Assault</game><game id="7489">Act of War: Direct Action</game><game id="20952">World in Conflict: Soviet Assault</game><game id="14073">Warcraft III: The Frozen Throne</game><game id="5681">Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War - Dark Crusade</game><game id="20739">Tom Clancy's EndWar</game><game id="4867">The Lord of the Rings: The Battle for Middle-earth II</game><game id="14676">Perimeter</game><game id="2115">Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War</game><game id="8546">Age of Empires III</game><game id="13062">StarCraft</game><game id="20674">StarCraft II: Wings of Liberty</game><game id="17353">Star Wars: Force Commander</game><game id="20103">Warcraft II: Tides of Darkness</game><game id="2478">Act of War: High Treason</game><game id="14805">KKND2: Krossfire</game><game id="1552">Dune 2000</game><game id="13125">Aliens Versus Predator: Extinction</game><game id="6447">The Lord of the Rings: The Battle for Middle-earth II - The Rise of the Witch-King</game><game id="14236">Dune II: The Building of a Dynasty</game><game id="14081">Fragile Allegiance</game><game id="15262">Imperium Romanum</game><game id="10768">Battlestations: Midway</game><game id="20580">Sid Meier's Civilization Revolution</game><game id="21011">Commanders: Attack of the Genos</game><game id="2007">Worms</game><game id="18407">Thrillville: Off the Rails</game><game id="4135">Outpost Kaloki X</game><game id="4653">Band of Bugs</game><game id="20793">Warhammer: Battle March</game><game id="8421">Outlive</game><game id="25651">R.U.S.E.</game><game id="20521">Halo Wars</game><game id="29541">Elements of War</game><game id="24079">StarCraft II: Legacy of the Void</game><game id="24078">StarCraft II: Heart of the Swarm</game><game id="15235">Dark Reign: The Future of War</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4344/944606-command_conquer_3_tiberium_wars.jpg</image></root>