<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17602</id><name>Gish</name><description>Overview Gish, a 2D PC platform game created by                Edmund McMillen and               Alex Austin (   Chronic Logic), was distributed by Stardock in 2004 and is currently available on Steam. On May 29, 2010, the game was made      open source.Story Gish and his lady friend, Brea, a human, are taking a stroll one day in the park. Suddenly a mysterious figure appears from an open man-hole and kidnaps Brea. The mysterious figure takes her with him underground into the sewers of Dross. Our hero, Gish, a ball of tar, dives straight in after her. Now he has to battle his way through the sewers to save his lady friend.Gameplay Gish rides a wrecking ball into people's hearts... or at least into that guy's face.Gish is a ball of tar with yellow, glowing eyes and fanged teeth. His gelatinous nature lets him stick to most surfaces, slip through small spaces, and become solid, which also increases Gish's mass. These three abilities let Gish do different things.Sticky GishThe ability to become sticky lets Gish climb walls, move across ceilings, and grab on to enemies and loose objects.  Slippery GishThe ability to become slippery allows Gish to fit into smaller-spaces, move faster downhill, and prevent getting squashed.   Solid GishThe ability to become solid and heavy allows Gish to break through certain platforms, crush foes, fling objects off from on top of him, sink in water, and fall faster. Gish, despite being a ball of tar, has the ability to jump. A first attempt of jumping will only result in a small amount of lift, the player is required to bounce him higher and higher to get the desired momentum to reach the necessary height. To bounce higher, the player must hold the down button on landing and pressing jump at the lowest point of Gish's compression. Because Gish is physically simulated, it is also possible to compress him by bouncing on sharp corners, Gish will bounce even further while doing this.The platforming aspect of Gish is pretty straight forward and traditional; the player needs to get from point A-to-B without dying. There are many pitfalls which may cause death, lava and also monsters. The player will have to employ Gish's abilities to navigate through the levels, and sometimes have a puzzle to bypass. The environment has a few interactive elements, Gish can swing pendulums, flip levers (including seesaw-like platforms), move rocks and an assortment of other things. Physics are fundamental to how Gish plays out.There are almost always a few secrets per level to be found on Gish, some of which are homages to its roots: platform games from days gone by.  ItemsThere are a few useful items to be found in Gish. Small Amber - gives 50 points eachMedium Amber - gives 100 points  eachLarge Amber - gives 1000 points each (these are rare, though)Tarballs - restores 10 healthExtra Lives - extra life! (very rare, though) Game Modes Single player In the single player players can play the story and help Gish through 34-level as he travels through the earth searching for his kidnapped girl friend, or play in collection mode where you race against time to collect all the amber on 24-levels unique to this mode of play.Versus mode Go long... and flat, Gish!In the 2-player multiplayer there are 5 different games, each consisting of three maps. There's a Football, Sumo, Greed, Pit fight, and Dragster game; In football the player will attempt to take the ball across their opponents goal line for seven points, or get it through the uprights for three; in sumo the goal is for the players to do anything they can to get their opponent into the water; in greed players race to collect pieces of amber, who ends with the most amber at the end wins; in pit fight players attempt to smash the opponent into the spikes to defeat them; finally, in dragster, you have a simple race to a finish line. Awards 2005 IGF Grand Prize (Seamus McNally Award) 2005 IGF Innovation in Game Design Game Tunnel's Game of the Year Game Tunnel's Adventure Game of the Year Home of the Underdogs Top Dog 2004 IGF Finalist   Humble Indie BundleGish has recently been included in the             Humble Indie Bundle (spanning from the 4th of May to the 11th of May 2010) - a bundle that costs anything you want. All three platforms were available (Windows, Mac and Linux) plus the game was            DRM free. After the sale, Gish was made     open source.  TriviaGish makes a cameo in the indie PC game "Dumbo  Cool".Gish is an unlockable character in Meat Boy and Spewer (both flash games) and more recently in the multiplatformer        Super Meat Boy.  System Requirements Minimum system requirements  Operating Systems: Windows 98/ME/2000/XP, Linux 2.4 , Mac OS X 10.1   Processor: AMD, Intel or G3 1000  MHz processor  Video: Video card supporting OpenGL with 32 MB of memory  Memory: 256 MB RAMRecommended system requirements  Processor: AMD, Intel, or G4 1500  MHz processor  Video: Video card supporting OpenGL with 64  MB of memory  Memory: 256 MB RAM</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="31678">Tales from Space: About a Blob</game><game id="35429">Blocks That Matter</game><game id="36298">Tales From Space: Mutant Blobs Attack</game><game id="37697">Aether</game><game id="38899">Nihilumbra</game><game id="35505">Sound Shapes</game><game id="40464">Fly'N</game><game id="21634">Smart Ball</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15693/658041-250px_gish_box_art_1_.jpg</image></root>