<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17739</id><name>AeroFighters Assault</name><description>OverviewAerofighters Assualt is the fourth and last game in the                      Aero Fighters franchise. Rather than being a       top down shoot 'em up like it's predecessors, Aerofighters Assault takes advantage of the Nintendo    Comparison of the US/EU and JP title screens      64's capabilities by becoming a                   3D air combat series similar to               Ace Combat. Players are able to choose from six (two of which are unlockable) aircraft, each with unique special weapons. Although    modeled and named after actual jets, the planes in Aerofighters Assault handle in an arcade like fashion, carry payloads in impossible quantities, and use fantastical special weapons.     Controls The aircraft in Aerofighters Assault control in an arcade fashion, where stalls are non existent. The analog stick controls pitch, with up and down inverted as they would be on a jets joystick. Afterburners are mapped to the up C button, increasing speed, and the air-brake is mapped to the down C button, decreasing speed. Players can control yaw with the left and right C buttons, controlling their respective directions. As for armaments, the Z button is used to fire each planes primary machine gun, A fires the players primary missile attack, and B activates the defensive chaff. When available, each jets special weapon may be fired with the R button. The D-pad can be used to view camera angles around the players aircraft.  GameplayAvailable Game Modes PracticeMain gameDeathmatchBoss Attack Main Game     F-14 Tomcat participating in the first story mission     Each mission for the main storyline is first briefed, allowing the player to acknowledge their location in the world, and view the enemies that will be present. If applicable, the players mission time is also given. Objectives vary from protecting a certain asset, or destroying certain enemies. Each stage has a boss fight after the given objectives are completed.</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="24">Flight Simulator</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20037">Ace Combat 3: Electrosphere</game><game id="9026">Chopper Attack</game><game id="6250">Air Combat</game><game id="3605">Ace Combat 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/233/327520-us_boxfrunt.jpg</image></root>