<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18007</id><name>Spiritual Warfare</name><description>OverviewSpiritual Warfare was originally released for the NES as an unlicensed game (without Nintendo's official approval) in 1992, and was later ported to the PC, Genesis, and Game Boy. It is a Zelda clone taking very few deviants from the path set by the classic NES game.PlotThe game never fully explains the plot, but you play the role of a christian man as he travels through the game world converting non-believers and fighting demons until at the end of the game you fight the final boss, who ends up being non-other than Satan himself.GameplaySpiritual Warfare is a Legend of Zelda clone with nearly every item resembling an item from that game. The main character, known only as 'Christian' mainly travels around the game-world conventing non-believers and trying to find new items to help him unlock new areas in the game-world, much like the original Zelda game. Most items in the game also closely resembled items in a Zelda game. For example: The 'Master Sword' was replaced with the 'Sword' of the Spirit' and the 'bombs' in Zelda were replaced with 'Vials of God's Wrath'. Also resembling Zelda, nearly every level ends with a boss encounter at the end of which the player is rewarded with a piece of the Armor of God which will let him access a new area of the game.( For example, the Belt of Truth let's him move rocks, including the rocks blocking the path between the Park and the Downtown.SoundtrackThe soundtrack in the game consists of an instrumental version of the hymn "What a Friend We Have In Jesus" being continuously looped in the background.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="8">Educational</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20589">Bomberman</game><game id="11949">The Legend of Zelda</game><game id="2231">Crystalis</game><game id="2022">King of Kings: The Early Years</game><game id="14722">Miracle Warriors: Seal of the Dark Lord</game><game id="13986">Soul Blazer</game><game id="14381">Ultima IV: Quest of the Avatar</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3413/237206-spiritual_warfare.jpg</image></root>