<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18058</id><name>Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Eye of the Beholder</name><description>The game utilizes a stripped down version of the 3rd Edition ADD ruleset, with only four basic character classes. It is not a port of the original game, but it does include practically the same story and set pieces.Dark times are upon the city of Waterdeep, as an unspeakable evil is lurking under the city. Four adventurers are sent by the lords of Waterdeep to explore the underworld beneath, and bring the evil entity to justice. The game begins in the sewers, just as the party realizes they are trapped inside, thanks to a huge cave in caused by Xanathar, the beholder whom the title of the game refers to. The party has to keep going down, deeper and deeper beneath the city, through Dwarf and Drow settlements, towards the lair of Xanathar, to destroy this evil once and for all.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="24865">The Dark Spire</game><game id="11234">Eye of the Beholder</game><game id="1500">Eye of the Beholder II: The Legend of Darkmoon</game><game id="14326">Eye of the Beholder III: Assault on Myth Drannor</game><game id="36231">Legend of Grimrock</game><game id="18518">Dungeon Master</game><game id="15771">Dungeon Master II: The Legend of Skullkeep</game><game id="9489">Might and Magic: Clouds of Xeen</game><game id="14535">Might and Magic: Book I</game><game id="19917">Might and Magic II: Gates to Another World</game><game id="12559">Might and Magic III: Isles of Terra</game><game id="3411">Might and Magic: Darkside of Xeen</game><game id="5980">Might and Magic: World of Xeen</game><game id="17886">Might and Magic VI: The Mandate of Heaven</game><game id="4398">Might and Magic VII: For Blood and Honor</game><game id="3239">Might and Magic VIII: Day of the Destroyer</game><game id="11396">Might and Magic IX</game><game id="36425">Frayed Knights: The Skull of S'makh-Daon</game><game id="9180">Wizardry: Proving Grounds of the Mad Overlord</game><game id="16625">Wizardry II: The Knight of Diamonds</game><game id="4504">Wizardry III: Legacy of Llylgamyn</game><game id="7113">Wizardry IV: The Return of Werdna</game><game id="13839">Wizardry V: Heart of the Maelstrom</game><game id="6393">Wizardry: Bane of the Cosmic Forge</game><game id="12013">Wizardry: Crusaders of the Dark Savant</game><game id="11906">Wizardry 8</game><game id="14350">Etrian Odyssey</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2437064-box_dadeotb.png</image></root>