<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18095</id><name>Need for Speed: ProStreet</name><description>OverviewNeed for Speed: Pro Street is a continuation of the long time running Need for Speed franchise. Need for Speed breaks off from the norm in Need for Speed games with legal street racing edging Forza Motorsport. Competitively Pro Street is used as the World Cyber Games PC Racing game. Details:EA's 11th in series, Need For Speed: ProStreet, moves the series from illegal street racing to the track.  The game focuses around a young man named Ryan who moves his way up through battles to take on the king of racing. The Street King is Ryo Watanabe, a punk who runs his mouth about how much better he is than everyone else. Ryo drives a Mitsubishi Lancer Evo X. There are two versions of his Evo : one has a different spoiler, but that's the only real difference.Game Modes:Drag Racing: This mode involves racing in a straight line aiming for perfect shifts. This mode usually revolves around 1/4 mile and 1/2 mile tracks and even sometimes contains a wheelie competition.Grip Racing: This mode involves track based courses aiming for perfection in the turns. There are even several classes within this type of racing, from normal grip, class grip, sector shootout, to time attacks. In normal grip, it is you against the rest of the field (no matter the cars specs) to be the first to complete all the laps. In class grip, you will be placed against 3 other cars with equivelent type of equipment and settings. In sector shootout, you earn points by pulling the fastest time through certain sections of the track. In time attack, it is whoever can pull the fastest lap out of the whole field.Speed Racing: This mode involves high speed racing on long highway type of course where you must learn to use small and percise controls at such high speeds. In this mode, you will either need to be the first to cross the line or pull the overall fastest trap times in certain sections.Drift Racing: This mode involves taking a small portion of a track and see who can pull the best drifts which involve getting your car sideways while keeping your speed up.PlotThe main protagonist of NFS: Pro Street is the wannabe "Street King", Ryan Cooper. You roll up with your Nissan 240SX on race day as you attempt to become champion for each racing event that's held. The first official raceday you will encounter is Battle Machine. You move along onto different race days as you complete and become victorious on them. After winning Battle Machine you are then sposnosred by Super Promotion to compete at the Showdown at Chicago Airfield. After you dominate the airfield you move along to  R3act Team Sessions, you break records, earn cash, earn parts, unlock cars etc. Ryan Cooper then goes to challenge each race modes race King. You defeat each Street King and then move upto to the Showdown King himself, Ryo Watanabe. Once you defeat Ryo you are crowned the Street King of the world.Soundtrack Airbourne - Blackjack  Avenged Sevenfold - Almost Easy  Bloc Party - Prayer  Chromeo - Fancy Footwork (Guns 'n Bombs Remix)  Clutch - Power Player  CSS - Odio Odio Odio Sorry C  Datarock - I Used to Dance With My Daddy (Karma Harvest Mix)  Digitalism - Pogo  Dude 'n Nem - Watch My Feet  DUNE - A Blast Beat  The Faint - Dropkick The Punks  Foreign Islands - We Know You Know It  The Horrors - Draw Japan  Junkie XL (Feat. Lauren Rocket) - More  Junkie XL (Feat. Lauren Rocket) - More (Junk O Flamenco Remix)  Junkie XL (Feat. Lauren Rocket) - More (Junk O Punk Remix)  Junkie XL (Feat. Lauren Rocket) - More (Junk O Rock Remix)  Klaxons - Atlantis To Interzone  MSTRKRFT - Neon Knights  Neon Plastix - On Fire  Peaches - Boys Wanna Be Her (Tommie Sunshine's Brooklyn Fire Retouch)  Plan B - No Good (Chase  Status and Benni G Remix)  Plan B (Feat. Epic Man) - More is Enough  The Rapture - The Sound  Smallwhitelight - Spite  The Toxic Avenger - Escape (Bloody Beetroots Remix)  TV on the Radio - Wolf Like Me  UNKLE feat Josh Homme - Restless  We Are Wolves - Fight and Kiss  Wiley - Bow E3  Yeah Yeah Yeahs - Kiss Kiss  Year Long Disaster - Leda Atomica  Yelle - A Cause des Garcons (Riot in Belgium Remix) Cars    * 2001 Acura Integra Type R    * 2001 Acura Integra LS    * 2006 Acura RSX    * 2005 Acura NSX    * 2005 Aston Martin DBR9    * 2007 Audi R8    * 2007 Audi RS4    * 2007 Audi S3    * 2006 Audi S4    * 2007 Audi TT Quattro    * 2001 BMW E46 M3    * 2008 BMW E92 M3    * 2007 BMW Z4 M Coupé    * 2006 Bugatti Veyron 16.4    * 2006 Cadillac CTS-V    * 2008 Chevrolet Camaro Concept    * 1967 Chevrolet Camaro SS    * 1970 Chevrolet Chevelle SS    * 2006 Chevrolet Cobalt SS    * 1967 Chevrolet Corvette C2 (Sting Ray)    * 2005 Chevrolet Corvette C6    * 2006 Chevrolet Corvette Z06    * 1971 Dodge Challenger    * 1967 Dodge Charger    * 2006 Dodge Viper Coupe    * 1996 Ford Escort RS Cosworth    * 2005 Ford Focus ST    * 2006 Ford GT    * 2003 Ford Mustang GT    * 2006 Ford Mustang GT S-197    * 1999 Honda Civic CX Hatchback    * 2006 Honda Civic Si    * 2000 Honda S2000    * 2003 Infitini G35 Coupe    * 2006 Koenigsegg CCX    * 2006 Lamborghini Murcielago LP640    * 1991 Lancia Delta Integrale Evo    * 2006 Lexus IS350    * 2006 Lotus Elise    * 1995 Mazda RX-7    * 2006 Mazda RX-8    * 2006 Mazdaspeed 3    * 1998 McLaren F1    * 2004 Mercedes SL65 AMG    * 1999 Mitsubishi Eclipse    * 2006 Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution IX MR-edition    * 2008 Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution X    * 1989 Nissan 240 SX S13    * 2006 Nissan 350Z    * 1999 Nissan Skyline R34    * 1999 Nissan Silvia S15    * 2008 Nissan GT-R    * 2008 Nissan GT-R Proto    * 2006 Pagani Zonda F    * 1970 Plymouth Hemi Cuda    * 1968 Plymouth Road Runner    * 1965 Pontiac GTO    * 2006 Pontiac GTO    * 2006 Pontiac Solstice GXP    * 2008 Porsche 911 (997) GT2    * 2006 Porsche 911 (997) Turbo    * 2006 Porshe Cayman S    * 2005 Seat Leon Cupra    * 1967 Shelby GT-500    * 2006 Shelby GT 500    * 2006 Subaru Impreza WRX STI    * 1986 Toyota Corolla GT-S AE86    * 1998 Toyota Supra    * 2006 Volkswagen Golf GTI    * 2006 Volkswagen Golf R32 </description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20729">GRID</game><game id="1101">Ridge Racer 7</game><game id="5881">Forza Motorsport 2</game><game id="19809">Project Gotham Racing 3</game><game id="6582">Test Drive Unlimited</game><game id="9651">Need for Speed Underground 2</game><game id="11055">NASCAR 08</game><game id="788">The Fast and the Furious</game><game id="5648">Burnout Paradise</game><game id="21307">Juiced 2: Hot Import Nights</game><game id="20038">NASCAR: Dirt to Daytona</game><game id="20927">Midnight Club: Los Angeles</game><game id="941">Project Gotham Racing</game><game id="2279">Project Gotham Racing 2</game><game id="8437">TOCA 2: Touring Car Challenge</game><game id="7019">Ridge Racer V</game><game id="16276">Ford Bold Moves Street Racing</game><game id="20919">Ford Racing: Off Road</game><game id="7431">Ford Racing</game><game id="12950">Gran Turismo 3 A-Spec</game><game id="7777">Juiced</game><game id="10124">Midnight Club: Street Racing</game><game id="284">NASCAR 2005: Chase for the Cup</game><game id="17872">TOCA Race Driver 3 Challenge</game><game id="8438">NASCAR 06: Total Team Control</game><game id="21657">Initial D: Extreme Stage</game><game id="21689">Wangan Midnight</game><game id="1052">Super PickUps</game><game id="5819">Speed Devils</game><game id="25254">Roadsters</game><game id="20418">Midnight Club II</game><game id="5875">Midnight Club 3: DUB Edition</game><game id="21114">Midnight Club: Los Angeles Remix</game><game id="24995">Forza Motorsport 3</game><game id="25485">Test Drive Unlimited 2</game><game id="25961">Blur</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3699/1790553-nfs_ps_cover.jpg</image></root>