<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18128</id><name>Mobil 1 British Rally Championship</name><description>Mobil 1 British Rally Championship ("Rally  Championship"in Europe) was a driving game released in 1999. It was the last game developed by Magnetic Fields. The game simulated the actual British rally championship, letting the player compete either in a simulation style "championship mode" that recreates the actual races, or arcade style time trials, single races and split screen multiplayer.   It featured 36 tracks and 22 cars, and was known for the quality of it's graphics, the realism of the races and it's difficulty, as a single track could take over 20 minutes to complete. The game featured realistic car damage that, in simulation mode, had to be repaired in order to pass inspections between each race. Any damage that could not be fixed in time would carry over.  Damage would affect the car's handling, engine, windows, body etc. Even tires could be punctured if worn out.  Changing tires during a race would start a minigame where the player had to stop a needle at the right time to get the best possible tire change time. Two selectable co-drivers were available; Derek Ringer and Claire Mole. In addition to audible pace notes, arrows could be displayed on screen showing upcoming turns. The video replay function let the player edit and save entire races. Vvideo could be trimmed, cut and pasted; camera angles could be changed and could even switch between player cars in a recorded split screen race.  TracksThe game includes six rallies, each separated into six individual tracks.    Vauxhall Rally of Wales (gravel)Pirelli International Rally (forest)Scottish Rally (gravel)SEAT Jim Clark Memorial Rally (tarmac)Stena Line Ulster Rally (tarmac)Sony Manx International Rally (tarmac) Cars A5Ford PumaNissan Micra Maxi A6Skoda FeliciaProton CompactHonda CivicCitroën SaxoPeugeot 106 Maxi A7Nissan AlmeraFord EscortSkoda OctaviaFord Escort MaxiVauxhall AstraHyondai Coupé Evo IIVW GolfRenault MéganeSeat Ibiza Cupra Sport  A8Mitsubishi Lancer Evo IVProton Wira/PersonaSeat Cordoba WRCMitsubishi Lancer Evo VSubaru Impreza ERCPeugeot 206 WRC </description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2936/1127576-cover.jpg</image></root>