<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18168</id><name>007: The World is Not Enough</name><description>OverviewComing off the failure that was Tomorrow Never Dies, publisher EA wanted to return to James Bond's roots as a first-person shooter. Developed by Black Ops and Eurocom and published by EA, The World is Not Enough, based off the movie of the same name, was released in the year 2000. The Nintendo 64 version of the game featured a multiplayer mode that was absent from the PlayStation version. The Nintendo 64 version also supported both Rumble Pak and Expansion Pack accessories. The game features 14 single player missions that follow the story of the film very closely. Just like GoldenEye 007, the game featured three difficulty levels: Agent, Secret Agent, and 00 Agent. Completing missions on a certain difficulty would allow you to unlock additional multiplayer maps such as a dark Eastern European forest, a version of MI6's Scotland Headquarters and ski resort complete with working gondolas, and an airplane. The PlayStation version is known for lacking three levels, a level of difficulty and multiplayer modes.The campaign contained multiple gadgets and numerous weapons the player could use. Each weapon had a second setting on it, such as the SA90, which could switch between single and burst modes of fire.The World is Not Enough contained a robust split-screen mode found in most James Bond games. Players could customize their experience in various ways. They could choose what weapons they wanted to be available ( sniper rifles, explosive weapons, close combat etc.), choose how they wanted their avatar to look while playing in the game, have either vertical or horizontal split-screen, and select score limit and match time. Players could fight in teams, Free-for-All, Last Man Standing, uplink, Capture the Flag and King of the Hill modes. During the game, players could pick up various gadgets and aids such as body armor and night vision goggles.WeaponsSubmachine GunsP90Ingalls Type 90Meyer TMPExplosive WeaponsGL40 Grenade LauncherSentinel Heat-Seeking Missile Launcher - Can fire in single or fully automatic modes.Frag GrenadeSticky GrenadeHandgunsRaptor Magnum - Includes optional laser sight.James Bond's classic Wolfer P2KAssault RiflesAK-47M4 Mustang - A variant of the M16.Meyer BullpupSniper RiflesSA90</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5756">Danger Girl</game><game id="10047">Turok 3: Shadow of Oblivion</game><game id="14123">GoldenEye: Rogue Agent</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1779935-box_twine.png</image></root>