<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18227</id><name>NHL 08</name><description>Single PlayerNHL 2008 introduced new game mechanics, and fixed the major problems of NHL 2007, making one of the greatest hockey games of the NHL franchise. All the modes had endures from the previous version, Dynasty, Season, Play Now, and now Shootout. These modes are largely the same as they had been, except of course shootout, which now enabled players to play as the goalie, although its much more difficult to learn the controls. Dynasty mode enables players to play and manage their favorite team as they see fit, however trading can still be unrealistic as teams will trade away franchise players without thinking twice. The problems with goaltending from NHL 2007, has largely been rectified, but there are still various glitches in the game.MultiplayerThe same local multiplayer is there, but online play was largely revamped, allowing for larger games to be played, and leader boards created.FeaturesFrame rate is locked at 60 frames per second, up from NHL 07's 30 frames per second. On the fly Artificial Intelligence that adapts to the player's play styles. Goalie mode for playing as the goalie for the duration of a game. Custom user plays for offense and defense. Fluid skating animations. In depth Create-A-Team section. New RBK Edge Hockey Jerseys.  The RBK Edge jerseys can be unlocked through the My NHL 08 menu under RBK Edge.  The code to unlock the jerseys are "h3oyxpwksf8ibcgt". American Hockey League (AHL) added.  Cover AthletesEric Staal (Caroline Hurricanes) is the main cover athleteHenrik Zetterberg (Detroit Red Wings) in SwedenTeemu Selanne (Anaheim Ducks) in FinlandJaromir Jagr (New York Rangers) in Czech RepublicMark Streit (Montreal Canadians) in SwitzerlandSoundtrackAirbourne - Stand Up For Rock N' RollPulling the goalieAnberlin - A Whisper And A ClamorBayside - The Walking WoundedDatarock - Fa-Fa-FaDisco Ensemble - This Is My Head ExplodingDustin Kensrue - I Knew You BeforeEnter Shikari - Sorry, You're Not A WinnerJupiter One - Turn Up The RadioLuna Halo - Kings  QueensManchester Orchestra - Wolves At NightMando Diao - The Wildfire (If It Was True)Paramore - Misery BusinessPlayRadioPlay! - Compliment Eacah Other Like ColorsPop Levi - Sugar Assault Me NowSantogold - L.E.S. ArtistesScanners - RawThe Black Keys - Just Got To BeThe Mooney Suzuki - 99%The Ponys - Double VisionThe View - Comin' DownThe Wolfmen - Jackie SaysXbox 360 AchievementsShoot it! - As the lead NHL 08 Profile Record 25 shots in 1 period of play on Superstar Mode. - 50G Penalty Kill special - As the lead NHL 08 Profile Score a goal when 2 men down on Pro Mode - 25G Last Minute of play - As the lead NHL 08 Profile Score a goal in the last minute of play on Superstar Mode. - 25G AHL upset - As the lead NHL 08 Profile Beat an NHL team with an AHL team on Superstar Mode - 25G Elite League upset - As the lead NHL 08 Profile Beat an NHL team with an Elite League team on Superstar Mode - 25GDropping the butterfly Penalty Shot Hero - As the lead NHL 08 Profile Score a goal on the penalty shot in Pro Mode - 25G Stay out of the box - As the lead NHL 08 Profile Play an entire game in Superstar Mode without getting a penalty - 25G He Shoots, He Scores - As the lead NHL 08 Profile Score a goal with the Goalie on Superstar Mode - 25G Players of the game - As the lead NHL 08 Profile Earn all 3 stars in Superstar Mode - 25G Create a Team - As the lead NHL 08 Profile use a Created Team in a Play Now game - 25G Create a Skater - As the lead NHL 08 Profile use a Created Skater in a Play Now game - 25G Create a Goalie - As the lead NHL 08 Profile use a Created Goalie in a Play Now game - 25G Goalie's nightmare - As the lead NHL 08 Profile Score 70 Goals with one player in Dynasty Mode - 50G On a roll - As the lead NHL 08 Profile Win 5 games in a row in the Playoffs in Dynasty Mode - 50G Regular Season best - As the lead NHL 08 Profile have your Team finish the regular season with the best overall record - 50G Tournament Champs - As the lead NHL 08 Profile Win the EA Sports World Tournament - 50G Fun for all - As the lead NHL 08 Profile Be on the winning team in an Online Team Play game - 25G Playing as a team - As NHL 08 Lead Profile win an Online Ranked VS. Game with a friend on the same Xbox 360 console - 50G OT Winner - As the lead NHL 08 Profile Win an Online Ranked Versus Game in Overtime - 25G Shootout Mastery - As the lead NHL 08 Profile Win an Online Ranked Versus Game in Shootout Overtime - 50G Shorthanded, No Problem - As the lead NHL 08 Profile Score a Shorthanded Goal in an Online Ranked Versus Game - 25G Seeing lots of rubber - As the lead NHL 08 Profile Record 40 shots or more on goal in an Online Ranked Versus Game - 50G Shutting the door - As the lead NHL 08 Profile Record a shutout in an Online Ranked Versus Game - 50G Shootout King - As the lead NHL 08 Profile Play 25 Online Ranked Shootout Games - 25G Online all the time - As the lead NHL 08 Profile Play 50 Online Ranked Versus Games - 75G Beating tough competition - As the lead NHL 08 Profile Beat an opponent ranked Online in the Top 50 - 100G </description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="39">Hockey</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22131">NHL 2K8</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2276030-box_nhl08.png</image></root>