<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18231</id><name>Tony Hawk's Underground 2: Remix</name><description>StoryThis game is very similar to Tony Hawk's underground 2, except that there are some events that are very and vastly different than the original game.You begin the game by creating a character, or using the default created skater from the previous game. The game starts when your created skater (or the default) is seen ripping it up at a local spot of New Jersey, a level from the previous game, then, a mysterious van raced upon the player and the player was promptly smashed and tossed into the Van by two bloody-masked costumed kidnappers. Inside, you find other skaters who have been kidnapped too such as Eric Sparrow (The player's rival), Mike Vallely, Wee Man, Paulie Ryan, Rodney Mullen, Bob Burnquist, Chad Muska, Eric Koston, and the Player as well. Then, Bam Margera and Tony Hawk appeared and explained their plans for the first annual World Destruction Tour, a "sick-as-hell" around-the-world skateboarding tour that they both put together and the kidnapped skaters will get the opportunity to join. The main goal of the World Destruction Tour is to create havoc, create chaos and have a good time. The skaters then split into two teams, Team Hawk and Team Bam, and you are picked last out of the group, but joined Team Hawk. The tour goes to real world locations like Boston, Santa Cruz, Australia, New Orleans, Las Vegas, Atlanta, Kyoto, Berlin, and Skatopia and more, with the two teams competing for points by doing silly and dangerous stunts. The story is very lighthearted and just plain silly at times, featuring such characters like Big Foot stealing an engineer skateboard, skeletons doing the bidding of the dead by a demon wizard, The bull going rampage after a mime, Cannons blasting at a construction site, a boat sailing at the sea without a sailor, Fire blasting up two round things and creating destruction at night, Destruction by a mysterious statue two times by a stupid sleeping construction worker, pieces of trains creating hovak by a train stopped by a disturbance, a monster appearing with action to beat up a japan superhero, a piece of cash statue falling to a mini cash bank with created chaos, and three steps to go to an alien ship, a mayan temple, and a mysterious place named hell. The team's first stop is Santa Cruz.. You must do some goals to accomplish. When the player goes with the guest skater, there would be a storm coming up. Eric Sparrow was trying to fight to walk on the storm, and the beach got wet. Then, the player would have access to the Arcade room. After that, The Player and Rodney Mullen would spill Pee or something on a Show-Off Surfer. He would go after the player and Rodney Mullen. After that, you would meet The both teams and Bam Mangera was disappointed because almost all of the both teams clearly suck EXCEPT for Mike Vallely who had a beautiful Woman in his arms. Then Bam told Phil Mangera, his Dad to spin the Wheel of Loogies. Bam spit the Wheel of Loogies for the faith. Then Phil took the card that Bam spit and it was called "Sink or Swim". which means one of the Rookies or Losers needs to step forward to do the stunt and Bam was talking to player to get in front. The player would have to do a 500 Grab trick and some air to get to the other building. The Player won and He / She would move to Atlanta or Boston. If you chose Atlanta, then you completed some of the goals, after you completed some goals, Mike Vallely and Bob Burnquist tried to make a ridiculous stunt and the cops tried to get them. The Cops tried but Bam and his team would blow paddleballs on the cops and they retreated. When Bam's team won, Phil spinned the Wheel of Loogies and Bam spit on one of the Cards. This time Phil grabbed the Spitted Card and it was "Cut One Loose" that which means one of the teamates will be eliminated. When there was a phone call on Vallely's cellphone, they said that the Cops arrested Bob Burnquist when Bam was throwing the paddleballs. that means Bob is the one eliminated. If you chose Boston, then the story would be different. After you comlpeted some goals, A dumb fat guy was talking with a beautiful woman. Then Bam would throw paddleballs on him and the Dumb Fat guy collapsed. Then when Bam's team won, Phil spinned the Wheel of Loogies and Bam spit on one of the Cards. This time Phil grabbed the Spitted Card and it was "Cut One Loose" that which means one of the teamates will be eliminated. So all of th4e teammates would stand in a circle and Bam would aim and spin it to blow to the eliminated person and that when to the faith of Bob Burnquist who got his nuts hit by the Paddleball and that hurted. And transported Burnquist home. The next stop was Barcelona, Spain. after you get to 700 points (If in sick mode), There would be a message from Bob Burnquist and the Message would say : "In case anyone cares, yes, my nuts are finally healing and I can still see the Mark of the paddleball...Thanks". After you completed the goals, This time, Tony's team won and The Wheel of Loogies would go to Bam's team and this time, one of both team's teamates would have to switch onto the other team, So Eric Sparrow was switched to Tony's team while the player would be switched to Bam's team. That was a relief to Bam, but an annoyance to Tony. The Player now will join Bam's team along with Wee-Man, Paulie Ryan, Phil Margera, Eric Coston, and some other teammates too. The player would decide to go to Kyoto or Berlin. If you chose Kyoto, it would be different. If you switched players with Voltraman, he would sticker slap on the alarms as his goal and a Big Monster would appear. Voltraman would make a big blast on him and he would turn to little Monsters., After that, Eric Sparrow would try to do a trick, but failed and fell on a chinese biulding. The player would return to the team. After that in the game, the teams meet Nigel Beaverhausen, a strange documentarist, who wants to film the tour for the public. Both teams refuse, and instead play a joke on him and would head to Austrilia. If you chose Berlin, the story once again will be different. After you complete some goals, You will meet Natas Kaupas. And he will teach you a brand new trick and it's his signiture move and it's the new trick in Tony Hawk's Underground 2 REMIX By Natas Kaupas. It's called the Natas Spin. The Player will need to find a water pump or something and press R The Triangle button on the Pump to do the Natas Spin. After you complete goals, Eric Sparrow would try to do a trick, but failed and got hit by an ice-cream cart. Then the player would return to the team After that in the game, the teams meet Nigel Beaverhausen, a strange documentarist, who wants to film the tour for the public. Both teams refuse, and instead play a joke on himand would head to Austrilia. On Austrillia, If you Natas Spin the Hydrodent thing, then it will wake up the sleeping Contruction site person and he will start to wake up and would make a disaster and everyone would panic and some places will be crashed on destruction. After that, If you switched to the secret skater, he will grind the Construction site car and it will make more destruction than ever. After you complete some goals, At the end of the leg, the player is supposed to be eliminated by being hit by mousetraps launched at him/her for getting the last points of the team, but due to Phil Mangera spotting a mathematical error in the teams points, Bam puts a mouse trap on Phil's ear and everyone laughed. This means that Since Eric Sparrow and The Player that got the last points, They have to compete until when a Kid Skater asked Tony to make an autograph of a video and when Bam, Tony, and everyone else saw it, it was the video of the tour, created by Nigel Beaverhausen. Bam then decides that whoever humiliates Beaverhousen will stay on the tour. So, the player won and Nigel Beaverhousen was wedged on the top while Eric Sparrow was elimated from the tour. As Eric was wailing, Beaverhousen fell on Eric by his butt. The player would decide to go to New Orleans or Las Vegas. If you chose New Orleans, there is two surprises. When you raise something from the dead, There is a Reaper Clown who raised skulls and told them to combine into Zombies. Then the player would make an Airwalk and the Spirit would blast the Reaper Clown away from the dead. After you complete several goals, Bam returns with two guys who is racing with him and were hit. When Nigel BeaverHousen returned, He made another offer to them. This time, they accepted it because Nigel Promised that he will pay all of the entire events they have done. After Bam told the guy to spit, The new goal is called "The Equilizer" and both teams are both screwed up. The player would acid Drops, climbs, and Spine Transfers. After that, The other teamates fell on the pond with the police helicopter and the police arrested all of them EXCEPT for the Player, Tony Hawk, and Bam Mangera, who escaped from the stunt challenge. they would go the Skatopia. If you chose Las Vegas, the story once agian will be different. After that, When Nigel BeaverHousen returned, He made another offer to them. This time, they accepted it because Nigel Promised that he will pay all of the entire events they have done. After Bam told the guy to spit, The new goal is called "The Equilizer" and both teams are both screwed up. The player would acid Drops and climbs. After that, The other teamates fell on the building with the police helicopter and the police arrested all of them EXCEPT for the Player, Tony Hawk, and Bam Mangera, and went to skatopia. When They went to Skatopia, Bam told Tony and the Player that they will never win him. So, when the Player just found a Chainsaw for Jessie James and he was going to make you a Chainsaw Skateboard, A monster named Bigfoot arrived at the Scene and Stole the Chainsaw Skateboard at made destruction through Skatopia on the trees. After you complete the goals, Bam was tired of it. He decided to explode the place. After Bam puts bombs and everything, Tony found out and told everyone single person and animal (Espesialy Ryan Shekler and Bigfoot) to get out of Skatopia and escaped safley while the player was still on the mountain of Skatopia. Bam dared the player to get out of the place in a skating combo for 1000 points. So the player won and Tony's team won. As the rest of the teammates Phil, Mike, Rodney, Paulie, Chad, Eric Koston, Wee-Man, and some other teammates came back by robbing Beaverhousen's Trailer as Beaverhousen came back again too with another of his trailers. Nigel asked the both teams of where is the World Destruction Tour tape. Bam gave him the tape and on the screen was Phil Margera pooping on the toilet. Nigel Beaverhausen was officialy embarrassed and all the skaters laughed and Tony grabbed the speaker as Bam gave Nigel a wedgie and Nigel Beaverhousen secremed and that was actually the end of the Tony Hawk Underground 2 REMIX story era. Classic ModeAs well as the story you can also play the classic mode. which allows players to skate through both new and remade classic levels in the traditional 10-goal, two-minute time limit mode which where included in the first of the Tony Hawk games. Some of the levels in classic mode are remakes from other Tony Hawk games.Unlockables Completion bonusesComplete story mode under the easy difficulty setting to unlock Shrek and Space Monkey characters.Successfully complete story mode under the normal difficulty setting to unlock the Alien Doctor, Boat Captain, Lost Soul 1, Paulie Ryan, and The Hand characters; and Tony Hawk's Pro Skater School, Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3 Canada, and Pro Skater levels.Complete all classic mode goals under the sick difficulty setting to unlock the Australian Cop, Bratwurst Vendor, Corn Vendor, German Cop, German Drunk, Horn Player, Lost Soul 2, Metal Detector Man, Pirate, Skatopia Punk, and Zombie 2 characters; and the Downhill Jam level in free skate mode.Complete all gaps to unlock all food vendors, all musicians, the Bigfoot One, Boxer, Inline Skater, Lost Soul 3, Lounge Singer, Mayan, Skaboto, and Space Monkey 3 characters; and the Always Special, Moon Gravity, Perfect Grind, Perfect Manual, and Perfect SkitchNew TricksThese are the new tricks:Natas Spain (R The Triangle Button) On a Pump.Flips / Rolls ( Hold The Square or Circle Button and press up, down, left, and right to do any Roll combination.)Vert Wallieplant ( Go and jump on a ramp and press the X button to to the vert walleplant.)Sticker Slap (go directly to a wall and jump and press the X button twice to sticker slap to the opposite direction.)Graffiti Tag ( When you're walking or you can doing a combo run out, go straight to a wall a spray out your graffiti tag by pressing the triangle button.)Powerslide ( double tap the down direction button and press the R button to revert twice, but in the opposite direction)CheatsPerfect rail balanceEntertightropeas a code to unlock the "Perfect Rail Balance" option at the cheat menu during a game. Original Tony Hawk's Pro Skater Tony HawkEnter birdman as a code. Choose the "Secret Characters" option at the character selection screen in classic or free skate mode to access the original Tony Hawk.Moon GravityEnter icanfly as a code to unlock the "Moon Gravity" option at the cheat menu during a game. Perfect Manual BalenceEnter wheelie as a code to unlock the "Perfect Manual balence" option at the cheat menu during a game Perfect skichesEnter grabaride as a code to unlock " Perfect Skiches balence" option at the cheat menu during a game Always SpecialEnter imonfire as a code to unlock "Always special" option at the cheat menu during a game</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="23">Skateboarding</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20661">Skate 2</game><game id="5228">skate.</game><game id="8819">Skate or Die</game><game id="1013">The Simpsons Skateboarding</game><game id="8445">Disney's Extremely Goofy Skateboarding</game><game id="25647">Transworld Surf: Next Wave</game><game id="25743">Sunny Garcia Surfing</game><game id="28135">Skate 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2269422-box_thug2r.png</image></root>