<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18232</id><name>Track &amp; Field</name><description>Overview110m HurdlesTrack  Field is an Olympic themed arcade game developed and published by Konami. It is known as Hyper Olympic in Japan.It has been ported to over nine different platforms including the NES, as well as Xbox Live Arcade, since its original release.Track  Field introduced a button-mashing style of gameplay in which the player must press a button as fast as possible, and their in-game character interacts with the environment accordingly. This style of gameplay is still used today by many popular titles. The arcade release accomodated up to four players at once. The NES version (arguably the most popular) was designed for only two players. Track  Field has received graphical and sound updates, leaderboards, online play, and additional events since its initial release in 1983.GameplayLong JumpIn the arcade version of Track  Field, players had two "run" buttons and one "action" button. The run buttons were used to increase the speed of the character on-screen, while the action button was used to do things like initiate a jump or adjust the angle of a javelin throw. The Nes version (possibly due to hardware limitations) had only one run button.100 Meter Dash110 Meter HurdlesHammer ThrowHigh JumpJavelin ThrowLong JumpIn each event, there is a qualifying time or level that the player must achieve to advance to the next event; failing to qualify (in one heat for running events or three tries in the other events) ends the game. Events that were later added to Track  Field after the arcade release include: 100-meter freestyle, skeet shooting, vault, archery, triple jump, weight lifting, and pole vault.Xbox Live ArcadeA slightly enhanced version of Track  Field was released for XBLA in 2007. It includes full Xbox Live support (ranked and player matches) and in-depth leaderboards.The Track  Field LegacyArchery was added after the original arcade release.Over the years, Konami released several games featuring gameplay from the same vein as the original:Konami '88 (1988) (Arcade)Track  Field II (1988) (NES)Track  Field (1992) (Game Boy)International Track  Field (1996) (PS)Hyper Athlete (1996) (Arcade)Nagano Winter Olympics '98 (1998) (N64, PS)International Track  Field 2000 (1999) (N64, PS, GBC)ESPN International Track  Field (2000) (DC, PS2, GBC)Track and Field (2007) (Xbox Live Arcade)New International Track  Field (2008) (NDS)</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="42">Track &amp; Field</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20619">New International Track &amp; Field</game><game id="21617">Rayman: Raving Rabbids</game><game id="19786">Boot Camp</game><game id="20471">Beijing 2008: The Official Video Game of the Olympic Games</game><game id="7309">Stadium Events</game><game id="12273">Olympic Summer Games</game><game id="22678">Summer Athletics</game><game id="10667">Dance Aerobics</game><game id="15063">The Activision Decathlon</game><game id="3788">Microsoft Decathlon</game><game id="14643">Decathlete</game><game id="11985">Snoopy's Silly Sports Spectacular</game><game id="40518">The Triathron</game><game id="40811">Track Meet</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/13/139866/2435938-18013501.jpg</image></root>