<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18240</id><name>The King of Fighters 2003</name><description>OverviewThe last King of Fighters for the Neo-Geo gaming console, introduced the children of Rugal Bernstein's storyline, with a new main character named Ash Crimson. Unlike previous main characters in the series, Ash Crimson plays an anti-hero whose only out for himself. The game has different endings depending on how well you do before reaching the final boss. This has become a common theme in the series since King of Fighters 97. Rushing to finish the game will get you nothing but ending credits. However, if you meet the conditions, then you'll see the real conclusion for each team in the game. Unfortunately, SNK's tradition for making nearly impossible to beat final bosses, is also alive and well in this gameCharactersHero TeamAsh CrimsonDuo LonShen WooFatal Fury TeamTerry BogardJoe HigashiTizocArt of Fighting TeamRyo SakazakiRobert GarciaYuri SakazakiKorea TeamKim KaphwanChang KoehanJhun HoonIkari Warriors TeamLeonaRalf JonesClark SteelOutlaw TeamGatoBilly KaneRyuji YamazakiWomen Fighters TeamKingMai ShiranuiBlue MaryBenimaru TeamBenimaru NikaidoShingo YabukiGoro DaimonHigh School Girls TeamAthena AsamiyaHinako ShijouMalinK' TeamK'MaximaWhipThree Sacred Treasures TeamKyo Kusanagi (also with an EX version, known as the evil clone Kusanagi)Iori YagamiChizuru Kagura (also a sub-boss)OtherMaki Kagura (sub-boss)Adelheid Bernstein (boss)Mukai (boss)Unlocking the Fake and Real game endingsTo reach the fake final boss, finish possessed Kusanagi (Mid-boss) with a normal move. This results in the game suddenly ending with rolling credits, after beating the fake final boss.To reach the real final boss and see the real endings, finish possessed Kusanagi (Mid-boss) with a special finishing move. This will take you to the real climax, followed by the ending for each team, should you defeat the final boss.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7751">Art of Fighting Anthology</game><game id="22629">Rage of the Dragons</game><game id="3744">Def Jam: Fight for NY</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="16793">Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="11156">X-Men vs. Street Fighter</game><game id="9309">Marvel Super Heroes Vs. Street Fighter</game><game id="13999">Kizuna Encounter: Super Tag Battle</game><game id="8605">Marvel vs. Capcom: Clash of Super Heroes</game><game id="4348">Project Justice</game><game id="18484">Killer Instinct</game><game id="21952">Killer Instinct 2</game><game id="10614">Killer Instinct Gold</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1614/840967-kof03_ng_jp.jpg</image></root>