<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18288</id><name>Last Bronx</name><description>OverviewReleased in May 1996, the same month as Soul Blade, the competition was steep from the beginning.Looking at the specifications and the reputation of the previously released games, Last Bronx would seem to be a sure winner. It was launched on Sega's model 2 board, and Sega had an excellent history with previous fighting games (Fighting Vipers, Virtua Fighter 1, 2, and the third installment which would be released in arcades later that year). Soul Blade's developer Namco had only released Tekken 1 and 2 in the 3d fighting genre, and so Last Bronx appeared to be the favorite, but in fact it was Soul Blade that became the more popular of the two games.Last Bronx was, despite the arcade competition, released for the Sega Saturn in 1997 and later the PC and Playstation 2 (as part of the Sega Ages series of releases for PS2 in japan).Last Bronx is a fighting game where the characters wield weapons similar to Soul Blade and Battle Arena Toshinden.The game is very fast paced and included the same three button system as the Virtua Fighter series, GUARD, PUNCH (weapon swing), and KICK.CharactersCharacters in the game are all gang leaders of different gangs.There are 8 playable characters initially, with one additional unlockable character.Joe - Metal NunchakuLisa - Doble Baston (two metal sticks)Ken Kono (Redeye) - Steel TonfasKudo - Samjiegun (three-section-staff)Kurosawa - Wooden Training KatanaNagi - Dual SaisSaburo - Giant Wooden HammerTommy - Bo/StaffYoko - Wooden Tonfas</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5662">Fighting Vipers</game><game id="1513">Battle Arena Toshinden Remix</game><game id="15584">Virtua Fighter</game><game id="5238">Battle Arena Toshinden</game><game id="10081">Tekken</game><game id="5692">Samurai Shodown</game><game id="16407">Samurai Shodown II</game><game id="8768">Capcom vs. SNK: Millennium Fight 2000</game><game id="12312">SNK vs. Capcom: Match of the Millennium</game><game id="20728">Tatsunoko vs. Capcom: Ultimate All Stars</game><game id="8605">Marvel vs. Capcom: Clash of Super Heroes</game><game id="12125">Capcom Fighting Evolution</game><game id="1235">Street Fighter</game><game id="4819">Cyber Troopers Virtual-On: Oratorio Tangram</game><game id="3744">Def Jam: Fight for NY</game><game id="2410">Def Jam: Vendetta</game><game id="6399">Bushido Blade</game><game id="10218">World Heroes Anthology</game><game id="18554">World Heroes</game><game id="4249">The King of Fighters '94</game><game id="2760">Art of Fighting</game><game id="7751">Art of Fighting Anthology</game><game id="14078">Primal Rage</game><game id="18484">Killer Instinct</game><game id="489">ClayFighter</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="16444">Eternal Champions</game><game id="8021">Eternal Champions: Challenge from the Dark Side</game><game id="4747">World Karate Championship</game><game id="3839">Dead or Alive</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/19134/859913-lb_cover_us.jpg</image></root>