<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18320</id><name>WCW/nWo Revenge</name><description>OverviewThe game would become THQ’s swan song for its WCW license on the N64. They produced 1 more WCW game for the PS1, before acquiring the WWE license. The game is regarded as one of the best wrestling games, and possibly the best WCW game developed for the consoles. With the highest average rating of any WCW game on GameRankings. The gameplay accommodated very competitive multi-player, and really captured the WCW atmosphere with great animations, and presentation, and a huge roster.Differences From WCW vs. nWo World TourRevenge introduced many new features not included in the original World Tour. This includes wrestler entrances, the ability to bring weapons into the ring, and an instant replay feature. Other additions include new arenas based on the WCW's shows and pay-per-view events and the ability to edit the costumes and names of existing wrestlers. The game also introduced multiple Special moves.GameplayLike world tour, the controls focus offensively on weak/strong attacks  grapples. Defensively the game focused on the timing of blocking and evades. The Left button acted as evade, while the right button acted as block. If the player timed a block correctly, they could counter an enemies attack. For example, if Goldberg attempted a spear and the player blocked too early Goldberg would simply be unsuccessful. If timed perfectly, Goldberg would be caught in a submission. The gameplay was highly centered on balance. Opponent’s taunts and special moves could be used against them. By rotating the analog stick counter clockwise a taunt could be stolen. If an opponent had a devastating finishing move, it could be stolen by executing a successful grapple with the special meter flashing, and pressing A B at the same time.One major issue with the game once discovered was the analog break. If a player was caught in a submission or pin, they could repeatedly push the analog stick in a direction to break free. This rendered a pin or submission attempt virtually useless against other human players.PresentationHow Many nWo members can Sting take out with his bat this match?The game really captured the WCW product presentation wise. Players contained signature entrances, and taunts. Wrestlers had multiple special moves, and many signature holds. The game included the Nitro arena, along with more popular PPV themes like Starcade.ArenasMonday NitroStarrcadeBash at the BeachSouled OutSuperbrawlHalloween HavocWeapons ListChainSuit caseBlack bat ( Sting Trademark)Silver batTrophyMicrophoneStop signTrash canChair ( La Parka Trademark)Broken Table FragmentRosternWo Hollywood"Hollywood" Hulk HoganThe GiantBrian AdamsScott HallScott NortonBuff BagwellEric BischoffScott SteinerCurt Hennig (Unlock by beating U.S. Championship)nWo WolfpackKevin NashStingLex LugerRandy SavageKonnanRaven's FlockRavenLodiScotty RiggsSick BoyReeseKidman (Unlock by beating Cruiserweight Championship)WCWRoddy Piper (Unlock by beating World Championship)Diamond Dallas PageGoldbergBret HartChris BenoitRick SteinerFit FinlayBooker TSaturnDisco InfernoJim NeidhartThe British BulldogGlacierMeng (Unlock by beating Tag Team Championship)Barbarian (Unlock by beating Tag Team Championship)Van HammerKanyon/Mortis (Unlock by beating Television Championship)Yuji NagataLarry ZbyszkoLa ParkaStevie RayWrath (Gameshark required)WCW (Cruiserweights)Chris JerichoEddie GuerreroPsychosisRey Mysterio, Jr.Dean MalenkoJuventud GuerreraUltimo DragonChavo Guerrero, Jr.Alex WrightEWFAKI Man / THQ ManShogunThe ExecutionerDr. FrankJekelMaya Inca BoyDAWHawk HanaKim CheeDake KenBrickowskiMing CheeHan Zo MonManagers(Playable by pressing Z on the 3rd or 4th controllers)Jimmy HartKimberly PageMiss ElizabethVincentRick RudeDusty RhodesSonny OnooCriticismsThe game was lacking in the sound department, largely in part to the restrictions of the N64 cartridge. The entrances consisted of a few possible midi sound clips. The game featured no match commentary, and no specific entrance themes.Collision detection remained an issue as in World tour. Though collision detection had been improved, many reviews claimed of issues with floating limbs, and bodies. The game was criticized as being too similar to World Tour.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="10">Wrestling</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12592">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2008</game><game id="1204">WCW Mayhem</game><game id="11394">WWF No Mercy</game><game id="3667">WWF Wrestlemania 2000</game><game id="3826">WWF Super Wrestlemania</game><game id="16435">WWF Attitude</game><game id="18801">WWF War Zone</game><game id="21620">WWE Day of Reckoning 2</game><game id="23212">Virtual Pro Wrestling 64</game><game id="26888">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2010</game><game id="9216">Power Move Pro Wrestling</game><game id="30637">Lucha Libre AAA Heroes del Ring</game><game id="13440">Backyard Wrestling: Don't Try This at Home</game><game id="18333">Backyard Wrestling 2: There Goes the Neighborhood</game><game id="28430">WWF Royal Rumble</game><game id="23213">Virtual Pro Wrestling 2: Ōdō Keishō</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2409917-box_wcwnwor.png</image></root>