<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18380</id><name>Sacred Gear</name><description>Overview Sacred Gear is a 2D action multiplayer shooter that was developed and published by Baphomet Games for the PC in 2006. Sacred Gear was developed by 22 students from Blekinge Institute of Technology in Sweden. This group of 22 students was called Baphomet Games. The goal of Baphomet Games was to complete a game with the 22 students in 10 weeks.  Gameplay Sacred Gear is a class based deathmatch/team deathmatch online enabled game. The goal of the game is simple, eliminate all of the opposition. All of the flying abilities and weaponry rely on the use of steam. The player has a steam gauge which will deplete with use. The steam will refill when not in use.  Classes Vanguard   The Vanguard Class     Vanguard is the heavy defense class of Sacred Gear. The Vanguard class is the slowest class, but makes up for it in the defensive power.   Special Ability Warstomp - Warstomp will send a shockwave out from the Vanguard depleting the steam gauges of nearby opposing players. Warstomp will also drain half of the users steam gauge.Nemesis   The Nemesis Class     The Nemesis is the quickest of the classes in Sacred Gear. The Nemesis is about picking off opponents from far away rather than up close. The Nemesis has a sniper rifle named the Gods Eye.  Special Ability Crystal Trance - Crystal Trance will turn the player invisible. While the player is invisible the steam gauge will continuously deplete. The invisibility will last as long as there is steam in the steam gauge.Templar   The Templar     The Templar is the balanced class in Sacred Gear. The Templar has medium armor and speed, but has no special ability. The Templar class also carries a grenade launcher.  Vehicles In Sacred Gear there are two vehicles that can be used to help destroy the enemies. The Grinder   The Grinder     The Grinder is a spiked wheel that will kill an enemy on contact. In order to both drive the Grinder and use its spiked weapon, two players will have to work together. The first player that enters the Grinder will be in control of driving it while the second player will be in control of the weapon. A third player can also enter the Grinder and use a mounted flamethrower called the Witchburner.  The Stormbrig   The Stormbrig     The Stormbrig is an airship rather than a ground vehicle and may fly to any location on the game map. The Stormbrig contains a large cannon named the Haymaker which fires a large lead ball. The lead ball will bounce around the level, killing any player it comes in contact with. When the large lead ball comes to a stop it will then explode, hurting anyone in its vicinity. The Stormbrig can be controlled by two players, the first player controls where the ship moves and controls the Haymaker while the second player controls a machine gun turret.  Download The game can be freely downloaded by visiting Baphomet Games official website  here</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/10/103881/1846405-sacredgear.jpg</image></root>