<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18419</id><name>Land of the Dead: Road to Fiddler's Green</name><description>OverviewLand of the Dead: Road to Fiddler's Green is a 2005 video game prequel to George Romero's zombie film Land of the Dead. It was developed by Brainbox Games for the PC and Xbox. Road to Fiddler's Green is about a farmer named Jack who is desperately trying to survive a landscape full of ravenous zombies as he makes his way to the so-called City of the Living, Fiddler's Green.Critical ReceptionThe game was widely panned by critics for its poor frame rate, collision detection, and A.I. problems. Former GameSpot editor Alex Navarro wrote of the PC version of the game:"There is an almost pseudo-brilliance to the sheer awfulness of Land of the Dead: Road to Fiddler's Green. Loosely based within the same universe as zombie pioneer George Romero's Land of the Dead film from earlier this year, Road to Fiddler's Green isn't content on being another completely unplayable movie-to-game translation. It's almost as though the developers wanted to capture the essence of the zombie through each and every aspect of the game. In many ways, it feels like it was once a regular, workaday, full-featured first-person shooter that was horribly murdered by zombies and then resurrected into a shambled, decrepit, undead version of its former self. Every component of this game is slow to react, dumb as a doornail, and irreparably broken. It shuffles along at a sluggish, depressing pace while pieces of it literally fall apart at the seams. And the only thing going through its figurative mind is the unquenchable instinct to attack and feed on your free time and money. This game is either one of the most avant-garde pieces of gaming artistry to ever find its way to the retail market, or one of the worst PC games you'll ever play--though, it's probably the latter."</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="38900">The Walking Dead: Survival Instinct</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/11095/1338269-land_of_the_dead.jpg</image></root>