<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18519</id><name>Phalanx</name><description>GameplayThe first stage in the game. The background is comprised of seven layers of parallax scrolling.Phalanx is a side-scrolling space shooter. The ship which the player controls has the ability to switch between three different movement speeds, allowing for greater dexterity when avoiding enemy threats. Also unlike most space-shooters, the player's ship can take up to three hit points worth of damage, and an item existed which would restore this health. There are three different difficulty levels available at the start, a fourth can be accessed by entering a cheat code.The player's ship has three slots for weapons, which can be switched between at will. When the player grabs a fourth weapon, the one which they are currently equipped with will be switched out with it. Dropping a weapon will create a "smart bomb" effect which differs depending on the weapon which was dropped.BoxartThe Game Boy Advance version features more representative cover art.The gameplay of this title has been significantly overshadowed by its SNES box art, which instead of depicting a space ship fighting or anything relevant like that, instead features an old man playing a banjo with a spaceship zooming in the background, with the words "The Hyper-Speed Shoot-Out In Space" to the right of the man. The publisher has stated that the decision was made due to wanting to do something different. Versions of the game which came on other platforms featured different pictures that came without old banjo men.</description><genres><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13745">R-Type</game><game id="15508">Gradius</game><game id="8479">Super R-Type</game><game id="19750">R-Type II</game><game id="3458">R-Type III: The Third Lightning</game><game id="3623">Gradius II</game><game id="7617">Gradius III</game><game id="3955">Sigma Star Saga</game><game id="2211">Mogura Reverse</game><game id="32758">Gaia Seed</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2364533-snes_phalanx.jpg</image></root>