<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18603</id><name>World of Warcraft: The Burning Crusade</name><description> World of Warcraft: The Burning Crusade is the first expansion pack for     Blizzard's popular MMORPG,  World of Warcraft. It was released in North America, Europe and Oceania on January 16, 2007 and sold 2.4 million copies in its first day. These sales figures made  World of Warcraft: The Burning Crusade the best-selling PC "game" of 2007.FeaturesThe level cap was increased from 60 to 70.Two new playable races. The     Blood Elves and     Draenei. Each with their own major city in their respective faction.     Silvermoon City and     the Exodar.The Blood Elves are addicted to mana, and as a result all of their playable classes use mana in some way, aside from their rogues, who use energy. They were once the valiant High Elves, but after their kingdom was utterly destroyed by the undead Scourge, they have been forced to live with their constant need for magic. They despise the     Alliance, whom they believe abandoned them to the undead, but cannot survive without an affiliation in the struggle between the Alliance and     Horde, so they team up with the     Orcs,     Forsaken and other members of the     Horde.The Draenei are a shamanistic race, but have been chased by the evil Burning Legion for as long as they can remember and are forced to defend themselves, which is ultimately fruitless, and find themselves crash landing on     Azeroth. They sought help from the first friendly beings they could find - the Alliance. The peaceful Draenei now join the Alliance in the fight against the Burning Legion, their mortal enemies.Jewel-crafting - a new crafting profession. This profession allows you to make gems for high level armor, which you can socket and improve stats with. They can also make jewellery like necklaces and rings.A new region was added to accommodate those characters reaching the new level cap -     Outland, the otherworldly remains of the exploded planet   Draenor, once home to both the Draenei and Orc  races.Outland contains 6 zones:     Hellfire Peninsula, Zangarmarsh,     Terokkar Forest, Nagrand, Blade's Edge Mountains, Netherstorm and Shadowmoon Valley.In addition to the new zones, many instances were added to the zones in Outland. 11 instances can be attempted while leveling through levels 60-70, with 5 specifically for those at the level cap.As an added challenge, all of the     Outland instances have a "heroic" mode. This provides a much harder challenge for groups while still keeping the same feel of the normal instance.There are 9 raid instances, which are meant to be completely in groups of 10 or 25 people, depending on the raid. This is the ultimate challenge for Player versus Environment (     PvE) focused characters.The different raids and instances pit you against some of the most powerful beings in the known Warcraft universe. Gruul, who single-handedly defeated most of the Black Dragonfight, awaits adventurers in his lair.     Illidan Stormrage from     Warcraft III and its expansion is now able to be killed in a very complex and difficult battle atop of his     Black Temple.The Player versus Player (     PvP) system has been completely reworked, and Arenas have been introduced. These are basically duels in groups of either 2, 3 or 5 people and is the ultimate challenge for PvP players.Daily Quests (Dailies) were introduced to the game with this expansion. They are quests that are repeatable each day that lead to various rewards such as equipment, tabards, non-combat pets, crafting recipes, and mounts.Changes in Later PatchesThe difficulty of many quests in the various  Burning Crusade zones have been inexplicably lowered since the release of  Cataclysm. Several group quests have been altered, usually without changing the quest rewards. For instance, the giant stone monsters     in this early Hellfire Peninsula quest chain are no longer Elite, so the quest can be now be finished  without a group.InstancesThe Burning Crusade added many new instances to the game and also added Heroic Mode which offered upgraded versions of all the 5 man instances. The Burning Crusade also did away with 40 man raids and added many high level 5 man instances.5-Man DungeonsHellfire CitadelHellfire RampartsLocation: Hellfire PeninsulaLevel Range: 60-62Player Cap: 5The Blood FurnaceLocation: Hellfire PeninsulaLevel Range: 61-63Player Cap: 5Shattered HallsLocation: Hellfire PeninsulaLevel Range: 69-70Player Cap: 5Coilfang ReservoirSlave PensLocation: ZangarmarshLevel Range: 62-64Player Cap: 5The UnderbogLocation: ZangarmarshLevel Range: 63-65Player Cap: 5The SteamvaultLocation: ZangarmarshLevel Range: 70Player Cap: 5AuchindounMana-TombsLocation: Terokkar ForestLevel Range: 64-66Player Cap: 5Auchenai CryptsLocation: Terokkar ForestLevel Range: 65-67Player Cap: 5Sethekk HallsLocation: Terokkar ForestLevel Range: 67-69Player Cap: 5Shadow LabyrinthLocation: Terokkar ForestLevel Range: 69-70Player Cap: 5Caverns of TimeEscape from Durnholde KeepLocation: TanarisLevel Range: 66-68Player Cap: 5Opening the Dark PortalLocation: TanarisLevel Range: 68-70Player Cap: 5Tempest KeepThe MechanarLocation: NetherstormLevel Range: 70Player Cap: 5The BotanicaLocation: NetherstormLevel Range: 70Player Cap: 5The ArcatrazLocation: NetherstormLevel Range: 70Player Cap: 5Magisters' TerraceLocation: Isle of Quel'DanasLevel Range: 70Player Cap: 510 Man RaidsKarazhanLocation: Deadwind PassLevel Range: 70Player Cap: 10Zul'AmanLocation: GhostlandsLevel Range: 70Player Cap: 1025 Man RaidsSerpentshine CavernLocation: ZangarmarshLevel Range: 70Player Cap: 25Battle for Mount HyjalLocation: TanarisLevel Range: 70Player Cap: 25The EyeLocation: NetherstormLevel Range: 70Player Cap: 25Magtheridon's LairLocation: Hellfire PeninsulaLevel Range: 70Player Cap: 25Gruul's LairLocation: Blade's Edge MountainsLevel Range: 70Player Cap: 25Black TempleLocation: Shadowmoon ValleyLevel Range: 70Player Cap: 25Sunwell PlateauLocation: Isle of Quel'DanasLevel Range: 70Player Cap: 25New Races and Classes Alliance Dwarves:Hunter, Paladin, Priest, Rogue  Warrior Humans:Mage, Paladin, Priest, Rogue, Warlock  Warrior Night Elves:Druid, Hunter, Priest, Rogue  Warrior Gnomes:Mage, Rogue, Warlock  Warrior Draenei:Hunter, Mage, Paladin, Priest, Shaman  Warrior Horde Orcs:Hunter, Rogue, Shaman, Warlock  Warrior Undead:Mage, Priest, Rogue, Warlock  Warrior Tauren:Druid, Hunter, Shaman  Warrior Trolls:Hunter, Mage, Priest, Rogue, Shaman  Warrior Blood Elves:Hunter, Mage, Paladin, Priest  WarlockSoundtrackThe music for World of Warcraft:The Burning Crusade was created by Blizzard Entertainment's Sound Department and a copy of the games soundtrack was included as part of the Collectors Edition of the game.World of Warcraft: The Burning Crusade SoundtrackThe Burning Legion (Main Title) 3:58Shards of the Exodar 4:38The Sin'dorei 6:39The Dark Portal (Cinematic Intro) 2:57Origins 4:23Bloodmyst 4:16Wastelands 4:13Caverns of Time – The Battle of Mount Hyjal 2:30Azuremyst Isle 2:42Silvermoon City 2:11Netherstorm 4:20Caverns of Time – The Escape from Durnholde 4:28Outland Suite 2:44The Tower of Karazhan 4:15Illidan 3:10Caverns of Time – Opening of the Dark Portal 2:38Hellfire 1:59The Gates of Ahn'Qiraj (Exclusive Track) 4:00Shadow of the Necropolis (Exclusive Track) 4:22Taverns (Exclusive Track) 4:26Lament of the Highborne (Exclusive Track) 2:57System requirementsPC System RequirementsOS: Windows 2000 (Service Pack 4) or Windows XP (Service Pack 2)Processor: Intel Pentium3 800MHz or AMD Athlon 800MHzMemory:Minimum: 512 MB RAMRecommended: 1GB RAMVideo:Minimum: 32MB 3D graphics processor with Hardware Transform and Lighting, such as an NVIDIA GeForce 2 class card or aboveRecommended: 64MB VRAM 3D graphics processor with Vertex and Pixel Shader capability, such as an NVIDIA GeForce FX 5700 class card or aboveSound: DirectX-compatible sound cardMac System RequirementsOS: Mac OS X 10.3.9 or newerProcessor:Minimum: 933MHz G4/G5Recommended: 1.8GHz G5/IntelMemory:Minimum: 512MB RAMRecommended: 1GB DDR RAMVideo:Minimum: NVIDIA or ATI graphics processor with 32MB VRAMRecommended: 64MB VRAMAll PlatformsControls: A keyboard and mouse are required. Input devices other than a mouse and keyboard are not supported.Connectivity: You must have an active broadband Internet connection to play.Mouse: Multi-button mouse with scroll wheel recommended.PatchesFrom its release in January 2007 to the release of World of Warcraft: Wrath of the Lich King in November 2008, The Burning Crusade received several patches that added and altered features of the game.Patch 2.1 added "The Black Temple" Raid instance as well as the Nether Drake Questline.Patch 2.2 added built-in voice chat to the game as well as fixing many bugs.Patch 2.3 added the Raid Instance "Zul'Aman", Guild Banks and increased the leveling Speed for players below level 58.Patch 2.4 added the new area of "Quel'Danas" which contained several new daily quests and 2 new dungeons.Patch 3.0.2 added many features of "Wrath of the Lich King" to the game such as Barbershops, Inscription and also implemented an Achievements System into WoW.Patch 4.3 lowered the difficulty of many quests by replacing Elite mobs with regular versions.ESRBThe ESRB rated the game Teen for Blood, Suggestive Themes, Use of Alcohol, Violence.</description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12376">The Lord of the Rings Online: Shadows of Angmar</game><game id="9641">Age of Conan: Hyborian Adventures</game><game id="11142">Final Fantasy XI Online</game><game id="20666">Warhammer Online: Age of Reckoning</game><game id="7316">City of Villains</game><game id="11082">Guild Wars: Nightfall</game><game id="21399">Last Chaos</game><game id="18547">EverQuest II</game><game id="21707">Fury</game><game id="12149">Dark Age of Camelot</game><game id="4791">Vanguard: Saga of Heroes</game><game id="22085">CABAL Online</game><game id="22997">The Lord of the Rings Online: Mines of Moria</game><game id="23559">Priston Tale</game><game id="23572">Priston Tale 2</game><game id="22542">Ragnarok Online 2: The Gate of the World</game><game id="23433">Shin Megami Tensei: Imagine</game><game id="1036">RYL: Path of the Emperor</game><game id="24766">Cartoon Network Universe: FusionFall</game><game id="22187">Flyff - Fly For Fun</game><game id="23342">Tales of Pirates</game><game id="6204">EverQuest: The Shadows of Luclin</game><game id="8390">EverQuest: The Planes of Power</game><game id="13183">EverQuest: The Scars of Velious</game><game id="27876">Age of Conan: Rise of the Godslayer</game><game id="545">Asheron's Call</game><game id="13869">Istaria: Chronicles of the Gifted</game><game id="24336">Fiesta</game><game id="16614">Ragnarok Online</game><game id="27070">Mu Online</game><game id="29238">Allods Online</game><game id="29355">Tera</game><game id="23122">Warhammer 40,000: Dark Millennium Online</game><game id="33226">The Lord of the Rings Online: Rise of Isengard</game><game id="32285">EverQuest II: Destiny of Velious</game><game id="35853">EverQuest II: Age of Discovery</game><game id="38488">Rift: Storm Legion</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2276930-box_wowtbc.png</image></root>