<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18604</id><name>Sango Fighter</name><description>Sango Fighter is a 2D fighting game, in the vein of Street Fighter II, featuring numerous historical figures from China's Three Kingdoms era as playable characters, each with their own array of hand-to-hand attacks, weapons, and special moves.Sango Fighter boasts a story mode, where the player must fight against low-powered minions in one-on-one combat before taking on his nemesis during a given match. After this, the main enemy for that match will appear and the player will need to fight him without the benefit of recovering any health lost during the minion battle. After some of this fighting, the enemy may retreat, while another minion subs in, before returning for a last stand. In the regular "arcade" mode, the "minion" gameplay addition is left behind in favor of traditional fighting game cadence.Sango Fighter plays with one punch and one kick button, limiting the variety of normal attacks you can execute. However, it otherwise controls almost identically to a traditional 2D fighter, where pressing "up" causes your combatant to jump and pressing the direction away from your adversary causes him to block.Special attacks such as energy projectiles, body-launching moves and otherwise unique strikes are executed with a combination of directional presses and an attack button.In addition, backing away and blocking also increase a special meter underneath your life bar. As this meter fills, it will increase the potency of your special attacks--such as increasing the size and power of projectiles.Sango Fighter is one of the few games released for Funtech's Super A'Can 16-bit platform. It was also released on computing platforms, specifically from NEC, as well as DOS. On DOS, even without a sound card, Sango Fighter still featured digitized voices of characters shouting special moves as well as the usual array of fighting game grunts and exhortations (as well as music) which were played through the PC speaker.The game was never released in the United States by its developer, Panda Entertainment, officially, though it eventually saw a localized release by Accend--without Panda's approval.In 2009, after acquiring the license from the remnants of Panda Entertainment, Super Fighter Team re-released the game as freeware. They released it again in 2011, with a generic soldier as an unlockable character, as well as some minor tweaks to the engine.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9658">Dynasty Warriors</game><game id="13368">Sango Fighter 2</game><game id="40945">Wǔlín Zhēng Bà Zhī Yīngxióng Tiē</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/16/164924/2524870-2361047-sango.jpg</image></root>