<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18624</id><name>Thrasher Presents: Skate and Destroy</name><description>The CharactersPro'sCon'sAxlA good all-round skater, but tends to skate burley.He's very good at spinning, popping enormous ollies and flinging himself through the air.His tech skills are below par, but he can grind any rail, curb, coping with anything you throw at him.Tough and versatile, looks more like a surfer than a skater.Enormous OlliesKahliA good all-round skater but he tends to focus on fliptricks and ledges more than other street terrain.When it rains he busts raps on the streets to make ends meet.Can RapScabThe pure burler.Is horrible at all of the fliptricks but he rides faster, lands easier, and has a huge ollie.Has more torn flesh than a George A. Romero flick.Tattoo'sJasmineA good all-round skater.Most of her ratings are average but she is fairly good at half-pipe.A vertical fiend.She spins more than a spinning top but still sticks the tricks.Sticks TricksRoachA complete tech skater who excels at advanced fliptricks and grinds and has a bit harder time spinning.His ollies are quite low.H e doesn't wear underwear either.Hangs LowCyrusA good all-round skater.Most of his ratings are average but he has a fairly high ollie.He does below average fliptricks.Cyrus was raised by a pack of wolves until a hunter shot his whole family.Wolf BoyLevelsUSAHometownNew YorkThe SubwayWashington Square ParkBrooklyn Bridge BanksLos AngelesVenice BeachLA RiverThe CourthouseSan FranciscoChina BanksThe HillsEmbarcaderoInternationalSouth BankDer KolossuemSoundtrackRappers Delight - Sugarhill GangPlanet Rock (Elektric Mix) - Afrika Bambaataa  Soul Sonic ForceWhite Lines (Don't Do It) - Grandmaster FlashKing Of Rock - Run DMCI Know You Got Soul - Eric B  RakimRebel Without A Pause - Public EnemyKool Keith Housing Things - Ultramagnetic MC'sI'm Housing - EPMDTalking All That Jazz - StetasonicAward Tour - A Tribe Called QuestJust To Get A Rep - Gang StarrFreestyle Noize - The FreestylersMy Beatbox - Deejay Punk-RocCrossfader Dominator - SniperMultiplayerThere are seven different multiplayer modes available in Thrasher: Skate  Destroy but none are playable for two players simultaneously, all operate in a turn-by-turn fashion.Sessions - Each player has a two minute run to post the best total score.Nickel Bag - Players take turns at score the highest individual trick score..Horse - Players take turns at busting tricks in a 'simon says' fashionTop Dog - Each player takes a turn at busting a tick in five different locations within a level, highest total points wins.Sick Fix - Players take turns at inflicting the most damage to themselves, more damage equals more points.Long Grind - Execute the longest grind to win the round.Big Wallride - Biggest wall-ride 'arc' wins.CheatsType in the following names in the cheat menu to unlock different decks:ToddlandPorkboyThrillhoVengeMardukZontarBytorBee Suit GuyPick Roach without a hat. Enter BEESUITGUY as the name. Voila! You are wearing a bee suit.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="23">Skateboarding</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5228">skate.</game><game id="20661">Skate 2</game><game id="5464">Grind Session</game><game id="28135">Skate 3</game><game id="30195">Shaun White Skateboarding</game><game id="37026">Tony Hawk's Pro Skater HD</game><game id="42370">R: Rock'n Riders</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2269424-box_tpsad.png</image></root>