<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18673</id><name>Pokémon Yellow: Special Pikachu Edition</name><description>OverviewPokémon Yellow: Special Pikachu Edition is the fourth installment in the Pokémon series. It was developed by Game Freak for the Nintendo Game Boy, and is essentially an updated version of the Pokémon Red/Blue titles, with changes made in order for the game to more closely follow the events of the Pokémon anime series.Perhaps the most significant change from the previous versions is the fact that you are no longer given the choice of the three Starter Pokémon (Squirtle, Bulbasaur and Charmander), but are instead given a Pikachu by Professor Oak at the start of the game (as also occurs in the anime series). Pikachu follows the character around the world instead of being stored in a Poké Ball, and its personality and attitude towards the player can be affected how you play the game (frequently fainting causes Pikachu to become hostile towards you, for example).StoryPokémon Yellow's story is very similar to that of Pokémon Red/Blue.The player is allowed to create his or her own character by deciding their name. Fromthere, the player is greeted to Pallet Town, a place where Ash Ketchum from the Pokémon Anime series originated from.Rather than picking one of the three Pokémon Professor Oak had to offer, the player was greeted by Pikachu. And from then on, having a similar story to that of the Anime, Pikachu will be the only Pokémon that decides to follow the player around rather then staying in its Pokéball. Pikachu will follow the player in his or her quest of achieving 8 badges to head on to the Pokémon League, a tournament where Pokémon trainers show how much they've learned about their Pokémon.The player is then greeted to a variety of cities which was also mentioned in the Anime. The player will be greeted to many main characters within the Anime series such as Brock, the gym leader of Pewter City, and Misty, the gym leader Cerulean city.The player will also meet the antagonist of the Anime series and the Red/Blue versions of the game, Team Rocket, a nefarious group of people who dedicate their lives to capture Pokémon. Players will also meet a variety of gym leaders throughout their journey and also a plethora of trainers who will either challenge or be challenged by the player.Parallels to AnimeThe point of Pokemon Yellow was to tie the game in with the anime a little more, starting from a redesign of all the characters, and even the Pokemon. Gary, Professor Oak and, most notably, Misty and Brock have been redesigned to look more like the characters from the anime. Your starter is a Pikachu, no matter what, and Gary starts with an Eevee. Gary has no fan club, however, as he does in the show.Team Rocket is a major player as per the original games, but Jesse and James are now actual characters, using Koffing, Ekans and Meowth (Meowth doesn't talk, however). Giovanni, the boss of Team Rocket, has had his team overhauled to be more in tune with his anime counterpart, most notably including a Persian.Pokemon Centers are now stocked with with Nurse Joy counterparts, as well as Chanseys, who were assistant nurses in the show as well. Your character also has the option of getting all the starter Pokemon again, and in similar ways to the show: Bulbasaur is given away by a girl after you defeat Misty because she feels he's being held back by staying there with her; Charmander is given away by some dude who doesn't want it anymore; Squirtle is given away by Officer Jenny for being too much of a rabble-rouser.Most importantly, however, is Pikachu, as mentioned before, and the fact it follows you around. It even goes through stages similar to those of the Pikachu in the show, where it at first distrusts you but then grows to enjoy you more. It also refuses to be evolved if you try (making you have to trade over a Pikachu from another game if you want a Raichu).Differences from Red/BlueThis game is mostly an update to the games, and a lot of the gameplay changes are cosmetic. Genders, abilities and breeding aren't introduced until later games, and the game is mostly at the simplest RPG roots (see Gameplay below). Other changes are enumerated above as just making it more like the anime, so in the end, the other biggest change is for collectors of the Pokemon. The exclusive Pokemon in this version are a mix of both games, making it far easier to catch them all. Some of the trades have been changed as well, or removed completely (the man who traded you the Jynx in Red/Blue is replaced by the girl who gives you Bulbasaur, for example). It's an incremental upgrade, and set the standard for Crystal and Emerald coming further down the line.GameplayThe gameplay in Pokémon Yellow is based upon the turn-based battle system that debuted in Red/Blue version. The player's Pokémon are only allowed to have a maximum of 4 attacks. There are different kinds of attacks, such as special attacks and physical attacks. The attacks and all Pokémon are also all divided in types, such as water type, fire type, rock type, psychic type, and should a Pokémon use an attack with similar type to his he gains a boost in damage. The Pokémon are able to learn new abilities; however, since they are only allowed to have 4 attacks, the player must choose wisely if he or she wishes to forget an attack in order to learn a new attack, for a forgotten technique can not be recovered in most cases.Learning new attacks require the Pokémon to level up. Leveling up happens by gaining experience points when challenging and defeating other Pokémon, which can be from other trainers or random Pokémon found in the wild. When facing another trainer the player will have to choose a Pokémon in their inventory to battle one of the opponent's Pokémon, if emerging victorious, the trainer will also earn money used buy items such as potions, Poké Balls, etc. When enough experience is collected, the Pokémon will be able to learn certain attacks based on their type, the attack and which level is happens depends on the Pokémon. The player is also allowed to switch Pokémon in mid-battle if the situation permits it; however, the Pokémon switched and the Pokémon which was switched for will divide the experience received equally should the enemy be downed. This strategy allows players to level up weak Pokémon quickly if done correctly. And if the player levels up their Pokémon to a certain level, the Pokémon will evolve. Evolving allows the Pokémon to take on a new form, becoming stronger and being able to learn attacks that it wouldn't be able to learn before. But if the player wishes for their Pokémon to stay at that stage, he or she can rapidly tap the B button to stop the evolution when the evolution screen sets in.When players put their Pokémon into battle, they will most likely receive damage eventually. If the Pokémon are injured too much, the player must take them to the Pokémon Center in order for the Pokémon's Hit Points (HP) to be fully restored and all stat changes be restored to normal. But if there isn't a Pokémon Center nearby, players are able to buy potions and other healing items to heal their Pokémon during or after battle. Players can buy potions from PokéMarts located throughout the game as well as finding the items scattered around during the adventure. The player is only able to buy a maximum of 99 of each different type of item. Like any RPG, items play a decisive role in the game, some items give the ability to teach a Pokémon techniques, even some which the Pokémon wouldn't normally learn though leveling up, these are called Technical Machines (TM), and they work as normal attacks would do when taught to any Pokémon able to receive such technique, though there are 50 of them in the game, each TM can only be used once, being rendered useless afterwards; though most of them can only be attained once, some of them can be bought in shops and can theoretically be used how many times the player wishes, granting the player has the money to buy. There's another kind of technique called Hidden Machines (HM), this can be used as much as the player wants, it doesn't lose effect after usage, and though they can also used to attack during battle, their primary function is to help the player overcome certain natural obstacles during the adventure, such as cutting trees obstructing the way, or surfing. A Pokémon is required for these actions and once the Pokémon learns a Hidden Machine they will never unlearn it.In order to catch Pokémon, the player requires to have Pokéballs. A Pokéball allows a player to capture any wild Pokémon in the game. Some Pokémon are stronger than others; therefore, it requires the player to weaken them first with his or her Pokémon before it can be caught. Pokéballs are purchased from the PokéMart. There are different types of Pokéballs, and each of them have a different percentage of effectiveness on catching Pokémon. Since the player is only able to carry a maximum of 6 Pokémon within their inventory any extra Pokémon caught is instantly sent to be stored in the PC. If a player decides to switch Pokémon, then they would be required to go to a PC located in any Pokémon Center to do so, from there, the player is allowed to switch whatever Pokémon that he or she has already caught from their PCs to their inventory and vice-versa.Your primary goal in Pokémon Yellow is becoming the greatest Pokémon trainer of all, to to achieve that you have to train Pokémon to take on the Elite Four, which is formed by the very four best Pokémon trainers around, after taking down all the Pokémon from the four trainers you still have to face the Elite Champion to, then, if you manage to win the battle, become the newest champion. To do that you won't have access to Pokémon Center's care for your Pokémon and you will have to deal with the six Pokémon you choose in the beginning against all 5 trainers, it is allowed to stock up items and use them in any of your Pokémon at will, but changing one Pokémon downed for some other with full health won't be allowed. When you beat the Elite and the champion your name and Pokémon will go down in the hall of fame. You can still come back and battle the Elite Four anytime after you beat them the first time, it's actually one of the best places in the game for easy and high amount of experience, and you also receive money out of each trainer defeated, making it a great monetary source as well.Pokémon GymsDuring the adventure you'll have to face 8 different gym leaders and beat them to acquire their badges, and with them, get allowed into Victory Road and reach Indigo Plateau for the Elite. Each Pokémon Gym Leader is an specialist in some Pokémon type, it's important to notice their type for better chances of counter-attacking with a strong type Pokémon. Here are the gym leaders, their location, their specialty and Pokémon used.Pewter City GymLeader - BrockBadge - Boulder BadgePokémon Type - Rock/GroundPokémon Used - Geodude, OnyxCerulean City GymLeader - MistyBadge - Cascade BadgePokémon Type - WaterPokémon Used - Staryu, StarmieVermilion City GymLeader - Lt. SurgeBadge - Thunder BadgePokémon Type - ElectricPokémon Used - RaichuCeladon City GymLeader - ErikaBadge - Rainbow BadgePokémon Type - GrassPokémon Used - Tangela, Weepinbell, GloomSaffron City GymLeader - SabrinaBadge - Marsh BadgePokémon Type - PsychicPokémon Used - Abra, Kadabra, AlakazamFuchsia City GymLeader - KogaBadge - Soul BadgePokémon Type - Bug/PoisonPokémon Used - Venonat, Venonat, Venonat, VenomothCinnabar City GymLeader - BlaineBadge - Volcano BadgePokémon Type - FirePokémon Used - Ninetails, Rapidash, ArcanineViridian City GymLeader - GiovanniBadge - Earth BadgePokémon Type - GroundPokémon Used - Dugtrio, Persian, Nidoking, Nidoqueen, RhydonThe Elite FourThe very four best Pokémon trainers are the ultimate challenge for this game, you have to beat them all along with the current Pokémon Champion to achieve your goal of becoming the greatest Pokémon TrainerElite Four LoreleiPokémon Type - Water/IcePokémon Used - Dewgon, Cloyster, Slowbro, Jynx, LaprasElite Four BrunoPokémon Type - FightingPokémon Used - Onyx, Hitmonchan , Hitmonlee, Machamp, OnyxElite Four AgathaPokémon Type - GhostPokémon Used - Gengar, Golbat, Haunter, Arbok, GengarElite Four lancePokémon Type - Dragon/FlyingPokémon Used - Gyarados, Dragonair, Dragonair, Aerodactyl, DragoniteElite Four Champion Gary Oak (Rival)Pokémon Type - Gary has a very balanced teamPokémon Used - Gary's Pokémon for the final battle will depend on which Pokémon his Eevee evolved into. The evolution will depend on your actions in the game, here are the three sets of Pokémon he might be usingWith Vaporeon - Sandslash, Alakazam, Exeggutor, Ninetales, MagnetonWith Jolteon - Sandslash, Alakazam, Exeggutor, Ninetales, CloysterWith Flareon - Sandslash, Alakazam, Exeggutor, Cloyster, MagnetonEvolving Gary's EeveeGary's Eevee evolution hinges on the first two battles with him-first in Oak's office and then in the route outside of Viridian, before the Pokemon League entrance. They proceed as follows:VaporeonTo get Vaporeon, you must lose both battles with him (alternately, you could just skip the second battle, which counts as a loss). Presumably this is to make his later battles easier, since Pikachu is super-effective against water. A cunning trainer would let Gary win both times, though, and just use this to destroy him easier later.FlareonWin one, lose the other. It doesn't really matter which you win and which you lose, but it's easier to win the first match and then, once more, skipping the second battle.JolteonProcess of elimination should show that to get him to fight with a Jolteon, simply win both matches. It's the hardest evolution, because you're not very effective against it with your Pikachu.Technical MachinesHere's a list of all Technical Machines found in the game.Technical MachinesAttack--TM01Mega PunchTM02Razor WindTM03Sword's DanceTM04WhirlwindTM05Mega KickTM06ToxicTM07Horn DrillTM08Body SlamTM09Take DownTM10Double EdgeTM11Bubble BeamTM12Water GunTM13Ice BeamTM14BlizzardTM15Hyper BeamTM16Pay DayTM17SubmissionTM18CounterTM19Seismic TossTM20RageTM21Mega DrainTM22Solar BeamTM23Dragon RageTM24ThunderboltTM25ThunderTM26EarthquakeTM27FissureTM28DigTM29PsychicTM30TeleportTM31MimicTM32Double TeamTM33ReflectTM34BideTM35MetronomeTM36Self DestructTM37Egg BombTM38Fire BlastTM39SwiftTM40Skull BashTM41Soft BoiledTM42Dream EaterTM43Sky AttackTM44RestTM45Thunder WaveTM46PsywaveTM47ExplosionTM48Rock SlideTM49Tri AttackTM50SubstituteHidden MachineHere's a list of all Hidden Machines found in the game.Hidden MachineAblityHM01CutHM02FlyHM03SurfHM04StrengthHM05FlashSurfing PikachuOne of the new features in Pokémon Yellow is the possibility to play a mini-games called "Surfing Pikachu", you just had to show up at the house near the beach in route 19 and have a Pikachu who knows the technique "Surf" as one of his four moves. Of course Pikachu doesn't naturally learn Surf so the player could get one at Nintendo events, but the best way to get a Pikachu with Surf would be Pokémon Stadium 2. If you manage to beat Round 2's Prime Cub Master Ball with a team containing the Pikachu you receive at the beginning of Pokémon Yellow (it has to be Pikachu from Yellow, the one the follows you around) without using continues and making Pikachu participate of all battles until the end, then you would have the option to teach Surf to Pikachu at the end, being able to use it in the game and participate the mini-game.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13470">Dragon Warrior Monsters</game><game id="9238">Animal Crossing: Wild World</game><game id="17676">Monster Rancher</game><game id="23128">Robopon: Sun Version</game><game id="8307">EarthBound</game><game id="2731">Mega Man Zero</game><game id="24009">Dragon Quest Monsters 1 &amp; 2</game><game id="24011">Dragon Quest Monsters: Caravan Heart</game><game id="27048">Fossil Fighters</game><game id="22912">Magi Nation</game><game id="3879">Digimon World 3</game><game id="21906">Digimon RPG</game><game id="14870">Digimon Tamers: Digimon Medley</game><game id="6834">Digimon Adventure: Anode Tamer</game><game id="3164">Digimon Rumble Arena 2</game><game id="22672">Digimon World Championship</game><game id="21651">Digimon World 4</game><game id="24388">Digimon World: Dusk/Dawn</game><game id="17979">Digimon World 2</game><game id="21933">Digimon World DS</game><game id="12071">Digimon Digital Card Battle</game><game id="27976">Koto Battle: Tengai no Moribito</game><game id="21079">Dinosaur King</game><game id="12893">Animal Crossing</game><game id="23783">SimAnimals</game><game id="21096">Animal Crossing: City Folk</game><game id="15861">Pokémon Crystal</game><game id="3966">Pokémon Red/Blue</game><game id="18673">Pokémon Yellow: Special Pikachu Edition</game><game id="10489">Pokémon Trading Card Game</game><game id="21127">Pokémon Ranger: Shadows of Almia</game><game id="13974">Pokémon Mystery Dungeon: Blue/Red Rescue Team</game><game id="23375">Gangway Monsters</game><game id="19154">Pokémon Pinball</game><game id="17113">Hey You, Pikachu!</game><game id="33000">Shin Megami Tensei: Persona 2 - Innocent Sin</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2171295-box_pkmnyv.png</image></root>