<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1869</id><name>Medal of Honor: Pacific Assault</name><description> Classes Allied Infantry Corpsman Engineer Ammo TechnicianAxis Heitai (infantery)Kangohei (Corpsman) Kosakuhei (Engineer)Shichuhei (Ammo technician)WeaponsALLIED .30 Caliber M1 Carbine Rifle M1928A1 Thompson SMG w/ 50 Round Drum M1 Garand w. Bayonet Reising Model 55 SMG Springfield M1903 Rifle M1918 A2 Browning Automatic RIfle (BAR) Springfield M1903/A5 Sniper Rifle Model 11 Remington Semi-Automatic Riot Gun M1911 PistolAXISModel 38 6.5mm Arisaka Rifle w. Bayonet Type 100 Submachine Gun Model 97 6.5mm Sniper Rifle Model 44 Cavalry Carbine Rifle w. Bayonet Model 96 6.5mm Light Machine Gun w. BayonetDevelopmentSingleplayerThe singleplayer is developed by  Electronic Arts Los Angeles and it's using a modified version of the IdTech 3 engine and Havok physics and the music is composed by Christopher Lennertz.  Multiplayer  The mulitplayer component is developed by  TKO Software the company that developed the  Medal Of Honor Breakthrough an expansion pack to  Medal Of Honor Allied Assault . The reason why they split the development between these two studios aren't explained and that might be a part of the reason why the multiplayer component of this game weren't received well by the consumers. Just 2 months after the release it was hard to find a working server to play on. ReleaseThe game was released in two different versions. The first one is the DVD version released on 2nd of November 2004, Later on there was a CD version released on the 9th of november 2004.System Requirements If you're playing this game on a modern computer you might have issues with the fact that the game can't be played according to the launcher but it works just max it out and you will have a great FPS.MinimumOS: Windows 2000/ XP Processor: Intel Pentium 4 1,5Ghz RAM: 512Mb DDR Graphics: 64Mb memory, Pixel Shader and  DirectX 8.1 support, Transform and Lightning Support capabilities HDD: 4Gb</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20980">The History Channel: Battle for the Pacific</game><game id="20777">Call of Duty: World at War</game><game id="10127">Deadly Dozen: Pacific Theater</game><game id="16752">Medal of Honor: Rising Sun</game><game id="24485">Call of Duty: World at War Final Fronts</game><game id="9223">World War II Combat: Iwo Jima</game><game id="31362">Red Orchestra: Rising Storm</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15228/817126-thebox.jpg</image></root>