<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18753</id><name>Tekken 5</name><description>OverviewTekken 5 was developed and published by Namco and released on February 24, 2005. It was released in the arcades in December of 2004. It is the sixth game in the Tekken series. The game also features the three original Tekken games for the PlayStation, as well as one of Namco's earlier arcade games, StarBlade. Story After the conclusion of         The King of Iron Fist Tournament 4, we see feathers floating down from when         Devil Jin flew off into the night. However, the silence was soon be interrupted with the roar of an approaching aircraft. Almost immediately, a group of Jack-4 robots crashed through the ceiling. Although  Heihachi suspected that         Kazuya was responsible for the intrusion, he soon realized he was wrong, with Kazuya equally as bewildered by the sudden attack. "Why are you here?" yells Heihachi as the wave of Jack robots approaches.         Heihachi and Kazuya destroy scores of Jacks, but reinforcements appear almost as quickly as the duo of father and son can destroy them. Heihachi begins to lose his breath, and Kazuya takes advantage of this, betraying Heihachi, he throws him int the middle of the army of Jacks, and then escapes while the Jack robots are busy with Heihachi. While several Jack robots pile on top of Heihachi, holding him down, one lands in front of Heihachi and self destructs. The Hon-Maru is then devastated with a massive explosion.Close by, all this is being watched by a man in black (        Raven). He raises his hand, presses a button on the radio in his ear and says "Heihachi Mishima...is dead...". At that moment, a Jack robot attacks the man from behind, but he evades the attack and cuts the Jack robot in half, disappearing an instant later. The Hon-Maru is completely destroyed and has been replaced with a raging inferno. The next day, news of Heihachi Mishima's death spread rapidly across the globe, with most people believing that Heihachi Mishima's death would bring the end to the Mishima Zaibatsu. However, behind the scenes, someone has taken his place, and business went on as usual. A month later, it was announced that the Mishima Zaibatsu will hold The King of Iron Fist Tournament 5.   Meanwhile, Jin Kazama's Devil Gene is going berserk, and he decides  to search for the one responsible for the change by entering the  tournament. Kazuya also enters to find out exactly who in G Corporation  sent the Jack-4's to kill him, and take his revenge. As Jin and Kazuya progress through the tournament, the secret sponsor  is finally revealed: Jinpachi Mishima, the father of Heihachi and who has been missing for the  past fifty years. As it turns out, Jinpachi is the founder of the  Mishima Zaibatsu and was a respected martial arts master until his  greedy son, Heihachi, stole the company from him and had him imprisoned  underneath Hon-Maru after Jinpachi attempted a Coup d'état (Heihachi was  steering the company into the military industry, something Jinpachi  believed was not right). Jinpachi died soon afterwards of starvation,  until the Devil took over his mind and granted him immortality (as well  as a Devil Gene), and Jinpachi was finally freed from his prison when  the Jack-4's destroyed Hon-Maru. As of now, the Devil Gene is slowly  consuming Jinpachi's mind, and Jinpachi has announced the tournament in  hopes that someone will kill him and put an end to his reign of terror  before it even starts. In the end, Jin makes it to the final, and faces his Devil-powered  great-grandfather in combat. Ultimately, Jin manages to defeat Jinpachi,  who dissolves into dust and disappears, his wish fulfilled. Jin is now  the new owner of the Mishima Zaibatsu. GameplayThe fighting is the same as always and for the first time, Namco has introduced a new feature in which you can customize your characters. As you fight in the Main mode, you earn money for every time you defeat someone. Then you can use it at the Customization mode and buy several sorts of items to personalize you character.  It is also the first game in the Tekken series to utilize the Card System for the Arcade Version of the game. This enables players record wins and losses, attain rankings through victories and customize their characters with items.  Before the release of the Playstation 2 version the rankings were 9th Kyu (lowest) to Master (highest). New rankings were released for the PS2 Arcade version with the highest being the Tekken Lord.  As per tradition in Tekken games, Namco have introduced several new characters in Tekken 5. Although Jack-5 and         Roger Jr. and almost identical to Jack-4 and Roger respectively, and         Asuka Kazama and Devil Jin bear similarities to         Jun Kazama and         Jin Kazama (in         Tekken 3) respective move-sets, both         Feng Wei and Raven are brand new characters. The new characters bring the overall amount of playable characters to 33.  Character RosterNew Characters         Asuka Kazama (Jin Kazama's cousin)          Feng Wei (Student and murderer of Asuka's father)          Raven (Agent sent to observe Tekken Zaibatsu)   Jack-5 (Updated version of Jack 4)           Roger Jr. (Son of Roger from Tekken 2)  Devil Jin (Jin Kazama in his devil form)         Jinpachi Mishima (Main boss and f  ounder of the Mishima Zaibatsu)    Returning Characters        Anna Williams         Baek Doo San         Bruce Irvin         Bryan Fury         Christie Monteiro         Craig Marduk         Eddy Gordo         Ganryu         Heihachi Mishima         Hwoarang         Jin Kazama         Juilia Chang         Kazuya Mishima  King         Kuma         Lei Wulong         Lee Chaolan         Ling Xiaoyu         Marshall Law         Mokujin         Nina Williams         Panda         Paul Phoenix         Steve Fox         Wang Jinrei         Yoshimitsu   Game ModesStory ModeIn story mode, you choose a character then play through eight  AI controlled opponents before the final battle with the tournament sponsor Jinpachi Mishima. As well as prologue, epilogue and an ending CG scene, each character gets "sub-boss" cut-scenes, where two characters will interact before and after their fight (for example, Kazuya Mishima's sub-boss is Raven, who calls Kazuya a "coward" for fleeing from the Hon-Maru).Arcade ModeIn arcade mode, the player faces an unlimited amount of AI controlled characters, presenting the player with a chance to win gold in order to customize their character and also to raise the character's rank (each character starts out as a beginner and ends as a Tekken Lord).VS BattleIn VS Battle, two players can battle each other, with a counter keeping score of how many wins each player has.Team BattleIn team battle, two players select a team of 2-8 characters, and engage in a series of one round bouts, until all the members of one players team are eliminated. Team Battle can also be played alone, with the player selecting 2-8 characters, fighting a random team of AI controlled opponents (the AI controlled team size will be the same size as your own).Survival ModeIn survival mode, the player selects a character and plays an unlimited amount of AI controlled opponents in one round bouts. The basis off Survival mode is to see how many wins you can amount off one life bar, although after the end of each battle the player regains a small amount of health.Time AttackIn Time Attack mode, the game records how quickly you can progress through Story Mode, although when playing Time Attack, the player is not presented with any epilogues, prologues, sub-boss cut-scenes or ending cinematic videos.Arcade HistoryA mode that contains arcade versions of Tekken, Tekken 2, Tekken 3 and also "Starblade", another Namco developed arcade game. Each Tekken game already has all time release characters unlocked automatically.Devil WithinDevil Within is a side game similar to the Tekken Force games found in Tekken 3 and Tekken 4. It is a 3D beat-em'-up game where the player plays as Jin as he attempts to find a way to rid himself of the Devil Gene.Customization ModeIn customization mode, you can customize your character with items and accessories such as sun-glasses, swords and variants of their existing clothes (or hairstyles), including being able to change the color of their clothing.Re-releasesTekken 5.1 came out only in arcades in Summer 2005 that changed the health bar to green and red while altering some characters' moves while introducing some new ones as well.The game was later re-released under the subtitle "Dark Resurrection" for the arcades and for the PSP and the PS3. The PSP version runs at full 60 FPS during matches. Other modes include Tekken Dojo, where the player fight ghosts of other players that can be uploaded and downloaded online. They can also download official ghost packs from arcades all over the world. In Gold Rush mode, the player fights for in-game cash. New versions of Tekken Bowl and Command Attack; bonus games from Tekken Tag Tournament and Tekken 4, are also included.    PS3 VersionIt was re-released on March 1, 2007 for $19.99, which runs at 60 frames per second and supports full 1080p HD resolution. A first for the series. The game features the same modes as the Arcade version, including ghost battles and a gallery mode, Practice mode and Survival mode. The game also features Jinpachi Mishima is playable character for the first time. However, unlike its PSP counterpart, the PS3 version lacks Story mode and Bonus mode. A patch was released on the on the North American Store on August 30, 2007 and contains an Online Versus mode and Online rankings as well as a practice mode.   ReceptionTekken 5 was one of those games that got mixed opinions. The last game (   Tekken 4) was received with mostly negative reviews due to being a far cry from the original Tekken formula. This caused to sales to be just....eh. This was to blame to the new system of fighting,a small roster (relative to the rest of the series) and just a bunch of other stuff that would work only if we were talking about a different franschise. Realising this,  Namco Bandai decided it would be best to return to the old formula. This caused a lot of reviewers to be extremely positive about the game,while others bashed Namco for fearing doing something new. However,Tekken 5 sold extremely well world wide,and was met with mostly positive reviews due to (for the time) incredible graphics,awesome character customization,a giant character roster and (in Japan only) online multiplayer. Soundtrack  Track 1      I'm Here Now (Remix)      1:57Track 2     Sparkling     1:51Track 3     Mode Select (Tekken 5)     2:33Track 4     Who's Afraid Of...     1:45Track 5     Dragon's Nest     2:42Track 6     Red Hot Fist     1:40Track 7     Formless Like Water     2:00Track 8     Unforgiven     2:06Track 9     Crimson Sunset     2:40Track 10     Moonlit Wilderness     1:57Track 11     Gold Rush     1:34Track 12     Massive Stunner     1:57Track 13     Antares     2:34Track 14     Streets     1:19Track 15     Street Wise (Asura Mix)     1:34Track 16     Frozen Paradise     1:41Track 17     Ka-En-No-Mai     2:03Track 18     Orbital Move     1:56Track 19     Poolside     2:31Track 20     Ground Zero Funk     2:28Track 21     The Finalizer     2:01Track 22     Give Me Your Name     1:41Track 23     One More     1:08Track 24     Neonatal     1:02Track 25     Raven's Ending     0:46Track 26     Feng's Ending     0:35Track 27     Asuka's Ending     0:21Track 28     Heihachi's Ending     1:10Track 29     Kazuya's Ending     0:32Track 30     Jin's Ending     0:41Track 31     Lee's Ending     0:59Track 32     Steve's Ending     0:55Track 33     Lei's Ending     0:41Track 34     Nina  Anna's Ending Part 1     0:32Track 35     Nina  Anna's Ending Part 2     0:15Track 36     Paul's Ending     0:30Track 37     Law's Ending     0:53Track 38     Hwoarang's Ending     0:41Track 39     Baek's Ending     0:29Track 40     Christie's Ending     0:30Track 41     Marduk's Ending     1:01Track 42     King's Ending     0:50Track 43     Julia's Ending     0:47Track 44     Ganryu's Ending     1:08Track 45     Bryan's Ending     0:48Track 46     Yoshimitsu's Ending     0:32Track 47     Bruce's Ending     1:13Track 48     Jack-5's Ending     1:01Track 49     Panda  Kuma's Ending     1:05Track 50     Wang's Ending     1:15Track 51     Jinpachi's Ending     0:36Track 52     Devil Jin's Ending     0:42Track 53     Roger Jr.'s Ending Part 1     0:34Track 54     Roger Jr.'s Ending Part 2     0:21Track 55     Mokujin's Ending     0:27Track 56     Xiaoyu's Ending Part 1     0:21Track 57     Xiaoyu's Ending Part 2     0:28Track 58     After All     0:42Track 59     Marital Symphony Opus 5     3:24</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4313">Virtua Fighter 4</game><game id="2895">Battle Arena Toshinden 3</game><game id="10651">Mortal Kombat: Unchained</game><game id="3760">Street Fighter: The Movie</game><game id="9603">Star Wars: Masters of Teräs Käsi</game><game id="11065">Shaman King: Power of Spirit</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="16842">Street Fighter: Anniversary Collection</game><game id="13753">Dead or Alive Ultimate</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="22895">Godzilla Kaiju Daikessen</game><game id="23007">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja Heroes</game><game id="21007">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja Heroes 2: Phantom Fortress</game><game id="23220">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja</game><game id="22519">Naruto: Uzumaki Chronicles 2</game><game id="21582">Naruto Shippuuden: Gekitou Ninja Taisen! EX 2</game><game id="10126">X-Men: Next Dimension</game><game id="9855">Soulcalibur III</game><game id="13129">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai 3</game><game id="21195">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai Tenkaichi 3</game><game id="13875">Plasma Sword: Nightmare of Bilstein</game><game id="21550">Super Dragon Ball Z</game><game id="7792">Dead or Alive 4</game><game id="4891">Virtua Fighter 4: Evolution</game><game id="22305">Street Fighter III: 2nd Impact</game><game id="28865">Naruto Shippuden: Clash of Ninja Revolution 3</game><game id="35032">Kinnikuman Muscle Grand Prix Max 2: Tokumori</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2114383-box_tekken5.png</image></root>