<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18777</id><name>The Club</name><description>CharactersThe Club has eight playable characters.Dragov: A Russian convict who is rescued by The Club. He is the strongest character, but slow.Renwick: A former New York detective. He is well balanced.Finn: A gambler whose debts landed him in trouble with the mob. He is also well balancedSeager: A Canadian extreme sports junkie. Fast but slightly weak.Kuro: A Japanese double agent. Kuro is among the fastest competitors in The Club.Killen: An Australian man who survived through The Club once. Killen is well balanced.Adjo: Seeks to redeem his violent past, but is ultimately forced to participate in the tournament. Adjo is also one of the strongest competitors.Nemo: A psychopath who only lives to kill. Nemo is extremely fast and quite strong.MultiplayerThe game has online multiplayer with seven modes.Kill Match: Basic DeathmatchScore Match: Compete to get the best scoreHunted Killer: One player is Hunted, their score goes up. Everyone else tries to kill the Hunted so they can become the huntedTeam Kill Match: Basic Team DeathmatchTeam Seige: Attack and Defense style modeTeam Skullshot: Each team tries to destroy five targets on the others side.GameplayThe game plays a lot like a regular third-person shooter, but has a combo system for kills. Each kill starts a combo meter, and every kill thereafter adds to the combo meter as long as it is within the combo time limit. The modes are all based on score, with score goals that can go up into the millions. You also get extra points for doing style shots, such as killing someone out of a roll.System RequirementsMinimumSupported OS: Microsoft® Windows® 2000 or XP with latest service packs installedProcessor: 2.0 Ghz Intel Pentium 4, AMD Athlon XP 2000 processorGraphics: 100% DirectX 9.0c compatible 64MB video card with latest manufacturer driversDirectX Version: DirectX 9.0cMemory: 512 MB RAMHard Drive: 6 GB uncompressed free hard disk spaceRecommendedProcessor: 2.5 Ghz Intel Pentium 4, AMD Athlon XP 2500 processorMemory: 1 GB RAMGraphics: ATI Radeon X800 series or higher video card with latest manufacturer driversXbox 360 Game InstallationThe Club requires 5.2GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD.</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16194">Smash TV</game><game id="19809">Project Gotham Racing 3</game><game id="30313">Bodycount</game><game id="29539">Naughty Bear</game><game id="15175">Outtrigger</game><game id="32811">Resident Evil: The Mercenaries 3D</game><game id="2242">The Punisher</game><game id="36441">Xotic</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2543575-box_theclub.png</image></root>