<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18808</id><name>F-Zero X</name><description>OverviewF-Zero X is the franchise's first showing on the Nintendo 64. F-Zero X was released in 1998. It was developed by Nintendo EAD and published by Nintendo. Everything is better in this iteration with more playable characters, more courses, and more modes. A second game in the same engine was out on the Nintendo 64 Disk System (Nintendo 64DD) in Japan with a track editor. The original F-Zero X was later re-released on the Wii Virtual Console.GameplayGrand PrixGetting close to the finish line!The main mode of F-Zero X in which there are five cups selectable (two of them have to be unlocked like the X Cup, a cup filled of randomly generated courses). Four difficulties are also selectable (Master as to be unlocked). With more cars on the track (30 to be exact), the racing is fast and chaotic as opposing racers will bump you as well as a rival driver you have to beat. Whoever has the highest number of points wins the cup after five courses. Like the original F-Zero, you have lives since your car has a health meter and you will lose one life if your car brakes down (health is at zero) or you fall off the stage. Also from the original, boosting is in as soon as the second lap begins as using it takes off a portion of the car's health.Time AttackThis mode is your car and only your car going through a certain course as fast as possible.Death RaceThe goal of this mode is to take out all your competition as fast as possible.VersusUp to four players locally can compete on any of the courses.Characters, Vehicles and Vehicle GradesEach vehicle is given a letter grade ranging from A (top) to E (lowest) on body, boost and grip.Body: The body rating represents the machine's strength in regards to the damage it can withstand from collisions against the wall and competing racers.Boost: The boost rating represents the machine's boost usage in terms of speed increase and duration.Grip: The grip rating represents the machine's grip in terms of maintaining control while turning a corner.Driver NameVehicle NameBody GradeBoost GradeGrip GradeCaptain FalconBlue FalconBCBDr. StewartGolden FoxDADPicoWild GooseBBCSamurai GorohFire StingrayADBJody SummerWhite CatCCAMighty GazelleWild GazelleEACBabaIron TigerBDAOctomanDeep ClawBBCDr. ClashCrazy BearABEMr. EADGreat StarEADBio RexBig FangBDABillyMad WolfBBCSilver NeelsenNight ThunderBAEGomar  ShiohTwin NoritaEACJohn TanakaWonder WaspDADMrs. ArrowQueen MeteorEBBBlood FalconBlood HawkBAEJack LevinAstro RobinBDAJames McCloudLittle WyvernEBBZodaDeath AnchorEACMichael ChainWild BoarACCSuper ArrowKing MeteorEBBKate AllenSuper PiranhaBCBRoger BusterMighty HurricaneEBBLeonSpace AnglerCCADraqMighty TyphoonCADBeastmanHyper SpeederABDBlack ShadowBlack BullAEAThe SkullSonic PhantomCADCups  StagesRace OrderJack CupQueen CupKing CupJoker CupDD Cup 1DD Cup 2Track 1Mute City 1Sector AlphaFire FieldRainbow RoadSilence 3Mute City 4Track 2SilenceRed CanyonSilence 2Devil's Forest 3Sand Ocean 3Space Plant 2Track 3Sand OceanDevil's Forest 2Sector BetaSpace PlantDevil's Forest 4Port Town 4Track 4Devil's ForestMute City 2Red Canyon 2Sand Ocean 2Port Town 3Fire Field 2Track 5Big BlueBig Blue 2White Land 2Port Town 2Devil's Forest 4White Land 3Track 6Port TownWhite LandMute City 3Big HandBig Blue 3Big FootX-CupThe X-Cup is a special cup where the game self-generates six race courses to race on. This cup can be unlocked after completing the Joker Cup on expert difficulty.SoundtrackOriginal Soundtrack"Endless Challenge" - 2:45"Dream Chaser" - 3:37"Fall Down to the Scream" - 2:26"Decide in the Eyes" - 3:34"Devil's Call in Your Heart" - 2:20"The Long Distance of Murder" - 2:33"Crazy Call at Cry" - 3:12"Drivin' Through on Max" - 2:41"Climb Up! And Get the Last Chance!" - 2:50"All Need is 30 Deaths" - 1:52"Title BGM" - 2:53"Car Select" - 1:19"Option" - 1:02"Start Demo" - 0:09Goal Fanfare" - 0:10"Goal BGM" - 1:17"Retire" - 0:12"Game Over" - 0:17"Grandprix Ending" - 1:25"Staff Roll" - 2:46"Win! The Staff Ghost 1 Mute City" - 1:28"Win! The Staff Ghost 2 Silence" - 1:20"Win! The Staff Ghost 3 Devil's Forest" - 1:27"Win! The Staff Ghost 4 Port Town 1" - 1:39"Win! The Staff Ghost 5 Red Canyon" - 1:23"Win! The Staff Ghost 6 Big Blue 2" - 1:13"Win! The Staff Ghost 7 White Land" - 1:43"Win! The Staff Ghost 8 Fire Field" - 1:28"Win! The Staff Ghost 9 Sector-β" - 1:45Guitar Remixes"The Long Distance of Murder" - 2:44"Drivin' Through on Max" - 3:12"Crazy Call at Cry" - 3:19"Title BGM" - 3:10"Decide in the Eyes" - 4:04"Climb Up! And Get the Last Chance!" - 4:26"Endless Challenge" - 3:17"Dream Chaser" - 3:43"Grand Prix Ending" - 3:27"Staff Roll" - 5:21</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12064">WipEout 64</game><game id="9774">Extreme-G 2</game><game id="9060">Rollcage</game><game id="12298">WipEout 3</game><game id="13526">Star Wars: Episode I - Racer</game><game id="20610">WipEout HD</game><game id="14796">WipEout Pure</game><game id="20596">WipEout Pulse</game><game id="9707">WipEout</game><game id="20878">Speed Racer: The Videogame</game><game id="19906">AeroGauge</game><game id="3654">WipEout XL</game><game id="23156">F-Zero X Expansion Kit</game><game id="10084">Mario Kart 64</game><game id="13882">F-Zero: GP Legend</game><game id="6368">Mickey's Speedway USA</game><game id="30163">G-Surfers</game><game id="2260">Sonic R</game><game id="35496">WipEout 2048</game><game id="21285">Rollcage Stage II</game><game id="8949">S.T.U.N. Runner</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1805111-box_fzx.png</image></root>