<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19028</id><name>Mace: The Dark Age</name><description>Story Overview For centuries an impenetrable darkness has shrouded Europe and North Africa, with countless victims succumbing to the ravenous hunger of unchecked pestilence and war. Once a promising glimpse of humanity’s potential, the cradle of civilization has become a well of despair.   Many great kingdoms have been devastated, but a select few have grown more powerful. These comprise of the covenant of seven – lords who have allied with Asmodeus, a practitioner of the dark arts who wields the fabled Mace of Tanis. The Mace is imbued with necropotic energy, offering those who wield it a tantalizing promise of ever-lasting life and unbridled power.   With this power comes a terrible price: Asmodeus must feed off despair, disease, and poverty. In limited doses, Asmodeus grants the Seven the power they need and crave. In return, they expand their kingdoms with bloody battles and torment their peasants. But can no longer sustain Asmodeus’ ravenous appetite. He now reaches east into the orient, to find new lords who yearn to sample the dark powers.   But there is a rebellion. Each of the Seven, addicted to the corrupting power of the Mace, dispatch their best warriors to kill Asmodeus and steal his power. Leaders from the east sense Asmodeus’ plottings and strive to destroy him before it’s too late.   Heirs to kingdoms long since vanquished, seek revenge on Asmodeus and those who wield the dark energy. They are the fiercest fighters on Earth, and they all have one thing in common. They all must possess the Mace!    Warrior List and moves   Move index   B – Back         S – Strong D – Down       K – Kick F – Forward    E – Evade J – Jump          Q - Quick   Al Rashid   -The evil Al Rashid was raised from birth to become a master in the arts of the unseen death. The son of Khalid, King of Assassins, he was raised in a towering fortress high in the mountains of . He wields twin scimitars, rumoured to have been forged magically from the very winds of the . These blades grant Al Rashid extreme speed, lightning reflexes, and the power to harness the forces of the wind. His mission is to kill Asmodeus and become King of Assassins himself.   Combo Starters:   Air Quick – Q (in air near ground) Block Attack – B S   Basic Combos:   K, Q, K S, S, Q   Comboable Specials:   Dodge Left – E S Dodge Right – E Q Sand Devil – Hold S for 2 seconds, then release Flashcut Left – D, F, S (try following with D, F, Q) Power Chop – Q S (2 attack is anti-crouch) Sweep Kick – B K Big Spin Uppercut – F, D, F, S Side kick – B, F, K (try following with F S and then Big Spin Uppercut)   Stand Alone Specials:   Blade Tornado – F, D, B, S Double Chop – F Q S (anti crouch) Air Dive – B, F, Q (while in the air)   Fatality B, D, F, B, S (in close)   Fighting Statistics   Speed 7 Power 7 Reach 7 Armour 5     Countess Taria -The evil Countess Taria, daughter of the Duke of Iberia, one of the Covenant of Seven. She is a skilled fighter and a high priestess in black magic. She is in search of the ultimate power, and wants to place herself on the throne.   Combo Starters: Air Quick – Q (in air nearground) Dagger Stab – B Q Left Side Attack – E Q   Basic Combos: S, K, K Q, Q, S   Comboable Specials: Flip Kick – D, F, K Fireball – D, F, Q Right Side Attack – E S Double Low Spin – F, D, B, S (can be followed by another special after the 2 hit) Rush Forward – B, F, S   Stand Alone Specials: Bladegeyser – F, D, Q (can be followed with a special) Air Fireball – D, F, Q (while in air) Low Dagger – S K (can be followed with a special) Overhand – F Q S High Thrust – Q S (can be followed with a special)   Fatality Hold S, then release (within sweep distance)   Fighting Statistics Speed 8 Power 7 Reach 7 Armour 7     The Executioner -The Executioner is good at his job, and has created a vast and well stocked dungeon suited to his needs. He is loyal to Sir Dregan, one of the Covenant of Seven. In order to ensure that Dregan holds the reigns of power, the Executioner must put his considerable skills to the test in killing Asmodeus. And he thinks the Mace would make a cool torturing device.   Combo Starters: Head Stab – B Q Air Attack – Q (in air near ground)   Basic Combos: S, K, Q Q, Q, S   Comboable Specials: Big Swing – B S Corps Kiss – D, F, Q Devastator – B, F, Q Axe Hook – B, D, F, S (Hooks then throws opponent) Sweepchop – D, B, S (Sweep then anticrouch)   Stand Alone Specials: Fadeback – Q S (anticrouch) Overhand – F Q S   Fatality B, D, F, B, D, F, Q (in close)   Fighting Statistics Speed 5 Power 9 Reach 9 Armour 5   Koyasha -The Highest ranking master of Ninjutsu in her native land, said to be the deadliest ninja ever to walk the Earth. She is now working for mysterious powers who want to seize control of the Mace for purposes unknown.   Combo Starters: Air Quick – Q (in air near ground) Far stab – Q S Back Kick – S K (jumping cross over)   Basic combos S, Q, K Q, K, K   Comboable Specials: Spin Kick – B, D, F, K (can be done up to 3 times, and followed with a special) Left attack – E Q Ankle Biter – E S Lowhigh – F, D, F, S Sweep – B K Deception – F, D, B, S (can be followed with special) Slide – B, F, K (can be followed with special) Electo Shuriken – D, F, Q (tap Q again for another one)   Stand alone Specials: Heel Drop – F, D, B, K (anticrouch) Overhand – F Q S Air Grab – Q S (must be in air near standing opponent)   Fatality B, F, B, F, Q   Fighting Statistics Speed 10 Power 6 Reach 5 Armour 3    Lord Deimos  - A member of the Covenant of Seven, Lord Deimos rules his populace with an iron grip atop his mountain fortress in his native . No one currently alive has seen his face, and few are allowed inside his dark castle. Further, it is told, his blood-red armour is forged of molten lava, hand-forged by the very demon himself. Now that the covenant of Seven are battling each other, Deimos seeks to kill Asmodeus and rule all the know lands with the evil power.   Combo Starters: Air Quick – Q (in air near ground) Iron Fist – B Q   Basic Combos: S, S, Q S S, D S, D S   Comboable Specials: Soul Kick – B, F, K Hell-icopter – B, D, F, S (can be followed with a special) Shoulder Rush – F, F, S (can be followed with a quick power) Fire Wall – B, D, F, Q Quick Power – B, F, S   Stand Alone Specials: Homerun Swing - Q S Overhand – F Q S Mega Thrust – B Q S (press Q when hitting to toss)   Fatality F, B, D, F, S (within sweep distance)   Fighting Statistics Speed 5 Power 9 Reach 10 Armour 9     Mordos Kull  - A battle-scarred veteran of countless wars, Kull’s weapon is for sale to the highest bidder. An orphan with an unknown family history, Kull was raised by gypsy peasants in the rigged Italian foothills. He learned to fight by experience, throwing off the marauding brigands. He found he fought most effectively with a Flail, a devastating weapon that causes massive internal injuries. He is being paid to kill Asmodeus, but he may have plans of his own.   Combo Starters: Air Quick – Q (in air near ground)   Basic Combos: S, Q, B S Q, S, Q   Comboable specials: Dragons Strike – F, D, F, S Shield Rush – B, F, S (can be followed with Dragon Strike) Side Kick – B, F, K (can be done up to 3 times) Dodge left – E S Dodge Right – E Q Helliattack – B, D, F, S (can be followed with a special)   Stand Alone Specials: Block high, go low – F, D, B, Q (Defensive Attack) Block Low, go high – F, D, B, S (Defensive Attack, Anticrouch) Sweep – B K Anticrouch – F Q S Flail Twirl – B Q S (can be followed with a special)  Ringer – Q S (can be followed with a special)   Fatality D, D, B, S (in close)   Fighting Statistics Speed 7 Power 8 Reach 8 Armour 7   Namira   -Kidnapped from the royal palace and sold into slavery as a child, Namira grew up in the harem of a lesser sultan whose deviant appetite for pleasure was as twisted as his hideous face. Combining a deadly, swift scimitar with a seductive style of fighting that mesmerized her opponents, Namira is a lethal killing machine. Namira seeks to learn the truth about her identity from Asmodeus, killing him if she has to.   Combo Starters: Air Quick – Q (in air near ground)   Basic Combos: K, S, Q K, K, B K   Comboable Specials: Spin Left – B Q (can follow with another spin by hitting Q again) Spin Right – B S (can follow with another spin by hitting S again) Heelslap – D, F, K (can be followed by K) Sweep – B K High Kick – F, F, K Twirl – Q S K Dodge Slash – E S   Stand Alone Specials: High Thrust – Q S (can be followed with a special) Low Thrust – S K (can be followed with a special) Anticrouch – F Q S Heel Drop – B, F, K (anticrouch) Powerchop – B Q S (anticrouch, can be followed by special) Block High cutlow – F, D, Q (Defensive Attack)   Fatality D, D, B, F, K (in close)   Fighting Statistics Speed 9 Power 5 Reach 7 Armour 3   Ragnar Bloodaxe  - A berserker from the icy fjords of the great north, his strength and rage are unmatched in all the land, and the quick strikes from his twin axes are deadly indeed. Little is known about his motivations to seek out Asmodeus and recover the Mace of Tanis.   Combo Starters: Air Quick – Q (in air near ground)   Basic combos: Q, S, Q S S, Q, Q   Comboable Specials:  Sweep – B, D ,F, S Roll n’ Scoop – B, F, K Fake Roll n’ Scoop – F, F- K (Horns hit but there is no scoop)   Stand alone Specials: Head Rush – B Q S (sends character flying) Big Chop – Q S (anticrouch) Anticrouch – F Q S (anticrouch) Double Axe Attack – Q S K (anticrouch) Frenzy – F tap Q quickly Thunder Clap – B, F, Q   Fatality B, D, F, B, K (in close)   Fighting Statistics Speed 6 Power 9 Reach 6 Armour 4   Takeshi Tsunami:   captionBorn the second son of a noble and powerful Japanese family, he is the youngest Samurai in the Emperor’s High command. He is out to restore the family honour and redeem his brother Ichiro, who has succumbed to the dark spell of Asmodeus.   Combo Starters: Air Quick – Q (in air near ground) Steel Waterfall – F, D, B, S Hop Kick – B, F, K   Basic combos: S, Q, S Q, Q, S   Comboable Specials: Flipping Uppercut – B, D, F ,S Energy Palm – B, F, S (can be followed by Q S and then another special) Typhoon Fury – F Tap Q quickly   Stand Alone Specials: Sweep – B K High Thrust – Q S (can be followed with a special) Low Thrust – S K (can be followed with a special) Zen Dodge – E S (can be followed with a special) Left Spin – E Q (can be followed with a special) Dodge Slash – F Q S   Fatality F, D, B, D, F, S (in close)   Fighting Statistics Speed 8 Power 7 Reach 7 Armour 8   Xiao Long  caption Born the son of a Chinese Warlord, Xiao Long was trained in the skills of martial combat. When he was fourteen, Xiao’s father burned out Xiao’s eyes and cast him outside the city walls to meet his fate. Taken in by the monks, Xiao has become a deadly fighter by mastering the sixth sense. Sensing that a great evil is encroaching, Xiao sets out to prevent the spread of pestilence to his native land. To do so, he must vanquish Asmodeus and destroy the Mace.   Combo Starters: Air Quick – Q (in air near ground) Kneehit – Tap B Q Hop Kick – B, F, K   Basic Combos:   S, Q, K Q, K, K   Comboable Specials:   1000 Staffs – Hold S for 2 seconds, release (can be followed by special) Staff Sweep – D, F, Q (then another Special) Leg Sweep – B K Fierce – Q S Spin Kick – B, D, F, K Lowhigh – F, D, B, S (sweeps the chops) Slide Right – E Q   Stand Alone Specials: Orb – Hold B for 2 seconds F, S (holds victim still for 1.5 seconds) Block/Kick – F, D, B, K (can be followed with a special) Thrust – B, F, Q (can be followed with a special) Slide Left – E S Knockout – B, D, F, S Overhand – F Q S   Fatality B, F, B, F, S   Fighting Statistics Speed 10 Power 5 Reach 6 Armour 3     Sir Dregan   Asmodeus made Dregan a member of the Covenant of Seven, promising Dregan access to plenty of Souls in return for his loyalty. Now Dregan has learned that Asmodeus has known the location of his lost soul and that the power of the Mace can restore his humanity.    Ichiro   Ichiro wants more than just the taste of power; he hungers to control the great Mace, and once and for all crush his younger brother Takeshi. Ichiro will rule and turn it into the greatest warrior nation the world has ever seen.   Gar Gudrunson   Gar Gudrunson, of the dwarves, has a vision: he is marching across the battlefields above a strange engine, solidly built of iron and brass and powered by steam. In his dream, Gar’s bizarre creation smashes the enemy and wins freedom for the dwarfs’ legions. Hellknight  The Hellknight is a minor demon from hell who has been dispatched to destroy Asmodeus and return the Mace of Tanis to its rightful owner. Each use of the Mace drains power from Hell, sending the nether realms into chaos. Following the trail of evil energy, the Hellknight has at long last found the Earth and the .</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="561">Dark Rift</game><game id="10533">Conker's Bad Fur Day</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2375808-box_mtda.png</image></root>