<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19126</id><name>EverQuest Online Adventures</name><description>OverviewContinent of TunariaThe setting takes place in the world of Norrath on the continent of Tunaria 500 years before Everquest for the PC. Many of the locations that are in Everquest Online adventures were renamed to fit in with the lore of Everquest PC. Each race has their own capital city in which they start their adventure: Barbarians in Halas, Dark Elves in Neriak, Dwarves in Moradhim, Elves in Tethelin, Erudite in HighBourne, Gnomes in KlikAnon, Halflings in Rivervale, Humans (Eastern) in Freeport, Humans (Western) in Qeynos, Ogres in Oggok, and Trolls in Grobb.GameplayThe game play is based on a leveling system in which the player is required to participate in combat against enviromental Non-playable characters and doing quests to recieve experience. The current level cap is 60 but when a player reaches this level the Class Masteries system allows the player to further develop their character. There is also a Player versus Player (PVP) system that allows two players to duel.Races and ClassesNorrath is home to nine unique races (Ten if you separate Eastern and Western Humans). Players are also able to choose from fifteen playable classes.RacesBarbarianBarbarianA hearty race of warriors, Barbarians hail from the frozen wastelands of Halas. Though formidable fighters many Barbarians follow the mystical ways of the shaman class.(Available classes: Rogue, Shaman, Warrior)Dark ElfDark ElfThe mirror opposite of the Elf, the Dark Elf hate other races as much as other races hate them. Dark Elves believe other races are beneath them and that one day they will rule Norrath.Because other races hate Dark Elves, many cities are off limits and travel is some times hard for them. Dark Elves believe that mastering all skills and talents is key for taking all of Norrath.Dark Elves prefer magic and science but also train in physical combat.(Available classes: Alchemist, Cleric, Enchanter, Magician, Necromancer, Rogue, Shadowknight, Warrior, Wizard)DwarfDwarfSmall but strong, the versatile Dwarves are as capable of swinging a sword or club as they are of casting a spell to heal an injured comrade. Dwarves live in the underground caverns of Moradhim and spend much of their time mining the precious minerals that keep Norrath running.(Available classes: Cleric, Paladin, Rogue, Warrior)ElfElfElves fight for the ways of good and righteousness. They are intelligent creatures capable of following a wide variety of classes. Depending on what class you choose determines what your beginning city will be: the high treetop village of Tethelin or the pristine city of Fayspires.(Available classes: Alchemist, Bard, Cleric, Druid, Enchanter, Magician, Paladin, Ranger, Rogue, Wizard)EruditeEruditeAn intelligent race, Erudites are skillful magic users, leaving manual battle to lesser races and the occasional paladin or Shadowknight. Erudites live on the west coast of Norrath in the harbor city of Highbourne.(Available classes: Alchemist, Cleric, Enchanter, Magician, Necromancer, Paladin, Shadowknight, Wizard)GnomeGnomeWithin the underground caverns of Klick'Anon, Gnomes roam the burrows and go about their daily business. An easy-going race, Gnomes create machines, honing their tinkering abilities on one new invention after another.(Available classes: Alchemist, Cleric, Enchanter, Magician, Necromancer, Rogue, Warrior, Wizard)HalflingHalflingA small and agile race, the Halfling call Rivervale their home. Though Halfling are small in size, their dexterity makes them excellent fighters.(Available classes: Cleric, Druid, Rogue, Warrior)HumanHumanHumans have the largest selection of classes. Humans begin their adventure in Qeynos, Freeport, or Surefall Glade, depending upon the class you choose. The western humans tend to be follows of justice while the eastern humans tend to stick to the shadows.(Available classes: Alchemist, Bard, Cleric, Druid, Enchanter, Magician, Monk, Necromancer, Paladin, Ranger, Rogue, Shadowknight, Warrior, Wizard)OgreOgreOgres are a race bred for war. Their massive frames provide them with strength and stamina greater than other races. They're most comfortable on the frontline of an assault, decked out in the heaviest of armor and holding a huge weapon. An ancient curse dulled their minds, Which has limited their ability to wield magic.(Available classes: Warrior, Shadowknight, Warrior, Wizard)TrollTrollVoracious fighters, Trolls are mean. They hate every other race on Norrath and would like nothing more than to dine on their flesh. In addition to being exceptional warriors, many trolls have followed the ways of the shadowknight or the shaman. Trolls make their home in Grobb.(Available classes: Shadowknight, Shaman, Warrior)ClassesAlchemist**BardClericDruidEnchanterMagicianMonkNecromancerPaladinRangerRogueShamanShadowknightWarriorWizard**Alchemist is only available in EverQuest Online Adventures: FrontiersOther InformationEaster EggsThe city Qeynos is Sony EQ backwards.</description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19215">EverQuest Online Adventures: Frontiers</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2275986-box_eqoa.png</image></root>