<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19134</id><name>Street Fighter Alpha 2</name><description>OverviewStreet Fighter Alpha 2, known as Street Fighter Zero 2 in Japan, Asia, South America, and Spain. Is a 2D fighting game developed and published by                                     Capcom. Street Fighter Alpha 2 is seen as a overhaul over                                     Street Fighter Alpha: Warriors' Dreams than a actual sequel. The game features a number improvements over the last game including gameplay systems, character moves, and stages. GameplayStreet Fighter Alpha 2 retains most of the features in                                     Street Fighter Alpha: Warriors' Dreams like the three level super combo gauge, alpha counters and air-blocking. The main new feature in Street Fighter Alpha 2 is the custom combo system which replaces chain combos from the previous game.  When the custom combo guage is at level 1 or above the player can activate a custom combo by by pressing two punch buttons following a kick. Custom combos grant the player a limited amount of time to chain almost any attacks together into a combo. The time limit is dependent on how much power was in the super meter when the combo was initiated.Ports Street fighter games where often ported to home platforms. However most home platforms could not keep up with the CPS-2 hardware; this led to gameplay changes between platforms.    The North American SNES Box Art      The    Sega Saturn version was an improvement over its arcade counterpart. The Saturn version had a survival mode as well as art gallery in addition to all thew arcade gameplay features.   The    SNES version was the greatest affected. It has only one of the secret characters found in the other versions, a classic version of Chun Li. This version also has slow sprite decompression resulting in load times on the cartridge.      Characters          Character select screen All ten selectable characters from Street Fighter Alpha: Warriors' Dreams return along with Akuma, Dan and M. Bison being in the starting lineup.                                      Ryu                                     Ken                                     Chun-Li                                     Guy                                     Sodom                                     Birdie                                     Adon                                     Charlie                                     Rose                                     Dan                                     Sagat                                     M. Bison                                     Akuma                                     Rolento                                     Gen                                     Zangief                                     Dhalism                                     Sakura                                     Evil Ryu                                   Shin AkumaCameosDan's Stage                                Fei Long Guy's StageFrom left to right                                Andore                              CodyJessica                            Bill Bull                           Abigail                          Edi E                         Haggar                        J                       Damnd                      Poison                     AxlKen's StageKens Stage Featuring a Large Cast of Capcom Cameos       From left to right                    Lord Raptor                  Hsien-Ko                 Mei-Lin                Unknown Soldier Player 1     Unknown Soldier Player 2               Morrigan              Jumbo              Biff Slamkovich             Ginzu           Captain Commando          Michelle Heart         Strider Hiryu        Linn Kurosawa       Felicia      Pure</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3185">ClayFighter 63 1/3</game><game id="14669">Virtua Fighter Animation</game><game id="21614">Shaman King: Spirit of Shamans</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="4124">The King of Fighters '97</game><game id="8605">Marvel vs. Capcom: Clash of Super Heroes</game><game id="5640">Capcom vs. SNK: Millennium Fight 2000 Pro</game><game id="4249">The King of Fighters '94</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="21519">The King of Fighters XII</game><game id="28437">Super Street Fighter IV</game><game id="30416">K-1 Pocket Grand Prix 2</game><game id="34082">Skullgirls</game><game id="43092">Kuài Dǎ Chuánshuō</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1791303-box_sfa2.png</image></root>