<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19171</id><name>Andre Agassi Tennis</name><description>Overview  Andre Agassi stars in his first tennis game that came out for the       SMS,      SNES,     Genesis and    Game Gear. This tennis game does not have any other notable tennis stars to note but features many game play options like practice, tournament and skins tournament that makes this game unique from other tennis games before it came out.GameplayThe game uses the same rules of tennis that is played today. A player must get 40 points to win a game, 6 games to win a set and win 2 sets out of the 3 to finish the full match. The game allows you to play either singles or doubles in either tournament or skins tournament. You can even select what court surface to play on like grass, clay, hard or indoor. After you select a type of game, you will have a choice of any of these players: Andre AgassiTiger BallRon PepperDon MattBob "Bit" ChinGeorge KingCarol ArkCasie NovaEach play has attributes for them like speed, strength (backhand, forehand and server) and accuracy (backhand, forehand and server) which makes your choice of a player an interesting one. Once a player has been selected, two main buttons will been used during the match. The (A) button will help you lob the ball in the air while the (B) button will help you hit the ball normally (this is for the Genesis version). When the ball is served or hit on your side of the court, your job is to have your player get a close as possible to the ball and hit it back. You will use either a backhand or forehand depending on your position before hitting the ball. You can move around the court and position yourself using the D-pad.Game Modes Practice Mode - This mode allows you to select a player and have a ball machine feed you balls so you can practice your game. There are not winner or losers in this mode.Tournament Mode - Like a career mode, you select a player to play in a tournament and face many opponents before facing your final opponent and winning it all.Skins Tournament Mode - This is a tournament that places money down on each hit that takes place during the match. Whoever wins a point will receive the total amount of money in the pot. The pot starts with $10 and doubles each hit from there on in</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="25">Tennis</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23423">Agassi Tennis Generation</game><game id="5332">ATP Tour Championship Tennis</game><game id="18664">Super Tennis</game><game id="23133">Super Family Tennis</game><game id="32594">Top Spin 4</game><game id="38922">Date Kimiko no Virtual Tennis</game><game id="28144">International Tennis Tour</game><game id="40446">Super Final Match Tennis</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2362846-sms_andreagassitennis_au.jpg</image></root>