<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19180</id><name>Motocross Madness 2</name><description>OverviewFollowing up Microsoft's popular  Motocross Madness, Motocross Madness 2 features an overhauled graphics and physics engine as well as a brand new career mode. It carries the same game modes as its predecessor, but with larger and more detailed maps.Race ModesPro-Circuit: MCM2's career mode, the player starts off with an average bike and gear and must work their way to the top. The player is awarded money for winning races and can purchase items such as new bike parts and protective gear.Baja  Enduro: The player is pitted against opponents to race through a certain number of 'Gates', similar to Midtown Madness's Checkpoint mode. The player to race through all 'Gates' wins.Nationals: The player must race a certain number of laps within a dirt-track, and the first one to finish all laps wins the race.Stunt: The player performs stunts around an open track (Farm, trailer park, ski course, construction site, etc.) under a set time-limit and are awarded points depending on how dangerous the stunt is or how many stunts the player performed in mid-air. The player with the most points at the end of the round wins.Supercross: Supercross is similar to Nationals, but is set on a much larger scale. Tracks are set in football stadiums and baseball fields, and the tracks are twice as large as the ones in Nationals.BikesLicensed bikes from Honda, Yamaha, KTM and Suzuki are available in-game, and if the player has an image editing program (Such as Photoshop), players are able to create new paintschemes for their bike.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6787">Supercross Circuit</game><game id="4603">Motocross Madness</game><game id="9981">MX vs. ATV Unleashed</game><game id="17685">MotoGP: Ultimate Racing Technology 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/20737/762212-mcm2.jpg</image></root>