<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19181</id><name>Return to Castle Wolfenstein</name><description>OverviewReturn to Castle Wolfenstein is the sequel to the original Wolfenstein 3D developed by id Software. You reprise the role of William "B.J" Blazkowicz the protagonist from Wolfenstein 3D. As you go deeper into Nazi Germany and the Third Reich, you start to encounter paranormal events such as the dead coming back to life and experimental soldiers such as the "loper". The single-player is of a lengthy value and the multiplayer has a deep character-class that became widely popular. The Xbox version has split-screen Co-op. To unlock the levels you have to beat the single player in order to continue from one specific level.PlotPlaying as B.J. Blazkowicz, you wake in a remote castle in Europe. After escaping the castle you are given a mission to infiltrate Himmler's S.S. Paranormal Division by finding Helga von Bulow in a European village. You discover a series of catacombs and eventually, Helga, in a bombed out church. You find that Helga transforms into a giant creature of dismembered bodies and souls. After defeating Helga you are given instructions to head into the remote German forest to gather Intel on a secret Nazi V2 rocket plane. After escaping with the plane, B.J. is given the objective to infiltrate Deathshead secret weapons base located in a bombed out city.After locating the secret weapons base you must find the location of Deathshead's secret X-Labs. The X-Labs base in the Norwegian Arctic is your next objective. Upon entering the X-Labs B.J. is greeted by scientific mutants and super soldiers created by the Nazis. Deathshead escapes from the X-Labs, but after learning of his plans you are given orders to go back the Castle Wolfenstein to stop the revival of Heinrich I from his grave. After making your way through a village and château you discover the dig site. Finally you arrive at Castle Wolfenstein and discover that the ceremony has proceeded. After a brutal fight with Heinrich you find yourself killing Nazis for fun in the final cutscene as some RR.EnemiesNazi SoldierElite GuardNazi OfficersBlack GuardScientistsZombieFlaming ZombieZombie KnightLoperSuper Soldier PrototypeSuper SoldierSoulsHelga's TransformationHeinrich IWeaponsKnifeLugerColt .45 (x2)Grenades ( Stielhandgranate and Pineapple)DynamiteMP40Thompson SMGSten (silenced)Mauser Rifle (scope)Snooper RifleFG42PanzerfaustVenom GunFlamethrowerTesla GunLevelsMission 1: Ominous RumorsMission 2: Dark SecretMission 3: Weapons of VengeanceMission 4: Deadly DesignsMission 5: Deathshead's PlaygroundMission 6: Return EngagementMission 7: Operation ResurrectionMultiplayerThe multiplayer portion of the game was developed by Nerve Software and quickly became the most popular aspect of the game. and influential in the genre. Return to Castle Wolfenstein's multiplayer component featured a class based system and unique team oriented, objective based gameplay.The Allies and Axis must complete specific goals on each map in order to win the round, in most cases Allies attack while the Axis defend. There were primary and secondary objectives. Primary objectives had to be completed to win the game but not secondary objectives even though completing them would aid in the completion of the primary objective An objective would be, for example, on Omaha Beach, the Allies must first blow a hole in a wall in order to get access to the Axis bunkers.Each character class helps their team in different ways, the Medic can supply health packs and revive fallen comrades, the Lieutenant can drop ammo packs and call for air strikes, the Engineer can repair vehicles and plant dynamites while the Solider can use a lot of different weaponry. Thanks to the popularity of this mode, numerous mods starting appearing the most famous one being OSP. OSP is used for competitive play like at QuakeCon because of the control it gives to the players and the admins.There are three separate multiplayer modes:Standard: This mode has one round of offense and one round of defense for both teams. Both teams get a pre-decided amount of time to complete all objectives on the map.Stopwatch: This mode has two rounds of offense and two rounds of defense for both teams. Team A would attack would try to complete all objectives as quickly as possible in order to create a time for Team B to compete against. If Team A is unable to set a time in the first round, no score will given to either teams. Team B will be on attack in the second, and third round. Team A will be on attack in the fourth and final round of that map (ABBA). If Team A were to set a time, and Team B beats it, Team B will be awarded one point. The team that has the most points at the end of the four rounds wins.Checkpoint: The objective in this mode is to control all the flag points located in various locations of the map. The first team to control all flags simultaneously wins the round.DevelopmentThe game is powered by the Quake 3: Team Arena Engine. Different versions of the game exist:The original release version (also called version 1.0).The game of the year edition (2002-v. 1.33) that came with the game Wolfenstein 3D and new multiplayer maps (Ice, Tram, Trenchtoast and Keep).The platinum edition (2004-v. 1.42) that came with Wolfenstein: Enemy Territory and Wolfenstein 3D.The game was ported to Linux and Mac in 2002 and then to Playstation 2 and Xbox in 2003 with bonus content.Wolfenstein: Enemy TerritoryWolfenstein: Enemy Territory was originally planned to be an expansion pack for Return to Castle Wolfenstein, however it was released as a seperate, multiplayer only, free game. The game features two teams faced against each other (One team defends objectives while others attack). The game is class based and team oriented. Play as a Soldier, Medic, Engineer, Covert Ops, and Field Ops. Each class features separate weapons and skills.ClassWeaponsSkillsSoldierHeavy Weapons: Mortar, MG42, Flamethrower, Bazooka, and SMGAbility to run with heavy weaponsMedicSyringe, SMG, GrenadeDrop health packs, revive teammates, and regenerate healthEngineerSMG, Rilfe, Rifle Grenades, Pistol, KnifeRepair Vehicles, build embankments, arm/defuse demolitionsCovert OpsSilent Sten, Scoped FG42, Silenced scoped rifle, smoke grenades, place remote explosives, Silenced Pistol, KnifeDisguise in enemy uniform, shows enemy positions on mini map, shows enemy landminesField OpsKnife, SMG, PistolDrop ammo packs, call air strikes, call artillery strikesPC RequirementsOperating System: Windows 95 OSR2/98/ME/NT 4.0 (SP5)/2000/XPProcessor: Pentium II 400 MHz CPU or Athlon CPUGraphics Card: 16 MB full OpenGL compiant graphics cardRAM Memory: 128 MB RAMHard Drive Space: 800 MBSound Card: DirectX 3.0 or higher compatible sound cardDirectX: 3.0</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6074">Day of Defeat</game><game id="19429">The Ultimate Doom</game><game id="19230">Medal of Honor</game><game id="65">Serious Sam</game><game id="10955">Unreal Tournament 3</game><game id="7747">John Romero's Daikatana</game><game id="21912">Planetside: Core Combat</game><game id="14947">ÜberSoldier</game><game id="10049">Medal of Honor: Underground</game><game id="8271">Commandos: Strike Force</game><game id="1629">Call of Duty</game><game id="7326">Doom</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2287889-rtcw.png</image></root>