<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19200</id><name>Fatal Fury Special</name><description>Overview Fatal Fury Special (known in Japan as Garou Densetsu Special) is a fighting game developed and published by                             SNK for the                            Neo Geo and is an update to                           Fatal Fury 2. It's an update similar to                          Street Fighter II': Champion Edition, as the background stages are slightly changed and the four bosses are now playable. The game also includes the return of three characters from the original                         Fatal Fury (                       Duck King,                       Tung Fu Rue, and                      Geese Howard) along with a secret character from the                    Art of Fighting franchise (                    Ryo Sakazaki). The game also features a faster game speed and a new combo system. Ports SNES North American Box Art     The game was ported to the                 SNES,                Game Gear,               Sega CD, and              PC Engine (in Japan, with a special "Arcade Card" add-on). SNK also released Fatal Fury Special to the             Neo Geo CD. The original Neo Geo version was also included in the            Fatal Fury Battle Archives Volume 1 compilation for the           PlayStation 2 and was released on the                  Wii Virtual Console on November 4, 2009. It was also released on the          Xbox 360 as an         Xbox Live Arcade game on September 5, 2007 featuring online play, HD display,        achievements and leaderboards. GameplayThe gameplay is directly from Fatal Fury 2, with the exception of allowing players to combo their attacks. This makes Fatal Fury Special the most competitive Fatal Fury game before      Garou: Mark of the Wolves. Returning Characters  Character Select Screen Showing Terry and Andy  Terry Bogard                                        Andy Bogard                                       Joe Higashi                                      Mai Shiranui                                     Kim Kaphwan                                    Big Bear   Jubei Yamada                                   Cheng Sinzan                                Billy Kane  Axel Hawk Laurence Blood                              Wolfgang Krauser New Characters  In Fatal Fury Special fan favorite characters where added from the the first Fatal Fury. This includes the boss character Geese Howard. CharacterNationality  Brief Stage Description StageTung Fu Rue     JapaneseMountain top with old bridge           Duck King   American American Night Clubue      Geese Howard  American Ancient Temple       Secret Character Ryo Sakazaki is a hidden boss in Fatal Fury Special. To fight Ryo you must beat the game without losing a single round. and after the last boss he will appear to challenge you.    CharacterNationality Brief stage description Stage Ryo Sakazaki American   </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="243">Street Fighter II: The World Warrior</game><game id="4249">The King of Fighters '94</game><game id="8680">Street Fighter Alpha 3 MAX</game><game id="10674">Garou: Mark of the Wolves</game><game id="11156">X-Men vs. Street Fighter</game><game id="6665">Super Street Fighter II</game><game id="21952">Killer Instinct 2</game><game id="7751">Art of Fighting Anthology</game><game id="21699">The King of Fighters '98 Ultimate Match</game><game id="7111">Savage Reign</game><game id="14669">Virtua Fighter Animation</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="10486">Fighter's History</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4737/451375-ffspecial.jpg</image></root>