<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19246</id><name>Vampire Night</name><description>Plot A struggle between light and dark, from 300 years back, is about to ensue. The parties involved are Albert and Michael, the two vampire hunters representing light, and the vampires representing dark. The story takes place in an alternate version of the year 2006, when progress looks stuck in the 19th century.    Albert and Michael rescue a 12- year old girl named Caroline who witnessed a couple of villagers held hostage by the vampire Sarcoma. After rescuing the villagers and Caroline, the vampire hunters proceed into the castle to destroy the remaining forces of dark. Although the forces of evil reveal that they created Albert and Michael and used them to kill themselves, but they became afraid of death and tried to stop them. It is important to note that the hunters are in fact Dhampyrs (half-vampires), due to their glowing eyes and sunglasses. The outcome is a pyrrhic victory for the forces of good as the forces of evil are stopped but at the cost of Albert's and Michael's lives. From the Wikipedia page.  Characters Vampire Hunters-  Albert and Michael are half vapmires created by Count Augustine.  This results in Albert and Michael having special abilities like; superhuman strength, a leaping ability and vampiric traits such as golden-glowing eyes. They are determined to wipeout vampires for good.  The Survivor- Caroline  is a 12-year old girl whose traumatic experiences of her childhood  "ages" her before her years. She is the only survivor of a vampire onslaught. Albert and Michael saved her from the onslaught and continue to look after her throughout the game.  Vampires/Bosses- Count Auguste/Sir Vampire- Leads the army of vampires in the war against light and dark. He created Albert and Michael to destroy himself just in case he could no longer bear immortality but became afraid of dying and tried to stop them. Bathe'lemy- A vampire Knight who searches for the meaning of life.Guillaume- A scientist gone mad who was ridiculed from his homeland because of his sick experiments.Raoul-  A dark-minded fencer who wants to avenge his love interest Sophie by killing humans.Diane- A mermaid that fell in love with Count Auguste. The count turned her into a vampire and now she serves the forces of darkness as the Ice Queen. She is willing to do anything to please her master (Count Auguste) and often battles the vampire hunters because of this. </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17486">Mad Dog McCree</game><game id="6490">Hogan's Alley</game><game id="20519">Ghost Squad</game><game id="1113">Gumshoe</game><game id="15867">Time Crisis</game><game id="15365">Time Crisis 2</game><game id="9898">Time Crisis 3</game><game id="21468">Time Crisis 4</game><game id="10543">Virtua Cop</game><game id="9341">Virtua Cop 2</game><game id="1744">Lethal Enforcers</game><game id="12213">Lethal Enforcers II: Gun Fighters</game><game id="12829">Revolution X</game><game id="4125">The Lost World: Jurassic Park</game><game id="9780">Silent Scope</game><game id="16423">Silent Scope 2: Dark Silhouette</game><game id="4304">Silent Scope 3</game><game id="6077">Crisis Zone</game><game id="20460">Target: Terror</game><game id="21276">CarnEvil</game><game id="15008">Confidential Mission</game><game id="16218">Battle Clash</game><game id="3484">Metal Combat: Falcon's Revenge</game><game id="15848">Resident Evil: Survivor</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2491492-box_vn.png</image></root>