<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19281</id><name>Oddworld: Abe's Exoddus</name><description>OverviewCreated by Oddworld Inhabitants under the direction of Lorne Lanning. Released in November 1998 to the same critical acclaim (notably for its wonderful 2D graphics and graphically stunning cutscenes which were entertaining as well) as the first title.Get the slaves away from the gas and snap them out of it.A platformer with a dark sense of humor, Abe's Exoddus is considered a bonus title in the Oddworld series because it is not part of the main quintology. While keeping the same core gameplay as the original it adds numerous additions including the much needed quick save, characters having different emotions and some being blind, new enemies, and the ability to possess Paramites, Scrabs, Glukkons, and your own farts after drinking SoulStorm Brew and use it as an explosive.You travel through several areas including the Necrum Mines, FeeCo Depot, Slig Barracks and the SoulStorm brewery itself.StoryAbe leading his followers to SoulStorm brewery.Abe's Exoddus takes off where Abe's Oddysee ended. Abe, the hero of the first game and liberator of the Mudokon slaves of RuptureFarms, returns home to a heroes welcome from all 99 Mudokons he saved. Clumsy as he is, he trips and is knocked unconscious. He is then visited by a vision from the "Three Weirdos". Abe is told about a new threat from the the Magog Cartel. He finds out their using slaves to mine Necrum, the sacred Mudokon city of the dead, to collect bones that they add to the ultra-addictive SoulStorm Brew.Abe and a group of Mudokons set out across the desert to find the SoulStorm brewery and free the slaves. Just as they are about to give up and go home they hear a noise in the distance getting closer and closer. Suddenly a huge train screams past them and it's heading right to the brewery. With new found hope they set off and follow the train. When they finally arrive at SoulStorm they climb the fence and enter. Just as they get in, Abe loses his footing, slips and falls down a set of cliffs, cutting him off from the rest of the group and beginning the first level of the game.EndingsIt's not fair! We had twice zee flavour!There are two different endings in the game depending on how many Mudokon slaves you rescue.If you save 0-149 slaves, you get the bad ending.If you save 150-300 slaves, you get the good ending.Additionally, if all 300 Mudokons are saved, the player is rewarded with a concept art gallery, and if 276 Mudokons are killed, Abe is sent back to the FeeCo Depot with permanent invincibility.EnemiesThere is a vast range of enemies in Oddworld. Here is a brief description of them.Pants! I need some pants!Crawling Sligs - Sligs without pants or a harness. Despised by Glukkons, Mudokons and especially other Sligs, they are complete cowards and when threatened they rush to find a pair of pants.Here boy!Sligs - The primary security force for all Magog Cartel structures. They use mechanical pants and normally are equipped with a machine gun.Somethin' smells!Flying Sligs - Same as Sligs but instead of using the mechanical pants they use mechanical harness with a grenade launcher.SlogSlogs - Sligs best friend. Fast attacking creatures used as guards and back-up for Slig patrols.SloggieSloggies - Baby Slogs. Younger, smaller and not as fast as a full grown Slog. They can still take a nasty chunk out of you.FleechFleeches - Starting off as pets of Glukkons, they grow too big and are flushed down the toilet. Colonies now infest Oddworld's underworld.SlurgSlurgs - Pathetic, useless slug-like creatures. Not a threat but when stepped on they make a high pitched screech alerting anything in the area, normally Fleeches.ParamiteParamites - Fast, efficient hunter carnivores. They'll make short work of Abe, or anything else that looks like a tasty meal.ScrabScrabs - Scrabs are highly territorial and incredibly hardy predators that originated from the desert. Scrabs have beaks powerful enough to snap bone.GlukkonGlukkons - The big dogs of Oddworld. They own and control Magog Cartel. Greedy, ruthless and only care about them self. They won't attack you but he sure that they'll have a decent amount of armed protection.GreeterGreeters - A tin can with a huge smile. First used as self-promoting vending machines they now act as security guards after discovering they had the habit of electrocuting their customers.Munch's Oddysee teaseUpon completion of Abe's Exodus and viewing the final cinematic the next game in the series; Munch's Oddysee was shown simply as a title and a Mudokon speaking the words: "and don't even think about running it on your measly 32 bit system!"True to their word, the game was in full 3D and ran on the 128-bit Xbox.It was also mentioned in the manual for the game.Oddworld Inhabitants finally released both Munch's Oddysee and Stranger's Wrath on PCs in a compilation titled The Oddboxx on December 20, 2010.Another reference to Munch was a sign in a later part of Exodus which read 'Vykers Labs, Coming Soon'. The Vykers Labs are a location in Munch's Oddysee run by the Vykers, a creepy bunch of lanky purple skinned tripod creatures that enjoy experimenting on captured animals.Original System RequirementsCPU Type: PentiumCPU Speed: 120 MHzRAM Required: 16 MBGraphics Type: SVGAGraphics Resolution: 640x480Color Depth: High Color</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="758">Heart of Darkness</game><game id="1066">Flashback: The Quest for Identity</game><game id="17785">Heart of the Alien: Out of this World Parts I and II</game><game id="17483">Out of This World</game><game id="20330">Gex 3: Deep Cover Gecko</game><game id="22011">Zeno Clash</game><game id="5729">The Curse of Monkey Island</game><game id="11470">Scaler</game><game id="2235">Planescape: Torment</game><game id="36447">Rocketbirds: Hardboiled Chicken</game><game id="35489">The War of the Worlds</game><game id="30380">Limbo</game><game id="36870">Stealth Bastard: Tactical Espionage Arsehole</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4938/872383-oddworld.png</image></root>