<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19316</id><name>Headhunter</name><description> OverviewJack Wade is a headhunter in a near future Los-Angeles. After Jack awakes from a coma he realizes that he cannot remember his own identity.  The only way to regain what he has mysteriously lost is by embarking on a quest for his past in hopes of saving his future. When the Anti-Crime Network's (A.C.N) chief officer is murdered, it's up to Jack to bring his killers to justice by any means necessary. Headhunter is a tactical espionage game that combines a limited open world setting with stealth action and gunplay .  Characters  Jack Wade - The main character and protagonist in the main story line.  Queen of Hearts - Import/Export ship for X-Must Energy Drink.  Adam - Adam is genetically altered and represents a superior human race in the game.   Hank Redwood - a bounty hunter for ACN.  Doctor Ernst Zweiberg - Adams creator  Angela Stern - Jack's assistant that also works for the A.C.N ( Anti-Crime Network)  Eve - A virus planned to be released by the ACN, used  to destroy the human race and form a perfect race.  Wolfpack - Wolfpack is an outlaw gang that is tasked to retrieve human organs in trade for money and weapons.  ACN (Anti-Crime Network) - the future law system which plans to distribute the virus in shipments of X-Must Energy Drink.  Biotech - Company responsible for inventing the weapons featured in Headhunter.  Grey Wolf - An initial enemy of Jack that eventually becomes a friend and aid.  Alan Sharp - President of ACN.  L.E.I.L.A. (Law Enforcement Intelligence and License Approval) - a virtual reality simulator which give ACN bounty hunters a license.  Ramirez - a member of Wolfpack who divulges critical information of the connection between ACN and Wolfpack.  Gladiator - A challenging boss character.  Underwater Arena - an underwater gladiatorial prison owned by ACN.   Weapons Stimulator Automatic - Basic handgun with a 10 round magazine, but can be upgraded to 16 rounds later in the game. Resonator Grenade -  Standard grenade. Scorpion Neurostunner  - A tranquilizer, must be charged up.Regulator Shotgun - Standard shotgun, does lots of damage close up, but much less farther away. Sub Machine Gun - Machine gun with a 30 round magazine.   Missile Launcher - A missile launcher that tracks your enemies.  Proximity Mine - Explosive which detonates when other come near it.    </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5961">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell</game><game id="12388">Metal Gear Solid 2: Sons of Liberty</game><game id="6709">Hitman: Codename 47</game><game id="7004">Hitman 2: Silent Assassin</game><game id="27248">Frame City Killer</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2428397-box_hh.png</image></root>