<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19322</id><name>Rise of Nations: Thrones &amp; Patriots</name><description>Rise of Nations: Thrones and Patriots is the expansion pack to Rise of Nations, the expansion added 6 new races, Dutch, Americans, Lakota, Iroquois, Indians, and Persians. The Expansion also added new Wonders.Also included were four new "Conquer the World" Campaigns. Alexander the Great, Napoleon I of France, Cold War, and New World.  New Races  Dutch            Start with 1 Commerce Tech Already researched                    Commerce research 25% cheaper                    Start with a Market and 2 free Merchants                    For every 100 of a resource in your treasury beyond           starting level receive  5 income for that resource (except           Knowledge).           This income can exceed Commerce Cap by 50.                    Receive two Light Ships whenever a New Dock is built.                    Ship Upgrades 10% Cheaper           Unique Units Armed Merchant (Ancient Age)Armed Merchant (Industrial Age)Armed Caravan (Ancient Age)Armed Caravan (Industrial Age)Armed Supply Wagon (Medieval Age)Armed Supply Truck (Industrial Age)Brig (Medieval Age)Fluyt (Gunpowder Age)Clipper (Enlightenment Age)Americans  Government Upgrades are free at the SenateFirst Wonder is built instantly provided no other nation is in the process of building it (excludes Space Program and Suppercollider)Aircraft Carriers are 20% cheaper   Start with 1 Science Tech already researchedReceive 2 free bombers whenever an airbase is built((Begins at Modern Age)Receive a free Scholar whenever a new University is builtMilitary ground units upgrade 25% cheaperReceive  3 Food, Timber, Metal, and Wealth for every non Scout barracks unit while they are not garrisoned Unique Units  Continental Marines (Enlightenment Age)Marine Riflemen (Industrial Age)Marine Infantry (Modern Age)Assault Marines (Information Age)   Lakota            Instead of building Farms and Granaries, receive           Food for each Citizen, Scout, and Calvary unit (except when           garrisoned).                    Farms and Granaries in Captured Enemy Cities Instantly           Destroyed.                    Have no National Territory, and can construct           buildings in any territory not held by another nation.                    Ranged Cavalry upgrades are free.           Unique Units Sunka Wakan (Classical Age)Eagle Feather Horse (Medieval Age)Musket Horse (Gunpowder Age)Repeating Rifle Horse (Enlightenment Age) Iroquois            Get one free Scout unit with each New Barracks built                    Scouts get free upgrades and can move through forests                    Woodcutters also gather  2 Food each                    All units heal when not moving or attacking in friendly           territory                    Military units in friendly territory are hidden when not           attacking                    Barracks units  10% hit points                    First Senate build is free and builds instantly           Unique Units Spearman (Ancient Age)Mohawk Spearmen (Classical Age)Heavy Mohawk Spearmen (Medieval Age)Elite Mohawk Spearmen (Gunpowder Age)Takohs (Ancient Age)Akweks (Medieval Age)Okwari (Enlightenment Age) Indians            Buildings (except Wonders, forts, Towers, Lookout and           Cities)do not ramp up in cost                    Wonders, forts, Towers and Lookout ramp up at half the           rate                    City Economic Radius is increased by  4                    War Elephant upgrades are free, and War Elephant units           are 15% cheaper                    Caravan income is increased by  15%           Unique Units War Elephant (Classical Age)Mahout (Medieval Age)Gun Mahout (Gunpowder Age)Culverin Mahout (Enlightenment Age) Persians            Start with 50% Bonus Food                    Second City built acts as a second Capital.                    Both receive Capital border bonus, and both must be captured to eliminate player                    Receive Taxation upgrades for free                    Civic research 30% Cheaper                    Always have the maximum number of Caravans          Unique Units Immortals (Ancient Age)Anusiya (Classical Age)Athanatoi (Medieval Age)Arquebus Immortal (Gunpowder Age)</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14391">Heroes of Might and Magic: A Strategic Quest</game><game id="2846">Age of Empires II: The Age of Kings</game><game id="8897">Stronghold 2</game><game id="24079">StarCraft II: Legacy of the Void</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4647/1249818-riseofnation.jpg</image></root>