<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19362</id><name>Final Fantasy XI Online: Rise of Zilart</name><description>Overview Rise of ZilartRise of the Zilart was the first expansion pack to be released for Final Fantasy XI.  It was released in Japan on April 17th, 2003 for the PlayStation 2 and Windows PCs.  The expansion was released packed in with the base game for the North American launch of FFXI on October 23, 2003 for Windows and March 24, 2004 for PlayStation 2.New Jobs IntroducedThree new jobs were added with this expansion:Ninja (NIN) - Masters of Ninjutsu magic, and wielders of katanas, Ninjas have assumed a tank role in Final Fantasy XI.Samurai (SAM) - Some of the best damage dealers in FFXI, Samurais have the ability to gain Tactical Points (TP) at a rate much quicker than most other jobs, allowing them to perform weapon skill abilities with their great katanas much more frequently.Dragoon (DRG) - Accompanied by their faithful Wyverns, Dragoons use their spears and incredible jumping abilities to attack their foes.New Avatars Introduced Rise of the Zilart added most of the avatars for the Summoner job class, and the expansion is required to obtain all avatars aside from   Carbuncle, and   Diablos (  Chains of Promathia).The new avatars added were:   Shiva   Ifrit Ramuh  Garuda  Leviathan TitanNew Storylines Rise of the Zilart adds a completely new storyline to the world of Vana'diel where you learn of the story of the ancient races known as the Kuluu and the Zilart, and their quest for ascension into paradise. Also additional storylines were added for the three main nations of Vana'diel, completing the stories behind their unique histories and current state of affairs.New Areas Over 40 new areas and 6 regions were added to Vana'diel. Kutzoz Region - Western and Eastern Altepa Deserts, Quicksand Caves, Cloister of Tremors, Chamber of Oracles, and the desert oasis Rabao.Vollbow Region - Kuftal Tunnel, Gustav Tunnel, Cape Terrigan, Valley of Sorrows, and the Cloister of Gales.Elshimo Lowlands Region - Yuhtunga Jungle, Sea Serpent Grotto, the pirate cove Norg, and the Mithra home of Kahzam.Elshimo Highlands Region - Yhoator Jungle, Ifrit's Cauldron, Cloister of Flames, Cloister of Tides, Temple of Uggalepih, Den of Rancor, and the Sacrificial ChamberLi'Telor Region - The Sanctuary of Zi'Tah, Boyahda Tree, Dragon's Aery, Cloister of Storms, Ro'Maeve, and the Hall of the GodsTu'Lia Region (commonly known as "Sky") - Ru'Aun Gardens, The Shrine of Ru'Avitau, Ve'Lugannon Palace, La'Loff Amplitheater, and the Celestial Nexus.Other Areas - Stellar Fulcrum and Full Moon FountainAddition of "Kings" Notorious MonstersThis expansion also saw the introduction of Notorious Monsters known by most players as "kings". These particular monsters have a 21-24 hour respawn time, and are notorious as being some of the most sought after Notorious Monsters in Final Fantasy XI, even almost 5 years after being introduced.  These NMs are also unique as after a random number of spawns, a stronger version will appear, and these monsters have some of the most wanted items in the game.These monsters are:Normal: Fafnir / Stronger: Nidhogg (Wyrm) - Found in Dragon's AeryNormal: Adamantoise / Stronger: Aspidochelone (Turtle) - Valley of SorrowsNormal: Behemoth / Stronger: King Behemoth (Behemoth) - Behemoth's Dominion SoundtrackThe Rise of the Zilart soundtrack was released on September 24, 2004, and was re-released with the FINAL FANTASY XI: Premium Box on March 27, 2008 01 - Kazham  02 - Yuhtunga Jungle03 - Battle Theme #304 - "Dash de Chocobo"05 - RabaoRise of the Zilart OST 06 - Altepa Desert07 - Battle in the Dungeon #308 - Grav'iton09 - Norg10 - Tough Battle #211 - The Sanctuary of Zi'Tah12 - Ro'Maeve13 - Hall of the Gods14 - Fighters of the Crystal15 - Tu'Lia16 - Ve'Lugannon Palace17 - Eald'narche18 - Belief19 - End Theme </description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22997">The Lord of the Rings Online: Mines of Moria</game><game id="20666">Warhammer Online: Age of Reckoning</game><game id="6204">EverQuest: The Shadows of Luclin</game><game id="21458">White Knight Chronicles: International Edition</game><game id="27896">World of Warcraft: Cataclysm</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4086/281122-379b_8.jpg</image></root>