<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19388</id><name>Ape Escape 3</name><description>StoryA Pipo monkey reporting the news. The evil specter is attempting another plan to take over the world by broadcasting his own TV stations. The shows on the stations are so stupid that they turn everyone who watches them into a mindless couch potato. Spike, Professor, and Jimmy have been turned into mindless couch potato's already so its up to Kei and his sister Yumi to save the world. GameplayThe game allows the player to choose between a playable male character (kei) and a playable female character (Yumi) at the beginning of the game. The gameplay consists of basic platforming and capturing monkeys. The right stick is for aiming and swinging weapons (such as the monkey net). Players can have four items equipped at once, on the X, Square, Circle and Triangle face buttons. Unlike some platformers, Ape Escape uses the R buttons to jump.Mesal GearMesal Gear poster showing Snake, Pipo Snake, and Pipo Ocelot.The game also includes three mini games, one of which is Mesal Gear were you get to play as Pipo Snake, a monkey with Solid Snake's DNA in him. Snake has been captured by the monkeys and it is up to Pipo snake to save snake and stop the monkey Metal Gear.</description><genres><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11407">Vexx</game><game id="18376">Looney Tunes Back in Action</game><game id="24969">Tokobot Plus: Mysteries of the Karakuri</game><game id="25720">Jak and Daxter: The Lost Frontier</game><game id="20351">Kya: Dark Lineage</game><game id="18309">Ratchet &amp; Clank</game><game id="4966">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Up Your Arsenal</game><game id="8837">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Size Matters</game><game id="4618">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Going Commando</game><game id="11470">Scaler</game><game id="10717">Maximo: Ghosts to Glory</game><game id="18926">Malice</game><game id="12209">Spyro: A Hero's Tail</game><game id="8420">Spyro: Enter the Dragonfly</game><game id="20908">The Legend of Spyro: Dawn of the Dragon</game><game id="6134">The Legend of Spyro: The Eternal Night</game><game id="3883">The Legend of Spyro: A New Beginning</game><game id="13169">Ty the Tasmanian Tiger</game><game id="159">Ty the Tasmanian Tiger 2: Bush Rescue</game><game id="19188">Ty the Tasmanian Tiger 3: Night of the Quinkan</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1875175-box_ae3.png</image></root>