<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19393</id><name>Mega Man 8: Anniversary Edition</name><description>OverviewMega Man 8 (Rockman 8: Metal Heroes in Japan) is the eighth iteration of the original Mega Man series. The title was released in 1996 in Japan and 1997 in the rest of the countries for the PlayStation and Saturn. Mega Man 8 was release to commemorate the 10th anniversary of the series.StoryThe beginning of the story.The story starts off with two forces engaging in battle in the far ends of outer space. As a result of their battle, they crash land into planet Earth.Afterwords, Mega Man and Rush are battling Bass and Treble. Mega Man, with no intentions of fighting Bass, tells him to stop what he's doing. Bass refuses and continues to attack Mega Man, but Bass and Treble crash land into a building and Bass ends up tangled up by wires. Roll appears and calls Mega Man over; Mega Man and Rush leave the premises with Bass left hanging.Mega Man receives a message from Dr. Light - telling him that strange energy readings were occurring on a island and tells him to investigate the situation. Mega Man reaches the island and finds Dr. Wily coming out of a crater with a purple energy orb. Wily then flies off into the distance. Mega Man was about to go after Dr. Wily, but something else in the crater catches Mega Man's eyes - a damaged robot. Mega Man immediately calls Dr. Light to rescue it.Dr. Wily then releases four new robot masters to counter Mega Man. Mega Man battles and defeats each of the robots and receives an purple energy orb like the one Dr. Wily had. He then finds out that Dr. Wily implanted each of the robot masters with the purple energy orb.Mega Man heads to Dr. Light's lab to check up on the robot that he found back at the crash site. Dr. Light tells Mega Man that the repairs on the robot are going well. Dr. Light also tells him about the purple energy orb - Dr. Light explains that it's a powerful energy that cannot fall into the wrong hands. Mega Man and Dr. Light leave the lab. Once they leave, the mysterious robot wakes up. He then becomes stunned at what he sees - the purple energy orb. He storms off through the lab, leaving a giant hole in the ceiling. Mega Man and Dr. Light arrive too late onto the scene. Then Mega Man hops on Rush and goes after the robot.Mega Man finds him on the other side of the Earth in a mine shaft. The mysterious robot fights Mega Man but the battle gets interrupted by Proto Man. Proto Man tells Mega Man about Dr. Wily's new castle, Wily Tower. Mega Man moves along and encounters a giant robot created by Dr. Wily; Mega Man fights the robot but gets caught in its grip. Then the mysterious robot comes to Mega Man's aid and destroys the giant robot. The Mysterious robot introduce himself as Duo and explains what his objective is.Duo also explains the purple energy orb that he had when Mega Man discovered Duo. He refers to it as "Evil Energy," and it is a dangerous energy that will engulf the entire world. It was up to Mega Man and Duo to track down the evil energy and destroy it. The remaining evil energy was located in Wily Tower but a barrier was protecting the premises; four new robot masters hold the key to take down the barrier.Mega Man destroys the four robot masters and takes down the barrier. He finally enters Wily Tower and fights off any robotic forces that got in his way. Mega Man soon encounter Bass and Treble, and engage into a fight. He defeats Bass and Treble, and then encounters Dr. Wily.The final cutscene of the game.With the help of Proto Man and Duo, Mega Man defeats Dr. Wily once again. The entire fortress starts to collapse, and Mega Man gets trapped inside. Mega Man ends up in a open field unconscious. Duo finds him and finds out that the evil energy is inside him. Duo goes into Mega Man's thoughts and destroys the last bit of evil energy. Mega Man wakes up and searches for Duo, but ends up finding Proto Man. Proto Man tells Mega Man that Duo has left the planet Earth and also left him a final message, "Thank You."GameplayThe gameplay is similar to the previous games, but with some additions. The main priority is the player picks a level and fights the end boss; Mega Man will earn a weapon for defeating the boss. Rush also returns with some special abilities. Also returning from Mega Man 7 is the item store.Like Mega Man 7, only four robot masters are available at the start. After the player beats the first four, the other four will appear. The weapons earned from the first four robot masters play a big role in the other four levels; for example, in Search Man's stage, the thunder claw that was earned from Clown Man, is used to get through spiked gaps by using the thunder claw to grab on to metal poles and swing to the other side.Rush returns in Mega Man 8, this time with new abilities. Old abilities like Rush Marine and Rush Coil have been retired, but new abilities are introduced. Each new ability can be earned by defeating the mid bosses in some of the game's levels. The first new ability is Rush can transform into a motorcycle - Mega Man can hop on, shoot projectiles, and run at high speed. The other is Rush will drop a random item for Mega Man, which can be a health item or ammunition for Mega Man's weapon. Rush can also fly up in the air and drop health or ammunition items for Mega Man. The last new ability is Rush can fly up in the air and aid Mega Man in battle by dropping missiles on enemies.The item store.Also returning from Mega Man 7 is the item store. Items that were available in Mega Man 7 were purchased by collecting bolts that were dropped by enemies. In Mega Man 8, bolts are hidden throughout the level, the player must carefully spent the bolts to purchase upgrades for Mega Man. Certain upgrades can improve Mega Man's Mega Buster, or affect other abilities such as sliding or climbing up a ladder. The upgrades include the following:Power Shield - Won't be pushed back when received a hit.Spare Extra - Four lives will be giving to Mega Man instead of three at the start of a level.Shooting Part - Five Mega Busters can be shot all together when charged.Energy Balancer- The weapon with the least amount of energy will be refiled when an energy icon is received.Exit - When a boss is defeated, Mega Man can exit a stage at any time.Laser Shot - A piercing laser will be shot when the Mega Man Buster is charged.Arrow Shot - A arrow will be shot out when the Mega Buster is charged.Auto Shoot -When the Mega Buster is charged, the Mega Buster will be fired automatically.Step Booster - Mega Man can climb a ladder faster than before.Energy Saver - Will save the amount of energy required for a special weapon.Super Recover - Increase the health or weapon energy Mega Man recovers.Spare Charger - Weapons will be refilled when exited from a stage.Hyper Slider - The power slide will increase in distance.High Speed Charge - Shortens the time for the charge shot.Rapid Part - Three Mega Man Busters will be fire each time the fire button is press.Boost Part - The Mega Buster's charge time will be decrease.Exchanger - When life energy is obtained while the life gauge is full, it will be transfer to the special weapons that's low on energy.StagesTengu Man's StageTengu Man's stage takes place high up in the air. Some section of the stage has the wind's current blowing directly towards the right, which affects Mega Man's movements by pushing him back. The stage also features a section Mega Man encased in a bubble floating upwards while dodging spiked balls suspended in mid-air. A Rush Jet section is feature in the stage; Mega Man and Rush go through hoards of enemies like a 2-D shooter. Auto, Eddie, and Beat can aid Mega Man and Rush through the Rush Jet sections of the game.Frost Man's StageMost of this stage has Mega Man going through the stage on a rocket board. While going through it, waring sighs will appear - telling Mega Man to jump or slide. Enemies such as Big Telly will appear to drop bombs on Mega Man, the other enemy is Rabbiton - a skiing robotic rabbit, and the last is Penpen EV - a robotic pigeon that gets on its belly and does a jet boost.Clown Man's StageAn amusement park that has been taken over. Clown Man's stage contains platforms with asymbol on them. In the background a robot will appear and ring a bell, which will activate the symbols on each platform. If Mega Man where to be standing on one of them, the effect of one of the symbols will go off. The symbols include "X," which means a piece of debre will fall on Mega Man, or a boxing glove will pop out of the platform, a skull symbol will drop Mega Man below the platform, a arrow symbol will bring Mega Man back to the beginning of the section of the stage, a question mark symbol will transport Mega Man to a random location, and a circle symbol means the safe zone - nothing will occur.Grenade Man's StageReturning from Mega Man 7 is Count Bomb CD - a platform that will self-destruct in three seconds. The enemy originally appear in Brust Man's Stage. Another version of Count Bomb is introduce, Count Bomb GEO - a walking time bomb. Sections of the stage contains explosive platforms, one of them is built with a fuse and the entire platform will go off if the fuse is lit. Fire Met will appear and lit the fuse; casing the entire platform to explode. Mega Man will fall to his death unless he makes it out in time.Sword Man's StageAt the start of this stage, Mega Man has to open up four walls by performing various tasks in four different sections of the stage. The second half has Mega Man on a paddle boat going through molten hot lava. But Mega Man must be careful as the lava will shoot up. Mega Man can use it as a boost up to the next section. Mega Man will also go through platform sections that has a giant robotic hammer known as Kao go Meh da. What he'll do is follow Mega Man to the platform he's on, and slams the platform into the lava with Mega Man on it.Aqua Man's StageAn underwater adventure that is filled with Surumaker that will dash towards the direction that Mega Man is in, and the Shellens will use the same attacks method as the Mets. Underwater levels in previous Mega Man games acted in the same way as it would be on land, the only differences is it will affect Mega Man's jumping. In Mega Man 8, Mega Man can swim instead of doing an actual jump. Aqua Man's stage has areas of spikes on the top and bottom, Mega Man has to carefully remain in the middle by swimming in order to get through.Astro Man's StageThe main part of Astro Man's stage is Mega Man going through a maze The maze is one big circle - as Mega Man moves forwards, hell head back where he started. certain walls will block some passage, they can be moved up or down to alter the route. Mega Man's priority is to carefully think about which walls to move around in order to get to the exit.Search Man's StageIn this stage, the thunder claw and the flame sword weapons play a big role. Swarms of enemies will be running or flying around to give Mega Man a hard time. There's also an extensive amount of Thorn Vines planted throughout the stage, they can only be destroy by using the flame sword. There's also a section with multiple metal poles that Mega Man can use by swinging around with use of the thunder claw to get through obstacle.Robot MastersName and PortraitAttack/WeaknessFrost ManAttack: Ice WaveWeakness: Flash BombTengu ManAttack: Tornado HoldWeakness: Ice WaveClown ManAttack: Thunder ClawWeakness: Ice WaveGrenade ManAttack: Flash BombWeakness: Thunder ClawAqua ManAttack: Water BalloonWeakness: Astro CrashSword ManAttack: Flame SwordWeakness: Water BalloonSearch ManAttack: Homing SniperWeakness: Flame SwordAstro ManAttack: Astro CrashWeakness: Homing SniperVersion DifferencesCutMan, in the Saturn version of the game.Mega Man 8 was released on the Sega Saturn and Sony PlayStation. As with most multi-release games, different bonuses were given for both versions, but because Sony asked for the game later than Sega, the PlayStation version received nearly no bonus material of any sort.Sega SaturnPlayStationA bonus menu featuring exclusive artwork from both fans and Capcom, and a sound and music test screen.Alternate music in Tengu Man's level.Cut Man and Wood Man battles, both sporting remixed versions of their original songs and resulting in bolts being dropped by the destroyed enemies. In the PlayStation version, the bolts are just left there free to take.TriviaWhen the game was pitched to Sony at the time of its release, it was turned down because it was a 2D game. Sony at the time did not feel 2D games had a place on the PlayStation. After the game was offered to Sega to be on Saturn, Sony decided it would be unfair for its competitor to have a game from a famous series. Thus the PlayStation version, rushed and lacking the extra content in the Saturn version, but in return, Capcom had to make a game that featured what the PlayStation was made for: 3D. This resulted in the making of Mega Man Legends, exactly what Sony wanted from Capcom.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7860">Bionic Commando</game><game id="4350">Contra</game><game id="17939">Konami Collector's Series: Castlevania &amp; Contra</game><game id="16188">Clash at Demonhead</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1806075-box_mm8.png</image></root>