<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19415</id><name>Interstate '76: Nitro Pack</name><description>OverviewThe Interstate '76: Nitro Pack is a mission pack for Interstate '76 that does not require the original game in order to play. With an extended oil crisis as setup and the mid-1970s American Southwest as a backdrop, the story is a prelude of sorts to Groove Champion's quest for revenge in Interstate '76, and it follows a series of loosely related missions taking place in the years before he becomes a crime fighter, telling the stories of Jade Champion and her vigilante compatriots. The contents of these missions are very similar to that of its predecessor, mainly consisting of vehicular combat between a wide variety of highly customizable automobiles. Several new cars, weapons, and paint jobs have been added to allow further options when preparing for missions. GameplayThough the T.R.I.P. mode does not return in the Nitro Pack, it is replaced by a significantly expanded Scenario mode, with this mode comprising the majority of the expansion's new content. Similar to Scenario mode in Interstate '76, missions can be undertaken in any order, and any vehicle and weapon load-out may be chosen beforehand. The initially available missions are split into three sets, each in the perspective of one of the game's protagonists, Taurus, Jade, or Skeeter. Once these are completed, a fourth set from the perspective of the villainous Natty Dread is unlocked.  Though Interstate '76 placed a heavy emphasis on narrative, with numerous pre-rendered cutscenes before, after, and sometimes during missions, this tradition is not carried over in the expansion, with most expository information conveyed in-engine as missions begin. Furthermore, the Scenario campaign of the Nitro Pack does not contain a single cohesive narrative, opting instead for more self-contained "episodic" missions that often have very little connection to missions preceding or following them.  Melee mode also returns in Interstate '76: Nitro Pack, consisting of Multi Melee (multiplayer) and Instant Melee (skirmish) modes.VehiclesThe Nitro Pack adds fourteen new vehicles to the mix, bringing the total number of automobiles to thirty-seven. Some of these are altered versions of cars from Interstate '76, though for the most part they are entirely new. As with the original game, they are fictionalized versions of real-world cars, with their names often alluding to the cars that inspired them. See Interstate '76 for information regarding vehicles also featured in Interstate '76.VehicleReal-World InspirationForward MountsRear MountsABX Grappler Ford M151 MUTT / Willys MB US Army Jeep1 Top1 RearCourcheval Hacienda Chevrolet El Camino / GMC Caballero1 Front2 Top1 RearDover Rampage Dodge Charger1 Front1 Top2 DropJefferson Limo Lincoln Continental Limousine3 Front1 TopNoneLeopard XLC Jaguar XK-E2 Front1 DropMoth Cargo Truck International Harvester Cargostar2 Front1 Top1 RearMoth Loadmaster International Harvester Cargostar2 Top1 Rear1 DropMoth Tanker Truck Dodge Big Horn2 Front1 Top2 RearRansom Marshal Pontiac GTO1 Front1 Top2 RearSkeeter's Van Dodge Ram Van2 Front1 Rear1 DropClown Car Volkswagen Beetle2 Front1 RearWarendorf FV Volkswagen Beetle1 Front1 TopNoneAmbulance Cadillac Superior Crown Royale Ambulance1 Front2 Top2 DropHearse Cadillac Superior Crown Royale Hearse1 Front2 Top2 RearWeaponryOnly a handful of new weapons are introduced in the Nitro Pack, but each one represents new combat options not offered by any of the established armaments. The Chemical Mortar, for instance, kills drivers rather than damaging their car, while equipping Caltops allows players to puncture the tires of any vehicle pursuing them. See Interstate '76 for information regarding weapons also featured in Interstate '76.WeaponClassTurret CapabilityWeight in lbs.Ammo Capacity4Get-U-Not MissileSPP PodNo2128Ball O'FlameFlamethrowerYes8018Chemical MortarMortarNo1253CaltropsDropperN/A21230</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/11/118253/1719267-nitropackboxart.png</image></root>