<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19477</id><name>Heritage of Kings: The Settlers</name><description>OverviewThe Settlers: Heritage of Kings is a real time strategy game that was released in 2005 for the PC and published by Ubisoft. It was developed by Blue Byte Software and is the fifth game in The Settlers Series. The game breaks from the pattern of previous Settlers games by simplifying and modernising some of the core gameplay features of the series.PlotThe game starts in Thalgrund and follows the story of a young boy named Dario. He is suddenly attacked by minions of the evil Mordred. After fending off the attack, he learns from his dying mother that he is the true heir and ruler of the land. He sets out to locate his last living relative, Helias, accompanied by Eric, his childhood friend. On their Journey they encounter numerous enemies including ferocious barbarians of Folklung and Norfolk, dark hordes, and the rival nations of Barmecia and Cleycourt. Finally, Dario marches on Evelance where Mordred resides and an epic battle ensues. With the battle won, Dario assumes his rightful place on the throne, and liberates the kingdom from the evil Mordred.GameplayThe objective of the game is to create a thriving settlement, while amassing an army to defeat rival nations.ResourcesThere are six resources in the game. Your goal is to collect as many resources as possible, while limiting your enemy's ability to do so.Thalers: Gained by having workers occupying buildings in your city. Soldiers are paid wages from your pool of Thalers.Clay: Clay can be found in Orange Shafts or little clumps. It's important for building, though it's value tends to decrease towards the endgame.Wood: Wood can be collected once you have researched Construction from the College. Wood remains important throughout each level.Stone: Stone can be collected from Quarries or clumps, and is used in the construction of buildings. It's demand will increase as the game progresses.Iron: Iron is used for upgrades and creating military units. This is the most important resource in any combat heavy mission.Sulphur: Sulphur is the least valuable of your resources. It has some use through upgrades, but is mainly used for Weather research and building artillery.ExpansionsHeritage of Kings had two expansion packs released. Heritage of Kings - Expansion Disc, and Heritage of Kings - Legends Expansion Disc. These expanded the core gameplay by adding bridge building, additional single and multi-player maps, and four new campaigns following on from the story of the main game. The expansions also introduced three new playable characters; Drake, Yuki and Kala.System requirementsMinimumSupported OS: A 100% Windows 2000/XP/Vista-compatible computer systemProcessor: Pentium III or AMD Athlon 1 GHzMemory: 256 MBGraphics: 32 MB DirectX 9.0c-compliant graphics cardDirectX Version: DirectX 9.0cSound: DirectX 9.0c-compliant cardHard Drive: 1.5 GB free hard disk spaceMultiplayer: Broadband Internet connection with 64 kbps Kbps upstream or fasterRecommendedSupported OS: A 100% Windows 2000/XP/Vista-compatible computer systemProcessor: 2.4 GHz Pentium 4 or AMD AthlonMemory: 512 MBGraphics: 64 MB DirectX 9.0c-compliant graphics cardDirectX Version: DirectX 9.0cSound: DirectX 9.0c-compliant cardHard Drive: 1.5 GB free hard disk spaceMultiplayer: Broadband Internet connection with 128 kbps Kbps upstream or faster</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8460">Diggles: the Myth of Fenris</game><game id="18721">Cultures</game><game id="2859">Cultures: Die Saga</game><game id="19132">Cultures 2: The Gates of Asgard</game><game id="3769">Zeus: Master of Olympus</game><game id="5211">Zeus Official Expansion: Poseidon</game><game id="3144">Cleopatra: Queen of the Nile</game><game id="17680">Pharaoh</game><game id="10942">The Nations</game><game id="625">Alien Nations</game><game id="5457">Cultures: Die Abenteuerbox</game><game id="31533">The Legend of Mystery - High Cultures</game><game id="14638">Northland</game><game id="1489">8th Wonder of the World</game><game id="3009">Immortal Cities: Children of the Nile</game><game id="738">Black &amp; White 2: Battle of the Gods</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/30196/1824244-kings.jpg</image></root>