<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19533</id><name>Thomas the Tank Engine &amp; Friends</name><description>Control Thomas the Tank Engine as he's got to take special trips he has to organise: Take children to the seaside, medicine to the hospital or deliver the mail. Beware of dead ends, level crossings, other trains and vehicles through your route! Based on the famous television and railway series, this game is designed for ages 3 and up.    Sega Genesis version  The Sega Genesis release of Thomas the Tank Engine and Friends is  different from the rest. This game puts the player in the role of the  engineer, and the player may choose an engine. After the player selects  one, a Mario Paint based game shows up, and the player can colour  the engine and the engineer, but the only one that will have a direct  effect on graphics in the game is the engineer. There is no difference  with the engines; all have the same statistics.     There are three modes to use: Race, Game, and Explore. Race puts the  player in a competition against another engine. The player must collect  sweets and balloons, but avoid mud, red balloons, and engines. After the  player wins enough games, Sir Topham Hatt gives the player a medal.      The mode "Game" features Sir Topham Hatt giving instructions to the  player. He asks for cars to be brought to a certain station in a certain  order, but they must get there quickly. If the job takes too long, Sir  Topham Hatt will scold the player. If the assigned job is done speedily,  Sir Topham Hatt will praise the player. Eventually, the player will  earn a medal.      The mode "Explore" simply is letting the player look around the entire  map of Sodor. The mode is just like the other two, only there are no  jobs.   Unlike all the other releases, this game does not have The Railway Series stories.   Unreleased NES gameIn 2008, many unreleased NES prototypes were found, and one of them was a NES version of the SNES game Thomas the Tank Engine and Friends. The game is identical to the SNES game, but with no voice and lower quality graphics. </description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="8">Educational</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16841">Jump Start: Dino Adventure</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/35482/1412453-605654boxart_1w.jpg</image></root>