<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19581</id><name>EverQuest: Dragons of Norrath</name><description>Overview  Northeast AntonicaAfter ending the threat of Mata Muram on his own turf, the land of Kuua (Omens of War), the Wayfarers Brotherhood and those who helped them returned to Norrath it in disarray.  Unbeknownst to the world's people, a dark influence had permeated Norrath, and a new era was beginning.  This historical period would become known as The Age of War.  By the time the Wayfarers returned from Kuua, tensions had already escalated to the point that two legendary figures had returned to the spotlight to lead their respective armies of good and evil.  Firiona Vie, the powerful High Elf royal, leads Norrath's Keepers while Lanys T`Vyl, the daughter of Innoruuk, commands Dark Reign.  Both had already set up recruitment camps in the Lavastorm Mountains.  A Gnomish mining company has recently discovered a passage through the mountains into a previously unexplored region of northeast Antonica.  The lands here are a nest for the dragons of Norrath, where, for centuries, they have been born and raised uninterrupted.  Both factions of good and evil believe this discovery to be invaluable.  With race, class, religion, and faction standing in mind, It is up to each individual adventurer of Norrath to decide which side to take before journeying into the northern reaches.  The ninth expansion to EverQuest brought about several changes and additions to the game.  Much like the Lost Dungeons of Norrath expansion, much of the content here is mission-based instanced zones.  Missions are delved out by certain NPC's in each faction's camp.  Unlike LDoN though, players could enter non-instanced versions of the same zones for regular adventuring, grinding, or soloing.  The expansion also brought about a revamp to the Lavastorm Mountains zone.  Highlights of Dragons of Norrath include: New Guild Hall: A new instanced zone for your guild to prepare.  It comes equipped with a bank, supply vendors, and portals to popular druid and wizard teleport locations through the world.  Buff timers are stopped while in this zone as well.New Guild Lobby: A new zone in the Plane of Knowledge where guilds can recruit and meet with other guilds.  Disciples here can also summon corpses from anywhere in the world for a fee.New Good/Evil Perks: Completing tasks for either Norrath's Keepers or Dark Reign will earn crystals that can be redeemed for unique items or abilities.New Bandolier: A new hotkey makes it easier to switch out weapon sets when the need arises.New Potion Belt: A new hotkey allows for quicker access to potions and other magical items in your inventory.New Mail System: Players can now send persistent messages to anyone even if they are not online.New AA's: Dozens of new Alternate Advancement abilities unique to Dragons of Norrath.New Cultural Armor: Elaborate quests for each race requiring efficiency in multiple trade skills.   GeographyTirranun the ProtectorAfter passing through the caves at the northern end of the Lavastorm Mountains, adventurers will find themselves in The Broodlands.  The first to make the passage were met by a mighty dragon by the name of Tirranun the Ancient Protector.  The dragons have remained hidden for centuries and they intend to keep it that way.  Tirranun escaped defeat at the hands of the Norrathian forces and fled to the dungeons in the mountains to warn the others.   Each of the dungeons found here have several variations depending upon which mission was taken from the Norrath's Keepers, Dark Reign, or Wayfarers Brotherhood camps. The BroodlandsFrom the Broodlands, adventurers can enter and explore several different dungeons.  Hidden in these dungeons are five powerful dragons including Tirranun.   The Accursed Nest  Vishimtar the FallenThe Nest was once a paradise in which young dragons were raised, but it has since fallen into darkness due to a wretched curse.  The Curse of Shadowspire has affected not only the land but the inhabitants themselves, including the mighty dragon, Vishimtar the Fallen.  It is believed that the curse is the work of Venril Sathir, the lich king of Karnor's Castle in The Dreadlands of Kunark.  He plans to get his revenge on the dragons at the root of the issue.Circle of DrakesClues The Curse of Ju`rekDragon's EggIn the ShadowsLair of the BlackwingLost ComradesThe Rampaging MonolithRival PartySpider's EyeWeb of Lies  The Ascent  Kessdona the EnlightenedThis snowcapped mountainous region rests beyond the Stillmoon Temple and not far from Everfrost Peaks, although no passage between the two have been found.  Those brave enough to reach its summit will be met unkindly by Rikkukin the Defender and Kessdona the Enlightened.  These serpent-like dragons are quite powerful.Death Comes SwiftlyDrake EggsKessdona's PerchReflections of SilverSignal FiresStorm Dragon ScalesSudden Tremors  Lavaspinner's Lair    Lavaspinner's LairAs the name would imply, this dungeon is full of flowing lava and volcanic ash.  Despite the abrasive environment, this region is likely the least difficult for adventurers to progress through.  The creatures found here are relatively weak compared to the ones in the other dungeons. Calling EmoushThe Drake's MenaceForbin's ElixirA Halfling's GreedInfestedLavaspinner HuntingLavaspinner's LocalsVolkara's Bite  Stillmoon Temple    Stillmoon TempleThis once tranquil temple has since been overrun by a horde of deceptively powerful goblins.  The temple, including its zen garden and wading pool, are still guarded fiercely by ancient stone golems. Animated Statue PlansBest Laid PlansDiseased PumasGuardian of the SandsScales of JusticeSickness of the SpiritTrial of Perseverance  Thundercrest Isles    Thundercrest IslesThe floating islands of Thundercrest are quite reminiscent of the Plane of Sky, which makes sense considering the matriarch of the storm dragons resides here.  Yar`Lir can found in her chambers on the center isle.  Finding one's way to this middle island can be nearly as maddening as the Plane of Sky itself. Behind Closed DoorsThe CreatorAn End to the StormsThe Gilded ScrollHistory of the IsleHoly HourHouse of the Autumn RoseLair UnguardedScions of ThundercrestThroes of Contagion  Tirranun's Delve    Tirranun's DelveThe dragon that originally was tasked in preventing anyone else from entering the lands of the storm dragons now resides here, beneath the Lavaspinner's Lair.  The extreme temperatures and harsh terrain will keep even some of the most hardened adventurers away, but those that can maneuver through the cavern's traps, goblins, and spiders may attempt to finish off Tirranun. Children of GimblaxHave Note Will TravelStorming the Goblin Temple</description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/17724/874819-eqnorrath.png</image></root>