<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1959</id><name>Atelier Iris 2: The Azoth of Destiny</name><description>Story *SPOILER ALERT*  The game starts off with Viese leaving her apprentice title behind and becoming a full-fledged alchemist. She rushes home to tell Felt the good   news, but she can't seem to find him. She starts looking around for him, and later finds him at the Belkhyde Gate, a locked passageway to another world. They later wander into a forest to find Dour, a Mana spirit, with whom Viese can make a pact with. An essential task in becoming an alchemist. Along the way, they come across an ancient and mysterious sword called the Azure Azoth; a sword Felt is pretty familiar with, as he   daily tries to pull it from its resting place, to no avail. No one has ever managed to pull it out, but Felt is determined to do it sometime. After Viese makes the pact with the spirit, an earthquake strikes Eden. All over the island, holy grounds of the Mana spirits vanish. They decide to head to the Mana Temple and report   the damage and what they've seen. However, before they set off, Felt is interrupted by a strange   voice calling him from the Azure Azoth. He then tries to pull the sword out   once more and finally succeeds. The voice speaks again, telling him that   he must go to Belkhyde because Eden is in great turmoil and risk.About a  week  later, after the investigation surrounding the earthquake has been  completed,  Felt sets out for the Belkhyde gate again, which now has been unsealed  by the  Azure Azoth. After a good-bye moment with Viese, he sets out through  the  gate and into the world of Belkhyde. After fighting and stumbling his way through  the  Tatalian desert, barely alive, he collapses and is found by Noin. She claims to  be  part of the Simsilt, which later is revealed to be a resistance army  fighting  to liberate the land of Belkhyde from the oppression of the Empire.  Felt and  Noin becomes friends, and later goes to rescue Max, the leader of the Simsilt,  from the  Riesevelt lighthouse in the capital city. After the rescue they're chased out by the Empire and runs into a female assassin with a pair of  crimson scythes. A battle breaks out, but the party leaves victorious. They later move on to Simsilt's base, Agito Cove. At  around this point  Felt and Viese find out about the Share Ring, a ring  that allows the  users to send items to one another. After recruiting  Hagel, the  blacksmith, and being rescued yet again in the Tatalian  desert, this  time by a dragon man named Gray, Felt  travels back to Agito. He sets out on a journey by boat to the eastern continent  during which  Felt takes in a, for him, totally new sight: the Sea. During the journey to Altena Church, Felt finds the assassin girl that   tried to kill him earlier, poisoned in the middle of a forest. He brings   her back to Max's Camp, and Viese (still left back in Eden) manages to make a cure for the poison and sends it to Feld via the Share Ring. It is revealed that the girls name is Fee. Felt, Fee and Gray then head for   Altena Church, but are stopped by Chaos, who easily defeats everyone but Gray, who chases him off. When they finally reach Altena Church,   the purpose of the Azoths, Eden and the Gardo Continental Drive are   revealed. Viese, back in Eden, finds a map of workshops scattered all over   Belkhyde. After   repairing the workshops one by one, portions of Eden's   holy grounds reappear, allowing Viese to make pacts with new Mana spirits. They lend their hands when Viese is   performing certain tasks.   This ends with a final battle against Theodore, the consul of Riesevelt,   and his Empire subordinates in Riese Palace.   After some celebrations, Felt goes out searching for Chaos, who was not   present in the earlier battle. He finds one of the Altena nuns on the bridge   leading to the western continent. She tells him Chaos has gone to   Altena Church. When Felt arrives at the church, he finds Mother Eizlen frozen by the Crimson Azoth's spell Exzanosis, which earlier also was used on Max.   Felt fights Chaos in the lower levels of the church, where the   Gardo Continental Drive is stored, but is also frozen with the Exzanosis   spell, and the Azure Azoth breaks. Viese, anxious about not hearing anything from Felt in three weeks (via the diaries they shared amongst each other through the Share Ring) travels to   Belkhyde through the Belkhyde Gate, and goes through partly the same journey as he did, but since she almost know where to go, she traverse the world a lot faster.   She finds Fee trying to escape from the maids in the palace, as they pestered her with new clothes all the time, making her somewhat of a dress-up doll. They gang up with Gray and the party set   off to Agito, since the western bridge was damaged. After meeting Noin, they   de-freeze Max with the Mell Orb. He is pleased with their   progress of liberating Belkhyde and defeating Theodore. They set off to Altena Church and finds Eizlen, whom they de-freeze, and goes down into the lower levels of the church to   find Felt, also frozen. However, the Mell Orb won't work on Felt. They decide to hunt down a special ore from the nearby caves. There they meet Poe, banging his head against a wall while regretting his accidental marriage to Mitsue, a catgirl they met earlier on.   After using the new-found ore to unfreeze Felt, Eden suddenly appears   in the middle of Lake Midgard, a lake created by the rage of the  Crimson  Azoth in earlier times. The party does everything in their power to fix the Azure Azoth back to full power so that they can fight Palaxius (unleashed from inside the Crimson Azoth) who possessed Chaos. They traverse the world, repairing the sword. After the Azure Azoth is fully restored, Felt is able to break the cursed   mist that Palaxius spread all over Eden. After chasing him to the   Temple of Creation, Felt and his friends find out about Iris, the   reincarnation of Lilith. Felt and friends engage   Palaxius in a fierce battle, and manages to defeat him. Iris is freed and peace strikes the world. All the characters goes back from whence they came, or find new purposes in life that they aim for. Poe is seen trying to impress Mitsue but still failing, Gray   oversees the next generation of Simsilt, Galahad fells a tree, while   Noin works on her cooking skills (which are still terrible), and Fee,   surrounded by paperwork, looks disdainfully at Max. Felt, Iris and Viese   return to Noir, Eden's main city, and back to their workshop.They all end up saying: "I'm home".  GameplayThe gameplay is typical for a j-rpg, and almost the same as in Atelier Iris: Eternal Mana with turn-based battles, random encounters, towns and dungeons. The random encounters is limited for each map, and a gauge in the corner of the screen drains for each fight. When the gauge is empty, no more encounters is met with on that map. The battles are fought with a Final Fantasy X-esque Conditional Turn-based system in which the game pauses when you select prompts for your  characters, so you can act without time pressure, but fast characters  and enemies can still act several times before others can act even once. A display in the top of the screen shows the order of  turns for every character and enemy so that you can use strategic  thinking when selecting actions. After battle the characters gain EXP, skill points (if they have an Alchemy Item equipped), gold and possibly items. There are two basic forms of physical attacks: Charge and Break attacks. A  Charge attack will increase the level/points of the party's skill gauge. This  allows the party members to access their individual skills which all has different costs in points. Many  skills are more powerful attacks, a few are healing techniques, some  are status attacks, and others affect various other battle elements. A  Break attack, on the other hand, does not affect the skill gauge but  will knock an enemy backward along the turn bar - possibly far enough to  enter a special thick section of the bar. Once there, the enemy will be  stunned. Stunned enemies move more slowly along the turn bar and receive  additional damage from attacks. Additional Break attacks will knock the  enemy back progressively shorter distance, meaning the player will have to  strategically switch between Charge and Break attacks to both stun  enemies and unleash skills on them in the same battle. Each attack on  any opponent while an enemy is stunned will increase the combo counter  by one and add to the total combo damage. At the end of battle, the  combo counter and total combo damage amount will result in additional  EXP, up to double the usual amount per foe. Therefore, it is to the player's  advantage to use the combo system as much as possible.Each character is automatically equipped with a weapon but can further  equip two accessories and two alchemy items. Weapons provide mostly  offensive power, accessories boost various stats, and alchemy items  provide skills. While an alchemy item is equipped, its particular skill  will be in effect. However, by gaining enough skill points after battles  it is possible to learn the alchemy item's skill  permanently. In this way, each character has the potential to learn a  wide range of skills varying from stat-increasing skills to others that  can dodge or block attacks. Instead of having the normal free-roaming world map from Atelier Iris: Eternal Mana, Atelier Iris 2 has a world map with specific places of interest that the player can move between. The player chooses a spot, but the characters move automatically between them. You walk around freely in dungeons and towns though, and the field-only actions from the previous game (like using Mana as a footstool and flying) has been stripped down and now only include jumping and absorbing elements.Outside of battle you control two separate characters, Felt and Viese, which can be selected and switched between whenever at save points. Both characters can eventually come together, thus  eliminating the need to switch between them. Felt focuses on exploration and battle, in the beginning, and Viese focuses more on synthesis and support. She is the only one who can use alchemy, and as it's one of the main sources for getting items in the game, the player should explore the world for recipes and ingredients. Felt has the ability to synthesis weapons which increases the power of weapons and can also add special properties to them. This requires the right items and the right Mana spirit. Most of the time, Felt collects recipes for synthesis, and Viese tries to create them via alchemy synthesis, home in Eden, using the necessary ingredients and elements. Elements which can be found around the world, and are absorbed from existing items in the world, like for example barrels (wood elements) and stones (stone and fire elements). The items you can create include equipment items, usable items and story-related items. There are three types of alchemy synthesis; Mana Items, Accessories, and Alchemy Items. Mana Items are items that can be recreated by Felt using Mana power once Viese has made them initially. Accessories are equipment, increasing stats and giving the characters special abilities. Alchemy Items are miscellaneous items that cover a wide range of uses. Alchemy requires not only the right amount of ingredients, but also the right Mana Spirit.   Mana Spirits As in Atelier Iris, the main driving forces behind the alchemy of the  game are the Mana Spirits. The transformation element from the previous  game has been eliminated; instead, Atelier Iris 2 offers a larger  number of Mana Spirits. Below is a list of each Mana and his or her  respective element: Dour: The Mana Spirit of Wood. Dour is the first  Mana with whom Viese makes a pact during the opening chapter of the  game.Zuvelk: The Mana Spirit of Metal. It is only  after Viese makes a pact with him that she and Felt can use the Share  Ring, an essential item in the game.Uru: The Mana Spirit of Fire. Humorously admires  Viese's "command" over Poe.Aroma: The Mana of Aroma. She joins after Viese finds and  grows a particularly rare species of flower, the Hal Flower, for Meila.  Her reason for making a pact with Viese is rather peculiar: she seems to  like Viese's scent.Plua: The Mana Spirit of Darkness. Plua does not  have the confidence to make a pact initially, but she will change her  mind once Viese returns after speaking to her fellow dark Mana and  friend, Lutanus.Diemia: The Mana Spirit of Stone. Diemia wants a  Glow Lamp in order to be able to read in the darkness of his cavern  before he will make a pact. A running gag from the previous game is that  Diemia is often used as a living stepladder for party members.Nymph: The Mana Spirit of Water. She makes a pact  with Viese after the new alchemist saves her life in Marmel Forest.Silwest: The Mana Spirit of Air. She makes a  pact automatically and actually *gives* an item instead of asking for  one. The item she gives is Hexi Glass, which helps out in making the  Viese Charm alchemy item. This item gives a character-specific skill to  Felt.Jiptus: The Mana Spirit of Poison, she tells Viese  to read the lithograph in her sanctuary before she will make a pact.  Thus, a Rainbow Cloth is required to make a pact with her.Faustus: The Mana Spirit of Illusion. He always  ends his sentences with "poyo." Faustus makes a pact in exchange for  being freed from a treasure chest abandoned in the library - a  misadventure stemming from an ill-fated game of hide and seek.Siren: The Mana Spirit of Sound. A close friend of  Klavia, she joins automatically after Klavia gains her singing  confidence.Aion: The Mana Spirit of Life. She is one of the  oldest of the Mana Spirits, second only to the Mana Spirit of Creation,  Lilith. Aion also proves to be very difficult to work with, as her  knowledge of her abilities has given her a very high opinion of herself.  She tells Viese to make pacts with Eital (light Mana) and Plua (dark  Mana) before she will herself make a pact herself.Eital: The Mana Spirit of Light. Eital requests a  Comet Gem in exchange for making a pact with Viese.Lilith: The Mana Spirit of Creation, from whom  all other Mana are descended. To become an alchemist, a person must  "pledge to uphold the sacred tenets of Lilith." No one has seen her in  centuries. MusicThe soundtrack for Atelier Iris 2: The Azoth of Destiny was composed by Ken Nakagawa  Daisuke Achiwa and was released May 18, 2005 in Japan  by Team Entertainment.It was recorded at Space Veilo. Tracklist (Translated):  Disc One: Disc Blue01 - Eternal Story (Full Version) 02 - Bonds 03 - Engraved History 04 - At the Murmuring Brook 05 - Go Novice Alchemist 06 - Continent That Rides the Wind 07 - Gentle Breeze and the Earth 08 - Tumbling Tree Spirit 09 - That Kid's Shop Is Successful? 10 - The Journey Continues 11 - Blazing Earth 12 - Shining Sword 13 - Victory Is in Our Hands 14 - Under a Small Roof 15 - Oasis Town 16 - Hidden Treasure 17 - Revealing the Secret Arts 18 - Crest 19 - Shadow of the Imperial Capital 20 - Big Bridge 21 - DANGER! 22 - Terrestrial 23 - The Wise and Happy Footmen 24 - Exciting Cave Exploration 25 - Hometown of the Spirit for EM2 26 - Emotions Sent Yonder 27 - Resounding Heartbeat 28 - Mountain Road 29 - It's the Sea! 30 - Exploration at the Beach 31 - Flag of Freedom 32 - Boys On The Plains 33 - Charge 34 - Ambitions in the Heart 35 - Sleeping Girl 36 - Carmine 37 - Demise 38 - Change!  Total Time: 65 minutes and 01 second.  Disc Two: Disc Red 01 - Spring Breeze 02 - Carefree Shopping 03 - WATER ROAD 04 - Mandible of the Abyss 05 - Emperor Fangs 06 - Circle of Friends 07 - Dumb Request at an Embarrassing Time 08 - Deep Green Earth 09 - Mysterious Friend 10 - Foliage 11 - Footsteps of Darkness 12 - Lost Poem 13 - Truth 14 - Let's Do Our Best Again Tomorrow 15 - Nice Weather Today 16 - Dancing Kodama 17 - To the Underground Tunnel 18 - Grit 19 - Marduk 20 - Time of Overflowing Sadness 21 - Memories In Sepia 22 - Revolutionary Time 23 - Holy Power 24 - Crimson Omen 25 - Seething Fighting Spirit 26 - The Mystery Deepens 27 - Folklore 28 - Epitaph 29 - The Legacy 30 - Flying Bird 31 - Sky Corridor 32 - Danger Zone 33 - Slasher Blue 34 - Decision Time 35 - Decisive Battle in the Blue Sky 36 - Red Lucifer Rising 37 - Promised Place 38 - The Door to the Journey   Total Time: 70 minutes and 13 seconds.  Opening Song: ETERNAL STORY by Haruka Shimotsuki  Ending Song: 旅立ちの扉 (Tachidachi no Tobira / Door of Departure) by Mami Horie </description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17621">Ar tonelico: Melody of Elemia</game><game id="1861">Dark Cloud</game><game id="10129">Grandia II</game><game id="259">Grandia III</game><game id="21237">Tales of Symphonia</game><game id="14210">Tales of the Abyss</game><game id="5315">Tales of Legendia</game><game id="11703">Tales of Rebirth</game><game id="595">Tales of Eternia</game><game id="21541">Ar tonelico II: Melody of Metafalica</game><game id="8918">SEGA AGES 2500 Vol.1: Phantasy Star - Generation:1</game><game id="2924">SEGA AGES 2500 Vol.17: Phantasy Star - Generation:2</game><game id="25349">SEGA AGES 2500 Vol.32: Phantasy Star Complete Collection</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2154860-box_ai2taod.png</image></root>