<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19654</id><name>Frontlines: Fuel of War</name><description>SettingFrontlines: Fuel of War is set in 2024 where two major alliances, the Western Coalition consisting of the U.S.A. and the E.U., and the Red Star Alliance, which consists of the Russian Federation and the People's Republic of China. The two factions battle it out over oil, in an oil rich nation of the Red Star Alliance. The world is running out of fuel, and wars ensue to ensure the military might of one of these factions. Throughout a commentary is given about the troubles on the homefront, and the riots going on in the Western Coalition.GameplayThe Gameplay revolves around taking strategic objectives to move the frontline forward, as soon as you move the frontline forward the enemy loses spawn points, weapons, and equipment and you have to take more strategic objectives until you capture the battlefield. The game takes alot of notes from games like  Battlefield 2, having similar grand scale, having acces to tanks, jets, helicopters etc. and having similar gameplay to Battlefield 2. The game also revolves around unit classes, which consist of:Anti VehicleAssaultHeavy AssaultSniperSpecial OperationsClose Combat Additionaly, you can choose a role after choosing a unit class, these consist ofGround Support - This role consists of reparing vehicles and building turrets.EMP - EMP specializes in immobilizing vehicles and electronic devices, they are also invisible to radar and can carry an EMP launcher at higher levels.Drone Tech - Drone Tech is all about using robots to the players advantage. This role starts off with the ability to employ UAV, highlighting enemies in the area, as you rank up you can employ destructable robots, to a drone with a built in mini gun.Air Support - As the name implies this role specializes in air support. They use bombs, cluster bombs, and gunships to help turn the tide of battle.  System Requirements MinimumSupported OS: Windows XP (32/64) or Windows Vista (32/64)Processor: Intel Pentium 2.8HT or AMD Athlon 2800 Memory: 768MB/1GB for VistaGraphics: nVidia 6800GT (SM3) or ATI X800XT (SM2) w/ Latest applicable video driversDirectX Version: DirectX 9.0Sound: AC '97 or equivalent DirectX 9.0c compatible sound cardHard Drive: 12 GBInternet: Broadband connection (min upload 768K for hosting games) RecommendedSupported OS: Windows XP (32/64) or Windows Vista (32/64)Processor: Intel Core2 E6400 (2.13GHz) or AMD X2 5000 Memory: 1.5GBGraphics: nVidia 8600GTX or ATI X2600 w/ Latest applicable video driversDirectX Version: DirectX 9.0Sound: Creative Labs X-Fi sound cardHard Drive: 12 GBInternet: Broadband connection (min upload 768K for hosting games)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17828">Battlefield 2142</game><game id="20655">Battlefield: Bad Company</game><game id="16866">Battlefield 2</game><game id="12716">Battlefield 1942</game><game id="21220">Battlefield Heroes</game><game id="18883">Enemy Territory: Quake Wars</game><game id="7076">Battlefield 2142: Booster Pack - Northern Strike</game><game id="21646">Battlefield 2: Modern Combat</game><game id="21105">Stormrise</game><game id="25246">Battlefield: Bad Company 2</game><game id="25413">Lost Planet 2</game><game id="26633">Homefront</game><game id="9993">Halo 3</game><game id="2078">Mobile Forces</game><game id="38072">Ravaged</game><game id="38039">Call of Duty: Black Ops II</game><game id="27006">Battlefield 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1817640-box_flfow.png</image></root>