<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1975</id><name>Syberia II</name><description>OverviewSyberia II is a        Point and Click adventure game released in 2004 for the PC, Playstation 2 and Xbox, by        MC2-Microïds. The game was authored and directed by        Benoît Sokal, the creator of the franchise. Syberia II is an continuation of the original        Syberia (released in 2002) and has identical gameplay and art direction. Improvements were made on the graphics engine by adding larger environments and more fluid character animation. Plot Syberia II's plot starts exactly where the previous game ended. The player once again takes control of        Kate Walker, as she decides to give up her career as a lawyer and to follow        Hans Voralberg to a remote part of Russia known as Syberia searching for the once thought to be extinct Mammoth's. When they arrive there, they continue to do their search for Mammoth's, exploring the location and talking to people along the way, the characters continue to pursue information to find out if Mammoth's truly exist anymore.Reception While the reviews of Syberia II had scored the game lowerer than the first game, the reviews still remained positive towards the game and it's presentation. Many of these reviews had a common complaint about Syberia II and it's "cliffhanger" ending. Although the first game ended on an appropriate "cliffhanger", many of the reviews for the sequel said the ending of the game was either too abrupt or too depressing, depending on their understanding of the final scene.  While the game doesn't provide any clear explanation about what becomes of Kate after she reaches Syberia with Hans, the creator of the series, Benoît Sokal has stated in interviews that there will not be a Syberia III. After Syberia II's ReleaseSokal left Microïds shortly after the release of Syberia II and founded his own company called White Birds Productions to release Paradise, a game that uses a similar style of gameplay as Syberia, but is not in anyway directly related to that series. On the 1st of April, 2009, Microïds announced that Syberia III would be released on PC and PlayStation 3 in June 2010. On 17, April 2009, another press release was issued, explaining that the PC version will be released, but the PS3 version may not, due to problems with Sony. Benoît Sokal mentioned in the press a number of times that he would only participate in a Syberia sequel if there was a sufficient financial backing  to design and develop it properly. In 2009 Microïds decided to invest in the Syberia franchise, later asking the fans of Syberia send them emails of support for the game.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8759">The Longest Journey</game><game id="22871">Beyond Atlantis II</game><game id="22262">Dracula Origin</game><game id="7022">The Space Bar</game><game id="3141">Still Life</game><game id="22127">Art of Murder: FBI Confidential</game><game id="21090">A New Beginning</game><game id="23532">Nikopol: Secrets of the Immortals</game><game id="13230">Grim Fandango</game><game id="6728">Zak McKracken and the Alien Mindbenders</game><game id="23594">Still Life 2</game><game id="22111">The Whispered World</game><game id="4399">Sam &amp; Max Episode 204: Chariots of the Dogs</game><game id="21914">A Vampyre Story</game><game id="24845">A Vampyre Story 2: A Bat's Tale</game><game id="10915">Beneath a Steel Sky</game><game id="4897">The Moment of Silence</game><game id="16489">Sinking Island</game><game id="5804">Broken Sword: The Sleeping Dragon</game><game id="16905">Broken Sword: The Angel of Death</game><game id="1177">Glass Rose</game><game id="3815">Shadow of Destiny</game><game id="12912">NiBiRu: Age of Secrets</game><game id="5729">The Curse of Monkey Island</game><game id="4403">Post Mortem</game><game id="24777">Return to Mysterious Island II</game><game id="12749">Agatha Christie: Murder on the Orient Express</game><game id="9164">Agatha Christie: Evil Under the Sun</game><game id="10375">Voyage</game><game id="30913">The Next Big Thing</game><game id="19536">Dinotopia</game><game id="20054">Atlantis Evolution</game><game id="7396">Mysterious Journey II: Chameleon</game><game id="32373">Art of Murder: Cards of Destiny</game><game id="3437">Sentinel: Descendants in Time</game><game id="33104">AlternativA</game><game id="17399">Paradise</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15035/641726-sybii.jpg</image></root>