<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19861</id><name>Onimusha 2: Samurai's Destiny</name><description>Story  After hearing news of his village being attacked,             Jubei Yagyu (modeled on the likeness of the late Japanese actor Yusaku Matsuda) hurries back only to find that all of the villagers have been destroyed by an unknown force. After following a mysterious voice that calls his name, Jubei learns that the person who attacked his village was           Nobunaga Oda and the only way to defeat him is to find 5 sacred orbs.GameplayBasic combat in Onimusha 2 involves physical and magical attacks which are each mapped to one button, issens; counter moves performed by attacking an opponent immediately before they strike you, and targeting, which powers up your next strike if held long enough. Movement is controlled with the directional pad, and dodges and backsteps can be performed during combat by pressing in a direction away from the enemy you are targeting. If a player obtains enough purple souls, they can temporarily transform into an Oni and gain improved combat abilities. Defeating enemies yields red souls, which can be used to power-up your weapons, in addition to souls that restore health, magic power, and oni power. Onimusha 2 introduces a new friendship mechanic to the series which allows players to give gifts to several secondary playable characters. Becoming friends with these secondary characters can result in many alternate cut-scenes throughout the game, as well as playable scenarios. WeaponsYagyu Sword A basic samurai sword that you begin the game with. It has been passed down through the generations in Jubei's family and lacks magical power.  Buraitou Found in Yagyu Village only after Jubei gains the power to collect souls, the Buraitou is a samurai sword imbued with the power of thunder. Using its magical ability will release a flurry of lightning-charged strikes on a single enemy.  Hyoujin-Yari Found in the Imasho Gold Mine, the Hyoujin-Yari is a pole-arm that contains the power of ice. Using its magical attack will cause Jubei to slam the pole-arm into the ground, creating a blast of ice that inflicts damage on enemies within a certain area.   Senpumaru A wind-imbued naginata found in the Fog Valley. The Senpumaru's magical attack creates a large tornado that draws nearby enemies towards Jubei and damages them.   Dokoutsui   A hammer that contains the power of earth. It is found within the main room of the Oni Palace. Using the Dokoutsui's magical attack creates an earthquake, heavily damaging all on-screen enemies.  Rekka-ken A broadsword containing the power of fire, the Rekka-Ken is a secret weapon found in Gifu Castle and cannot be upgraded. The Rekka-Ken's magical attack unleashes a circle of fire around Jubei.  Ranged Weapons Several ranged weapons may be found throughout the game, including a bow various guns.Partners  The characters which can become your partner are  Kotaro Fuma - Chief Ninja of the Fuma clan who was sent to scout Nobunaga by the Hojo clan.  Magoichi Saiga – Leader of the Saiga gun troop.  Ekei Ankokuji – A monk who is a master of the Houzouin spear. He also dreams of becoming a feudal lord even if it means joining Nobunaga.  Oyu – A mysterious women who has some connection with Nobunaga.Characters   Jubei Yagyu "An ambitions young warrior and the hero of this story. The first leader of the Yagyu clan and originator of shin-in style. sword combat. Also known as Sougen Yagyu or Sekisyusai. All leaders of the Yagyu clan are given a childhood name of Jubei."Oyu "A fencer who wears western style armor and wields a western sword. She is breath-taking but mysterious. Her past is shrouded in mysterious."Ekei "A master spearfighter in the Houzouin style. He is a monk who loves money."Kotaro "A Fuma Ninja who works for the Hojo clan. He confounds his opponet with his agile movement and countless Ninjutsu."Magoichi "The leader of the "Saiga Shu" gun troop in Kii prefecture. Bold, bright and cool-headed, he is good at handling both a gun and sword."  Nobunaga Oda "An ambitions warlord, determined to rude Japan with an iron fist. In league with demons, he orders his troops to attack Odani Castle."</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16741">Devil May Cry 2</game><game id="7750">Tenchu: Return from Darkness</game><game id="6959">God of War</game><game id="20592">God of War: Chains of Olympus</game><game id="11314">God of War II</game><game id="20461">God of War III</game><game id="4493">Castlevania: Curse of Darkness</game><game id="15790">Castlevania: Lament of Innocence</game><game id="21380">Prince of Persia: The Two Thrones</game><game id="19998">Tenchu: Dark Secret</game><game id="14034">Rygar: The Legendary Adventure</game><game id="11334">Blood Will Tell: Tezuka Osamu's Dororo</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2115767-box_onimusha2.png</image></root>