<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19864</id><name>Final Fantasy Tactics</name><description>OverviewFinal Fantasy Tactics is a strategy role-playing game that was released by Square Enix (formerly Squaresoft) for the Playstation in January of 1998. While the game is part of the Final Fantasy franchise, its gameplay pays more homage to the tactical RPG Tactics Ogre than any of its brethren. However, the game retains a number of Final Fantasy related features such as chocobos, magic and a job system, incorporating these into the turn-based strategy premise. The game was re-released with an enhanced feature set for the PlayStation Portable in 2007 under the title Final Fantasy Tactics: The War of the Lions.GameplayFinal Fantasy Tactics' gameplay revolves primarily around the strength of its battle system. Most of the time in game is spent fighting either scripted story-driven battles or random encounters. The rest is devoted to character development, negotiating the world map and following the game's labyrinthine plot.Battle SystemFinal Fantasy Tactics' battle system takes the familiar traits of the core series' battle mechanics and mixes them with a traditional turn-based-strategy style of gameplay. Battles are fought in 3D isometric environments, with both the player's troop of soldiers and the band of enemies represented by 2D sprites commonly referred to as "units".World MapBetween battles, like most Final Fantasy games, Final Fantasy Tactics provides the player with a world map to traverse. FF Tactics' 2D world map functions more as a menu, as the player does not have active control over the on-screen character. Instead, the character can be moved to any available location on the world map using an icon. There are two primary types of locations on FF Tactics' world map, the first of which is towns. When the player visits a town, he or she has the option to:Visit the local Tavern, catch up on recent Gossip and possibly undertake an Errand.Stop at the Outfitter to buy and sell weapons, armor and other items.Pass by the Warriors' Guild to recruit new soldiers.Exclusive to certain locations, visit the Poachers' Den to buy poached items at reduced prices.Job SystemThe Job System.Like most Final Fantasy games, there is a unique system in place that determines how your magic, abilites, and stats work. The basis of combat revolves around the Job System, a class-based concept that has you changing jobs, and using said actions of that class on the battlefield, which will yield you Job Points (JP). As you gain JP you will level up your specific class of character, as well as gain the right to unlock new abilities, by expending these points. Familiar character classes from past Final Fantasy games appear in this game as jobs, including Wizards, Priests, Thieves, Lancers, and Summoners. Most new characters start out as either a Squire or a Chemist, and work their way up the proverbial ladder, to unlock new Jobs -- and likewise -- new bone-crushing skills.JobsSquireSquireSquire is the base job from which all physical classes grow. While their abilities allow them to perform a wide variety of tasks, they are not particularly adept at any of them. However, every character will want to spend enough time in the job to obtain the JP Boost skill that increases all JP earned by 50%.Prerequisites: NoneWeapons: Axes, Flails, Knives, SwordsArmor: Hats, ClothesMove/Jump Rate: 4/3Evasion Rate: 5%Active Stats: Phys - C; Mag - D; HP - C; MP - D; Spd - CGrowth Rate: Phys - D; Mag - D; HP - C; MP - F; Spd - FFundaments (job skill)NameDescriptionRangeAreaDelayJPFocusIncreases physical attack power by 1 until end of battle01Now300RushPhysical attack with high chance of knock-back11Now80StoneRanged physical attack41Now90SalveRemoves Blind, Poison, Silence11Now150ReactionNameDescriptionTriggerJPCounter TackleAttacks with Rush regardless of abilityPhysical attack180SupportNameDescriptionJPEquip AxesEquip Axes regardless of Job170BeastmasterGrants adjacent friendly monsters within 3H an additional ability200DefendAdds the Defend command, doubles evasion rate until next turn50JP BoostIncreases the amount of JP earned by 50%250MovementNameDescriptionJPMove +1Increases maximum movement range by 1200ChemistChemistUnlike most Final Fantasy games, Chemists are the only job in Final Fantasy Tactics with the skill to use items. As the base class for all spell-casters, their physical abilities are somewhat lacking. However, their offensive capabilities increase drastically when equipped with guns.Prerequisites: NoneWeapons: Guns, KnivesArmor: Hats, ClothesMove/Jump Rate: 3/3Evasion Rate: 5%Active Stats: Phys - D; Mag - D; HP - D; MP - D; Spd - CGrowth Rate: Phys - F; Mag - F; HP - D; MP - D; Spd - FInnate Ability: Throw ItemItem (job skill)NameDescriptionRangeAreaDelayJPPotionUses a Potion to restore 30 HP41Now30Hi-PotionUses a Hi-Potion to restore 70 HP41Now200X-PotionUses an X-Potion to restore 150 HP41Now300EtherUses an Ether to restore 20 MP41Now300Hi-EtherUses a Hi-Ether to restore 50 MP41Now400ElixirUses an Elixir to fully restore HP and MP41Now900AntidoteUses an Antidote to remove Poison41Now70Eye DropsUses an Eye Drops to remove Blind41Now80Echo HerbsUses an Echo Herbs to remove Silence41Now120Maiden's KissUses a Maiden's Kiss to remove Toad41Now200Gold NeedleUses a Gold Needle to remove Stone41Now250Holy WaterUses a Holy Water to remove Undead and Vampire41Now400RemedyUses a Remedy to remove Blind, Confusion, Oil, Poison, Silence, Sleep, Stone, Toad41Now700Phoenix DownUses a Phoenix Down to remove KO41Now90ReactionNameDescriptionTriggerJPAuto-PotionUses weakest available potion on selfHP loss400SupportNameDescriptionJPThrow ItemsThrow items at a range of 4350SafeguardPrevents equipped items from being broken or stolen250ReequipAdds the Reequip command, change equipment mid-battle0MovementNameDescriptionJPMove-Find ItemEnd movement on specific tiles to discover hidden items100KnightKnightCapable of equipping the heavy armor and shields, Knights are extremely durable front-line warriors. Rather than deal damage, they focus on disabling their opponents by selectively destroying crucial equipment and reducing an opponent's key attributes.Prerequisites: Squire Level 2Weapons: Knight's Swords, SwordsArmor: Shields, Helmets, Armor, RobesMove/Jump Rate: 3/3Evasion Rate: 10%Active Stats: Phys - B; Mag - D; HP - C; MP - C; Spd - CGrowth Rate: Phys - B; Mag - F; HP - B; MP - D; Spd - FArts of War (job skill)NameDescriptionRangeAreaDelayJPRend HelmDestroys target's head equipmentWeapon0Now300Rend ArmorDestroys target's body equipmentWeapon0Now400Rend ShieldDestroys target's shieldWeapon0Now300Rend WeaponDestroys target's weaponWeapon0Now400Rend MPReduces target's MP by 50% of maxWeapon0Now250Rend SpeedReduces target's Speed by 2 until end of battleWeapon0Now250Rend PowerReduces target's physical attack power by 3 until end of battleWeapon0Now250Rend MagickReduces target's magical attack power by 3 until end of battleWeapon0Now250ReactionNameDescriptionTriggerJPParryBlocks physical attacks from the front or sides, rate based on equipped weaponPhysical attack200SupportNameDescriptionJPEquip Heavy ArmorEquip Helms and armor regardless of Job500Equip ShieldsEquip Shields regardless of Job250Equip SwordsEquip Swords regardless of Job400ArcherArcherArchers are long-ranged physical attackers that excel when they hold the high-ground. Through their aim skill they are able to increase their damage exponentially. However, the long charging time required can make them hard to use effectively against faster targets.Prerequisites: Squire Level 2Weapons: Bows, CrossbowsArmor: Hats, ClothesMove/Jump Rate: 3/3Evade Rate: 10%Active Stats: Phys - B; Mag - D; HP - C; Mag - C; Spd - CGrowth Rate: Phys - B; Mag - F; HP - C; MP - D; Spd - FAim (job skill)NameDescriptionRangeAreaDelayJPAim +1Charges attack to deal additional damageWeapon14100Aim +2Charges attack to deal additional damageWeapon15150Aim +3Charges attack to deal additional damageWeapon16200Aim +4Charges attack to deal additional damageWeapon18250Aim +5Charges attack to deal additional damageWeapon110300Aim +7Charges attack to deal additional damageWeapon114400Aim +10Charges attack to deal additional damageWeapon120700Aim +20Charges attack to deal additional damageWeapon1351200ReactionNameDescriptionTriggerJPAdrenaline RushIncreases speed by 1 until end of battleHP loss900Archer's BaneEvades bow and crossbow attackBow/crossbow attack450SupportNameDescriptionJPEquip CrossbowsEquip Crossbows regardless of Job350ConcentrateEnemies are unable to evade your physical attacks400MovementNameDescriptionJPJump +1Increases maximum jump height by 1200MonkMonkMonks are melee fighters that eschew the armor and heavy weapons of their martial allies. With access to a wide variety of skills including the ability to strike foes from extremely long range and restore MP to multiple allies, they are effective in almost any situation.Prerequisites: Knight Level 3Weapons: N/AArmor: ClothingMove/Jump Rate: 3/4Evasion Rate: 20%Active Stats: Phys - B; Mag - D; HP - B; MP - C; Spd - BGrowth Rate: Phys - C; Mag - F; HP - B; MP - C; Spd - FInnate Ability: BrawlerMartial Arts (job skill)NameDescriptionRangeAreaSpeedJPCyclonePhysical attack striking all adjacent targets02Now150PummelPhysical attack11Now300AurablastRanged physical attack31Now300ShockwaveRanged physical attack striking all targets in a line4-way8Now600Doom FistCauses Doom status11Now300PurificationRemoves Berserk, Blind, Confuse, Disable, Immobilize, Poison, Silence, Sleep, Stone, Toad from all adjacent targets02Now200ChakraRestores HP and MP to all adjacent targets02Now350ReviveRemoves KO status and restores 20% HP11Now500ReactionNameDescriptionTriggerJPCritical: Recover HPRestores 100% HPHP critical500CounterAttacks with Attack commandPhysical attack300First StrikeCancels the enemy's attack and attacks with Attack commandAttack command1300SupportNameDescriptionJPBrawlerRaises unarmed attack strength, effectiveness of Martial Arts skills, success rate of Steal, and strength of Rush and Stone200MovementNameDescriptionJPLifefontRestores 10% maximum HP when moving at least one tile during a turn300White MageWhite MageAll but one of the spells in the White Mage's arsenal are dedicated to bolstering allies. While the charge time their spells require can cause them to be trickier to use than a Chemist's potions, the strength of their healing and their ability to target multiple characters simultaneously make White Mage's the best class to bring your party back from the brink of destruction.Prerequisites: Chemist Level 2Weapons: StavesArmor: Hats, Clothes, RobesMove/Jump Rate: 3/3Evade Rate: 5%Active Stats: Phys - C; Mag - C; HP - D; MP - A; Speed - BGrowth Rate: Phys - C, Mag - F; HP - B; MP - B; Spd - FWhite Magicks (job skill)NameDescriptionMPRangeAreaDelayJPCureRestores HP642450CuraRestores HP10425180CuragaRestores HP16427450CurajaRestores HP204210800RaiseRemoves KO status and restores 50% HP10414200AriseRemoves KO status and restores 100% HP204110600ReraiseGives Reraise status (automatically raises target if target gains KO status)163171000RegenGives Regen status (restores 12.5% max HP each turn)8314350ProtectGives Protect status (reduces Physical damage by 33%)632470ProtejaGives Protect status24327600ShellGives Shell status (reduces Magical damage by 33%)632470ShelljaGives Shell status20327600WallGives Wall status (reduces Physical and Magical damage by 33%)24314400EsunaRemoves Berserk, Blind, Confuse, Disable, Immobilize, Silence, Sleep, Stone, Toad18323300HolyMagical attack that deals Holy damage56516600ReactionNameDescriptionTriggerJPRegeneratorGives Regen statusHP loss400SupportNameDescriptionJPArcane DefenseReduces magic damage received by 33% and success rate of magic status attacks400Black MageBlack MageBlack Mages are the heavy hitters amongst the spell-casting jobs. While their abilities may lack subtlety, their access to a wide variety of elemental damage types make them particularly dangerous in the hands of a mindful commander.Prerequisites: Chemist Level 2Weapons: RodsArmor: Hats, Clothes, RobesMove/Jump Rate: 3/3Evasion Rate: 5%Active Stats: Phys - D; Mag - B; HP - D; MP - A; Spd - CGrowth Rate: Phys - D; Mag - F; HP - D; MP - A; Spd - FBlack Magicks (job skill)NameDescriptionMPRangeAreaDelayJPFireMagic attack that deals Fire damage642450FiraMagic attack that deals Fire damage12425200FiragaMagic attack that deals Fire damage24427500FirajaMagic attack that deals Fire damage484310900ThunderMagic attack that deals Lightning damage642450ThundaraMagic attack that deals Lightning damage12425200ThundagaMagic attack that deals Lightning damage24427500ThundajaMagic attack that deals Lightning damage484310900BlizzardMagic attack that deals Ice damage642450BlizzaraMagic attack that deals Ice damage12425200BlizzagaMagic attack that deals Ice damage24427500BlizzajaMagic attack that deals Ice damage484310900PoisonInflicts Poison status6423150ToadInflicts Toad status12315500DeathInflicts KO status244110600FlareMagic attack605171000ReactionNameDescriptionTriggerJPMagick CounterAttacks with identical spell regardless of range or abilityMagic attack800SupportNameDescriptionJPArcane StrengthIncreases magic damage and healing by 33%, success rate of magic status attacks, and effectiveness of magic-dependent skills (ie. Geomancy, Iaido etc)400Time MageTime MageDespite a lack of reliable offensive abilities, the buffs and ailments Time Mages are capable of causing can drastically shift the tide of battle. They are most effective when teamed up with powerful damage-dealers.Prerequisites: Black Mage Level 3Weapons: StavesArmor: Hats, Clothes, RobesMove/Jump Rate: 3/3Evade Rate: 5%Active Stats: Phys - D; Mag - C; HP - D; MP - A; Spd - CGrowth Rate: Phys - D; Mag - F; HP - D; MP - B; Spd - FTime Magicks (job skill)NameDescriptionMPRangeAreaDelayJPHasteGives Haste status8322100HastejaGives Haste status30327600SlowInflicts Slow status832280SlowjaInflicts Slow status30327600StopInflicts Stop status14327350ImmobilizeInflicts immobilize status10323100FloatGives Float status8422200ReflectGives Reflect status12412300QuickGrants full CT gauge24414900GravityDeals damage equal to 25% of target's maximum HP24426250GravigaDeals damage equal to 50% of target's maximum HP504210550MeteorMagic attack7044201500ReactionNameDescriptionTriggerJPCritical: QuickGrants full CT gaugeHP critical800Mana ShieldDamage lowers MP before HPHP loss400SupportNameDetailsJPSwiftnessHalves delay before abilities are executed, no effect on Aim, Bardsong, Dance, or Jump1000MovementNameDescriptionJPTeleportMove to any square with a chance of failure that increases based on distance650LevitatePermanent Float status540SummonerSummonerBy calling upon a wide variety of mythical beings, Summoners are capable of causing numerous effects over large areas of the battlefield. Unlike most magic, summons are capable of discerning between friend and foe ensuring that allies are never damaged and enemies are never healed. Unfortunately, this causes their spells to be slower, more costly, and generally less powerful than the more compact spells of their fellow casters.Prerequisites: Time Mage Level 3Weapons: Rods, StavesArmor: Hats, Clothes, RobesMove/Jump Rate: 3/3Evade Rate: 5%Active Stats: Phys - D; Mag - C; HP - D; MP - A; Spd - DGrowth Rate: Phys - F; Mag - F; HP - D; MP - A; Spd - FSummon (job skill)NameDescriptionMPRangeAreaDelayJPMoogleRestores HP to allies8433110ShivaMagic attack that deals Ice damage to enemies24437200RamuhMagic attack that deals Lightning damage to enemies24437200IfritMagic attack that deals Fire damage to enemies24437200TitanMagic attack that deals Earth damage to enemies304310220GolemBlocks physical damage40AlliesAllies4500CarbunkleGrants Reflect status to allies30435350BahamutMagic attack that deals damage to enemies6044151600OdinMagic attack that deals damage to enemies504413900LeviathanMagic attack that deals Water damage to enemies484413860SalamanderMagic attack that deals Fire damage to enemies484313860SilphInflicts Silence status to enemies26437400FaerieRestores HP to allies28437400LichDeals damage equal to 50% of target's maximum HP to enemies404310600CyclopsMagic attack that deals damage to enemies6243121000ZodiarkMagic attack that deals damage to enemies994417**Zodiark can only be learned by being hit by it and survivingReactionNameDescriptionTriggerJPCritical: Recover MPRestores 100% MPHP critical400SupportColumn HeadColumn HeadJPHalve MPHalves MP cost of abilities1000ThiefThiefWhile they are agile and dexterous, Thieves are possibly the least effective of all the jobs in combat. However, with enough perseverance they are capable stripping an opponent bare. This means it is always a good idea to keep at least one party member with the Steal skill active at all times as certain rare items can only be acquired through stealing.Prerequisites: Archer Level 3Weapons: KnivesArmor: Hats, ClothesMove/Jump Rate: 4/4Evade Rate: 25%Active Stats: Phys - C; Mag - D; HP - D; MP - D; Spd - BGrowth Rate: Phys - C; Mag - F; HP - C; MP - D; Spd - CSteal (job skill)NameDescriptionRangeAreaDelayJPSteal GilSteal gil (speed * level)11Now10Steal HeartInflicts Charm against monsters or humans of the opposite sex31Now150Steal HelmSteal Helmet11Now350Steal ArmorSteal Armor11Now450Steal ShieldSteal Shield11Now350Steal WeaponSteal Weapon11Now600Steal AccessorySteal Accessory11Now500Steal ExpSteal Exp (speed + 5)11Now250ReactionNameDescriptionTriggerJPVigilanceEnters Defense position, doubles evasion rateAttacked by other character200Gil SnapperReceive Gil equal to HP lostAttacked by other character200Sticky FingersBlock other character's Throw command, adds item to inventoryAttacked by Throw command200SupportNameDescriptionJPPoachKO'ing a monster with a physical attack causes the corpse to disappear and an item to appear in the Poachers' Den200MovementNameDescriptionJPMove +2Increases maximum movement range by 1560Jump +2Increases maximum jump height by 1500OratorOratorOrators are best used in non-critical encounters for their ability to cause a permanent change in the Bravery and Faith attributes of their allies. The overall ineffectiveness of their other skills, however, causes them to be largely useless in combat despite their ability to equip guns.Prerequisites: Mystic Level 3Weapons: Guns, KnivesArmor: Hats, Clothes, RobesMove/Jump Rate: 3/3Evade Rate: 5%Active Stats: Phys - D; Mag - D; HP - D; MP - D; Spd - CGrowth Rate: Phys - D; Mag - F; HP - C; MP - F; Spd - FInnate Ability: Beast TongueSpeechcraft (job skill)NameDescriptionRangeAreaDelayJPEnticeTarget becomes a Guest that joins the party after battle31Now100StallReduces CT gauge to 031Now100PraiseIncreases Bravery by 4 until end of battle*31Now200IntimidateDecreases Bravery by 20 until end of battle*31Now200PreachIncreases Faith by 4 until end of battle*31Now200EnlightenDecreases Faith by 20 until end of battle*31Now200CondemnInflicts Doom status31Now500BegReceive Gil from enemy31Now100InsultInflicts Berserk status31Now300Mimic DarlavonInflicts Sleep status31Now300* For every 4 points of Bravery/Faith gained/lost, 1 is permanentReactionNameDescriptionTriggerJPEarplugBlocks Speechcraft skillSpeechcraft skill300SupportNameDescriptionJPEquip GunsEquip Guns regardless of job800TamePhysical attacks recruit monsters with HP critical500Beast TongueSpeechcraft skills work against monsters100MysticMysticThe ultimate debuffers, Mystics have access to the widest variety of ailment-inflicting spells in the game. They can also be surprisingly effective at dispatching enemies at close range when equipped with Poles.Prerequisites: White Mage Level 3Weapons: Books, Poles, Rods, StavesArmor: Hats, Clothes, RobesMove/Jump Rate: 3/3Evade Rate: 5%Active Stats: Phys - D; Mag - C; HP - D; MP - B; Spd - CGrowth Rate: Phys - D; Mag - F; HP - D; MP - B; Spd - FMystic Arts (job skill)NameDescriptionMPRangeAreaDelayJPUmbraInflicts Blind status4422100EmpowermentDrains MP equal to 33% of target's maximum MP2412200InvigorationDrains HP equal to 25% of target's maximum HP16412350BeliefCauses Faith status6414400DisbeliefCauses Atheist status6414400CorruptionInflicts Undead status20415300QuiescenceInflicts Silence status16413170FervorInflicts Berserk status16415400TrepidationDecreases Bravery by 30 until end of battle*20414200DeliriumInflicts Confuse status20415400HarmonyRemoves Faith, Float, Haste, Invisible, Protect, Reflect, Regen, Reraise, Shell34413800HesitationInflicts Disable status10425100ReposeInflicts Sleep status24426350IndurationInflicts Stone status164110600* For every 4 points of Bravery lost, 1 is permanentReactionNameDescriptionTriggerJPAbsorb MPGain MP equal to cost of spell castMagic attack250SupportNameDescriptionJPDefense BoostReduces physical damage received by 33%400MovementNameDescriptionJPIgnore WeatherEliminates movement penalty for Marsh, Poisonous Fen, and Swamp tiles during rainstorm and thunderstorm200ManafootRestores 10% maximum MP when moving at least one tile during a turn350GeomancerGeomancerGeomancers are melee fighters capable of inflicting damage and a variety of status ailments at long range. Because their skills change depending on where they are standing, a strong sense of position is required to utilize them to maximum effectiveness.Prerequisites: Monk Level 4Weapons: Axes, SwordsArmor: Hats, Clothes, RobesMove/Jump Rate: 4/3Evade Rate: 10%Active Stats: Phys - C; Mag - C-; HP - C; MP - C; Spd - CGrowth Rate: Phys - B; Mag - F; HP - B; MP - B; Spd - FGeomancy (job skill)NameDescriptionRangeAreaDelayJPSinkholeMagic attack that inflicts Immobilize status52Now150TorrentMagic attack that deals Water damage and inflicts Toad status52Now150TanglevineMagic attack that inflicts Stop status52Now150ContortionMagic attack that inflicts Stone status52Now150TremorMagic attack that deals Earth damage and inflicts Confuse status52Now150Wind SlashMagic attack that deals Wind damage and inflicts Disable status52Now150Will-o'-the-WispMagic attack that deals Fire damage and inflicts Sleep status52Now150QuicksandMagic attack that deals Water damage and inflicts Doom status52Now150SandstormMagic attack that deals Wind damage and inflicts Blind status52Now150SnowstormMagic attack that deals Ice damage and inflicts Silence status52Now150Wind BlastMagic attack that deals Wind damage and inflicts Slow status52Now150Magma SurgeMagic attack that deals Fire damage and inflicts KO status52Now150NameTerrain TypeSinkholeSoil, WastelandTorrentCanal, Lake, Ocean, River, WaterfallTanglevineGrassland, Underbrush, VinesContortionEarthen Wall, Flagstone, Gravel, Gravestone, Stone WallTremorBasalt, Stone OutcroppingWind SlashBook, Brick, Bridge, Coffin, Furnishings, Iron, Moss, TreeWill-o'-the-WispCarpet, Coffer, Stairs, Wooden Deck, Wooden FloorQuicksandMarsh, Poisonous Fen, SwampSandstormSalt Flat, Sand, StalactiteSnowstormSnowWind BlastChimney, RoofMagma SurgeLava, MachineryReactionNameDescriptionTriggerJPNature's WrathAttacks with Geomancy regardless of range or abilityPhysical attack or Geomancy300SupportNameDescriptionJPAttack BoostIncreases physical attack damage by 33%400MovementNameDescriptionJPIgnore TerrainEliminates movement penalty for Water tiles during clear weather220LavawalkingPermits movement over and standing on Magma tiles150DragoonDragoonA staple of the Final Fantasy franchise, Dragoons are heavy-armored polearm specialists. Their key Jump ability allows them to strike at great distance and, with proper timing, inflict incredible damage.Prerequisites: Thief Level 4Weapons: PolearmsArmor: Shields, Helms, Armor, RobesMove/Jump Rate: 3/4Evade Rate: 10%Active Stats: Phys - B; Mag - F; HP - C; MP - D; Spd - CGrowth Rate: Phys - B; Mag - F; HP - B; MP - D; Spd - FJump (job skill)NameDescriptionRangeAreaDelayJPHorizontal Jump 2Allows Jump to target a distance of up to 2 tiles2150/Spd150Horizontal Jump 3Allows Jump to target a distance of up to 3 tiles3150/Spd350Horizontal Jump 4Allows Jump to target a distance of up to 4 tiles4150/Spd550Horizontal Jump 5Allows Jump to target a distance of up to 5 tiles5150/Spd800Horizontal Jump 8Allows Jump to target a distance of up to 8 tiles8150/Spd1100Vertical Jump 2Allows Jump to reach an elevation difference of up to 21150/Spd100Vertical Jump 3Allows Jump to reach an elevation difference of up to 31150/Spd250Vertical Jump 4Allows Jump to reach an elevation difference of up to 41150/Spd400Vertical Jump 5Allows Jump to reach an elevation difference of up to 51150/Spd550Vertical Jump 6Allows Jump to reach an elevation difference of up to 61150/Spd700Vertical Jump 7Allows Jump to reach an elevation difference of up to 71150/Spd1000Vertical Jump 8Allows Jump to reach an elevation difference of up to 81150/Spd1500ReactionNameDescriptionTriggerJPDragonheartGrants Reraise statusPhysical attack600SupportNameDescriptionJPEquip PolearmsEquip Polearms regardless of job400MovementNameDescriptionJPIgnore ElevationJump height is infinite during movement700SamuraiSamuraiSamurai are durable melee warriors with an extraordinary ability. Through their Iaido skill, they are capable of cause powerful effects in a large radius around themselves that intelligently targets only allies or enemies when appropriate. Katanas are the fuel for Iaido abilities, however, and with a chance to shatter on each use, Iaido can become extremely expensive.Prerequisites: Knight Level 4; Monk Level 5; Dragoon Level 2Weapons: KatanasArmor: Helmets, Armor, RobesMove/Jump Rate: 3/3Evade Rate: 20%Active Stats: Phys - B; Mag - C; HP - D; MP - C; Spd - CGrowth Rate: Phys - B; Mag - F; HP - D; MP - C; Spd - FIaido (job skill)NameDescriptionRangeAreaDelayJPAsuraMagic attack03Now100KotetsuMagic attack03Now200OsafuneDecreases MP03Now300MurasameRestores HP03Now400Ame-no-MurakumoMagic attack, inflicts Slow status03Now500KiyomoriGrants Protect and Shell status03Now600MuramasaMagic attack, inflicts Confuse and Doom status03Now700Kiku-ichimonjiMagic attack4-way8Now800MasamuneGrants Haste and Regen status03Now900ChirijiradenMagic attack03Now1000ReactionNameDescriptionTriggerJPBonecrusherAttacks with a physical attack that does damage equal own max HPHP critical200ShirahadoriBlocks physical attacks including monsters and GunsPhysical attack700SupportNameDescriptionJPEquip KatanaEquip Katana regardless of job400DoublehandEquip one weapon in both hands, increases Attack command and Aim skill damage900MovementNameDescriptionJPSwimEliminates movement penalty for water tiles, permits movement in water up to a depth of 4, and allows action at any depth300NinjaNinjaWith their extremely high speed and the ability to wield a weapon in each hand, Ninjas are one of the most offensively dangerous jobs in the game. This prowess, however, is tempered somewhat by the fact that they are incredibly fragile and have a largely ineffective job skill.Prerequisites: Archer Level 4, Thief level 5, Geomancer Level 2Weapons: Knives, Flails, Ninja BladesArmor: Hats, ClothesMove/Jump Rate: 4/4Evade Rate: 30%Active Stats: Phys - B; Mag - D; HP - D; MP - D; Spd - AGrowth Rate: Phys - B; Mag - F; HP - D; MP - C; Spd - AInnate Ability: Dual WieldThrow (job skill)NameDescriptionRangeAreaDelayJPShurikenThrow ShurikenMove range1Now50BombThrow BombMove range1Now70KnifeThrow KnifeMove range1Now100SwordThrow SwordMove range1Now100FlailThrow FlailMove range1Now100KatanaThrow KatanMove range1Now100Ninja BladeThrow Ninja BladeMove range1Now100AxeThrow AxeMove range1Now120PolearmThrow PolearmMove range1Now100PoleThrow PoleMove range1Now100Knight's SwordThrow Knight's SwordMove range1Now100BookThrow BookMove range1Now100ReactionNameDescriptionTriggerJPVanishGrants Invisibility statusPhysical attack1000ReflexesDoubles all Evade ratesN/A400SupportNameDescriptionJPDual WieldEquip a weapon in each hand, striking with both during Attack command1000MovementNameDescriptionJPWaterwalkingPermits movement over and standing on Water tiles420ArithmeticianArithmeticianWhile Arithmeticians may be ponderously slow, this is only to compensate for their ability to cast any known spell from the White, Black, Time and Mystic schools of magic. Through carefully calculating their targets based on a number of factors, their spells can reach across the screen instantly with no MP cost or delay.Prerequisites: White Mage Level 5; Black Mage Level 5; Time Mage Level 4; Mystic Level 4Weapons: Books, PolesArmor: Hats, Clothes, RobesMove/Jump Rate: 3/3Evade Rate: 5%Active Stats: Phys - D; Mag - D; HP - D; MP - C; Spd - FGrowth Rate: Phys - F; Mag - F; HP - D; MP - B; Spd - FArithmeticks (job skill)NameDescriptionRangeAreaDelayJPCTSpell targets based on CTN/AN/ANow250LevelSpell targets based on LevelN/AN/ANow350ExpSpell targets based on ExpN/AN/ANow200HeightSpell targets based on HeightN/AN/ANow250PrimeSpell targets prime numbersN/AN/ANow300Multiple of 5Spell targets multiples of 5N/AN/ANow200Multiple of 4Spell targets multiples of 4N/AN/ANow400Multiple of 3Spell targets multiples of 3N/AN/ANow600ReactionNameDescriptionTriggerJPCup of LifeDistributes excess healing received to other party membersHP gain200SoulbindRestores 50% of damage received and deals an equal amount of damage to attackerHP loss300SupportNameDescriptionJPExp BoostIncreases the amount of Exp received by 100%350MovementNameDescriptionJPAccrue ExpGrants 1 Exp for every tile moved400Accrue JPGrants 2 JP for every tile moved400BardBardA job unique to male characters, Bards have a wide variety of songs that benefit allies located anywhere on the map. Their only shortcomings lie in the fact that their abilities are not particularly powerful and often times will miss their target.Prerequisites: Summoner Level 5; Orator Level 5Weapons: InstrumentsArmor: Hats, ClothesMove/Jump Rate: 3/3Evade Rate: 5%Active Stats: Phys - F; Mag - C; HP - F; MP - C; Spd - CGrowth Rate: Phys - F; Mag - F; HP - F; MP - F; Spd - FBardsong (job skill)NameDescriptionRangeAreaDelayJPSeraph SongRestores MP; 100% success rateAlliesAllies6100Life's AnthemRestores HP; 100% success rateAlliesAllies6100Rousing MelodyIncreases speed by 1 until end of battle; 50% success rateAlliesAllies8100Battle ChantIncreases physical attack power by 1 until end of battleAlliesAllies8100Magickal RefrainIncreases magical attack power by 1 until end of battle; 50% success rateAlliesAllies10100Nameless SongGrants Haste, Protect, Shell, Regen, or Reraise; 50% success rateAlliesAllies10100FinaleGrants full CT gauge; 50% success rateAlliesAllies20100ReactionNameDescriptionTriggerJPMagick BoostIncreases magical attack power by 1 until end of battleHP loss500Faith BoostIncreases Faith by 3 until end of battle*Magic effect400* For every 4 points of Faith gained, 1 is permanentMovementNameDescriptionJPMove +3Increases maximum movement range by 31000FlyIgnore tile penalties and obstacles while moving5000DancerDancerThe dances this female-only job can perform are capable of targeting every enemy on the map regardless of range. While they are not always successful, with a little luck entire armies can be danced into submission.Prerequisites: Geomancer Level 5; Dragoon Level 5Weapons: Cloths, KnivesArmor: Hats, ClothesMove/Jump Rate: 3/3Evade Rate: 5%Active Stats: Phys - C; Mag - C; HP - F; MP - D; Spd - CGrowth Rate: Phys - C; Mag - F; HP - F; MP - F; Spd - FDance (job skill)NameDescriptionRangeAreaDelayJPWitch HuntReduces MP; 100% success rateEnemiesEnemies6100Mincing MinuetReduces HP; 100% success rateEnemiesEnemies6100Slow DanceReduces speed by 1 until end of battle; 50% success rateEnemiesEnemies8100PolkaReduces physical attack power by 1 until end of battle; 50% success rateEnemiesEnemies8100Heathen FrolickReduces magical attack power by 1 until end of battle; 50% success rateEnemiesEnemies10100Forbidden DanceInflicts Blind, Confuse, Poison, Silence, Sleep, Slow, Stop, or Toad; 50% success rateEnemiesEnemies10100Last WaltzInflicts empty CT gauge; 50% success rateEnemiesEnemies20100ReactionNameDescriptionTriggerJPFuryIncreases physical attack power by 1 until end of battleHP loss600Bravery BoostIncreases Bravery by 3 until end of battle*Physical attack700*For every 4 points of Bravery gained, 1 is permanentMovementNameDescriptionJPJump +3Increases maximum jump height by 31000FlyIgnore tile penalties and obstacles while moving5000MimeMimeOne of the strangest jobs to utilize, Mimes are only able to move and use an Attack command on their own turn. However, any time an ally performs an action, the Mime will duplicate it based on their current facing. While this can be incredibly difficult to use effectively, careful planning can practically double a party's effective turns.Prerequisites: Squire Level 8; Chemist Level 8; Summoner Level 5; Orator Level 5; Geomancer Level 5; Dragoon Level 5Weapons: NoneArmor: NoneMove/Jump Rate: 4/4Evade Rate: 5%Active Stats: Phys - B; Mag - C; HP - B; MP - D; Spd - AGrowth Rate: Phys - A; Mag - B; HP - A; MP - F; Spd - FDark Knight*Dark KnightModeled after the Fell Knight Gaffgarion, Dark Knights are deadly melee fighters capable of draining their foes. When facing a cluster of enemies, they can sacrifice their health to deal heavy damage over a wide area.Prerequisites: Knight Mastered; Black Mage Mastered; Geomancer Mastered; Dragoon Level 8; Samurai Level 8; Ninja Level 8; Kill 20 enemiesWeapons: Axes, Fell Swords, Flails, Knight's Swords, SwordsArmor: Shields, Helms, Armor, Clothes, RobesMove/Jump Rate: 3/3Evade Rate: 0%Active Stats: Phys - B; Mag - D; HP - D; MP - C; Spd - CGrowth Rate: Phys - B; Mag - F; HP - D; MP - F; Spd - FDarkness (job skill; sword required)NameDescriptionRangeAreaDelayJPSanguine SwordDrains HP from the target31500Infernal StrikeDrains MP from the target31500Crushing BlowPhysical attack that deals elemental damage based on weapon equipped, inflicts Stop status31300Abyssal BladePhysical attack that deals elemental damage based on weapon equipped, costs 20% max HP to use3Cone1000Unholy SacrificeMagic attack that deals Dark damage, inflicts Slow status, costs 30% max HP to use031200SupportNameDescriptionJPHP BoostIncreases max HP by 20%2000VehemenceIncreases effectiveness of attacks and damage received by 50%400MovementNameDescriptionJPJump +3 (Male characters)Increases maximum jump height by 31000Move + 3 (Female characters)Increases maximum move range by 31000Onion Knight*Onion KnightRestricted from learning or equipping any job abilities, Onion Knights are melee fighters restricted to using the simple Attack command. While they are able to utilize any weapon or piece of armor, their low initial attributes and inability to earn experience results in what is largely considered a worthless job. Because they do not gain job points, Onion Knights cannot increase their job level through regular means. However, for every 2 job classes a characters masters, their Onion Knight job level increases by one. It is only when 14 jobs have been mastered and the Onion Knight job level has been increased to 8 that the Onion Knight begins to approach any level of effectiveness, with above average stats in every category.Prerequisites: Squire Level 6, Chemist Level 6Weapons: AllArmor: AllJob Level  8Move/Jump Rate: 3/3Evade Rate: 5%Active Stats: Phys - D; Mag - F; HP - F; MP - D; Spd - CGrowth Rate: Phys - F; Mag - F; HP - D; MP - C; Spd - FJob Level 8Move/Jump Rate: 4/4Evade Rate: 30%Active Stats: Phys - B; Mag - C; HP - B; MP - A; Spd - AGrowth Rate: Phys - A; Mag - B; HP - A; MP - A; Spd - A* Job added in Final Fantasy Tactics: War of the LionsPrimary Player CharactersIn addition to generic soldiers and monsters that can be recruited by the player, over the course of the campaign a number of unique characters critical to the main storyline will join the party. These characters have a unique job skill with abilities available only to themselves. In the cases of the human characters, these unique jobs replace the Squire job on the job wheel.Ramza BeoulveThe son of a noble lord and a common woman, Ramza and his sister Alma lived a privileged childhood as members of house Beoulve. Having inherited his father's penchant for heroism and passion for justice, he finds himself at odds with his half-brothers after discovering the despicable ways in which they fight to gain power for themselves. Embarking on a quest to discover himself and the truth of the world, he takes his mother's surname Lugria.SquireRamza has a modified Squire job with attributes that gradually improve as the story progresses. Amongst his unique abilities is the spell Ultima which he can only learn by being hit with it and surviving.Weapons: Flails, Knives, Swords, Knight Swords (Ch.4)Armor: Hats, Clothes, Robes, Shields (Ch.2), Helms (Ch.2), Armor (Ch.2)Move/Jump Rate: 4/3Evade Rate: 10%Active Stats: Phys - C; Mag - C; HP - C; MP - B; Spd - CGrowth Rate: Phys - C; Mag - D; HP - C; MP - B; Spd - DMettle (job skill)NameDescriptionMPRangeAreaDelayJPFocusIncreases physical attack power by 1 until end of battle--010300RushPhysical attack with high chance of knock-back--11080StoneRanged physical attack--41090SalveRemoves Blind, Poison, Silence--110150TailwindIncreases speed by 1 until end of battle--310200ChantHeals for 40% of user's max HP, costs 20% max HP to use--1100Steel (Ch.2)Increases Bravery by 5 until end of battle*--310200Shout (Ch.4)Increases Bravery by 20, and physical and magical attack power by 1 until end of battle--010500Ultima (Ch.4)Magic attack10425***For every 4 points of Bravery gained, 1 is permanent*Ultima can only be learned by being hit by it and survivingMustadio BunansaA talented engineer, Mustadio inadvertently draws the attention of the Baert Trading Company after excavating the Tartarus Zodiac Stone from beneath the machine-city of Goug. Kidnapped alongside his father, he divulges the secret hiding location for what only he knows is a decoy stone. After being rescued by his newfound friend Ramza, the two set off on a journey to discover the truth behind the stone and the motives of those who were willing to kill to obtain it.MachinistAn expert marksman, Mustadio has the ability to surgically target key points of his enemy's body to limit their ability to act. While he can utilize these talents with any weapon, he is at his best when equipped with a gun, sniping enemies from afar.Weapons: Guns, KnivesArmor: Hats, ClothesMove/Jump Rate: 3/4Evade Rate: 18%Active Stats: Phys - C; Mag - C; HP - C; MP - D; Spd - BGrowth Rate: Phys - C; Mag - F; HP - C; MP - C; Spd - FAimed Shot (job skill)NameDescriptionRangeAreaDelayJPLeg ShotInflicts Immobilize statusWeaponWeaponNow200Arm ShotInflicts Disable statusWeaponWeaponNow300Seal EvilInflicts Stone status on undead targetsWeaponWeaponNow200Agrias OaksMember of the Lesalian Royal Guard and personal bodyguard to Princess Ovelia, Agrias crosses paths with Ramza numerous times during his early travels. After her betrayal by Cardinal Delacroix, she manages to escape but finds herself on the run from his thugs. A timely encounter with Ramza and his crew allows her to dispatch her pursuers, and the group sets off to rescue the princess from her execution.Holy KnightOne of the most powerful characters, Agrias's Holy Knight abilities allow her to deal heavy damage over a wide area at range as long as she has a sword equipped. If she doesn't manage to fell her opponents in a single stroke, she also has a chance to inflict a variety of status ailments with her attacks.Weapons: Knight's Swords, SwordsArmor: Shields, Helms, Armor, RobesMove/Jump Rate: 3/3Evade Rate: 25%Active Stats: Phys - C; Mag - C; HP - B; MP - C; Spd - CGrowth Rate: Phys - C; Mag - F; HP - B; MP - B; Spd - FHoly Sword (job skill; sword required)NameDescriptionRangeAreaDelayJPJudgment BladePhysical attack, inflicts Stop status22Now0Cleansing StrikePhysical attack, inflicts Doom status31Now400Northswain's StrikePhysical attack, inflicts KO status31Now500Hallowed BoltPhysical attack, inflicts Silence status32Now700Divine RuinationPhysical attack, inflicts Confuse status4-way5Now800Rapha GalthenaChildren destined to inherit a mystic power, Rapha and her fraternal twin Marach were kidnapped shortly after their birth by the Grand Duke Barrington. Raised to become an assassin, it was many years before Rapha learned the truth of their past and Barrington's destruction of their village. Unable to convince her brother of the truth, she defects to protect her latest target Ramza in hopes that he will help her put an end to Barrington's evil once and for all.SkyseerRapha's Skyseer abilities are unique magic attacks that, unlike regular magic, deal the same damage regardless of her Faith and the Faith of her target. Also unlike regular magic are the multiple random factors that determine how effective her spells are. While most area-of-effect spells strike every tile within their radius once, however her spells strike a random number of tiles a random number of times. She can inflict heavy damage just as easily as she can completely miss her target.Weapons: Poles, StavesArmor: Hats, Clothes, RobesMove/Jump Rate: 3/3Evade Rate: 10%Active Stats: Phys - C; Mag - C; HP - C; MP - C; Spd - BGrowth Rate: Phys - C; Mag - F; HP - C; MP - B; Spd - FSky Mantra (job skill)NameDescriptionRangeAreaDelayJPHeaven's WrathMagic attack that deals Lightning damage, strikes random tiles 1-10 times423100AshuraMagic attack that deals Fire damage, strikes random tiles 1-10 times424200Adamantine BladeMagic attack that deals Wind damage, strikes random tiles 1-10 times425300MaelstromMagic attack that deals Water damage, strikes random tiles 1-10 times426400Celestial VoidMagic attack, inflicts Blind, Confuse, Poison, Silence, Sleep, Slow, Toad, strikes random tiles 1-10 times425500DivinityMagic attack that deals water damage, strikes random tiles 1-10 times427600Marach GalthenaServing for years as a member of the Khamja assassination team, Marach refused to believe the accusations of evil his twin Rapha levied against their apparent benefactor the Grand Duke Barrington. It is not until Ramza's forces attack Riovanes castle that Marach realizes the truth, overhearing Barrington gloat about raping his sister. After being mortally wounded protecting Rapha, he is mysteriously revived by the Scorpio Zodiac Stone and finds himself honor bound alongside his sister to aid Ramza in his travels.NetherseerThe opposite of standard magic, Marach's spells grow more powerful the lower the Faith is and his target and himself. While this gives him the potential to do incredible damage, it also makes him difficult to use effectively. This is only exacerbated by the fact that his spells strike randomly within their radius, making every attack with him a gamble.Weapons: Poles, RodsArmor: Hats, Clothes, RobesMove/Jump Rate: 4/3Evade Rate: 8%Active Stats: Phys - C; Mag - C; HP - C; MP - B; Spd - BGrowth Rate: Phys - C; Mag - F; HP - B; MP - B; Spd - FNether Mantra (job skill)NameDescriptionRangeAreaDelayJPHell's WrathMagic attack that deals Lightning damage, strikes random tiles 1-10 times423100Nether AshuraMagic attack that deals Fire damage, strikes random tiles 1-10 times424200Nether BladeMagic attack that deals Wind damage, strikes random tiles 1-10 times425300Nether MaelstromMagic attack that deals Water damage, strikes random tiles 1-10 times426400Corporeal VoidMagic attack, inflicts Blind, Confuse, Poison, Silence, Sleep, Slow, Toad, strikes random tiles 1-10 times425500ImpietyMagic attack that deals Earth damage, strikes random tiles 1-10 times427600Cidolfus Orlandeau (T.G. Cid)An expert swordsman and brilliant strategist, Orlandeau earned the moniker "Thunder God Cid" for his actions as general during the Fifty Years' War. However, because of his growing distaste for the actions of Duke Goltana, he soon finds himself branded as a traitor and imprisoned. Aided by Ramza's childhood friend Delita as part of a greater plot, his death is faked allowing him to escape prison and follow Ramza on his journey.Sword SaintA master in the truest sense, Orlandeau has access to the skills of all the other major swordsmen in Ivalice. Capable of tapping into the abilities of Holy, Divine, and Fell Knights, there's is almost no foe he is incapable of overcoming.Weapons: Katanas, Knight's Swords, Ninja Blades, SwordsArmor: Shields, Hats, Helms, Armor, Clothes, RobesMove/Jump Rate: 4/3Evade Rate: 12%Active Stats: Phys - B; Mag - C; HP - B; MP - A; Spd - BGrowth Rate: Phys - B; Mag - C; HP - B; MP - B; Spd - DSwordplay (job skill; sword required)NameDescriptionRangeAreaDelayJPJudgment BladePhysical attack, inflicts Stop22Now0Cleansing StrikePhysical attack, inflicts Doom31Now400Northswain's StrikePhysical attack, inflicts KO31Now500Hallowed BoltPhysical attack, inflicts Silence32Now700Divine RuinationPhysical attack, inflicts Confuse4-way5Now800Crush ArmorPhysical attack, destroys target's body equipment31Now200Crush HelmPhysical attack, destroys target's head equipment31Now400Crush WeaponPhysical attack, destroys target's weapon31Now500Crush AccessoryPhysical attack, destroys target's accessory31Now800ShadowbladeDrains HP from the target31Now100DuskbladeDrains MP from the target31Now500Meliadoul TengilleUnaware of her father Folmarv's violent posession by a Lucavi, Meliadoul blames Ramza, labeled as a heretic by the Glabados Church, for the death of her younger brother Isilud. However, when Marquis Elmdore reveals his true form, she realizes her mistake and quickly leaps to Ramza's aid. Together they manage to defeat the Lucavi demon Zalera and continue on a quest to end the supernatural threat.Divine KnightMeliadoul's Divine Knight abilities allow her surgically destroy her the equipment of her enemies, making her most effective against humans. While she is still capable of dealing damage to characters without equipment, the Safeguard ability renders her attacks useless.Weapons: Crossbows, Knight's Swords, Polearms, SwordsArmor: Shields, Helms, Armor, Clothes, RobesMove/Jump Rate: 4/3Evade Rate: 10%Active Stats: Phys - B; Mag - C; HP - C; MP - C; Spd - CGrowth Rate: Phys - A; Mag - F; HP - B; MP - D; Spd - FUnyielding Blade (job skill; sword required)NameDescriptionRangeAreaDelayJPCrush ArmorPhysical attack, destroys target's body equipment31Now200Crush HelmPhysical attack, destroys target's head equipment31Now400Crush WeaponPhysical attack, destroys target's weapon31Now500Crush AccessoryPhysical attack, destroys target's accessory31Now800Secondary Player CharactersAt certain key points within the campaign, players will have the opportunity to discover unique characters with their own ancillary storylines. While recruiting these characters is not necessary to advance the plot, the special abilities that they bring the the party make them worth seeking out.Beowulf CadmusThe former commander of the Lionel Gryphon Knights, Beowulf was stripped of his rank and declared a heretic by Celebrant Bremondt Freitberg who coveted his fiancee, Reis. A curse from the Celebrant meant for Beowulf transformed Reis into a dragon, and as she fled he quickly followed. Tracking her to the mining town of Gollund, Beowulf encounters Ramza and his party on their hunt for the rumored holy dragon. As they are beset by monsters, they are forced to join forces to avoid being overwhelmed.TemplarBeowulf's Templar abilities function very similar to those of a Mystic, inflicting a variety of powerful status ailments on his target. However, by channeling the magic through his sword, he is able to cast his spells instantly and with greater accuracy.Weapons: Knight's Swords, Knives, SwordsArmor: Shields, Helms, Armor, Clothes, RobesMove/Jump Rate: 4/3Evade Rate: 14%Active Stats: Phys - B; Mag - C; HP - C; MP - A; Spd - CGrowth Rate: Phys - C; Mag - C; HP - B; MP - B; Spd - FSpellblade (job skill; sword required)NameDescriptionMPRangeAreaDelayJPBlindInflicts Blind status641Now50SyphonDrains MP equal to 25% of target's maximum MP241Now100DrainDrains HP equal to 25% of target's maximum HP1241Now180FaithCauses Faith status1041Now200DoubtCauses Atheist status1041Now200ZombieInflicts Undead status1441Now150SilenceInflicts Silence status1641Now90BerserkInflicts Berserk status1641Now200ChickenDecreases Bravery by 50 until end of battle*1241Now500ConfuseInflicts Confuse status1441Now200DispelRemoves Faith, Float, Haste, Invisible, Protect, Reflect, Regen, Reraise, Shell2041Now300DisableInflicts Disable status1441Now50SleepInflicts Sleep status2041Now170BreakInflicts Stone status2441Now300VengeanceMagic attack, deals damage equal to Beowulf's max HP minus his current HP2081Now600*For every 4 points of Bravery lost, 1 is permanentReis DuelarFiance to Beowulf Cadmus, Reis was inadvertently transformed into a dragon by a curse cast by a jealous Celebrant Bremondt. As a side effect she lost her memory and, confused and disoriented, she began to wander Ivalice. Her travels eventually led her to the Gollund Coal Mine where she took up residence. With rumors spreading of the mine's holy dragon infestation, Ramza and Beowulf arrive just in time to rescue Reis from the Archaeodaemon Syneugh.Beowulf is determined to free Reis from her curse and together with Ramza, manages to acquire the Cancer Zodiac Stone. Through the stone's magic she is restored to her original human form and, indebted to Ramza for his aid, she and Beowulf agree to stay with the group to lend their aid whenever possible.Holy DragonAs a Holy Dragon, Reis has incredibly high health, mobility, and attack power. Also, unlike other dragons, she has access to breath attacks belonging to all three primary elemental schools.Move/Jump Rate: 5/3Evade Rate: 5%Active Stats: Phys - A; Mag - A; HP - B; MP - D; Spd - BBreath (monster skill)NameDescriptionRangeAreaDelayIce BreathMagic attack that deals Ice damage21NowFire BreathMagic attack that deals Fire damage21NowThunder BreathMagic attack that deals Lightning damage21NowDragonkinReis retains her incredible draconic strength and powers even after returning to human form. Her inability to utilize standard equipment is offset by her incredibly high stat growth. This allows her to quickly outshine the other characters when she switches to different jobs.Weapons: BagsArmor: Hair Adornments, Minerva BustierAccessories: Armlets, Lip Rouge, Perfume, RingsMove/Jump Rate: 3/3Evade Rate: 7%Active Stats: Phys - B; Mag - C; HP - B; MP - B; Spd - AGrowth Rate: Phys - A; Mag - A; HP - A; MP - B; Spd - DInnate Abilities: Beastmaster, Dual Wield, TameDragon (job skill)NameDescriptionRangeAreaDelayJPIce BreathMagic attack that deals Ice damage21Now0Fire BreathMagic attack that deals Fire damage21Now0Thunder BreathMagic attack that deals Lightning damage21Now0Dragon's CharmTarget dragon or hydra becomes a Guest that joins the party after battle21Now300Dragon's GiftRestores HP to and removes Berserk, Blind, Confuse, Disable, Immobilize, Oil, Silence, Sleep, Stop, Toad from target dragon or hydra, costs HP to use21Now300Dragon's MightIncreases target dragon or hydra's Bravery by 5, and physical attack, magical attack, and speed by 2 until the end of battle*21Now400Dragon's SpeedGrants full CT gauge to target dragon or hydra21Now400Holy BreathMagic attack that deals Holy damage, strikes random tiles 1-10 times43Now900*For every 4 points of Bravery gained, 1 is permanentZodiac SystemUnique to Final Fantasy Tactics is its implementation of Zodiac signs as a gameplay mechanic. Every character in the game has a Zodiac sign attributed to them, and this affects their ability to interact with other units on the battlefield. A character's Zodiac sign is often critical in determining the amount of damage an attack will cause, the likelihood of success of certain abilities (such as Steal or Time Magicks), and their susceptibility to attacks from other units. Taking Zodiac signs into account is often a crucial aspect of battle in Final Fantasy Tactics, to ensure that maximum damage is dealt to a threat without endangering any weak units unnecessarily.StoryThe game is a refreshing break from other RPGs of this era, as the storyline takes a fairly mature turn, although the original version of the game was said to be fairly confusing due to translation issues. Final Fantasy Tactics takes place in the fictional kingdom of Ivalice, which is no stranger to war. The game follows Ramza Beoulve, a young man that is part of a royal bloodline. He shortly finds himself stuck in a family feud after his father's death, and the throne of the kingdom is at stake.At the center of this plot is not only Ramza, but his childhood friend Delita Hyral. While Ramza was born illegitimately, he was brought up by his noble father. In contrast, Delita and his sister Teta were both lowborn. Despite their differences, Ramza and Delita view each other as equals and remain close due to their outlook on friendship. Things become more complicated, however, as Delita is cast out by the Beoulves, and in response takes his own path, which separates the two friends.SettingThe PSP version features animated cutscenes.The story takes place in the fictional kingdom of Ivalice, located in a peninsula surrounded by sea on the north, west and south, with a headland south of the landmass. Its geography features ranging landscapes, from plains to mountain ranges to deserts and forests. Ivalice is heavily populated by human beings; though, intelligent monsters are sporadically spread throughout. Even though magic is predominant in the land, ruins and artifacts indicate that past populaces had relied on machinery such as airships and robots.Ivalice is a kingdom of seven territories, united under a monarch. Ivalice's neighbors are the kingdom of Ordalia in the east and Romanda, a military nation to the north. While the three nations share common royal bloodlines, major wars have taken place between them. An influential religious institution known as the Murond Glabados Church heads the dominant faith, centering around a religious figure known as Saint Ajora.The story takes place after Ivalice ended its war with the two nations in what is known as the Fifty Years War, and is facing economic problems and political strife. Adding to its problems is the recent death of the king, whose heir is only an infant. A regent is needed to rule in place of the prince, and the kingdom is split between Prince Goltana, represented by the Black Lion, and Prince Larg, symbolized by the White Lion. The conflict leads to what is known in the game as the Lion War. Behind this backdrop is a revelation by the game's fictional historian Alazlam J. Durai, who seeks to reveal the story of an unknown character whose role in the Lion War was major but was covered up by the kingdom's church.The setting is based around this character, named by default as Ramza, and revolves around his early life and the future conflicts he faced while the events that changed the kingdom unfold.CharactersRamza BeoulveCentral to the plot of the game are two main characters, Ramza Beoulve and Delita Hyral. The two characters were childhood friends even though both were born of differing social classes. (Ramza as a noble / Delita as a commoner) Both disregarded this fact and grew up together believing in justice and honor as taught by Ramza's father Balbanes. As the story progressed, the two characters faced many conflicts that changed their viewpoints on life. Delita sought to manipulate the upper class to achieve his dreams; while, Ramza believed in justice and honor regardless of name and class.The game's plot is portrayed through the eyes of Ramza Beoulve (main player character). His exploits in the war introduced him to a number of characters with their own roles and agenda concerning the war and the fictional world Ivalice. The most prominent factions at the beginning of the story are those of Prince Goltana and Prince Larg. Both are nobles that sought to obtain control of the throne by being the guardian to the monarch's young heir and were thus engaged in a war. The story progresses to include characters from the Murond Glabados Church, which have been controlling Ivalice silently and engineering the war in question.Players are able to recruit generic player characters from towns and customize them using the job system of the Final Fantasy series. Several battles feature friendly A.I. controlled special "Guest" characters which may be recruited depending on the progression of the story. The special characters normally have a unique class initially assigned, but they can still can be customized into the generic classes. Aside from main playable characters, the developers have also incorporated cameo roles from other Squaresoft games. The characters were designed by Akihiko Yoshida, who was also in charge of the illustration and character designs of games such as Tactics Ogre, Final Fantasy Tactics Advance, Final Fantasy XII, and Vagrant Story.SoundtrackThe soundtrack to Final Fantasy Tactics was composed by Hitoshi Sakimoto and Masaharu Iwata. It was released in Japan on June 21, 1997.FINAL FANTASY TACTICS Original Sound TrackFINAL FANTASY TACTICS Original Sound TrackTotal length: 151:06Disc 1:Brand Logo, Title Back 1:09Backborn Story 1:34P.R. Movie 0:47Unit Introductions 3:50Player Creation 1:45Prologue Movie 2:52Chapel 1:00Enemy Attack 0:59Trisection 2:37Cadets 1:57Attack Team 0:48Unavoidable Battle 1:45Mission Complete 0:24Hero's Theme 1:12A Chapel 2:33Meeting with Algus 2:03World Map 0:53Shop 0:52Soldier Office 1:03Pelt, Bone, and Meat Trader 0:56Formation Screen 0:57Brave Story 1:18Pub 1:01Data Screen 0:57Desert Land 2:51Alma's Theme 1:12Suspicious Atmosphere 1:53Decisive Battle 2:22Cry of Pain 0:55Remnants 3:05Anxiety before the Battle 2:02Tension 1 2:41Game Over 0:21Tutorial 2:10Random Waltz 1:52Ovelia's Theme 2:41Apoplexy 4:10Zalbag, the Holy Knight 2:03Run Past Through the Plain 1:58Strategy 2:42Delita's Theme 1:42Back Fire 3:01Disc 2Memories 1:45Dycedarg's Theme 1:27Antipyretic 3:40Saint Ajora's Theme 2:51Bloody Excrement 2:46And I Ran Away 0:28Espionage 2:25Advent 3:20Ovelia's Anxiety 3:41Under the Stars 3:14Battle on the Bridge 3:30The Cardinal's Anger 2:41In Pursuit 2:33Shock, Despair 2:19Saint Ajora's Theme Deluxe 1:10Cry of Pain 2:40Requiem 3:13Terror 1 2:08The Pervert 3:53Antidote 3:09Thunder God Cid's Theme 1:52Treasure 2:47Night Attack 2:49Terror 2 2:02Ultema, the Nice Body 2:17Ultema, the Perfect Body 3:26Final Battle Fanfare 0:17Epilogue Movie 1:36Staff Credits 5:38ReceptionIGN awarded the game the Editor's Choice Award on 1998, praising the in-game graphics as "amazing" and the battle environments with its extra details as being "extremely well designed". Gamespot has named Final Fantasy Tactics as one of its Greatest Games of All Timethe first Final Fantasy game to be so honored. However, its legacy remains fairly obscure compared to Final Fantasy VII, also released for the PlayStation that year. The game still entered many "best games of all time" lists, receiving 84th place in the "Top 100 Favorite Games of All Time" poll by Japanese magazine Famitsu during March 2006, 19th in a 2005 list by GameFAQs users, 45th in Game Informer's list, 43rd in Electronic Gaming Monthly's, and 38th in IGN's.The War of the LionsIn 2007, a port of Final Fantasy Tactics was released for Sony's PlayStation Portable system. The port, entitled Final Fantasy Tactics: The War of the Lions, includes a number of version-specific features added during the porting process. These include:A completely new translation featuring several discontinued English words, intended to add to the game's Medieval feel.New cinematic cut-scenes, complete with voice acting.New cameo characters including Final Fantasy XII's Balthier and Luso from Final Fantasy Tactics A2: Grimoire of the Rift.New side quests, including a dungeon known as Midlight's Deep.Two additional jobs; Dark Knight and Onion Knight.Added multiplayer components, allowing players to team up in new "Rendezvous" co-op missions or take on each other in "Melee" mode.Many JP costs of skills were tweaked - making them more expensive to unlock16:9 Display</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16942">Tactics Ogre: Let Us Cling Together</game><game id="7281">Astonishia Story</game><game id="19905">Vandal Hearts</game><game id="25732">Tenchi Muyou! Game-Hen</game><game id="24212">Growlanser</game><game id="3368">Summon Night 2</game><game id="18876">Summon Night</game><game id="25844">Vandal Hearts: Flames of Judgment</game><game id="7259">Arc the Lad</game><game id="10652">Arc the Lad II</game><game id="15251">Dark Wizard</game><game id="9532">Disgaea: Afternoon of Darkness</game><game id="7522">La Pucelle: Tactics</game><game id="20431">Saiyuki: Journey West</game><game id="27994">Final Fantasy Tactics: The War of the Lions</game><game id="32907">Grotesque Tactics: Evil Heroes</game><game id="33443">Bomberman Wars</game><game id="14295">Wachenrder</game><game id="27113">Record of Agarest War</game><game id="34768">Age of Fear: The Undead King</game><game id="34522">Shin Megami Tensei: Devil Survivor 2</game><game id="32143">Tactics Ogre: Let Us Cling Together</game><game id="36871">Telepath RPG: Servants of God</game><game id="35687">Rainbow Moon</game><game id="37291">Hero Academy</game><game id="37629">The Banner Saga</game><game id="40157">Disgaea D2: A Brighter Darkness</game><game id="36394">Fire Emblem: Awakening</game><game id="41807">Devil Survivor 2: Break Record</game><game id="42775">Massive Chalice</game><game id="37959">Project X Zone</game><game id="43805">Champs: Battlegrounds</game><game id="36104">Card Hunter</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1814645-box_fft.png</image></root>