<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19937</id><name>Wallace &amp; Gromit Fun Pack</name><description>The Wallace  Gromit Fun Pack is divided into two seperate sections:The Crackin' Compendium, which contains the games and a film clip browser. The Customise-O-Matic, which allows the desktop to be customised (sounds for system events, icons, screensavers and wallpapers).  The Crackin' Compendium"Cracking toast, Gromit!"Home PageFrom the home page, each of the four activities, signified by paintings hanging on the kitchen wall, are selected by being shot with the porridge gun. Animated help and a text summary is available from the gnome, and to quit or watch the credits, the appropriate piece of toast is selected.The Quiz-O-MaticThis is a multiple choice quiz for 1 to 4 players comprising questions based on the Wallace  Gromit films. Before each quiz, a gadget (either the porridge gun, Techno-Trousers, Wallace's dresser or the Knit-O-Matic) comprising between 5 and 12 pieces. A machine part is awarded each time a player answers a question correctly. The first player to complete their gadget is the winner.A rotating disc in the top left-hand corner of the screen indicates which film each question relates to:Rocket - A Grand Day Out Techno-Trousers - The Wrong Trousers Balls of Wool - A Close Shave Wallace and Gromit portrait - General knowledge  Answers are selected by clicking one of the buttons at the bottom of the screen - A, B, C or D. To pass on a question, a lever on the right of the screen can be pulled for another question, however this functionality can only be exploited once by each player over the course of a single quiz. A meter at the top of the screen shows how much time is left to answer the question. If not answered in time or answered incorrectly, play moves on to the next player. The game can be paused via the space bar, however only between questionsThe Bungee Game"The bounce has gone from his bungee."The object of this game is to score points by getting Gromit to clean as many windows as possible whilst the porridge gun covers them with soap suds.The left and right arrow keys are used to move Gromit horizontally between rows of windows. He can only be moved when he is at the top of his bounce. The enter key is used to wipe away the suds with his sponge, but this can only be done on his way down, one window at a time.Gromit must rinse his sponge in the bucket at the bottom of the screen after every five wipes, however there is a mouse underneath who occasionally moves it out of reach. Extra points can be scored by rescuing Shaun the sheep as he walks by. Preston, an evil "cyberdog" and main antagonist from A Close Shave, is also on the prowl throughout the building and can appear at any of the clean windows. Gromit starts with three lives, represented by the cans at the bottom left-hand corner of the screen. A life is lost whenever all the windows become covered in suds, or if Preston grabs Gromit on his way down. Two bonus lives are awarded at 5,000 and 10,000 points respectively.The Great Train Game"Leave him to me, I'll get the bounder!"The object of the Great Train Game is to score points by filling in the gaps in the railway track, enabling Gromit to cross the kitchen floor. There are twenty levels, all named after different cheeses, increasing in difficulty. Your score depends on the number of track pieces used and the number of attempts were needed for each level.Each of the six different track pieces are selected from the box at the bottom of the screen, and then placed by clicking on the screen in the desired position. Once a piece has been selected, it can be used as many times as the player wishes.Gromit has five lives for each level. If a piece of track hasn't been placed in time and he comes to a gap in the track, the train will crash and he will lose a life. To make things more difficult, Feathers McGraw can change the direction of some existing pieces on the map by pulling his lever.The Daily Lamp-PostThe Daily Lamp-Post is a newspaper which contains 17 scenes from the first three Wallace  Gromit films. Clips are selected by clicking on headlines in the contents list or scrolling through the individual pages, and then again on the photographs. System RequirementsThe Wallace  Gromit Fun Pack required the following for optimal performance:486 Multimedia PC with 50Mhz processor and 8MB of RAM Double speed CD-ROM drive 16 bit (64k) colour display set to 640 x 480 SoundBlaster 16 bit audio card Suitable loudspeakers or headphones Mouse or other pointing device Windows 3.1, 3.11 or Windows 95 26MB of available hard disk space  </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="14">Trivia/Board Game</genre><genre id="15">Compilation</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/495/870396-1209493919_00.jpg</image></root>