<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1994</id><name>Chip 'N Dale: Rescue Rangers</name><description>OverviewThe lab.    Chip 'N Dale: Rescue Rangers is one of many successful collaborations between    Disney and    Capcom. It is the video game adaptation of the popular Disney cartoon by the same name.Much like the cartoon, the game revolves around   Chip,  Dale, and their companions in the Rescue Rangers, Monterey "Monty" Jack, the female mechanic Gadget Hackwrench, and the housefly Zipper. The game takes you through several varied locations on your quest to stop the evil, suit-wearing feline " Fat Cat". Much like other Capcom NES games the game had a very memorable soundtrack with catchy tunes that drove the gameplay forward.Gameplay / MechanicsStage 1, Neighborhood. Chip has picked up an apple.The game is a basic platformer much in the same vein as other Capcom action/platforming games like    Mega Man or    Duck Tales. The game utilizes the diminutive size of the characters to create large environments. Before your quest to stop Fat Cat and rescue Gadget is over you will see the garden stage, the kitchen stage, the casino, the factory, a huge tree and many more. You select them from a    Bionic Commando like map and all will have you jumping on huge things in the environment like books, cash registers or trashcans. The game features both single player or 2 player Co-op. You collect Flower "cards" that will often require some searching under boxes to find them all.The game also draws on the success of    Super Mario Bros 2, specifically the mechanic of picking up and throwing stuff. The same mechanic is in Rescue Rangers where you can pick up objects like    apples (or the small boxes that are always scattered around the levels) and throw them at the enemy to stun or knock them out. You can also throw your Co-op partner. Similar to    New Super Mario Bros Wii, this mechanic is more often humorously used for competition than cooperation, throwing your partner into enemies or off cliffs. Zipper the bee acts as your    invincibility star. On the rare occasion when you find him, you can mow down everything in your path.The game includes many big and memorable    bosses and defeating them often includes picking up objects and throwing them at their    weak spots . The final boss fight pits the players against Fat Cat himself, where Chip and Dale must dodge the remains being flicked from a cigar while throwing a ball at Fat Cat's face.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9441">Tiny Toon Adventures: Buster Busts Loose!</game><game id="9412">QuackShot starring Donald Duck</game><game id="6710">World of Illusion starring Mickey Mouse and Donald Duck</game><game id="9513">Castle of Illusion starring Mickey Mouse</game><game id="3376">Inspector Gadget</game><game id="14307">Monster in My Pocket</game><game id="8958">Disney's The Little Mermaid</game><game id="1813">Bee 52</game><game id="20169">Darkwing Duck</game><game id="19944">Disney's Aladdin</game><game id="20975">Mega Man 9</game><game id="22059">Mickey's Dangerous Chase</game><game id="1777">Disney's TaleSpin</game><game id="20020">The New Zealand Story</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2361216-nes_chipndalerescuerangers.jpg</image></root>