<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19981</id><name>NASCAR Legends</name><description>NSCAR Legends is not your every day NASCAR game, well not exactly. This game focuses on the 1970 NASCAR Grand National Season instead of the current NASCAR schedule and driver line up.MODES:This is about the only area of the game that will look like every other NASCAR game with Single Player, Multi Player, and Championship Season options.DRIVERS:Here is were the game shows its unique side. Instead of piloting the #24 pretending to be Jeff Gordon, or even the #3 as Dale Earnhard, you will be piloting the #43 as Richard Petty or the #22 as Bobby Allison. Also, do not expect to be driving the Car Of Tomorrow, a Toyota or a Chevrolet instead hop behind the wheel of a Mercury, Dodge, Ford or Plymouth.  #06 Neil Castles  #3 Junior Johnson  #4 John Sears  #6 Buddy Baker  #8 Ralph Earnhardt  #11 A.J. Foyt  #17 David Pearson  #21 Cale Yarborough  #22 Bobby Allison  #24 Cecil Gordon  #27 Donnie Allison  #30 Dave Marcis  #32 Dick Brooks  #34 Wendell Scott  #40 Pete Hamilton  #42 Lee Petty  #43 Richard Petty  #48 James Hylton  #55 Tiny Lund  #64 Elmo Langley  #67 A.J. Foyt  #71 Bobby Isaac  #72 Benny Parsons  #88 Darrell Waltrip  #98 LeeRoy Yarbrough  #99 Charlie Glotzbach TRACKS:Unless you are a NASCAR super fan, or just live in one of these areas, you probably don't recognize some of these tracks as 5 of them have been abandoned and some have even been destroyed altogether.  Talledega Motor Speedway  Atlanta Motor Raceway  Bristol Motor Speedway  Bowman-Gray Stadium  Lowe's Motor Speedway  Darlington Raceway  Greenville-Pickens Speedway  North Wilkesboro Speedway  Ontario Motor Speedway  Richmond Fairgrounds  Riverside International Raceway  Texas World Speedway  Thompson International Speedway</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9493/325597-nascar_legends_box_art.jpg</image></root>