<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20131</id><name>Otogi: Myth of Demons</name><description>OverviewOtogi: Myth of Demons is a             hack and slash action game released in 2003 exclusively for the   Xbox, the game was developed by            From Software and published by           SEGA.RaikohThe game takes place in feudal          Japan and has players take up the role of         Raikoh Minamoto, an undead warrior and member of the emperor's elite assassins who must stop a ferocious demonic army that has been unleashed upon the Earth.After receiving a mission to kill his own father Raikoh disgraces himself by refusing to complete the task, instead he steals his clan's ancestral sword and flees the capital city of Kyoto.Before he gets beyond the city's walls the seal that separates the human and demon worlds is broken and Kyoto is completely decimated by wave after wave of demons. Raikoh barely survives the resulting destruction and is plunged in to the netherworld, there the princess saves him and holds him in a state between life and death.In return for saving the world from the clutches of the demon hordes she will give to him a new body and allow him to reclaim his honor as an assassin.  Gameplay Otogi is a        hack-and-slash game with a number of elements that were noteworthy for its release in 2003. Many of the game's stages contained structures that could be destroyed by the player, and it was not uncommon to see an entire area leveled after a heated fight. Raikoh's       sword also had some unique properties in that its weight could be used to lift the player off the floor. By continuously using combos, Raikoh could essentially "fly" around an area to reach hidden areas or to avoid danger on ground level. Many players and critics have likened the gameplay to Sega's      Shinobi revival on     PS2; Raikoh has a similar pace and can dash through the air (leaving a ghostly trail behind) much like that game.Other Info1 playerIn-game Dolby Digital</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6602">Ninja Gaiden Black</game><game id="6681">Devil May Cry 4</game><game id="2838">Bujingai: The Forsaken City</game><game id="20553">Ninja Gaiden II</game><game id="2136">Onimusha: Dawn of Dreams</game><game id="6959">God of War</game><game id="5581">No More Heroes</game><game id="23661">Ninja Blade</game><game id="22637">Shinobi</game><game id="22069">Nightshade</game><game id="39749">Ninja Gaiden 3: Razor's Edge</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2243872-box_otogi.png</image></root>