<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20169</id><name>Darkwing Duck</name><description>Overview / Releases The forestDarkwing Duck is another one of the very well made and very successful collaborations between  Disney and  Capcom ( Duck Tales,  Rescue Rangers,  Aladdin and more..) that had a golden era in the early to mid 90´s. Its based of the Disney cartoon with the same name and it feautures St.Canards dark superhero  Darkwing Duck or Drake Mallard as his name is when its still daylight. The setting is pretty dark and can be compared to that of  Batman but with alot of satire and humor thrown in.  Darkwing Duck was inspired by a couple of specific  Duck Tales episodes and both  Launchpad McQuack and Gizmo Duck appears in both series, the first one being a returning character in Duck Tales. A total of three seasons were made of the cartoon series with a total of 91 episodes. Darkwing was a duck that really liked danger and darkness in a kind of tongue in cheek way and he often liked to say things like "Lets get dangerous" or "It´s gonna get scary big time!". The first release of the game was for the  NES in 1992 and it was followed up by a Game Boy release a year later, in 1993. Gameplay / Mechanics I am Darkwing Duck!The game plays pretty much like Capcoms classic super hit series  Mega Man. Its an  action  platformer for the NES where you can  jump and  shoot (or both at the same time).  Enemies are placed out in many different forms and shapes and often have patterns that will take away from your health.  Platforming can often be very challenging and if you die you have to start back at the beginning of the  stage again. Many would claim that Darkwing is almost a direct copy of Mega Man with many stages having similar  themes and similar graphical design when compared to Mega Man or Mega Man 2 stages. At the end of every stage a  boss from the cartoon awaits wich often takes some  figuring out before killing. The stages are selected from a overview  map of the city and they range from the heart of town to the outskirts.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8958">Disney's The Little Mermaid</game><game id="19944">Disney's Aladdin</game><game id="17124">Disney's Hercules: Action Game</game><game id="1994">Chip 'N Dale: Rescue Rangers</game><game id="16592">Disney's Chip 'N Dale Rescue Rangers 2</game><game id="2554">Chip 'N Dale Rescue Rangers: The Adventure in Nimnul's Castle</game><game id="15799">DuckTales</game><game id="14532">DuckTales 2</game><game id="5251">Mega Man</game><game id="14026">Mega Man 2</game><game id="4518">Mega Man 3</game><game id="7860">Bionic Commando</game><game id="20483">Bionic Commando Rearmed</game><game id="20975">Mega Man 9</game><game id="16460">Tiny Toon Adventures</game><game id="1777">Disney's TaleSpin</game><game id="25451">Cid the Dummy</game><game id="30993">Mega Man</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2361637-nes_darkwingduck.jpg</image></root>