<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20217</id><name>Bomberman Generation</name><description>Single-Player Mode The single-player game in Bomberman Generation follows in the footsteps of the mildly successful N64 games, while throwing in enough new ideas to significantly improve upon the limited formula.  There are five worlds for Bomberman to explore, each with levels creatively labeled 1-1, 1-2, and so on.  At the end of each level, Bomberman faces a relatively simple mini-boss, and twice per world Bomberman encounters a large boss.  These bosses require some strategy to beat, and often necessitate a trial-and-error system to find out how to hurt them.  Bomberman starts out with the ability to kick and throw bombs, and begins by only having access to one bomb, with a limited blast.  Various pick-ups throughout the levels increase the number of bombs Bomberman can use, as well as increase his speed, and increase the blast radius of his bombs.  Early on in the game, Bomberman learns how to pick up a bomb and charge it to create a super bomb, which often is used in puzzles, and for defeating bosses.  The basic formula of the levels is one quite familiar to gamers – progress through by defeating enemies, pushing switches (with bombs of course), and solving straightforward puzzles.  Many of the puzzles are quite simple – In one early level, the player must use a super bomb to knock a boulder off of a tower, and on top of a door-opening switch.  There are numerous side-paths that contain power-ups – enough to satisfy any completist gamer.  One important addition is that of different types of bombs – the player can find an element, and fuse it with a standard bomb to create elemental bombs.  Certain bombs work better against different bosses and enemies, and also have special effects – water bombs can explode even while under water, and also put out fires that block your way.  The single-player mode of Bomberman Generation will take 5-8 hours for a gamer to complete, depending on how much the player explores, and searches for each and every power-up. The most interesting addition to the single-player experience is the introduction of Charabombs.  Charabombs are Pokemon-esque creatures capable of modifying Bomberman’s powers.  For example, one Charabomb allows Bomberman to throw bombs higher and longer, and another reduces the damage Bomberman receives by half.  Also, Charabombs compete in a battle mini-game.  Interestingly enough, the player does not control the Charabomb during the battle, but instead chooses 3 different strategy pieces beforehand, and these meld to create one overall strategy for the Charabomb during the battle.  One strategy is “Defensive”, while another is “Get Wild”.  The last Charabomb standing, or the one with the most energy after 3 rounds, is the winner, and if your Charabomb wins, you gain the use of the loser.  Throughout the levels, there are power-ups that increase the Charabombs’ stats, and provide one more reason to thoroughly search every level.  The Charabomb part of Bomberman Generation not only adds deeply to the gameplay, but also provides a fun mini-game for gamers. MultiplayerStandard  – The classic Bomberman battle mode.  Relatively untouched gameplay-wise, the only addition is to allow players, when blasted by a bomb, to move to a bomb-turret at the outside of the arena, where they can move around and shoot bombs at the players still competing. Reversi Battle – When a player’s bomb explodes, the floor panels will flip to the color of that player’s Bomberman.  If a player is hit by a bomb blast, they lose half of their panels.  The player who owns the most panels at the end of the game wins. Coin  – Breaking barrels or hitting Bomberman Bandits cause coins to appear.  There are three different types of coins, each with their own value.  When a Bomberman is hit by a blast, he will lose half his coins.  The player with the most coin-points at the end of the game wins. Dodge  – In this game, you cannot use bombs, but you can punch and kick bombs that reign down from the sky.  As time goes by, more bombs drop, and they increase in power.  The last Bomberman standing is the winner. Revenge  – Here, players start out in bomb-turrets outside of the arena, and they gain points by throwing bombs and exterminating the moles within the play field.  The first player to reach the goal score is the winner.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1840751-box_bmangen.png</image></root>