<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20270</id><name>DJMAX Online</name><description>The first project created by Pentavision Entertainment after it's establishment in 2004. The majority of the development team for this title were staff members on AmuseWorld's EZ2DJ arcade series up until it's cancellation. They used their knowledge and experience in rhythm games to fashion one of the first massively multiplayer PC rhythm games available in Korea.Gameplay is your standard fare of falling notes that correspond to keys on your controller (in this case, a standard QWERTY keyboard). When the notes reach a timing line on the lower portion of the screen, the player hits the corresponding key and receives a timing grade from Miss to 100%, as well as an increase in score. While having a relatively balanced learning curve, DJMAX ONLINE followed in EZ2DJs footsteps and contained some of the most difficult songs ever seen in a rhythm game of this style to date.The online servers for DJMAX ONLINE remained active in 3 key regions (Japan, Korea, China) between a time period of 2004-2008. North American players used accounts on the Japanese server to access the game during this time as no official release was ever made outside of asia.Partial SonglistSong NameArtist1st-syncFORTE ESCAPEA.I (Artificial Integrity)FORTE ESCAPEBanana shakeHumming Urban StereoAsk To Wind ~Live Version~Forte EscapeBrave it outGonZoCARMEN TOREADORWavfactoryCherokeexxdbxxDancin' Planetplanet boomEnd of the MoonlightFORTE ESCAPEENEMY STORMCROOVEfuturismForte escapeGRID SYSTEMTsukasaJupiter DrivingxxdbxxLet's go baby3rd CoastMILESElectronic BoutiqueNB RANGER POWERNIENOblivioNESTiRAIN+Jeppet Co, PD CASKERSay my loveJJ GROOVESINESTiSPACE OF SOULM2U</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2951">beatmania</game><game id="8631">GuitarFreaks 3rdMIX &amp; DrumMania 2ndMIX</game><game id="22343">beatmania IIDX 14 GOLD</game><game id="41326">EZ2ON</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/23793/2201952-djmaxfl0.jpg</image></root>