<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20314</id><name>David Crane's A Boy and his Blob: Trouble on Blobolonia</name><description>Overview  David Crane 's A Boy and His Blob: Trouble in Blobolonia is the first of two games starring the titular            Boy (no name given) and his blob,           Blobert.  The Boy is unable to perform many actions on his own; being limited to walking and throwing jellybeans.  When Blobert eats the thrown jellybeans he transforms into various items to assist the Boy in overcoming obstacles. The creator of  A Boy and His Blob was          David Crane;  who also created the  Pitfall series and  Freeway for        Activision.   A Boy and His Blob is one of the earliest games to incorporate the idea of masking loading times; all of the Earth screens and all of the Blobonia screens exist as just two separate chunks of data; the lengthy trip between worlds on Blobert's Root Beer Rocket form hides the game taking the time to dump one planet's data and load up the other's. Jellybean Powers  Blowtorch - Cinnamon Jelly Bean - For burning spiderwebs.  Brick Wall - Ketchup Jelly Bean - No effect. (Blobert will only eat the Ketchup Jelly Bean if he is tricked by the Boy throwing     The boy and his blob in action.     two beans in rapid succession (1 Honey and 1 Ketchup). Otherwise the Ketchup Jelly Bean is used to summon Blobert.)  Bridge - Strawberry Jelly Bean - Used to cross some gaps.  Bubble - Cola Jelly Bean - Used to breathe underwater.  Coconut - Coconut Jelly Bean - Used to scout ahead. (The view follows the Coconut as it rolls.)  Hole - Punch Jelly Bean - Creates a hole which can lead to new sections.  Hummingbird - Honey Jelly Bean - Flying Blobert can follow more quickly.  Jack - Apple Jelly Bean - Raises objects out of the way.  Key - Lime Jelly Bean - Used to unlock doors.  Ladder - Licorice Jelly Bean - Reach new heights.  Rocket - Root Beer Jelly Bean - Transports Boy and Blobert between Earth and Blobolonia.  Trampoline - Tangerine Jelly Bean - Allows jumping.  Umbrella - Vanilla Jelly Bean - Prevents damage both from high falls, and falling objects.  Vitablaster - Orange Jelly Bean - A weapon that launches vitamins at enemies. GameplayBecause of the Boy's limited mobility, the Boy and His Blob games involve more puzzle solving than many of their contemporaries.   LegacyA single sequel,  David Crane's A Boy and His Blob in: The Rescue of Princess Blobette, was released for the     Nintendo Game Boy in 1991. Very little was seen of the game for many years; an    attempted remake of the original for the   Nintendo DS was announced in 2005 but cancelled in 2007. On October 13th 2009 a  more successful remake  was released on the                Nintendo Wii. Improved graphics and hand painted backgrounds were used in this title. </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15110">Little Nemo: The Dream Master</game><game id="23112">The Maw</game><game id="34094">Jelly Boy</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2361184-nes_boyandhisblob.jpg</image></root>