<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20336</id><name>Xenosaga: Episode I - Der Wille zur Macht</name><description>OverviewXenosaga: Episode I - Der Wille zur Macht is an RPG for the PlayStation 2 developed by Monolith Software. Development of the game was spearheaded by Tetsuya Takahashi and other members of the team that had previously developed Xenogears while with Squaresoft. The overarching narrative was meant to connect loosely with the universe of the PS1 title. Der Wille zur Macht was also intended to be the first part of a six-game story arc, but due to internal pressures brought on by publisher Namco that affected the direction of the second episode, the story was ultimately truncated into a trilogy.The subtitle "Der Wille zur Macht," or "The Will to Power," is a reference to a text of the same name written by philosopher Friedrich Nietzsche, as are the subtitles of the subsequent entries in the trilogy.StoryAs the introductory chapter in a multi-game story, the plot of Episode is primarily driven by the introductions of the major players in the narrative and the events meant to drive the series forward. The story is set in the distant future, where humans have colonized deep space and created an interstellar civilization, leaving Earth behind. Humanity is at war with a race of mysterious, antagonistic creatures called the Gnosis. Meanwhile, rival factions struggle for control over a mysterious artifact known as the Zohar; a device rumored to be of immense power. During this conflict, researcher Shion Uzuki is on board a ship transporting a Zohar Emulator; a device created to mimic the true Zohar, but with a far lesser degree of power. Shion is running tests on KOS-MOS, a combat android designed for the express purpose of destroying Gnosis, when the ship comes under attack by the creatures. Shion and fellow researcher Allen Ridgelley manage to escape with KOS-MOS's help and are quickly drawn into a galaxy-wide conspiracy.CombatCombat in Xenosaga.The combat in Xenosaga is very similar to that of its spiritual predecessor Xenogears. The combat is broken up into character combat and mech (Anti-Gnosis Weapon System, or A.G.W.S.) combat. The player characters are able to switch freely between fighting on foot or in an A.G.W.S., and individual characters can be swapped out of combat and replaced with inactive party members on the fly. The battles are turn based and function on an Action Point (AP) system. Characters are assigned a certain amount of AP at the start of each turn which can be used for individual attacks that can be chained together until the AP is depleted. Leftover AP can be stored for the character's next turn to spend on more powerful attacks and techniques. Ether skills, the game's equivalent to a magic system, can also be used.A.G.W.S. can be equipped and used by some but not all party members; of the primary playable characters, only Shion, chaos, and Jr. are able to pilot them. Each unit is unique and fully customizable; the player can arms them with weapons such as swords, machine guns, rifles and beam weapons. During combat, the player must simply select the weapon that they wish to attack with; however, A.W.G.S. cannot chain attacks, nor do they feature any special attacks.SoundtrackDisc OneNo.TitleJapanese titleLength1."Prologue"Prologue4:322."Opening"Opening4:023."Battle"Battle2:594."Battle's End"戦闘終了0:425."Starting Test"起動試験2:196."Rising Emotions"想いで3:147."Gnosis"Gnosis4:228."Awakening"覚醒2:239."Shion's Crisis"シオンの危機1:5410."Battling KOS-MOS"戦闘するKOS-MOS3:1511."Sorrow"哀しみ3:4312."Life or Death"Life or Death3:1513."Game Over"Game Over0:4214."Margulis"Margulis4:2415."Breaking Space Ship Pursuit"追われる宇宙艇3:3316."Relief"Relief2:4317."Daily"日常1:5518."U.M.N.MODE"U.M.N. MODE2:3919."Durandal"Durandal2:3220."Invasion Inside an Enemy Ship"敵艇内への侵攻0:3921."U-TIC System"U-TIC機関2:4522."Closed Minded Girl"心を閉ざした少女2:1323."Kookai Foundation"Kookai Foundation1:5524."Shion ~Past Memory~"Shion 〜過去の記憶〜1:11Disc TwoNo.TitleJapanese titleLength1."Ormus"Ormus2:272."Nephilim"Nephilim2:313."Warmth"温もり1:424."Insecurity"不安4:085."The Resurrection"The Ressurection1:546."Beach of Nothingness"虚無の浜辺2:287."Green Sleeves"Green Sleeves2:258."Zarathustra"Zarathustra3:069."KOS-MOS"KOS-MOS2:2710."Panic"Panic2:2111."Song of Nephilim"Song of Nephilim1:0412."The Miracle"The Miracle1:5213."Inner Space"Inner Space1:4714."Albedo"Albedo3:4515."Omega"Ω4:0716."Proto Merkabah"Proto Merkabah5:2517."Last Battle"Last Battle5:0518."Pain"Pain5:3619."Escape"Escape2:3020."Kokoro (Heart)"Kokoro5:3521."Shion ~Emotion~"Shion 〜想い〜1:19Disc ThreeNo.TitleJapanese titleLength1."Shion ~Memories of the Past~"Shion ～過去の記憶～1:152."Prologue"Prologue4:353."Gnosis"Gnosis4:254."U-TIC Facility"U-TIC機関2:495."The Girl Who Closed Her Heart"心を閉ざした少女2:156."Ormus"Ormus2:297."Nephilim"Nephilim2:338."Warmth New Recording"温もり (new recording)2:019."The Resurrection"The Resurrection1:5310."Beach of the Void New Recording"虚無の浜辺 (new recording)2:3511."Green Sleeves New Recording"Green Sleeves (new recording)2:2712."KOS-MOS"KOS-MOS2:2813."The Miracle"The Miracle1:5314."Zarathustra"Zarathustra3:0515."Ω"Ω4:0816."Escape"Escape2:3317."Pain"Pain5:3918."Kokoro"Kokoro5:3719."Shion ~Emotion~"Shion ～想い～1:2420."World to be Born"World to be Born3:1921."Pain -piano version- New Recording"Pain -Piano Version- (new recording)2:46Disc FourNo.TitleJapanese titleLength1."Opening"Opening4:022."Battle"Battle2:593."Battle's End"戦闘終了0:424."Starting Examination"起動試験2:225."Thoughts"想いで3:196."Awakening"覚醒2:217."Shion's Crisis"シオンの危機1:548."Fighting KOS-MOS"戦闘するKOS-MOS3:199."Sadness"哀しみ3:5410."Life or Death"Life or Death3:1611."Game Over"Game Over0:4212."Margulis"Margulis4:2913."Followed Space Shuttle"追われる宇宙艇3:4314."Relief"Relief2:4715."Everyday"日常1:5416."U.M.N. MODE"U.M.N.Mode2:3917."Durandal"Durandal2:3318."Invasion Inside an Enemy Ship"敵艦内への侵攻0:4119."Kookai Foundation"Kookai Foundation1:5820."Anxiety"不安4:0821."Panic"Panic2:2722."Song of Nephilim"Song of Nephilim1:0623."Inner Space"Inner Space1:4724."Albedo"Albedo3:5025."Proto Merkabah"Proto Merkabah5:3026."Last Battle"Last Battle5:04</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18304">Xenogears</game><game id="259">Grandia III</game><game id="10129">Grandia II</game><game id="17659">Grandia</game><game id="13560">Mega Man X: Command Mission</game><game id="16716">Legend of Legaia</game><game id="12099">Star Ocean: Till the End of Time</game><game id="4492">Phantasy Star II</game><game id="7400">Phantasy Star</game><game id="13493">Phantasy Star IV: The End of the Millennium</game><game id="18253">Phantasy Star III: Generations of Doom</game><game id="7197">Dragon Quest V: Hand of the Heavenly Bride</game><game id="3960">Shadow Hearts</game><game id="20128">Wild Arms Alter Code: F</game><game id="4822">Wild Arms 3</game><game id="36273">Persona 4 Golden</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2092603-box_xenosaga1.png</image></root>