<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20449</id><name>Mortal Kombat vs. DC Universe</name><description>OverviewOfficially released on November 16, 2008 in North America, Mortal Kombat vs. DC Universe is a significant departure for                               Midway's long-running                               Mortal Kombat series. The game is a crossover between a selection of                               Mortal Kombat fighters and characters from the world of                               DC Comics. The game initially announced in April 2008 at Midway's annual press event in Las Vegas.                               Ed Boon, the co-creator of the Mortal Kombat series, was on-hand to give the initial details and show a brief teaser trailer. At the time of the game's announcement, only four characters were confirmed as appearing in the game.                        Scorpion and                        Sub-Zero represented the game's Mortal Kombat side.                        Superman and                        Batman were the first two confirmed DC characters. Since that time, the full roster was released via press releases and updating showings of the game at trade shows for both the game and the comic industries. The game's backgrounds cover a variety of famous MK and DC locations. The story that justifies the tying together of these two groups involves the merging of universes. The chaos that ensues with the DC version of Earth begins coming together with MK's Earthrealm serves as the backdrop for the game. The fighters become infected with "kombat rage," a state in which the urge to battle overtakes their entire body. This is what the game uses to justify situations where "good" characters fight amongst themselves. This is the first Mortal Kombat game developed for the Xbox 360 and PlayStation 3 and it uses  Unreal Engine 3, also a first for the MK series. Along with the new engine, the game's fighting has been redesigned and moves away from the multiple unarmed and weapon-based fighting styles found in the previous PS2/Xbox/GCN games. Due to the game's crossover with DC Comics and the wider potential audience that brings, Mortal Kombat vs. DC Universe was built with an ESRB T (Teen) rating in mind. This means that the grisly fatalities that have become something of a calling card for the MK series are not present in MK vs. DC. However, the game still has finishing moves. Midway has stated that it intended to push this game right up to the line that separates the ESRB's T rating from its M for Mature rating. The European release of the game shows slightly more violence due to the availability of a "15" rating, as opposed to the implied age of 13 in the US. Most notably, the Joker's fatality is censored in the US release.  GameplayMortal Kombat vs. DC Universe is primarily a 2D fighting game. Though players can   side step, the side step is too slight to be very useful up close, maintaining most of the usefulness of projectile attacks. The game places four numbered attack buttons on the face of the controller. On the shoulders is a block button, a sidestep button, a regular throw, and a button to initiate "Klose Kombat" sequences. Unlike the past 2D MK games, MK vs. DC's fighters have varied normal moves as opposed to assigning nearly identical normal attacks to each fighter. Special moves are performed by entering specific motions and button presses on the controller. Generally speaking, the top two attack buttons are primarily used for punches while the bottom two buttons are usually kicks. This varies by character and by combo. This varies from the classic Mortal Kombat setup, which put high and low punches on the left side of the controls and kicks on the right. The game's combo system retains many of the same concepts that MK was founded on with plenty of juggle-friendly moves. Up close, some normal attacks can be strung together into combos and like   Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3, fighters can begin combos from a jumping punch. Jumping punches and kicks will turn around the face foes who end up behind the fighter when the attack button is pressed. Mid-Fight Minigames There are three different in-game systems that take the players out of the standard fighting mechanics and bring them into brief, counter-based minigames. Klose Kombat is a new fight mode that is initiated by pressing the KK button from within throw range. If it connects, the camera zooms up and the action slows a bit. The attacking player can hit any of the face buttons to perform an attack. The defending player attempts to guess which button the attacker will press. If the defender guesses correctly, the Klose Kombat mode is broken. If not, the attacker can attempt another move. This concept also applies to Freefall Kombat, which works while players fall from one level of a stage to the next. In this situation, if the defending player successfully guesses the button press, the attack is countered and the roles switch. After a few successful hits, the player in control can press a button to bust out a special mid-air attack that does extra damage and sends the victim crashing to the ground below. The third and final in-fight system is Test Your Might, which is a concept that originated as a bonus round in the original   Mortal Kombat. Here, however, it's used to give players something to fight over while crashing through buildings horizontally on supported stages. This is basic   button mashing, with the attacking player attempting to maximize the damage done while moving to the next part of the stage. The defender also mashes in an attempt to reduce damage. Fatalities With the exception of story mode, finishing moves can be performed by the winner of a fight during a brief window before the match ends. To help differentiate between the "good" DC characters that wouldn't normally kill their opponents, some characters have "heroic brutalities" instead of fatalities. The end result is roughly the same, as both types of finishers trigger flashy animations that result in the definitive defeat of the enemy. Each character has two finishing moves.  RosterCounting the two unlockable characters that are attained by completing  each side of the story mode, there are 22 characters in the game, 11 per  side. The Mortal Kombat side of the roster has been described as a  "greatest hits" roster, consisting entirely of characters who debuted in  Mortal Kombat or   Mortal Kombat II. The DC side of the roster  pulls from a few different places, including obvious choices like  Superman, Batman, and Wonder Woman, as well as less-popular characters  like Deathstroke and                        Captain Marvel. Midway planned to release Quan Chi and Harley Quinn as DLC characters but   those plans were scrapped.  Here is the official roster for both sides:    Mortal KombatDC Universe  Baraka  Jax  Kano  Kitana  Liu Kang  Raiden  Scorpion  Shang Tsung  Shao Kahn  Sonya Blade  Sub-Zero  Batman   Captain Marvel     Catwoman     Darkseid     Deathstroke     The Flash     Green Lantern     The Joker     Lex Luthor     Superman     Wonder Woman     Xbox 360/PS3 Game InstallationMortal Kombat vs. DC Universe requires 6.4GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD.  The Install file for the PS3 measures in at 1.02GB.</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20728">Tatsunoko vs. Capcom: Ultimate All Stars</game><game id="2612">Marvel vs. Capcom 2: New Age of Heroes</game><game id="9309">Marvel Super Heroes Vs. Street Fighter</game><game id="19043">Fighters Megamix</game><game id="16793">Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors</game><game id="11065">Shaman King: Power of Spirit</game><game id="22953">Ultimate Fighter</game><game id="18251">Deadly Arts</game><game id="19738">Bloody Roar</game><game id="10872">Wu-Tang: Shaolin Style</game><game id="23833">Tekken 6: Bloodline Rebellion</game><game id="16349">Justice League Task Force</game><game id="243">Street Fighter II: The World Warrior</game><game id="8605">Marvel vs. Capcom: Clash of Super Heroes</game><game id="10476">War Gods</game><game id="12411">Soulcalibur</game><game id="28102">Kabuki Ittou Ryoudan</game><game id="617">NeoGeo Battle Coliseum</game><game id="28437">Super Street Fighter IV</game><game id="30944">Marvel vs. Capcom 3: Fate of Two Worlds</game><game id="30558">Sunday vs. Magazine: Shuuketsu! Choujou Daikessen</game><game id="31233">Dragon Ball: Raging Blast 2</game><game id="32156">Green Lantern: Rise of the Manhunters</game><game id="38480">Injustice: Gods Among Us</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/26/772420-mkdc_generic_fob.jpg</image></root>