<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20451</id><name>MotorStorm: Pacific Rift</name><description>OverviewMarking a shift from the dusty desert terrain found in the original MotorStorm, Pacific Rift takes place in a vibrant tropical island. The players race across the various terrain in this tropical paradise as they deal with the environment as well as rival racers. Mud, undergrowth, vines, trees, lava pools, rivers and lakes will all stand in the way of the goal. These elements will affect the gameplay in different ways, depending on the size of the vehicle. While smaller, lighter vehicles will get slowed by vines and branches, the newly added monster trucks can just plow through such obstacles. Bodies of water will also play a role as they can cool down engines, though they will also slow down the player's vehicle, and venturing into water that's too deep can be catastrophic. The game features four-player split-screen support, as well as 20-player online play. The online servers will be shut down on October 1st, 2012.Vehicle TypesHere are all the vehicle types in MotorStorm Pacific Rift, including the new addition, the Monster Truck.BikeATVBuggyRally CarRacing TruckMudpluggerBig RigMonster TruckThe Four ZonesThis time, the MotorStorm festival takes place across four distinct, themed zones on The Island, providing 16 varied tracks in all.Fire Zone: "Situated deep within The Island's volcanic lava fields, the Fire Zone is full of red-hot dangers forged in natures crucible. Prepare to speed across fiery racetracks characterized by rocky wastelands are creeping sheets of lava."Air Zone: "High above the tropical treeline stands the Air Zone, featuring racetracks on sheer cliff edges, fast downhill runs and massive big-air jumps. Lighter vehicles will profit from more control in this landscape - but a Big Rig is just as good for sending opponents crashing into the void."Earth Zone: "Dense and dirty, the Earth Zone throws racers deep into The Island's thick jungles and forests. Routes in and around the heavy undergrowth are littered with hazards and visibility is often minimal. You'll need to think fast and make split-second decisions to avoid a mass of deadly obstacles!"Water Zone: "From mountain lakes to coastal shores, the Water Zone offers serene beaches, plunging waterfalls and treacherous river canyons. Racetracks are often dangerously narrow as they cut a path through flowing water, so be on the lookout for alternative routes that will lead to dry land."Often, tracks will have a blend of "zones" so, certain Air tracks will contain lava featured in Fire tracks, and certain Water tracks will have dense jungle and mud seen in Earth tracks etc. This helps prevent the zone's from feeling too sperated and gives The Island, a more natural life-like feel.SoundtrackAlex Metric - In Your MachineAmon Tobin - Trickstep (Pacific Rift Mix)Animal Alpha - Fire! Fire! Fire!Aphex Twin - Come to Daddy (Pappy Mix)Black Daniel - Gimme What You Got (Alex Metric Remix)Black Sun Empire  State of Mind - Red Velvet (VIP Mix)Black Tide - Show Me the WayThe Body Snatchers - Twist UpBoys Noize - Lava LavaBullets and Octane - I Ain't Your SaviorClutch - Pure Rock FuryCut in the Hill Gang - Soul to Waste (MotorStorm Edit)David Bowie - Queen BitchDeath from Above 1979 - Romantic Rights (Erol Alkan's Love from Elbow Re-Edit)Death from Above 1979 - Blood on our Hands (Justice Remix)DJ Fresh - ChainsawThe Exploders - Wolf Cub (Pacific Rift Edit)Fatboy Slim - Everybody Needs a 303 (Plump DJs Remix)Goose - Black Gloves (The Bloody Beetroots Remix)Hadouken! - Liquid Lives (Noisia Instrumental Remix)Hervé - Zombie Dance (MotorStorm Edit)The Hives - No Pun IntendedIn Flames - Move Through MeLeftField - Phat PlanetMachine Head - DavidianMegadeth - SleepwalkerMinistry - Jesus Built My HotrodNick Thayer - Mind ControiNirvana - Swap Meet (Diplo MotorStorm Remix)Noisia - Groundhog (MotorStorm Re-Edit)Parker - Western Soul (Aphrodite Remix - MotorStorm Dub)Pendulum - TarantulaThe Planets - SlasherPrimal Scream - Necro Hex BluesThe Qemists - On the Run (MotorStorm Remix)The Qemists - StompboxQueens of the Stone Age - Sick Sick SickSaving Abel - New TattooSaviours - Caverns of MindSimian Mobile Disco - ParachuteSouth Central - Golden DawnSupa Bajo - Lalula (Instrumental)Trouble - Come Touch the SkyUlterior - WeaponsThe Whip - TrashTeaser TrailersPacific Rift had its first teaser trailer released earlier in 2008 on March 12th. The target render trailers showcased the new destructible environments and the super realistic character models.DemoA demo was given limited release on the 11th of September 2008. In Europe this was distributed by sending out invite promotional codes via e-mail to random users. In the USA it was distributed with Episode 4 of Qore. The demo features one track, Raingod Spires, and features both single player and two-player split-screen multiplayer. The demo features three vehicles, a Monster Truck, a Racing Truck, and a Bike. The demo is already available on the Playstation Store.ExpansionSince the game's release, there have been two expansion packs released to the PlayStation Store. The two packs, known as Speed and Adrenaline, were released a week apart from each other, with Speed releasing on July 2, 2009 and Adrenaline releasing on July 9, 2009.The Speed expansion pack includes three new tracks, known as Quicksands, Engorged, and Dark Fire Swamp, four new vehicles, and a new mini festival, adding 48 new events to the game. The Adrenaline expansion pack contains three new tracks, known as Reefrunner, Brimstone, and Hollowed Earth, four new vehicles, six new characters, and new paint jobs for the vehicles. Both packs cost $9.99.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5648">Burnout Paradise</game><game id="12976">Need for Speed: Most Wanted</game><game id="11055">NASCAR 08</game><game id="7880">Jet Moto</game><game id="3916">DiRT</game><game id="20132">Sega Rally Revo</game><game id="13787">Jet Moto 2</game><game id="284">NASCAR 2005: Chase for the Cup</game><game id="8438">NASCAR 06: Total Team Control</game><game id="20933">Baja: Edge of Control</game><game id="23461">FUEL</game><game id="16728">Powerslide</game><game id="15429">Excitebike 64</game><game id="20957">Pure</game><game id="24513">DiRT 2</game><game id="15821">4 Wheel Thunder</game><game id="11571">Ignition</game><game id="25226">Need for Speed World</game><game id="357">Burnout 3: Takedown</game><game id="20484">Burnout</game><game id="13514">Burnout 2: Point of Impact</game><game id="16492">Burnout Revenge</game><game id="4970">Burnout Legends</game><game id="8459">Burnout Dominator</game><game id="27007">Fireburst</game><game id="26452">MX vs. ATV: Reflex</game><game id="30986">Nail'd</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1832927-box_mstormpr.png</image></root>