<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20462</id><name>SingStar</name><description>Overview The first installment in the popular SingStar series to hit the PlayStation 3 is simply titled SingStar. Unlike most of the PlayStation 2 releases, SingStar PS3 doesn't come with a specific genre or era tied to it. Instead, the song list attempts to cover multiple genres, with more of a focus on songs that are popular in a specific territory. For example, the French release of this game has a track from French house pioneers, Daft Punk. The goal of SingStar is to match the pitch and cadence of the original songs by singing into one of two microphones. With two players, the songs can be broken up into duets. At the end of each song, a score is given based on how well each player sings.  SingStar on the PlayStation 3 also adds a substantial online component to the game.  SingStore  The SingStore allows players to download additional songs for a fee. In the US, songs cost $1.49 and include both the song and the music video, which plays in the background while you sing. While the game's European launch was plagued with infrequent store updates and an initially paltry selection, the US version launched with 200 songs already available for purchase. SingStar Online ProfileThe other online component in SingStar is a cross between a video upload site and a social networking application. Players create profiles, fill out brief "about yourself" questions, and from there, players can upload and view 30-second video clips of song performances. These videos can be rated by other users. Snapshots and audio recordings can also be posted for other users.  Tracklists International Tracklist The Automatic -  Monster Blink-182 -  All The Small Things Blur -  Coffee and TV Britney Spears -  Toxic The Cardigans -  Lovefool Coldplay -  Fix You The Fratellis -  Chelsea Dagger Gorillaz -  Feel Good, Inc. Gwen Stefani -  Cool Junior Senior -  Move Your Feet The Killers -  Mr. Brightside Macy Gray -  I Try Musical Youth -  Pass The Dutchie Ne-Yo -  So Sick Orson -  No Tomorrow OutKast -  Hey Ya! Primal Scream -  Movin' On Up Pussycat Dolls - Beep Radiohead -  No Surprises Razorlight -  America REM -  Losing My Religion Robbie Williams feat. Nicole Kidman -  Something Stupid Scissor Sisters -  I Don't Feel Like Dancin' The Stone Roses -  She Bangs The Drums Supergrass -  Alright Twisted Sister -  We're Not Gonna Take It U2 -  Beautiful Day Weezer -  Buddy Holly Wolfmother -  Love Train The Zutons -  Valerie  American Tracklist Amy Winehouse -  Back To Black Beck -  Loser Blind Lemon -  No RainBlink-182 - All The Small ThingsBritney Spears - Toxic Coldplay -  Clocks Corinne Baily Rae -  Put  Your  Records On Dave Matthews Band -  Crash Into Me David Bowie -  Let's Dance Faith No More -  Epic Franz Ferdinand -  Do You Want To?  Jane's Addiction - Been Caught Stealing  New Found Glory - My Friends Over YouNe-Yo - So SickOutKast - Hey Ya!  Pixies - Here Comes Your ManR.E.M. - Losing My ReligionRadiohead - No Surprises Ramones - I Wanna Be SedatedScissor Sisters - I Don't Feel Like Dancin'The Automatic Automatic - MonsterThe Cardigans - LovefoolThe Killers - Mr. BrightsideThe Pussycat Dolls - Beep  The Rolling Stones -  Sympathy For The Devil  The Smashing Pumpkins - TodayU2 - Beautiful Day  Warrant - Cherry PieWeezer - Buddy HollyWolfmother - Love Train </description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21171">Lips</game><game id="9860">Rock Band</game><game id="20673">Guitar Hero World Tour</game><game id="3738">Boogie</game><game id="23757">High School Musical 3: Senior Year Dance!</game><game id="23880">Ultrastar Deluxe</game><game id="16438">Karaoke Revolution Party</game><game id="20714">Rock Band 2</game><game id="12241">Guitar Hero Encore: Rocks the 80s</game><game id="26636">Lips: Number One Hits</game><game id="26757">Connie Talbot: Over the Rainbow</game><game id="26656">Def Jam Rapstar</game><game id="27036">SuperStar Karaoke</game><game id="28029">We Sing</game><game id="28936">Disney Sing It: Pop Hits</game><game id="27944">Karaoke Revolution</game><game id="30339">Lips: I Love the 80's</game><game id="31283">We Sing Encore</game><game id="31978">Karaoke Revolution: Glee</game><game id="32213">We Sing Robbie Williams</game><game id="33070">Karaoke Studio</game><game id="35638">Everybody Dance</game><game id="39075">Everyone Sing</game><game id="40311">Typing Karaoke</game><game id="38547">Sing Party</game><game id="40642">Karaoke</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14036/824175-singstar_cover.jpg</image></root>