<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20477</id><name>Arcana Heart</name><description>OverviewArcana Heart is a anime themed 2D fighting game that was brought over from        Japan by          Atlus U.S.A., Inc. It focuses on flashy high number combos and flashy special attacks. The story revolves around the Elemental World, a world which used to be connected to earth. At one point they split and the ancient Arcana went to live in the Elemenatal World. One day a magical rift is opened in the sky above         Tokyo and the boundry between the worlds is breaking. The earths only hope are with young girls who are able to communicate with the Arcana.   When selecting a character you have a choice between an Arcana Heart version or an Arcana Heart FULL version. In the japanese release the arcade game came out with a FULL version full of tweeks and rebalancing. So in the console version you are able to play a non FULL version character against a FULL version. Gameplay Arcana Hearts plays more like a VS game than anything. The attacks are Weak (Square Button), Medium (Triangle Button), Strong (Circle Button), and Special (X Button). While light, medium, and stong are used for regulars punch and kick type attacks, the special button is used to either home in on your opponent or use a Arcanas move.      Harness the power of your Arcana   The homing system will allow the character to chase its opponent no matter where they are on the screen. When you use a move that will send your opponent flying you are able to homing cancel out of the move and chase your opponent down and continue the combo. On your bottom meter there are 3 bars, using a special will use up on of these bars and it will refil as the match goes on. The game has 11 characters and 11 Arcanas to choose from. With being able to mix and match fighters to Arcana there are 121 combinations to fight with or against. Mix and match to find a combination that fits your fighting style.   ModesStory ModeIn the world of Arcana Heart a magical rift has appeared above Tokyo. Choose one of the 11 fighters and 11 Arcana and fight to stop the evil Mildred from opening the rift between the human world and the Elemental world. As you progress through the story mode you will be able to choose you opponent from an onscreen map before battle. Atlus has taken out the voice over from the pre battle and victory chats between characters for story mode in the english release. Arcade ModePick a fighter and a Arcana and fight your way through Arcade Mode and try to get the high score along the way. Progress through the stages and try to become the ultimate Arcana Heart fighter.  Versus ModeGet your friends over to play some Arcana Hearts with you. Prove to the that you can control the deadly power of the Arcana.  Training ModePractise all of the 121 possible combinations in training mode.  Get those combos down pat.  Gallery ModeView the artwork for both the fighters and Arcana. Watch openings from the Arcade version, FULL version, and the anime opening. Listen to your favorite character or stage theme from the music soundtrack in game, and a few extras that will have to be unlocked.   Characters InformationAppearanceHeart Aino Age: 14Height: 5'11"Weight: 101lbs.Residence: Cafe~Aino, upstairsFavorite Subject: Art, Music, P.E.Worst Subject: Language Arts, HistoryAino is the cover girl of Arcana Hearts. She is always cheerful and  wants to help people out and beleives that any problem can be solved  with love. Though sometimes her helpful attitude can be annoying to some  people.    Heart Aino Saki Tsuzura Age: 14 Height: 5'2" Weight: 99lbs. Residence: Ebisu, Tokyo Favorite Subject: English, Math, Science Worst Subject: ArtThe daughter if a successful business man and is best friends with Aino.  One day when she moved to England a portal sucked up her and her friend  Fiona. She escaped but Fiona didn't. Now that a similar portal is  opening above Tokyo she is trying to close it.  Saki Tsuzura  Kamui Tokinomiya Age:  Unknown Age Appearance: 16 Height:  Weight:  Residence:  Favorite Subject:  Worst Subject:  Kamui  is not just a school girl, she is known as the Thousand Year Protector.  She is in a state of eternal sleep until her Arcana wakes her when  there is a danger to the human world. Uses a samurai sword to do combat.      Kamui Tokinomiya KonohaAge: 13 Height: 4'6" Weight: 77lbs. Residence: Hinode City Park Favorite Subject: Physical Education, Break Time Worst Subject: Any class that forces her to sit in a desk  Konoha  is from a clan of warriors who were part human and part dog. Though her  clan still had dog ears and tail, Konoha tries to hide them. When the  Thousand Year Protector is awoken someone from the clan is chosen to be  the Millennium Guard and be a side kick to the Thousand Year Protector.    Konoha Lilica Felchenerow Age: 14 Height: 5'0" Weight: 92lbs. Residence: Lives with her father Favorite Subject: Ditching Class Worst Subject: All    Part human and part demon Lilica uses these powers to her advantage.  She is able to detect the distortion above Tokyo but does not seem to  care.      Lilica Felchenerow Yoriko Yasuzumi Age: 14 Height: 4'8" Weight: 97lbs. Residence: Koenji, Tokyo Favorite Subject: World History, Art Worst Subject: Math  A  young girl who is into occult things on day preformed a demon named  Mike, the self-proclaimed "Demon King". Mike foces Yoriko to inestigate  the magical disturbance, while eating some doughnuts.  Yoriko Yasuzumi Maori Kasuga Age: 14 Height: 5'0" Weight: 99lbs. Residence: Kasuga Shrine Favorite Subject: Art, Home Ec, Japanese History Worst Subject: Science  Maori  is a shrine madien who preforms rituals relating to the Elemental  world. She lives with her older sister and two younger sisters and they  help her in battle.    Maori Kasuga Lieselotte AchenbachAge: 10Height: 3'7"Weight: 41lbs.Residence: Teikyo Hotel, TokyoFavorite Subject: Doesn't go to schoolWorst Subject: Doesn't go to school  She  is known as the "Crimson-Eyed Criminal". Lieselotte lost her parents  when she was young and it has left her emotionally scared, and has made  her into the cold hearted assassin she is today. She is able to control a  puppet that is in her suitcase which she carries everywhere.  Lieselotte Achenbach Mei-Fang Age: 3 years in operation Height: 5'6" Weight: 211lbs. Residence: Yokohama Favorite Subject: All Worst Subject: None  Mei-Fang  is a Chinese made robot, created by Mei Ling Hua. With the knowledge of  4000 years of Chinese recipes and marital arts, she has come to Tokyo  to find her creator.    Mei-Fang  Kira Daidohji Age: 11 Height: 4'0" Weight: 48lbs. Residence: A "house" she built in her backyard Favorite Subject: Elemental Science Worst Subject: Art Though  she is a child genius she was forced to go back to elementary school  when she came to Japan. Because of this she is very arrogant and want to  take over the world.    Kira Daidohji Flona Mayfield Age: 13 Age Appearance: 11 Height: 4'5" Weight: 68lbs. Residence: The Elemental World Favorite Subject: Home Ec  Worst Subject: All the rest  Born  to a wealthy family in Britian, Fiona was one day sucked into the  Elemental World with her friend Fiona. She serves Mildred who promised  her a way home.    Flona Mayfield Mildred Avaion (BOSS) Age: 17 Height: 5'8" Weight: 130lbs. Residence: England Occupation: Director of the British MEA  Mildred is the boss character of Arcana Hearts, and is secretly researching the magical barrier.  Mildred Avallone Arcana Arcana Name: Arcana of Love - PartiniasDescription: In the middle ages when war was going on, a woman tried to show compassion to all people but was burned as a witch.  Default Character: Aino Heart  Arcana Name: Arcana of Lighting - Bhanri Description:  She was once the Queen of a war torn land and died protecting it. The people revived her and she became an Arcana.Default Character: Saki Tsuzura  Arcana Name: Arcana of Time - Anutpada Description: It is a mechanical timepiece that gained free will.  Default Character: Kamui Tokinomiya  Arcana Name: Arcana of Nature - Moriomoto Description: It is the king of plants and understands all plant life. Default Character: Konoha  Arcana Name: Arcana of Wind - Tempestas  Description: He is the form on wind and birds. Formed a bond with Lilica when she nursed him back to health. Default Character: Lilica Felchenerow  Arcana Name: Arcana of Death - Dieu Mort Description: An exicutioner who loved chopping off heads, but one day chopped off his own head out of curiosity. Default Character:  Yoriko Yasuzumi  Arcana Name: Arcana of Earth - Ohtsuchi Description: It is a protector that has been made from sturdy clay.  Default Character: Maori Kasuga  Arcana Name: Arcana of Shadow - Gier Description:  It is the embodiment of all mens deepest, darkest desires. He lurks in the shadow and feeds on emotions. Default Character: Lieselotte Achenbach  Arcana Name: Arcana of Fire - Lang-Gong Description: A wolf who lived alone in a chinese forest, he was immortalized by hermits and sages. Default Character: Mei - Fang  Arcana Name: Arcana of Water - Niptra Description: Lived when the world was covered all in water. Became the largest and wisest fish. Default Character:  Kira Daidohji  Arcana Name: Arcana of Metal - Orichalkos Description: As one of the oldest Arcana it is feared by most creatures in the Elemental world. Fiona is the only person who is not afraid of him. Default Character:  Fiona Mayfeild</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11156">X-Men vs. Street Fighter</game><game id="21699">The King of Fighters '98 Ultimate Match</game><game id="21863">Melty Blood: Act Cadenza</game><game id="10674">Garou: Mark of the Wolves</game><game id="21344">Hokuto no Ken: Shinpan no Sousousei Kengou Retsuden</game><game id="21768">BlazBlue: Calamity Trigger</game><game id="21367">Sengoku Basara X</game><game id="5030">The King of Fighters XI</game><game id="22812">Battle Fantasia</game><game id="379">Waku Waku 7</game><game id="18647">JoJo's Bizarre Adventure</game><game id="16738">Galaxy Fight: Universal Warriors</game><game id="20292">Astra Superstars</game><game id="800">Guilty Gear XX Λ Core</game><game id="27723">Vanguard Princess</game><game id="21930">Touhou 7.5 - Immaterial and Missing Power</game><game id="21325">Touhou 10.5 - Scarlet Weather Rhapsody</game><game id="27857">Touhou Hisoutensoku - Choudokyuu Ginyoru no Nazo o Oe</game><game id="34218">Chaos Code</game><game id="34082">Skullgirls</game><game id="35030">Akatsuki Blitzkampf</game><game id="34135">Under Night In-Birth</game><game id="36274">Persona 4 Arena</game><game id="27693">Daemon Bride</game><game id="41378">The Queen of Duellist Gaiden α+</game><game id="44008">Dengeki Bunko: Fighting Climax</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1860081-box_aheart.png</image></root>