<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20476</id><name>America's Army: True Soldiers</name><description>America's Army True Soldiers brings the same tactical shooting action that the series has grown famous for while introducing some new game mechanics to help compete with the growing shooter market today.  The game offers some basic character customization allowing the user to pick from a selection of faces and give a nickname to their character.  Like previous games in the franchise, True Soldiers focuses heavily on squad based tactics and cooperation.  Communication between players and the use of formations are key in order to successfully pull off ambushes, traps, or coordinated attacks or defense.  The game provides the user with AI controlled teammates but also supports up to 16 player coop for the story missions.  True Soldiers integrates a new class system allowing players to choose from five different classes each with two usable weapons one of which will need to be unlocked.  These five classes are the Rifleman, Grenadier, Sniper, Automatic Rifleman, and Squad Leader.  Each class plays a different role on the battlefield and the balancing of classes on your squad is the key to your success.True Soldiers is heavily focused on multiplayer and allows players to create their own clans. The game offers a variety of gametypes all with different objectives for your squad.  These include an elimination mode(Team Deathmatch), a mode where a squad must reach and secure an extraction point, a defend the base game mode, and also a VIP mode where you must eliminate the enemy VIP.  Voice chat in True Soldiers is a little different than in most shooters today, you can only talk to and hear those around you, friend or foe.  This means that if you are trying to flank an enemy base and you need to direct your squad, your best bet is to whisper to avoid detection.  Probably the most important mechanic introduced by True Soldiers is the Honor system.  Whenever a player heals a squad member, drags a wounded squad member to safety, shares ammo, or sacrifices them self to eliminate enemies, players will receive a certain number of honor points.  Accumulating enough honor points will cause the player to rank up.  When you rank up you can choose to specialize your soldier in three different categories Valor, Marksmanship, and Physical Training. Each area has their own benefits; Valor  increases damage resistance and squad bonuses, Marksmanship increases zoom and reduces gun drifting when scoped, and Physical Training  allows the player to run farther and faster, reduces healing time, and increases the maximum amount of equipment you can carry.  Achievements Meritorious Achievement Star50 Complete all eight "Wargame" missions without any casualties.Gold Achievement Star40 Complete any six "Wargame" missions without any casualties.Silver Achievement Star30 Complete any four "Wargame" missions without any casualties.Bronze Achievement Star20 Complete any two "Wargame" missions without any casualties.Operation Blue Bird15 Complete Sniper Role "Wargame" missions.Operation Brown Bear15 Complete Auto-Rifleman Role "Wargame" missions.Operation Black Cat15 Complete all Grenadier Role "Wargame" missions.Operation Gray Wolf15 Complete all Rifleman Role "Wargame" missions.Distinguished Skill Citation30 Reach Professional level in any two skills.Meritorious Skill Citation25 Reach Professional level in any one skill.Gold Skill Citation20 Reach Skilled level in all skills.Silver Skill Citation15 Reach Skilled level in any three skills.Bronze Skill Citation10 Reach Skilled level in any one skill.Distinguished Combat Service60 Win 250 missions (4  players in game) acting in any Role.Meritorious Combat Service45 Win 150 missions (4  players in game) acting in any Role.Gold Combat Service35 Win 75 missions (4  players in game) acting in any Role.Silver Combat Service25 Win 25 missions (4  players in game) acting in any Role.Bronze Combat Service15 Win 10 missions (4  players in game) acting in any Role.Operation Gold Lion30 Win all missions (4  players in game) of the Co-op Multiplayer campaign.Helo Hunter Award20 Destroy 50 Helicopters in multiplayer (4  players in game).Tank Hunter Award20 Destroy 50 Ground Vehicles in multiplayer (4  players in game).Indirect Fire Support Award20 Distinguished Leadership Award; 100 KIA's by Artillery Strikes in multiplayer (4  players in game).Distinguished Combat Medic50 Successfully perform First Aid upon teammates 250 times (4  players in game).Meritorious Combat Medic40 Successfully perform First Aid upon teammates 100 times (4  players in game).Gold Combat Medic30 Successfully perform First Aid upon teammates 50 times (4  players in game).Silver Combat Medic20 Successfully perform First Aid upon teammates 25 times (4  players in game).Bronze Combat Medic10 Successfully perform First Aid upon teammates 10 times (4  players in game).Distinguished Auto-Rifleman20 Win 25 missions (4  players in game) as Auto-Rifleman.Distinguished Grenadier20 Win 25 missions (4  players in game) as Grenadier.Distinguished Leadership20 Win 25 missions (4  players in game) as Team Leader.Distinguished Rifleman20 Win 25 missions (4  players in game) as Rifleman.Distinguished Sniper20 Win 25 missions (4  players in game) as Sniper.Meritorious Auto-Rifleman10 Win 10 missions (4  players in game) as Auto-Rifleman.Meritorious Grenadier10 Win 10 missions (4  players in game) as Grenadier.Meritorious Leadership 10 Win 10 missions (4  players in game) as Team Leader.Meritorious Rifleman10 Win 10 missions (4  players in game) as Rifleman.Meritorious Sniper10 Win 10 missions (4  players in game) as Sniper.Combat Injury Star10 Win 25 missions (4 plus players in game) in which you were wounded at least once, but not killed.Golden Eagle20 Join a Unit (Clan) and win 10 missions (4  players in game) as a Unit member.Pistolier Award (M9)20 Win 10 missions (4  players in game) with an M9 accuracy of 80% or higher (15  shots fired).Rifleman Award (M16A4 / M4A1)20 Win 10 missions (4  players in game) with an M16A4/M4A1 accuracy of 80% or higher (30  shots fired).Automatic Rifleman Award (M249)20 Win 10 missions (4  players in game) where 30  targets were suppressed with the M249.Grenadier Award (M203)20 Neutralize 75 targets with M203 grenade launcher in multiplayer (4  players in game).Sniper Award (M24/M107)20 Win 10 missions (4  players in game) with an M24/M107 accuracy of 80% or higher (10  shots fired).</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3550">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six: Vegas</game><game id="21912">Planetside: Core Combat</game><game id="21665">Operation Flashpoint: Dragon Rising</game><game id="32243">Operation Flashpoint: Red River</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1789965-box_aats.png</image></root>