<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20494</id><name>Command &amp; Conquer 3: Kane's Wrath</name><description>OverviewRed Alert 3 Beta key included in every box.The Kane's Wrath campaign is comprised of 13 Brotherhood of Nod missions in which players see Kane rise back to power and take his position as leader of The Brotherhood once again. The events of the storyline in Kane's Wrath take place before, during and after the events of Tiberium Wars, effectively bridging the gap between Tiberium Sun: Firestorm and CC 3: Tiberium Wars as well as continuing the story beyond the plot of the previous game.In addition to new unit additions for each side, 6 new sub-factions have been added, splitting the GDI, Nod and Scrin factions 3 ways for a total of 9 unique armies. The GDI are split into The Steel Talons, a force specializing in the superior firepower of its walker units (such as the Tiberian Sun-era Titan and Wolverine), and ZOCOM, whose specialty lies in using cutting-edge sonic technologies to defeat its enemies. The Brotherhood of Nod is split into the Black Hand, a force of shock troops who use flame-based weaponry to destroy the opposition, and the Marked of Kane, the powerful, stealthy and high-tech remnants of CABAL's cyborg forces. The Scrin have been split into Reaper-17, a sect which utilizes vastly powerful ground forces to pound enemies into submission, and Traveler-59, a sect that uses speed, mind-control and teleportation as its primary weapons. Each of these sub-factions contains units and structures of the base army, as well as a range of modified and completely-new units that play to their specialties.The GDI, Brotherhood and the Scrin also gain new "epic" units, which must be built in specially-designed structures (which can also produce regular vehicles) and can completely change the flow of battle. The GDI gain the MARV (Mammoth Armed Reclamation Vehicle), a supertank that has a powerful main sonic cannon and can harvest tiberium by driving through it. The Brotherhood gain the Redeemer, an advanced, laser-armed walker that uses a "rage generator" to drive nearby enemy units berserk. Finally, the Scrin gain the Eradicator Hexapod, which can crush even enemy tanks under its gigantic legs and gains credits for its owner by doing so. Each of these units has the ability to garrison a number of friendly troops, gaining their weaponry in doing so. This makes epic units incredibly flexible and powerful weapons platforms that can sway the outcome of late-game battles.Global Conquest modeIn addition to the mission-based campaign, Command and Conquer 3: Kane's Wrath adds a whole new mode to the original game: Global Conquest. This mode introduces turn-based strategy into Command and Conquer. Players fight on a world map as one of the three factions. They can build bases all over the world, battle enemy forces and generally try to establish their faction as the dominant world power. Like many turn-based strategy games, there are several ways to win, depending on which faction is chosen at the start. Battles start when two opposing enemy forces meet or if a force tries to destroy an enemy base. Splitting with conventional turn-based strategy games, there are no defined territories that players own--just spheres of influence generated by bases and armies. Players can automatically resolve an engagement when the pop-up comes up and whoever has the strongest and largest force will be calculated, but players can also play out the battle in an RTS skirmish.Sub-factionsNod:Marked of Kane: Remnants of CABAL's forces, these cybernetic soldiers have been lying dormant since the Second Tiberium War, waiting for Kane to return. They make excellent use of stealth units and EMP to confuse and obliterate their opponents.The Black Hand: Founded by the man who led the Brotherhood in the Second Tiberium War, Anton Slavik. The Black Hand are the most feared soldiers in the armies of the Brotherhood, purifying heretics with unforgiving flame. Brother Marcion became the leader of the Black Hand after assassinating Slavik.GDI:ZOCOM: Short for Zone Operations COMmand, these elite troops specialize in operating in areas infested with tiberium. ZOCOM works to reclaim infested areas through the use of sonic technology. The same technology is also used to great effect against GDI's enemies.Steel Talons: The Steel Talons make heavy use of mechs to fight against Nod and the Scrin. Superior frontal firepower has proven to be an extremely effective doctrine for the Steel Talons, and they have been among the first to make a widespread adoption of railgun technology.Scrin:Reaper-17: The heavy shock forces of the Scrin invaders. Reaper-17's troops have an almost-religious devotion to slaughter, making use of shields and blue tiberium to brutalize any force foolish enough to engage them.Traveler-59: A mysterious sect of the Scrin forces, the Traveler-59 troops outpace and outhink their opponents, using a combination of speed and mind control to subjugate their prey.Every sub-faction has its own exclusive and modified units, structures and technologies.CastJoseph Kucan as KaneThe mastermind and leader of Nod. As the title suggest, the game focuses on Kane and his actions leading up to, during and after the third Tiberium war.CABAL/LEGIONCabal, the sentient AI that went rogue after the second Tiberium war. Reconstructed into the new and more power, Legion. Completely loyal this time, however still not trusted by many Nod followers after the devastation Cabal did.Carl Lumbly as Brother MarcionAfter Kane's supposed death at the end of the second war and the death of Anton Slavik, Marcion went on to lead the Black Hand and take control of Nod, claiming Kane was a false prophet.Natasha Henstridge as Alexa KovacsAlexa idolizes Kane in every way. Her parents were killed by Cabal's cyborg army, due to this, she distrusts Legion and fears he may turn rogue like Cabal.System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Windows XP/Vista (64-bit not supported)Processor: 2GHz (2.2GHz Vista)Memory: 512 MB (1GB Vista)Graphics: nVIDIA GeForce 4, ATI Radeon 8500 or greater (ATI Radeon 9200 and 9250 PCI, nVIDIA Geforce 4 MX cards not supported.); for Vista NVIDIA GeForce 6100 or ATI Radeon 9500 or greaterDirectX®: DirectX 9.0 compatibleHard Drive: 6GB of free spaceSound: DirectX 9.0 compatibleController Support: Keyboard, mouse, optional controller (Xbox 360® Controller for Windows)</description><genres><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4867">The Lord of the Rings: The Battle for Middle-earth II</game><game id="2115">Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War</game><game id="19335">Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War - Winter Assault</game><game id="5681">Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War - Dark Crusade</game><game id="14073">Warcraft III: The Frozen Throne</game><game id="20952">World in Conflict: Soviet Assault</game><game id="13062">StarCraft</game><game id="20521">Halo Wars</game><game id="2478">Act of War: High Treason</game><game id="14805">KKND2: Krossfire</game><game id="1552">Dune 2000</game><game id="13125">Aliens Versus Predator: Extinction</game><game id="6447">The Lord of the Rings: The Battle for Middle-earth II - The Rise of the Witch-King</game><game id="14236">Dune II: The Building of a Dynasty</game><game id="6164">World in Conflict</game><game id="14081">Fragile Allegiance</game><game id="5647">Imperium Galactica II: Alliances</game><game id="20674">StarCraft II: Wings of Liberty</game><game id="24079">StarCraft II: Legacy of the Void</game><game id="33907">APOX</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1810148-box_cnc3kw.png</image></root>