<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20541</id><name>Mystery Dungeon: Shiren the Wanderer</name><description>Overview Mystery Dungeon: Shiren the Wanderer (MD:SW) is a cult-favorite console          roguelike originally developed by         Chunsoft for the        Super Famicom as part of their       Mystery Dungeon series.  Chunsoft's previous Mystery Dungeon game starred Torneko, MD:SW was their attempt to recreate that same magic but without having to pay license fees.  As Fushigi no Dungeon 2: Fūrai no Shiren, it  never made it stateside, even when it saw a re-release for the     Game Boy in 1996. A decade later the game was ported to the    Nintendo DS; two years later it was brought stateside.  Those familiar with Square's Chocobo Mystery Dungeon games will see the foundations of that franchise laid about Shiren The Wanderer. However, Shiren is a much more difficult game, to the point where dying and restarting is almost necessary to have a successful playthrough. As is tradition with roguelikes, dying "resets" the game world in some ways but the effects of your previous presence still lingers in some form or another. Sometimes, people remember who you are. At other times, you might encounter completely different folks or monsters. You lose everything you have on-hand when you die, but you can store weapons in safehouses for later retrieval--or leave them in the safehouse for them to grow and power up (and retrieve even  later when you've inevitably died yet again).</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4464">Izuna: Legend of the Unemployed Ninja</game><game id="21034">Izuna 2: The Unemployed Ninja Returns</game><game id="13105">Baroque</game><game id="25307">Penguin no Mondai: Saikyou Penguin Densetsu!</game><game id="13974">Pokémon Mystery Dungeon: Blue/Red Rescue Team</game><game id="27074">Penguin no Mondai X: Tenkuu no 7 Senshi</game><game id="4202">Evolution: The World of Sacred Device</game><game id="5276">World of Dragon Warrior: Torneko: The Last Hope</game><game id="1644">Eternal Quest</game><game id="40027">Elysion</game><game id="40257">The Guided Fate Paradox</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2469695-box_mdstw.png</image></root>