<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20568</id><name>Rayman Raving Rabbids 2</name><description>OverviewRayman Raving Rabbids 2 is what those of you who played the first one would expect, plenty of crazy, highly competitive minigames. The difference between this incarnation of the crazy bunnies and the previous one is that all the minigames can be played with 4 players simultaneously whereas in the previous game, Rayman: Raving Rabbids, you had to take turns.Game modesThere are a total of 45 minigames in the game, plus five on-rail shooting levels.TripsThe main mode consists of five different trips around the world. Each trip has eight different minigames plus a music game. There is a difficulty setting between easy and normal for the normal games, and a choice of instrument, along with a difficulty rating of one to three stars, for the music games. Whichever difficulty you choose, there is no way of failing any of the games, the only goal is to set a high score. By setting high scores and completing trips you unlock costumes and shooting games.The five different trips are:USAEuropeAsiaSouth AmericaTropics - unlocked after playing the first four tripsFree playReplay all the minigames you've unlocked. The more trips you play, the more minigames you unlock.PlazaVisit the plaza to customize your characters, use the jukebox, watch the credits and launch the shooting games. Customizing characters are just visual and have no in-game effect. The shooting games are on-rail, with rabbids rendered in real-time over full motion video of cities and famous locations around the world.</description><genres><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8362">Mario Party 8</game><game id="13685">WarioWare: Smooth Moves</game><game id="21824">Cooking Mama: World Kitchen</game><game id="12208">WarioWare Twisted!</game><game id="20395">Incredible Crisis</game><game id="3410">Mario Party 5</game><game id="5995">Mario Party Advance</game><game id="1372">Shrek Super Party</game><game id="15952">Crash Bash</game><game id="31744">Raving Rabbids Travel In Time</game><game id="35552">Rabbids: Alive &amp; Kicking</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1810963-box_raymanrr2.png</image></root>