<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2056</id><name>Enclave</name><description>PlotEnclave takes place in a fictional medieval setting, where the world has been torn apart by magic. Millennia ago, dark armies battled the good people of Celenheim and pushed the to the brink of destruction. When the battle was nearing it's end a lone wizard appeared high atop a ridge; with a staff held up in both hands. He defiantly slammed the staff hard into the ground, and unleashed a terrible fury of nature. That night, the world erupted; the skies grew black, the earth turned red with fire, blood, and chaos. A rift formed that raced forth, tearing the Earth apart, and destroying everything in it's path. During the aftermath, the demon Vatar and the mysterious wizard disappeared, and both were believed to be lost forever.The rift that formed separated light from dark, protecting Celenheim (now an Island), from the darkness on the other side. The inhabitants of the Enclave grew strong over many prosperous centuries but...the Earth is healing, and as the rift slowly closes, darkness again threatens Celenheim.GameplayEnclave is a single player third person action game where you take control of one of seven characters. Each has unique abilities determined almost entirely by their equipment. There are two campaigns in the game, Light and Dark, with the latter becoming unlocked after finishing the Light Campaign.Enclave uses a unique upgrading system that encourages experimentation. More equipment becomes available as the game progresses, but the gold required to use it is at a fixed amount in the game, and only the most hardcore players will find every hidden stash of gold in every level, and even then they will still need to make some tough decisions. For example, a character playing as the Knight may forgo heavy armor so they can bring in a better weapon. Alternatively, while playing as the Huntress, the player has a wide selection of arrows to choose from, but also has a backup dagger. Players can opt to use the cheapest (and least effective) dagger to free up more funds for more arrows. If a player decides their load-out isn't effective, they can build a new one without losing any gold, and they may also choose to replay previous levels to find more gold.One major drawback of the game is it's saving system, or rather lack there of. You can only save between levels so if you die near the end of a 90 minute level you have to start all over. Couple that with levels typically getting their most difficult near the end, as well as a few cases where instant death is possible, and you have a perfect recipe for frustration.Light Side ClassesKnightHuntressWizardDruidEngineerHalfling9320 Battle DroidDark Side ClassesBerserkerAssassinSorceressLichBombardierGoblinFeticiaOriginal System RequirementsMinimumWindows 98/ME/2000/XPPentium III 700MHz or AMD Athlon Processor128MB RAM4X CD-ROM Drive2.5GB Hard Disk Space16MB Direct3D Accelerated Video CardDirectX 8.1KeyboardMouseRecommendedPentium III 1.2GHz or AMD Athlon Processor192MB RAM32MB Direct3D Accelerated Video CardDirectX 8.1DirectX compatible 3D Sound CardDigital DistributionEnclave was re-released by Good Old Games for $6 (at normal non/sales price) with compatibility  support for Windows XP, Vista, and 7 for both 32 and 64-bit.Other VersionsOriginally, a Gamecube version was planned to be released alongside the PC version (with all the same improvements made to the game), but was later canceled. A Wii update titled Enclave: Shadows of Twilight has been announced for release on May 22nd 2012, and is being published by Topware.Enclave II; a direct follow up and sequel was announced for Xbox, PlayStation 2, Gamecube, and PC but was later canceled apparently due to licensing issues.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12648">Knights of the Temple: Infernal Crusade</game><game id="5263">Knights of the Temple II</game><game id="21473">Blade of Darkness</game><game id="9641">Age of Conan: Hyborian Adventures</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1795888-box_enclave.png</image></root>