<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20567</id><name>Puzzle Quest: Galactrix</name><description>OverviewAs          Puzzle Quest: Challenge of the Warlords uses a          Bejeweled-based puzzle, Galactrix uses a mix between          Hexic and Bejeweled to battle foes. Gameplay The Puzzle BoardPuzzle Quest: Galactrix uses a circular board filled with hexagonal tiles. On the players turn, the player selects a tile, then chooses which of the six adjacent tile spots that the original tile will move to, causing the two tiles to switch places. Just as in the first     Puzzle Quest, matching different tile types will bring different results. Tiles  Red - Weapons  Yellow - Engines  Green - Space Ship's Computer  Blue - Space Ship's Shields  Purple - Psi Power  Silver - Intel  Each fighter has a        shield and a         health bar, the shield must be depleted before health can be damaged.  The shield can then be restored by matching Blue tiles.  Damage is caused by matching up numbered attack tiles called mines that replace the       skull tiles of Challenge of the Warlords. When matched, the amount of damage done is equal to the sum of all the numbered attack tiles.    Story Humans have colonized distant stars, and four conglomerates have become the law of the land. One of the corporations is delving into dangerous experimentation, that could have dire implications for humankind. The player begins as an inexperienced space ship pilot. As the player gains experience and skills, the will get more intel on the nefarious experimenting going on. Online Demo  On the 20th of January a free to play flash-based          demo of Puzzle Quest: Galactrix. The demo contains one battle with 3 special moves.  There is also a downloadable    PC demo available via          Big Download, during the demo players will get to visit several star systems but will not be able advance their character past level 5 or save their character.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14169">Bejeweled</game><game id="18287">Hexic</game><game id="21635">Neves</game><game id="12562">Tetris 2</game><game id="22608">Bejeweled 2</game><game id="12020">Luxor 2</game><game id="20751">Hexic 2</game><game id="13308">Luxor</game><game id="23282">Henry Hatsworth in the Puzzling Adventure</game><game id="25766">Puyo Puyo 7</game><game id="26045">Witch's Workshop</game><game id="25516">Puzzle Kingdoms</game><game id="26115">Monster Eggs II</game><game id="26139">Alchemist</game><game id="25947">Yosumin!</game><game id="27504">RockinRoll</game><game id="28329">Gyromancer</game><game id="21968">7 Wonders 2</game><game id="27236">Numblast</game><game id="29417">Kurulin Fusion</game><game id="30765">AlphaBounce</game><game id="27890">Puzzle Chronicles</game><game id="32126">Magical Drop F: Daibouken mo Rakujanai!</game><game id="33019">Bejeweled 3</game><game id="24075">Infinite Space</game><game id="35410">Runespell: Overture</game><game id="35165">Sequence</game><game id="39155">10000000</game><game id="42019">Scurvy Scallywags</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1894716-box_pqg.png</image></root>