<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20576</id><name>Section 8</name><description>OverviewSection 8 chronicles the missions of an elite interstellar infantry squad as they take on dangerous missions on Earth's frontier colonies.StoryIn the future on war-torn planets Mankind's greatest battle is about to begin with the frontier colonies being devastated by a growing insurrection. Earth has dispatched the elite 8th armored infantry (codenamed section 8) to fight back against the insurrection . The nickname Section 8 refers to an old American military type of regulation for a reason of being mentally unable for duty.These suicidal missions that the crew of Section 8 volunteers has branded them by all other types of the military units insane.GameplayThis isn't your daddy's convoyMuch of the game-play in Section 8 revolves around tactical battles usually based around the conquest game mode made popular by the Battlefield franchise. It includes many of the standard features you would expect to see in this type of first person shooter including different equipment load-outs, along with the ability to call in artillery, supply points, and other tech to aid you and your comrades in battle. Furthermore the game implements a unique method of spawning, the players are given a overhead view of the map from there they pick where they want to spawn and than in real time they drop in from 1500ft in the air, players can then choose to break right before landing so they may shoot as soon as they land or land with zero breaking where they must take a few seconds to recover. Section 8 is planned to have 32 player Multiplayer online which will consist of the standard match types and will employ all the unique features mentioned above.Dynamic mission objectivesDuring every multiplayer match along with the normal capture the point game play there will also be a chance of an additional secondary mission which can range from escorting a VIP to protecting a Convoy that's on its way to your base. These missions are designed to add some variety to the game and help out the side that is losing (if your team is losing you might get a commando mission which will spawn a super powerful AI commando that will aid your team).LevelsOperation: First ContactOperation: Black BoxOperation: GuardianOperation: LiberationOperation: SpearheadOperation: CipherOperation: DecommissionOperation: EntrapmentCustomizationPassive Modules!Much like the multiplayer experience in games such as Call of Duty 4, players will have a running total of EXP gained and each kill or objective completed will give EXP. Also, players will be able to customize their character with different weapons and gadgets.This will allow players to have the perfect soldier; whether they want a tank or a lighting fast hit and run fighter, it all depends upon how they use the games "Passive Modules". There are nine different Passive Modules in Section 8 and you may equip up to ten Passive Modules, but only four of the same kind may be equipped at once.PC System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows XP (Service Pack 3), Vista (Service Pack 1), Windows 7Processor: Intel Pentium 4 3.0 GHz, or any Dual Core processor, AMD Athlon 64 3000Memory: 1 GB RAM (XP), 2 GB RAM (Vista)Graphics: 256 MB RAM Video Card, NVIDIA GeForce 7800 series, ATI X1800, or equivalentDirectX®: DirectX 9.0c (Shader Model 3.0)Hard Drive: 6 GB Hard Drive SpaceRecommendedOS: XP (Service Pack 3), Windows Vista (Service Pack 1), Windows 7Processor: Intel Dual or Quad Core 2.4 GHz, AMD Athlon X2 4000Memory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: 512 MB RAM Video CardDirectX®: DirectX 9.0c (Shader Model 3.0)Hard Drive: 6 GB Hard Drive SpaceUseful LinksOfficial Site: http://www.joinsection8.com/</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18883">Enemy Territory: Quake Wars</game><game id="3874">Quake III Arena</game><game id="24876">CellFactor: Psychokinetic Wars</game><game id="15529">CellFactor: Revolution</game><game id="13683">Quake 4</game><game id="24035">Halo 3: ODST</game><game id="6026">Medal of Honor: Airborne</game><game id="20699">Resistance 2</game><game id="18162">Team Fortress 2</game><game id="30185">Blacklight: Tango Down</game><game id="32620">Section 8: Prejudice</game><game id="36230">Blacklight Retribution</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1891360-box_section8.png</image></root>