<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20588</id><name>Super Smash Bros. Brawl</name><description>OverviewSuper Smash Bros. Brawl logo.The third game in the Super Smash Bros. franchise, Super Smash Bros. Brawl was released on March 9, 2008 on the Wii after many years of delay. Published by Nintendo and developed by Sora, Ltd. it was one of the most anticipated games for the Wii. Brawl added refinements to the actual Smash Bros. gameplay, and filled the game to the brim with nostalgia: remixes of classic game music, levels dedicated to various Nintendo games, references to Nintendo's history and the biggest roster of Nintendo characters in the series to date. Solid Snake and Sonic make an appearance in Brawl marking the first time in the series non-Nintendo characters are playable. Brawl is the first entry in the Super Smash Bros. franchise to include online play, as well as a much more involved single player campaign (complete with a story and cutscenes).GameplayThe gameplay in Brawl remains basically unchanged from the other games in the Super Smash Bros. franchise. Players select a character from a wide assortment of game series and duke it out with each other. Characters don't have a health bar typical to standard fighting games. Instead, Brawl uses a percentage system for dealing with damage. Basically, the more damage that is dealt, the higher their percentage meter goes up, and the higher that meter is, the easier it is to be knocked off the stage. Players will earn points for smashing people off of the levels, and lose points when they got knocked off by an opponent, so battles boil down to trying to hit opponents of while simultaneously trying to stay on the level. Alternatively a lot of players will opt to play stock matches where every player has a set number of life's and then players will try and reduce their opponents lives to zero and be the last man standing.Mario, Snake, Yoshi and Zelda are ready to fight.Players have both a regular attack button and a special attack button. The regular attack button is usually a fast attack button, but holding down the button and pressing the analog stick either left, right, down or up can unleash a "Smash Attack," which will send an opponent flying towards the edge of a stage, increasing the chance of defeating an opponent and gaining points. For a quick uncharged smash attack the player can just quickly flick the c-stick in the way the player wants to attack.Each character has a special attack that is mapped to a specific direction on the analog stick. Special attacks do more damage than regular attacks, but often don't have the Smash property to send an opponent flying. Special attacks are thus most often used to rapidly drive up an opponents percentage meter until a Smash Attack can send them flying. A characters upwards special attack is known as a recovery and is usually used to help a player make his way back to the stage after he has been knocked flying, for example Pit will start flying for a limited time and Marth shoots upwards in the air attacking with his sword. Special attacks vary from counters, ranged attacks, combination attacks, powerful attacks and more.Staying on one of the game's 41 different stages, in between Smash Attacks, special attacks, and items, is not a simple task. Each of the levels, based off of other classic Nintendo levels, can do just as much damage to a player as an opponent. One of the levels, based off of the Game Boy Advance game Wario Ware, Inc.: Mega Microgame$!, will interrupt combat throughout the match and offer players an opportunity to play in a microgame (based off of the microgames from WarioWare). Completing the microgame correctly will earn your character a power up such as invincibility or a boost, while failing the microgame will punish players with things like taking damage to being stunned for a limited time. Many of the stages have different random effects that will activate throughout the battle.Smash BallsSamus's Final Smash; afterwards, her armor falls off.One of the biggest changes from the previous games in the series is the introduction of Smash Balls. If they are turned on these items will appear randomly on the stage, and when broken by the player, allow the character to perform a Final Smash. When a character has a smash move stored the will be surrounded by a glow and you can hold it for as long as you want until you choose to use it by pressing the B button. If you are attacked while you have a Final Smash move stored the Smash Ball can be beaten out of you and another character can attack it to gain a Final Smash while you lose your own. Many characters have their own unique Final Smash (for example, Samus fires a powerful laser beam, Link unleashes a flurry of sword strikes, and Fox summons a Landmaster Tank). Another item addition in Brawl is the Assist Trophy. Effectively like a longer lasting version of the Poké Ball, the Assist Trophy summons a character into battle, where he/she will usually begin to do battle with all opposing players.The Subspace Emissary (Adventure Mode)The World is Disappearing!A new game-type in Brawl is the single player story mode, The Subspace Emissary. Subspace Emissary is a side-scrolling action game that expands on Melee's adventure mode by including a plot told to the player through cut-scenes. The game mode, sporting 30+ stages, takes the player through many different parts on the Nintendo universe such as on the halberd, the well-known heroes fight to save their world from being sucked into Subspace. As the player progresses, more and more characters will be added to his or her party which will unlock the character for play in the game's other modes. This mode is one of the best way to gain trophies with many that are exclusive to The Subspace Emissary and by using the brand new trophy capture feature by turning enemies and bosses you encounter into trophies.This game mode features several unique aspects not seen in other Smash Bros. game modes. Two of the most notable enhancements are stickers and the team system. Stickers, which are gained during play, allow the player to improve the stats for a character of their choice. These improvements are only usable in Subspace Emissary and do not carry over to the other game types. The team system allows the player to select up to four characters to use during a particular level. Although the selection is limited to a few characters at first, the player is always able to choose the order in which the characters are used.Cooperative play is also supported. When played in this way, the secondary player is able to assist the main player along the way but the camera always remains focused on the main player. Lives are shared, so players must work together to make sure they don't lose all of them. If player two drifts to far away from the main player he can hold down a button to quickly teleport over to the main player, if you stay off the screen to long you will slowly take damage.Character RosterUnlocked At StartFightersFrom FranchiseBowserMarioDiddy KongDonkey KongDonkey KongDonkey KongFoxStar FoxIce ClimbersIce ClimberIkeFire EmblemKing DededeKirbyKirbyKirbyLinkThe Legend of ZeldaLucasEarthBoundMarioMarioMeta KnightKirbyOlimarPikminPeachMarioPikachuPokémonPitKid IcarusRedPokémonSamus / Zero Suit SamusMetroidWarioMarioYoshiMarioZelda / SheikThe Legend of ZeldaSecret FightersFightersFrom FranchiseCaptain FalconF-ZeroFalcoStar FoxGanondorfThe Legend of ZeldaJigglypuffPokémonLucarioPokémonLuigiMarioMarthFire EmblemMr. Game and WatchGame and WatchNessEarthBoundR.O.B.Robotic Operation BuddySnakeMetal GearSonic the HedgehogSonic the HedgehogToon LinkThe Legend of ZeldaWolfStar FoxStagesThere are a total of 41 stages in Brawl, with 31 all new stages (with remakes of Battlefield, Final Destination, Pokemon Stadium etc.) and 10 returning favorites from Super Smash Bros. Melee. There is also a stage creator that lets players create, play, download and share unlimited amounts of stages. The game starts with 29 stages unlocked, but requires the player to complete certain tasks to unlock the remaining 12.StageFranchiseAdditional75mDonkey KongSecret stageBattlefieldSuper Smash Bros.Big BlueF-ZeroSecret stageMelee stageBridge of EldinThe Legend of ZeldaBrinstarMetroidMelee stageCastle SiegeFire EmblemCorneriaStar FoxMelee stageDelfino PlazaMarioDistant PlanetPikminFinal DestinationSuper Smash Bros.Flat Zone 2Game and WatchSecret stageFrigate OrpheonMetroidGreen GreensKirbySecret stageMelee stageGreen Hill ZoneSonic the HedgehogSecret stageHalberdKirbyHanenbowElectroplanktonSecret stageJungle JapesDonkey KongSecret stageMelee stageLuigi's MansionMarioSecret stageLylat CruiseStar FoxMario Bros.MarioMario CircuitMarioMushroomy KingdomMarioNew Pork CityEarthBoundNorfairMetroidOnettEarthBoundMelee stagePictoChatPictoChatPirate ShipThe Legend of ZeldaSecret stagePokémon StadiumPokémonMelee stagePokémon Stadium 2PokémonPort Town Aero DiveF-ZeroRainbow CruiseMarioMelee stageRumble FallsDonkey KongShadow Moses IslandMetal GearSkyworldKid IcarusSmashvilleAnimal CrossingSpear PillarPokémonSecret stageSummitIce ClimberHyrule TempleThe Legend of ZeldaMelee stageWarioWare, IncWarioWareYoshi's IslandMarioYoshi's IslandMarioMelee stageList of ItemsIn this game there were only six items from Melee that did not make a return. These items were the Barrel Cannon, Egg, Cloaking Device, Flipper, Red Shell and Parasol.NameDescriptionAssist TrophyThis item, once collected will unleash one random Assist Trophy Character that can either help or hurt players in battle. Your assist character will not damage you.Banana PeelWhen a character walks over it, they trip.Beam SwordA neon sword that extends when swung.Blast BoxWhen hit with a fire based or strong attack, it explodes, damaging characters in close proximity.BumperSends characters who touch it in the opposite direction in which they hit it.Bunny HoodProvides increased speed and jumping abilities to a character.ContainerThis item contains various usable weapons or power-ups.Deku NutUnleashes a flash that stuns foes for a short period of time.Dragoon Parts3 separate parts, once combined, allows a character to home in on opponents. If it lands, character(s) hit are likely to be knocked out.FanAn item that provides quick attacks.FoodThis replenishes damage when eaten.Franklin BadgeThis small pickup item, while equipped provides full protection against projectiles and sends them back the way they came.FreezieFreezes foes that get hit with it when thrown.Golden HammerCauses extreme damage, and is rarer than a Hammer.Golden Squeaky HammerLooks like the Golden Hammer, but does no damage when struck. Also squeaks.Green ShellSlides across the stage when thrown.HammerCan cause serious damage, although leaves you vulnerable if its head falls off.Heart ContainerRecovers 100% damage when grabbed.Home-Run BatCan provide a knockout when you use a Smash attack, while having a unique animation for each character that uses it.HotheadCircles a platform causing damage to opponents.LightningMakes everyone but the user small.Lip's StickPuts a flower on a character's head that it hits, dealing them damage over time.Maxim TomatoRecovers 50% damage when eaten.Metal BoxMakes a character heavy and improves their defense while covering them in a metal coat.Mr. SaturnA weak, projectile weapon.PitfallTraps foes in the ground that walk over it.Poison MushroomDecreases the size of a character for a short time, making them easier to knock out.Poke BallLike an Assist Trophy, but can be thrown. It brings out a random Pokémon that provides a random effect.SandbagCan be used as a projectile against others and produces trophies, CD's and stickers when attacked.Screw AttackTurns a character's standard jump into the Screw Attack.Smart BombCauses an explosion which expands over a very short period of time.Smash BallThis item, once hit a few times by a character, allows that character to perform a Final Smash attack.Smoke BallObscures the view in a limited range, and it can stick to characters.Soccer BallLaunches enemies with a flaming impact when hit.SpringShoots characters skyward when jumped on.Star RodShoots out stars when used with a Smash attack.StarmanProvides invincibility to a character for a short amount of time.Super MushroomIncreases the size of a character for a short time, increasing their attack and defence.Superspicy CurryFlames shoot out of your characters' mouth for a while making it hard to get to you while providing quick damage to opponents.Team HealerReplenishes a teammate's health when used correctly. Otherwise it can heal an opponent.TimerMakes other characters slower for a short period of time.UniraLaunches enemies with its' spike defence.Warp StarLaunches a character on the star skyward then back to deliver a large attack on enemies. It is somewhat maneuverable.Poke BallsBellossom will put the player to sleep.Poké Balls are items that have been in all three Super Smash Bros. games so far. When thrown, a random Pokémon will be summoned into battle.In Super Smash Bros. Brawl there are 31 Pokémon in total that can be summoned from Poké Balls, 16 of which have been in previous Super Smash Bros. games and 15 which are new to Brawl. This is the largest number of Pokémon to date.NameDescription of the effectBellossomBellossom creates a cloud of powder around itself. If a player comes into contact with this cloud their character will be put to sleep.BonslyBonsly walks around the stage and can be picked up by a player. This player can then use it as a weapon to attack other players. It can cause players to be knocked from the stage with as little as 50% damage.CelebiTrophies are dropped by Celebi.ChikoritaLeaves shoot out from Chikorita's head. These leaves travel in a straight line, and will damage anyone they hit.DeoxysDeoxys will fly up, and send a Hyper Beam downwards. Anyone who touches this will be sent flying.ElectrodeWill glow red, and turn darker and darker until it explodes, damaging anyone in the explosion area. Occasionally it will not explode, and can be picked up by players and be thrown. On even rarer occasions, it will appear not to explode, but then explode a few seconds later.EnteiShoots our fire, doing approximately 70% damage to anyone who gets hit by it.GardevoirWalks around the stage creating a circular barrier. Projectiles will not penetrate this barrier, but players can freely walk in and out of the barrier.GoldeenGoldeen will flip flop around the stage. It is completely harmless.GroudonGroudon is extremely large, and will damage anyone who touches him, although he does not move.GulpinThe player will be swallowed by Gulpin if they go near it, causing damage. They will be spit out a few seconds later.Ho-ohFlies into the sky to the back of the stage, and shoots fire at the players.JirachiDrops some stickers and flies away.KyogreWill shoot water, which causes no damage, while flying around the screen, but causes damage by touching players.Latias  LatiosThey Disappear off the side of the screen, then zooms backwards and forwards, causing damage to anyone in the way.LugiaFly's to the background before releasing a very powerful AeroBlast that can kill even low damage characters.ManaphySwaps the players characters.MeowthThrows coins at the players.MetagrossSlams onto the ground causing a shockwave that will damage anyone on the ground.MewDrops collectibles.MoltresFlies around the screen causing lots of damage to anyone it touches.MunchlaxWalks around the stage, eating any items apart from Pokéballs.PiplupSurfs around the stage. If a player gets hit by the wave they will be washed away.SnorlaxJumps up and off the screen, before increasing in size and falling down, damaging anyone in his way.StaryuFlies around searching for a player. When it finds a player it will fire projectiles at them, doing damage.SuicuneShoots an Ice Beam at players causing damage.TogepiWill randomly do one of five effects:Plants a flower in the head of a nearby character which will gradually cause damage.Fires an ice blast that freezes players, and causes some damage.Shakes the ground causing damage, and characters near the Togepi will become lodged in the ground.Puts characters to sleep using a powder.Creates a black smoke, impairing players vision, however this does not affect computer characters.TorchicJumps up and down doing a fire attack.WeavileAttacks players, causing only a small amount of damage, but stuns anyone hit.WobbuffetMoves back and forth when a player or item hits him. While moving, will cause damage if he comes into contact with someone.Assist TrophiesAssist Trophies are items that can be used in Super Smash Bros. Brawl. Similar to Poke Balls, Assist Trophies when picked up and activated will summon a random character into battle. Unlike Poke Balls, the summoned character is not a Pokemon and instead is a character from other Nintendo franchises, like Little Mac from Punch-Out, or a Hammer Bros. from Super Mario Bros.NameDescription of the EffectAndrossThe Andross appears in the back ground of the arena and shoots deadly one hit kill polygons at the players.BarbaraBarbara strums on her guitar creating sound waves. This assist trophy can only be unlocked after you obtain 25 Songs.DevilThe whole stage is moved by Devil in different directions.Dr. WrightDoctor Wright summons a building to rise up out of the ground which can carry opponents out of the arena.ExcitebikesRides around the stage hitting players.MetroidMetroid latches onto players and attacks them thus gives them damage.Mr. ResettiResetti appears and starts scolding the player, if attacked, he causes an explosion.NintendogA massive dog blocks the screen and the players sight.Ray MK IIIThe Ray MK III flies around the stage shooting missiles and green energy bullets. This assist trophy can only unlocked after playing 100 Brawls.Samurai GorohGoroh slashes his swords thus giving damage to the players while chasing opponents.Saki AmamiyaSlashes and fires with his Cannon Sword.Shadow the HedgehogShadow slows down time with Chaos Control. The summoner continues to move at normal speed. This assist trophy can only be Unlocked by unlocking Sonic.StafyStafy spins around the arena hurting players.WaluigiWaluigi repeatedly stomps players into the ground using either his stomp attack or his tennis racket.Grey FoxGrey fox runs around slashing opponents. Also reflects stray projectiles. This assist trophy can only be Unlocked by unlocking Snake.Infantry  TanksTanks and soldiers roam across the stage shooting at players. This assist trophy can only Unlocked by playing 300 Brawl.IsaacHe pushes opponents off the stage by using a skill called Move. This assist trophy can only unlocked by playing 200 Brawls.Hammer BroThe Hammer Brother throws hammers hurting any players who get hit.HelirinHelirin floats around the arena and acts like a wall allowing players to smash players onto her.JillShe attacks opponents with her power drill.Kat  AnaKat and Ana fly in different directions slashing at anybody in front of them.Knuckle JoeKnuckle Joe delivers a series of jabs to his opponents and finishes with either an uppercut attack or a power punch.Lakitu  SpinysLakitu drops Spinys onto the field where he walks around hurting whoever he touches.Little MacLittle Mac runs around madly punching players.LynShe delivers a single, powerful strike usually focused on one player.JeffJeff shoots homing rockets at his opponents.Brawl SoundtracksBrawl's soundtrack consists of over 300 songs. Here is a list of them:A - Mario franchiseNo.SongFrom gameA01OverworldSuper Mario Bros.A02UndergroundSuper Mario Bros.A03UnderwaterSuper Mario Bros.A04Easton KingdomSuper Mario LandA05Airship FortressSuper Mario Bros.A06Castle / Boom BoomSuper Mario World / Super Mario Bros. 3A07Title / EndingSuper Mario WorldA08OverworldNew Super Mario Bros.A09Luigi's Mansion MedleyLuigi's MansionA10Gritzy DesertMario  Luigi: Partners In TimeA13Delfino Plaza [Original]Super Mario SunshineA14Ricco Harbor [Original]Super Mario SunshineA15Bob-Omb Battlefield [Original]Super Mario 64A16Super Mario Bros. MedleySuper Mario Bros.A17Mario Bros. MedleyMario Bros.A20Mario CircuitSuper Mario KartA21Luigi's CircuitMario Kart 64A22Waluigi PinballMario Kart DSA23Rainbow Road [Original]Mario Kart Double Dash!!B - Donkey Kong franchiseNo.SongFrom gameB01Jungle JapesDonkey Kong CountryB02Map Overworld - Bonus Round [Original]Donkey Kong CountryB03Donkey Kong MedleyDonkey KongB04Donkey Kong Medley 2Donkey KongB05King K. RoolDonkey Kong CountryB06Stickerbrush SymphonyDonkey Kong Country 2: Diddy's Kong QuestB07Battle for Storm HillDonkey Kong Jungle BeatB08Jungle HijinxDonkey Kong CountryB09Level MusicDonkey KongB10Jungle Level 1 [Original]Donkey Kong Barrel BlastC - The Legend of Zelda franchiseNo.SongFrom gameC01Zelda Main ThemeThe Legend of ZeldaC02OverworldThe Legend of ZeldaC03TempleZelda II: The Adventure of LinkC04Dark WorldThe Legend of Zelda: A Link to the PastC05Dark World WoodsThe Legend of Zelda: A Link to the PastC07Link's Awakening MedleyThe Legend of Zelda: Link's AwakeningC08Hyrule FieldThe Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of TimeC09Ocarina MelodyThe Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of TimeC10Windmill / Ganondorf's Theme / Serenade of WaterThe Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of TimeC11MolgeraThe Legend of Zelda: The Wind WakerC12Kakariko VillageThe Legend of Zelda: A Link to the PastC13Gerudo ValleyThe Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of TimeC14Termina FieldThe Legend of Zelda: Majora's MaskC15Dragon Roost Island [Original]The Legend of Zelda: The Wind WakerC16Sailing Theme [Original]The Legend of Zelda: The Wind WakerC17Hyrule Field [Original]The Legend of Zelda: Twilight PrincessC18Hidden Village [Original]The Legend of Zelda: Twilight PrincessC19Midna in Distress [Original]The Legend of Zelda: Twilight PrincessD - Metroid franchiseNo.SongFrom gameD01Brinstar RemixMetroid / Metroid Prime PinballD02Norfair RemixMetroidD03Ending ThemeMetroidD04Ridley Boss ThemeSuper MetroidD05Theme of Super MetroidSuper MetroidD06Sector 1Metroid FusionD07Metroid Prime Menu [Original]Metroid PrimeD08Parasite Queen Boss Battle [Original]Metroid PrimeD09Meta Ridley Boss Battle [Original]Metroid PrimeD10Hunter Theme [Original]Metroid Prime 2: EchoesE - Yoshi franchiseNo.SongFrom gameE01EndingYoshi's StoryE02AthleticYoshi's IslandE03Above GroundYoshi's IslandE05Flower GardenYoshi Touch  GoE06WildernessYoshi's Island DSE07Athletic (Alternate version)Yoshi's IslandF - Kirby franchiseNo.SongFrom gameF01Legendary Air Ride MachineKirby Air RideF02King Dedede's ThemeKirby's Dream LandF03Boss MedleyKirby MedleyF04Butter BuildingKirby's AdventureF05Gourmet RaceKirby Super StarF06Meta Knight's RevengeKirby Super StarF07MarxKirby Super StarF08Zero TwoKirby 64: The Crystal ShardsF09Nature Area [Original]Kirby Air RideF10Checker Knights [Original]Kirby Air RideF11Frozen Hillside [Original]Kirby Air RideF12Squeak BattleKirby: Squeak SquadG - Star Fox franchiseNo.SongFrom gameG01Main ThemeStar FoxG02CorneriaStar FoxG03Main ThemeStar Fox 64G04Area 6Star Fox 64G05Star Wolf's ThemeStar Fox 64G07Fortuna [Original]Star Fox AssaultG08Fichina [Original]Star Fox AssaultG09Star Wolf [Original]Star Fox AssaultG10Space ArmadaStar FoxG11(Unknown)H - Pokémon franchiseNo.SongFrom gameH01Main Pokémon ThemePokémon Red / Blue / GreenH02Pokémon Centre ThemePokémon Red / Blue / GreenH03Route 1 / Viridian CityPokémon Red / Blue / GreenH04Pokémon Gym / EvolutionPokémon Red / Blue / GreenH05Wild Pokémon BattlePokémon Ruby / Sapphire / EmeraldH06Elite 4 BuildingPokémon Ruby / Sapphire / EmeraldH07Wild Pokémon BattlePokémon Diamond / PearlH08Palkia / Dalgia BattlePokémon Diamond / PearlH09Team Galactic BattlePokémon Diamond / PearlH10Route 209Pokémon Diamond / PearlI - F-Zero franchiseNo.SongFrom gameI01Mute CityF-ZeroI02White LandF-ZeroI03Fire FieldF-ZeroI04Menu [Original]F-Zero XI05Dream Chaser [Original]F-Zero XI06Devil's Call In Your Heart [Original]F-Zero XI07Climb Up! And Get The Last Chance! [Original]F-Zero XI08Brain Cleaner [Original]F-Zero GXI09Shotgun Kiss [Original]F-Zero GXI10Planet Colors [Original]F-Zero GXJ - Fire Emblem franchiseNo.SongFrom gameJ02Fire Emblem Main Theme (Vocal version)Fire Emblem: Shadow DragonJ03MedleyFire Emblem: Shadow DragonJ04With Mila's Divine Protection (Celica Map 1)Fire Emblem GaidenJ06Combat PreparationFire Emblem: The Sacred StonesJ07Winning RoadFire Emblem: Sword of SealsJ08Strike / Rise to the ChallengeFire Emblem: Blazing SwordJ09Against the Black Knight [Original]Fire Emblem: Path of RadianceJ10Crimea Attacks [Original]Fire Emblem: Path of RadianceJ11Power-Hungry Fool [Original]Fire Emblem: Path of RadianceJ12Victory Is Near [Original]Fire Emblem: Path of RadianceJ13Eternal Bond [Original]Fire Emblem: Radiant DawnK - Mother / Earthbound franchiseNo.SongFrom gameK01SnowmanK05Humoresque of a Little DogK07Porky's ThemeMother 3K08Mother 3 Love ThemeMother 3K09Unfounded Revenge / Smashing Song of PraiseMother 3K10New Pork CityMother 3L - Pikmin franchiseNo.SongFrom gameL01World Map [Original]Pikmin 2L02Forest of Hope [Original]PikminL03Environmental Noises [Original]PikminL04Ai no UtaPikminL05Tane no UtaPikmin 2L06Main Theme [Original]PikminL07Stage Clear / Title [Original]PikminL08Ai no Uta (French version)PikminM - WarioWare franchiseNo.SongFrom gameM01WarioWare, Inc.WarioWare, Inc.: Mega Microgame$M02WarioWare, Inc. MedleyWarioWare, Inc.: Mega Microgame$M03Mona Pizza's Song (JP)Mawaru Meido in WarioM04Mona Pizza's SongWarioWare: Twisted!M05Mike's Song (JP)Sawaru Meido in WarioM06Mike's SongWarioWare: Touched!M07Ashley's Song (JP)Sawaru Meido in WarioM08Ashley's SongWarioWare: Touched!M09M16Assorted MicroGame$ SongsN - Animal Crossing franchiseNo.SongFrom gameN01Title ThemeAnimal Crossing: Wild WorldN02Go K.K. Rider!Animal CrossingN03(Unknown K.K. remix)N05The RoostAnimal Crossing: Wild WorldN06Town Hall / Tom Nook's StoreAnimal Crossing: Wild WorldN07K.K. Cruisin' [Original]Animal CrossingN08K.K. Western [Original]Animal CrossingN09K.K. Gumbo [Original]Animal CrossingN10Rockin' K.K. [Original]Animal CrossingN11DJ K.K. [Original]Animal CrossingN12K.K. Condor [Original]Animal CrossingP - Kid Icarus franchiseNo.SongFrom gameP01UnderworldKid IcarusP02TitleKid IcarusP03SkyworldKid IcarusP04Kid Icarus MedleyKid IcarusQ - NES ClassicsNo.SongFrom gameQ01NES MedleyQ02Stack-Up / Robot Block MedleyQ04ChillDr. MarioQ05(Song name unknown)Clu Clu LandQ06Balloon TripBalloon FightQ07(Song name unknown)Ice ClimbersQ08(Song name unknown)Shin OnigashimaQ09(Unknown)Q10Type ATetrisQ11Type BTetrisQ12Tunnel SceneXQ13(Song name unknown)Wrecking CrewQ14(Song name unknown)Nazo no MurasamejouR - Nintendo DS, Wii  Various other GamesNo.SongFrom gameR02PictoChatR03Electroplankton AmbienceElectroplanktonR04Game  WatchR05(Unknown)R06Lip's ThemePanel de PonR07Marionation GearChou Soujuu Mecha MGR08TitleBig Brain AcademyR09Golden Forest1080 SnowboardingR10Mii ChannelR11Wii Shop ChannelR12Battle Theme MedleyGolden SunR13Shaberu! DS Cooking NaviR14Excite TruckR15Brain Age ThemeBrain Age: Train Your Brain in Minutes a DayR16Opening ThemeWii SportsR17Cow RacingWii PlayS - Metal GearNo.SongFrom gameS02EncounterMetal Gear SolidS03Theme of TaraMetal GearS04Yell "Dead Cell"Metal Gear Solid 2: Sons of LibertyS05Snake Eater (Instrumental)Metal Gear Solid 3: Snake EaterS06MGS4 [Theme of Love] Smash Bros. Brawl VersionMetal Gear Solid 4: Guns of the PatriotsS07CavernMetal Gear SolidS08Battle in the BaseMetal Gear Solid 3: Snake EaterS10Opening ThemeMetal Gear 2: Solid SnakeS11Calling to the NightMetal Gear Solid: Portable OpsT - Super Smash Bros. and Victory ThemesNo.SongFrom gameT01CreditsSuper Smash Bros.T02MenuSuper Smash Bros. MeleeT03OpeningSuper Smash Bros. MeleeT05Master Hand BattleSuper Smash Bros. BrawlU - Sonic the HedgehogNo.SongFrom gameU01Green Hill Zone 1Sonic the HedgehogU02Scrap Brain ZoneSonic the HedgehogU03Emerald Hill Zone 1Sonic the Hedgehog 2U04Angel Island Zone 1Sonic the Hedgehog 3U06Sonic BoomSonic CD US versionU07Super Sonic RacingSonic RU08Open Your HeartSonic AdventureU09Live and LearnSonic Adventure 2U10Sonic HeroesSonic HeroesU11Right There, Right NowSonic RushU12His WorldNext Gen Sonic the HedgehogU137 Rings in HandSonic and the Secret RingsW - Super Smash Bros. MeleeNo.SongFrom gameW01Princess Peach's CastleSuper Smash Bros. MeleeW02Rainbow CruiseSuper Smash Bros. MeleeW03Jungle JapesSuper Smash Bros. MeleeW04Brinstar DepthsSuper Smash Bros. MeleeW05Yoshi's IslandSuper Smash Bros. MeleeW06Fountain of DreamsSuper Smash Bros. MeleeW07Green GreensSuper Smash Bros. MeleeW08CorneriaSuper Smash Bros. MeleeW09Pokémon StadiumSuper Smash Bros. MeleeW10Poké FoatsSuper Smash Bros. MeleeW11Big BlueSuper Smash Bros. MeleeW12MotherSuper Smash Bros. MeleeW13IcicleSuper Smash Bros. MeleeW14Flat ZoneSuper Smash Bros. MeleeW15Super Mario Bro. 3Super Smash Bros. MeleeW16Battle ThemeSuper Smash Bros. Melee / Pokémon Gold / SilverW17Fire EmblemSuper Smash Bros. MeleeW18Mach RiderSuper Smash Bros. MeleeW19Mother 2Super Smash Bros. MeleeW20Dr. MarioSuper Smash Bros. MeleeW21BattlefieldSuper Smash Bros. MeleeW23Multi-Man MeleeSuper Smash Bros. MeleeW24TempleSuper Smash Bros. MeleeW25Final DestinationSuper Smash Bros. MeleeW26Kongo JungleSuper Smash Bros. MeleeW27BrinstarSuper Smash Bros. MeleeW28VenomSuper Smash Bros. MeleeW29Mute CitySuper Smash Bros. MeleeW30Menu 1Super Smash Bros. MeleeW31Giga Bowser BattleSuper Smash Bros. MeleeX - Super Smash Bros. Brawl General ThemesNo.SongFrom gameX01Main ThemeSuper Smash Bros. BrawlX02Menu 1Super Smash Bros. BrawlX03Menu 2Super Smash Bros. MeleeX04Final Destination 2Super Smash Bros. BrawlRemoved SongsSome songs were intended to be in Brawl but were removed for unknown reasons or copyright issues. They are not included in the game, but have been salvaged through viewing the game's file folders on a computer that can run Wii discs.No.SongFrom game01Because I Love YouEarthBound02Eight MelodiesMother03MGS2 ThemeMetal Gear Solid 2: Sons of Liberty04Beware the Forest's MushroomsSuper Mario RPG: Legend of the Seven Stars05Hippie Battle ThemeMother06You Can Do AnythingSonic CD07The Loner, Falco LombardiStar Fox Command08Ballad of the WindfishThe Legend of Zelda: Link's Awakening09Yoshi's Cookie Type AYoshi's Cookie10Boss Battle ThemeMario  Luigi: Partners in Time11The Chosen OnesFire Emblem12Smiles and TearsMotherTrophiesTrophies also appear in Super Smash Bros. Brawl. They are essentially unaltered from Melee, though there are many more, 544 to be more accurate. When players get enough trophies, they unlock something.To obtain character trophies, players must finish Classic mode with that character. To obtain characters' Final Smash trophies, players must finish All-Star mode with that character.In addition, some new ways of receiving trophies have been added. Some trophies, such as the Subspace Army characters' trophies, are not available at the Coin Launcher. Players will have to enter Adventure Mode, fight an enemy, and throw a trophy stand ("smash plate" in Japan) at it when its hit points is critical in order to capture it as a trophy. Additionally, in the Subspace Emissary, the storyline states that fighters who fall in this world in battle are forcibly reverted back to Trophies. Also, if you manage to get a Celebi from a poke-ball, it will drop some trophies. However, there is only a 1 in 493 chance of it happening. It is also interesting to note that the trophies of the smashers in the Subspace Emissary are a lot shinier than those gained by beating Classic Mode.Tournament PlayLike its predecessor, Super Smash Bros. Melee, Super Smash Bros. Brawl has been a popular game for tournaments. Super Smash Bros. tournaments have both 1 vs. 1 brackets and 2 vs. 2 brackets. Free-for-all mode is rarely or near to never used in tournament play. Tournaments generally take place in double-elimination brackets.Common Tournament Rule setsAt the time of the game's launch, there were many discussions concerning which rule set to employ in tournaments. Due to Super Smash Bros. Brawl's inherent similarity to Super Smash Bros. Melee, the Melee rule set was often used during the earliest tournaments. This rule set consisted of:Items turned to "None"Stock/Time3 Stock8 MinutesThe "Sudden Death" mode which occurs after the time expires and both combatants have the same stock is not taken into account in tournament tie-breaking. Instead, the damage percentage each character sustained at the point when time ran out is compared and the character with the lower percentage is the winner.However, tournament organizers and players quickly noticed that the pacing of Brawl was considerably slower than that of Melee. In Melee, characters, particularly Falco Lombardi, Marth and Fox McCloud, could trap opponents in combos and then "spike" (the term used for a technique that hits the enemy sharply downwards) them off the stage, leading to quick deaths if either player made the mistake of entering these combos. In Brawl, these combos were not present at this stage in the metagame, and because of this matches took longer. For this reason Brawl tournament organizers generally choose to lower the stock and time to 3 stock, 8 minutes. There has been discussions of lowering that even further, due to the length of matches using some characters.Other parts of the Melee rule set have stayed the same for Brawl.Additional RulesMany of the game's more "inventive" stages are deemed unsuitable for tournament play, due to excessively random elements, odd layouts, glitches that can be exploited in the stage, and character-specific benefits belonging to the stage. These stages are separated into "counterpicks" and "banned stages." Counterpicks can be picked by the loser of the previous match (which was played on a neutral stage), while banned stages can only be played if both players agree to it. An example of a neutral stage is "Smashville," an example of a counterpick, "Frigate Orpheon," and of a banned stage, "Rumble Falls."Certain stages are invalidated due to ways they can be exploited by the player. Hyrule Temple, for example, is banned because a Sonic player could hit the opponent once, and then run away until time runs out. It is impossible for any character to catch him if the Sonic player does not make a mistake. A problem that eliminates a lot of stages to the "banned" category is that stages with walls, such as "Shadow Moses Island," are completely invalidated by King Dedede's chainthrow, which turns infinite when he can do it over and over again against a wall until the opponent's damage reaches 999%. For this reason, Shadow Moses and many other stages are banned.The aforementioned Dedede chain throw is not banned in tournament play, due to the fact that King Dedede himself would have to be banned in that case. It is also not unique: there are several chain throws in the game, however none of them are banned for the same reason. There are currently ten known infinite grabs:King Dedede can perform infinite grabs on Luigi, Mario, Donkey Kong, Bowser and Samus.Marth can perform an infinite grab on Ness and Lucas.Pokémon Trainer can perform an infinite grab on Ness and Lucas.Lucas can perform an infinite grab on Ness.ControversyThe planned 2008 Evolution fighting game tournament has sparked a remarkable amount of controversy over its choice of rules, particularly between Evo's own forums, Shoryuken, and Smash World Forums, a forum frequented by many big-name players in the Smash community, such as Gimpyfish, Forward and ChillinDude. This was caused by Evo's tournament organizer and owner, "MrWizard," deciding that instead of following the guidelines of the Smash World Forums community for tournament rules, he would try something new. This mainly involved items being turned onto the "medium" setting, and the inclusion of Smash Balls. Items have become a "taboo" in the smash community due to their random nature (items are relegated to certain spawn points but follow no pattern in which point they spawn at). Items are disliked in professional circles because the mindset required for tournament play does not have the skill required to deal with the random nature of items. For this reason many professional Brawl players were outraged that such a large and prestigious tournament would change the rules so strongly.CriticismBrawl on a tournament level has been criticized since release by tournament players and casual players alike, for several reasons. One of the principal issues for tournament players is the inclusion of "tripping," a mechanic which causes the player to have a small chance of their character tripping and falling down whenever the analog stick is held completely in one direction. Another problem competitive players have with the game is the lack of combos compared to Melee, as well as the elimination of glitches that took advantage of the physics engine such as "wave dashing". The lack of combos is generally attributed to the lack of hit stun (i.e. the amount of time before a character can perform a move after they have been hit by their opponent).Casual players have a much different complaint with the tournament game and its players, in that some consider people who use such things as King Dedede's chain grab and other exploits in order to win are "not having fun." Gimpyfish and Hugs would later argue against this on the 1UP Show, saying that tournaments were a lot of fun for them as long as they win.Other Info1-4 PlayersNunchuk compatibleClassic Controller compatibleGamecube controller compatible</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3712">Power Stone 2</game><game id="3164">Digimon Rumble Arena 2</game><game id="21788">Jump Ultimate Stars</game><game id="18522">Onimusha: Blade Warriors</game><game id="547">Dream Mix TV World Fighters</game><game id="25158">Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Smash-Up</game><game id="16794">Small Arms</game><game id="21870">The Outfoxies</game><game id="34429">Cartoon Network: Punch Time Explosion</game><game id="22307">Battle Stadium D.O.N</game><game id="18011">Power Stone Collection</game><game id="20100">Power Stone</game><game id="9985">Sonic Battle</game><game id="20334">Digimon: Battle Spirit</game><game id="18389">Digimon Rumble Arena</game><game id="23162">One Piece: Gear Spirit</game><game id="21520">Viewtiful Joe: Red Hot Rumble</game><game id="2154">One Piece: Grand Battle</game><game id="21376">Guilty Gear Dust Strikers</game><game id="23622">Rave Master</game><game id="20733">Castle Crashers</game><game id="35692">Newgrounds Rumble</game><game id="38140">PlayStation All-Stars Battle Royale</game><game id="39954">Pen 1 Grand Prix: Penguin no Mondai Special</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/82063/2561025-ssb.jpg</image></root>