<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20597</id><name>Gran Turismo 5 Prologue</name><description>Gran Turismo 5 Prologue is the first commercial                   Gran Turismo product available for the                  PlayStation 3. The game was released both on disc at retail stores and as a downloadable game via the                 PlayStation Network. The disc-based version features an exclusive video, but both versions were released at a price point of $39.99.  This game marks the 10th anniversary of                Polyphony Digital's car simulation series, and marks the first time in that decade that the game has been playable online. Up to 16 players can race on six different tracks in one of over 70 cars. In this installment a new realistic in-car view has been added, which includes speedometers, odometers, functional rear view mirrors, wing mirrors, and real-time lighting and shadows within the car.   Aside from the 30 single player events that are available in the game, there is an single player arcade mode for you to customize any race.  In addition, there is a split screen mode for two players to race locally in a head-to-head race.   It has been announced that there will be additional downloadable content released for GT5 Prologue, including additional tracks and vehicles. The latest update, October 2008, was titled "Spec III". A variety of changes were brought with the update, including 3 new cars (Ferrari California, Lotus Evora, GT by Citroen), increased prize money for events, and lowered difficulty. Also anticipated is a downloadable update that will include damage modeling which is noticeably absent in the current version. Car List Acura  1991 Acura NSX  Alfa Romeo  2006 Alfa Romeo 147 TI 2.0 Twin Spark  2006 Alfa Romeo Brera Sky Window 3.2 JTS  Amuse  Amuse S2000 GT1 Turbo  Art Morrison  1960 Art Morrison Corvette  Aston Martin  2006 Aston Martin DB9 Coupe  Audi  2007 Audi R8 4.2 FSI R Tronic  2007 Audi TT Coupe 3.2 Quattro  Blitz  2007 Blitz Dunlop ER34  BMW  2007 BMW 135i Coupe  2008 BMW 135tii  2007 BMW M3 Coupe  2003 BMW Z4  Chevrolet  2006 Chevrolet Corvette Z06  Citroen  2006 Citroen C4 Coupe 2.0VTS   Concept by Gran Turismo   Chevrolet Corvette Tuned  Dodge Viper SRT10 Tuned  Ford GT LM Spec II  Gran Turismo 350Z RS  Lotus Elise 111R Tuned  Lotus Elise Tuned  Mitsubishi Evo IX Tuned  Mitsubishi Evo X Tuned  Nissan Skyline Coupe Tund  Renault Clio Sport Tuned  Suzuki Cappuccino Tuned  Suzuki Swift Sport Tuned GT by Citroen (Spec III update)    Daihatsu  2002 Daihatsu Copen Active Top  2007 Daihatsu OFC-1  Dodge  Dodge Viper GTS  Dodge Viper SRT10 Coupe   Ferrari  1976 Ferrari 512BB  2006 Ferrari 599  1992 Ferrari F40  2006 Ferrari F430 2008 Ferrari California (Spec III update)  Ford  2006 Ford Focus ST  2005 Ford GT  2007 Ford Mustang V8 GT Coupe Premium  Honda  2004 Honda Integra Type R  2002 Honda NSX Type R  Jaguar  2006 Jaguar XK Coupe  Lancia  1991 Lancia Delta HF Integrale Evoluzione  Lexus  2007 Lexus IS F   Lotus  2004 Lotus Elise 111R  1996 Lotus Elise  2008 Lotus Evora (Spec III update)  Mazda  Mazda Atenza Sport  2002 Mazda RX-7 Spirit R Type A (FD)  2003 Mazda RX-8 Type S  Mercedes-Benz  2002 Mercedes-Benz SL 55 AMG  Mine's  2006 Mine's BNR34 Skyline GT-R N1 Base  Mini  2006 Mini Cooper-S  Mitsubishi  2005 Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution IX GSR  2007 Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution X GSR Premium Package  Nissan  2007 Nissan Fairlady Z Version S  2007 Nissan GT-R  2005 Nissan GT-R Proto  2007 Nissan Skyline Coupe 370GT Type SP  2007 Nissan Skyline Coupe Concept  2002 Nissan Skyline GT-R V-spec II Nur  2006 Nissan Skyline Sedan 350GT Type SP  Renault  2000 Renault Clio Renault Sport V6 24V   Subaru  2005 Subaru Impreza Sedan WRX STI Spec C Type RA  2007 Subaru Impreza WRX STI  Suzuki  1995 Suzuki Cappuccino  2007 Suzuki Cervo SR  2007 Suzuki Swift Sport   TVR  2002 TVR Tamora  2000 TVR Tuscan Speed 6  Volkswagen  2001 Volkswagen Golf GTI  2005 Volkswagen Golf V GTI  Track List Daytona International Speedway  Superspeedway  Road Course   London  Forward  Reverse   Eiger Nordwand  Forward  Reverse   Fuji Speeday  Fuji Speedway F  Fuji Speedway GT   Suzuka Circuit  Suzuka Circuit  East Course   High Speed Ring  Forward  Reverse   Gran Turismo TV GT-TV is an online interactive on-demand channel within GT5P featuring licensed automotive and motorsport programming from around the world.  As an extension of Gran Turismo, GT-TV is a new way to experience the thrill of racing and learn more about the cars you love to drive both in the game and on the street.  GT-TV includes both free content and pay-per-view content. Channels  Gran Turismo TV Specials Top Gear Best Motoring Super GT D1 Grand Prix Video Option   Music List Cargo - "GT-FORCE"  Daiki Kasho -  "Edge of the World" Daiki Kasho  Ayesha Cole - "SURV1V3"DJ Shadow - "LOVE LOVE"Does it Offend You, Yeah? - "With a Heavy Heart"The Earaches - "Not the Kind of Man I Am"Friendly Fires - "On Board"Justice - "Let There Be Light"Kavinsky - "Testarossa Autodrive (SebastiAn Remix)"Kemmei - "Love  Peace"Klaxons - "Golden Skans"Nittoku Inoue -  "Road Star"Makoto - "Back 2 U"The Mars Volta - "Goliath (EL-P Remix)"Masahiro Andoh - "Moon Over The Castle (GT5 Prologue Version)"   Mitsuharu Ura  Furani - "The Last Helping"   Mitsutoshi Sato - "Constructor's BluesMitsutoshi Sato - "Flatout"Naomee - "Sky High Mountain Breeze"  Naomee - "Twieky 4"  Nittoku Inoue - "Get Away" Nittoku Inoue - "Road Star"Pride Tiger - "Let 'Em Go"Satoshi Bandoh - "Farewell"  Satoshi Bandoh - "When the Rains Come"SebastiAn - "Dolami"Thin Lizzy - "The Rocker (Richard Evans Remix)"Weezer - "Automatic (LA Riots Remix)" Yudai Sato - "Are You Ready?" Yudai Sato - "Current of the Times" Yasuo Sako - "Wind From Rio"</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5881">Forza Motorsport 2</game><game id="6978">Enthusia Professional Racing</game><game id="19809">Project Gotham Racing 3</game><game id="20936">Ferrari Challenge Trofeo Pirelli</game><game id="8779">Sega GT 2002</game><game id="531">TOCA Race Driver 2</game><game id="15965">Sega GT</game><game id="5869">TOCA Touring Car Championship</game><game id="8831">Need for Speed: Porsche Unleashed</game><game id="941">Project Gotham Racing</game><game id="2279">Project Gotham Racing 2</game><game id="6137">Driving Emotion Type-S</game><game id="8437">TOCA 2: Touring Car Challenge</game><game id="7019">Ridge Racer V</game><game id="16276">Ford Bold Moves Street Racing</game><game id="20919">Ford Racing: Off Road</game><game id="5977">Need for Speed III: Hot Pursuit</game><game id="7431">Ford Racing</game><game id="7777">Juiced</game><game id="10124">Midnight Club: Street Racing</game><game id="17872">TOCA Race Driver 3 Challenge</game><game id="23526">GTR: Evolution</game><game id="13535">GT Pro Series</game><game id="1052">Super PickUps</game><game id="22693">RACE Pro</game><game id="24995">Forza Motorsport 3</game><game id="25225">Need for Speed: SHIFT</game><game id="20418">Midnight Club II</game><game id="5875">Midnight Club 3: DUB Edition</game><game id="20927">Midnight Club: Los Angeles</game><game id="21114">Midnight Club: Los Angeles Remix</game><game id="24513">DiRT 2</game><game id="42693">Forza Motorsport 5</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/22/175742-gt.jpg</image></root>