<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20601</id><name>Killzone 2</name><description>OverviewKillzone 2 CGI Trailer (E3 2005)Killzone  2 is a military-themed first-person shooter that offers a  futuristic,  sci-fi slant as the soldiers of the  ISA head to the enemy's  home  planet to fight back against the invasion seen in the previous  game.  This  sequel to the 2004                                PS2 title from                                Guerrilla Games was  first announced during  Sony's E3 2005 press conference via a  pre-rendered teaser trailer. The footage left many in awe, and even more    in speculation debating the legitimacy of the trailer being real  gameplay. Later, it was confirmed and clarified by Sony that the footage  was indeed a computer generated target render, leaving many  disappointed.    The game utilizes an intuitive                                cover system,  referred to by the developers as "lean and peek." Guerrilla   strived  toward the creation of a cinematic gameplay experience. In what they    call "Hollywood Realism", the camera perspective remains in  first  person for the vast majority of the game, with the HUD being minimalist.    That includes moments where the player must take cover, climb  ladders, and when cut scenes gain full attention.   This  cover system  allows the player to simply hold a trigger to latch onto cover, and then  move the movement-assigned analogue stick in the direction of the  player's choice - whether it be up, left, or right  .   Virtually any  position can be used as a cover anchor.   The player can also enter a                                scope/                               iron sight  with   their weapon when leaning out from behind cover. Vehicles, on  the other hand, are not controlled in  first-person view for the sake of  streamlining.                                 Destructible environments and                                cover are  a crucial part of  Killzone 2, with nearly every piece of cover being  able to be chipped away by gunfire and explosions until only a frame  remains. Less permanent objects, such as trash bags, tin cans, and  chairs, are movable and destructible. According to  Guerrilla, the  inclusion of  destructible cover was not something added for players to  be able to rip everything apart until it's completely non-existent    like                                Battlefield: Bad Company   , but was added to further instil a more intense sense of realism,  where everything in the world reacts as you would expect, and portrays  movements which make sense in terms of real-world physics. SIXAXIS Motion Controls   Killzone 2 supports SIXAXIS                                motion controls  as well, "in ways that make sense". Valves can be turned by holding the  L1 and R1 buttons, the character's left and right hands, respectively,  and then making a twisting motion with the controller, acting as if the  player is interacting with a tangible object. C4 charges can be placed  with a similar functionality, and the Sniper Rifle has a steady-shot  component built in. When the player zooms in on an enemy or object, the  controller must be kept completely still to ensure the greatest possible  accuracy.                                Jeff Gerstmann also noted that the game's loading screens feature "quite possibly the best use of  SIXAXIS technology to date".  Killzone 2 includes full                                Trophy support,  DualShock 3 rumble support, as well as some level of                                Home integration.                                Guerrilla Games released patch version 1.27  on June 4th, 2009, among the changes being the inclusion of a High  Precision control option.  Players can toggle between the classic  Killzone 2 control style and one similar to other online shooters, such  as the popular                                Call of Duty 4: Modern Warfare.   By default, this feature is set to "On" for new players and "Off" for  existing players.  The patch also tweaked the multiplayer portion of the  game, adding a party system that allows friends to consistently stay on  the same team and squad.  Furthermore, all badges are now available  when playing Skirmish Mode, so that players of lower rank can experience  offline the weapons and abilities of each badge while playing with and  against bots. Single Player CampaignThe Alpha Team (from left to right: Garza, Rico, Sev, Natko)   Killzone 2 is set two years after the events of the first game, after the dust settled from the                                Helghan  invasion of planet  Vekta. The ISA are now taking the war back to the  enemy, in attempt to capture the  Helghan leader, Emperor                                Scolar Visari. But unlike the past games set in a world of                                Helghast  army invasion,  Killzone 2 takes place on the  Helghast home planet,   Helghan, where a fully fledged war has begun. You play as a new  character to the                                Killzone franchise, named                                Sev, who is part of an elite four man special forces group called the Alpha Team. The squad is made up of Master Sergeant                                Ricardo Velasquez (aka  Rico), Sergeant 1st Class                                Tomas Sevchenko (aka  Sev), Corporal                                Shawn Natko (aka  Natko), and Lance Corporal                                Dante Garza (aka  Garza).   Alpha  Team, along with hundreds of ISA troops, are deployed over Pyhrrus, the  capital city of Helghan, to begin the final invasion of the Helghast  home planet. The Invasion proceeds as planned until the Helghast  activate their arc tower defenses, wiping out much of the first wave of  the assault.  ISA scientist Evelyn Batton discovers that the arc  towers are built out of an element called Petrusite, mainly located at  Tharsus Refinery. Alpha Team is sent to find a way to disable the  towers.In the course of the mission, Sev and Rico leave to activate a  communications tower, and the rest of the team is kidnapped by the  Helghast. They find the team being held by Colonel Radec, who is about  to execute them. Rico rushes in to save the squad, resulting in Garza  being killed and Radec escaping.  The Team returns to the New  Sun, the ISA flagship, when the Helghast begin a massive assault and  board much of the fleet. Colonel Radec infiltrates the bridge of the New  Sun, kills Evelyn,steals the ISA nuclear strike codes, and mortally  wounds Fleet Commander Jan Templar. Templar sacrifices himself,  deactivating the New Sun's engines and crashes the ship into Tharsis  Refinery, deactivating the city's defense grid.  The ISA and  Alpha Team regroup to attack Visari's palace, but a nuclear bomb is  detonated in the city, wiping out most of the ISA forces. The remaining  soldiers storm the palace, and Alpha Team severely injures Radec, who  commits suicide to avoid capture.  Sev and Rico confront Scolar  Visari, who tells them that even if he dies, he will be a martyr to the  Helghast, only strengthening their war effort. He says that he is the  only one keeping the Helghast under control. Rico, avenging Templar and  Garza, kills Visari, whose last words are, "The madness begins." Sev  leaves the palace, shaken from what has happened, and sees a Helghast  fleet wiping out ISA forces, proving what Visari had said. Online MultiplayerOnline Multiplayer Gameplay   Killzone 2 offers a robust                                online multiplayer  aspect, with  Guerrilla going as far to say that it makes up about "50%  of  Killzone 2". The  multiplayer features up to 32 player games (16 vs  16), 12 different military ranks to unlock, 46 different ribbons and  medals to unlock, up to 64 player                                clans, 8 different maps (which vary in size),                                tournaments of up to 256  clans, 6 different                                classes  which each have a primary and secondary ability, called badges (Total  of 12 badges to mix and match), and 12 different character models (Non-    customizable); two character models for each  class type (ISA  model/HGH version).   Classes in  Killzone 2 offer players a way  to cater to their custom play style. There are a total of 6 different  unique  classes;   Engineer, Medic, Scout, Assault, Tactician,   Saboteur. Each class has two badges; a primary and secondary badge (the  primary badge   determines character model), which are tailored to that   classes' specific play style. Online Multiplayer Sniper  For example, the Medic's primary badge ability gives the player access to a specialized                                weapon that can heal downed/injured teammates (by shooting an electric charge at them). The secondary badge allows medics to toss a                                health pack  which other players can pick up. But the unique aspect of  classes in   Killzone 2, is the combining of badges; for example, a player could take  the primary badge of the Saboteur  class (Which allows the player to  disguise themselves as randomly selected enemy player), and the  secondary badge of the Assault  class (Which temporarily increases  running speed), allowing the player to run faster and be  disguised as the enemy. You can change your badge ability combination  depending on what game type you are playing as well. The above badge  combination for example, may best suit your play style for a game of                                capture the flag.  Since each player may have their own combination of badges, this  changes the  multiplayer experience greatly, both on a strategic level  as well as suiting to your preferred play style. Note that not all  badges/abilities will be accessible from the start, players have to  unlock some  classes fully (secondary abilities) by ranking up.   Killzone's multiplayer also features robust  clan support, with up to 64 player  clans, clan                                leaderboards,  and  clan  tournaments. You can even setup clan challenges against  other  clans in-game, this is where the 'Clan Valor'   system comes in.  Valor is KZ2's  online currency for  clans; whichever  clan has more  valor points, the higher they are on the  leaderboards.   Though  clans  start off with a certain amount of valor to get started, in order for  them to climb up the  leaderboards they must challenge other  clans and  bid a certain amount of their valor; whoever wins the game takes all.  This system is similar to gambling, where in order to gain more, you  must risk more, though here in the end one of the two  clans will always  end up losing valor, which also means moving down on the  leaderboards.  If a  clan has somehow lost all of their valor points, they will be  unable to challenge other  clans and be forced to play in specific   tournaments in order to gain enough valor to start challenging other   clans again.  Tournaments can also be made, allowing up to 256  clans to  compete against each other, giving them a chance to win large amounts  of valor points.Although certain players have the ability to request air support from                                AI controlled                                sentry bots, vehicle support was not included on release and despite rumors to the contrary has not appeared through a patch to the game.  Guerrilla is also trying to differentiate  Killzone 2's  multiplayer  experience from most shooters on the market, with the introduction of  other unique aspects (alongside  classes and much   more), such as  in-game  squad mechanics, trustworthy spawning system, as well improving  the general flow/pacing of action. Through in-game mechanics, players  can easily create a new  squad on their team, which other teammates can  join on-the-fly. Anywhere from 2 to 8 players can be in a specific   squad, allowing a maximum of 8  squads per team if they so choose.  Players in a  squad will also share unique information amongst each  other, such as the  squads overall  health, each players specific  badges/ class combinations, as well as a custom chat channel. Spawning  in  online is also made easy; After death the map will be displayed, as  well as what spawn points are available to choose from, to the left of  the map is a live video feed of what is going on at whichever spawn  point you have selected. This means you will have no one to blame for  spawning in the middle of an explosive battle but yourself.   The player  can also choose to spawn on the  squad leader (if in a  squad), making  it easier to always stay close and never get separated. Something else  you don't regularly see in other multiplayer games, is a constant flow  of action. In  Killzone 2, after completing a specific task   or  mission, the game doesn't bring up a lobby screen or  menu, it  dynamically continues the game and pulls up the next mission, creating a  constant flow of action.   Apart from players being able to  automatically join a game using the 'Quick Join' feature (which attempts  to match you up with players of similar skill level),  Guerrilla has  also stressed how important it is to them to allow users to "play what  he wants to play". As well as trying to fulfill this goal with the  custom  classes system, players can also create custom games whenever  and however they want.  Customizations include the obvious features such  as what maps, gameplay modes, and  weapons are supported, but also  deeper things such as how the  classes work. The game will include  official dedicated servers from  Sony, as well as players' custom  servers.  Guerrilla promises to enable players with  customizations to  create their gameplay experience the way they want it to be in  Killzone  2 online multiplayer. Killzone 2 is heavily tied into  Guerrilla's  online website,                                Killzone.com. Users are able to link their                                PlayStation Network  ID to the site, in order for their  online, and even single player  stats to be monitored, tracked, and shared  amongst the community. As  well as having access to the sites forums,  Guerrilla Games news  updates, and more, each player will has their own profile displaying all  kinds of  Killzone 2 stats, as well as                                Killzone Liberation  (PSP) stats. Statistics include everything from  leaderboards rank,  current  clan, favorite gametype,  weapon, map, or  class, to awards  such as medals and ribbons.     Multiplayer Modes Assassination:  One team member is the target and one team has to keep him safe, the  other has to take him out.  Body Count: Similar to  traditional team death match game play.  Search and  Destroy: Defend an objective and make sure the other faction does  not place charges.  Search and Retrieve: Bring the  propaganda pack to the drop-off point and try and stop the other faction  from taking it to theirs.  Capture and Hold: Capture  and hold points around the maps and try and keep the other faction from  doing the same.  Multiplayer Classes and AbilitiesRifleman This  is the  default multiplayer character and is assigned to the player  when no  primary badge is selected. However, a secondary badge can still  be  added. Riflemen class has available several different weapons to  choose  from, with the exception being for the specialized ones.Medic   Primary badge ability:  Grants the player the ability to revive downed team mates.    Secondary badge ability: Grants the player the ability to throw a health  pack.  Engineer     Primary badge ability: Grants to player the ability to set up an   automated turret which automatically targets the enemy players.    Secondary badge ability: Grants the player the ability to repair  ammunition dispensers, mounted guns, and automated turrets.Tactician  Primary badge ability: Grants the player the  ability to throw a colored smoke grenade, which serves as a spawn point.    Secondary badge ability: Grants the player the ability to  request air support from a sentry robot which targets enemy players Assault   Primary badge ability: Gives the player  heavy armor, which is double the strength as normal.    Secondary badge ability: Temporarily boosts the player’s running speed. Saboteur    Primary badge ability: Allows the player to  assume the disguise of a  randomly selected enemy player. The disguised  player will display the  name of the enemy unit which they are pretending  to be.   Secondary badge ability: Grants the player the  ability to throw a sticky, proximity-activated C-4 explosive charge.    Scout:       Primary badge ability: Grants the player the ability to use a cloaking  suit to become almost invisible.     Secondary badge ability: Grants  the player the ability to tag all   on-screen enemy players with a hidden  marker, this ability then   broadcasts their coordinates to team mates.  Multiplayer MapsPyrrhus RisePyrrhus Rise   Among the first of the  Petrosite mining fields  (therefore being  one  of the older, depleted mines), Pyrrhus Rise is named after  the  Helghan  capital. ISA Command was hoping to get an easy picking from the    Helghast, thinking the security here would be slightly more lax than    elsewhere. Little did they know the  extent to which the Helghan army   fights to hold on to every little piece of  turf they own.      Opponents battle not only each other, but the  elements as well - harsh   blowing wind, gaping canyons, rolling terrain, and the  occasional   bullet flying haphazardly through the air. With over ten ammunition   boxes, four mounted weapons,  five square kilometers to play in, and   long lines of sight for those with the  keen eyes, this is the largest   of the original multiplayer maps. Four bridges span the monstrous canyon   just  off center of the map. The bridges mark  the lowest point in the   map, and with either end of the map being elevated, is  an area prone  to  sniper fire. Dead Man’s  land is what they call it. Cover abounds   in  the map, but with the large amount of open space, it’s a race from  cover  to  cover while trying to achieve the mission objectives. Salamun Market  Salamun Market Winding  itself through Salamun Market is a road  marked and scarred  from  recent battles, showing the importance of this area. With either   faction turtled up at either end  of the map, the showdown starts with   the large two-story building located in  the center of the map, as well   as the focal point for most shoot-outs, showing  the strategic   importance of the location. Offering some of the best of indoor   close-quarter combat  and open outdoor spaces, Salamun Market turns out   to be quite an entertaining  map. Boasting an outstanding fourteen    ammunition boxes, twelve mounted weapons, and thirteen explosive   barrels, all  crammed in two and a half square kilometers, this is one   intense map. Variation  in navigating the map is key here, as the urban   layout is quite friendly to  different routes. With a nearly straight    line of sight to either key end of the map, two sniper buildings make   an easy  and importance appearance. Helghan Industries  Helghan Industries Once  a bustling experimental technology facility,  Helghan  Industries  sealed its own doom when they failed to erase all sensitive    information from the surrounding databanks, making this a focal point   for the  invading ISA, as well as the defending Helghan army.   Placing focus on vertical combat, Helghan  Industries is one of the   unique types of maps that the game has to offer. With a two tier  bridge  overlooking the main route  through the map, an open eye is  absolutely  key in the map. With choke points abounding, it offers  combatants  a  chance to show what they are made of. Showcasing nearly  three square  kilometers of room, ten ammunition boxes,  and six mounted  weapons, it  is quite a well rounded map. Visari Hammer  Visari Hammer Home  to one of the massive Arc Cannon protecting Helghan,  the Visari   Palace is a vital piece in the puzzle the Helghan strategy. In a   desperate attempt to stop the brutal  pounding the ISA ships are taking   in orbit, numerous small drop ships have  landed nearby, with the only   goal of disabling the cannon, allowing for a  foothold to be made in   this key area.  Possibly the most complicated, multilayered map  of   the original set, Visari Hammer is a maze when it comes to finding  your  way  around, and those new to the map are likely to cause as much  harm  trying to  find their way to the firefights, as the enemy is   decimating the few who did  manage to stumble upon their barrels. While   the map may seem small upon first glance, once you make your way   through the myriad  of tunnels and covered pathways, it starts showing   just how large it is when  you get lost from your team. Hosting just    over two square kilometers of play space, fourteen ammunition boxes, and   seven  mounted weapons, it is quite a well balanced map. Profound   knowledge of what corridors lead  where is key, as you may accidentally   find yourself in the opposing base,  facing the business end of an   automated turret.  Radec Academy   Radec Academy A  focal point in both the eyes of the Helghast and  ISA, the Radec   Academy is the main graduating source of the Helghan army. Losing this   place would be devastating, both  in terms of emotionality and sheer   strength, to the Helghan war machine. Which is why it is high on the   priority of  the invading ISA.  One small courtyard. Two small  floors.  Just over one square kilometer to move  about. The formula for a   completely  chaotic battleground. Every win here is  felt by the losses   sustained. Nothing  comes cheaply. Tharsis Depot   Tharsis Depot Petrosite  is one of the most powerful fuels in the  galaxy. Tharsis  Depot is  where a major  concentration of these barrels is found. The  faction  finding themselves on the end of these depots will find  themselves   having a huge advantage in turning the tide of the war.  Both sides know  this.  Offering a scant one kilometer of killing  space,  prepare to  have your abilities tested in this short lived map.  Having eight  ammunition boxes, and no mounted  weapons, this map knows  it means  business.  With a fair number of concrete cubes being stacked  about,  there is no  shortage of cover. But what happens when  you  lose that  cover, or you’re found out is when you really know what you’re   made  of. A control room towards the  center of the map plays home to  a  number of the mission types, and plays quite  a versatile role, as   there are walkways abounding and offering little  cover. With each  base  camp being a close  boost run away, the fighting in the map is  nothing  short of glorious. Blood Gracht  Blood Gracht The  canal in Blood Gracht used to be a sight on the  eyes, with the   residential units surrounding allowing for a scenic  neighborhood. War   leaves such a  scar. Resorting to guerrilla tactics,  the army of   Helghan is making their way to stopping and reversing the incoming  ISA   invasion, halting the advance into the capital.  An asymmetrical  map  with less than a square  kilometer of killing space, this map plays   host to eight ammunition boxes, and  three mounted weapons. With the   canal  being straight as a sniper shot, it plays nearly like a shooting   gallery to those  sitting atop with a keen eye and quick finger.    Verticality does play a more than a small role here, with a plethora of    ways to get to your intended target. Due  to close quarters and the   hectic nature of combat, those skilled at deception  will find   themselves comfortably at home here in the Gracht. Corinth Crossing  Corinth Crossing Bridges  have been a key strategic key in the  history of warfare.  Corinth  Crossing  finds itself home to such a bridge.  Those who  control the  bridge and surrounding areas will find themselves  holding a  key  strategic advantage.  Having a bridge as your set piece  plays host to a   built in set of ideas. Back and forth  gameplay,  small verticality,  and a tug of war that is going to happen. This  plays just like that.  With bases being at either end of the bridge,   the conflict zones come  into play at the top of the bridge and the base  of the  bridge, where  the majority of the mission objectives are  located. There are  holes in  the surfaces of the bridges, so a watchful  eye on where you step is   key, unless you’re comfortable with facing  your enemy completely  unprepared.   Steel  Titanium Map PackVektra Cruiser   Vekta Cruiser This  map is set on the Vektan warship from the single player game. Combat   takes place over multiple levels with a more open area in the middle   and cramped corridors surrounding it. Wasteland Bullet  Wasteland Bullet This  map featured a very original concept with the entire level taking   place on a moving train. Players were able to leap between carriages   however there would occasionally be towers and signal lights passing   between them as the train moved along which could knock players onto the   tracks. Gun turrets also featured heavily in this level with many  being  placed at strategic points for defending objectives. Flash  Thunder Map PackBeach Head   Beach Head This  map was perhaps the most unpopular of the DLC maps released. It is   essentially a narrow corridor with very little vertical structures and   only light cover. The layout of the map meant battles were typically   fought in close quarters. Southern Hills   Southern Hills This  map features large, open areas surrounding a significant multi-level   structure in the middle of the map. The most significant change   Guerrilla made from the original Killzone map was the addition of a   "nuclear strike" which would hit the map after a specific interval. When   it did all players exposed in the open would instantly be killed which   made for interesting gameplay, particularly on the search and retrieve   game mode. Napalm  Cordite Map PackSuljeva Cliffside    Suljeva Cliffside This  map was loosely based around the mining facility you visit in the   singleplayer game. It takes place on a narrow cliffside but features a   walkway that runs along either side and connects through the middle as   well as tunnels leading to a multi-level complex at either 'base'. Only   this map contains the new Flamethrower weapon. Arctower Landing   Arctower Landing This  battle takes place on the rooftops from the early portion of the   single player game. There is a significant complex on either end with a   bridge connecting two in the middle. Only this map contains the new   Boltgun weapon.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20699">Resistance 2</game><game id="9993">Halo 3</game><game id="11757">Crysis</game><game id="2133">Call of Duty 4: Modern Warfare</game><game id="20834">Brothers in Arms: Hell's Highway</game><game id="24035">Halo 3: ODST</game><game id="10461">Clive Barker's Jericho</game><game id="3207">Quake II</game><game id="20777">Call of Duty: World at War</game><game id="25246">Battlefield: Bad Company 2</game><game id="24713">Modern Warfare 2</game><game id="21116">MAG</game><game id="2600">Halo: Combat Evolved</game><game id="7547">Warhammer 40,000: Fire Warrior</game><game id="29221">Call of Duty: Modern Warfare Reflex Edition</game><game id="30544">Conduit 2</game><game id="30185">Blacklight: Tango Down</game><game id="20663">F.E.A.R. 2: Project Origin</game><game id="26423">Call of Duty: Black Ops</game><game id="26694">Brink</game><game id="36230">Blacklight Retribution</game><game id="23708">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine</game><game id="38608">Alien Rage</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1794112-box_killzone2.png</image></root>