<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20612</id><name>Space Siege</name><description>OverviewSpace Siege is a dungeon crawler-type action-RPG and the spiritual successor to Dungeon Siege. Space Siege was announced as the newest project from developer Chris Taylor in July 2007. In July 2008, a demo for the game was released onto the internet. A console version is reportedly being "considered" but nothing is official yet.SettingThe game takes place on the ISCS Armstrong, which is a colony ship that supports a variety of environments. The ship is controlled by a sub-sentient AI called PILOT. The governments of Earth mandated PILOT to be installed on all ships, to make navigational calculations quicker and easier. There are many other secondary AIs which concentrate on a single part of the ship. The ship also houses many robot drones that support a variety of duties. From security to heavy-lifting, the Armstrong has a robot for every task on the ship.CharactersSeth WalkerSeth Walker, the protagonist of Space Siege.Seth is the character that the player will control throughout the game. He is a member of the Allied Security Force, and trained in traditional combat and robotic engineering. He believes that robots are a better solution compared to cybernetics, and is apprehensive to use any cybernetics.Gina ReynoldsShe is the Communications Officer on the ISCS Armstrong, so she knows the layout and systems of the ship very well. She is fiercely anti-cybernetics and believes they should never be used.Dr. Edward DeSotoHe is a great supporter in cybernetics believing it is the next step in human evolution. He is one of the finest cybernetic surgeons in the world and believes the controversy surrounding cybernetics only helps him push his platform.Jake HendersonHe has been a soldier his entire life, specializing in handheld and larger defensive weapons. He is a lifelong friend of Seth’s and will try to protect Seth during his adventure.Frank MurphyHis life has been filled with failure: alcoholism, divorce, and inability to move up the career ladder. However he is one of the most knowledgeable mechanics on the Armstrong. There is no system on the ship that Frank does not know about.Unique Gameplay MechanicsRobotic AssistantsHR-V, Seth's robotic pal.In Space Siege, Seth has a robotic ally a Hudgeson's Unit referred to as an HR-V Unit (pronounced "Harvey"), that will always follow him around. HR-V is under your command to perform offensive and defensive abilities, and has the ability to be upgraded with new armor, weapons, and other special items. The player can also gain the ability to manufacture and deploy single use robot drones, and sentry guns, as they level up.Cybernetic UpgradesAs your Seth progresses through the game his skills and abilities will improve, just like any other RPG. However, Space Siege has a twist in that the method you improve your skills will affect the story. Improving Seth with cybernetics will make him much more powerful but compromise his humanity. Keeping him more human will make enemies more difficult to defeat but allows Seth to keep his humanity.System RequirementsMinimum RequirementsOperating System: Windows XP/ VistaProcessor: 2.6GHzRAM Memory: 512MBFree Disk Space: 3GBVideo Card: Vertex Shader / Pixel Shader 2.0 and 128MB RAM (ATI Radeon 9800/nVidia GeForce 6800)Sound Card: DirectX CompatibleRecommended RequirementsOperating System: Windows XP/ VistaProcessor: 3.0GHzRAM Memory: 1GBFree Disk Space: 3GBVideo Card: Vertex Shader / Pixel Shader 2.0 and 256MB RAM (nVidia GeForce 8600 GT)Sound Card: DirectX Compatible</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2059">Dungeon Siege</game><game id="1727">Dungeon Siege II</game><game id="8638">Titan Quest</game><game id="13762">Titan Quest: Immortal Throne</game><game id="20803">Diablo III</game><game id="5985">Diablo</game><game id="7584">Etrom: The Astral Essence</game><game id="9989">Hellgate: London</game><game id="17722">Shadowgrounds Survivor</game><game id="1119">Diablo II</game><game id="13217">Champions of Norrath</game><game id="3156">Champions: Return to Arms</game><game id="13293">Dungeon Siege: Legends of Aranna</game><game id="6083">X-COM: Enforcer</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4963/306219-spacesiegeboxart.jpg</image></root>