<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20631</id><name>Dance Dance Revolution HOTTEST PARTY 2</name><description>General  Typical DDR Gameplay Dance Dance Revolution: Hottest Party 2 features the exact same gameplay that any other Dance Dance Revolution Game feaures: stepping on arrows located on a Dance Mat to the beat of music to achieve a high combo. The game also features hand movements which are realized with the Wiimote and  Nunchuck attatchement, a system introduced in Dance Dance Revolution: Hottest Party. Differences to DDR: Hottest Party   A player playing with a Mii instead of a premade character.The game features a completley new soundtrack (see below), which contains songs from the last four decades.  More Wiimote and Nunchuck support  Four Player multiplayer (as opposed to two player only) Mii support was added to the game. This way the character can use their own customized avatar as a dancer isntead of premade dancers.  New characters which move more realistically. New stages and enviroment with more visual effects have been added.  New Dance Modes and competition modes such as "Dance n' Defend". Track ListBlack or White - Prince RoyalBust A Move - Young MC (Includes Promotional Music Video Background!)Come Rain Come Shine - Jenn CunetaD.A.N.C.E. - JusticeMakes Me Wonder - Sunshine SupermanNite Runner - FRAZRed Alert - Basement Jaxx (Includes Promotional Music Video Background!)Scramble - System 7Tribulations - LCD SoundsystemUmbrella - Haley HuntWe Got The Beat - Pop n' FreshLesson by DJ - U.T.D.  FriendsLesson2 by DJ - MC DDRCloser to my Heart (jun remix) - NM feat. Heather ElmerDesert Journey - dj TAKAescape - U1  Krystal BINTO YOUR HEART ("Roughage" remix) - NAOKI feat. YASMINEKYOKA-SUIGETSU-ROW (DDR EDITION) - TERRA feat. Uchusentai NOIZJUST BELIEVE - Lea Drop feat. Marissa ShipRacing with Time (NAOKI'S 999 remix) - jun feat. Heather TwedeSTAY (Joey Riot remix) - DANNY D</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7010">StepMania</game><game id="25047">Dance ManiaX 1ST MIX</game><game id="20673">Guitar Hero World Tour</game><game id="20403">Dance Factory</game><game id="30096">Pump It Up: Exceed</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2280564-box_ddrhp2.png</image></root>