<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20648</id><name>Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles: My Life as a King</name><description>Overview   Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles: My Life As a King is one of the first original downloadable games on the  Wii.The game can be purchased from the Wiiware channel in the Wii Shop channel. Developed by Square Enix the game takes place in the same universe, after the story of the Gamecube game  Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles.Plot    The story revolves around the young  King Leo as he's rebuilding his fathers kingdom. Leo uses a magical power called Architek granted to him by the crystal. Over the course of the game,  Leo finds out more and more about his father and the mysterious Dark Lord. There are also several smaller stories players can find by interacting with the people of Leo's kingdom.Gameplay    The gameplay is basically going through Leo's daily duties as a king. the first thing you always do is to post a behest for your adventurers to fulfill. The rest of the day is devoted to interacting with the people and building various constructions, more of which are available after your adventurers defeat certain bosses. After adventurers beat a boss, they also bring in elementite which is needed to use architek. The days go on like this, with a cutscene here and there and the occasional holiday, if you declare one.Downloadable ContentDownload content for My Life as a King was released on April 1, 2008. The download content offered new dungeons, races, buildings, and clothing. The pricing range for the content was 100 - 800 Wii Points. All the download content was released at the same time and it appears that this release will be the only DLC for My Life as a King.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1628">SimCity Societies</game><game id="10007">Dark Cloud 2</game><game id="7274">ActRaiser</game><game id="17123">ActRaiser 2</game><game id="1861">Dark Cloud</game><game id="17680">Pharaoh</game><game id="21631">Little King's Story</game><game id="21401">MySims Kingdom</game><game id="25798">Takt of Magic</game><game id="21454">Majesty 2: The Fantasy Kingdom Sim</game><game id="32248">The Sims Medieval</game><game id="24354">Magician’s Quest: Mysterious Times</game><game id="17113">Hey You, Pikachu!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3715/589732-i2icgorhrbtvkpeiszdwrgcgwvphg8_u.jpg</image></root>