<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20665</id><name>Far Cry 2</name><description>OverviewFar Cry 2 is a first-person shooter developed by Ubisoft Montreal and published by Ubisoft. It was released on October 21, 2008 in North America and on October 23, 2008 in Europe and Australia. Although featuring new characters and storylines, Ubisoft marketed Far Cry 2 as the true sequel to Far Cry. Crytek, developers of the original game, were not involved in the development of Far Cry 2. The game is available on Microsoft Windows, PlayStation 3 and Xbox 360.StoryThe game gives you a opportunity to soak up a beautiful sunset.Far Cry 2 is a sequel only in name, and is said to have absolutely no ties to the past games, other than the obvious one man army style of gameplay. As such, this game will have no mutants, no monsters, and no feral abilities such as those found in Far Cry Instincts. Instead, the player will choose one of nine playable characters. The other 8 characters whom you did not choose will then appear in other parts of the game. However, they are not like most NPCs. If they die, they will remain dead, and your missions and or story from there on out, may be drastically different. Ubisoft has stressed this as one of the many things that contribute to the replayability of Far Cry 2. These NPCs will also come in handy when you "die". If your health reaches zero, and you have recently asked your buddy to be on stand by while visiting a safe house then a small FMV plays of that Buddy pulling you out of battle and saving you. They will give you a sidearm and then carry on.As you play FC2 you are working towards the common goal of finding and assassinating an arms dealer known as The Jackal. The Jackal is the sole reason civil war consumes the game's African locale because he continues dealing arms to both sides of the conflict. However, there are multiple endings due to the dynamic elements of the game (e.g. the aforementioned death of a buddy NPC). One of Far Cry 2's much touted elements is its dynamic gameplay; every decision you make may end up impacting the story. If one of the mercenaries were to die, the game would re-organize the social structure according to that mercenary's death. You can ally your self with friendly NPCs who can provide perks to help you make your way through the game world.GameplayPropagating fire.Far Cry 2 takes place in a large, open-world, fictional African country; which is complete with towns, bodies of water, deserts, and a number of enemy encampments and bases to attack of infiltrate. The map is approximately 52 square kilometers which is larger than Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas or Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion. Far Cry 2 is powered by the DUNIA Engine (in many languages this means "earth" or "world"), which is compatible with PC, Xbox 360, and PlayStation 3. The engine features a dynamic day/night cycle, real-time weather effects and persistent environmental decay (such as trees that snap apart and then regrow over time), as well as fire propagation affected by weather, which allows the player to set fires to destroy or distract, possibly even killing enemies. Animals are also included in the game, although only herbivorous animals. Although carnivorous animals were rumored to be downloadable content, they were never released or announced. These dynamic gameplay elements encourage the player to play the game in a number of different ways.The environment of Far Cry 2 is packed full of enemies. Over the course of the game players will encounter many guard outposts, safe houses, and military checkpoints that are swarming with APR and UFLL forces. Both factions will engage in combat if they spot you no matter what your standing with the faction, and it is never clear exactly what faction the soldiers belong to because they do not wear uniforms or any other form of identification. These two things were the result of a design choice reflected in multiple main character's dialogues with the player, where they reflect on the fact that the player is a "deniable asset", and explain that even "allied" soldiers will attempt to kill you.Factors including weather, day and night cycles and "advanced" A.I. behavior help make the player improvise. The artificial intelligence does several things to create a more realistic enemy. Enemy troops from both the UFLL and APR will sleep, eat and patrol like real people. In the afternoons they may be active and vehicles may be patrolling the woods and desert whereas at night or at dawn the mood and activity will be slower and more relaxed. The AI also can do such things things as pursing the enemy when their weapons or vehicles are stolen or hijacked. They will hunt you down, but again, depending on the mood, will determine just how ugly they choose to get.Some player-usable vehicles include (but are not limited to):BoatsHang glidersJeepsBuggiesLarge truckSmall carIn Far Cry 2, safehouses play an important role. At a safehouse you can rest, restock, and meet with "buddies" and save the game. There are many of them scattered around the environment, and are marked by a tent icon on the map. Before you can use a safehouse you must clear its immediate vicinity of enemy soldiers. After that you can safely enter and gain access to the cot, ammo, gun crates, and medical supplies inside. With the cot you can sleep until a certain time of day, which is useful if you want to get up in the middle of the night to go attack a heavily guarded enemy camp. Weapon crates can be purchased at the arms dealer for rough diamonds and are used to store weapons. As long as you have a corresponding crate for the type of weapon you are holding, you can put it into the crate to store for future use, which is useful if you want to hide backup weapons in your safehouses in case you ever get into a tight spot. As you and your buddies use your safehouses, the amount of supplies stored there will increase. You will find more ammo and first aid supplies on your shelves.The game features officially licensed jeeps, which are driven in first person.Weapons and vehicles can fail, due to things such as jamming, stalling, or have engine failure depending on how long you use it for. Several vehicles have a turret but not all of them have, for example: the Datsun look-alike, the big truck, the one person buggy and a few more do not have a turret. NPCs, however, will not get into vehicles with you; The player must get out of the driver's seat and into the turret. Vehicles have two states of disrepair. One is a white smoke that is coming from the engine and the other is a black smoke. Black smoke means that failing to soon repair your vehicle will kill the engine and stop your vehicle dead in its tracks. To repair a vehicle simply walk towards the engine and press Y or triangle. Your character will then take out a wrench and tighten what gamers are calling 'the magic bolt' on the engine several times which seems to repair the vehicle completely.Injury is important in the world of Far Cry 2. Your character will have a five bar health meter. If any bars get only partially depleted they will regenerate automatically, but any bars that are fully depleted will have to be restored by using a syringe (or drinking water bottles that are commonly found at camps around the world). You can carry five syringes at a time at the beginning of the game and one syringe will fully restore your health as long as you have more than one health bar section left. If you have less than one bar section remaining then the player's character will remove bullets from their body, snap fingers back into position and even splint broken bones which takes significantly longer to do than using a syringe, so healing early is a wise thing to do. There are said to be over 60 different animations regarding your characters health.In Far Cry 2, players will have many ways of obtaining missions. The main way of obtaining missions will be talking to persons of interest like faction leaders at their respective headquarters or buddies at the local bar. Once you begin a conversation that involves them needing work done you can press a button to obtain an info folder from them. Contained in the folder will be the coordinates of your objective for your map and a short description of your mission that can be accessed from the pause menu in case you forget something. These missions usually involve destroying some strategic thing around the world like fuel tanks, vehicles, or VIPs. Missions can also be taken on from cell phone towers. Approaching a box on the cell phone tower will give you the option to tap into the tower, which will cause you phone to ring. After picking up the phone a heavily distorted voice will tell you the location of someone that they want assassinated and tell you that payment will be supplied as soon as the job is done.One thing in Far Cry 2 will always be haunting you no matter who you kill, is your malaria. Very soon after the game starts you contract the disease, and you have to start carrying malaria pills to control your symptoms. You are given a nice supply of the pills at the beginning, but eventually these run out and you need to find more. The local priest can help you with this, but is reluctant at first because of the fact that you are a mercenary. Eventually he gives in because he hates to see people sick, and gives you the location of an Underground house. These Underground houses are the hideouts of the few unfortunate civilians remaining in the country. They have malaria pills, but in turn you will need to complete a task for them to get the pills. When a malaria attack strikes, you must take a pill within a certain amount of time or else you will not survive. A malaria attack while swimming can result in your character drowning.WeaponsThe player has access to a large amount of weapons in Far Cry 2, all of which are based on real weapons in the real world. The player has 3 slots to load their weapons into, each representing a three different categories of weapons.Primary WeaponsYou primary weapons which are generally wielded with two hands. This includes battle rifles, assault rifles, sniper rifles, shotguns, a silenced sub-machine gun, and grenade launchers.AK - 47DifficultyCasualNormalHardcoreInfamousDefault30 + 15030 + 9030 + 9030 + 60Ammo Upgrade30 + 30030 + 15030 + 12030 + 90Weapon Class: Assault RifleMagazine Capacity:30Accuracy Upgrade:2 DiamondsFire Mode:AutomaticReliability Upgrade:2 DiamondsWeapon Cost:10 DiamondsAmmo Upgrade:10 Diamonds (Assault Webbing)Shop Availability:Leboa-Sako, Convoy 2Multiplayer Availability:Commando, Level 2Weapon description and Field NotesEven with its age, the AK-47 remains one of the best assault rifles available. It is one of the favorites of local militias and mercenaries because it is one of the most reliable weapons in the game. A drawback of the AK-47 however, is that it is not the most accurate rifle, but it does decent damage at close to medium ranges. The accuracy can be less of an issue if you fire in smaller bursts for greater control over the weapon. There is also golden version of the AK-47, which is even more reliable.AR - 16DifficultyCasualNormalHardcoreInfamousDefault30 + 15030 + 9030 + 9030 + 60Ammo Upgrade30 + 30030 + 15030 + 12030 + 90Weapon Class: Assault RifleMagazine Capacity:30Accuracy Upgrade:5 DiamondsFire Mode:3 round burstReliability Upgrade:5 DiamondsWeapon Cost:20 DiamondsAmmo Upgrade:10 Diamonds (Assault Webbing)Shop Availability:Bowa-Seko, Convoy 2Multiplayer Availability:Saboteur, Level 4Weapon description and Field NotesThe AR-16 is probably one of the best assault rifles available in the game. It becomes available when you have finished the second convoy mission in the southern sector (Bowa-Seko). It is the only assault rifle equipped with magnified reflex scope, instead of just the more common iron sights found on other weapons. The scope has green dot that helps you aim at your targets, which fits nicely with the AR-16's three-round burst fire; allowing minimal recoil for highly accurate shots. Reliability is much lower to a rifle like the AK-47, however.AS50DifficultyCasualNormalHardcoreInfamousDefault5 + 455 + 255 + 255 + 15Ammo Upgrade5 + 855 + 455 + 355 + 25Weapon Class: Sniper RifleMagazine Capacity:5Accuracy Upgrade:8 DiamondsFire Mode:Semi-AutomaticReliability Upgrade:8 DiamondsWeapon Cost:35 DiamondsAmmo Upgrade:15 Diamonds (Marksman Bandolier)Shop Availability:Bowa-Seko, Convoy 3Multiplayer Availability:Sharpshooter, Level 4Weapon description and Field Notes:The AS50 is the ultimate high-powered sniper rifle. It has the longest effective range in the game, along with the highest damage output of all the firearms. It is capable of destroying enemy vehicles with only a few shots. It is recommended that you aim at engine block of the vehicles to yield the most damage per shot. The AS50 is of course effective against softer targets like humans, and does not require a headshot for a guaranteed one shot, one kill. However, the drawbacks of the AS50 are that it is extremely expensive, it degrades at a quick rate, and can jam after only a short amount of usage.Dragunov SVDDifficultyCasualNormalHardcoreInfamousDefault10 + 4010 + 2010 + 2010 + 10Ammo Upgrade10 + 8010 + 4010 + 3010 + 20Weapon Class: Sniper RifleMagazine Capacity:10Accuracy Upgrade:5 DiamondsFire Mode:Semi-AutomaticReliability Upgrade:5 DiamondsWeapon Cost:20 DiamondsAmmo Upgrade:15 Diamonds (Marksman Bandolier)Shop Availability:Leboa-Sako, Convoy 4Multiplayer Availability:Sharpshooter, Level 2Weapon description and Field NotesThe Dragunov SVD is an old Soviet-era designed sniper rifle. This rifle is one the more efficient sniper rifles. What it lacks in power compared to the other sniper rifles is compensated by a higher rate of fire and large magazine size. This allows a sniper to shoot 10 rounds in much faster succession. The Dragunov’s high rate of fire makes it a great weapons for quickly sniping multiple targets.FAL ParatrooperDifficultyCasualNormalHardcoreInfamousDefault30 + 15030 + 9030 + 9030 + 60Ammo Upgrade30 + 30030 + 15030 + 12030 + 90Weapon Class: Assault RifleMagazine Capacity:30Accuracy Upgrade:3 DiamondsFire Mode:AutomaticReliability Upgrade:3 DiamondsWeapon Cost:10 DiamondsAmmo Upgrade:10 Diamonds (Assault Webbing)Shop Availability:Bowa-Seko, StartMultiplayer Availability:Commando, Level 4Weapon description and Field NotesThe FAL Paratrooper one of the most balanced assault rifles in Far Cry 2. It is very accurate at long distance, but a small drawback is that is not as reliable as the AK-47. However, it makes up for it by having significantly less recoil, making it easier to handle and keep your aim on targets. Firing the FAL Paratrooper in small bursts is still recommended, as with all assault rifles.G3-KA4DifficultyCasualNormalHardcoreInfamousDefault30 + 15030 + 9030 + 9030 + 60Ammo Upgrade30 + 30030 + 15030 + 12030 + 90Weapon Class: Assault RifleMagazine Capacity:30Accuracy Upgrade:3 DiamondsFire Mode:AutomaticReliability Upgrade:3 DiamondsWeapon Cost:6 DiamondsAmmo Upgrade:10 Diamonds (Assault Webbing)Shop Availability:Leboa-Sako, StartMultiplayer Availability:Commando, Level 4Weapon description and Field NotesThe G3-KA4 is one of the most common assault rifles you will encounter. It is not a bad weapon, but it is weaker in the damage output compared to the other assault rifles you can obtain. The G3-KA4 is also not very reliable, and has a high tendency to jam. While you should replace this weapon quite quickly, if you need to replace this weapon you can just pick up a new one when the current one starts to jam because it is so commonly found on enemies.Homeland 37DifficultyCasualNormalHardcoreInfamousDefault6 + 666 + 426 + 426 + 30Ammo Upgrade6 + 1266 + 666 + 546 + 42Weapon Class: Assault RifleMagazine Capacity:6Accuracy Upgrade:1 DiamondsFire Mode:Pump - ActionReliability Upgrade:1 DiamondsWeapon Cost:4 DiamondsAmmo Upgrade:10 Diamonds (Shotgun Bandolier)Shop Availability:Leboa-Sako, StartMultiplayer Availability:Guerilla, Level 1Weapon description and Field NotesIf you need to weapon that are good at close combat, the Homeland 37 is and excellent shotgun. It is the most basic pump-action shotgun, which means it has a low rate of fire, but the simple design makes to jam very rarely, which is an important trait during close combat. You must reload the weapon one shell at a time, which means it will take longer to fully reload your weapon. The Homeland 37 is a very cheap weapon and packs a powerful punch. Both upgrades for the shotgun is a merely sum of two diamonds.M1903DifficultyCasualNormalHardcoreInfamousDefault5 + 455 + 255 + 255 + 15Ammo Upgrade5 + 855 + 455 + 355 + 25Weapon Class: Sniper RifleMagazine Capacity:5Accuracy Upgrade:3 DiamondsFire Mode:Bolt - ActionReliability Upgrade:3 DiamondsWeapon Cost:10 DiamondsAmmo Upgrade:15 Diamonds (Marksman Bandolier)Shop Availability:Leboa-Sako, StartMultiplayer Availability:Sharpshooter, Level 1Weapon description and Field NotesThe bolt-action M1903 sniper rifle has a large drawback compared to the other sniper rifles, as the bolt-action design means you have to come out of the zoomed view of the sniper scope after firing to operate the bolt-action. This also means that it does not have a great rate of fire. However, it is most accurate sniper rifle in the game, it is deadly at any range. If you make your shots count, this is a great sniper rifle. Being the first sniper rifle in the game, it will serve you well until you move up to the more advanced and modern designs.MGL-140DifficultyCasualNormalHardcoreInfamousDefault4 + 164 + 84 + 84 + 4Ammo Upgrade4 + 244 + 164 + 124 + 8Weapon Class: Grenade LauncherMagazine Capacity:4Accuracy Upgrade:8 DiamondsFire Mode:Semi - AutomaticReliability Upgrade:8 DiamondsWeapon Cost:35 DiamondsAmmo Upgrade:10 Diamonds (Grenadier Webbing)Shop Availability:Bowa-Seko, Convoy 3Multiplayer Availability:Rebel, Level 4Weapon description and Field NotesThe multiple grenade launcher (MGL) can swiftly fire 40mm high-explosive rounds. The grenades are fed by drum-like cylinder, not so different from the common revolver. A difference to the M-79 grenade launcher is that it fires its rounds in a flatter trajectory, making the MGL-140 easier to aim. In addition, it features a magnified scope, which make it a lot easier to get a direct hit with fired grenades at longer ranges. This intuitive targeting makes it possible to engage the enemy at a tremendously long range, making it ideal to take out vehicles and grouped personnel.Silent MP5DifficultyCasualNormalHardcoreInfamousDefault30 + 15030 + 9030 + 9030 + 60Ammo Upgrade30 + 30030 + 15030 + 12030 + 90Weapon Class: Submachine gunMagazine Capacity:30Accuracy Upgrade:5 DiamondsFire Mode:AutomaticReliability Upgrade:5 DiamondsWeapon Cost:20 DiamondsAmmo Upgrade:10 Diamonds (Assault Webbing)Shop Availability:Leboa-Sako, Convoy 3Multiplayer Availability:Saboteur, Level 2Weapon description and Field NotesThis MP5 is a silent variant of the popular MP5 sub-machine gun, as it uses a sound suppressor that muffles sound and helps eliminate muzzle flash. This is a truly game-changing weapon, as it allows you to silently remove guards without the risk of detection. A drawback however, is that the suppressor greatly reduces the MP5’s effective range and damage output, meaning headshots with this weapon are required for maximum effectiveness.SPAS-12DifficultyCasualNormalHardcoreInfamousDefault12 + 6012 + 3612 + 3612 + 24Ammo Upgrade12 + 12012 + 6012 + 4812 + 36Weapon Class: ShotgunMagazine Capacity:12Accuracy Upgrade:3 DiamondsFire Mode:Semi - AutomaticReliability Upgrade:3 DiamondsWeapon Cost:10 DiamondsAmmo Upgrade:10 Diamonds (Shotgun Bandolier)Shop Availability:Leboa-Sako, Convoy 3Multiplayer Availability:Guerilla, Level 2Weapon description and Field NotesThe SPAS-12 is a semi-automatic shotgun design which is ideal for close combat. A drawback of the shorter barrel is that the shotgun has a lower range than other shotguns. Nevertheless, it has very decent rate of fire, but is hampered recoil. The SPAS-12 features a internal tube magazine holding 12 shells, but when reloading it must be loaded one shell at a time, just like the pump-action shotgun.USAS-12DifficultyCasualNormalHardcoreInfamousDefault12 + 6012 + 3612 + 3612 + 24Ammo Upgrade12 + 12012 + 6012 + 4812 + 36Weapon Class: ShotgunMagazine Capacity:12Accuracy Upgrade:8 DiamondsFire Mode:AutomaticReliability Upgrade:8 DiamondsWeapon Cost:35 DiamondsAmmo Upgrade:10 Diamonds (Shotgun Bandolier)Shop Availability:Bowa-Seko, Convoy 4Multiplayer Availability:Guerilla, Level 4Weapon description and Field NotesThe USAS-12 is a fully automatic shotgun. This gives the USAS-12 an advantage in stopping power over the other shotguns in Far Cry 2, as the shotgun possesses a rate of fire that cannot be compared. Holding down the trigger will release a devastating amount of damage, but will also be followed by an incredible amount of recoil. It is a phenomenal close quarter combat weapon, as the magazine reload allows you to reload faster than any other shotgun model. Reliability is a problem with the weapon however, so be prepared to replace it often.Secondary WeaponsMostly one-handed firearms such as pistols, sub-machine guns, a flare gun, and IEDs.Eagle .50DifficultyCasualNormalHardcoreInfamousDefault8 + 408 + 2412 + 248 + 16Ammo Upgrade8 + 808 + 4012 + 328 + 24Weapon Class: PistolMagazine Capacity:8Accuracy Upgrade:3 DiamondsFire Mode:Semi - AutomaticReliability Upgrade:3 DiamondsWeapon Cost:10 DiamondsAmmo Upgrade:7 Diamonds (Pistol Belt)Shop Availability:Bowa-Seko, StartMultiplayer Availability:Gunner, Level 1Weapon description and Field NotesThe Desert Eagle .50 is a massive handgun. The Eagle’s .50 caliber rounds can deliver a powerful shot that can neutralize or immobilize with just one shot. Drawbacks of the weapon include a slow rate of fire and a very nasty recoil that makes the barrel go skyward with each shot.Flare PistolDifficultyCasualNormalHardcoreInfamousDefault1 + 181 + 121 + 91 + 6Ammo Upgrade1 + 241 + 181 + 121 + 9Weapon Class: PistolMagazine Capacity:1Accuracy Upgrade:1 DiamondsFire Mode:Single ShotReliability Upgrade:1 DiamondsWeapon Cost:4 DiamondsAmmo Upgrade:10 Diamonds (Pyrotechnic Satchel)Shop Availability:Leboa-Sako, Convoy 1Multiplayer Availability:Sharpshooter, Level 3Weapon description and Field NotesMercenaries and the local militia signal for reinforcements with flare pistols. Flare pistols are not that effective as an offensive weapon, but if you are excellent shooter you can hit an enemy and he will catch fire and will burn to death in seconds. Flare pistols can also be used as a diversion by starting fires around enemy bases. Flare pistols can only load one shot at time, meaning you will need to reload after every shot fired.Improvised Explosive Device (IED)DifficultyCasualNormalHardcoreInfamousDefault5332Ammo Upgrade8543Weapon Class: ExplosiveMagazine Capacity:Not availableAccuracy Upgrade:3 DiamondsFire Mode:Remote DetonatedReliability Upgrade:3 DiamondsWeapon Cost:10 DiamondsAmmo Upgrade:10 Diamonds (Grenadier Webbing)Shop Availability:Leboa-Sako, StartMultiplayer Availability:Guerilla/Saboteur, Level 3Weapon description and Field NotesImprovised Explosive Devices are bombs constructed by using any readily available explosives, such as land mines, pipe bombs, or mortar shells. Just attach a remote detonation device to an existing explosive, and you have a IED. These bombs can be useful during sabotage-oriented missions. To use it, just place it next to your target, move to a safe distance, and detonate the IED. You can also use multiple IEDs at a time, meaning you can string together are much larger explosion which is useful for attacking convoys.M-79 Grenade LauncherDifficultyCasualNormalHardcoreInfamousDefault1 + 51 + 31 + 31 + 2Ammo Upgrade1 + 81 + 51 + 41 + 3Weapon Class: Grenade LauncherMagazine Capacity:1Accuracy Upgrade:5 DiamondsFire Mode:Single ShotReliability Upgrade:5 DiamondsWeapon Cost:20 DiamondsAmmo Upgrade:10 Diamonds (Grenadier Webbing)Shop Availability:Bowa-Seko, Convoy 1Multiplayer Availability:Commando, Level 3Weapon description and Field NotesThe M-79 grenade launcher is a single-shot weapons with powerful 40mm grenade rounds. The rounds are highly explosive, and are effective against both personnel and vehicles, making this weapon an outstanding choice as secondary weapon. You have to aim a bit higher to compensate for the large arc of the launcher. Enemies in the game do not carry this weapon, as it is only available at the weapon shop.MAC-10DifficultyCasualNormalHardcoreInfamousDefault30 + 15030 + 9030 + 9030 + 60Ammo Upgrade30 + 30030 + 15030 + 12030 + 90Weapon Class: SMGMagazine Capacity:30Accuracy Upgrade:3 DiamondsFire Mode:AutomaticReliability Upgrade:3 DiamondsWeapon Cost:10 DiamondsAmmo Upgrade:10 Diamonds (Light Assault Webbing)Shop Availability:Leboa-Sako, Convoy 2Multiplayer Availability:Guerilla, Level 1; Gunner, Level 3Weapon description and Field NotesThe MAC-10 is a compact sub-machinegun with very high rate of fire, which compensates for the low damage output. A fast burst can quickly kill a target. The MAC-10 should only be used as a close quarter combat weapon due to the limited range. It takes some practice to master the weapon, as it can be very difficult to control the recoil, so short bursts are recommended. The MAC-10 also chews through magazines at a very fast rate, so it will require many reloads. Even with these drawbacks, the MAC-10 is a good partner to accompany a sniper-rifle.MakarovDifficultyCasualNormalHardcoreInfamousDefault8 + 408 + 248 + 2430 + 16Ammo Upgrade8 + 808 + 408 + 3230 + 24Weapon Class: PistolMagazine Capacity:8Accuracy Upgrade:1 DiamondsFire Mode:Semi -AutomaticReliability Upgrade:1 DiamondsWeapon Cost:4 DiamondsAmmo Upgrade:7 Diamonds (Pistol Belt)Shop Availability:Leboa-Sako, StartMultiplayer Availability:Sharpshooter/Rebel, Level 1Weapon description and Field NotesThe Makarov is one of the most common pistols found in the game. Most local militia and foreign mercenaries carry a Makarov, so buying it at the weapon shop is not all that necessary as it can be easy be picked up from your victims. The weapon is far from the most powerful secondary weapon you can get your hands on, but it is actually the most accurate pistol. The recoil is minimal, so it makes it quite easy to keep aim on your targets.Silent Makarov 6P9DifficultyCasualNormalHardcoreInfamousDefault8 + 408 + 248 + 2430 + 16Ammo Upgrade8 + 808 + 408 + 3230 + 24Weapon Class: PistolMagazine Capacity:8Accuracy Upgrade:2 DiamondsFire Mode:Semi -AutomaticReliability Upgrade:2 DiamondsWeapon Cost:6 DiamondsAmmo Upgrade:7 Diamonds (Pistol Belt)Shop Availability:Leboa-Sako, Convoy 1Multiplayer Availability:Saboteur, Level 1Weapon description and Field NotesThe Makarov 6P9 is nearly identical to the standard Makarov but is equipped with a sound suppressor, minimizing the weapon’s report and eliminating muzzle flash. The Makarov is the first silent weapon available for purchase. It is very deadly if you score a headshot, but if you miss, it runs the risk of possibly alerting nearby enemies. The recoil is minimal, so accuracy is high even when being fired rapidly.Star .45DifficultyCasualNormalHardcoreInfamousDefault8 + 408 + 248 + 2430 + 16Ammo Upgrade8 + 808 + 408 + 3230 + 24Weapon Class: PistolMagazine Capacity:8Accuracy Upgrade:2 DiamondsFire Mode:Semi -AutomaticReliability Upgrade:2 DiamondsWeapon Cost:6 DiamondsAmmo Upgrade:7 Diamonds (Pistol Belt)Shop Availability:Leboa-Sako, Convoy 1Multiplayer Availability:Commando, Level 1Weapon description and Field NotesThe Star .45 pistol is a variation on the .45-caliber handgun utilized by the US military from 1911 to 1985. The damage output by the Star .45 has a good balance between the under-powered Makarov and the high-powered Eagle .50. This is a very reliable pistol, a feature that explains why it has been a popular choice for nearly hundred years. While not as accurate as the Makarov, it is still much easier to control than the Eagle .50.UziDifficultyCasualNormalHardcoreInfamousDefault30 + 15030 + 9030 + 9030 + 60Ammo Upgrade30 + 30030 + 15030 + 12030 + 90Weapon Class: SMGMagazine Capacity:30Accuracy Upgrade:5 DiamondsFire Mode:AutomaticReliability Upgrade:5 DiamondsWeapon Cost:20 DiamondsAmmo Upgrade:10 Diamonds (Light Assault Webbing)Shop Availability:Bowa-Seko, StartMultiplayer Availability:Rebel, Level 3Weapon description and Field NotesThe Uzi is an improvement over the MAC-10, and can be obtained from the weapon shop as soon you enter Bowa-Seko. This sub-machine gun is much more reliable than the MAC-10, as it is less likely to jam and much easier to control in comparison. In addition, it has a better range than the MAC-10, so it is the perfect backup weapon for a sniper that needs some firepower.Special WeaponsIn this category, the weapons are mostly heavier and have a specialized purpose, including light machine guns, RPGs, a flamethrower, a mortar, and a dart rifle.Carl G Rocket LauncherDifficultyCasualNormalHardcoreInfamousDefault1 + 51 + 31 + 31 + 2Ammo Upgrade1 + 81 + 51 + 41 + 3Weapon Class: Rocket LauncherMagazine Capacity:1Accuracy Upgrade:8 DiamondsFire Mode:Single ShotReliability Upgrade:8 DiamondsWeapon Cost:35 DiamondsAmmo Upgrade:15 Diamonds (Rocketeer Satchel)Shop Availability:Bowa-Seko, Convoy 4Multiplayer Availability:Gunner, Level 2Weapon description and Field NotesThe Carl G Rocket Launcher is one of most well-liked anti-tank weapon systems in the world. The payload is a high-explosive rocket that can be guided by continuing to aim at the target after it has been fired. This makes the Carl G ideal for moving targets. Even though the Carl G is designed to destroy vehicles, it can be effectively used to take out human targets as well.Dart RifleDifficultyCasualNormalHardcoreInfamousDefault5 + 455 + 255 + 255 + 15Ammo Upgrade5 + 855 + 455 + 355 + 25Weapon Class: Sniper RifleMagazine Capacity:5Accuracy Upgrade:3 DiamondsFire Mode:Bolt - ActionReliability Upgrade:3 DiamondsWeapon Cost:10 DiamondsAmmo Upgrade:10 Diamonds (Marksman Bandolier)Shop Availability:Leboa-Sako, Convoy 4Multiplayer Availability:Saboteur, Level 1Weapon description and Field NotesThe Dart Rifle is the ultimate stealth weapon in Far Cry 2. The Dart Rifle has the ability to neutralize targets at long range without a sound. It fires a high-velocity sub-sonic dart that is deadly with a single headshot, and also features a magnified scope. The weapon is a bolt-action design, so you have to take come out of aiming with the scope to load a new dart. Headshots are of importance, as a dart to any other body parts allows the victim to be alerted, which will attract other hostiles.LPO-50DifficultyCasualNormalHardcoreInfamousDefault500300300200Ammo Upgrade1.000500400300Weapon Class: FlamethowerMagazine Capacity:Not availableAccuracy Upgrade:5 DiamondsFire Mode:Continuous-FlowReliability Upgrade:5 DiamondsWeapon Cost:20 DiamondsAmmo Upgrade:10 Diamonds (Pyrotechnic Satchel)Shop Availability:Bowa-Seko, Convoy 3Multiplayer Availability:Rebel, Level 1Weapon description and Field NotesThe LPO-50 flamethrower dates back to the Soviet-era. It features very high damage, but the effective range is extremely short meaning it is most effective when deployed in close combat. It does not feature any aiming mechanism or iron sights. Just aim it in the direction you want engulfed in flames. A visible fuel gauge will tell you how much fuel you have in reserve.M-249 SAWDifficultyCasualNormalHardcoreInfamousDefault100 + 400100 + 200100 + 200100 + 100Ammo Upgrade100 + 900100 + 400100 + 300100 + 200Weapon Class: Light MachinegunMagazine Capacity:100Accuracy Upgrade:5 DiamondsFire Mode:AutomaticReliability Upgrade:5 DiamondsWeapon Cost:20 DiamondsAmmo Upgrade:15 Diamonds (Gunner Pack)Shop Availability:Bowa-Seko, Convoy 1Multiplayer Availability:Gunner, Level 4Weapon description and Field NotesThe M-249 Squad Automatic Weapon (SAW) can be a great choice for special weapon. It features a very large magazine capacity, and well-balanced features. It has a slightly lower damage output and is a bit less reliable when compared to the PKM, but it makes up this weakness with a higher rate of fire and higher accuracy. The lower recoil makes it more easy to keep on target than the PKM, even when firing in longer bursts.PKMDifficultyCasualNormalHardcoreInfamousDefault100 + 400100 + 200100 + 200100 + 100Ammo Upgrade100 + 900100 + 400100 + 300100 + 200Weapon Class: Light MachinegunMagazine Capacity:100Accuracy Upgrade:3 DiamondsFire Mode:AutomaticReliability Upgrade:3 DiamondsWeapon Cost:10 DiamondsAmmo Upgrade:15 Diamonds (Gunner Pack)Shop Availability:Leboa-Sako, Convoy 2Multiplayer Availability:Gunner, Level 1Weapon description and Field NotesThe PKM is the first light machinegun available in Far Cry 2. It is great addition, as it gives you heavy firepower and a good rate of fire. The recoil is rather extreme however, causing the weapon to buck wildly with each burst you fire. Firing in small bursts is recommended. Despite its drawbacks, the PKM is more reliable and jams less frequently than M-249 SAW, which makes this a solid overall weapon.RPG-7 Rocket LauncherDifficultyCasualNormalHardcoreInfamousDefault1 + 51 + 31 + 31 + 2Ammo Upgrade1 + 81 + 51 + 41 + 3Weapon Class: Rocket LauncherMagazine Capacity:1Accuracy Upgrade:5 DiamondsFire Mode:Single ShotReliability Upgrade:5 DiamondsWeapon Cost:20 DiamondsAmmo Upgrade:15 Diamonds (Rocketeer Satchel)Shop Availability:Leboa-Sako, Convoy 4Multiplayer Availability:Rebel, Level 2Weapon description and Field NotesThe RPG-7 first appeared on the market in the early 1960s and remains as one of the most common anti-tank weapons in the world. There are several variants of the weapon, but this model sports an iron sight that is not that much different from an assault rifle. It is a fire and forget weapon, meaning unlike the Carl G rocket launcher, the rocket cannot be guided after being fired. It travels in a relatively straight path to the target. It is excellent to use against vehicles, but takes some training to hit moving targets.Ammo upgradesAmmo upgrades are purchased from the weapon shop’s computer. These upgrades increase the particular ammo types that can be carried. After being purchased, they appear in the “upgrades menu” of your in-game journal. The amount of ammo carried is also affected by the difficulty setting, which is detailed on this page in the Weapons section. For the cost, availability, and general description of each ammo upgrade, see the table below.NameDescriptionAvailabilityCostAssault WebbingIncreases the amount of assault rifle and silent MP5 ammo carried.Bowa-Seko10Grenadier WebbingIncreases the number of grenades and IEDs carried.Leboa-Sako10Gunner PackIncreases the amount of light machine gun ammo carried.Bowa-Seko15Light Assault WebbingIncreases the amount of SMG ammo carried.Leboa-Sako10Marksman BandolierIncreases the amount of Sniper ammo carried.Bowa-Seko15Pistol BeltIncreases the amount of pistol ammo carried.Leboa-Sako7Pyrotechnic SatchelIncreases the amount of moltovs, flares and flamethrower fuel carried.Bowa-Seko10Rocketeer SatchelIncreases the amount of rocket and mortar ammo carried.Bowa-Seko15Shotgun BandolierIncrease the amount of shotguns shells carried.Leboa-Sako10MissionsFar Cry 2 has many different types of missions, each yielding different types of rewards.Story Missions - All types of objectives, some of which can affect the outcome on the ending and the whole game.Faction Missions - These missions are given by the warlords and other leaders of the factions. The reward in most cases are diamonds and reputation.Underground Missions - These missions are important, as they are given by the Underground faction that protects the civilians in Far Cry 2. Missions usually involve delivering passports to civilians that are trying to escape the country. Malaria medicine is the reward for these missions.Buddy Side-Missions - These are alternate objectives to your faction missions. Your best buddy in Far Cry 2 will often make suggestions as to how to complete a faction mission. The reward for these missions include reputation, buddy history, and safehouse upgrades (an assault truck, extra resources, etc).Personal Buddy Missions - Your buddies may request help with their personal missions. There are 2 missions per buddy. To gain access to these missions, visit the bars and speak to them to accept the missions. The reward is reputation and buddy history.Convoy missions - These missions are given by vendors at the weapon shops. All them involve taking out weapon convoys. Rewards include gaining access to new weapons for purchase at the weapon shops.Assassinations - Given to you by hacking into cell towers. These missions require you to eliminate a certain target, with diamonds as reward.Act I: Tutorial MissionsThe Road to PalaTown EscapeLumber CampPit FighterSlaughterhouseDunk CageDeliveryAct I: UFLL MissionsDirect SpearOeduard RexGrow OpAct I: APR MissionsCop KillerReap What Ye SowJunkyard DogAct I: World 1 FinaleFool's ErrandDefense ReversalExile to World 2Reprisal KillingAct II: World 2 PrimerHornet's NestJackal's Buddy RescueAct II: UFLL MissionsFlying JackalSubverting: Flying JackalBunker BusterSubverting Bunker BusterA Bridge Too FarSubverting A Bridge Too FarAct II: APR MissionsDental PlanSubverting: Dental PlanRadio ArmageddonSubverting: Radio ArmageddonPipeline CrossingSubverting Pipeline CrossingAct II: The Chaos BeginsPrison BreakAct III: Fractured FactionsReprisal Killing vs. UFLLReprisal Killing vs. APRHouse Cleaning: Part 1House Cleaning: Part 2Act III: World 2 FinaleHeart of DarknessThe Final BattleMultiplayerFar Cry 2 multiplayer supports up to 16 people (8 vs. 8) across 14 standard maps (18 including Downloadable Content), along with the ability to create, publish, use and share your own custom maps. Ranked Matches earn experience towards a persistent player rank, earning Diamonds for every level that allow you to purchase unlockables for each class. Far Cry 2 has up to 30 ranks. There are 6 classes in the game, and it's possible to upgrade each at least 3 times with the aforementioned diamonds. Custom games allow for persistence over several maps as long as the users stay in the same room for the duration of the games. Progress in Custom games is lost once a server is ended entirely.GametypesDeathmatch- Standard free-for-all game type in which players kill each other for points. The round ends when a player finally reaches the score limit.Team Deathmatch- Two teams of up to eight players each compete by killing members of the opposing team for points. Reviving other players on your team (while they are wounded) removes points from the opposite team's score. Ranked Team Deathmatch games last until the kill count reaches 100, or until 15 minutes are up.Capture the Diamond- A capture the flag variant in which players steal a case of diamonds from the opposing team's base and bring it back to theirs. In order to score a point for your team, your own diamond must be present at your base as well as theirs. Diamond carriers emit a "security smoke" to note their locations. Red smoke denotes the other team's carrier, and Green smoke reveals your own.Uprising- This is a team-based game type revolving around capturing several strategic points around the map. Each team has a captain, and the captain is the only person who can occupy a point by sitting in it for 20 seconds while being guarded by his team. Once one team has control over all of the map's strategic points, it then becomes their objective to kill the opposing captain to win the game.In ranked matches you need to get kills to get experience that allow you to rank up. When you rank up, you will get diamonds will help you upgrade your classes. When you rank up, the rank and the guns only stay with you on ranked match. Achievements can also be earned for ranking up appropriately.ClassesCommando - A standard mid-range assault class, adept at shoot-and-run tactics.Sharpshooter - A long-range class with marksman weaponry.Guerilla - A short-range class designed for ambush tactics and close-quarters combat.Rebel - An explosives-focused class, well-rounded for both offensive and defensive usage of bombs and flame weapons.Gunner - A heavy-weapons class, highly effective when grounded in one place.Saboteur - A stealth-focused class that possesses silenced weapons and carries explosives.Map Editor  SharingIn-Editor Testing.Far Cry 2 features a Map Editor, which allows players to create, share, download, rate and play on customized maps using in-game tools. The map editor is not a full "SDK editor" like the UnrealEd or HAMMER, which means that it does not allow players to import custom models or images. It features most if not all of the models found in the single-player game, and it allows players to customize many of them through a "snap" system, to create elongated bridges, unique buildings, very long ladders, etc. for greater freedom of creation. The map editor also allows for heavy terrain alterations, and comes with several special tools that allow the creator to perform detailed changes to land with simplified console controls, making the editor much easier to use than the average PC editor.PC Map Editor Interface.Maps can be made for many purposes, or one single purpose. There is a checklist in the menus of the editor that allows creators to tailor their maps to their specifications for game variants. Certain criteria must be met by the creator before the map is validated, making sure that diamond placements, capture points and spawn locations cannot be abused within measurable reason to give an advantage to one team.Players can choose to host games and share the maps from their own hard drive, or upload the map to the central server for ratings and downloads. Each platform has its own server, so a PC user won't see a PS3 user's maps. Players can search for a specific map name, sort by size or recommended player amounts, date added, rating, etc. There are also server-created "Highest Rated" lists and "Most Popular" lists. Ubisoft Montreal also maintains an "Ubisoft Recommended" list, where it promotes maps that it finds to be exceptional. Ubisoft updates the week periodically, but the Highest Rated/Most Popular list changes daily using server statistics.Additional ContentCollector's Edition.Limited (GameStop Pre-Order) Edition  Collector's EditionAnyone who pre-ordered Far Cry 2 at Gamestop was automatically signed up (at no extra charge) to receive the "limited edition" of the game. This version (which was dubbed the Gamestop Pre-order Edition by Ubisoft) contained a code that would unlock several extra missions that told the story of several men who had come before you to try killing the Jackal. These missions are estimated to provide an additional 6 hours of gameplay. This edition also came with an extremely useful map of the entire world and in a sleeve that had different cover art on it than the standard edition.The actual Collector's Edition (not the pre-order/limited edition) came housed in a wooden box and had the aforementioned map, a Far Cry 2 disk, a Far Cry 2 t-shirt, a "making of" DVD, and a code for 8 exclusive missions.DLCWeapons included in Fortune's Pack DLC.The Fortune's Pack DLC is now included with the Steam version of Far Cry 2, and is available on Xbox Live Marketplace and Playstation Network for 800 Microsoft points and $9.99 respectively. It adds:3 new weapons (Sawn off Shotgun (Secondary slot), Silenced Shotgun (Primary Slot) and High Explosive Firing Crossbow (Special Weapon Slot)2 new vehicles (Quad bike and Unimog)5 new multiplayer mapsPC System RequirementsMinimumCPU: Pentium 4 3.2 Ghz, Pentium D 2.66 Ghz, AMD Athlon 64 3500 or betterRAM: 1 GBVideo card: nVidia 6800 or ATI X1650 or better; Shader Model 3.0 required; 256 Mb of graphical memoryMedia reader: DVD-ROMHard drive space: ~12 Gig of HD space.RecommendedCPU: Intel Core 2 Duo Family, AMD 64 X2 5200 , AMD Phenom or betterRAM: 2 GBVideo card: nVidia 8600 GTS or better, ATI X1900 or better; 512 Mb of graphic memorySound: 5.1 sound card recommendedSupported video cards: NVidia 6800, NVidia 7000 series, 8000 series, 9000 series, 200 series. 8800M and 8700M supported for laptops. ATI X1650 - 1950 series, HD2000 series, HD3000 series, HD4000 series.Xbox 360 Game InstallationFar Cry 2 requires 4.5GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD. While the installation does not seem to reduce load times by much, it does seem to help the frame rate.</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11757">Crysis</game><game id="11725">S.T.A.L.K.E.R.: Shadow of Chernobyl</game><game id="20655">Battlefield: Bad Company</game><game id="20697">Mercenaries 2: World in Flames</game><game id="7633">Mercenaries: Playground of Destruction</game><game id="8197">Boiling Point: Road to Hell</game><game id="485">Delta Force: Black Hawk Down</game><game id="21524">Warhound</game><game id="1986">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six: Vegas 2</game><game id="20672">Rage</game><game id="20742">Just Cause 2</game><game id="20599">inFamous</game><game id="24035">Halo 3: ODST</game><game id="20964">Metro 2033</game><game id="26754">Crysis 2</game><game id="2133">Call of Duty 4: Modern Warfare</game><game id="24713">Modern Warfare 2</game><game id="22858">Rogue Warrior</game><game id="21236">Afrika</game><game id="26119">S.T.A.L.K.E.R.: Call of Pripyat</game><game id="21302">S.T.A.L.K.E.R.: Clear Sky</game><game id="30313">Bodycount</game><game id="40440">Miasmata</game><game id="38040">007 Legends</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2381878-win_farcry2_cropped.jpg</image></root>