<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20671</id><name>Tom Clancy's H.A.W.X</name><description>OverviewTom Clancy's H.A.W.X. (High Altitude Warfare - Experimental Squadron), is a flight combat game taking place in the same world as Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon: Advanced Warfighter. Developed by Ubisoft Romania, H.A.W.X. takes place in a world where private military companies are growing ever more powerful. As these PMCs g row, a global conflict breaks out, and one of the largest PMCs attacks the United States. In this game 50 planes will be available to the players to use in aerial combat. The game will feature four-player co-op mode in the campaign, which players will be able to jump in and out at anytime during the game. The multiplayer will support 16 players battling online to gain in-game money or experience to invest in new weapons and equipment. The developers added an Enhanced Reality System, which gives the player access to anti-crash system, radar, incoming missile detection, damage control system, weapons trajectory control, and the option to command your AI wingmen .Each target you destroy in the game will add to your experience total; the player may level up 40 times in the game, and at each level it will unlock new single player campaign missions, new aircraft, and new weapon systems to specific aircraft in the hangar. Experience can be earned both in the single-player campaign as well as the multiplayer mode of the game.CampaignThe campaign in HAWX is 18 missions long, and follows the story of the pilot Major David Crenshaw. The player will begin the game flying for the United States and particitipating in a mission to assist the Ghost Recon team down on the ground in Juarez, Mexico. Shortly thereafter the HAWX Squadron is decommissioned from the United States Air Force and is eventually contracted with the Private Military Company, Artemis. Artemis is in the business of warfare, taking contracts from different nations and companies to defend, escort, or destroy opponents to their interests; the HAWX Squadron is there to carry out those missions. The story is relatively diverse and will take the player into various situations all around the world, and for different services.The campaign is set between GRAW 2 (the first mission in HAWX is at the same time as the last mission in GRAW 2) and before the events of Endwar (The game makes mention of the joint US - EU missile shield). The game also makes mention of some of Tom Clancy Universe organisations like Third Echelon.AircraftsMig-29 Fulcrum - Built by the legendary MIG corporation in the late 1970's the Mig-29 is a generation 4 fighter that is a remarkably versatile and effective multi-purpose aircraft. Well built and relatively inexpensive it is utilized in the air forces of nearly 30 countries around the world. In addition to having a powerful engine that can propel the Mig-29 to top speeds of almost Mach 2.3 the Mig-29 and its derivatives are one of the most agile aircraft in the world. In fact, until the advent of Thrust vectoring enabled aircraft in the 2000's the Mig-29 could outperform in close combat any warplane that was currently in service.Mig-33 Super Fulcrum - The super Fulcrum is a more advanced export version of the Mig-29Su-35 Super Flanker - The Superflanker is a generation 4.5 long range heavy multi role fighter built by Russia. Unlike the western system of adding a number to designate aircraft evolutions, the Russians rename their planes as newer models are produced. As such the Su-35 is the final evolution of the legendary Su-27 series of planes that were originally built by the USSR. This model is considered to be close cousin of the Indian airforce's SU-30 MKI that is considered by many experts to be one of the most advanced and potent weapon system on the planet.Su-37 Terminator - The terminator was an experimental plane built to study thrust vectoring. For all practical purposes it is an SU-27 that has been modified with thrust vectoring engines.Su-47 Berkut - The Su-47 was originally conceived in the early 1980's to the next generation of fighters in the soviet air force. However, after the collapse of the USSR, the Su-47 was made into an advanced technological demonstrator. Its unique feature is its forward swept wings which gives it exceptionally good performance in sub-sonic speeds.F-16 FIGHTING FALCON - Built in the 1970's the generation 4.0 Falcon remains to date the most popular western aircraft ever built, with around 4400 exported to foreign countries. The falcon is considered to be a multi purpose aircraft and it has an impeccable service record. The aircraft has been constantly upgraded over the passage of time and remains a very versatile and effective platform.F-22 RAPTOR - The raptor is the world's first and only Generation 5.0 Fighter and it optimizes the USAF's dominance of the sky. Built with stealth in mind, the aircraft is capable to fighting its way into heavily defended areas and then fighting its way out of there. Although much of its specifications are classified, it is regarded as the best fighter in the world by many aviation experts.F-35 LIGHTNING II - The Lightning-2 takes the venerable F-16 platform and the heavier F-22 and incorporates many of their best features. Designed to replace the F-16, it is a single engine STOVL capable aircraft. While not as advanced as its more expensive cousin, the Raptor, the F-35 is still considered to be a generation 5.0 aircraft.Eurofighter Typhoon - Built by a consortium of European countries, the Eurofighter is a twin engined, generation 4.5 aircraft. It is considered by many experts to be the best 4.5 gen fighter and its performance has been compared very favorably to the F/A-18, F-16 and even the Generation 5.0 Raptor. Like many of the recently produced aircraft, the Typhoon is capable of Supercruising; where the aircraft is capable of supersonic flight without the use of Afterburners, saving considerable amount of fuel.JAS-39 Gripen - The latest aircraft to come out of Saab, the Gripen is a key compeitor to the Typhoon and shares many features with its European cousin. It is one of the first military aircraft made by Sweden designed to be sold to other countriesF-4G Advanced Wild Weasel - A specialised anti-radar version of the F4 Phantom. Used as part of Operation Desert Strike in the first Gulf WarF-5A Freedom Fighter - A light jet designed to be sold by the US to foreign powers needing fighters. Most famous for its role in Top Gun as the enemy MIGS and as the adversary aircraft at Top GunEF-111A RAVEN - A Electronic warfare version of the F111 AardvarkF-15C Eagle - The primary high altitude interceptor during the late stages of the Cold War. The C version is the single seaterF-5E Tiger II - An improvered version of the F5EF-117 NIGHTHAWK - The "Stealth Fighter" is in actual fact a ground attack aircraft. Most famous for its role in the first Gulf WarF-15E Strike Eagle - The multi-role version of the F15. This variant become the more important type after the end of the Cold War due to the lack of a need for interceptorsA-6A Intruder - An all weather naval ground attack aircraft. In service for 34 years, it served through Vietnam up to Desert StormMig-21 Fishbed - One of the Russian's primary fighters during the Cold WarF-15 Active - A modified F15 with thrust vectoring. Built by NASA to test thrust vectoring at high altitudeEA-6B Prowler - An electronic warefare version of the A-6Mig-25 Foxbat - A high altitude fighter, whose existence resulted in the production of the F-15FA-18C Hornet - Multirole Carrierbourne Aircraft. Also the jet used by the Blue Angels.A-7B Corsair II - A carrier-based light attack fighter. The Corsair was one of the first combat planes to feature a HUD (head-up display).FA-18 RC - A variatoin of the FA-18 model of aircrart.F-14A Tomcat - The aircraft from Top Gun. Two seater, all weather, carrier based fighterFA-18E Super Hornet - A single-seat, carrier-based, strike fighter aircraft equipped with a 20mm cannon and air-to-air or air-to-surface missiles.F-14B BombcatSu-25 Frogfoot - The Russian answer for the A10, this ground attack aircraft had its heyday over Afgahinstan in the 1980s against the MujahadeenAV-8B Harrier II - The American version of the world famous Harrier jumpjet. Currently in use with the US Marine CorpsF-14D Super TomcatSu-32 FNMIRAGE F1YF-17 CobraSu-34 FullbackMIRAGE IV PF-20 TigersharkSu-27 FlankerMIRAGE IIIYF-23 Black Widow IIMIRAGE 5X-29MIRAGE 2000 CA-10A Thunderbolt II - The Warthog, a anti-tank ground attack aircraft noted for the GAU Avenger cannon is carriesMIRAGE 2000-5F-2RAFALE CYF-12AJAGUAR - An joint project between the French and the British, this is a light ground attack aircraft. Now out of service with both the RAF and French, it still soldiers on with the Indian Air Force.Pre-order bonusFB-22 STRIKE RAPTORA-12 Avenger_IIF-18 HARVDownloadable ContentEuropean Assault PackThis pack includes six new aircraft:FB-22 Strike RaptorXA-20 Razorback (the US ground attack aircraft from Endwar)Saab 37 ViggenRafale MMirage 2000NMirage 4000The silver birds can be bought for 400 MS Points ($5.00) or $4.99 on the PlayStation Network.US Eagles PackThis pack includes an additional five aircraft:F4 Phantom IIF-111 AardvarkSR-71 BlackbirdA-12 AvengerPeak EagleThis pack can be bought for 400 MS Points ($5.00) or $4.99 on the PlayStation Network.Russian Falcons PackFive additional aircraft:MIG-23 FloggerSU-39 FrogfootM IG-31MIG-35F/A-18 with thrust vectoringThis pack can be bought for 400 MS Points ($5.00) or $4.99 on the PlayStation Network.Air SupremacyThe Air Supremacy pack brings together 16 of the aircrafts that have previously been released in the other packs, into one pack for a cheaper price.MIG-23 Flogger SU-39 Frogfoot MIG-31 MIG-35 F/A-18 with thrust vectoring F4 Phantom II F-111 Aardvark SR-71 Blackbird A-12 Avenger Peak EagleFB-22 Strike Raptor XA-20 Razorback (the US ground attack aircraft from Endwar) Saab 37 Viggen Rafale M Mirage 2000N Mirage 4000This pack can be bought for 800 MS Points on the Xbox Live Market place ($10.00) or $9.99 on the PlayStation Network.One point to make is the fact the downloads for these packs are only in KB. Therefore it is easy to assume that the packs are in fact only unlocking aircraft already in the game. Additionally, the aircraft also have to be unlocked in campaign mode by reaching certain levels.TriviaThey used a $100 million GeoEye satellite that mapped the Earth for Hawx. It's similar to the technology used for Google Earth, in fact the same company allowed Ubisoft access to 423 mile high photographs of real world locations. That's the same as being able to see objects on the ground that are at least 16 inches long.The game contains several references to other Tom Clancy games in both story elements and during the brieifings. For example, during the brief at the start of each mission, scenes from both GRAW 2 and Endwar are playing. Also, the SLAMS system from Endwar is mentioned repeatedly.This game takes place between the events of GRAW 2 and Endwar</description><genres><genre id="24">Flight Simulator</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19273">Ace Combat 6: Fires of Liberation</game><game id="12351">Lock On: Modern Air Combat</game><game id="5634">F-22 Lightning 3</game><game id="4928">F-22 Lightning II</game><game id="18744">F-22 Raptor</game><game id="9920">Ace Combat X: Skies of Deception</game><game id="13702">Red Baron Arcade</game><game id="12271">A-10 Cuba!</game><game id="20968">Heroes Over Europe</game><game id="1602">Ace Combat 04: Shattered Skies</game><game id="14827">Ace Combat 5: The Unsung War</game><game id="17960">Ace Combat Zero: The Belkan War</game><game id="20037">Ace Combat 3: Electrosphere</game><game id="24983">Stormbirds</game><game id="20722">Il-2 Sturmovik: Birds of Prey</game><game id="12289">Heatseeker</game><game id="26138">Air Legends</game><game id="32297">Ace Combat Assault Horizon</game><game id="29751">Ace Combat: Joint Assault</game><game id="23196">After Burner Climax</game><game id="35580">Top Gun: Hard Lock</game><game id="6055">Strike Commander</game><game id="43284">Ace Combat Infinity</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/13158/1048047-gb.png</image></root>