<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20675</id><name>Don King Presents: Prizefighter</name><description>GameplayDKP:P incorporates the face buttons for punching. You have a basic jab, cross, hook, and uppercut. Pulling the right trigger directs each punch to the body. By holding down the right bumper with any of the punch-buttons, you can perform "step-in" punches, which have more power and longer range. By moving the left analog stick up or down while holding the right bumper you will execute a variety of "step-around" punches, which as the name implies, are punches thrown as you step around your opponent, sometimes resulting in a better angle for the player to land the punch. Executive Producer, Matt Seymour emphasized the importance of having a 3D plane in Prizefighter the makes it possible to utilize angels for punching, as opposed to the 2D-fighting seen in previous boxing games, where both fighters are permanently locked onto each on a 2D plane fighting ring. For defense, pushing the right analog stick up or down results in a high or low block. By holding the left trigger, you can duck, weave and lean using the left analog stick. You are able to block while leaning. Also, double tapping the left analog stick towards any direction performs a "dash", which is a quick evasive move that will avoid punches when timed properly.There are three meters governing each fighter which are health, stamina and adrenaline. The health meter is depleted with every punch landed on your fighter, but staying away from the punches will slowly regain your health meter during the round. While you regain some health between rounds, the bar gets shorter as the rounds progress, depending on how much damage you take. The health meter also affects your overall speed, along with the stamina bar. The stamina meter gets drained faster than those seen in other boxing titles. Throwing a single flurry of punches could be enough to empty your stamina bar, at by then your fighter will be much slower and extremely vulnerable with his punches being significantly weaker. However, by resting for a few seconds your stamina bar will refuel. The system eliminates button mashing and forces the player to pick their spots and box as they would in a realistic manner. In addition, doing "dash" moves will quickly diminish your stamina meter. The adrenaline meter gives players access to more powerful signature punches. The meter is divided into three sections, with each section representing one signature punch. Holding the left bumper with any punch button results in different signature punches. When the meter is completely full, the player has a choice to go into "adrenaline mode" by pressing the left and right bumpers simultaneously. While in this mode, the color palette of the screen changes and the player stats are maxed out for approximately ten seconds and can punch harder and faster with no speed or stamina penalties. The adrenaline meter is filled usually from fighting well. By landing your own combos and defending well against your opponent your adrenaline meter will fill up. Most players will be able will fill at least the first section of the meter within a round, but filling the entire meter could take 2 or more rounds.The game also features one-hit KO's that result from a well places signature or step-in punch. Matches end after just one or two knockdowns, with the referee waiving the fight off without a count. The connect rate mirror real-life boxing matches, with each exhibition bout against the CPU averaging at around 37% of punches landed, as opposed to other boxing games with a relative higher rate. The AI is the toughest seen in any recent boxing game, with the CPU taking advantage of every opening and every mistake the player makes, as well as using sound defense and demonstrating overall awareness.RosterHeavyweightAndrew GolotaSamuel PeterSergei LiakhovichShannon BriggsCruiserweightChad DawsonEnzo MaccarinelliO'Neil BellSteve CunninghamMiddleweightKelly PavilkArthur AbrahamDaniel SantosEdison MirandaJoe CalzagheRicardo MayorgaRoman KarmazinWelterweightAndre BertoIvan KirpaJose Luis CastilloJulio Cesar Chavez, JrLuis CallazoLightweightJoan GuzmanJoel CasamayorJuan DiazJulio DiazNate CampbellFeatherweightChris JohnDaniel Ponce de LeonElio RojasJuan Manuel MarquezVic DarchinyanClassic BoxersJoe LuisKen NortonLarry HolmesRocky MarcianoFloyd PattersonArchie MooreJames BraddockMax BaerChris EubankNigel Benn</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="20">Boxing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8095">Fight Night Round 3</game><game id="14685">Fight Night Round 2</game><game id="21455">Black &amp; Bruised</game><game id="5372">Fight Night 2004</game><game id="20452">Fight Night Round 4</game><game id="32128">Fight Night Champion</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3699/1790547-don_king__prizefighter.jpg</image></root>