<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20684</id><name>Guitar Hero: Aerosmith</name><description>Overview Guitar Hero: Aerosmith is the second spin-off of the popular     Guitar Hero  series. It is developed by     Neversoft and published by     Activision, and is was released on June 29, 2008.  The game contains a story that mirrors the band's career, progressing from Aerosmith's first show at Nipmuc Regional High School in 1970 to the band's induction into the Rock  Roll Hall of Fame in 2001.  The game's six tiers are broken up by short videos featuring the members of Aerosmith talking about the importance of that tier's venue to the band (i.e., the experience of being signed at Max's Kansas City when that venue is reached). Longer versions of those videos can be purchased from the in-game store.  CharactersDMC performing Walk This Way The playable characters include the standard characters from    Guitar Hero III, such as    Axel Steel,   Johnny Napalm, and Lars Umlaut. These characters act as the guitarists for the opening band in career mode and can only be used while playing non-Aerosmith songs. New additions are Joe Perry, Tom Hamilton, and Brad Whitford of Aerosmith. It also features DMC of Run-DMC, who takes over as the lead singer when the player plays King of Rock or Run-DMC's version of Walk this Way, as well as being a playable guitarist. Each character (aside from the unlockable ones) have two costumes. Each costume has a set of palette-swaps that can be purchased from the in game store, The Vault. Each palette swamp not only changes their specific costume's color, but changes certain accessories/designs as well. Aside from a few extra palette swaps, the initial characters appear in the game just as they did in Guitar Hero III.Initial Character List    Axel Steel    Judy Nails    Johnny Napalm    Izzy Sparks    Xavier Stone    Lars Umlaut    Casey Lynch     MidoriUnlockable Characters (Purchased in The Vault)    Joe Perry    Tom Hamilton Brad Whitford Notable inclusionsGuitar Hero Aerosmith, while being poorly received by gaming press, included many first and lasts for the Guitar Hero franchise. It has been the only entry in the series to incorporate five band members on stage (Singer, Guitarist, Rhythm-Guitarist, Bassist and drummer) opposed to the standard four (sans rhythm-guitarist) usually implemented since the original. This was done to have all five members of Aerosmith be shown on stage at once. As a result, Neversoft had to program new camera angles and shots to compliment this change. To fill the fifth spot for the opening band, a new fictional NPC band member was created, the female rhythm guitarist. This would be her only appearance in the entire series thus far.  Musically, this was the first Guitar Hero to include a rap/hip hop song on the setlist, found in Run-DMC's  King of Rock. It was also the last game in the series to have a set-list that included covers. One feature that future GH iterations would note is the fact that all songs included on disc are master-tracks. While Guitar Hero: Aerosmith does include a majority of master recordings, four of the non-Aerosmith songs are still covered. As well as Guitar Hero: Aerosmith having the only appearance of female rhythm guitarist, it was also the last console game to feature the non-playable band first introduced in the original. Throughout the Guitar Hero franchise, playable characters were accompanied by a specific NPC singer, bassist, drummer and occasionally key-board player. These characters would stop appearing come the release of  Guitar Hero World Tour, although the male singer/drummer make a cameo appearance during the game's opening cinematic.     Track Listing Tier 1: "Getting the Band Together" (Nipmuc High School) 1. "All the Young Dudes" by Mott the Hoople (cover)  2. "Draw the Line" by Aerosmith  3. "Dream Police" by Cheap Trick  4. "Make It" by Aerosmith (Re-recording)  5. "Uncle Salty" by Aerosmith Tier 2: "First Taste of Success" (Max's Kansas City) 6. "All Day and All of the Night" by The Kinks (cover)  7. "I Hate Myself for Loving You" by Joan Jett  8. "Movin' Out" by Aerosmith (Re-recording)  9. "No Surprize" by Aerosmith  10. "Sweet Emotion" by Aerosmith Tier 3: "The Triumphant Return" (The Orpheum) 11. "Complete Control" by The Clash  12. "Livin' on the Edge" by Aerosmith  13. "Love in an Elevator" by Aerosmith  14. "Personality Crisis" by New York Dolls (cover)  15. "Rag Doll" by Aerosmith Tier 4: "International Superstars" (Moscow) 16. "Bright Light Fright" by Aerosmith  17. "King of Rock" by Run-D.M.C.  18. "Nobody's Fault" by Aerosmith  19. "She Sells Sanctuary" by The Cult  20. "Walk This Way" by Run-D.M.C. featuring Aerosmith Tier 5: "The Great American Band" (Half Time Show) 21. "Always on the Run" by Lenny Kravitz  22. "Back in the Saddle" by Aerosmith  23. "Beyond Beautiful" by Aerosmith  24. "Dream On" by Aerosmith (Re-recording)  25. "Hard to Handle" by The Black Crowes (cover) Tier 6: "Rock N Roll Legends" (Rock  Roll Hall of Fame) 26. "Cat Scratch Fever" by Ted Nugent  27. "Mama Kin" by Aerosmith (Re-recording)  28. "Sex Type Thing" by Stone Temple Pilots  29. "Toys In The Attic" by Aerosmith  30. "Train Kept A Rollin" by Aerosmith  31. "Guitar Battle vs Joe Perry" by Joe Perry The Vault 32. "Combination" by Aerosmith  33. "Kings and Queens" by Aerosmith  34. "Let The Music Do The Talking" by Aerosmith  35. "Mercy" by Joe Perry  36. "Pandora's Box" by Aerosmith  37. "Pink" by Aerosmith  38. "Rats In The Cellar" by Aerosmith  39. "Shakin' My Cage" by Joe Perry  40. "Talk Talkin" by Joe Perry  41. "Walk This Way" by Aerosmith </description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/13158/970626-gb.png</image></root>