<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20686</id><name>MLB Power Pros</name><description> MLB Power Pros is the first game in Konami's long-running super-deformed baseball series to be released in North America. While Konami developed the game and typically publishes its own products, Take-Two Interactive's exclusive deal with Major League Baseball led to a deal between the two companies, and the game bears the 2K Sports logo domestically.  The baseball in Power Pros is fairly typical for the genre, but the game's cutesy, super-deformed look doesn't mean that the game is simple. There's a fairly involved season mode that puts players in the role of general manager with a goal of winning the World Series within ten seasons. Players will be in charge of training the team, buying equipment, and trading players. Another mode, called Success Mode, is story-based, telling the tale of a college ball player attempting to make it to the bigs. Here, players will have to juggle part-time jobs, academics, and other non-baseball aspects. MLB Power Pros also has an extensive shop where players can spend points they earn by playing games. Ichiro is ready to hitGame Modes Success Success mode lets you create your own character and play his college career. In Success mode playrs will have to find the balance between school, work, practice, and love interests. Most of the story is told by dialog trees and moral decisions based on what fate cards you are currently holding. Your ultimate goal is to win the college championship, increase you skills, and get drafted by your favorite team.LeagueIn League mode players can compete against 2 to 6 friends or AI in a tournament to win the championship.Season Season mode lets you take the role of a general manger of a team for ten years. During your time in control you will have to draft player, make trades, buy equipment, and win the World Series, before your tenure is over. ShopMLB Power Pros also includes an extensive shop that players can spend points they earn in games. The store includes baseball cards of all current teams as well as uniforms, batting and pitching stance, and stadiums. </description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="34">Baseball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20876">Major League Baseball 2K8</game><game id="15449">Backyard Baseball 2001</game><game id="12532">Backyard Baseball 2003</game><game id="21254">Major League Baseball 2K5</game><game id="22546">Major League Baseball 2K6</game><game id="22776">Out of the Park Baseball 9</game><game id="17271">Triple Play 2002</game><game id="7000">Triple Play 2001</game><game id="9670">Triple Play Baseball</game><game id="14025">Triple Play 2000</game><game id="20893">Backyard Baseball 2009</game><game id="22947">Backyard Baseball 2007</game><game id="8283">Bases Loaded</game><game id="5259">Super Baseball 2020</game><game id="25342">Pro Yakyuu Team o Tsukurou! 2</game><game id="25344">Pro Yakyuu Team o Tsukurou!</game><game id="13328">Wii Sports</game><game id="30996">Pro Yakyuu Spirits 2010</game><game id="34317">Pro Yakyuu Spirits 4</game><game id="34318">Pro Yakyuu Spirits 2</game><game id="34319">Pro Yakyuu Spirits 2004</game><game id="26594">Pro Yakyuu Spirits 3</game><game id="34324">Pro Yakyuu Spirits 5</game><game id="34323">Pro Yakyuu Spirits 2004 Climax</game><game id="34325">Pro Yakyuu Spirits 5 Kanzenban</game><game id="34283">Pro Yakyuu Spirits 2011</game><game id="35847">MLB Bobblehead Pros</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2261122-box_mlbpp.png</image></root>