<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2068</id><name>Command &amp; Conquer: Tiberian Sun</name><description>Command  Conquer: Tiberian Sun was the highly anticipated sequel to the first CC. The game pits the good forces of the Global Defense Initiative (GDI) versus the fanatical Brotherhood of Nod (NOD) once again in an epic battle for world domination. Like most games in the series, Tiberian Sun is a real-time strategy game with a lengthy single-player campaign for both NOD and GDI, complete with full motion video cutscenes including actors such as Michael Biehn and James Earl Jones in major roles, as well as a plethora of on- and offline multiplayer options.StoryWhile the game is set only twenty years after its predecessor, the world of Tiberian Sun is much different. The lethal Tiberium continues to infect the world at an ever-increasing rate which has made most of the Earth uninhabitable for human beings. To survive, GDI has moved to the arctic regions of the world while NOD has set up camp underground.The game’s story is driven by the difference in goals between GDI and NOD. As GDI strives to maintain world peace and discover the root cause of Tiberium, NOD is hell-bent on achieving world domination. The story is complicated by the apparent loss of Kane, NOD’s leader, at the end of the first Tiberian War which has thrown the Brotherhood into leaderless disarray, but do not count them out just yet as NOD has created through genetic mutation via Tiberium a set of ultra-powerful units that more than compensate for the clan’s lack of organization.The ForgottenDuring the GDI evacuation, some places of the world such as the inner city and many of the poorer regions of the world were ignored. These "forgotten" people were forced to live with Tiberium and watch helplessly as the mysterious green crystals brought about a slow death. Initially partial to NOD due to the aid the Brotherhood provided, The Forgotten have formed an uneasy alliance with GDI after seeing the effects of NOD's experiments on their loved ones.New UnitsGDI's MLRSTiberian Sun made a large shift in theme and setting from the first game - gone are the present day or near future technologies, instead replaced with cyborgs, orbital infantry drops, unmanned drones and a heavier focus on hovercraft and air units. The most notable enhancements are the Mech units that replaced the typical tank for GDI and the subterranean vehicles used by NOD to strike terror anywhere on the map without warning. NOD's BansheeGDI's Titan  Marketing CampaignTiberian Sun was originally teased in the original 1995 Command  Conquer, with a rendered movie among the trailers of upcoming titles on the game CD, featuring a GDI Wolverine mech going through testing at a firing range.During the pre-launch marketing campaign, the German crossover metal band Think About Mutation did a Command  Conquer themed cover of Frankie Goes To Hollywood's "Two Tribes", in the music video the band wore NOD themed uniforms and the futuristic helmet from the game's cover art, and several clips from the game's cutscenes were shown. The cover art for the CD single also had a variation of the Tiberian Sun cover, with a female soldier instead of the male from the final release.The music video is available at http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9XzxxhkjyHQ.Critical ReceptionThe game suffered somewhat from high expectations and disappointment at several delays during the game’s development process - EA acquired Westwood mid development, and rushed the game to release, with several announced features omitted which would then be made available in the Firestorm expansion pack. Though some expressed disappointment with it's technical flaws, the game still mostly received positive reviews, many praising the new voxel based graphics engine, the multiplayer modes and the soundtrack by Frank Klepacki and Jarrid Mendelson. It received several awards and was embraced by CC fans worldwide. It was EA Games' fastest selling title at the time - selling 1.5 million copies within the first month.</description><genres><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13062">StarCraft</game><game id="615">Dominion: Storm Over Gift 3</game><game id="5415">StarCraft: Brood War</game><game id="17353">Star Wars: Force Commander</game><game id="14805">KKND2: Krossfire</game><game id="13125">Aliens Versus Predator: Extinction</game><game id="14236">Dune II: The Building of a Dynasty</game><game id="19680">Total Annihilation: Kingdoms</game><game id="8421">Outlive</game><game id="16156">Dark Reign 2</game><game id="18072">Command &amp; Conquer: Red Alert 2</game><game id="25481">Officers</game><game id="20952">World in Conflict: Soviet Assault</game><game id="25546">Sun Age</game><game id="1759">Tanktics</game><game id="1552">Dune 2000</game><game id="19932">Emperor: Battle for Dune</game><game id="33907">APOX</game><game id="15235">Dark Reign: The Future of War</game><game id="5205">Dark Reign: Rise of the Shadowhand</game><game id="38775">State of War 2: Arcon</game><game id="40429">Echelon: Explore, Discover and Eliminate</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3419/617320-196969_15506_front.jpg</image></root>