<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20698</id><name>Wheelman</name><description>OverviewWheelman is a driving game starring Vin Diesel, developed and published by Midway Games. It was first announced in February 2006 and is one of three projects being developed between Midway and MTV. On Febuary 18, 2009, Midway announced that it had partnered with Ubisoft to help publish Wheelman. Wheelman was produced in collaboration with Diesel's own game company Tigon Studios. A demo for Wheelman was released on Xbox Live Marketplace for download on March 5, 2009.PlotThe game features Milo Burik (Vin Diesel) as a a driver who comes out of retirement after he saves a woman from his past. This rescue leads him into a gang war in Barcelona, Spain.LevelsPart 1 – Intel GatheringMission: FranticMission: Back to BarcelonaMission: You Scratch My BackMission: Meeting Old FriendsMission: Interviewing FelipeMission: MiccaMission: Introducing BenitoMission: Finding FamilyMission: ZapateadoMission: Stand and DeliverMission: Miguel's StingMission: The Big DistractionMission: Green Cross CodeMission: Letting Off SteamMission: Pick of DestinyPart 2 – Acting on the InfoMission: Follow a WheelmanMission: Defeating FelipeMission: Visiting GalloMission: The Balance of PowerMission: The Balance of Power - Hold 'EmMission: The Balance of Power - No ProtectionMission: The Balance of Power - Seller's MarketMission: Milo's InMission: Balance of Power – Street Race RiotMission: Balance of Power – Keep it MovingMission: Balance of Power – Carrier RescueMission: Balance of Power – Romanian BattleMission: Balance of Power – Lantos BattleMission: Balance of Power – Chulos BattleMission: The RescueMission: Get GalloSide-QuestsSide-Quest: Cat StatuesSide-Quest: ContractSide-Quest: FugitiveSide-Quest: Hot PotatoSide-Quest: Made to OrderSide-Quest: RampageSide-Quest: Street ShowdownSide-Quest: TaxiSide-Quest: Cinematic JumpsGameplayDriving portions.The game contains a mix of driving and on-foot missions, though the great majority focuses specifically on driving. Wheelman offers a number of flashy vehicular special moves. You can slam into cars alongside yours with the right analog stick. An even flashier move involves slowing down time, spinning your car 180 degrees, shooting the driver or gas tank of a pursuing vehicle, and then whipping back around to speed away and escape your pursuit.Wheelman is set in a virtual version of Barcelona, Spain. Many of the places in the game are based on real places. Those include:Arc de TriomfAvinguda del Paral-leiCasino MarinaDrugstore ClubEmbaixada de RumaníaLas ArenasMonument a Christofor ColomMuseu Nacional d'Art de CatalunyaParc de la CiutadellaPlaça de CatalunyaPlaça de TorosSagrada Familia Antoni GaudrTorre AgbarVehiclesWheelman features an array of vehicles, including some licensed cars. Milo Burik can drive a Pontiac G8 and a Opel Astra.TriviaAside from their look (and occasionally their name), cars in Wheelman are best identified by their license plates, all of which are references to classic Midway games. Games referenced in license plates include Mortal Kombat, Smash TV, Mortal Kombat Vs. DC Universe, BlackSite: Area 51, Ready 2 Rumble Boxing, Arctic Thunder, NARC, Spy Hunter, Cruis'n World, War Gods, CART Fury, Marble Madness, Robotron, Gauntlet, and Dr. Muto.Radio America's DJ is none other than Shaun Himmerick, who is a veteran developer of Mortal Kombat.Wheelman was the last published game to be developed by Midway Studios before the company's untimely death.ReceptionWheelman gained mixed reviews. Many critics didn't like the weak story or the game's lack of multiplayer. Game Informer gave Wheelman some praise, giving it a 8.5/10, praising the game's driving mechanics and action. IGN, on the other hand, were less kind and gave the game 4.8/10.Xbox 360 InstallationThe amount of memory it takes to install this game is 6.4 GB.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7020">Driver</game><game id="10953">Driver 2: The Wheelman is Back</game><game id="14491">Driv3r</game><game id="11153">True Crime: Streets of LA</game><game id="3345">True Crime: New York City</game><game id="10623">The Italian Job</game><game id="17604">Driver: Parallel Lines</game><game id="4486">Driver '76</game><game id="17036">Grand Theft Auto: Vice City</game><game id="20638">This Is Vegas</game><game id="9966">Scarface: The World is Yours</game><game id="5648">Burnout Paradise</game><game id="20484">Burnout</game><game id="13514">Burnout 2: Point of Impact</game><game id="357">Burnout 3: Takedown</game><game id="16492">Burnout Revenge</game><game id="8459">Burnout Dominator</game><game id="4970">Burnout Legends</game><game id="4318">Spy Hunter: Nowhere to Run</game><game id="31634">Driver: San Francisco</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2341492-vin_diesel.png</image></root>