<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20713</id><name>Computer Space</name><description>Background               Nolan Bushnell, studying at the University of Utah, was one of the privileged few who attended a university which could afford the expensive DEC PDP-1 computer system. The thing that took up a significant amount of Bushnell's time was a game called                Spacewar! which was developed for that machine.Figuring there was a market for such entertainment in amusement centers, Bushnell set about creating an affordable version of Spacewar! which could be produced and sold for a reasonable price. With the help of  Ted Dabney, Bushnell developed the machine, and Nutting Associates, a producer of coin-operated trivia machines, funded the venture.The result was not commercially successful, but paved the way for coin-operated           arcade machines, and lead to Bushnell's founding of          Atari.Game Features for this game differed significantly from the original Spacewar! model. At first the goal was to make a commercial version of the public Spacewar!, but Bushnell and  Dabney's final product presaged        Asteroids more, in that it was a single-player game where the player attempted to destroy       projectile-spitting saucer craft. The player had a limited amount of time to destroy as many saucers as possible, and every time his or her rocket was destroyed, this was kept in a tally at the right. ImpactWhile the game was not commercially successful, it served as a basic model for arcade game design which remained strong for two decades. The machine was introduced at about the same time as the first     Odyssey home system was introduced, developed by                Ralph Baer and produced by                Magnavox. Bushnell's exposure to the Odyssey no doubt influenced his move to create Atari, and was a source of later legal contention between Magnavox and Bushnell, although the Atari home entertainment system went on to be much more commercially successful. Popular Culture A custom white Computer Space arcade cabinet is seen and played in the Charlton Heston film Soylent Green.Sources             http://www.thedoteaters.com/stage1.php              http://www3.sympatico.ca/maury/games/space/spacewar.html</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5099">Space Invaders</game><game id="16120">Space Armada</game><game id="12834">Alien Invaders - Plus!</game><game id="14030">Demons to Diamonds</game><game id="15941">Demon Attack</game><game id="23504">Vector Vaders</game><game id="12744">Chicken Invaders</game><game id="8125">Astrosmash</game><game id="13424">Cheesy Invaders</game><game id="1293">CHAMP Invaders</game><game id="21514">Spacewar!</game><game id="24276">Galaxy Game</game><game id="8149">Zone Ranger</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4076/282464-computerspace.jpg</image></root>