<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20726</id><name>Quantum of Solace</name><description>Overview Quantum of  Solace is a first-person shooter game for the                  Xbox 360,                 PlayStation 3,                Wii and               PC.  The game is the first James Bond title to be released by              Activision after acquisition of the James Bond video game license in 2006.  Being built upon             Infinity Ward's IW Engine, the game allows for large amounts of environmental damage and other effects, like those found in           Call of Duty 4 and          Call of Duty: World at War.  Although being focused in a first-person view, the game also switches to a third person view periodically, at points such as quick time events and cover sequences.  Quantum of Solace also features a checkpoint system that saves after key events in the story.          Daniel Craig provided his likeness and voice to the game, along with actors         Mathieu Amalric,       Mads Mikkelsen and  actresses      Olga Kurylenko,     Judi Dench  and    Eva Green.Due to the limitations of the console's hardware, the   PlayStation 2 version of Quantum of Solace could not take advantage of the Call of Duty 4 engine and became a third person shooter/stealth game instead.StoryThe story in the game follows immediately from the events of the 2006 film Casino Royale. Opening in Mr. White's Estate, the story follows that of Quantum of Solace loosely, but also flashes back to events from Casino Royale. Among these events is the famous chase in Madagascar from the start of Casino Royale, where Bond pursues a bomb-maker through a construction site. Other events were created specifically for the game, such as fighting on the roof of the train traveling to Montenegro. This does not appear in the film, and was created entirely for the game. MultiplayerMultiplayer in Quantum of Solace supports 12 players across seven different game modes on Xbox Live and PlayStation Network.  Over the course of a battle, players earn credits that can be used at an in game store, in real-time (without the need to exit out of the game) to purchase new weapons, items and perks.  Similar to Call of Duty 4, players can have five different customizable classes for yourself at anytime, and the basic load-out is the same as well, where you will start out with a primary weapon, pistol, and grenades. Different multiplayer modes include:Classic - Classic deathmatch mode is very similar to the Old-School Deathmatch gametype from Call of Duty 4.  Instead of choosing from your preset load-outs, all players start out with a pistol and all other weapons are scattered around the map.Conflict/Team Conflict - Essentially a deathmatch mode that allows you to choose from your preset load-outs. Conflict can also be played as a Team Deathmatch mode.Territory Control - As the name suggests, Territory Control is all about capturing and defending points across the map. Bond Versus - A randomly selected player is chosen to be Bond and everyone else is assigned to take him out. The Bond player must either kill all other players or disarm two of three bombs that are placed around the map. In order to make things a bit more balanced, the Bond player is given several advantages like two lives per round, a health boost, a faster run speed than other players, and the ability to see all enemies on his mini-map.Bond Evasion - Bond Evasion tasks a group of MI6 agents with protecting a randomly selected Bond character as he makes his way to an extraction point. The other team has to take the Bond player out before he reaches the extraction point.Golden Gun - The Golden Gun mode takes the iconic gold six-shooter from the Bond series and makes it the center of this mode. There are no teams and the only goal is to find the golden gun and kill as many other players with it as possible before you are killed.  After the timer runs out, the player with the most points wins. Levels White's Estate      Siena       Opera House      Sink Hole              Shanty Town      Construction Site      Science Center Exterior      Science Center Interior      Miami Airport      Montenegro Train      Casino Royale      Casino Poison      Barge      Venice      Eco Hotel  WeaponsHandguns:                  P99GF-18 A                  CR-1911LTK Super MagnumGF-17Nail GunSubmachine Guns: MantisSAF 9mmTLD-22SAF 45Shotguns:Hutchinson A3Hutchinson A4Assualt Rifles:FRWLA3 RakerTND 16M14Mk3 LLDVKP-08Ligh Machine Guns:8CAT-LSniper Rifles:V-Tak 31                  WA 2000Explosives:                  Proximity Mines                  Flash Grenade                  Frag Grenade                  Smoke Grenade                  Tear GrenadeConcussion GrenadeOther:                  Silencer                  ScopeHalo SightARO Scope   PC Specs  OS: Windows XP / Vista  CPU: Intel Pentium 4 2.4 GHz / AMD Athlon XP 2800 / any 1.8 GHz Dual Core Processor or better  RAM: 512 MB (XP) / 1 GB (Vista)  VIDEO: 128 MB or better (NVIDIA Geforce 6600 / ATI Radeon 9800 or better)   SOUND: DirectX 9.0c compatible   Xbox 360 Game InstallationQuantum of Solace requires 6.8GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD.    </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1986">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six: Vegas 2</game><game id="9993">Halo 3</game><game id="20488">Robert Ludlum's The Bourne Conspiracy</game><game id="23924">Spy Fiction</game><game id="20662">Gears of War 2</game><game id="11454">Resident Evil: The Umbrella Chronicles</game><game id="26423">Call of Duty: Black Ops</game><game id="23907">Secret Service</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1841798-box_qosolace_.png</image></root>