<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20743</id><name>Metal Slug 7</name><description>OverviewMetal Slug 7 is a game for the Nintendo DS, developed and published by SNK Playmore. The game was released in Japan on July 17, 2008 and came out November 18, 2008 in the U.S. Metal Slug 7 is the first numbered game in the series not to be released in arcades. At     Tokyo Game Show 2009 during Microsoft's keynote, a n Xbox Live Arcade port of Metal Slug 7 was announced for a winter release; in May 2010, an updated version of Metal Slug 7 (  Metal Slug XX) was released on the service.The game has seven different missions to play, each one with its own set of vehicles and weapons. CharactersThe same cast of characters from  Metal Slug 6 return in Metal Slug 7, each with their own specialty in battle. They include:  Marco: Basic handgun deals more damage, can rapid fire Handgun shots with a button command. Tarma: Slugs can take more damage, aim fixes while firing in a Slug. Can kick a Slug to randomly raise or lower its HP.Fio: Gains 50% more ammo from weapon pickups, start each new life with Heavy Machine Gun.Eri: Gains double ammo from grenade pickups, grenades can be aimed in eight directions.Ralf: Can survive one non-environmental attack per life, special  melee "Vulcan Punch," melee can damage vehicles, 50% less ammo from  weapon pickups.Clark: Special melee "Argentine Backbreaker" that grants temporary invincibility upon successful use. Has three lives per continue instead of two. VehiclesMetal Slug 7's vehicles include:Slug Truck - A train-like machine that requires a separate cannon to be attached to it.Slug Giant - The Slug Gigant is a giant robot. The vehicle has heavy firepower.Game ModesThe game features Arcade Mode and Combat School. Arcade Mode can be started from any stage that the player has completed. The game's difficulty level determines how many continues that the player has at his or her disposal.  The Combat School features a variety of side-missions. Commanding officer    Cynthia comments on the player's progress, gradually falling in love with the player as missions are completed.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4350">Contra</game><game id="2190">Gunstar Heroes</game><game id="13773">Soldat</game><game id="7227">Abuse</game><game id="15092">Turrican</game><game id="3016">Contra III: The Alien Wars</game><game id="4237">Contra 4</game><game id="692">Contra Advance: The Alien Wars EX</game><game id="11684">Contra: Shattered Soldier</game><game id="17008">Alien Soldier</game><game id="17452">Alien Hominid</game><game id="1421">Ranger X</game><game id="10077">Super C</game><game id="17939">Konami Collector's Series: Castlevania &amp; Contra</game><game id="21048">Commando Steel Disaster</game><game id="7765">Alien Rampage</game><game id="23692">Prinny: Can I Really Be the Hero?</game><game id="25563">Zombieville USA</game><game id="25714">Explodemon!</game><game id="21340">Time Slip</game><game id="26376">Contra ReBirth</game><game id="29479">GunForce II</game><game id="32189">Dolphin Blue</game><game id="13388">Shock Troopers</game><game id="840">Metal Slug 2: Super Vehicle - 001/II</game><game id="6941">Metal Slug: Super Vehicle - 001</game><game id="26481">Bionic Commando</game><game id="30945">Bionic Commando Rearmed 2</game><game id="39627">Intrusion 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2199363-box_ms7.png</image></root>