<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20821</id><name>Tiberium</name><description>Tiberium was a tactical first-person shooter based in the  Command  Conquer universe, and was being developed by EA Los Angeles, the same guys that did  Medal Of Honor and  Command  Conquer 3: Tiberium Wars.   Powered by     Unreal Engine 3, the game focused around Ricardo Vega, a retired    Global Defence Initiative battle commander put back into action to explore a   Scrin Threshold Tower eleven years after the Third Tiberium War has ended. Referred to as "Tower 6" by the Scrin, and "Tower Omega" by the GDI, it appears to be just a relic of the past. A ruin that stains the landscape. However, this seemingly harmless structure turns out to be the base of another Scrin invasion.  Few things were known about the gameplay, but the main focus was on squad gameplay. The player would have commanded up to four squads at once, and would have had to use them to counter the many types of enemies to be encountered by the player. The confirmed controllable squads were a Rifleman unit, a Missle unit, a Titan unit, and an Orca unit. If killed, new units would take the place of the fallen ones after some time.  The player would be able to attack too of course, and would have had to only worry about one weapon. The "GD-10" is a multi-purpose weapon that can change into an assault rifle, a grenade launcher, an anti-aircraft missile launcher, and an Ion Cannon sniper rifle. The ammo would not be displayed on a HUD (Heads-Up Display), but rather, on a visual display screen on the weapon itself. It is was never known if the player would have been able to use other weapons outside of the GD-10, as EA LA was tight about information on the game.  Tiberium was originally slated for a September 2nd release, but it was first pushed back to the publisher's 2010 fiscal year, then on September 30th, it was announced that EA had officially cancelled the game because it did not meet their quality standards.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4170">Command &amp; Conquer: Renegade</game><game id="21035">Half-Life 2: Episode Three</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/24/175982-tiberium001.jpg</image></root>