<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20823</id><name>2 Xtreme</name><description>GameplayIn 2 Xtreme you race against others as you pass through gates to collect power-ups while also scoring points and winning the race.  Points are scored by passing through gates and performing tricks.  Holding down the 'X' button will cause you to accelerate, at the expense of draining your health bar, and holding the 'O' button will make you crouch to maintain speed.  You can knock other players off their boards/bikes/skates by getting within close proximity of each other and pulling the appropriate trigger to fight.  The ease at which you will fall depends on the state of your health bar.  Some gates on the track give you bonuses like speed boosts, full health, increased jump height, and guaranteed knockdowns.  These abilities can be activated by pressing the 'L2' button.Game ModesThere are two gameplay modes in 2 Xtreme: Exhibition and Season.  ExhibitionExhibition is a normal race mode where you pick the vehicle and skater/biker/boarder then complete one race on the course of your choosing.  SeasonSeason mode is a 12 race competition, involving all 12 courses, against 9 other racers.  As the season progresses, each racer is ranked based on their finishing position, point totals, and race completion time.  The goal is to come out on top of the rest of the field at the end of the season.  During the season the course selection is predetermined and you are unable to change players.  However, you can still alter the vehicle attributes between races.LocationsYou can race through four levels:(each locale has three tracks)Las VegasIn-line skate down the Las Vegas Strip (circa 1996) and battle your way to the sign junkyard at the finish.Las VegasLos AngelesSkateboard through the streets of LA.Los AngelesAfricaMountain bike through the African course filled with wildlife and treacherous obstacles.AfricaJapanSnowboard through Japan while flying off of jumps and halfpipes.Japan ScoringPoints based on FinishFirst           12,500            Sixth            3,600Second       9,000            Seventh      2,600Third            8,000            Eighth         1,800Fourth         6,500             Ninth          1,200Fifth             4,800             Tenth                 0Bonus Points for TricksBonus points will be given to your player based on the difficulty of the trick performed.Easy (2-button combo)                   50 pointsAverage (3-button combo)           100 pointsHard (4-button combo)                 200 pointsBonus Points for Knockdowns150 points per KnockdownBonus Points for passing through GatesYellow                  150 pointsRed                      250 pointsGreen                   500 points Power-UpsPlayers could collect the following power-ups. Spring:Allowed players to jump higher, often high enough to do a trick without hitting a ramp. Dumbbells:Gave players extra strength to avoid being knocked over by other racers. Additional Information2 Xtreme has a Two Player splitscreen mode, with Player One on the top portion of the screen and Player Two on the bottom portion. There are four difficulty levels, with each level having increased player speed and density of pedestrians and vehicles.  Pedestrians and vehicles can only be found on the Las Vegas and Los Angeles courses.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="23">Skateboarding</genre><genre id="33">Snowboarding/Skiing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3631">Tony Hawk's Downhill Jam</game><game id="2570">Aggressive Inline</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2270778-box_2xtreme.png</image></root>