<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20822</id><name>LEGO Batman: The Videogame</name><description>Gameplay The one and only: Dark Knight.The game is split up into three unique-to-game stories based around  Batman, his allies and enemies. Everyone has escaped from  Arkham Asylum and it is up to Batman and  Robin to help round them up. The format is simiiar to that of other LEGO adventure games, which involves solving platformer puzzles (pulling levers, putting blocks on pressure pads, etc) and destroying the environment to collect coins, which can then later be used to buy extras such as suit upgrades and new playable characters. Once the story mode has been completed for a level, you can go back as any character of your choosing and try to access some secret places with your new abilities that were once unavailable to you. Hero or Villain You can play as The Joker too. There are two ways you can play Lego Batman; as a hero, or as a villain, and both offer different ways to play. Playing the game through the Hero campaign, you take control of Batman and Robin and try to stop the evil plans of  The Riddler and company. When completed, this then unlocks the Villain campaign, allowing you to see the game from a different perspective and take control of people such as  The Joker or  Clayface. You will be in the same environments as the Hero campaign, but you might be on the rooftops instead of the floor, or underground instead of up above. It is now your aim to thwart Batman and Robin and triumph with your evil plans.  Weapons and Gadgets Suits Batman and Robin can equip different suits to help them in their adventures.   Batman's suits: Glide Suit - Allows Batman to glide across the level. He can travel longer distances and get to higher parts of the level. Sonic Suit - Gives Batman a megaphone like weapon that emits sonic waves that can shatter blue LEGO glass.  Robin changing suits. Demolition Suit -  Allows Batman to drop Bat Bombs to blow up objects. Heat Protection Suit - Allows Batman to travel through heat related perils as well as manipulate red-hot LEGO blocks.Robin's suits:Water Suit -  Enables Robin to dive deeper into water to explore. Magnet Suit - Gives robin magnetic boots that allow him to walk on metal surfaces on walls and ceilings. Attract Suit - A vacuum like pack that allows Robin to pick up the debris from his adventures in LEGO Gotham City. Technology Suit - With this suit on, Robin can access Tech Panels that allow him to take control of various robotic elements within levels. Batarang Players can wield LEGO Batarang by moving a Batman (or Robin) symbol across the screen to target enemies while using Batman or Robin. The Batarang also allows players to block and reflect enemy bullets. Miscellaneous Information LEGO Batman: The Video Game is the first LEGO game based on a popular franchise to feature a brand new, unique story. Other installments have been restricted to that franchise's specific canon, such as following the first three Indiana Jones films in LEGO Indiana Jones: The Original Adventures. At Sony's 2008 E3 Press Conference they announced a PlayStation 2 LEGO Batman Bundle. The bundle includes a PS2 slim model, the LEGO Batman game and the Justice League: The New Frontier film on DVD.   Bundle with Pure for the Xbox 360Following 2008's holiday bundle of  Lego Indiana Jones and  Kung Fu Panda, the  Xbox 360 Elite model was bundled with LEGO Batman and  Pure during the 2009 holiday season at no additional cost.Xbox 360 Game Installation Lego Batman: The Video Game requires 6.0GB of space to install on a Xbox 360 HDD.</description><genres><genre id="37">Brawler</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3438">MediEvil II</game><game id="1563">Spyro 2: Ripto's Rage</game><game id="6134">The Legend of Spyro: The Eternal Night</game><game id="20330">Gex 3: Deep Cover Gecko</game><game id="15991">Chameleon Twist 2</game><game id="5366">Bionicle Heroes</game><game id="6781">The Simpsons Game</game><game id="24397">Fairytale Fights</game><game id="26753">LEGO Harry Potter: Years 1-4</game><game id="22432">LEGO Universe</game><game id="30399">Spider-Man: Shattered Dimensions</game><game id="22766">Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince</game><game id="31415">Scooby-Doo! and the Spooky Swamp</game><game id="32196">Marvel Super Hero Squad: The Infinity Gauntlet</game><game id="35388">LEGO Harry Potter: Years 5-7</game><game id="41090">LEGO Marvel Super Heroes</game><game id="36898">LEGO Batman 2: DC Super Heroes</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2116221-box_lbatman.png</image></root>