<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20820</id><name>Destroy All Humans! Path of the Furon</name><description>OverviewDestroy All Humans! Path of the Furon takes players on a journey through thirty different missions over twenty side missions all which feature the series Destruction and Enlightenment set in the Funked Out '70's. The newest installment in the acclaimed franchise, redefines the brand's irreverent Sci-Fi action gaming experience for the next-generation Xbox 360 video game and entertainment system from Microsoft with new weapons and mental abilities, high-fidelity destruction and expanded open-world gameplay. THQ on November 26, 2008 confirmed that the PS3 version of the game had been canceled due to troubles working with the Cell processor.In Destroy All Humans! Path of the Furon, players will pick up where prequel Destroy All Humans! Big Willy Unleashed leaves off, controlling Crypto in the Funked out 1970's when mysterious new enemy attacks Earth, sweeping Crypto up in a conspiracy that unravels his groovy new way of life and threatens the very survival of the Furon race. Players will take Crypto on a journey of Enlightenment and Destruction as he gains new powers, including the temporal fist, from an alien Kung Fu Master in order to take on his most difficult enemy yet-his own kind.Players will be using the money Pox and his loyal minion Crypto gained in Big Willy. They invest this money on a casino called "Space Dust" in which they have an stable stream of human DNA a well as dollars. The game revolves around Crypto's lack of enthusiasm when killing humans, this is due to an abuse on drinking and watching television all day, everyday and is pretty much a coach potato. The whole plot turns around when the Casino starts having trouble with the Mafia. Crypto discovers the conspiracy when fighting some of the Mafia robots called the Nexos, which come form Crypto's homeworld, at this point Crypto has returned to his human-hating self.Features:Destroy All Humans! Redefined - Destroy All Humans! Path of the Furon redefines the series for next-gen-increasing the size, scale and scope of Crypto's arsenal of alien weaponry, mental abilities and destruction.High Fidelity Destruction - Manipulate or destroy anything in the world, creating disaster movie inspired level of destruction and mayhem.Open World Game Play - Go anywhere at anytime via an open world mission structure-Explore 5 open world environments without ever leaving the game world, or take on a variety of side missions and mini-games.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16238">Alien Shooter 2</game><game id="20697">Mercenaries 2: World in Flames</game><game id="32573">Earth Defense Force: Insect Armageddon</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2136543-box_dahpotf.png</image></root>