<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20832</id><name>Tiger Woods PGA Tour 09</name><description>Play all new courses. Tiger Woods PGA Tour 09 features 16 courses, 5 of which are new to the series.  You can now play at Wentworth, Sheshan, Wolf Creek,  Bay Hill and The Gary Player Country Club.  There are also some new golfers to use this time around.The game now features      Tiger Woods' real life coach  Hank Haney who acts as your performance coach and guides you through your career, offering you assistance to improve your abilities.  Your coach is on hand to give you some help.You will also have the ability to fine tune each of your clubs to suit your individual style of play and evaluate your swing to make sure you are playing the best game of golf.There is four-player simultaneous online play along with tons of modes and the types of challenges you would expect from a Tiger Woods game.RosterMale Golfers       Tiger Woods      Ian Poulter       John Daly      Adam Scott      Mike Weir       Darren Clarke      Rory McIlroy      Nick Dougherty      Luke Donald      Vijay Singh      Jim Furyk      Colin Montgomerie      Chris DiMarco      Retief Goosen      Camilo Villegas       Jesper Parnevik       J.B. Holmes       Paul Casey Female Golfers       Paula Creamer      Natalie Gulbis      Christie Kerr      Morgan Pressel  Annika Sörenstam      Se Ri Pak Courses  Gary Player Country Club  St Andrews  Pebble Beach Golf Links  TPC at Sawgrass  Carnoustie Golf Links  Sheshan Golf Club  Wolf Creek Golf Club  Bay Hill Club and Lodge  Wentworth Club  Harbour Town Golf Links  Doral Golf Resort  Spa  Cog Hill Golf  Country Club  TPC at Boston  East Lake Golf Club  Westchester Country Club  Riviera Country Club  Firestone Country Club (available to download on Xbox Live Marketplace, 600 microsoft points)  Spyglass Hill Golf Course (available to download on Xbox Live Marketplace, 600 microsoft points) Game Modes  Stroke Play  Match Play  Skins  Bingo Bango Bongo  Stableford  Alternate Shot  Best Ball  Four-Ball  Greensome  Bloodsome  Battle Golf  One-BallMini-Games  Target  Target to Target  T.I.G.E.R  Capture the Flag  Putting Contest  Approach Contest  Closest to the Pin Contest  Long Drive ContestMy Career Mode  PGA Tour Season - 5 years of PGA TOUR events FedExCup Qualification and Playoffs  Tiger Challenge - Go head to head with PGA TOUR pros and fantasy golfers  Performance Tuning - Tune your clubs to suit your style or take part in Custom Drills designed for you by Hank Haney  My Skills  My Career StatsMy Golfer Mode  Photo Game Face - Upload photos of youself to the Tiger Woods website or use your Xbox Live Vision Cam to put your face on your created golfer  Change your appearance, visit the Pro Shop to purchase new items, change your clubs, change your in game animations  Club Tuner - Calibrate your clubs to fit your personal playng style  EA Sports  GAMERNET - Challenge the world to complete any shot you save in game better than you did it  My Tiger '09 - See all your records, trophies etc Xbox 360 Game InstallationTiger Woods PGA Tour '09 requires 6.0GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="28">Golf</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1325">PGA Championship Golf 2000: Titanium Edition</game><game id="2302">PGA Tour Golf: Tournament Course Disk</game><game id="697">PGA European Tour</game><game id="6799">PGA Tour Golf</game><game id="1336">Cyber Tiger</game><game id="13462">Hot Shots Golf</game><game id="1760">PGA Tour 96</game><game id="14247">PGA Tour Golf III</game><game id="1547">Hot Shots Golf: Open Tee</game><game id="21797">Golf</game><game id="6957">Outlaw Golf 2</game><game id="22799">PGA Tour 97</game><game id="17375">Jack Nicklaus 6: Golden Bear Challenge</game><game id="10089">Jack Nicklaus 5</game><game id="19715">Jack Nicklaus 4</game><game id="2617">Jack Nicklaus' Unlimited Golf &amp; Course Design</game><game id="9067">Links Championship Edition</game><game id="1598">Mario Golf: Toadstool Tour</game><game id="24570">Easy Golf</game><game id="26784">101 MiniGolf World</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2269433-box_twpgat09.png</image></root>