<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20848</id><name>NCAA Football 09</name><description>Overview PS3: Matt Ryan EA continues to improve upon its college football franchise with the silky-smooth NCAA Football '09.   Like any annual EA Sports game, this year's edition sports some new gameplay modes, as well as a ton of new in-game mechanics. The engine itself has even improved, as NCAA runs at a constant 60 FPS; the frame rate issues found in previous next-gen Madden and NCAA games have vanished, leaving a smooth, well rounded college football game. This is also the first NCAA Football game with different cover athletes for each console.           Cover Athletes:  PS3: Matt Ryan QB, Boston College                                                           Xbox 360: Darren McFadden RB, Arkansas                                                         PS2: DeSean Jackson WR, Cal                                                          PSP: Owen Schmitt FB, West Virginia University                                                          Wii: Sparty, Michigan State Mascot                                                                   Gameplay Modes PS2: DeSean Jackson Play NowHop into a game right away, pick the teams, and take the field with default settings. DynastyPick your favorite team and pick up where they left off, beginning in the 2008 offseason.  The player makes every decision for the team, from recruiting new players out of high school to naming a team captain.  When the season starts, you take the field as your team with the ultimate goal of winning a national championship.  The player can make Dynasty mode as in-depth or as non-taxing as he wants: any action (offseason or not) can be simulated to speed up the process.      PSP: Owen Schmitt  Campus LegendEither pick an existing college player, or create a brand-new high school senior to play as in Campus Legend mode.  Take the field as this player, increase your stats and skills, and lead your team to a national championship. Mini-gamesNCAA Football '09 includes some new ideas in its mini-game modes:HORSE - Just like in basketball, but with field goals!  Players can choose from where they kick their field goal, and the amount of wind in the stadiumSpecial Teams Challenge - Players take turn punting the ball away, each player tries to advance the ball as far as possible on each return.  First one to kick a field goal or score a touchdown wins!Tug Of War - Just like Special Teams Challenge, but with offensive plays instead of punts.Bowling - Each frame, take the field as the offense at the opponent's 10 yard-line.  You have two tries to get into the endzone, every yard counts as a pin.Option Dash - See how many yards and touchdowns you can score in a minute, just by running the option. Mascot MashupJust like Play Now mode, but instead of players on the field, you play as a team of mascots.  The mascots have superior stats, and their jukes and hurdles are replaced by barrel-rolls and somersaults.   In-game Mechanics    Wii: Michigan mascot Sparty  NCAA-Specific AnimationsSome this year's player animations won't be seen in Madden '09.  A load of tackle, catch, and juke animations were designed specifically for NCAA Football '09 and can't be found anywhere else. ComposureIf your team is performing poorly, or if the home team crowd is just too loud, your QB may lose his composure.  This results in poor throws and 'confusion' when trying to look at your play at the line of scrimmage.    QB QuizAfter a poor offensive play (usually an interception) you have the chance to regain your composure by answering the QB Quiz.  Three defensive plays are shown; you have to pick the one the opposing defense ran to shut you down.  A correct answer will refund composure, a wrong answer will lower your QB's composure even more. Ice the KickerAt the end of a half, if the opposing kicker is lining up to kick a field goal that would tie the game or put his team in the lead, you can call a timeout to ice the kicker.  When the kicker retakes the field, he'll have a much more difficult time aiming and kicking the game-changing field goal. TeamsYou wont find any surprises on the team list this year, NCAA Football '09 includes every team from every major Division 1 conference.    Xbox360: Darren McFadden</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="21">Football</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20711">Madden NFL 09</game><game id="20986">Backbreaker</game><game id="8480">All-Pro Football 2K8</game><game id="16585">Madden NFL 07</game><game id="21413">Madden NFL 08</game><game id="6648">Madden NFL 06</game><game id="4222">Madden NFL 2005</game><game id="11911">Madden NFL 2004</game><game id="15987">Madden NFL 2003</game><game id="10845">Madden NFL 2002</game><game id="8822">Madden NFL 2001</game><game id="12373">Madden NFL 2000</game><game id="13996">Madden NFL 99</game><game id="8679">Madden NFL 98</game><game id="17667">John Madden Football '92</game><game id="17607">John Madden Football II</game><game id="1234">John Madden Football</game><game id="21698">John Madden Duo CD Football</game><game id="13056">ESPN NFL 2K5</game><game id="805">NFL 2K1</game><game id="4659">NFL 2K</game><game id="10530">NFL 2K3</game><game id="14001">NFL 2K2</game><game id="6937">ESPN NFL Football</game><game id="16550">Quarterback Attack</game><game id="98">John Elway's Quarterback</game><game id="7966">NFL Quarterback Club 2000</game><game id="9596">NFL Quarterback Club 97</game><game id="10536">NFL Quarterback Club 98</game><game id="11504">NFL Quarterback Club 96</game><game id="18346">NFL Quarterback Club '99</game><game id="22136">NFL Quarterback Club</game><game id="1700">Joe Montana Football</game><game id="8417">NFL Blitz</game><game id="2849">NFL Blitz 2000</game><game id="12669">NFL Blitz 2001</game><game id="4352">NFL Blitz 20-03</game><game id="9044">NFL Blitz 20-02</game><game id="21512">NFL Blitz: Pro</game><game id="4166">Blitz: The League</game><game id="20920">Blitz: The League II</game><game id="5629">Backyard Football 2002</game><game id="4949">Backyard Football</game><game id="21816">Backyard Football 2006</game><game id="21815">Backyard Football</game><game id="13358">Backyard Football 2004</game><game id="3333">NFL GameDay ‘98</game><game id="24637">BCFX: The Doug Williams Edition</game><game id="25241">Madden NFL 10</game><game id="30003">NCAA Football 11</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2250721-box_ncaafb09.png</image></root>