<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20859</id><name>Ninja Reflex</name><description>OverviewNinja Refex is a minigame collection for the Wii, DS, and PC via Steam. In the game, up to 4 players can take on six different mini games that in premise will train you in skills vital for being a Ninja. Upon release for the Wii and the DS the game was heavily criticized for only having very few minigames yet still being a full priced title. To remedy this, Sanazaru Games developed "Ninja Reflex: Steamworks Edition" for Valve's digital distribution platform Steam for only $10, significantly less than the other versions.MinigamesThere are 300 challenges spanning across 6 minigames, with only two new unlockable challenges at a time per game. After beating a tier of challenges the player steps up a rank and two new challenges unlock for each game. However, instead of just beating the new challenges to rank up, the player must replay the old challenges each time as well. Starting as a white belt the ultimate goal is to reach the black belt, 3rd Degree.ShurikenUsing a shuriken the player must throw and hit stationary and moving targets. Eventually they become faster and demand adequate reflexes.KoiKoiHover over a fish with the cursor, wait for the fish to appear and grab it out of the water. Eventually the player must catch smaller and faster fish.HotariIn this game the player must wait for fireflies to appear, then catch them quickly before they dissapear.HashiHashiUse chopsticks to catch flies in succesion and place the flies in the bowl to succeed. Eventually they become extremely fast.KatanaThe player must anticipate the direction of the Oni Soldier's attack, counter it, and finally slay the enemy with a katana.NunchakuSwing the nunchaku in an "8" pattern and hit the target the Sensei throws at you.MeditationThe game also features a meditation mode in which the Sensei says relaxing things with long silences in between. It is meant for actual meditation and doesn't feature any gameplay.Steamworks EditionThe Sensei is meditating on top of a companion cube, a famous object from the Portal series.This version of the game makes no gameplay changes but enables steamworks, allowing the steam community to make cosmetic changes to the game using objects from Valve's games. Numerous Easter eggs can be found as a result.System Requirements on steamMinimum:Supported OS: Microsoft Windows® XP/VistaProcessor: Intel Pentium® 1.0 GHz or higher processorSystem Memory: Windows XP: 256 MB of RAM, Windows Vista: 512 MB of RAMVideo Card: DirectX 9.0-compatible video card/DirectX Version: DirectX® version 9.0 or higherHard Disk: 250 MB available hard disk space</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13328">Wii Sports</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4086/269256-ninja_reflexwii.jpg</image></root>