<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20857</id><name>Top Spin 3</name><description>Overview     Top Spin 3 is a                      tennis game that was developed by                                                           PAM Development, published by                                                          2K Sports, and released in 2008 on the                                                         Xbox 360,                                                        PlayStation 3, and                                                       Wii, though the Wii iteration differs quite a bit from the other home console versions. A watered-down portable version was also developed and made its way onto the                                                      Nintendo DS. The American cover of Top Spin 3 features                                                    Roger Federer at the front with                                                   Maria Sharapova and                                                  Andy Roddick to the left and right of him respectively.                   Andy Murray appears instead of Roddick in the British cover.GameplayTomas Berdych hitting the ball The                                                                                               Top Spin series has always been known to take a more realistic approach when it comes to the actual game mechanics, with a larger emphasis on player position and momentum to beat your opponent. Top Spin 3 is no different. Shot selection and placement is more important in this game than the more arcade-like rivals such as                                                                                              Virtua Tennis, which means choosing what to do with the                                                                                             ball is key to winning a rally. Balls can be hit flat, with top spin, or with slice, while drop and lob shots can also be executed.  The game features an evolved control scheme, which makes significant modifications to the gameplay compared to previous installments. A hold-and-release system is implemented to allow for greater flexibility; the player must hold down a shot button before the ball reaches them (starting at about the point at which the ball crosses the net), and then release just after the bounce to hit the shot. During the time the button is held, you can manoveur the player into the best position for the shot to maximise power and accuracy. This system puts an added emphasis on anticipation and variety to beat an opponent. All of these characteristics make Top Spin 3 an initially tricky title to get into. However, a tutorial mode walks the player through the basic and more complicated concepts of the game.  Single-Player Top Spin 3 includes a variety of game modes:ExhibitionExhibition allows two or four players, either all human or a mixture of humans and AI-controlled characters, to play a singles or doubles match with no repercussions. You'll probably have to face Roger Federer at some pointWorld Tour    The meat of Top Spin 3 is in its World Tour mode, where after                                                                                            creating a new tennis player, you start your career at the bottom as an amateur, slowly working your way up in hope that you will one day be invited to join the professional tour. By becoming the world number one, you will then have an opportunity to become an all-time tennis legend. Winning matches grants                                                XP, which can be used to improve your created player in different departments, and unlock points, which can be spent at the shop to acquire new clothes and gear.TournamentThe other single-player mode is Tournament mode. Here, the game allows you to compete in a variety of individual tournaments without playing through the World Tour. Multiplayer Multiplayer allows use of your created character from your offline career mode. There are two different modes that can be played online:  Player Match  This is a typical exhibition singles or doubles match. World TourThe World Tour mode allows you to enter several tournaments, including Grand Slams and Masters. In a tournament, you are drawn against others who have entered. By winning successive matches, you can progress through and eventually win the event. You can only enter each tournament once, so if you get knocked out or end up as champion, you must wait until the season ends before trying again. Each season in this mode lasts fifteen days.  Character Creation Top Spin 3 includes a deep character creator. All sorts of things like                                                                          gender, individual facial features (like eyes, nose, mouth, jaw, and cheeks), hair, stance, and technique can be modified. When altering the player's face, you can either use preset options or use sliders to have more control over the look.Roster  Due to contractual obligations,                                                                                          Rafael Nadal is only available exclusively to the PlayStation 3 version of Top Spin 3. Players that feature in both the Xbox 360 and PlayStation 3 versions are as follows: The gentlemenMen                                                                                         Roger Federer                                                                                          Andy Roddick                                                                                     Andy Murray                                                                                    David Nalbandian                                                                                   James Blake     Tomas Berdych    Gael Monfils                                                                                  Tommy Haas                                                                                 Mario Ancic   Mark Philippoussis The ladiesWomen                                                                                Justine Henin                                                                                   Svetlana Kuznetsova                                                                              Amelie Mauresmo                                                                              Maria Sharapova                                                                            Caroline Wozniacki                                                                           Nicole Vaidisova Legends                                                                          Boris BeckerBjorn BorgMonica Seles The Wii roster does not include Borg or Seles. VenuesMany of the events featured are based on their real-life counterparts. This includes three Grand Slams and eight Masters tournaments. Wimbledon does not feature, as the developer was unable to attain the rights for it. A fictional grass court in Ireland is used instead.  There are dozens of different venues that can be played in:Brinsley Carlenton Court - the game's equivalent of Wimbledon   Grand Slams    Australian Open - Melbourne,                                                                     Australia (Hard)Roland Garros - Paris,                                                                    France (Clay)Brinsley Carlenton Court - Dublin,                                                                   Ireland  (                                                                 Grass) US Open - New York,                                                                 USA (Hard) MastersPacific Life Open - Indian Wells, USA (Hard)Sony Ericsson Open - Miami, USA (Hard)    Roland Garros Stadio San Alessandro - Rome,                                                                Italy (Clay)Hamburg Stadhalle - Hamburg,                                                               Germany (Hard)Canada Tennis Center - Toronto,                                                              Canada (Hard)  Cincinnati Tennis Center - Cincinnati, USA (Hard) Madrid Indoor Sports Arena - Madrid,                                                             Spain (Indoor)BNP Paribas Masters - Paris,                                                            France (Indoor) Other Hard Venues    The Indian Wells Masters Vienna Tennis Center - Vienna,                                        AustriaSeoul Colosseum - Seoul,                                       South KoreaEstadio do Sol - Estoril,                                      PortugalTexas Arena - Dallas, USAAmsterdam Tennis Park - Amsterdam,                                     NetherlandsAbhijava Stadium - New Delhi,                         IndiaChicago Public Courts - Chicago, USASilvije Krleza - Omis,                                    CroatiaAtlanta's Doves - Atlanta, USAKobe Community Tennis Courts - Kobe,                                   JapanEl Sol Spring Camp - Mexico City,                                  MexicoMediterranean Leisure Club - Zekynthos,                                 GreeceTennis Park - Hamilton, BermudaOther Clay VenuesBarcelona Tennis Arena - Barcelona, SpainWestside Drive - Houston, USABuenos Aires Tennis Center - Buenos Aires, ArgentinaCasablanca Tennis Complex - Casablanca,                                MoroccoTeranga Tennis Court - Dakar, SenegalOther Grass VenuesLondon Tennis Club - London,                               EnglandThorsten Brom Stadium - Munich,                              GermanyBoston Bay Tennis Center - Boston, USANew Hampbridge College Court - New Hampbridge, EnglandOther Indoor VenuesMoscow Tennis Arena - Moscow,                             RussiaDubai Sports Complex - Dubai, UAERio Beach Tennis Center - Rio de Janeiro,                            BrazilTokyo Tennis Box - Tokyo, JapanSuva Sports Resort - Suva, FijiStavgaard Tennis Hall - Stavgaard,                           Sweden SoundtrackThe game has a        licensed soundtrack of eight songs from six different music artists. The track that features most prominently--for example, in the opening montage and the main menu--is "Huddle Formation" by British indie band The Go! Team. Other artists and songs in Top Spin 3 are:   Boys Like Girls - "The Great Escape" Calvin Harris - "Acceptable in the 80s", "Disco Heat", "The Girls"Franz Ferdinand - "Do You Want To?"Jamiroquai - "Canned Heat" Stone Roses - "Fool's Gold" The Wii VersionTop Spin 3 on the Wii is slightly different when compared to the Xbox 360 or PlayStation 3 games. While there is no World Tour mode or online multiplayer, it does have a handful of                 party games that can be played with three friends. The game is also played with                motion controls using a Wii remote and a nunchuk attachment, and is much easier to pick up and play, as is expected from a Wii title.  The DS VersionIn addition to the majority of players and venues from the home consoles, the DS cart also contains Play Now, Career, Tournament, and Minigames modes and multiplayer functionality. The Career mode is similar to the World Tour mode, but has a few changes, most notably the option to play training games to boost your player's stats or to play event              minigames to earn new items for your character. Reception   Top Spin 3 on the DS  The Xbox 360 and PlayStation 3 versions of Top Spin 3 were generally positively received by gaming critics. The majority of reviewers discuss the tough learning curve, but conclude that once you get the hang of the game, it becomes very satisfying to play. IGN noted that "deep controls liken Top Spin 3 to the genuine article more than most sports games", calling them "inaccessible" but in time "you'll reap the rewards". Eurogamer calls it a "technical tour-de-force" and the "thinking man's tennis title", but 1UP was less complimentary, saying that it's "prohibitive to folks who don't want to spend hours in the school of hard knocks".  The Wii and DS iterations garnered mixed reviews. Some critics have commented on how the Wii game lacks the depth and lasting appeal to make it a memorable tennis simulation. Top Spin 3 on the DS has been acknowledged to be a vast improvement on Top Spin 2, as its predecessor suffered from severe frame-rate issues, but opinion is split on whether the core gameplay is fun or not.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="25">Tennis</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19443">Virtua Tennis 3</game><game id="21145">Smash Court Tennis 3</game><game id="19029">Top Spin</game><game id="17111">Top Spin 2</game><game id="10676">Virtua Tennis</game><game id="16770">Rockstar Games presents Table Tennis</game><game id="6073">Mario Tennis</game><game id="3038">Tennis Critters</game><game id="25294">Virtua Tennis 2009</game><game id="24396">Grand Slam Tennis</game><game id="32369">Virtua Tennis 4</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2266555-box_ts3.png</image></root>