<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>209</id><name>Tiny Toon Adventures: The Great Beanstalk</name><description>Tiny Toon Adventure is a platformer/point-and-click adventure game made on NewKidCo. Based off the Tiny Toon Adventures Cartoon series, it has the same style and voice actors of the regular show. Buster and Plucky are in an economic mess so they had to sell their cow. Buster sold the cow for magic beans. Plucky threw the beans out the window and they grew into a beanstalk. The story shares with Jack and the Beanstalk. The object of the game is to find 3 items to get 3 pieces of a key. You'll have to climb up the beanstalk to reach a fairytaile world to find the item where you'll have to click your way to find it. You'll hav to find 3 keys in order to get a chicken that lays golden eggs, a huge amount of cash, and a golden harp.You go around in a platforming stage following Buster on where to go. You have to find certain items that Babs tells you on the intercom system. Find an item and you get a piece of a key. To find items, you'll have to point and click your way around fairy-tale levels like Humpty Dumpty and Little Bo Peep. Anything  you click on  leads to it reacting with a cutscene. find all 3 pieces of the key and you're able to go into the castle. go in the castle 3 times so you can get  your chicken, your money, and your harp.The game has its Tiny Toon charm as it has witty jokes and puns all around. Even though Steven Spielberg wasn't a part of this game, the comedy stayed where it's at</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="8">Educational</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4372">Maniac Mansion: Day of the Tentacle</game><game id="3019">The Secret of Monkey Island</game><game id="11852">Sam &amp; Max Hit the Road</game><game id="6049">Sam &amp; Max Save the World</game><game id="8430">Pajama Sam: No Need to Hide When It’s Dark Outside</game><game id="931">Putt-Putt Travels Through Time</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2280533-box_ttatgb.png</image></root>