<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20908</id><name>The Legend of Spyro: Dawn of the Dragon</name><description>GameplayThis new installment of the     Spyro franchises boasts a more advanced game play system. A new feature to    Spyro is that he is able to fly at anytime in the game instead of just gliding.   The game also features a co-op which lets other players drop in and control   Cynder. This also lets a single player control both Spyro and Cynder and uses them as a “Tag Team”. Like all Spyro games “Dawn of the Dragon” is a free-roamer letting the player explore the Dragon world in much detail.      Both Spyro and Cynder are playable characters. As always Spyro can control fire, in addition to ice, electric and earth breath. While Cynder controls Wind, poison, shadow and fear. The powers were given to her when she was under the control of the Dark Master, Cynder is a bit faster that Spyro but not as powerful. They also have a system called melee combos, which means the more hits in secession a player lays onto a enemy the more blue gems will appear. Blue gems are used to power up Spyro’s and Cynder’s breath moves. Along with the Blue gems there are the Red gems which restore health, Green gems which restore Dragon breath and Purple gems [also called fury gems] that when collected will enable the player to use a extremely powerful attack called “ A Devastating Attack” which kills all enemies and even bosses have a small chance of surviving the attack.   Along with their powers, Spyro and Cynder can find and equip Dragon armor which has a number of different attributes.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14623">Jak and Daxter: The Precursor Legacy</game><game id="3438">MediEvil II</game><game id="4228">Haven: Call of the King</game><game id="11407">Vexx</game><game id="7804">Rocket: Robot on Wheels</game><game id="20330">Gex 3: Deep Cover Gecko</game><game id="15991">Chameleon Twist 2</game><game id="18376">Looney Tunes Back in Action</game><game id="24969">Tokobot Plus: Mysteries of the Karakuri</game><game id="10533">Conker's Bad Fur Day</game><game id="96">Kao the Kangaroo</game><game id="25720">Jak and Daxter: The Lost Frontier</game><game id="19388">Ape Escape 3</game><game id="35545">Fuse</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2136555-box_tlosdotd.png</image></root>