<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20928</id><name>Golden Axe: Beast Rider</name><description>OverviewTyris FlareGolden Axe: Beast Rider is an action-adventure game developed by US studio  Secret Level and published by Sega. This game was released on October 14, 2008.  Beast Rider is a reinvention of the  Golden Axe series which made its home console debut on the  Sega Genesis. Unlike the original game which featured co-op play throughout, Beast Rider is a single-player game in which the player assumes the role of  Tyris Flare, the amazon warrior of the original game. PlotThe game's story is a retelling of the original game's conflict against the forces of  Death Adder.  Early on in the game, Tyris' tribe is destroyed by Death Adder's army, leaving her as the last among her kind.  She meets up with the dwarf warrior  Gilius Thunderhead, who presents her with pieces of the fabled Golden Axe, and is charged with the task of restoring the weapon to its full strength. GameplayThe gameplay is split into three parts: combat, magic, and beast riding. The battle system features swordplay similar to that found in other third-person action games, with the focus on fighting large groups of enemies, while a parry and evade system should add some depth. As well as featuring bloody combat and dismemberment , stringing together long combos allow players to initiate brutal cinematic kills.To pilot a beast, Tyris must climb onto the creature and drive her sword into the creature's back as a makeshift method of control. Mountable beasts range from dragons to giant apes and most are based on creatures featured in the original game.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20621">Viking: Battle for Asgard</game><game id="6959">God of War</game><game id="13072">Devil May Cry</game><game id="7876">Heavenly Sword</game><game id="21210">Conan</game><game id="20482">Beowulf: The Game</game><game id="30636">Garshasp: The Monster Slayer</game><game id="21348">X-Blades</game><game id="35629">Bloodforge</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2409905-box_gabr.png</image></root>