<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20939</id><name>Disgaea 3: Absence of Justice</name><description>OverviewDeveloped by Nippon Ichi, Disgaea 3: Absense of Justice, was released on the PlayStation 3 in Japan on January 31st, 2008.  Eight months later, the title landed in North American shores, distributed by Atlus and published by NIS America, on August 26th, 2008.  Disgaea 3 is not only the first title in the franchise released for the PlayStation 3, but Nippon Ichi's first entry as a developer as well.   StoryMao is a Netherworld Honor Student inside of Maritsu Evil Academy.  This is a school wherein someone achieving honors means they have ditched classes and refused to complete homework.  Proper studying consists of poring over comic books and video games. Raspberyl, one of Mao's female classmates, is a delinquent, meaning she comes to class early and prepared and completes her homework.  One day, while finishing a manga, Mao realizes that heroes are destined to battle and defeat overlords. He decides to become a hero and defeat the Overlord of the Netherworld, who just so happens to be his father and the Dean of Evil Academy, where Mao is an honor student. With a little push from Mao's conspiring Butler, Geoffrey, Mao's quest for hero status begins.It isn't long before Raspberyl learns of Mao's plot, which stomps on her own plans to become Maritsu Evil Academy's Number One Delinquent.  Raspberyl follows along with Mao in order to stop him, arguing with him through words rather than battling through violence.  Almaz, a human Hero, watches their argument and rushes in to defeat them.  Mao, however, defeats the human which grants him Almaz's title of Hero.Changes from Previous Disgaea GamesStory Characters now keep their stat modifiers/increases when Reincarnated.  Created Characters/Monsters keep other certain stats, such as Movement Range, when Reincarnating.New Skills for Tower Attacks and ways to build Towers in the first place, such as by a Character walking-up the Tower and not having to be lifted.Evilities have been added.  They are abilities that grant certain Characters very unique attributes, such as the Prinny's ability to be Healed 100% for only 1 HL.Skills are now purchased using Mana, instead of using the actual weapons to level them up.  You now are required to Reincarnate to unlock higher Skill Levels.Skills can no longer be transferred via the Pupil System.  You must now use the Class World to accomplish the same thing (Skills can still be used via the Club System, just not "learned").Guns are now based on HIT and SPD stats,  instead of only on the HIT stat. Axes now penalized the SPD stat instead of the HIT stat, which makes them not miss as much.Geo Symbols have been replaced by Geo Blocks and they can now be stacked.Damage output shows higher amount of digits, up to the billions.Some sprites use up to 4 times the amount of animation data, yet they are still not HD.Backgrounds/Battlefeilds are now in HD.Patch History Patch 2.0 was released on 12/23/2008 and was 202 MB in size.  This Patch enabled DLC to be installed and fixed a bug with changing music in the Item World, among other minor bug fixes.Patch 2.1 was released on 2/10/2009 and was 140 MB in size.  It fixed a bug with the Drop-out Rate, in the Class World, which was introduced in Patch 2.0.  Trophy and PlayStation Home SupportTrophies (as well as PlayStation Home Rewards) became available in the Japanese Version of Disgaea 3 via a Patch on 3/26/2009. Trophies were added to the American version of Disgaea 3 on 7/16/2009.Here is the translated Trophy List:BronzePlay for 10 hours straight, without exiting the game.Capture an Enemy Monster.Finish an Item World run, from Floor 1 to 100, without using a Mr. Gency's Exit (or leaving by any other means, such as a Random Event or by being offered after an Item Boss).Speak with the Cat Monster, on top of the Tower, in the Tower Room of the Item World.Collect all the treasures, during Reverse Pirating.Kill an enemy unit with a 10 hit combo.Kill an enemy unit with a 10 unit Tower Attack.Have one Character perform 9 Counter Attacks in a row, after being the target of an attack.Have one Character deal 1 million damage in a single turn.Have one Character deal 100 million damage in a single turn.Achieve a 5 Color Geo Panel Chain Reaction.Achieve a 10 Color Geo Block Chain Reaction.Accomplish a 255 turn stationary bonus.Perform 100 Jumps total.Perform 5 Magichanges in a single battle.Pass a Home Room Proposal by force!Find Axel in the Item World.Defeat %PIRATE NAME% (NOTE: There are 21 Bronze Trophies for each Type of Pirate in the game, not including the 3 "Elite" Pirate Types).SilverDefeat the Prinny Pirates.Defeat the 10 Diez Gentlemen Pirates.Defeat the Baal Pirates.Find the Trophy Room in the Item World (only appears between Floors 90 to 100).Plunder/Retrieve all Innocents during Reverse Pirating. GoldFinish a Land of Carnage Item World run, from Floor 1 to 100, without using a Mr. Gency's Exit (or leaving by any other means, such as a Random Event or by being offered after an Item Boss).Plunder/Retrieve all Innocents, Treasures, and Level Spheres on the Map.Have one Character deal 10 billion damage in a single turn. PlatinumCollect all other Trophies to be awarded this Platinum Trophy. It's notable that as the trophy support was added so long after the game's release that there are no trophies for any story events, only for achieving difficult tasks mostly separate from the main game.Downloadable ContentNorth AmericaThe first batch of DLC ("Downloadable Characters" in Disgaea 3's case, for the most part) was released on 12/23/2008 (an odd early-week update, not on Thrusday, due to Christmas).  The second batch of DLC was released on 1/15/2009 and each release afterwards currently countiues on about every couple weeks to a month.So far, the following DLC is available on the U.S. PlayStation Store:12/23/2008 - Disgaea 3: Absence of Justice - Disgaea 2 Character Set @ $4.99 (This Pack includes the below 4 DLC, which can also be purchased individually)12/23/2008 - Disgaea 3: Absence of Justice - Disgaea 2 Character Theme @ $0.99 (Full Theme with Wallpaper, Sounds, and Icons for for your PS3 XMB) 12/23/2008 - Disgaea 3: Absence of Justice - Adell @ $1.99 (Humanoid Character from Disgaea 2)12/23/2008 - Disgaea 3: Absence of Justice - Rozalin @ $1.99 (Humanoid Character from Disgaea 2) 12/23/2008 - Disgaea 3: Absence of Justice - Nekomata @ $0.99 (Monster Character from Disgaea 2)1/15/2009 - Disgaea 3: Makai Kingdom Main Character Set @ $3.99 (This Pack includes a "free" Pram Wallpaper and includes the below 2 DLC, which can also be purchased individually)1/15/2009 - Disgaea 3: Makai Kingdom - Oracle Pram @ $1.991/15/2009 - Disgaea 3: Makai Kingdom - Lord Zetta @ $1.991/30/2009 - Disgaea 3: Absence of Justice - Hanako @ $1.99 (Monster Character from Disgaea 2)1/30/2009 - Disgaea 3: Absence of Justice - Taro @ $1.99 (Monster Character from Disgaea 2)2/12/2009 - Disgaea 3: Absence of Justice - Disgaea 2 Sacrebleu Character Set  @ $5.99 (This Pack includes a "free" Priere Theme and includes the below 3 DLC, which can also be purchased individually)2/12/2009 - Disgaea 3: Absence of Justice - Priere  @ $1.99 2/12/2009 - Disgaea 3: Absence of Justice - Tink  @ $1.99 2/12/2009 - Disgaea 3: Absence of Justice - Yukimaru  @ $1.99 2/26/2009 -   Disgaea 3: Absence of Justice -   Demon  Detective Set @ $3.99 (This Pack includes a "free"   Kogure Custom Theme and includes the below 3 DLC, which can also be purchased individually)2/26/2009 -    Disgaea 3: Absence of Justice - Kogure Custom Theme @ $0.992/26/2009 -  Disgaea 3:   Absence of Justice -  Kogure @ $1.992/26/2009 -     Disgaea 3:   Absence of Justice -   Marjoly @ $1.99   3/26/2009 - Disgaea 3: Absence of Justice - Item World Command Attack Mode @ $3.993/26/2009 - Disgaea 3: Absence of Justice - Defender of Earth Character Set @ $5.99 (This Pack includes the below 3 DLC, which can also be purchased individually)  3/26/2009 - Disgaea 3: Absence of Justice - Gordon @ $1.993/26/2009 - Disgaea 3: Absence of Justice - Jennifer @ $1.993/26/2009 - Disgaea 3: Absence of Justice - Thursday @ $1.994/23/2009 - Disgaea 3: Absence of Justice - Curtis @ $1.994/23/2009 - Disgaea 3: Absence of Justice - Prinny Curtis @ $1.994/28/2009 - Disgaea 3: Absence of Justice - Item World Survival Attack Mode @ $3.994/28/2009 - Disgaea 3: Absence of Justice - Fake Heroes Set @ $3.99 (This Pack includes the below 3 DLC, which can also be purchased individually) 4/28/2009 - Disgaea 3: Absence of Justice Character - Action Prinny @ $1.994/28/2009 - Disgaea 3: Absence of Justice Character - Dragon @ $0.994/28/2009 - Disgaea 3: Absence of Justice Character - Mid-Boss @ $1.99JapanJune 08Adell - 200 yenRozalin - 200 yenNekomata - 100 yenJuly 08Taro - 200 yenHanako - 200 yenKogure - 200 yenAugust 08Tink - 200 yenYukimaru - 200 yenPriere - 200 yenItem World "Command Attack" (Angel class) - 500 yenSeptember 08Pram - 200 yenBook Zetta - 200 yenMarjoly - 200 yenOctober 08Gordon - 200 yenJennifer - 200 yenThursday - 200 yenClass World "Command Attack" (Aramis) - 500 yenNovember 08Gig - 200 yenRevya - 200 yenHero Prinny - freeDragon - 100 yenDecember 08Kurtis - 200 yenPrinny Kurtis - 200 yenMid-Boss - 200 yenItem World "Survival Attack" (Pleinair) - 500 yenToro  Kuro events - free  </description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25844">Vandal Hearts: Flames of Judgment</game><game id="23693">Cross Edge</game><game id="26556">Trinity Universe</game><game id="27113">Record of Agarest War</game><game id="32107">Cladun: This is an RPG!</game><game id="27861">Shin Megami Tensei: Persona 3 Portable</game><game id="14528">Shining Force II</game><game id="29051">Ar tonelico Qoga: Knell of Ar Ciel</game><game id="31284">Hyperdimension Neptunia</game><game id="30167">Zettai Hero Project: Unlosing Ranger vs. Darkdeath Evilman</game><game id="29872">Dokapon DX</game><game id="35687">Rainbow Moon</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1832913-box_disgaea3.png</image></root>