<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20930</id><name>FaceBreaker</name><description>OverviewFaceBreaker is a boxing title that was developed by EA Canada and published under the EA Sports Freestyle label. More cartoonish and far less serious than EA's Fight Night series, the game was released on the Xbox 360 and PlayStation 3, along with FaceBreaker: K.O. Party on the Wii.CharactersBrickIceKekoaKirikoMolotovRomeoSocksSparrowSpinSteveTikiVoodooSoundtrackFacebreaker features the usual list of licensed EA tracks, mostly hip hop and guitar-heavy rock.Boys Noize - Arcade RobotBoys Noize - Oh!Dropkick Murphys - The Warrior’s CodeFort Knox Five feat. Mustafa Akbar - The Spirit of 75From First To Last - Worlds AwayFrom First To Last - Two As OneFrom First To Last - We All Turn Back To DustFujiya  Miyagi - Sucker PunchGogol Bordello - 60 RevolutionsKenna - Out Of Control (State of Emotion) – Free Donuts and Shellfish XXXChange with Ronnie Darko Spankrock RemixKinky - Uruapan BreaksLos Mocosos - Bandolera Era (Reggaeton Remix)Ozomatli - Street SignsTone Loc feat. Peaches - Wild Thing (Peaches RMX)Prophet Omega - CriminalQuit Your Day Job feat. R.A. The Rugged Man - Warmachine (Remake)Santogold - CreatorSweatmaster - AnimalThe Go! Team - Universal SpeechThe Hives - Square One Here I ComeThe Procussions - Fight HereThe Rivers - Knock Me DownTigarah - Girl FightTone Deaf Junkies - Kwaai TechticWolfmother - Woman (MSTRKRFT Remix)</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="20">Boxing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8095">Fight Night Round 3</game><game id="19836">Ready 2 Rumble Boxing</game><game id="11649">Ready 2 Rumble Boxing: Round 2</game><game id="23965">Punch-Out!!</game><game id="14768">Boxing Fever</game><game id="6029">Super Punch-Out!!</game><game id="24673">Ready 2 Rumble Revolution</game><game id="25648">Don King Boxing</game><game id="43401">BlackOut</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2291739-box_fbreaker.png</image></root>