<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20965</id><name>The Lord of the Rings: Conquest</name><description>OverviewThe Lord of the Rings: Conquest is based on the books and movies of The Lord of the Rings and promises also to give people new to the series an experience that will introduce them and tell the epic story. The game should play incredibly similarly to the Star Wars: Battlefront series as it is being developed by the same team and uses the same engine. A demo has been released on the Playstation Network on December 23, 2008, which takes about 1 GB of hard drive space. A demo was also released on the Xbox Live Marketplace on January 2, 2009 .CampaignThe Lord Of The Rings Conquest PosterThere are two campaigns in The Lord of the Rings: Conquest. The good campaign where you play men, elves, and dwarfs trying to save Middle Earth from Sauron. This includes the famous battle for Minas Tirith and Rohan. Likewise there is the evil campaign. This includes a story arc where Frodo does not destroy the Ring, instead a Ringwraith grabs it and brings it back to Sauron where he gets revived to reek havoc on Middle Earth. It is said that you will get to play as all the evil guys trying to destroy and take over what is left of Middle Earth. The campaign modes objectives range from defending a position to killing a certain amount of enemies or assaulting and taking over command points. The developer has also stated that there will be multiple ways to complete objectives from standing back with a bow and arrow to riding in with a horse, or even using siege weapons, although it has also been said that you will have to unlock some weapons and horses rather then just being given everything.GameplayThe gameplay is very similar to the Star Wars Battlefront series. There are command points where you spawn to kill the enemy, but in the campaigns there will beThe Lord Of The Rings Conquest Battle Scenevariations. In the command points you pick a class to play, only four classes has been released so far in the good campaign. The scout, the rogue of the bunch, warrior, the tank, archer and mage. The developers have hailed their new melee system which has significantly improved the warrior and tank classes. The archer and mage classes have both been shown to operate in the typical shooter model that the Star Wars Battlefront games have made popular. Pandemic games said that if you wanted you could play the whole game in a FPS style using archers and Mages. There are also heroes you get in certain parts of the campaigns, like Aragorn, Gimli and even Sauron. The heroes for multiplayer haven't been announced. Once you complete the first campaign, you can go through the evil campaign. The game assumes Frodo got caught dropping the Ring into Mount Doom, and goes back through Moria, Weathertop, the Shire, and more, ending with a battle at the Elven home of Rivendell. This concept is not unique as games such as The Lord of the Rings: Battle for Middle Earth 2 featured evil campaigns with events that did not actually occur in the series.MultiplayerThe online multiplayer features 4 modes: Conquest, Deathmatch, Hero Deathmatch and Capture the Ring. There is split screen and online co-op modes available for the campaigns. The online portion will allow for 16 players to battle-fight each other in the four multiplayer modes. There is basic conquest mode where you have to capture all the command points. Death Match is just a Team-based 'Kill everyone' mode. Hero Deathmatch is pretty much the same as Deathmatch, except everyone gets to use one of the Hero Characters. Capture the Ring is a take on Capture the Flag where both teams fight over the 'One Ring'.Other Game modes that have been talked about are Ringbearer and Stronghold. In Ringbearer, one player plays as a Frodo and the remaining players as Nazgul. Frodo must stay alive and evade the Nazgul as long as possible. The Nazgul that kills Frodo becomes the new Frodo. Stronghold is similar to Star Wars: Battlefront's Galactic Conquest mode. Both modes do not appear in the shipping game and are likely to be released as DLC. Players are allowed to control large creatures like Trolls for Saurons forces and Ents for the Free Peoples.CharactersLike Star Wars: Battlefront II before it, Conquest features powerful hero characters for both the good and evil sides of the conflict. Fan favorites such as Aragorn, Legolas and Gimli are included, as well as powerful evil hero characters such as the Balrog, Saruman and Sauron himself. The various heroes are essentially a more powerful version of one of the existing classes, for example, Aragorn is an upgraded Warrior and Frodo behaves like a Scout.Good Hero Characters:AragornLegolasGimliGandalfElrondIsildurFaramirEowynFrodoEvil Hero Characters:BalrogGothmogLurtzMouth of SauronNazgulSarumanSauronWitch-KingWormtongueClassesEach class has one unique style from a possible five - Melee, ranged, stealth and magic.Warrior: Primarily a melee based combat unit that uses swordplay. They gain strength to unleash powerful attacks and can set their swords on fire. Secondary weapon are axes to throw at enemies.Archer: The ranged based unit that uses a bow  arrow in combat. Various arrows are available to the player such as poison to do damage over time, fire to knock down enemies and a triple shot to attack multiple targets. Also has a close quarter attack to knock an enemy back.Scout: Has the ability to move unseen with great stealth.Carries two daggers, has the ability to cloak and can kill units from behind by surprise. The ranged attack is satchel charges filled with explosives to throw from a distance.Mage: The magic class, primary attack consists of lightning which can be charged for a greater damaging attack. They have the ability to heal allies and use the staff for melee combat. The mage can create an orb to protect himself and others around him from ranged attacks however is vulnerable to melee combat while doing so.Any AI Unit can ride a mount, these include horses for the allies and wargs for the enemy team respectively. The mounts can cover ground quickly, however damage will result in the player being dismounted. Melee weapons such as swords can still be used while riding, and players can also trample enemies by riding over them.Downloadable ContentHero Arena Bonus: (Free)Released: Feb. 5, 2009Hero Arenas:-The Great Hall of Moria- OsgiliathThis pack is available here.Second DLC Pack: (800 MS Points, $9.99)Released: Feb. 26, 2009Characters:-Arwen (Hero)- Boromir (Hero)-Gothmog (Hero)Maps:-Amon Hen-Battle of the Last AllianceHero Arenas:-Weathertop- Mina's TirithThis pack is available here.PC SpecsMinimum System Requirements:Windows XP SP2 or Windows Vista2.4 GHz Core Duo processor or equivalent1 GB RAM256 MB Video Card, with support for Pixel Shader 3.0 - nvidia 7800 or equivelentThe latest version of DirectX 9.0cDirectX 9.0c compatible sound cardAt least 6 GB of hard drive space for installation.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15481">Star Wars: Battlefront</game><game id="7094">Star Wars: Battlefront II</game><game id="12716">Battlefield 1942</game><game id="24949">Star Wars: Battlefront III</game><game id="8201">Lara Croft Tomb Raider: Anniversary</game><game id="21220">Battlefield Heroes</game><game id="21178">Ninja Gaiden: Dragon Sword</game><game id="25235">Under Siege</game><game id="26539">The Lord of the Rings: Aragorn's Quest</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14036/872980-front.jpg</image></root>