<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20963</id><name>Wario Land: Shake It!</name><description>Overview A scene from one of the ingame cutscenesWario Land: Shake It! is the latest in the Wario Land series. Developed by Good Feel (whose CEO comes from the now defunct Konami Computer Entertainment Kobe) and published by Nintendo, it was released on September 22, 2008. The game is known as Wario Land: The Shake Dimension in Europe and Wario Land: Shake in Japan. In the game, players take control of Wario, in his quest to get the Bottomless Coin Sack.The game features hand-drawn graphics and animated cutscenes by Production I.G. (a well-known anime company). The graphical style follows that of Super Mario Land 3: Wario Land, Wario Land 2, Wario Land 3, and Wario Land 4, but this is the first to have hand-drawn graphics. StoryThe land of Yuretopia is shattered by the evil Shake King. He claims all of the world's inhabitants and the Bottomless Coin Sack. Captain Maple Syrup watches the world being captured from somewhere else, and desires the legendary treasure for herself. She has Wario go to help, when one of the world's inhabitants escapes and begs Wario to become a hero for the kingdom.   After defeating the Shake King, Wario finds meets Queen Merelda, only to throw he aside and run after the Bottomless Coin Sack. He is filled with happiness, until Captain Syrup claims the treasure which the Merfle promised to her. That angers Wario and he attacks Merfle as the game ends.   Gameplay Shaking out some treasureWario Land: Shake It! is a traditional 2D platformer. There are secret passages in the several levels that Wario must traverse, and at the end of every level a small green creature called a Melful. After rescuing the Melful, Wario must back-track through the level in a minimal amount of time.  Every level has a set of missions a player can do. Like most games, this challenges get increasingly difficult as the game goes on. Missions can include getting a certain amount of treasure, back-tracking before a certain time, and not getting hit during the entire level. Along with those, missions can also deal with how the level is designed. Examples of this are blowing up all the bombs in a level or not falling in water.  Treasure is always on the mind of Wario and it shows in this game. Throughout each level, they're are coins just floating around for Wario to pick up. Along with those, there's coin bags which he has to shake to get all the shiny winnings. All this treasure isn't just for show. Players can use it in the shop Captain Syrup opens up early in the game. New life vessels and world maps are some of the items available. There's also secret treasure in every level that players. Each treasure found has it's own unique description.    Tilt the Wii Remote to move the bucketOne of the key new gameplay features in Wario Land: Shake It! is the Wii motion control implementation. Using the Wii Remote, players can do such things as shake enemies and treasure chests, control submarines or other vehicles, swing on ropes or vines, and much, much more.  </description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3849">Mischief Makers</game><game id="12739">Super Paper Mario</game><game id="15207">Yoshi's Story</game><game id="2866">Super Mario World 2: Yoshi's Island</game><game id="10347">Yoshi's Island DS</game><game id="8224">New Super Mario Bros.</game><game id="7314">Super Mario Bros. Deluxe</game><game id="7551">Super Mario World: Super Mario Advance 2</game><game id="5215">Super Mario Advance</game><game id="11016">Yoshi's Island: Super Mario Advance 3</game><game id="1334">Super Mario World</game><game id="18529">Super Mario All-Stars</game><game id="20716">Braid</game><game id="25451">Cid the Dummy</game><game id="68">Crash Bandicoot: The Wrath of Cortex</game><game id="19834">Super Mario Land</game><game id="12909">Crash Bandicoot: Warped</game><game id="31721">Rayman Origins</game><game id="31732">Donkey Kong Country Returns</game><game id="37124">Sonic the Hedgehog 4: Episode II</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2269439-box_wlsi.png</image></root>