<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20975</id><name>Mega Man 9</name><description>OverviewMega Man 9 is an action platformer developed by Inti Creates and Capcom Japan, and published by Capcom. Mega Man 9 was made to resemble the old NES classics, using old sprites, and old-school design philosophy. It was released late in 2008 on the download services for all three major platforms ( Wii Shop, Playstation Network, and Xbox Live Marketplace).FeaturesThe first Mega Man game to have a female Robot Master, Splash WomanIt has an option to activate/deactivate old-school graphical glitches, such as the pixel "flicker" that many NES games had, including the original Mega Man games. This option defaults to being turned on.The game is played much like the earlier games in the Mega Man franchise, using only a directional pad, a button to jump, and a button to shoot. Levels are selected from a screen displaying each level's respective boss and can be played in any order.Certain abilities from games after Mega Man 2 were removed, such as the slide. One feature that first appeared in Mega Man 7 is present: the shop.Promotional art, designed by Gerald de Jesus, is another throwback to the franchise's roots, as it reflects the crudely realistic nature of the box art of the first two Mega Man games.Online Rankings to see who are the fastest Mega Man 9 players in the world, as well as speed runs for each individual level.50 In-Game Challenges to test your Mega Man skills, ranging from beating a boss in under 10 seconds to beating the game without being hit.Downloadable Content (DLC)Proto Man ModeAs a "Special Games" mode separate from the standard Mega Man play, you can take control of Proto Man, clad in red and white, and donning his trademark scarf. Proto Man plays somewhat differently from his blue counterpart, and player accomplishments are not tracked in the rankings . Most notably his arm cannon has the innate ability to do a charge shot, akin to that of Mega Man 5, that can travel through and kill multiple small enemies. He also has a forward-facing shield that activates when jumping, and is lowered when firing and running, capable of blocking many kinds of projectile weapons. His starting inventory includes both the Coil and Jet tools, though they are not embodied by Rush. There is no shopping option on the Stage Select screen when playing as Proto Man, and playing as Proto Man will not allow the players to submit their results online.Endless AttackIn Endless Attack, your goal is to pass through as many screens as possible without dying. Along the way, Mega Man fans may notice that some areas in Endless Attack are remakes from previous Mega Man games. These including the opening part of Wily Castle 1 from Mega Man 1, the opening part of Flash Man's level and Heat Man's jumping blocks puzzle from Mega Man 2 as well as others. Sections are 3 to 8 screens a piece that are of a singular theme. Every 30 or so screens you will be forced to fight one of the 8 Robot Masters the game has to offer. The Endlesss attack brings a variety of new tilesets to the game, expanding the scenery. In Endless attack, Mega Man can utilize all of his special weapons, though they will run out of ammo just as they do in the normal game. The game ends when Mega Man dies, and the game tells you your score, measured in screens.Special StageThe Special Stage.The Special Stage can only be accessed through Time Attack mode. In the Special Stage, you battle your way through a level that involves 3 sub bosses, including the end boss for Wily Castle 2 and a new Robot Master, named Fake Man, a Robot Master that can be seen twice through the main game during cutscenes.The Special Stage requires players to use almost every weapon at your disposal to get through, and is much longer and more challenging than the stages in the regular game.Hero ModeA new difficulty setting that doubles the original difficulty of the game, as well as changes enemy placements in levels. The bosses retain their similar patterns however.Superhero ModeA new difficulty setting that triples the original difficulty of the game, as well as changes enemy placements in levels. Like Hero Mode, the bosses stayed the same in terms of pattern and difficulty.GameplayMega Man 9 takes a minimalist approach to gameplay as opposed to the more complex styles in the later Mega Man and Mega Man X titles. The slide tackle and duck from later titles were removed. The gameplay is largely based on Mega Man 2, which many consider one of the best in the series.Proto Man during combat.  Players can make Mega Man run, jump, and shoot. Mega Man can only have 3 shots on screen at a time, meaning that far away enemies must be shot at slowly, while nearby foes can be taken out quicker. As is the Mega Man formula, Mega Man begins with only his buster and the Rush Coil, a spring loaded dog. As the player progresses through the game, defeating each robot master, they gain that robot master's primary weapon. These weapons have a variety of uses beyond combat. For example, Hornet Man's Hornet Chaser can be used to obtain out of reach items. Later in the game, the player also receives the Rush Jet, where Mega Man's dog turns into a flying platform, allowing Mega Man to cross large obstacles. Many levels are designed with the weapons in mind, some with hidden items that can only be obtained once Mega Man has a certain power. The final levels of the game test Mega Man's ability to employ all of his weapons in combat.The levels were designed with the earlier games in mind, with an emphasis on difficult platforming, rather than combat. Mega Man must jump over large pits and dangerous spikes, often with enemies threatening to knock him to his demise. There are a number of new obstacles in the game. On Tornado Man's stage, Mega Man will board spinning platforms that turn him upside down, and he also faces harsh weather conditions that at certain points limit and other points enhance his jumping distance. Some stages have extending platforms that quickly retract and throw Mega Man after a certain period of time and, as usual for a Mega Man title, there is a disappearing block section. Many obstacles, such as spikes and lava jets, will kill Mega Man instantly, and therefore should be avoided at all costs.One of the few aspects of Mega Man games post-Mega Man 2 included in 9 is the store. Throughout all of the levels, Mega Man can gather bolts, which can be used as currency in the store. Mega Man can purchase anything from extra lives to extra costumes. Among the new and more useful things available is an item which will automatically use pick ups to recharge weapons in need of energy.StoryEight more robot masters.As is typical for Mega Man's world, robots have gone on the rampage. Dr. Light, the creator of Mega Man, is apparently to blame for a robotic attack, as the robots ravaging the city were created by him, and all of them were near their expiration date. Once their expiration date arrives, they will be terminated. Dr. Wily has seemingly no connection to the rampage, though he has a video showing Dr. Light declaring his desire for world conquest and Dr. Wily refusing to follow. Dr.Wily claims in this video clip that he is a changed man, and will do whatever it takes to stop Dr. Light.. Mega Man must seek out the truth and prove his creator is innocent and expose Wily for the real villain.Later in his quest, Mega Man discovers revealing footage of Dr. Wily talking to the robot masters. Dr.Wily informs them of the imminent demise, and offers to "repair" them. All of the robots, hoping to continue living, desire Dr.Wily do whatever it takes. Mega Man now knows who the true culprit is, and has evidence to prove it. Just as Mega Man finishes viewing the video, Wily swoops in and snatches it. It is off to Wily's castle once again!Robot MastersThe game features new Robot Masters that Mega Man has to fight:Magma ManMagma Man once worked as a security guard in a geothermal power plant, and was designed to withstand great temperatures. He wields the Magma Bazooka, a weapon that shoots three projectiles in separate directions. His weakness is the Tornado Blow, which not only does great harm, but also weakens his attacks considerably. His stage is home to large jets of magma which will bring Mega Man a quick death.Galaxy ManGalaxy Man was designed by Dr. Light to be an assistant at a space laboratory. He can compute rocket trajectories instantly. Galaxy Man is equipped with the Black Hole bomb, which can be fired and then detonated to suck in surrounding objects. Galaxy Man's weakness is the Concrete Shot. Mega Man may find himself a bit confused with the warp jumps scattered in Galaxy Man's lair.Concrete ManConcrete Man's stage.Concrete Man was built to construct dams, and has always taken great pride in his work, and has always valued those who work hard. He fights with the Concrete shots, which can create blocks of concrete and encase foes in a shell of concrete. He is weak against the Laser Trident. Mega Man needs to watch his step in the realm of Concrete Man, or he may find a few of the floors will collapse underfoot.Hornet ManHornet Man has a body that resembles a honeycomb, and worked as a supervisor at a theme park before his violent rampage. He has a great knowledge of all things botanical, as well as the powerful Hornet Chaser weapon, which tracks down foes and grabs items. Hornet Man is not fond of the Magma Bazooka, which easily dispatches he and his hornets. Hornet Man's stage has a number of platforms which can be shot in order to extend them, though if Mega Man is slow footed, they will throw him back where he began.Tornado ManTornado Man was built to monitor the weather, and used his Tornado Blow to counter incoming typhoons. This ability once used for good is now used to be a pain in Mega Man's derierre. Tornado Man's weakness is the Plug Ball. Tornado Man's stage has a great variety of obstacles, including spinning platforms and harsh winds.Plug ManAt one point in his lifespan, Plug Man was a humble inspector working in a television factory. Once he met Dr. Wily, however, things changed, and he utilized his lethal Plug Ball to bring terror to the world. He has never been a fan of the Jewel Satellite. Plug Man's stage is the home of everyone's favorite disappearing block sequence, as well as a few Mega Man dopplegangers.Jewel ManJewel Man's stageJewel Man's career was spent working in a diamond mine, polishing precious stones. He uses his Jewel Satellite to fend off his enemies, though the satellite is powerless against Black Hole Bombs. Jewel Man's stage features large swinging platforms, and spikes galore.Splash WomanThe most surprising addition to the lineup of robot masters, and the very first female robot master. She was built by Dr. Light as a rescue worker to aid those in danger at sea, and she resembles a mermaid. Splash Woman wields the devastating Laser Trident, which can travel through enemies. Splash Woman has always hated hornets, and the Hornet Chaser is no exception. Splash Woman's stage takes place underwater, and Mega Man must use bubbles as platforms to reach her.Bonus Robot MastersFake ManThrough DLC, Capcom has made one additional robot master available for Mega Man 9:Fake ManFake man resembles a police officer, currently for unknown reasons. The first boss featured as DLC. Fake Man's stage will only be playable in time attack mode, not in the main story or challenge mode. His level is "time sensitive," and is described as similar in difficulty to the Wily stages.Box ArtBox ArtAlthough the game is only available in downloadable form, Capcom designed the Mega Man 9 press kit to resemble an NES game package with the press assets disc encased in a shell shaped like a NES game cartridge; the "cartridge" was in turn packaged in a cardboard box of a design similar to those that NES games were packaged in. The box and cartridge case label were both designed to bear little to no resemblance to the game itself as a self-referential nod to the misrepresentative box art created for the western release of the first Mega Man on the NES. Capcom plans to release this to the public, but in extremely limited quantities. The artwork will also be featured on a t-shirt.Easter EggsBassOnce the player has beaten Dr.Wily, a cutscene will take place. In that cutscene, Bass can be seen on a screen in the backgroundSoundtrackAlbum coverJanuary the 19th 2009 the Complete soundtrack of Megaman 9 featuring 35 different songs will be available at the online Capcom store (available for preorder since the 11th), it will also contain a 10 page booklet with concept art of the different characters in color and liner notes from the game's director, producer, sound production  design and the comic artists. The Megaman 9 soundtrack will cost $29.95TracklistReverse cover of album.01 OPENING 102 OPENING 203 OPENING 304 TITLE05 MENU06 STAGE SELECT07 GAME START08 CONCRETE JUNGLE (CONCRETE MAN STAGE)09 THUNDER TORNADO (TORNADO MAN STAGE)10 SPLASH BLUE (SPLASH WOMAN STAGE11 PLUG ELECTRIC (PLUG MAN STAGE)12 JEWEL TEMPTATION (JEWEL MAN STAGE)13 HORNET DANCE (HORNET MAN STAGE)14 MAGMA BURNING (MAGMA MAN STAGE)15 GALAXY FANTASY (GALAXY MAN STAGE)16 BOSS17 STAGE CLEAR18 GET A WEAPON19 SHOP20 RUSH JET21 SUSPENSE22 DR. WILY UFO23 DR. WILY CASTLE24 FLASH IN THE DARK (DR. WILY STAGE 1)25 WE'RE THE ROBOTS (DR. WILY STAGE 2)26 STRANGE WORLD (DR. WILY STAGE 3)27 CASTLE OF EVIL (DR. WILY STAGE 4)28 WILY MACHINE29 ENDING30 STAFF ROLL31 OVERDRIVE SCRAMBLE (SPECIAL STAGE)32 MAZE OF DEATH (ENDLESS STAGE)33 GAME OVER34 OLD SE35 NEW SE</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10152">Bucky O'Hare</game><game id="2866">Super Mario World 2: Yoshi's Island</game><game id="20169">Darkwing Duck</game><game id="15799">DuckTales</game><game id="1994">Chip 'N Dale: Rescue Rangers</game><game id="8292">Super Metroid</game><game id="10323">Metroid Fusion</game><game id="21761">Metroid</game><game id="4350">Contra</game><game id="847">Metal Slug</game><game id="10077">Super C</game><game id="840">Metal Slug 2: Super Vehicle - 001/II</game><game id="15819">Castlevania Chronicles</game><game id="25115">Pole's Big Adventure</game><game id="16188">Clash at Demonhead</game><game id="1638">Mega Man X6</game><game id="6673">Castlevania</game><game id="15212">Ratchet &amp; Clank Future: Tools of Destruction</game><game id="14216">Castlevania: Symphony of the Night</game><game id="8583">Metal Slug Advance</game><game id="29536">Dark Void Zero</game><game id="28078">Sonic the Hedgehog 4: Episode I</game><game id="33119">The Tempura of the Dead</game><game id="31659">Moon Diver</game><game id="37706">Rokko Chan</game><game id="37124">Sonic the Hedgehog 4: Episode II</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8125/562580-megaman9boxart.jpg</image></root>