<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20973</id><name>Super Air Zonk: Rockabilly-Paradise</name><description>HistorySuper Air Zonk: Rockabilly Paradise is the follow up game to Air Zonk. Air Zonk was a side scrolling shooter game for the TurboGrafx-16 console, developed by Red Company and Hudson Soft. It was an unusual sequel to the prior Bonk games; Bonk's Adventure, Bonk's Revenge and Bonk 3, from Hudson and NEC that were successful on the TurboGrafx-16.Super Air Zonk was developed by Dual and published by Hudson. It was released on SuperCD for the TurboGrafx-16 CD attachment or the TurboDuo console. The TurboDuo was basically a TurboGrafx-16 system with an internal top loading CD drive. The game had a full CD soundtrack that featured rockabilly music. Unfortunately many critics and players considered the game poor and not as good as the first Air Zonk game, mainly due to its lack of parallax scrolling, which was used to good effect in the first Air Zonk Hu card game.Super Air Zonk was released 1993 in North America and was later re-released for the Wii Virtual Console on November 19, 2007.GameplaySuper Air Zonk had very similar gameplay to the first Air Zonk game. The game is a side scrolling shooter game with a unique gameplay style that is different from other shooters that existed on the TurboGrafx-16 and other consoles of the time. The game included the use of assistants to the game's main character Air Zonk and also several unique power ups throughout the game. Selection of the companion character in Super Air Zonk differs slightly from that of the first game.TriviaThe antagonist in Super Air Zonk is a futuristic version of King Drool, the dinosaur villain from the original Bonk video game series.</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="810">Parodius</game><game id="5879">Ordyne</game><game id="22244">Magical Chase</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9261/293614-saz_box_1.jpg</image></root>