<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20989</id><name>CrimeCraft</name><description>OverviewCrimeCraft is a Persistent World Next-Gen Shooter (PWNS) that combines elements from MMORPGs and Shooters and merges them into one package. Users will have the ability to create Gangs with their friends, take on professions, and also level up their character which in turn will earn them rewards and cash.Originally a subscription-based game, Vogster announced on Oct. 2nd 2009 that starting in November 2009, CrimeCraft would offer a free to play model, with optional premium subscriptions. Free to play subscription have full access to all of the features of the game. Paid players receive more XP, cash, and loot at the end of matches, as well as discounts in the stores and auction houses.Essence of the GameCrime - Perform various "tasks" and "jobs" for money and experience which can be used to help your avatar gain a reputation, learn new trade skills and perform new abilities in battle.Craft - Use the loot gained from battle to create your own weapons, clothing and performance boosts.Unreal Technology - Explore the vast world of Sunrise City beautifully rendered by the Unreal Engine 3.Intense Third Person Shooter action - Battle other players or AI enemies with a wide range of weapons, explosives, abilities, and enhancements at your disposal.Pay your way - Flexible payment models that lower the barriers of entry and give players options based on their playing style.Personalize - Amazing depth in the variety of clothes, weapons, items and skills available to distinguish your character and your crew from the masses playing online.Team up - Form virtual gangs to build a reputation, assign rankings, pool money and goods, and buy gang hideouts.Underground Economy - Control the quality and cost of manufactured items that you create, modify, or repair. Then sell, trade, or auction them to other players on the open black market.Game ModesThe game has several different game modes which, for the most part, are similar to standard FPS multiplayer modes. After the player chooses the type of match they want, a special area fitting that mode is loaded up, and as soon as enough people join the match begins. Each of these game modes has its own set of rules, and some of them are player vs player battles, whereas other game modes pits the players against AI bots.Turf WarThe goal in this mode is to capture control points. Players are divided into two teams, with each having one control point already in their possession, and 3 neutral ones that are available for capture by either side. By advancing from one point to the next, and capturing control points in a specific order, previous control points are locked, preventing the opposing team from capturing them. Once all neutral control points have been captured the battle for the enemy's own home point begins. The match is won when a team captures all control points, or by the team that has the most of them when the match timer reaches zero.Snatch 'N GrabA simple capture the flag mode. One team against another, with each team having their own flag. To earn points a team must capture the flag of the opposing team and bring it back to their own base. The team with the most points at the end of the match wins the game.Capture the ZoneConquest. Players are put into teams of 16 and are deemed with the task of trying to capture three very large points spread throughout the map. These points take a large amount of time to capture yourself, but the more teammates in a zone at once, the faster the point can be captured. Teams gain points based on how long they have the points captured. The player with the most points at the end of the match wins the game.RobberyA team based match where each team is given a safe with 100,000 in cash. Players must guard their own safe, while at the same time attempting to steal as much of the other team's money to win the game. Money can be stolen by standing on an interactive point near the safe; the longer the player stands near the safe, the more money they'll be able to steal. The catch is that they must bring this money back to their own safe, with the added handicap of being unable to sprint or roll to to evade enemy fire.ShootoutTeam Deathmatch. Two teams, each with the simple goal of killing as many members of the opposing team as possible. Whichever team racks up the most kills by the end of the match will be the winner.RiotA simple deathmatch game. Score points by killing other players in a free-for-all match. The player with the most points at the end of the match is declared the winner.SafeguardPlayers are put into into a single team with the objective of defending a weapon cache that's under constant attack by enemy bots. To win the match, players must make sure that the weapons cache doesn't get destroyed before the timer runs out.StockpilePlayers must recover valuable items captured by bots. In this game mode there are no teams, players fight only for themselves. However, players can only kill the AI controlled enemy bots, not each other. The goal is to gather as many valuable items as possible (weapons, armor, medicine crates, gadgets), as well as accumulating points by killing enemy bots.</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4065">Crackdown</game><game id="5618">Saints Row</game><game id="9989">Hellgate: London</game><game id="32868">CrimeCraft: BleedOut</game><game id="14366">25 to Life</game><game id="21591">Combat Arms</game><game id="29463">Alliance of Valiant Arms</game><game id="21220">Battlefield Heroes</game><game id="22218">WarRock</game><game id="40677">District 187: Sin Streets</game><game id="38242">Mercenary Ops</game><game id="30558">Sunday vs. Magazine: Shuuketsu! Choujou Daikessen</game><game id="34475">Hajime no Ippo: The Fighting!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1837492-box_ccraft.png</image></root>