<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20985</id><name>APB Reloaded</name><description>Overview   APB (All Points Bulletin) is an                                               MMOG , as  well as the latest creation  from                                              David Jones   and                                              Realtime Worlds, the developer of the well-received  Crackdown.   Set in a modern, fictional, urban city, the game pits law enforcement  against  gangs, as they both aim to wipe each other out. According to the   developer, this will be the first MMORPG in which the player's own  skill,  not the amount of time invested, would be the main factor in  character  progression. There have been several rumors surrounding the  game,  including that                                            Rockstar Games was planning on  purchasing APB in order to turn it into a                                          Grand Theft Auto   MMORPG. You can purchase a retail version of APB either in-store or via  digital download at standard retail price.  The game includes 50 hours of action game play out of the box plus  unlimited time in APB's social districts. Once your game time is up, you will have the option of buying another 20 hours for $7, or a monthly subscription for $10/month. You will also have the possibility to sell your customized designs for RTW points, which can be used to buy extended game time.The  quests given by                                                     NPCs will be more focused  on the                                                                                       PvP  aspect of the game. The main game  designer                                      EJ Moreland says that, for  example, in other MMOs, players  are asked to get 10 bat wings. In APB,  you will have to kill other  players to get whatever the NPC requires.  The enforcers will be  required to protect the common NPCs (citizens),  patrol the streets, and  catch wanted criminals.  Rather than rely on a traditional                                     XP leveling system, APB uses a form of                                    ranking called Prestige (for Enforcers) and Notoriety (for Criminals). Able to both rise and fall, the system is designed to encourage players to play their chosen faction as intended. As a result, Enforcers can expect their Prestige to rise when making a successful arrest or fall by harming innocent bystanders, whereas Criminals will find their Notoriety increase by evading capture and decrease if arrested. APB will not feature typical MMO mechanics such as                                  Talent Trees,                                 Skill Points or even                                Classes, instead players are able to customize the role of their character by using the in-game currency to purchase upgrades.Professions in APB will also be very different compared to existing MMOs and, if anything, is more comparable to games such as                               Forza Motorsport 3. Players will be able to earn in-game currency by creating various items and then selling them via a                              Auction House. Created items can vary greatly, from unique artwork and vinyl, to custom clothing and even heavily modified vehicles.     Factions Designed around the common 'cops vs. robbers' theme, APB will feature only 2 factions - Enforcers and Criminals. Each faction will have multiple organizations that players may choose to align themselves with however there will be no character classes as such. Enforcers      Sometimes a badge is all that separates the enforcers from the criminals.      Not your typical policeman, Enforcers are deputized mercenaries tasked with cleaning up the city of San-Paro. Given a gun and a badge, they have the freedom to enforce the law however they see fit, but reckless use of lethal force carries consequences.  Fresh-faced recruits have the option of aligning themselves with one of two enforcer organizations, the Praetorians or the Prentiss Tigers. Each featuring their own unique chain of command, players are able to work their way up the ranks of their chosen organization by accepting missions from                                                                        NPC contacts. As the player progresses, the will receive missions from increasingly higher ranking contacts  Enforcers are incentivised to adhere to a code of conduct that prohibits such things as harming innocent                                                                       NPC bystanders or dangerous driving and rewards using non-lethal force whenever possible. That however is not to say Enforcers must be squeaky clean, with infractions often able to be overlooked by bribing a contact within your organization. Criminals      He dares you to try spotting all of his stereotypical clichés.       Thug, gang-banger or just an all round bad guy. Whatever you call them, Criminals are motivated by two things - money and power. Not unlike their badged counterparts, wannabe                                                                    bad dudes are able to join one of the two major criminal organizations (aka                                                                     gangs) in San-Paro, the Blood Roses or the G-Kings.  Once under the wing of their chosen gang, budding criminals are able to bring death and destruction to San-Paro by picking up missions and bounties from gang leaders or simply by causing indiscriminate chaos on the streets. This type of activity doesn't stay unopposed for long however, as patrolling enforcers are able to report any witnessed criminal activity resulting in the immediate dispatch of other rank-matched enforcers.   Location Set in the fictional west-coast metropolis of San  Paro, APB divides the city into three distinct districts. Two of which,  the Financial District and the Waterfront District serve as the main  staging areas for APB’s combat heavy gameplay, while the Social District  focuses on friends, clans and customization as well as having an  increased population cap.  Financial District   With its numerous  skyscrapers and narrow alleyways, the Financial  District encourages  players to leave their vehicles behind and take to  the streets to engage  in intense fire fights. The types of missions  players can expect to  experience include bomb planting/defusing,  graffiti tagging/clean-up and  evidence gathering/destroying. Financial  District instances currently  have a population cap of 100 and occupy  the space of roughly 40 city  blocks.  Waterfront District   While similar in  size and scope to the Financial district (roughly 40  city blocks and a  population cap of 100), the Waterfront Distinct  carries its own unique  look and feel. With wide roads and a coastline  that stretches the entire  length of the map, car chases and massive  shootouts become a much more  common sight. Missions available in this  district include vehicle  escort/ambush, property raiding/defending and  time limited deliveries.   Social District   Removing itself of  all combat, instead the Social District focuses on  player interaction,  clan organization/recruiting and APB’s extensive  customization features,  including character and vehicle design as well  as music creation. All  Social District instances have an increased  population cap of 250  however the map size is significantly smaller due  to the absence of  vehicles. The district also acts as a way to reward  the best players by  displaying posters and billboards featuring their  character. Other  mechanics unique to the Social District include  jukeboxes that play  custom music to all players in its immediate  vicinity and cinemas  screening mission replays.  Customization As one of the most heavily promoted aspects of the game, APB features an array of utilities that allow for the in-game customization of your character, vehicles and even music.    Character  Creator Character         Similar to most other MMO's, APB allows  the player to choose their initial physical appearance such as gender,  race and hair style. While many of these things can be changed at a  later date, the prohibitively high cost of doing so suggests that care  should be taken during initial creation. All newly created characters  spawn with default clothing which can then be highly customized using  various pre-made items or create your own using the in-game design  tools.    Car CustomiserVehicle Similar to the character creator, players are able to  customize virtually every aspect of their vehicle. Beginning with paint  jobs and liveries, you are able to recreate any artwork on your car such  as gang tags, enforcer badges or even a personalized license plate.  Further on, players may choose to upgrade various other parts of the car  such as spoilers, steering wheels and car seats.As players progress  through the game, rewards such as new artwork and customization  categories will be made available via their chosen organization.   Music Studio Music While it may not rival some professional solutions,  APB contains a feature packed music studio that allows players to  create, mix and edit their own signature themes to accompany them  in-game. Once created, players are able to deploy themes so they can be  heard during various parts of the PvP based mission structure (such as  arresting other players, winning a mission, etc...). In addition to  this, you can create songs, which are longer variants of themes that can  be played from a players vehicle, or from the social district music  performance points.   VoIPAPB uses Vivox voice technology for voice chat. In addition to standard group voice chat functionality, Realtime Worlds also implemented 3D positional voice chat that accounts for position of the speaker and relative distance.   ControversyRealtime Worlds implemented a controversial audio advertising system in APB for VoIP users. Under the default VoIP plan, players will hear a five to fifteen second audio advertisement while switching between districts. According to Realtime Worlds, the ads will play no more than once every three hours.     Users can also choose to completely disable audio advertisements by purchasing VoIP premium passes that remove all audio advertisements for 30, 60, 90, or 180 days in exchange for a fee. Payment Models Included with the game is unlimited access to the Social District and 50 hours of playtime in the action districts (Financial and Waterfront). Once the 50 hours is up, players can choose between three different payment methods.  Unlimited AccessPay-As-You-GoRTW PointsUnlimited gameplay for 30 daysPay monthly ($9.99/£7.99/€8.99)20 Hours of game time (never expires) in the action districts$6.99/£5.59/€6.29Exchange in-game currency for gameplay time Earn points only by selling your creations on the market place to other playersRegardless of payment method, players will always have access to the Social District (even when their game time expires).  System Requirements These are based on requirements for beta testing, noted as of 24th February 2010.MinimumRecommendedOS: Windows XPProcessor: Core 2 Duo 2.13 GHz or equivalentMemory: 2GM RAMVideo: NVidia GeForce 7800 256MBHard Drive: 15GBSound: DirectX 9Internet: Broadband connection required to install and play     OS: Windows Vista / Windows 7 (recommend a 64-bit operating system)Processor: 2.4GHz Intel Core 2 Quad or equivalentMemory: 4GB RAMVideo: NVidia GeForce 8800 GTX 512MB or equivalentHard Drive: 15GBSound: DirectX 9Internet: Broadband connection required to install and play      Soundtrack APB sports over a 160 song soundtrack list.  Mad World -  Tears for FearsFavourite Jeans -  Bertie BlackmanRational Gaze -  MeshuggahBeautiful Tomorrow -  Beth RowleyRiot Act -  ExodusJohnny Got A Boom Boom -  Imelda MayHeat -  RecordkingzSo Fine -  TelepatheDeath -  White LiesZero -  Yeah Yeah YeahsCourage -  Alien Ant FarmGimme That Punk -  Audio BullysLava Lava -  Boys NoizeMercury -  ClutchProgenies of the Great Apocalypse -  Dimmu BorgirCentral Park -  Division of Laura LeeBright Lights -  The Ghost of A ThousandCome Clarity -  In Flames Hermaploitation 74 -  Herma PumaThe Shape Of Punk To Come -  RefusUnder The Knife -  Rise AgainstJohn Q Public -  Anomie Belle The Truth -  Bulletproof MessengerFang -  Druu Silhouette -  Fono Battle Front -  RareformZookeeper -  Honey ClawsBrotherhood of the Drum -  KJ SawkaChildren Of Neon Lights -  La Fleur FataleHawk Eyes -  Leopold And His Fiction Viva La Revolucion -  Love in OctoberA Lot Of Us (Feat. Ray Frazier) -  Mic Crenshaw Adolescent Plague -  NiftersBlock 4 Block Featuring Rasco (Cali Agents) -  Paulie Rhyme  DeedotThirty -  Peter Mulvey4pm -  pH10The Shadow -  QuantDress Down Day -  The Band of the EyeShe, Robot -  The CellsGet Out -  The ShackeltonsDark Scanner -  Tim BesamuscaTroubled Times -  WhoibeWe'll Bring You Down -  WinterpillsNumbers -  ZelazowaSheets -  AbrogateThe Sleepless Crusade -  AtlasiDrozer -  Benjamin TillmanSick Of Ants -  You Already KnowHome -  The Boy Who Trapped The SunAPB -  ChapteroneCoke And Trees -  Colin McShanepain(T) -  DevotionMedicinal -  DisownM.J. Union Dub -  DJon$"A Life In Ashes -  DragnerveHealthy Illness -  FarfletchedKnow Thyself -  Fire In The Eyes Of The City Someone Set Your Voicemail -  Freighter Aramis -  FuturoMutate -  GnomeatticKoishikunaru (Constant Spinning) -  HotelsinusThe Wrath of the Lambs -  illuminatusHit it out the park, son - J ack ButlerRaven Black -  Kains Island IDK -  KingbastardRewind -  Make SparksMusic -  MALAKAIWhere Ya At Now -  ModifydTerrorize -  Moses ClevelandBreak Before I Bend -  Mr TwistStare Into Oblivion -  Panic Cell Ground Zero -  Peter Mazeb*tch plz -  popErotiqThe Sound of That -  RedaeLApropos -  ReporterThe Fight Song -  River City RansomHave No Tyrant -  SGXCan't Disroot -  Stardown The End of the Parade -  The DepartedThis Is Not The End -  The BraveryThe Ballad of the Silver Gun -  The Sweet RevengeClean Cut -  The Theory of FunkativityLet It Go -  TriphobiaThe Phresh -  Vega TekniqueAs Gorgeous As -  We Love to Party Let's go to the distro -  You Me and the Atom BombWAR (Light and Darkness) - E TEN Akseov Alexey V Metropolis -  Bitplane Aporia -  Forever Never Swampwalker -  Jaakko TakaloRide of the Valkyries -  Richard Wagner Brindisi -  Giuseppe VerdiNight on Bald Mountain -  Modest Petrovich MussorgskyMars -  Gustav HolstFlower Duet -  Léo DelibesLes Torreador -  Georges BizetSymphony No.5 -  Ludwig van BeethovenCranes -  Abe VigodaThe Night We Nearly Got Busted -  Alabama 3 ATX" ArtistName -  Alberta Cross Champagne Glass -  AlphastatesCarbon Kid (Radio Edit) -  AlpinestarsDart For My Sweetheart -  Archie Bronson OutfitWhat If -  Bombay Bicycle Club If You Could Read Your Mind -  Clinic Everything Is Under Control -  Coldcut Pack It Up -  Spiderbait Pump My Pumps -  Dan Black Criss Cross -  Shy ChildBeautiful -  Good Shoes Cities Burning Down -  Howling Bells Don't Stop -  InnerpartysystemParallel Lines -  Junior BoysBasement -  Just JackDump o stinksion -  dLUDEdBorstal Breakout -  Sham 69 When You Walk in the Room -  Fyfe DangerfieldDeathbox -  MnemicBlue Lining, White Trenchcoat -  Mando DiaoYour Heart Is As Black As Night -  Melody GardotChains -  Mercury RevGold Guns Girls -  MetricThe Sun Smells Too Loud -  MogwaiPure Pleasure Seeker -  MolokoGained The World -  MorcheebaConstant Static -  New Found GloryHeaven Alive -  Oceansize Turn It Up -  Pixie LottThe Fountain -  Echo  The Bunnymen 1901 -  PhoenixColossal Insight -  Roots ManuvaSpellbound -  Siouxsie And The BansheesGod Complex -  Inside Your Frontal LobeIntermission - T he Death SetSale Of The Century -  The Futureheads Tick Tick Boom -  The HivesNo Time -  The Juan MacLeanAbout Your Dress -  The MacCabeesKnock You Down -  Life Since DeathNot The Only Person -  The Rumble StripsGet a Rise -  Killa KelaWe Want War -  These New PuritansThe Betrayal -  KassidyMake Up Your Mind -  The VacationRage Against The Tantrum -  Thomas TantrumNorth Carolina -  Lee And Willbee Hustle -  Urban D Ex -  AMOOf Our Lives -  AvosettaNow Sigh On, Scion -  Loki's MotifWK -  Negative pHFeeling -  Wake UpYou're So Cool -  Japanese VoyeursMountain Man -  Crash KingsDesensitized Generation -  Death WarrantCounterpoint -  DelphicInnocence -  Guy Valarino17 Horses -  Cortney TidwellYour Own Fireworks -  Toy FightShowdown -  PendulumNo Brakes / Hands -  Little BootsGoin' Back -  Devendra Banhart    Shut down and relaunchOn September 17th 2010. Barely 2 months after release (2 months and 17 days)   Ben 'APBMonkey' Bateman posted the below message. The forums were also shut down at this time. "APB has been a fantastic journey, but unfortunately that journey has come to a premature end. Today we are sad to announce that despite everyone's best efforts to keep the service running; APB is coming to a close. It's been a pleasure working on APB and with all its players. Together we were building an absolutely amazing game, and for that, we thank you. You guys are awesome!From all of the Realtime World staff we thank you for your continued support."       Gamersfirst, a free-to-play MMO company, subsequently acquired and relaunched APB as a free-to-play MMO.  It was renamed APB Reloaded.Intellectual Property SaleThe BBC         reported that the APB administrators were looking to sell the intellectual property rights due to the game's closure. One potential buyer was     Epic Games. It was speculated that Epic would have a less difficult time getting APB up and running again because the game uses Epic's    Unreal Engine. Epic's spokesperson   Dana Cowley did not comment directly on that issue. However, she did say, " Mark (Rein) absolutely loves APB, and everyone here loved what they saw."      Compensation After the closure of APB, EA offered compensation to the people who invested money in APB. This allowed people (who could prove they had bought the game) to pick something from the EA store of equal value, including:        Bad Company 2         Spore         Dragon Age         The Sims         Fifa 10</description><genres /><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/6247/1422518-926499_62895_front.jpg</image></root>