<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21015</id><name>Tournament Cyberball 2072</name><description>OverviewArcadeTournament Cyberball 2072 is a football game originally developed by Midway in 1989 as an arcade follow up to the original Cyberball.Atari Lynx PortThe game was ported to the Atari Lynx hand held system (dropping Tournament from the title) in the same year as the arcade with this port of the game being developed by Blue Sky Software.Xbox Live Arcade PortOn September 5th, 2007 an updated port of the game (also called simply Cyberball 2072) was released on Xbox Live Arcade. The Xbox 360 port of the game did not feature any kind of head-to-head against a human player, instead two players can only play cooperatively (online or offline) against an A.I. opponent. On February 17th, 2010 Cyberball 2072 was de-listed from the Xbox Live Arcade service.Midway Arcade Treasures 2Tournament Cyberball 2072 made an appearance on the compilation game Midway Arcade Treasures 2 for the Xbox, Playstation 2, and Gamecube platforms. The port contained in this collection is the emulated version of the arcade game.GameplayPlaying some robotic footballTournament Cyberball 2072 plays much like a traditional American football game, with a few rule changes and tweaks. The arcade version featured single, two player, and four player versions. Instead of human players robots are the players. There are different robot types and each have their own stats and play style.One difference in Tournament Cyberball 2072 over a traditional football game is that the ball is in fact a bomb instead of a football. The bomb is on a timer and can only be defused if the player can reach the 50 yard line or can score a touchdown.Another difference in this game is that there is no ability to kick a field goal or punt the ball, only passing and running plays can be used.Starting the GameChoosing rookie or advancedWhen starting a game of Cyberball a choice between Cyberball Rookie League or Advanced Cyberball.In Cyberball Rookie League there is no options given for choosing a coach to play against or a team, instead the action just gets started with random options chosen. This game also lowers the A.I. difficulty.If Advanced Cyberball is chosen then the option becomes available to choose the opposing coach and the team to play as. Advanced Cyberball is also what the GameBreaker Challenges are under and cannot be selected under the Rookie League.GameBreaker ChallengesTournament Cyberball 2072 has the option to play small GameBreaker Challenges rather than a full game. These challenges contain an objective for the player to complete. If the objectives are completed, money will be awarded which can then be used to upgrade players.CoachesIn Tournament Cyberball 2072 while playing Advanced Cyberball the opposing A.I. coach can be chosen. These different coaches will play differently from each other. There are four coaches that can be selected from:Doc DavisCoach Doc DavisQuote - "You'll never stop my balanced defense."Wins - 10Losses - 10Sky RogersCoach Sky RogersQuote - "My air attack will wear you down."Wins - 14Losses - 10I.M. PayneCoach I.M. PayneQuote - "My powerful ground game will crush you."Wins - 18Losses - 10Grace SavageCoach Grace SavageQuote - "You can't beat my flexible game plan."Wins - 22Losses - 10</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4376">Base Wars - Cyber Stadium Series</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5028/2525081-tournamentcyberball2072.png</image></root>