<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21034</id><name>Izuna 2: The Unemployed Ninja Returns</name><description>OverviewIzuna and her gang are back - and just in time for a wedding! Lured by the promise of free food (Why else would Izuna attend?), the festive event becomes a puzzling mystery when Izuna's sidekick Shino suddenly disappears, off in search of her long-lost sister. And making matters worse, the foreign gods have also arrived on Japanese soil, and they aren't very happy with the meddlesome, unemployed ninja. With disgruntled deities on the warpath, a sidekick to track down, and a missing sister out in the wild, it could all shape up to be one of Izuna's more exciting adventures. Sounds like a lot of work for a girl out of a job!GameplayIzuna travels through a dungeon.The object of Izuna 2 is to travel through various dungeons collecting weapons and defeating enemies to gain experience and level up. Normally, dungeons must be passed through many times to gain the necessary experience to proceed through more difficult stages. Each dungeon is entirely randomly generated, with enemies and stage layouts being entirely new every time you pass through them. This does mean that there is a slight lack of detail in every dungeon as there is not much room for randomly generated landmarks or defining features in every stage. You can choose which two characters you want to send into a dungeon, you meet more characters and add them to your party throughout the game. Each character can equip certian items and uses different weapons in different ways, giving them different strengths and weaknesses. Combat is turn-based. Every time Izuna moves or performs an action such as attacking or equipping an item, all of the enemies on that particular floor of the dungeon move or perform an action as well. Each floor is littered with "traps" that inflict differnet status effects or cause some other unfortunate consequence to whomever steps on them, player or enemy.  They player may select two characters to bring with them into a dungeon. Whenever the player feels like it they can switch characters with the select button, as long as they haven't overused the ability to do so. Traveling around a dungeon builds up the tag meter, which allows both characters to unleash a powerful tag-team attack which damages most if not all of the enemies visible on screen.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20911">Final Fantasy Fables: Chocobo's Dungeon</game><game id="20541">Mystery Dungeon: Shiren the Wanderer</game><game id="4464">Izuna: Legend of the Unemployed Ninja</game><game id="5885">The Nightmare of Druaga: Fushigino dungeon</game><game id="21294">Pokémon Mystery Dungeon: Explorers of Darkness/Time</game><game id="13974">Pokémon Mystery Dungeon: Blue/Red Rescue Team</game><game id="23107">Dragon Quest: Shounen Yangus to Fushigi no Dungeon</game><game id="5276">World of Dragon Warrior: Torneko: The Last Hope</game><game id="13105">Baroque</game><game id="23166">Away: Shuffle Dungeon</game><game id="25074">Pokémon Mystery Dungeon: Explorers of Sky</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2199418-box_izuna2.png</image></root>