<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21030</id><name>FIFA Soccer 09</name><description>OverviewFIFA 09 is the latest addition to EA's premier soccer/football video game, developed by EA Canada and published under the EA Sports brand. It was released on numerous platforms including Xbox 360, PlayStation 3, Wii, PC, PlayStation 2, PlayStation Portable, and Nintendo DS towards the end of 2008. The game features over 500 teams with 30 international leagues and 41 national teams, 49 stadiums and all new offline and online modes.  One of the new features in the game was the addition of; Adidas Live Season. This will provide weekly stat updates that cover all players and teams in the English Premier League, Spain's La Liga, France's Ligue 1, the German Bundesliga, Italy's Serie A and, strangely, the Mexican Pimera Division. Footballers in the game will have their stats chnged every week so their in game stats will rise or fall depending on how they play in real life.  The demo for Xbox 360 and PS3 was released on September 11th. It allows players to compete in a full exhibition match, two minutes for each half. If at full time the score reflects a draw, a penalty shootout takes place to determine the winner. Teams in the demo include Chelsea, AC Milan, Real Madrid, and Marseille.FIFA 09 hit shelves in Australia on October 2, in Europe October 3 and in North America October 15, 2008.   Gameplay Gameplay Features According to the producer of FIFA 09, David Rutter, over 250 key improvements were made from the previous iteration.  Graphics - Overall look of the game has been upgraded from its previous title, FIFA 08. There will be cut scenes while a player is being substituted and the reaction of that player varies depending on his impact during the match. Players are seen warming up if they are substituted during the half time. The crowd also has been improved in terms of graphics and has been regionalized.   Physic  Animation System - Improved physics system affects the players and the ball on the pitch thus adding even more realism to the game. Individual attributes of the players will now heavily Improved animation makes dribbling look and feel as smooth as ever.influence dribbling, running, tackling, heading, passing, and shooting, which are much more responsive. Mid-air collisions have been added as well.    Players, Teams, and Stadiums - The number of real-life players, teams, and stadiums have increased. The new licensed teams will include official logos and accurate kits.    Weather and Time - Unlike FIFA 08, weather options will be present such as rain and snow. These weather conditions affect the gameplay as well as the appearance of the players. For example, players will wear gloves and/or put their socks up higher. Players can choose the time of the game among day, dusk, and night. When the match starts out as dusk, the second half will begin as night.   Faces - Players' faces will be revamped in order to capture more of the actual characteristics of the real-life players with the 3-D modeling technology. The players get a makeover.   Keeper - Goal Keepers are extremely enhanced regarding their positioning and goalkeeping abilities this time around compare to the ones in FIFA 08 therefore reducing the chances of letting goals in the back of the net. Another new addition to the keepers is that they can change their mind in mid-dive by reaching their hands out the other way once they realize a mistake has been made.   Artificial Intelligence - The AI in FIFA 09 will now act more cleverly and realistically. Add your own color to the game with the new team tactics.   Custom Team Tactics - With over 50,000 combinations of team tactics, players can now incorporate their unique color of playing style to their desired team.    Celebrations - When a goal is scored, the player is able to decide which goal celebration to perform.     New Game ModesBe A Pro Seasons - FIFA 09 provides the opportunity to play as a single player, in any outfield position, on any team for a whole season mode. You start by choosing a real-life player or you can create your own and play through four seasons of career mode for your team. Along the way you will improve your player's stats, become captain of your club, get called up to the national team and eventually be crowned a club and/or national hero.  Be A Pro Online - Improving on the 5v5 mode in FIFA 08 EA has expanded this mode to allow up to 10 players on each team to take control of a player and work together. This mode has also been integrated with the Online Clubs mode. Online Clubs - Players can now create and join online clubs so that friends can easily meet up, practice and get into competitive matches together in the 10vs10 online mode. As many as 50 players may now join together to play against other clubs. The best clubs at the end of the season will play off to be crowned the best players of Be A Pro online. *Not all of the features listed above are included on all platforms.Downloadable ContentUltimate TeamEA announced their first downloadable expansion for FIFA 09 called Ultimate Team. This new mode revolves around collecting cards with over 4,000 star player cards to collect. Players will be given a starter pack upon starting the game mode and will be able to trade with other players online to build a strong team. New cards can also be acquired by playing games with your team and through an auction mode. There are 30 different types of card in all, including Managers, Coaches and Special Abilities.  The mode will also feature new tournaments for players to compete in online. FIFA 09 Ultimate Team will be available for download on Xbox 360 and PS3 from March 19 2009. When released whether you purchase the DLC o  r not, there will be a mandatory 1.3gb update that will add an Ultimate Team Demo to the game. The PS3 version of the update will also add Trophy support.  Tournaments  Gillette - EA Sports Champions of Gaming Tournament Registration opened on October 31st for the Champions of Gaming Tournament which will allow players from the Americas, Europe and Asia-Pacific to compete in a worldwide rankings compeition. The champion from each region will be able to travel to Orlando Florida in February 2009 to see who will be the ultimate champion and have the chance to meet some of the worlds biggest sporting stars. You can sign up within the FIFA 09 menu by submitting your name and email address.    Soundtrack  Artist - Song - Album ( Country)Caesar Palace - 1ne -  Dogs from V-Gas (Italy) Chromeo - Bonafied Lovin' (Yuksek Remix) -  Fancy Footwork: Deluxe Edition (Canada) CSS - Jager Yoga -  Donkey (Brazil) Curumin - Magrela -  Japan Pop Show (Brazil) Cut Copy - Lights And Music - In Ghost Colours (Australia) Damian "Jr. Gong" Marley - Something For You (One Loaf Of Bread) - (Jamaica) Datarock - True Stories - (Norway) DJ Bitman - Me Gustan - Latin Bitman (Chile)  Duffy - Mercy - Rockferry  (Wales) Foals - Olympic Airways - Antidotes (England) Gonzales - Working Together (Boys Noize Remix) - Soft Power (France) Hot Chip - Ready For The Floor (Soulwax Remix) - Made In The Dark (England) Jakobinarina - I'm A Villain - First Crusade (Iceland) Junkie XL - Mad Pursuit - Booming Back At You (Holland) Jupiter One - Platform Moon - Jupiter One (USA) Kasabian - Fast Fuse - (England)   Ladytron - Runaway - Velocifero (England) Lykke Li - I'm Good I'm Gone - Youth Novels (Sweden) Macaco - Movin' - (Spain) MGMT - Kids - Oracular Spectacular (USA) My Federation - What Gods Are These - Don't Wanna Die (England) Najwajean - Drive Me - Till It Breaks (Spain)  Plastilina Mosh - Let U Know - All U Need Is Mosh (Mexico) Radiopilot -Fahrrad - Fahrrad (Germany) Reverend And The Makers - Open Your Window - The State Of Things (England)  Sam Sparro - Black  Gold - Sam Sparro (USA) Señor Flavio - Lo Mejor Del Mundo - Supersaund 2012 (Argentina) Soprano - Victory - (France) The Airborne Toxic Event - Gasoline - The Airborne Toxic Event (USA)  The Black Kids - I'm Not Gonna Teach Your Boyfriend How To Dance With You (The Twelves Remix) - I'm Not Gonna Teach Your Boyfriend How To Dance With You (USA) The Bloody Beetroots - Butter - (Italy)    The Fratellis - Tell Me A Lie - Here We Stand (Scotland) The Heavy - That Kind Of Man - Great Vengeance And Furious Fire (England) The Kissaway Trail - 61 - The Kissaway Trail (Denmark) The Kooks - Always Where I Need To Be - Konk (England) The Pinker Tones - The Whistling Song - Wild Animals (Spain) The Script  - The End Where I Begin - The Script (Ireland) The Ting Tings - Keep Your Head - We Started Nothing (England) The Veronicas - Untouched - Hook Me Up (Australia) The Whip Muzzle - #1 - X Marks Destination (England) Tom Jones - Feels Like Music (Junkie XL Remix) -  (Wales) Ungdomskulen - Modern Drummer - Cry-Baby (Norway)  List of Teams  England PremiershipArsenalAston VillaBlackburn RoversBolton WanderersChelseaEvertonFulhamHull CityLiverpoolManchester City       Manchester UnitedMiddlesboroughNewcastle UnitedPortsmouthStoke CitySunderlandTottenham HotspurWest Bromwich AlbionWest Ham UnitedWigan Athletic England ChampionshipBarnsleyBirmingham CityBlackpoolBristol CityBurnleyCardiff CityCharlton AthleticCoventry CityCrystal PalaceDerby CountyDoncaster RoversIpswich TownNorwich CityNottingham ForestPlymouth ArgylePreston North EndQueens Park RangersReadingSheffield WednesdaySheffield UnitedSouthamptonSwansea CityWatfordWolverhampton Wanderers England League OneBrighton  Hove AlbionBristol RoversCarlisle UnitedCheltenham TownColchester UnitedCrewe AlexandraHartlepool UnitedHereford UnitedHuddersfield TownLeeds UnitedLeicester CityLeyton OrientMillwallMK DonsNorthampton TownOldham AthleticPeterborough UnitedScunthorpe UnitedSouthend UnitedStockport CountySwindon TownTranmere RoversWalsallYeovil Town  England League TwoAccrington StanleyAldershot TownBarnetBournemouthBradford CityBrentfordBuryChester CityChesterfieldDagenham  RedbridgeDarlingtonExeter CityGillinghamGrimsby TownLincoln CityLuton TownMacclesfield TownMorecambeNotts CountyPort ValeRochdaleRotherham UnitedShrewsbury TownWycombe Wanderers Italy Serie AAtalantaBolognaCagliariCataniaChievo VeronaFiorentinaGenoaInternazionaleJuventusLazioLecceMilanNapoliPalermoRegginaRomaSampdoriaSienaTorinoUdinese Italy Serie BAlbinoLeffeAnconaAscoliAvellinoBariBresciaCittadellaEmpoliFrosinoneGrossetoLivornoMantovaModenaParmaPiacenzaPisaRiminiSalernitanaSassuoloTrevisoTriestinaVicenza Spain Primera DivisionAlmeriaAthletic BilbaoAtletico MadridBarcelonaDeportivo la CorunaEspanyolGetafeMalagaMallorcaNumanciaOsasunaRacing SatanterReal BetisReal MadridRecreativoSevillaSporting de GijonValenciaValladolidVillarreal Spain SegundaAlcoronAthletico Madrid (B)Celta Vigo (B)CobenaFuenlabradaLanzaroteLeganesLugoMaritimaOurensePajara PlayasPontevedraPuertollanoRacing FerrolRacing Satanter (B TEAM)RayoSS ReyesTalaveraTorrelavegaUniversidad Las Palmas Turkey Süper LigAnkaragucuAnkarasporAntalayasporBesiktasBurasporDenizlisporEricyéssporFenerbahceGalatasarayGaziantepsporGenclerbirligiKayseriesporKonyasporManisasporRizesporSakaryaspor SivassporTrabonzonspor South Korea K-LeagueBusanChonbukChunnamDeajuDaejeonGwangju IncheonJejuKyungnamPohangSeongnamSeoulSuwonUlsan Austria BundesligaAltachGrazer AKMattersburgPaschingRapid WienSalzburgSturmSV RiedTirolWien Belgium Jupiler LeagueAnderlechtAntwerpBeveren BruggeBrusselsCercle BruggeCharleroiExcelsiorGentLierseLokerenMons - BergenRacing GenkRoeselareSint TruidenStandard de LiegeWesterloZulte Waregem Brazil CampeonatoAtlético ParanaenseBotafogoCorinthiansCruzeiroFigueirenseFlamengoFluminenseFortalezaGoiásGrêmioInternacionalJuventudePalmeirasParanáPonte PretaSanta CruzSantosSão CaetanoSão Paulo Vasco da Gama Denmark SuperLigaenAalborgBrondbyEsbjergHorsensKobenhavnMidtjyllandNordsjaellandOdenseRandersSilkeborgVejle Viborg France Ligue 1AuxerreBordeauxLe MansLensLilleLorientLyonMarseilleMonacoNanceNantesNicePSGRennesSaint EtienneSedanSochauxToulouseTroyesValenciennes France Ligue 2AjaccioAmiensBastiaCaenChateaurouxCreteilDijonGrenoble FootGueugnonGuingampIstresLe HavreLibourneMetzMontpellier NiortReimsStade BrestoisStrasbourgTours Germany BundesligaAachenArminia BielefeildBayer LaverkusenBayern MunchenBochumBorussia DortmundBorussia MonchengladbakCottbusFrankfurtHannover 96Hertha BSCHSVMainz 05NurnbergSchalke 04StuttgartWeder BremenWolfsburg Germany Bundesliga 21860 MunchenAugsburgBraunschweigBurghausenCarl Zeiss JenaErzgebirgeFC KaiserslauternFC KolnFreiburgGreuther Furth Hasna RostockKarlsruheKoblenzMSV DuisburgOffenbachPaderborn RSW EssenUnterhaching Holland EredivisieAdo den HaagAjaxAz alkmaarExcelsiorFC GroningenFC TwenteFC UltrechtFeyenoordHeerenveenHeraclesNACNECPSV EindhovenRKC WaalwijkRoda JCSparta RotterdamVitesseWillem II Mexico PrimeraAmericaAtlanteAtlasAzul CruzGuadalajaraJaguares ChiapesMonarcasMonterreyNecaxaPachucaQueretaroSan LuisSantos LagunaTiburonesTigresToluca UAGUNAM Poland EkstraklasaArkaBelchatowCracoviaGornik LecznaGornik ZabrzeGroclinKoronaLechLegiaLodzOdra Wodzislaw SlaskiPogonWidzewWisla KrakowWisla PlockZaglebie Portugal Liga BwinAcademicaAvesBeira MarBelenenseBenficaBoa VistaEstrela AmadoraFC PortoMaritmoNacionalNavalPacos FerreiraSetubalSporting BragaSporting LisbonUniao Leiria Scottish Premier League (SPL)AberdeenCelticDundeeDunfermlineFalkirkHeartsHibernianInverness Caledonian ThistleKilmarnockMotherwellRangersSt Mirren Sweden AllsvenskanAIKDjurgardenElfsborgGaisGefleGoteborgHackenHalmstadHammarbyHelsingborgKalmarMalmoOrgryteOster Swiss Super LeagueAarauBSC Young BoysFC BaselFC ThunGrasshoppersLuzernSchaffhausenSionSt GallenZurich  USA MLSChicago FireChivasColorado RapidsColumbus CrewDallasDC UnitedHouston DynamoKansas CityLA GalaxyNew England RevolutionNY Red Bulls Real Salt Lake  Australian Hyandai A-LeagueSydney FCMelbourne VictoryAdelaide UnitedWellington PhoenixQueensland RoarPerth GloryNewcastle JetsCentral Coast Mariners  Norway Tippeligaen  Aalesunds FKFC Lyn OsloFK Bodø/GlimtFredrikstad FKHamarkamerateneLillestrøm SKMolde FKRosenborg BKSK BrannStabæk FotballStromsgodset IFTromsø ILVålerengaViking FK  Xbox 360 Game InstallationFIFA Soccer '09 requires 6.0GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="40">Soccer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13165">Pro Evolution Soccer 2008</game><game id="20959">Pro Evolution Soccer 2009</game><game id="4551">Pro Evolution Soccer 2</game><game id="10340">ISS Pro Evolution</game><game id="2100">Pro Evolution Soccer 5</game><game id="2305">Actua Soccer</game><game id="21612">90 Minutes: European Prime Goal</game><game id="19165">Sensible World of Soccer</game><game id="10022">Sensible World of Soccer '96/'97</game><game id="16986">Sensible World of Soccer: European Championship Edition</game><game id="9951">UEFA Champions League 2006-2007</game><game id="23136">Tecmo World Cup '93</game><game id="15288">FIFA Street</game><game id="6718">Mario Strikers Charged</game><game id="19086">Total Club Manager 2004</game><game id="1586">Total Club Manager 2003</game><game id="15714">Total Club Manager 2005</game><game id="16157">David Beckham Soccer</game><game id="21242">Winning Eleven: Pro Evolution Soccer 2007</game><game id="25382">Real Football 2009</game><game id="25791">Pro Evolution Soccer 2010</game><game id="1386">Pro Evolution Soccer</game><game id="26124">Petanque Pro</game><game id="27148">Let's Make a Soccer Team!</game><game id="31024">SFG Soccer</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2266506-box_fifa09.png</image></root>