<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21089</id><name>Guinness World Records: The Video Game</name><description>OverviewWith either your Wiimote and Nunchuk on the Wii or your stylus on the DS you try to set virtual world records in one of 36 minigames. Your score in these games can then be uploaded to online leaderboards on both versions of the game. There is even a chance that the top scorers will be featured in future versions of The Guinness Book of World Records.The Wii title sports 33 different mini-games, gathered into three tiers. Each mini-game can be unlocked independently if you have enough points to spend. Points are earned through playing already unlocked mini-games, and you are rewarded different amounts depending on your skill. Breaking a world record earns you around 1200 points, so you will have to replay a fair amount of the mini-games to unlock them all.List of mini-games (Wii)Tier 1 (unlocked from start)Fastest Time to Tear 5 Phone BooksFastest Time to Pull a Plane 50mHighest Video Game ScoreHighest BMX JumpMost Tattooed PersonLongest Balance of a Vehicle on Your HeadFurthest Washing Machine ThrowMost Plungers Thrown in 1 MinuteFastest Time to Eat 10 CockroachesFastest Time to Shear 5 SheepMost Melons Crushed in 1 MinuteTier 2 (unlocked for 1000 points each)Fastest Time to Eat a PlaneLongest BMX JumpHighest Jump with a Pogo StickFastest 100m Hurdles on a UnicycleFurthest Toss of a Cow PatFastest 100m Egg and SpoonLand Speed RecordTallest BuildingFastest 100m on a Space HopperLongest Motorcycle JumpFastest Time to Pop 100 BalloonsTier 3 (unlocked for 5000 points each)Fastest RocketFastest Time to Pluck 3 TurkeysFastest 50m Tightrope WalkLongest Wing WalkFastest Time to Roll 5 CarsMost Arrows Caught in 1 MinuteFastest Time to Push a Lorry 50mFurthest Human CannonballMost Dominoes ToppledLongest BurpSmelliest Mammal</description><genres><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/7/77958/1325251-801764_1571big_large.png</image></root>