<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21139</id><name>Fatal Frame IV: Mask of the Lunar Eclipse</name><description>OverviewThe unlockable Zero Suit costume.Fatal Frame 4: Mask of the Lunar Eclipse for the Nintendo Wii is the fourth game in Tecmo's cult hit survival horror series. The game is developed by Tecmo and Suda 51's Grasshopper Manufacture and published by Nintendo. It was released July 31st, 2008 in Japan. Since the game is a Wii exclusive, Fatal Frame 4 features a Zero Suit costume from Nintendo's Metroid series as well as a Luigi costume(A homage to Luigi's Mansion) from Nintendo's Super Mario series.PlotSeveral years ago, Ruka Minazuki and four other girls were kidnapped and held captive on the mysterious Rougetsu Island, only to be saved by Detective Choushiro Kirishima. After two of the girls inexplicably perish, Ruka and the other survivors return to the island in search of answers and to piece together Ruka's memory. At the request of Ruka's mother, Choushiro follows the girls to the island, looking to help them once more.GameplayThe flashlight will be vital to players and their peace of mind.In an interview in the Creators Voice section of Wii.com, game director Makoto Shibata and producer Keisuke Kikuchi detailed their inspiration for the new mechanics in Fatal Frame 4. The player will controller the character movement with nunchuck, while the motion sensors in the Wii remote will allow the player to control the flashlight. The deveolpers commented that they found after extensive play testing that using the sensors in the Wii remote as opposed to the Wii remotes IR functionality would allow for a more immersive player experience. The game will also use a behind-the-back perspective to make players feel as if they are in the game. An added benefit of the new perspective is the ability to add more objects above the player's line of sight, which the old perspective restricted. Players will once again navigate a derelict Japanese mansion and other traditional Japanese houses. According to Kikuchi Fatal Frame 4 will have the largest number of explorable buildings in franchise history. The game will also feature four playable characters: Ruka, the other two girls Misaki Asô and Madoka Tsukimori, and Choushiro.</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2842">Haunting Ground</game><game id="13817">Alone in the Dark: The New Nightmare</game><game id="10780">Silent Hill 2</game><game id="14392">Silent Hill: 0rigins</game><game id="8804">Condemned: Criminal Origins</game><game id="22605">Cursed Mountain</game><game id="10369">Silent Hill 3</game><game id="17962">Clock Tower 3</game><game id="25707">Silent Hill: Shattered Memories</game><game id="26599">Ghostwire</game><game id="25888">Ju-On: The Grudge</game><game id="27264">Calling</game><game id="33374">Night of Sacrifice</game><game id="42171">DreadOut</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/10460/1288137-fatal_frame_iv_boxart.jpg</image></root>