<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21205</id><name>Crash Bandicoot Nitro Kart 3D</name><description>OverviewThe famous, funny and witty character Crash.    Crash Bandicoot Nitro Kart is a very simple racing game that has a similar game style as                      Mario Kart. The game is obviously a racing games and the    characters are chosen from six different characters known from the original                      Crash Bandicoot series. The game is  on the   iPhone and Zeebo console and is made by                      Vivendi Games Mobile. This game features remade tracks from a prior Crash Bandicoot racer,                       Crash Tag Team Racing. The game has a few different ways of playing, by playing through a single race, going through tournaments or going through a campaign. Gameplay   The gameplay is pretty simple, tilt to move, tap to jump, and tap to shoot. There are different locations on the screen to tap for different commands. A tutorial comes up straight away after the first time playing after purchasing explaining which locations to tap on the screen. The game accelerates automatically making it crucial to stay focused on turns. Throughout the games there are 'Boxes' that you can crash into. These boxes either contain the famous fruit from the franchise                      Wumpa Fruit, or the crate with the question mark giving you items to shoot or drop.    The game is broken down into four different ways to play; Quick Race, Cup, Story or Time Trial. Quick races are just single races that don't affect stats or anything, Pure fun, Pure racing. Next you have the Cup Races which are just tournaments. There are three different cups each including four levels in each. After clearing all the Cups you go onto the story mode. This is just a simple back story for why you would be racing. It includes boss battles which are just racing with a specific opponent. After completing the story mode the final and last way of playing is unlocked. Time Trials, set records of specific races with people worldwide and see if you can be the fastest out there. Characters The game consists of 6 playable different characters all seen in previous Crash Bandicoot games.                      Crash Bandicoot                       Dr. Neo Cortex                     Coco Bandicoot                      Ripper Roo  Yaya Panda                     Nitrous OxideAdditional characters were added in an update to the iPhone version of the game in June 2010.                   Dingodile             Polar  TracksCrash Bandicoot Racing 3D features 3 cups, consisting of 4 tracks each. Leaving racers with a total of 12 tracks to choose from. Even though the tracks are essentially remakes of tracks from           Crash Tag Team Racing, they were give new, much more generic, names.N-Tropy Cup - Too Easy For Grandma Egypt - Race among the PharaohsSolar - Around the Sun 'n backAdventure - AdventuringFairy - Fairyland TripWumpa Cup - Difficulty is Rising Adventure 2 - AdventuringEgypt 2 - Race among the PharaohsSolar 2 - Around the Sun 'n backFairy 2 - Fairyland Trip Aku-Aku Cup Egypt 3 - Race among the PharaohsSolar 3 - Around the Sun 'n backAdventure 3 - AdventuringFairy 3 - Fairyland TripItems      TNT Crate: A crate of explosives dropped behind the kart. Blasts anyone getting too close to your back.        Missile: Homing missile speeding along the track until it finds an unlucky target.       Speed Boost: Gives a short boost of super-speed when activated.Tropy Clock: Stretches time and slows all opponents to a crawl while you zoom by.      Bomb: A bouncing bomb is fired forward from the kart.     Shield: Protects you from all hard, or at least for a short amount of time.Kart Jacking: Switches place between you and the opponent placed directly ahead of you.Cursed Candle: Puts out the lights for your opponents for a few seconds, leaving them driving in pitch darkness.Aku-Aku: Gives you a boost of speed and enables you to send opponents flying when tackled.Oilcan: Releases a drop of black, slippery oil that can send opponents spinningBoost Pads: Drive over these rainbow colored pads to get an instant boost of speed.    Wumpa Fruit: Collect and keep up to 10 of these to get a speed boost. If you get blown up or crash, you will loose a few.C.R.A.S.H. Letters: Found only in certain levels, these Letters when collected unlock a new character.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6539">Mario Kart DS</game><game id="14134">Pac-Man World Rally</game><game id="20645">Mario Kart Wii</game><game id="6368">Mickey's Speedway USA</game><game id="26848">ModNation Racers</game><game id="22190">Street Racer</game><game id="26657">Sonic &amp; Sega All-Stars Racing</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1954/179351-crash.jpg</image></root>