<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21257</id><name>Harvest Moon: Magical Melody</name><description>StoryYou arrive in town and are asked by the Harvest Sprites to help revive the Harvest Goddess who has been turned to stone. To do this you must collect Magical notes. But you are not the only one who is trying to revive the Harvest Goddess. Jamie another rancher on the island seeks to revive the Goddess before you.Main CharacterYou get to take on the role of a new resident who can either be a girl or a boy. Your ultimate goal is to revive the Harvest Goddess but in the process you'll make friends and maybe even get married. Depending upon which gender you select you will be given a choice of either bachelors or bachelorettes to woo and eventually start a family with.MarriageIt is a common goal in the Harvest Moon series to make friends but while you at it why not find a wife/husband.BachelorsAlexA stern yet gentle guy who runs the local clinic.BasilA young plant enthusiast who wanders into town.BlueSometime during the game he appears at Blue Sky ranch.BobA muscle bound guy who shows you how the shipping bin works.CarlA guy who works at the Moonlight cafe and has dreams of one day opening his own cafe.DanA lively guy who seems a little strange.JoeAn energetic fella that works at the carpenter's shop with his brother Kurt.KurtJoe's brother who works at the carpenter's shop. Seems kinda' gloomy.LouisA very inventive guy who eventually moves into town.RayA guy who loves to fish and wander.JamieA hermaphroditic character, Jamie runs a separate farm and is your rival. Jamie can be wooed and married by both male and female players.BachelorettesAnnA girl who works at her father's shop.DiaA girl from a rich family who spends time in town to recover from her sickness.EllenShe is the one who gives you your dog. A very friendly girl.EveShe works at the Moonlight inn.GinaA young girl who helps take care of Dia.GwenA feisty girl who loves horses.KatieA girl who comes to work at Carl's cafe when it opens.LylaArrives in town and opens up a shop.MariaA quiet girl who works in the library.NinaLives and works at her mother's flower shop.JamieA hermaphroditic character, Jamie runs a separate farm and is your rival. Jamie can be wooed and married by both male and female players.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2168">Viva Piñata</game><game id="12893">Animal Crossing</game><game id="9238">Animal Crossing: Wild World</game><game id="21096">Animal Crossing: City Folk</game><game id="21631">Little King's Story</game><game id="22930">Rune Factory: Frontier</game><game id="28041">Farming Simulator 2009</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2139797-box_hmmm.png</image></root>