<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21307</id><name>Juiced 2: Hot Import Nights</name><description>Juiced 2 is the sequel to the 2005 racing game, Juiced. The game features many new features, new cars, improved graphics, and more customization options for your cars.  Demo The demo for the Xbox 360 version of the game was released on the Xbox LIVE Marketplace on the 1 9th of July, 2007. A second, multiplayer demo was also released, on the 14th of September 2007. It seems likely that Juiced 2 may be the final game in the Juiced series, as THQ have sold the publishing rights for this game, as well as that of the Stuntman franchise.   Single PlayerSingle player in Juiced 2 begins with you creating your character in the game. This character will be seen when browsing the menus, in your car, and also before a race. The menu is designed to look like the inside of a nightclub, complete         with a dancer in the background. Juice Games removed the calendar and respect system from this game, so they no longer are available. The game starts you off in League 8, which is the lowest league in the game. The higher the league, the faster the cars available to you. League 8 features standard cars, such as Honda Civics. As you move up in leagues, the cars you can purchase become more exotic and have superior performance. You can also upgrade your car so that it is suitable to race in a higher league. Character customization in the game is relatively basic, in comparison to some games. You select a preset character, and you can change the clothing. The character customization option is only available in the Xbox 360, Playstation 3, and PC versions of the game. In the other versions of the game, you simply don't have a character. Car modification in this game is vastly increased, in comparison to the previous Juiced game. In fact, the car customization is still superior to most racing games available currently. Players are able to customize their car's license plate, add custom graphics to their cars, and customize the car's body with spoilers, bumpers, body kits, etc. The game also allows customization of your car's interior - you can customize the steering wheel (it doesn't effect handling), and the seats.  To move into a higher league, players must complete a certain number of the goals they are given. Some of these goals are things such as winning a certain amount from gambling on one race, winning a pink slip from a certain person, intimidating a certain driver, and other such goals. Some of the later goals given are incredibly hard, so Juiced 2 does not remain an easy game for long.The customization aspect to Juiced 2  Driver DNAA unique feature in Juiced 2 is 'Driver DNA'. The game will build up a DNA strand of your own unique style. Your DNA can change depending on how much nitrous you use, how much you gamble on a race, if you drive aggressively, and more.  There are three possible ways your Driver DNA can go : Burning (you do this a lot), Neutral, and Ice Cold. Ice Cold basically says you're a calm, collected driver, and you only drive aggressively if necessary.   Ursula Mayes is your guide to Driver DNA at the start of the game. Unsurprisingly, she has Ice Cold DNA, making her the best AI driver in the game. Other players can view your DNA online before a race. They can download this DNA, and use it for a driver in their team, or race against it in the Driver DNA Lab. Driver DNA LabThe Driver DNA Lab in the game allows you to race against the DNA strands of your friends and competitors online, as well as allowing you to race against the DNA of different drivers. The Lab contains the DNA of several famous drivers, such as drifters. There is also a French football player you can race against. Ursula Mayes cannot be raced against in         the Lab, despite the fact she has the best DNA of any drivers in the game. SoundtrackRacing Soundtrack Acidecine - 16 Bit LolitasMind Killer  (Remix) - Adam FreelandHigh Speed Heist - Bruno CoonStone Crows - Bruno CoonLightning Strikes - Bruno CoonWhassisface - Adam FreelandNever Ever Enough - Adam FreelandHommeage - Adam FreelandBlocks - Adam FreelandFlourohorns - Adam FreelandMorodish - Adam FreelandSg Rei - Adam FreelandNeu! Rave - Adam FreelandSpin Machine - Adam FreelandE-Drone Part One - Adam FreelandShinjuku Socks - Adam FreelandFutcant - Adam FreelandGrrrr! - Adam FreelandMonza - Adam FreelandGlowstick - Adam FreelandYesYesYesYes! - Adam FreelandInfinity 2008 - Guru Josh ProjectHazy Way - Alex DolbyWhat She Wants - Alex MetricHypnotized - CollettePaddy's Revenge - Steve MacBest Looking Guy In Town - Natural Born HippiesPleasure Me (Instrumental) - D. RamirezDrummin' and Bassin' - DJ RapFor Lovers Not Fighters - Evil NinePjanoo - Eric PrydzRestless - Evil NineThis Is The Sound - K-SwingGet On - MoguaiVoodoo People (Intrumental) - ProdigyGo With The Flow - Queens Of The Stone AgeJump - TC  Distorted MindsKilla - Way Out WestWhat's Your Damage? (Remix) - Test IciclesDownfall (Instrumental) - Victory PhilWoman (Remix) - Wolfmother Results / PodiumMindkiller - Adam Freeland Menu Music  Mindkiller - Adam Freeland (DS Only)Hit Da Flow - MusicDoctorzMobb Wit It - MusicDoctorzOpen Sees - MusicDoctorzPretty Boy - MusicDoctorzStudents Of? - Music Doctorz  ReceptionReception for Juiced 2 was mixed. Metacritic calculated an average score of 66, which is merely one point more than its PSP-exclusive predecessor, Juiced Eliminator received. The highest score received for the Playstation 2 version of the  game was 80/100, by the Official UK Playstation magazine. This publication was quoted to have said:  A surprising success, Juiced 2 is a glamorous, feature-rammed racer with  variety by the hood-scoop load and mass appeal.       The lowest score given for the game was given by Gamespot. Gamespot rated the game 55/100, and were quoted to have said:The total lack of online play and lackluster driving mechanics sink this  derivative street racer into mediocrity.   According to the 7 user reviews for the game, the average is 6.2 out of 10, or 62/100.  System Requirements MinimumSupported OS: Windows® XP SP2 / Windows® Media Center / Windows® VistaProcessor: 3.0 Ghz Intel Pentium IV or equivalentMemory: 1 GB RAMGraphics: DirectX shader 3 compatible card, such as ATI X1300, NVIDIA 6600DirectX Version: DirectX® 9.0cSound: DirectX® 9 compatible sound cardHard Drive: 5.7 GB Hard Drive spaceRecommendedProcessor: Processor Core Duo/AMDMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: DirectX® shader 3 compatible card, such as ATI X1900, NVIDIA 7900 or betterSound: DirectX® 9 compatible sound card. Surround sound is supported as hardware allowsInput Devices: 100% Windows 2000/XP compatible mouse and keyboard or Xbox 360-compatible controller</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9927">SRS: Street Racing Syndicate</game><game id="18095">Need for Speed: ProStreet</game><game id="5875">Midnight Club 3: DUB Edition</game><game id="20729">GRID</game><game id="8844">Need for Speed: Carbon</game><game id="20741">Need for Speed: Undercover</game><game id="20919">Ford Racing: Off Road</game><game id="7431">Ford Racing</game><game id="12950">Gran Turismo 3 A-Spec</game><game id="11625">Ridge Racer DS</game><game id="10124">Midnight Club: Street Racing</game><game id="16492">Burnout Revenge</game><game id="32301">Cargasm</game><game id="17220">Top Gear RPM Tuning</game><game id="1321">L. A. Rush</game><game id="12254">Need for Speed Underground</game><game id="38497">Need for Speed: Most Wanted</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3699/1790548-juiced_2___hot_import_nights.jpg</image></root>