<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21302</id><name>S.T.A.L.K.E.R.: Clear Sky</name><description>OverviewClear Sky is the prequel to S.T.A.L.K.E.R. Shadow of Chernobyl, a near-future FPS taking place in a place called the Zone in the Ukraine. A second accident had occurred at Chernobyl, but instead of irradiating the land, it altered the laws of physics and reality itself within the region around it, creating deadly anomalies and bizarre artifacts that have become modern day treasures to those lucky enough to find one. SoC followed the adventures of a stalker as he headed into the previously unreachable heart of the Zone centered on Chernobyl itself, there to discover a dark secret that would change the world.The Zone is normally off limits to everyone and military checkpoints try to keep people out, but adventurers called S.T.A.L.K.E.R.s have managed to get in to risk their lives for that one discovery that could make them rich. Several factions live within the Zone and the military is more concerned about keeping people out than in dealing with the ones that are already there leaving most of them to pursue their own agendas whether it be protecting each other from the dangers there or enforcing the law in making sure that no one disturbs the status quo. The sequel takes place in 2012, a year before the events of the first game and follows the same FPS formula in a new storyline.StoryThe story involves a mercenary named Scar who succumbs to one of the random blowouts that sweep the region from Chernobyl. A blowout is a storm of radiation and energy that everyone is forced to take cover from if they want to live, but somehow, Scar survives exposure in the open while leading a group of scientists into the Zone. He is found and rescued by a group calling itself "Clear Sky" who are interested in studying the Zone and Chernobyl in order to understand their mysteries in the hopes that they might help mankind. They make it clear that Scar's resistant nature to a blowout isn't a permanent effect and that if he or Clear Sky do not find out why they are occurring far more frequently and stop it, Scar will eventually die.After following several leads and exploring the Zone, Scar manages to make his way to Chernobyl where he is asked to stop the leading character from the first game from reaching the reactor. The ending ties into the events at the start of the first game.GameplayThe game takes place in the Zone which is divided into several areas comprised of modern day, Soviet-styled, ruins, landmarks, and open areas of dead trees and blasted ground. Most of the areas are open to exploration right from the start while others will be made accessible depending on how far the player has gotten in their quest. The open-ended approach that it takes with its FPS formula is also enforced by the ability to take "jobs" from other stalkers and earn money which can be used to purchase items such as valuable ammunition to upgrades for both weapons and armor. The player can ignore the main quest and pursue their own adventures in the Zone before returning to it. There is no time limit placed on their activities.Clear Sky also shares SoC's use of real-world weapons. Players can also bleed to death or die from being shot only a few times as opposed to other FPSs that are far more lenient with regenerating health systems. Weapons and armor can also wear down from use and damage requiring the player to find technicians that can keep their equipment in working order. The sci-fi setting also lends itself to the use of artifacts, strange items formed within the anomalous and often deadly disturbances that litter the landscape thanks to the warping effects of Chernobyl's accident.The largest change from the previous title is in the expansion of factions within the game. Players can join most of the factions within the game after performing several jobs to prove their abilities and change their attitudes towards them which is tracked by the in-game PDA. Conversely, attacking members of a faction will slide their responses in the opposite direction. Factions won't often go to war with each other, but unlike in the previous game, it is possible to see faction headquarters defend themselves more often from roaming bandits. The player can also change the political landscape of a particular area by wiping out or aiding certain factions. A checkpoint that may be run by the Duty faction may be run by the Freedom faction the next day if the player decided to wipe out the previous inhabitants.Key FeaturesLiving-and-breathing world: virtual monsters and stalkers migrate around the Zone, similarly to the player they are preoccupied with day-to-day things – feeding, fighting, looking for prey, trading, sleeping, taking rest Freedom of movement around the storyline, limited only by the player’s will and abilitiesHunt down the valued artifacts The world of post-Soviet environment Authentic objectives of the Chernobyl exclusion zone – the power engineers city of Pripyat, Chernobyl NPP, Chernobyl-2 complex of over-the-horizon detection and more Atmosphere of eerie mystery and constant danger Multiple game endings System of weather effects and dynamic day  night shift Photo-realistic graphics, adding to the game atmosphere immersion Realistic ballistics, extensive arsenal of real weapon prototypes Unique multiplayer modes implemented within the game entourage – artefacts collection, anomalies, radiation, weather effects, day  night change etc Extensive map editor possibilities for multiplayer gaming Faction Wars  FactionsWith the introduction of Faction Wars into Clear Sky, both old and new factions fight over territory and resources in the Zone. Military: The Ukrainian Military, hostile to everyone in the Zone.Clear Sky:Scientists trying to learn more about the Zone.Renegades:Bandits fighting against Clear Sky.Stalkers:People trying to make a living and survive in the ZoneBandits:Thieves and criminals who steal and kill to get what they want.  Duty:A semi-militaristic faction, trying to help stalkers and want to stop the Zone from expanding. Hostile against Freedom.  Freedom:Anarchists who want the zone to be available for everyone. Hostile against Duty.Mercenaries:Mercs who will do almost any job for the right price.Monolith:A religious faction who worship the "monolith" in the Chernobyl Power Plant. Hostile towards anyone trying to get to the center of the Zone. WeaponsSome of the weapons you come across while traveling through the zone.Pistols:PMm Martha Fort- 12 Kora -919  Walker P9m   Shotguns:Chaser 13 Sawed off shotgun TOZ 34 SPSA14   Assault rifles:FT 200M GP 37 IL 86 Akm 74/2 Akm 74/u Obokan  Thunder S14   Sniper Rifles:SVDm 2 Vintar BC SVUmk2   Explosives:Bulldog 6 grenade launcher RPG-7 RGD-5 grenade F1 grenade  MultiplayerMultiplayer offers the basic gametypes of Deathmatch and Team Deathmatch. Players are divided into two teams: Freedom and the Mercenaries. The Freedom team uses ex-USSR weapons while the Mercenaries utilize NATO firearms to realize their objectives. Players can earn money during the match in order to purchase new weapons, ammunition, and armor similar to Counterstrike. The other game types that are offered is Capture the Artifact which is a slightly different variant of Capture the Flag, only now with artifacts protected by both factions and must be retrieved by either team and returned to base for a score. Artifact Hunt places an artifact somewhere on the map that both teams must fight over and carry back to their base. An additional twist in both artifact game types is that the artifact can be set to generate a deadly anomaly preventing anyone from picking it up for a time. Clear Sky Complete mod  Clear Sky Complete is a part of the Complete mod collection, made by the same people which made the previous Complete mod, STALKER Complete 2009 for Shadow Of Chernobyl. The Clear Sky Complete mods is modification made by professional 3D and graphic artists who are all dedicated to enhance the experience of the STALKER games. The designers themselves have said the goal of the mods is to improve the original game's graphic, sound and atmosphere, while preserving it's core elements. This Complete mod, Clear Sky Complete, is built upon the original STALKER Complete 2009 only making it fit for Clear Sky rather than Shadow of Chernobyl, of course. Clear Sky is the most graphically demanding game in the series, which makes this mod all the more interesting, as the designers have done a complete graphical overhaul on the game.   Graphics:Some of the graphical enhancements featured in the mod include stunning new lightning effects, natural daytime/night-time transitions vivid sunsets/sunrises, redesigned emissions, a new high resolution night-time constellation map, a full moon, and many other aesthetic improvements too numerous to list.  Textures: S.T.A.L.K.E.R. Clear Sky features improved textures compared to S.T.A.L.K.E.R. Shadow of Chernobyl, however there was still a lot of room for refinement. Instead doing a total retexture, the designers only needed to replace select sets with respect to game designer's vision. This new texture set contains the best work by the community along with the introduction of new rendering techniques authored by the designers' studio.   Sound:The sound overhaul was done to further enhance the ambiance and atmosphere of the Zone with the addition of higher quality and more realistic ambient audio files. Each map includes a sound theme that varies between night and day. All this has been integrated without diminishing the original sounds unique to Clear Sky, ensuring a superior audio experience. All weapon sounds have been replaced with comprehensive analogues, and footsteps, bullet impacts, anomalies, creatures, and many other sound categories have been improved.    Bug fixes:Bug fixes are the specialty of the Sky Reclamation Project, a community patch which brings the joint effort of a large number of community members together to address bugs still present in Clear Sky after its final patch, and eliminates many game breaking issues. This mod is included in Clear Sky Complete.  Other features: There is also a bunch of new features which is included in the Clear Sky Complete. Some of these are; The Wish Granter - activated via the ESC F1 keyboard shortcut, it is a hidden interface designed to let you enable vehicles, control weather, and place anomalies, characters, mutants and much more on the map. You can essentially build the game around your preferences through this interface.  Sleeping Bag - allows the player sleep in-game (featured in the STALKER Complete 2009 also), and features an advanced safety level indicator. Gnomus' Scopes - a scope system similar to one used in most modern FPS games.    Elite Nightvision - improved black  white night vision.  Teleport - allows the player to jump between points in the environment with the ability to save custom coordinates for future use. The HUD has been to some degree modified as well as the inventory screen. There has also been added a “smart quick-save” function which creates a seperat save file with level name, in-game data, and time each time it' s used.  SoundtrackThe  original score for S.T.A.L.K.E.R: Clear Sky was composed by MoozE.  Track No.Song TitleRunning Time 01 Swamps of Despair 04.19 02 Theme of Escape 08.34 03 Shadows 04.40 04 Theme of Gargabe 05.01 05 Radwind, pt.1 03.16 06 Fog 03.05 07 S.A.D. 04.35 08 Theme of Red Forest 05.31 09 Ghost City 04.42 10 Radwind, pt.2 02.16 11 Hospital 04.22 12 Sleeping In Ashes v.2 04.46System RequirementsMinimal Microsoft Windows XP(Service Pack 2)/Microsoft Windows 2000 SP4 Intel Pentium 4 2.0 Ghz / AMD XP 2200  512 MB RAM 10 GB free hard disc space 128 MB DirectX 8.0 compatible card / nVIDIA GeForce™ 5700 / ATI Radeon 9600 DirectX 9.0 compatible sound card LAN/Internet/Cable/DSL for Internet games Keyboard, Mouse   Recommended Microsoft Windows XP/Vista (SP1)  Intel Core 2 Duo E6400 / AMD 64 X2 4200  2 GB RAM 10 GB free hard disc space 256 MB DirectX 9.0c compatible card* / nVIDIA GeForce™ 8800 GT / ATI Radeon HD 2900 XT DirectX 9.0 compatible sound card LAN/Internet/Cable/DSL for Internet games Keyboard, Mouse    * for the DirectX 10 effects Windows Vista and DirectX 10 compatible video card are required</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17533">Deus Ex</game><game id="16426">Vampire: The Masquerade - Bloodlines</game><game id="11757">Crysis</game><game id="21912">Planetside: Core Combat</game><game id="9883">Deus Ex: Invisible War</game><game id="20504">Fallout 3</game><game id="21524">Warhound</game><game id="20964">Metro 2033</game><game id="25933">Fallout: New Vegas</game><game id="3226">Deus</game><game id="21478">Cryostasis</game><game id="21358">Deus Ex: Human Revolution</game><game id="8197">Boiling Point: Road to Hell</game><game id="21107">I Am Alive</game><game id="20665">Far Cry 2</game><game id="38078">The Dead Linger</game><game id="38389">Nuclear Union</game><game id="38126">Survarium</game><game id="42744">Stalker 1: Path of Fire</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3699/1832808-stalker___clear_sky_cover.jpg</image></root>