<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21357</id><name>SingStar Rocks!</name><description>TracklistsBloc Party - Banquet Blur - Song 2 Coldplay - Speed Of Sound The Hives - Hate To Say I Told You So Jet - Are You Gonna Be My Girl? Hole - Celebrity Skin Keane - Everybody's Changing The Killers - Somebody Told Me KT Tunstall - Black Horse And The Cherry Tree The Offspring - Self-Esteem The Rolling Stones - Paint It, Black The Scorpions - Wind Of Change United Kingdom Only SongsThe Bravery - An Honest Mistake Bowling for Soup - 1985 The Cardigans - My Favourite Game Deep Purple - Smoke On The Water Franz Ferdinand - Do You Want To Gwen Stefani - What You Waiting For? Hard-Fi - Hard To Beat Kasabian - Club Foot Kings of Leon - The Bucket Maximo Park - Apply Some Pressure Nirvana - Come As You Are Queen - Don't Stop Me Now Queens Of The Stone Age - Go With The Flow Razorlight - Somewhere Else Snow Patrol - Run Stereophonics - Dakota Thin Lizzy - The Boys Are Back In Town The Undertones - Teenage Kicks  America Only SongsAretha Franklin - Respect B52s - Love Shack The Cure - Friday I'm In Love DJ Jazzy Jeff and The Fresh Prince - Summertime Dusty Springfield - Son Of A Preacher Man Elton John - Rocket Man Fall Out Boy - Dance, Dance Gloria Gaynor - I Will Survive Good Charlotte - Girls  Boys Gwen Stefani - Cool Joss Stone - Super Duper Love (Are You Diggin On Me?) Lynyrd Skynyrd - Sweet Home Alabama Marvin Gaye - I Heard It Through The Grapevine Naked Eyes - (There's) Always Something There To Remind Me The Police - Every Breath You Take Scissor Sisters - Take Your Mama Thin Lizzy - The Boys Are Back in Town The White Stripes - Blue Orchid  </description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21171">Lips</game><game id="15661">Karaoke Revolution</game><game id="9860">Rock Band</game><game id="20673">Guitar Hero World Tour</game><game id="20714">Rock Band 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/495/273322-688237_gs_l_f.jpg</image></root>