<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21371</id><name>Avalon Code</name><description>PlotThe story begins with the game protagonist having dreams about the world coming to an end. And he is the chosen one, although not to save the world but to wield a magic book called the Book of Prophecy. To record everything in the world that is worth recording. You start the game by choosing either a male or a female character.GameplayTo record a targets code, which is a simplified DNA, you hit it with the book. Fortunately no one gets hurt because they can't even see the book coming down on them. With the code in the book, you see different puzzle pieces laid out on a grid, which you are able to remove. Which gives you the possibility to smash the book on a wounded person and get the targets code. And then remove the wounded code and put it on your enemy by smashing them and putting it into their code, which will cause a debuff such as reduced health. Or perhaps use the book on a poisonous plant, take the poison code and use it on your sword, which then gives your sword poisonous attributes. The game offers you the possibility to manipulate virtually everything. Fighting is done in realtime on the top screen. You have two weapons and each is controlled with the X and Y buttons. If you get behind an enemy and press A you enter in to a little mini-game where you juggle the enemy up, being able to hit the enemy all the way into space. You scan something with the Book of Prophecy by pressing B.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21633">Soma Bringer</game><game id="21448">Kingdom Hearts 358/2 Days</game><game id="22044">From the Abyss</game><game id="23516">Rune Factory 2: A Fantasy Harvest Moon</game><game id="21486">Rune Factory: A Fantasy Harvest Moon</game><game id="22015">Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles: Ring of Fates</game><game id="9471">Children of Mana</game><game id="24225">Destiny Links</game><game id="21446">Tales of the Tempest</game><game id="21445">Tales of Hearts</game><game id="21444">Tales of Innocence</game><game id="24226">Legacy of Ys: Books I &amp; II</game><game id="7060">Lunar Knights</game><game id="22006">Dragon Ball: Origins</game><game id="24307">Steal Princess</game><game id="27893">Cross Treasures</game><game id="27199">Rune Factory 3: A Fantasy Harvest Moon</game><game id="20615">Summon Night: Twin Age</game><game id="28324">Shounen Kininden Tsumuji</game><game id="29232">Lufia: Curse of the Sinistrals</game><game id="29254">Dragon Ball: Origins 2</game><game id="31644">Kingdom Hearts Re:coded</game><game id="35857">Hakuoki: Demon of the Fleeting Blossom</game><game id="23451">Yo-Jin-Bo: The Bodyguards</game><game id="11771">Brave Story: New Traveler</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2484684-box_ac.png</image></root>