<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21384</id><name>The Political Machine 2008</name><description>OverviewThe Political Machine 2008 is a turn-based U.S. presidential election campaign manager simulation, which puts players in charge of organizing and running a presidential campaign. The player can choose a series of pre-set candidates from either of the two main political parties, or they can create their own.Winning over swing voters is the key to successThe aim of the game is to win at least 270 electoral college votes on election day, thereby winning the presidency. In order to do this, the player will send their candidate, their VP candidate, or a series of surrogates to different states throughout the country in order to increase their candidate's approval rating. Players can organize speech appearances, create advertisements, win endorsements and manage field offices - all while competing with the opposing party's candidate on a wide range of issues in a battle to win over undecided voters.Playable CandidatesDemocratsCandidate selection screenFmr. President Bill ClintonSen. Hillary ClintonFmr. Sen. John EdwardsFmr. Vice President Al GoreSen. John KerrySen. Barack ObamaGov. Bill RichardsonUnlocksFmr. President Jimmy CarterFmr. President John F. KennedyFmr. President Lyndon B. JohnsonFmr. President Woodrow WilsonFmr. President Thomas JeffersonDownloadsFmr. Senator Mike GravelRep. Dennis KucinichRepublicansThe main menuLord Kona (A fictional alien character)President George W. BushVice-President Dick CheneyNew York City Mayor Rudy GiulianiSen. John McCainGovernor Sarah PalinRep. Ron PaulFmr. Governor Mitt RomneyUnlocksFmr. President Ulysses S. GrantFmr. President Richard NixonFmr. President Ronald ReaganFmr. President Theodore RooseveltFmr. President George WashingtonFmr. President Abraham LincolnDownloadsFmr. Governor Mike HuckabeeCharacter CreationThe character creation toolThe game also features a character creation tool which allows players to create a fictional presidential candidate and edit their appearance, traits, political party and other information in an effort to become the next president of the United States.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17361">Shadow President</game><game id="3371">The Political Machine</game><game id="1553">President Forever</game><game id="6998">Yes, Prime Minister</game><game id="6315">Constructor</game><game id="12188">Theme Hospital</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4086/284296-thepoliticalmachine2008_box.jpg</image></root>