<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21408</id><name>Rogue Trooper</name><description>BackstoryAfter being ravaged by a war between the Norts and Southers, Nu Earth has become a horrible nightmare of a planet. Chemical weapons have ruined the planets atmosphere, making it vital for humans to wear suits and breathing apparatuses. Since the planet is near a vital worm hole, the war rages on. In effort to make combat easier, Souther scientists created a clone army able to breathe and live in the toxic air. The troops are known as the Genetic Infantry. Each Genetic Infantrymen or G.I. has a bio-chip inplanted into its head which gives it its personality and skills. If a clone is downed a soldier can take out thier bio chip and insert into one of three slots on their helmet, rifle, or backpack.PlotAs the Genetic Infantry is sent into the Quartz Zone they discover that they have been caught in a trap and are shot down as they are deployed in their landing crafts by the Norts. As all members of theRogue on his mission of revengeGenetic Infantry are massacred the one soldier stands. He saves three of his friends by placing their bio-chips in the available slots. Gunnar in his gun, Bagman in his backpack, and Helm in his helmet. As they discover that they were set up by a Souther General the four go to hunt him down and the Rogue Trooper is born.LevelsQuartz Zone MassacreOrange Sea CoastNort Naval BaseTogether AgainNu PareeHoppa ChaseNort BaseSouther RR FacilityHovertrain JourneyPetrified ForestMountain PassHarpos FerryFinal FightGameplayRogue Trooper is a cover based third-person shooter. As so much of the game centers on finding strategic places to take cover and peak out for shots. The bio-chips of Rogue's friends also play an important role in the gameplay as each have their own abilities and add strategy to your attack.Gunnar: Placed in Rogue's gun and and can act as an automated turret, creating cover fire for Rogue as he moves forward with his pistol.Bagman: Placed in Rogue's backpack, Rogue collects salvaged metal from the battlefield and Bagman turns it into ammo, grenades, and mines.Helm: Placed in Rogue's helmet, Helm can hack computers, create distractions by creating a hologram of Rogue, and guides the group throughout the game.MultiplayerRogue Trooper features 2-4 cooperative multiplayer for online and splitscreen multiplayer. Rather than taking place in the main story, the multiplayer missions take place before the Quartz Zone Massacre and thusly the player has the option to play as Rogue, Gunnar, Bagman, and Helm.The multiplayer features two modesStronghold: A defensive mode where the goal is to defend your position against the incoming waves of Norts.Progressive: The players must fight their way through the enemy Norts and reach a safe point at the end of the map.System RequirementsMinimum: IBM PC or 100% compatible, Microsoft Windows XP or 2000, Intel Pentium 4 or equivalent, 256MB RAM, 100% DirectX 9.0c-compatible 64MB 3D Accelerated Card supporting v1.1 pixel and vertex shaders, Windows XP- or 2000-compatible sound card (100% DirectX 9.0c-compatible), 3GB free disk space, 100% Windows XP- or 2000-compatible mouse and keyboard Recommended: Intel Pentium 4 2.0GHz or equivalent, 512MB RAM, 100% DirectX 9.0c-compatible 128MB 3D Accelerated Card supporting v2.0 pixel and vertex shaders, Windows XP- or 2000-compatible sound card (100% DirectX 9.0c-compatible), 3GB free disk space</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12231">Gears of War</game><game id="1986">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six: Vegas 2</game><game id="30615">Gears of War 3</game><game id="1152">kill.switch</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/7900/290377-rogue_trooper.jpg</image></root>