<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21426</id><name>The Chronicles of Spellborn</name><description>OverviewThe Chronicles of Spellborn is a MMORPG developed by Spellborn International and published by    Frogster Interactive in Europe and   Acclaim Entertainment in the United States. It is currently in Open Beta. The company is also turning the game from a Pay 2 Play (P2P) service, to Free 2 Play (F2P)The Chronicles of Spellborn will be using the Unreal Engine and will featured many examples of European art.  Jesper Kyd, famed video game composer, is heavily involved in the project and will be providing much of the music for the game. Dutch band Within Temptation also composed two songs from the game. GameplaySpellborn will feature PvE and PvP gameplay, fast-paced combat that will rely on player skill rather than gear, large focus on storyline, and separating the look and stats of gear.In Spellborn a player can choose between two races Human and Daevis, both races can become all classes and neither have advantages or disadvantages. In the character creation screen the player can choose from three classes Warrior Mage or Rogue each dividing into 3 seperate classes at level 5: Warrior into Bloodwarrior, Wrathguard and AdeptMage into Ancestral Mage, Void Seer and Rune MageRogue into Deathhand, Skinshifter and Trickster The Chronicles of Spellborn is now free as   Acclaim retools it to be a      free2play game.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20666">Warhammer Online: Age of Reckoning</game><game id="18547">EverQuest II</game><game id="5767">Ultima Online</game><game id="545">Asheron's Call</game><game id="19138">Meridian 59</game><game id="19796">City of Heroes</game><game id="11142">Final Fantasy XI Online</game><game id="17494">Guild Wars</game><game id="7316">City of Villains</game><game id="16614">Ragnarok Online</game><game id="21399">Last Chaos</game><game id="21467">Rappelz</game><game id="22142">Darkfall</game><game id="13869">Istaria: Chronicles of the Gifted</game><game id="24336">Fiesta</game><game id="21891">Elveon</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3948/961394-the_chronicles_of_spellborn_pc.jpg</image></root>