<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21425</id><name>Naruto: The Broken Bond</name><description>OverviewNaruto: The Broken Bond is the sequel to Ubisoft's    Naruto: Rise of a Ninja and continues the story covering episodes 81-135 of the anime.  It was developed by Ubisoft Montreal for the Xbox 360 and released in North America on the 18th of November, 2008.  The Broken Bond covers three major story arcs and boasts a character roster of 30 playable characters, a brand new team mechanic, and an updated fighting engine.  The game also features full English and Japanese voice acting with music from the original anime, and all the cutscenes are now rendered using the games graphics engine. GameplayAdventureThe majority of the game is spent exploring the many environments in the game and solving various puzzles to proceed.  As with the last game The Broken Bond uses the village of Konoha as its main hub, allowing the player to interact with characters and take on a variety of side missions and minigames.  The village is fully explorable and there are a number of collectible coins that can be used to purchase item and weapon upgrades.  Once the player leaves Konoha the game allows for two other characters to travel with, and fight alongside Naruto.  Each character has their own unique ability and these abilities are often required to reach closed off areas and also to advance the story at certain times.FightingThe game again features a fighting system, modified from the Rise of a Ninja fighting engine, but this time allows players to switch with any travelling companions or unleash team attacks with the right button combination.  The fighting system has seen modest tweaks and improvements but remains fairly similar to the Rise of a Ninja system.  The online mode has also been improved with an all new ranking system and introduces experience based ranking.  This system rewards players for winning matches and assigns a rank based on the total experience of a player.  After obtaining enough experience a player will advance to the next rank, with the aim being to advance to the rank of Hokage.Character Roster                       Naruto (normal, green suit, Kyuubi)                       Sasuke (normal, Chuunin, Cursed Seal)                      Sakura                     Kakashi                    Choji                   Kiba                  Neji                 Shikamaru                Rock Lee               Gaara              Itachi (normal, ANBU)             Kisame            Tsunade           Jiraiya          Sakon         Jirobo        Kidomaru       Tayuya      Temari Kimamaro     Might Guy    Orochimaru   Haku  Zabuza 3rd Hokage     Xbox Game Installation  Naruto: The Broken Bond requires 3.4GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD.</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14300">Dragon Ball Z: Sagas</game><game id="20500">Dragon Ball Z: Burst Limit</game><game id="20486">Bleach: Shattered Blade</game><game id="20903">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja Storm</game><game id="38786">Naruto Shippuden: Ultimate Ninja Storm 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2215070-box_narutotbb.png</image></root>