<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21427</id><name>Korg DS-10</name><description>OverviewMS-10DS-10Named after the musical instrument producer Korg, the Korg DS-10 is music creation software designed specifically for the DS. The concept for the game arose when the physical similarities between the Korg MS-10 and the Nintendo DS were noticed.  Incidentally, this occurred in a bar when the producer witnessed two people having a conversation about the DS and Korg synthesizers.  The Nintendo DS seems the best candidate for this software largely because it has a touch screen which makes input easy, quick and responsive.  While trying to be a full fledged synthesizer, the Korg DS-10 is an excellent entry point into sound synthesis and composition for those who are still new to music creation.FeaturesVarious features in detailTwo patchable dual-oscillator analog synth simulators Four part drum machine with drum samples generated by the user with the synthesizer engine Six-track ( analog synth X 2, drum machine X 4) / 16-step / 16-pattern sequencer Delay, chorus and flanger sound FX 3 input methods: touch-control screen, keyboard screen, matrix screen Warp your sounds using Kaoss-pad style XY controller input on the touch screen  Link and sync up to 4 Nintendo DSs    </description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="492">Electroplankton</game><game id="18573">Jam Sessions</game><game id="647">MTV: Music Generator</game><game id="505">Daigasso! Band Brothers</game><game id="21366">Jam with the Band</game><game id="6343">Daigasso! Band Brothers Request Selection</game><game id="25032">EZ Muze: Hamst3r Edition</game><game id="27155">Korg DS-10 Plus</game><game id="23869">LSDJ</game><game id="23870">Nanoloop</game><game id="36822">C.P.U. Bach</game><game id="38479">Jam Sessions 2</game><game id="39669">Family Composer</game><game id="39783">Doremiko</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14036/843828-korg_cover.jpg</image></root>