<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21435</id><name>Hot Shots Golf: Open Tee 2</name><description>  Features:   Hot Shots Golf Open Tee 2 has a fun and wacky wardrobe where you can take the golfer that you are using or one of the golfers that you have unlocked and change there outfit completely.  The outfits give you the ability to either make your golfer look like the cool kid on the block or you can make them the craziest looking golfer.  Game saves and birdie chip-ins or eagles and even all of your hole in ones! on a video library so you can always go back and check out all those amazing shots that you made during your round. Keeps all your stats from the best round you had on each course to the amount of successful putts you've had and from there distance. Crazy Characters  Caddies – Choose from 24 different playable characters and five different caddies, each with their own distinct look and characteristics that embody the fun and spirit of the Hot Shots franchise. Single Player Mode Single Player Mode has for different game play styles one is Challenge mode.  Challenge mode is a game play style that is filled with match play and stroke play ranging from 9 to 18 holes.  As you play and unlock new golfers you get set on your way to unlocking the 12 golf courses.  As you unlock the new golfers and courses they get progressively harder the first golfers are novice second intermediate and then third expert.  The golf courses get tighter and more filled with hazards.  Another game in single player mode is mini-game mode which is fun to see who has the best accuracy.  Mini-game mode has 9 different obstacles with different holes worth different amounts of points depending on there toughness of position and there size and slope around them.  Another game-play style is stroke play which keeps your best score on the course that you are play so you can see how low you can go.  You can chose any course and either 9 or 18 holes for stroke play and see how you do.  Last but certainly not least is training mode which can be a huge help for those golfers that want to perfect there game on certain courses or the golfers that try to repeat there amazing shot on a certain hole.  Training mode allows you to chose one hole at a time that can help out when you have just that one hole that can tear your round apart and your trying to figure out what to do and fix it.   Multiplayer Mode Play in a "Real-Tournament" with up to 16 players to play a round simultaneously. During the round your opponents ball locations are shown in real time. You can also play 1 vs 1 match play. CoursesSouth Alps C.C.Nakagawa Public G.C.Autumn Pagoda G.C.Central Golf SquareOlive Coast C.C.Michinoku Pass C.C.Golden Desert G.C.Gamelan Island ResortRoyal  Links C.C.El Andes G.C.Dino Park G.C.Fortress Yard G.C.  Golfer'sNovice  CarlyLukeAliceMikaRioAliaIntermediateMalachyFrau AdaMontcalmLaurynShuJulieCJPatriciaExpertMifuneLeeChadLoganHollyRogerGloria   </description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="28">Golf</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21364">Golf: Tee It Up!</game><game id="10856">Tee Off</game><game id="2573">Tiger Woods PGA Tour 2001</game><game id="2302">PGA Tour Golf: Tournament Course Disk</game><game id="5493">Tiger Woods PGA Tour 2000</game><game id="7964">Tiger Woods PGA Tour 2005</game><game id="697">PGA European Tour</game><game id="6799">PGA Tour Golf</game><game id="1760">PGA Tour 96</game><game id="14247">PGA Tour Golf III</game><game id="6957">Outlaw Golf 2</game><game id="9316">Kirby's Dream Course</game><game id="21262">Disney Golf</game><game id="24256">Super Swing Golf Season 2</game><game id="24570">Easy Golf</game><game id="21379">ProStroke Golf : World Tour 2007</game><game id="25607">Pangya: Fantasy Golf</game><game id="33730">Fable: Coin Golf</game><game id="37624">@Field</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2222515-box_hsgot2.png</image></root>