<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21451</id><name>Trials 2 Second Edition</name><description>OverviewTrials 2 Second Edition is a motorcycle game that features 4 game modes: Race; Flip; Wheelie and Dynamic.The game is single-player only, but has significant replay value thanks to its use of online leaderboards which allow you to compare times against friends and the greater Trials 2 community. Trials 2 SE allows the downloading and watching of replays of other players' high-score runs and these can be invaluable when attempting to defeat some of the game's trickier tracks or obstacles. Replays can also be used as a ghost for one-on-one racing, or as a training aid to improve times and technique.GameplayThe Trials series may look like a simple racing game set in various strange environments but it is actually quite complex with a long (and some might say very steep) learning curve. The game is based on the sport of motorcycle trials, hence the name. Simply put, this consists of traversing an obstacle course using only a specialized dirt bike. The game is a 2D (in gameplay, not graphics) representation of the sport, and is entirely physics-based, with your control over the bike limited to gas, brakes and your rider's posture.Using only these abilities you are presented with a variety of increasingly difficult tracks and obstacles to surpass, such as getting your bike to climb across a series of rocks and boulders, making your bike jump from one platform to the next or climbing impossibly steep hills. Though such feats are present in real life trials, the game goes far beyond reailty with its levels. Large pipes suspended in mid-air at various angles; mountains built out of wooden planks; large rubber tire tunnels; and loop-the-loops all await the player in the deviously designed levels.But even if you do fail during these challenges (and you will fail), that's half the fun! Watching your rider slide off his bike like a sack of potatoes only to crash and tumble into the various ramps, walls and flaming barrels all the while groaning in pain from all the audible bone-snapping can be entertainment in itself, if you like that sort of thing. There's even a system in place to determine if an injury knocks the driver out, or outright kills him.Game modesRace: Clear a level as fast as possible without crashing to compete with the top ranked players.Flip: Get as many back-flips or front-flips as possible between the checkpoints from the start to the end of the level.Wheelie: Get your motorcycle on it's back-wheel, and try to keep it steady to the end of the level.Dynamic: Same as the Race mode, but this time the levels have dynamic physics-based obstacles and puzzles.TracksThere are 40 tracks to test your skills on:3 Tutorial tracks11 Easy difficulty tracks8 Medium difficulty tracks8 Hard difficulty tracks3 Flip tracks3 Wheelie tracks4 Dynamic physics tracksSince release RedLynx have released 21 free downloadable tracks for the game, these tracks are automatically downloaded when the game updates itself.PC System RequirementsOS: Windows XP (32-bit) or Windows Vista (32-bit or 64-bit)Processor: Intel Pentium 3 600 MHz or better, AMD Athlon XP or higherMemory: 256 MBGraphics: One of the following graphics cards (or higher) with at least 64 MB of memory: Nvidia GeForce FX 5200, ATI Radeon 9500, Intel GMA 900, VIA/S3 Chrome 9 or higherDirectX Version: 9.0cSound: An OpenAL compatible sound cardHard Drive: 220 MB</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6705">MTX Mototrax</game><game id="1284">MotoGP 2</game><game id="4603">Motocross Madness</game><game id="2145">Motocross</game><game id="4838">Motocross Championship</game><game id="7129">Freestyle Motocross: McGrath vs Pastrana</game><game id="15310">Motocross Mania 3</game><game id="13728">Motocross Stunt Racer</game><game id="15429">Excitebike 64</game><game id="25239">Monster Trucks Nitro</game><game id="335">Kikstart: Off-Road Simulator</game><game id="15042">Kikstart 2</game><game id="12765">Elasto Mania</game><game id="29109">Excitebike World Rally</game><game id="33114">Doritos Crash Course</game><game id="36705">Trial Xtreme</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4344/908184-trials_2_cover.png</image></root>