<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21472</id><name>iRacing.com</name><description>OverviewiRacing is an online-based racing game that consists of a persistent online service that hosts ongoing competitive series in which members race to improve their standing, better their skills and achieve higher and higher classes of licenses. The online league and standings operate in many ways like a racing MMO; players climb the ranks and improve skills to compete in bigger, faster races. New players begin as rookie drivers and can advance to bigger races by performing well enough to raise their license grade.Currently, the following content is in iRacing.CarsCR Racing Silver Crown CarCadilac CTS-VChevrolet Corvette C6.RDallara IndycarFord GTFord Mustang FR 500SFord Spec RacerFord V8 SupercarFormula 1 Lotus (1979)Formula 1 Williams-Toyota FW31HPD ARX 01CJR Motorsports Street StockLotus 49Lotus 79Mazda MX-5 CupMazda MX-5 RoadsterMcLaren MP4-12C GT3NASCAR Camping World Series SilveradoNASCAR Chevrolet Monte Carlo SSNASCAR Chevrolet SS Gen 6 Sprint Cup Car (2013)NASCAR Chevrolet Impala Gen-5 Sprint Cup Car (2007-2012)NASCAR Ford Fusion Gen 6 Sprint Cup Car (2013)NASCAR National Series Chevrolet Impala SSNASCAR Nationwide Series Impala (2010-2012)Pontiac SolsticeRadical SR8 V8Riley MKXX Daytona PrototypeSK ModifiedSkip Barber Formula 2000Star MazdaTour ModifiedUS Legends Cars Intl. Ford '34 CoupeVolkswagon Jetta TDICars in DevelopmentRUF RT 12 RNASCAR Nationwide Series Ford Mustang (2013)NASCAR Nationwide Series Chevrolet Camaro (2013)TracksAtlanta Motor SpeedwayBarber Motorsports ParkBrands HatchBristol Motor SpeedwayCentripital CircuitCharlotte Motor SpeedwayChicagoland SpeedwayCircuit Gilles VilleneuveCircuit de Spa-FrancorchampsCircuit Park ZandvoortCircuit ZolderConcord SpeedwayDarlington RacewayDaytona International SpeedwayDover International SpeedwayHomestead Miami SpeedwayIndianapolis Motor SpeedwayInfineon RacewayInterlagos (Autódromo José Carlos Pace)Iowa SpeedwayKansas SpeedwayKentucky SpeedwayLangley SpeedwayLanier National SpeedwayLas Vegas Motor SpeedwayLime Rock ParkMartinsville SpeedwayMazda Raceway Laguna SecaMichigan International SpeedwayMid-Ohio Sports Car CourseMosport International RacewayNew Hampshire Motor SpeedwayNew Smyrna SpeedwayOkayama International CircuitOran ParkOulton Park CircuitOxford Plains SpeedwayPhillip Island CircuitPhoenix International SpeedwayPocono RacewayRichmond International RacewayRoad AmericaRoad AtlantaSebring International RacewaySilverstone CircuitSouth Boston SpeedwayStafford Motor SpeedwaySummit Point RacewaySuzuka CircuitTalladega Super SpeedwayTexas Motor SpeedwayThe Milwaukee MileThompson International SpeedwayToyota Speedway at IrwindaleTwin Ring MotegiUSA National SpeedwayVirginia International RacewayWatkins Glen InternationalTracks Under ConstructionBathurstNew Jersey Motorsports ParkTech TracksLong BeachModesTesting: Take to the tracks you own with any of the rides you own to do some single-car testing in which you can tweak the setups and practice the racing line. Unlimited time limit.Open Practice: Take to the track in a open session of practice in which you can run out on track with your fellow iRacers online. All sessions are timed.Time Trials: Take to the track and see if you can lay down consistent laps around the circuit of your choice. Users must lay down 10 consecutive "clean" laps in order for the session results to become official. It's a race against the clock and track itself!Qualifying: Hit the track and lay down several fast laps in order to qualify for an official or unofficial iRacing-hosted race event. Your best time will determine where you will start on the grid.Race: Take to the track against a field of fellow iRacers as the green flag waves in both official and unofficial series races! Based on your performance in the race, your iRating for your current license rank will be affected by your actions on track in official races. Drive a clean race, and your ratings will increase. Get involved in accidents or driving dirty will see your ratings drop as a result of your actions. Unofficial races (such as Carb Cup) do not have an impact on your iRating.License ClassesWhen you first start out on iRacing, you will be given a Rookie Class license for both the iRacing Oval and Road Divisions. Each Rookie Class license starts off with a Safety Rating of 2.50 and an iRating of 1600. To advance up the ranks, you must advance your Safety Rating to 3.0 or higher along with meeting the special MPR requirements in order to be promoted to the next license class. The ranking system is listed below (from lowest to highest):Rookie Class (Red)Class D License (Orange)Class C License (Yellow)Class B License (Green)Class A License (Blue)Pro Class License (Black)World Class License (Black)</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23517">GTR Evolution</game><game id="20130">rFactor</game><game id="5856">NASCAR Racing 2003 Season</game><game id="6347">Grand Prix Legends</game><game id="14919">Grand Prix Challenge</game><game id="36993">Project CARS</game><game id="34542">F1 2011</game><game id="27298">rFactor 2</game><game id="43281">Assetto Corsa</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1592/194437-iracing_square_outline.png</image></root>