<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21471</id><name>Warsow</name><description>OverviewWarsow is a cel-shaded multiplayer FPS based on Qfusion (a modification of Quake 2 GPL engine). The game is currently available for free via the developer's website and from GOG.com.MovementWarsow puts a strong emphasis on movement. In addition to the regular style of movement gamers may be used to in Quake (Stafe Jumping etc), Warsow adds a 'Special' Key. Depending on the context, movement will be modified in one of the following unique ways;DashIf the Special key is hit while touching the ground, the user will perform a dash. This allows quick acceleration from a stationary position, rapid changing directions at high speeds.DodgePressing the Special key simultaneously with the left or right strafe key, the player will perform a quick dash, or side-step.Wall JumpUsing the special key while touching a surface performs a wall jump. Limited to once every 1.5 seconds, or until the player has touched the ground again.Ramp SlideVery important in the 'Race' game type, the user can perform a slide by pressing the Special key while running along any ramp. Speed can also be gained on ramps using a strafe jumping motion.Double Dash JumpOn the lip of a ledge, dash followed quickly by a jump can add extra height.WeaponsThere are 7 unique weapons in total (Not including the gun from Instagib), and depending on the game type set by the host, all weapons will have both a strong and weak ammo type.Gunblade (GB)The base weapon of virtually all the modes. Has a slow fire rate and must charge for a few seconds to regain it's full strength. Also has a blade that can be used in melee for reasonable damage, but at the speeds most player move can be tricky to employ effectively.Riot Gun (RG)As the game's shotgun, it's strength lies at close range where most of the pellets will connect. However it can be used at range for very weak opponents who are elusive. Listening for the telltale groan of an injured opponent usually means one or two shots with the riot gun will finish the job.Grenade Launcher (GL)Launches an explosive disc in a short arc. Strong grenades do not bounce whereas weak grenades will bounce once or twice before exploding. Very useful for deterring any pursuers.Rocket Launcher (RL)A weapon that's behavior will be familiar for all players of the Quake series. Warsow makes liberal use of the rocket launcher in offensive play, but combined with the 'Wall Jump' technique it can be used to navigate the maps quickly to escape or ambush other players.Plasma Gun (PG)The plasma gun, much like the rocket launcher, remains relatively unchanged from Quake. Very useful at close range for cutting down an opponent quickly, and at long range deterring on-comers. The spammer's weapon of choice.Laser Gun (LG)Emitting a short range energy beam, the laser gun is only useful in a few choice situations: Especially useful when following an opponent up one of the game's many jump pads. Very frustrating for players who have lost momentum or get cornered. The beam remains straight as long as you have strong ammo, but bends as you move with weak ammo.Electrobolt (EB)The railgun. Strong ammo makes the bolt hit instantly up to a range of 1024 units. Although with weak ammo the speed is diminished the electrobolt remains an effective long range weapon.Items  Power-upsThere are four kinds of armor pick-ups available to boost the player's armor points to a max. of 200, respawning at 25 second intervals;Armor ShardsAdds 5 armor points.Green Armor (GA)Adds 50 armor points, up to a max. of 100 armor.Yellow Armor (YA)Adds 100 armor points, up to a max. of 150 armor.Red Armor (RA)Adds 150 armor points.Pick-ups to boost the player's health points to a max. of 200 respawn 35 seconds after previous pick-up.Health BubblesAdds 5 health points.Small HealthAdds 25 health points, up to a max. of 100.Medium HealthAdds 50 health points, up to a max 100.Mega Health AddsAdds 100 health points.Two power-ups are made available in certain game modes:WarshellReduces the damage taken x4 for a period of 30 seconds.WarshockBehaves as 'Quad Damage' made famous in Quake, increasing the power of the player's weapons x4 for 30 seconds.Players who posses this power-up with glow brightly and are clearly visible. The items themselves respawn 180/90 seconds respectively after previous pickup on default hosts.Game ModesWarsow has several modes of play. Most will be familiar to competative FPS players across the spectrum of game styles. Abbreviated names for the game types follow the subtitle.Death Match/Free For All (DM/FFA)The classic 'every man for himself' mode. A time limit is set by the host, during which time the player must frag as many opponents as possible. Players must collect weapons and armor located at various points around the map to gain an advantage.Team Deathmatch (TDM)Working in teams (Default Purple and Orange), players must proceed to eliminate their opponents. Both items and power-ups are available.Capture the Flag (CTF)The teams must work together to both defend their own flag and capture their opponents flag in the set time limit.DuelPlayers fight in the style of DM, but with only one opponent the emphasis is on tactics, item control, and deception. Items do not spawn for the first 15 seconds of the game.Duel Arena (DA)Differing slightly from regular Duel, DA starts the two players with a set amount of health and armor, and usually the full complement of weapons available in Warsow.Clan Arena (CA)CA expands on TDM, giving you the full complement of weapons (Dictated by your 'Class', if it is made available by the host), with no team damage or self damage. Players often use wall jumps combined with rockets to gain high velocity to chase or run from opponents. In this mode, power-ups, armor and health are not available.RacePlayers try to complete the race, usually a course of ramps and obstacles, in the fastest time possible using techniques such as strafe jumping, wall jumps, plasma climbing, etc. Maps range from variations on simple straight shot races (See the 'Line' series of maps), to highly technical, tricky courses. Upon completion of the race, your time is noted on the score board and you are sent back to the start to try and improve. Also available for race mode, is the 'Freestyle' setting for practicing movement. Several freestyle maps are available that resemble a bizarre gym, with areas for strafe jumping pads, plasma climbing walls, and other such specialized areas. Untimed in Freestyle mode, you can practice until the map timer runs out.Instagib (Available all game modes iCTF, iDM, iCA, etc.)All the above game types area available in instagib, even race. Players are given a variant of the Electrobolt which kills an opponent in one hit.Minimum System RequirementsWindowsWindows XP / Vista / 72,0 GHz CPU (Dual-core recommended)512 MB RAM (1 GB recommended)3D graphics card compatible with DirectX 9.0cMacOS X 10.6.8 or laterIntel Core Duo 2 GHz+1 GB RAM64 MB of video memoryUseful LinksOfficial WebsiteWarsow Wiki</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3874">Quake III Arena</game><game id="17448">Unreal Tournament</game><game id="3207">Quake II</game><game id="6730">Painkiller</game><game id="13683">Quake 4</game><game id="18828">Unreal Tournament 2003</game><game id="13286">Unreal Tournament 2004</game><game id="10955">Unreal Tournament 3</game><game id="2955">XIII</game><game id="24798">Nexuiz</game><game id="1921">Marathon 2: Durandal</game><game id="34822">AssaultCube</game><game id="36015">Xonotic</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5872/409516-warsow.jpg</image></root>