<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21489</id><name>Mega Man: The Power Battle</name><description>OverviewA promotional poster.Mega Man: The Power Battle was released in the arcade in 1995. It is a spin-off of the Mega Man franchise. The game was developed and published by Capcom. In 2004, Mega Man: The Power Battle was released in North America for the first time in the Mega Man Anniversary Collection, for the PlayStation 2 and Nintendo GameCube. The game was also released as Rockman: Power Battle Fighters (along with its sequel, Mega Man 2: The Power Fighters) for the PlayStation 2. The story of Mega Man: The Power Battle involves Dr. Wily rebuilding Robot Masters. This prompts the heroes of the game to come and stop him. GameplayMega Man: The Power Battle has three playable characters: Mega Man, Proto Man, and Bass. The game also has cooperative play, with two different players fighting against bosses as a team. The game is very similar to other Mega Man games, except there is no stage for the player to traverse. There is merely a boss for the player to defeat to continue. Other than that, the gameplay is largely similar to other Mega Man games. Players can jump and shoot (holding down the shoot button charges the shot, while holding down the jump button does a dash).When the game begins, the player has the choice between several paths to take. Each path has different Robot Masters from the first seven of the nine Mega Man classic games.SoundtrackThe soundtrack.The soundtrack for the game was released in Japan as Rockman: The Power Battle.TitlePlayer SelectStage Select (Rockman 1-2)Stage StaringStage 1 (Napalm Man)Stage 2 (Crash Man)Stage 3 (Guts Man)Stage Select (Rockman 3-6)Stage 4 (Gyro Man)Stage 5 (Gemini Man)Stage 6 (Shadow Man)Stage ClearYou Got a New WeaponStage Select (Rockman 7)Stage 7 (Rockman 7)Stage 8 (Cloud Man)Stage 9 (Slash Man)Stage 10 (Freeze Man)Stage 11 (Junk Man)Stage 12 (Shade Man)Stage 13Vs. WilyStage: Wily BossStage: Wily MachineStage: Wily CapsuleContinueGame OverEnding - Rockman 1Ending - ForteEnding - BluesEnding - Rockman 2S.E. CollectionVoice Collection</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9155/203258-megaman_powerbattle1.png</image></root>