<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21480</id><name>UFC: Sudden Impact</name><description>UFC: Sudden Impact gives you all the mixed martial arts action found  only in the Octagon. You can create and customize your own Ultimate  Fighter and then fight your way through five gameplay modes, including  Tournament and Story. The game includes such UFC superstars as Chuck  Liddell, Tito Ortiz, Ken Shamrock, and Matt Hughes, as well as 10  unlockable and six hidden fighters. You can choose from 15 different  fighting disciplines, positions, and moves.   Gameplay  Tapout Ultimate Fighting Championship: Sudden Impact uses an 8 directional D-Pad and 4 buttons - each one responsible for the fighter's different limb (LP, RP, LK,RK). The grappling moves, counters and submissions can be executed by pressing 2 specific buttons together. Each fighter has his own selection of moves. The fights can be won by knockout, point advantage or tapout. This version contains visible indicators of fighters being damaged during fights such as bruises and dripping blood. The game also focuses on fence positioning giving players new manouver possibilities. Selectable fighters  Chuck Liddell         Pedro Rizzo                                       Tim Sylvia        Maurice Smith                                     Bas Rutten                                    Andrei Arlovski                                   Ricco Rodriguez                                  Gary Goodridge                                 Mark Coleman      Tsuyoshi Kohsaka                                Tito Ortiz                               Chuck Liddell    Andrei Arlovski                               Vitor Belfort      Ken Shamrock                             Pete Williams                            Renato Sobral                           Kevin Randleman                          Elvis Sinosic    Frank Shamrock                         Guy Mezger                        Eugene Jackson                       Phil Baroni                      Dave Menne Tim Sylvia Murilo Bustamante         Pete Spratt   Jens Pulver  B.J.PennYves EdwardsDuane Ludwig                     Matt Serra Caol UnoErica MontoyaGame modes  A story mode character's high kick K.O.     Arcade - player figting as one of the superstars or his own creation is pitted against series of CPU controlled opponentsChampion Road - players ultimate aim is to win a silver (5 fights) or gold (10 fights) title shot match in his own weight class. By doing that some previously unplayable characters are unlocked.Tournament - an eight fighter eliminatory tournamentVersus - 1P vs COM, !P vs 2P, COM vs COM, COM vs 2P, COM vs COMStory  - in this mode the player is given an opportunity ti create his own fighter with customizable body and clothing. The creation tools are not very detailed, because they only let players to choose from several predetermined face designs. Clothing and tattooss are unlocked as the player makes progress. The main idea of this mode is to prepare the fighter to enter the UFC league during three year training. Each year the player is given an opportunity to choose the fighting style he wants to specialise in (some of them need to be unlocked) and then decides if he wants to learn new moves or improve the stats by completing various tasks such as e.g. surviving the round without being hit, performing a specific combo or winning by tapout. After threee years of training the story mode character is selectable as a regular fighter in any gameplay mode.Training - in this mode palyers can set their and opponents' positions as well as display the input data.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21481">UFC: Tapout 2</game><game id="26815">EA Sports MMA</game><game id="27650">K-1 World Grand Prix</game><game id="29376">UFC Undisputed 2010</game><game id="13855">Ultimate Fighting Championship</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2133357-box_ufcsi.png</image></root>