<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21497</id><name>Simple Series 2000 Vol. 90: The Oneechanbara 2</name><description>Overview The second game in the             Onechanbara series, though the third in the franchise, The Oneechanbara 2 builds on the engine established in the original game,            Zombie Zone. The Oneechanbara 2 is a hack and slash game in the vein of           Capcom's          Devil May Cry or         Koei's        Dynasty Warriors games. This time,       Aya is joined by her sister,      Saki, and the mysterious     Reiko as they must find the cause of a second    Zombie outbreak. Retaining the "Cool Combo" system and the Rage and Blood meters found in the first game, The Oneechanbara 2 added some character specific moves, such as Aya's throwing knives, as well as smarter enemies, and new way's to defeat enemies.  It also introduced a   tag system to the series, allowing the player to select two characters and switch between them at anytime.  Alongside the story mode, the game also featured the arena style survival mode and the quest system. All these features were improved slightly, with all the story levels being different, the survival arena's being unique, and the quest being much more varied.  The Oneechanbara 2 is the only game in the franchise not released in English. Story "My name is Aya. I am the scion of a line of sword-weilding assassins going back hundreds of years. I have a sister, Saki, who carries the same blood I do. Ever since a brutal tragedy 49 days ago, she has been unable to regain conciousness. Then, one day, while being moved to another hospitalm she disappeared. Was she taken by someone ? Or... did she leave by herself ? All that was there was an ambulance smeared in crimson blood. Desperate to find my sister, I wasted no time in following her trail..."</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13072">Devil May Cry</game><game id="16741">Devil May Cry 2</game><game id="890">Devil May Cry 3: Dante's Awakening</game><game id="6681">Devil May Cry 4</game><game id="6602">Ninja Gaiden Black</game><game id="18546">Ninja Gaiden Sigma</game><game id="20553">Ninja Gaiden II</game><game id="6959">God of War</game><game id="11314">God of War II</game><game id="8720">Dead Rising</game><game id="24253">Burn Zombie Burn!</game><game id="35948">Lollipop Chainsaw</game><game id="39749">Ninja Gaiden 3: Razor's Edge</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2323872-box_ocb2.png</image></root>