<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21500</id><name>L.A. Noire</name><description>OverviewL.A. Noire is an action-adventure open world game developed by Team Bondi and published by Rockstar Games. It was released for PS3 and Xbox 360 in May, 2011, and PC in November, 2011, following a development period of more than 6 years.The game centers on the character of Cole Phelps as he rises through the ranks of the LAPD, solving cases and arresting criminals. The game features an open world rendition of 1947 Los Angeles and uses motion scan technology to produce facial models on the game characters capable of expressing nuanced realistic emotions.DevelopmentAnnouncement and ReleaseL.A. Noire was officially announced on September 25, 2006 by a short teaser trailer and an announcement that Rockstar would be teaming up with Team Bondi to release it. The game was originally announced as a PS3 exclusive and a second trailer for the game was released on October 5, 2006.Early Teaser ImageThe game then disappeared, its continuing existence only attested to in shareholder announcements by Take-Two, who continued to state that the game was still in development despite the fact that barely anything about the game had been revealed in nearly 4 years. The silence was finally broken by the March 2010 issue of Game Informer, which revealed that the game still existed and that it would be coming to both Xbox 360 and PS3 in late 2010. The game was then subsequently delayed and on November 11, 2010, a new trailer revealed cinematics, but no actual gameplay. A second trailer revealed that the game would be released on May 17, 2011 in the United States, while Rockstar Games' official website, announced Europe's release date to be May 20, 2011.Attention to DetailTeam Bondi set out to develop a fully realized 1940s Los Angeles. Team Bondi used over 140 000 photos from the era to recreate certain streets and most of the important landmarks from the Chinese Theater to the Hollywood Land sign. The clothes are all era specific as well as the slang used by certain characters. In order to correctly model the clothes, clothing from the sets of King Kong and Saving Private Ryan were loaned to Team Bondi. Furthermore, the radio that plays during the game features songs from the era as well as ads that were played in the 40s. Furthermore, the cars in the game are all from the era and were modelled in game thanks to Jay Leno, who let Team Bondi into his private car collection.The cases that Cole solves throughout the game are all based on real cases that happened during the 1940s and 50s around Los Angeles. The game even provides resolutions to previously unsolved cases such as the Daliah murders.Motion ScanMotion ScanTeam Bondi began to conduct research on motion scan technology 5 years before the game's release (which may explain why L.A. Noire was constantly delayed). The technology is said to let players see animations that traditional animation is unable to render. Motion scan focuses on rendering an extremely realistic face where cheekbones move as a character speak and eyes focus on points in the environment. Scenes were shot in two parts: first with motion capture, in order to render the body movements, and then with motion scan to render the dialogues (which was handled by sister company Depth Analysis). Shooting of the motion scan scenes was done in the "depth analysis room" where actors would wear make up in order to look like their 1940s character and recite their lines in front of cameras that were filming the front, the back and the top of their heads.L.A. Noire uses motion scan during the game's lengthy interrogation sequences where players must determine if a suspect is lying or not.The interrogation scenes as well as the detective scenes were handled by Team Bondi while Rockstar developed the shooting sequences.Working Conditions at Team BondiIn June 2011, several employees began speaking out about the allegedly horrible working conditions at Team Bondi, largely due to Brendan McNamara's poor management skills. According to the employees, they were forced to work overtime with no additional pay, and they were lied to about release dates in order to keep them working overtime. In addition, one source described McNamara as "the angriest person" he's ever met.Furthermore, one source explained that management made excuses for creating new positions for the purpose of hiring new employees for less money. On paper the new positions were of less importance, but in reality they were essentially identical to the ones they supposedly fell under. The result was new hires doing the same job as those in higher positions but for less pay.One source even offered an explanation as to why some critics described the game environment as "boring". According to this source, only one animator worked on gameplay during large parts of production, and Team Bondi literally had no one in their Lead Animator position from January 2008 all the way through until the final release date.GameplayThe gameplay is more or less described as an adventure game, rather than the usual Rockstar open world killfest. In this sense, it's more like Bully--still free roaming but with a stronger set of rules over the player. While searching for clues and interrogating,occasional gunplay sequences crop up. Unlike most games, the player's health is not displayed by an HUD. Instead, when the player takes damage, the game screen fades into a black and white tone. The player recovers health by taking cover and waiting a few seconds.The first mission revealed to the press was called "The Driver's Seat". It involved the police finding an abandoned car that had its interior covered in blood. In order to carry out the investigation, the player must find clues. Unlike other games, clues don't just pop up on the HUD, but it is up to the player to search for them. Different people can find different clues, a detail that changes the way the investigation plays out. This will also affect the length of certain investigations.Discovering clues is an important gameplay element in L.A. NoireLike your cellphone in GTA 4, the player always carries around a little notebook. Each clue, testimony and anything related to the investigation is added to the detective's little book. It will also serve as a way to display the current objectives and, like in Uncharted 2, players are able to flip through it in order to pull out viable information during testimonies, for example.During cases the player will always start off at a crime scene. There, the player must find clues and interview victims. Most clues usually lead up to the next event in the case. Some clues can further progress the case's finish. One major clue can change the outcome of the case.As the player progresses through the ranks, they earn "intuition points". With this they have the option to, remove an answer, show all clues, and "ask the community" (online connection required). The "show all clues" option usually can help by highlighting evidence at a crime scene. The "remove an answer" option removes wrong answers to give more chances at succeeding in interviewing a person.Crime DesksAs the character progresses through the game, Phelps will be assigned to new desks and partners.Patrol: The Patrol desk is a department of the LAPD concerned with monitoring assigned areas in Los Angeles. Phelps starts off as a police officer in this department as a "beat cop". Phelps is partnered with Ralph Dunn at the Patrol Desk.Traffic: The Traffic desk is a department of the LAPD concerned with hit-and-run, felony driving, car burglaries, and car thefts. "The Fallen Idol" is one case that hits the traffic desk. This is also where Phelps is partnered with Stefan Bekowsky.Homicide: The homicide desk is one of the most brutal and harrowing desks within the game, dealing with homicide. "The Silk Stocking Murder" is one of the cases at the homicide desk. Rusty Galloway is Phelps' homicide partner.Vice: The Vice desk is a department of the LAPD concerned with offenses involving prostitution, drugs, lewdness, lasciviousness, and other related obscenities. Phelps is partnered with Roy Earle at the vice desk.Arson: The Arson desk is a department of the LAPD concerned with maliciously, voluntarily, and willfully setting fire to another's property, or of the act of burning one's own property for an improper purpose, such as to collect the insurance. Phelps is partnered with Herschell Biggs at the arson desk.StoryOverviewIn a departure from previous Rockstar games, the main protagonist of L.A. Noire is righteous, and regularly finds himself in conflict with others who are less inclined to follow the rules. Cole Phelps is an honest detective, out to solve crimes and let the law do what it does best -- prosecute the offenders. In spite of that, he's not perfect. He has his failings, like any man, and it is they that drive him to try to hold himself and the world around him to the highest possible standard.Cole doesn't start the game as a successful detective. His beginnings lie in the role of a street cop working the beat, responding to everyday crimes whenever they happen. The more he works, though, the more opportunities he has to hone his investigative skills and impress his superiors, earning him progressively nicer desks back at Police HQ. With each promotion comes new responsibilities in new areas of police expertise, taking him from traffic all the way through arson. Each change in desk also brings a new partner, some of who are more trustworthy than others.SettingL.A. Noire is set in 1947 Los Angeles and draws heavily from both plot and aesthetic elements of film noir--stylistic films from the 1940s and 1950s that shared similar visual styles and themes including crime, sex, and moral ambiguity, and were often shot in black and white with harsh, low-key lighting. The game uses a distinctive coloring-style that pays homage to the visual style of film noir. A post-war setting is the backdrop for plot elements that reference the detective films of the '40s, such as political corruption and drugs, with a classic jazz soundtrack.Ninety percent of Los Angeles' buildings and signage are recreated in the game, with design and typography choices hearkening back to the advertising of the time period. Additionally, even the jingles playing on the car radios are authentic to that time, advertising products and offering public service messages one would have heard while listening to the radio during the 40's.CasesPatrol DeskCole Phelps, before he becomes a detective.Cole Phelps starts out as a beat cop, working the streets after being awarded the Silver Star during the second World War. This part of the game serves as a tutorial, teaching players about the game's different mechanics.Buyer BewareA shooting happens in broad daylight in front of a shoe store, and Phelps takes the Case. The victim is Everett Gage, the owner of the shoe shop. After interrogating one of the clerks, Clovis Galletta, it is revealed that a man by the name of Edgar Kalou may be behind it. After a short chase sequence, Phelps catches Kalou and proceeds to interrogate him. It is revealed that Galletta was about to buy something at Kalou's jewelry store before Gage sent her back to work. That Gage had just ruined his sale paired with Gage's reputation for being anti-jewish, Kalou murdered him in cold blood. It is implied that Kalou is sentenced to the gas chamber.Impressed by Cole's skills, James Donnelly, captain of the homicide division, promotes Phelps to the traffic division.Traffic DeskPromoted to Traffic, Phelps is paired with Stefan Bekowsky.The Driver's SeatThe case begins with an abandoned, blood-filled vehicle found in a train yard. After some research, Phelps discovers that the car is owned by one Adrian Black. His research also yields a bloody pipe and a receipt for a live hog. Phelps and Bekowsky go and visit the owner's wife, Margaret Black. There the two officers discover that the couple have a miserable marriage and that Mr. Black is having an affair. It's also made clear at this point that the bloodied pipe actually came from the house. The two detectives then go to interrogate Frank Morgan, the man who sold the hog to Black. Here players learn that Adrian Black is not dead, but instead faked his own death by covering his car in swine blood with plans to flee town. Phelps catches Black before he can leave town, and jails him for wasting police resources.Consul's Car (PS3 Exclusive)Phelps and Bekowsky must investigate on the disappearance of L.A.'s consul of Argentina's car.A Marriage Made in HeavenA hit and run is reported at Ray's Cafe. A married man, Lester Pattison, is found dead after being hit by a car. After snooping around, Phelps finds a an insurance letter inside the man's coat and a bloodied knife in a garbage can. He also learns that Lester and his wife, Lorna, were having an argument just before the accident. The detectives visit Lorna Pattison who seems unfazed with the news of her husband's death. Phelps eventually hunts down the driver who killed Lester who reveals that Lester was already dead before the car hit him. The morgue confirms that Lester's cause of death was from knife wounds. Phelps goes back to the Pattison residence and deduces that Lorna killed her husband with another man, Leroy Sabo, so the two could get the insurance and start a joint business venture. Sabo kills Lorna after she spills the beans, but is either arrested or killed by Phelps.A Slip of the Tongue (DLC)One of the pre-order DLC cases (also available for separate purchase)A stolen car is spotted and Phelps and Bekowsky are sent to intercept it. After a short car chase, the detectives manage to stop the car, owned by a young man named Cliff Harrison. He assures the police that he legally bought the car at a used car dealership and produces the pink slip to prove it, but fled because of drugs stored in the glove compartment. Phelps investigates the used car dealership where he finds out that the car was sold by a woman named Jean Archer, and that the pink slips were made by the Marquee Printing Company. The car sold by Jean was also registered to an empty lot. A man named Belasco is arrested for grand theft auto and it becomes clear that he and Jean belong to the same car smuggling ring. Phelps later finds and arrests Jean who was trying to scam the smuggling ring by selling the cars. She tells the detectives where the cars are stored and after a shoot out, they find and interrogate the chief of the warehouse who reveals that Marquee Printing Company is behind the smuggling ring. Due to the fact that the company's boss, Levitol, is neck deep in gambling debts, he started to sell pink slips to the mafia for profit. He is later arrested for fraud.The Fallen IdolThe case opens with a car being driven over a cliff. The two passengers, B-movie actress June Ballard and 15 year old Jessica Hamilton, survive the crash. June tells the detectives she thinks that movie producer Mark Bishop is behind the murder attempt since he didn't want to cast her in his new movie. Jessica also points at Bishop as the culprit, but she adds an accusation of rape to June's attempted murder allegation. Phelps goes to the Hamilton residence only to find it ransacked, the wife explaining that she does not know the whereabouts of her husband. The detectives go to prop set where they discover that Bishop is running an underground pornographic network. Before they can learn more, Roy Earle from Ad Vice intervenes, saying that the owner of the prop shop is in fact an informant. Phelps isn't the only one looking for Bishop, but so is the local mafia. Bishop is finally found on the set for a movie titled "Intolerance" and after a shoot out with the mob, he's arrested for rape.Due to Phelps' successes, he is promoted to homicide.Homicide DeskA grisly murder scene.The cases on the homicide desk share the same theme, centering around a single serial killer who focuses on drunk women. In the process of murdering his victims, the killer also strips them of their clothes and leaves weird writings on their bodies. Nicknamed the "Werewolf", this killer is based on a real life serial killer who terrorized L.A. in the late 40's. He was also commonly referred to as the Dahlia killer.Phelps investigates the murder of 4 women during the cases "The Red Lipstick Murder", "The Golden Butterfly", "The Silk Stocking Murder", "The White Shoe Slaying" and "The Studio Secretary Murder". Each time the victims are women who were having conflictual relationships with their husbands, and were murdered late at night while drunk. Because the murder weapon is always found, Phelps always convicts someone. He is pushed by Donnelly to convict communists and child molesters to grab headlines, while the evidence usually points more towards the husbands of the victims. It is worth noting that enough evidence exists for a conviction to go either way.The murder mystery ends with the case called "The Quarter Moon Murders". The killer, to show his power and cunning, as well as test both the mental and physical skills of Detective Phelps, leads him through L.A. with poems and personal items that belong to each of his victims. He leaves these things in dangerous, difficult to reach places in famous Los Angeles landmarks, such as the Hall of records and the Westlake Tar Pits. The case ends in the Christ Crown of Thorns church, where it's revealed that a bartender, who worked at different jobs through a temp agency and had been interviewed briefly by Phelps earlier in the investigation, is in fact the murderer. He studied each of the victims before murdering them, a process that allowed him to pin the crime on someone else. The killer is shot dead by Phelps but Donnelly arrives and tells Phelps that the public can not know who the real killer was as the killer was the son of an important politician running for election.At the personal request of vice detective Roy Earle, Phelps is moved off the homicide desk to administrative vice where he becomes Earle's partner.Vice CasesAnother investigation.The Black CaesarTwo junkies are found dead after taking army surplus morphine and seemed to have been engaged in illegal rackets. Phelps tracks the morphine back to a popcorn stand just outside the Hotel and gets into a small chase when the owner decides to make a run for it rather than answer some questions. After a short interrogation the stand owner fingers his supplier as Jermaine Jones a talent agent. In addition to giving up his supplier when put under a bit more pressure he also mentions the owner of the racketeering business as a slick fellow by the name of Merlon. Phelps and Roy visit the talent agency and find out Jermaine Jones buys his morphine from Merlon Otis who runs an illegal betting operation for a Jewish mobster by the name of Finkelstein. They also find out that Ramez Removals has close links to Vinny the Fink and clues Phelps onto another line of investigation. Next they visit Merlon Otis who also makes a run for it and has to be to chased down before they can interrogate him. Otis says that he moves the dope that Jose Ramez brings around who in turn gets the dope from the mob. The next stop is Ramez Removals where the detectives pick up some clues leading them to an ice company. The ice company in turn is just a front for the local mob, and is run by Mickey Coen's brother in law, Finkelstein. Phelps kills all the mobsters and finds the stash of army surplus morphine that was stolen off the navy ship in the beginning of the year, putting an end to the illegal morphine distribution.The Set-UpBoxer Albert Hammond wins a match that he was originally supposed to lose. He quickly takes flight, and Phelps must try to find him before the mob guns him down. Through some detective work at Hammonds hotel Phelps makes a connection between the boxer and a Candy Edwards with whom he had been having relations. Upon visiting the girl the two detectives find her in an altercation with an Italian gangster that Phelps knocks out in a fist fight. A quick sweep of the room reveals travel tickets, a packed suitcase and a list of possible bookies found in the jacket of the unconscious goon, along with a nasty looking knife. The duo question Candy, but as she proves uncooperative they decide to tail her instead hoping she'll lead them to Hammond. It's revealed that Candy visits all the bookies in town and cleans them out. She is the one who planned on Hammond throwing the match, and bet the other way. After tailing Candy to a bus station Cole observes her from afar while Roy suggests he had seen Hammond and goes after him. Shortly after she walks into the station bathroom a gunshot is heard . Quickly arriving at the scene Candy is found bleeding profusely from a chest wound and shortly after dies - an open window suggesting the way of the killers getaway. The two suspect that Hammond got greedy and used his girl as a baglady then killed her to collect all the winnings for himself. While heading towards the last clue pointing to Hammonds location, the coroner radios Cole to let him know that Candy died as a result of a knife wound, making the pistol found at the scene hers and pointing out the killer as a certain Italian goon with a knack for beating women and carrying switchblades. After a quick gun fight with the Italian mob intent on killing Hammond and making off with all the money themselves the detectives confronts Albert who explains his past in the military and how his honor, the last thing he had left, wouldn't let him lose. Having experienced a similar situation himself in the past, Phelps understands how important second chances are to a man and decides to let him go, ending the case.The Naked City (DLC)Phelps and Earle must investigate the death of Julia Randall, a beautiful model who appears to have overdosed on morphine. However, the bruises all over her body lend a suspicion of murder, and despite being single she wears a suspicious looking ring on her hand. After learning that Randall was on medication, Phelps and Earle pay a visit to her physician, a Dr. Stoneman who at first lies about her prescription, then reveals that Julia was one of the self-destructive types who tried to live life fast and make a name for herself in the City of Angels. The detectives then visit a tailor where Julia did modeling. Heather Swanson, one of the employees at the shop reveals that Julia was modeling for her fiancee, Henry Arnett. After interrogating Henry, it's revealed that Julia was both having an affair with Henry, and she was murdered. Phelps decides to tail Henry and finds out that he's trying to pawn contraband and leave for New Mexico. The contraband used to belong to Mrs Evestrom, who is also Heather Swanson's mother. Her things were robbed from her home while she was at Dr Stoneman's party. Phelps senses that something is wrong and goes to Arnett's apartment just in time to see a man who goes by "Willy" first beat up Arnett and then escape. Arnett spills the beans, explaining that he, Julia, Stoneman and Willy were all part of a robbery ring. The doctor would organize parties while the 3 others would rob the guests' homes. However, Julia wanted out, leading Arnett and Willy to murdering her, and Willy beating up Arnett in fear that he would give him up. Arnett is arrested, Stoneman commits suicide and Willy is killed by Phelps.Trailer via GiantbombManifest DestinyA shooting occurs in the 111 Club where a former squadmate of Phelps who had just purchases the establishment is shot dead. Here it is revealed that the morphine is still in circulation and has started a war between the gang controlled by Mickey Cohen and a former marine unit. It's discovered that the morphine was in fact stolen from the army by a soldier named Courtney Sheldon and a group of his former squadmates from Okinawa. Through the manipulation of Dr. Harlan Fontaine, Sheldon gives up the morphine thinking Fontaine will use it to aid returned soldiers by building homes for them where they can rest after the horrors of war. However, he wound up involved with crime boss Mickey Cohen who wishes to turn a profit by watering the morphine down and selling it on the streets. Through the course of the early investigation Phelps meets and questions Elsa Lichtman whom he becomes enamored with leading to an affair. Meanwhile Sheldon enacts the help of his former squadmates as well as that of Jack Kelso to scare off the mobsters from moving in on the morphine - which prompts the mob to put out a hitlist on all the former servicemen. Phelp's former squad mates begin getting killed off by mobsters one by one and through various clues picked up along the way he's able to make a connection back to Sheldon with proof to pin the morphine heist on him. Meanwhile a man by the name of Stoker is leaking information about LA's famous madame Brenda and the services she provides for both the LAPD and high officials alike. In a secret meeting with the chief of police and district attorney among others, Roy proposes to make Phelps the sacrificial lamb for the press by airing his infidelity with the German singer Elsa Lichtman which would draw the heat away from the LAPD and other officials involved in the prostitution Brenda scandal. Just as Phelps is about to crack Sheldon and get a confession out of him he's summoned by top ranking LAPD officials and suspended for adultery, stating that a criminal cannot be an LAPD officer. The information is leaked to the journalists and his wife throws him out of the house, leaving him no other place to turn to than the source of all this trouble - the apartment of Elsa Lichtman. While awaiting a peer review Phelps is demoted to the undesirable arson desk assignment and partnered with Herchel Biggs, who much like the rest of the LAPD that has found out about his infidelity with a German woman treats him with open hostility and disregard.Arson DeskThe Gas ManPhelps and BiggsPhelps investigates the burning of two houses. He learns that both houses were in the way of a redevelopment fund planning to build houses for GIs. Both houses also used the same gas filters that came from Instaheat factory. While investigating at the factory, Phelps learns that Instaheat is hiring criminals and that one of the employees burned the houses by reversing the gas filters and mosquito coils. Phelps arrests Walter Clemens and Matthew Ryan. Both are anarchists and both have a criminal past. The player must choose which of the two criminals that he wants to convict.A Walk in Elysian FieldsAnother house fire is assigned to Phelps and looks extremely familiar to the last two arsons. Like before, the house was supposed to be bought by Elysian Fields for the redevelopment fund. Phelps decides to go and investigate Elysian Fields and meets Leland Monroe, the CEO. He denies trying to chase away the final home owners by burning their houses. Meanwhile, the police department presses Cole to stop following the Elysian lead. Cole ends up killing the arsonist after an epic tram chase. However, he is unable to link the arsonist to Elysian.After the case, Roy visits Phelps to tell him to stay away from Elysian. Frustrated, Phelps discovers that one of Elsa's friends died while working for Elysian on the GI redevelopment fund. Because Elsa was his beneficiary, she received a large sum of money from the insurance company. Phelps decides that Elsa should go see Jack Kelso, a private investigator working for an insurance company called California Life and Fire to discover how her friend died, and why such a big sum of money was offered to her. At this point, the player plays as Kelso.House of SticksJack makes an investigation into the houses built by the redevelopment fund and discovers that they are constructed from bad wood found in an abandoned movie studio. Jack also discovers that many of L.A.'s top men are involved, including the mayor, Kelso's boss Curtis Benson, the chief of police, and Dr. Harlan Fontaine. As he is investigating however, Jack is kidnapped by Benson's men but he manages to escape before they can execute him.Nicholson Electroplating (DLC)At 9:45 in the morning, a thunderous explosion rocks Los Angeles. City blocks are flattened while smoke and ash fill the air. Detectives Phelps and Biggs race to the site of the former Nicholson Electroplating plant to find a pile of unanswered questions. What caused the explosion? What was the current project being worked on by Nicholson's employees? And where are chief chemist Dr Harold McLellan and his mysterious female assistant?A Polite InvitationJack KelsoJack pays a visit to Benson and discovers the conspiracy behind the redevelopment fund. The houses are being built out of crap wood so they can then be burned down. Thanks to an extremely high insurance rate, Elysian Fields hits the jackpot each and every time. They hand the money out to their stock owners, who just happen to be the mayor, Benson and the other top men. The redevelopment fund was financed thanks to the stolen morphine given to Dr. Fontaine by Courtney, who entrusted him with it to avoid trouble with the mob. Kelso enlists the help of Phelps and together, they plan to stop the dastardly plan and save Elsa, who's been kidnapped by Elysian's arsonist. The arsonist also also kills Dr. Fontaine.A Different Kind of WarJack attempts to find the person who kidnapped Elsa. He goes to Westlake Pest Control to find the address of the kidnapper. The story then switches to Phelps' investigation on the kidnapping of Elsa, which occurred on the day before Jack's investigation. During the investigation, Phelps learns that the matchstick houses are being built along the patch of the to-be-built freeway. He realizes that the housing fraud is not about insurance, it's about eminent domain.The story then switches back to Jack, as he arrives at the kidnapper's house in Rancho Rincon. Jack investigates the empty house and discovers the kidnapper-arsonist is Ira Hogeboom, a former war buddy. Jack calls Phelps, telling him to rendevous at the LA river tunnels where Ira is hiding out. Phelps meets up with Jack en route to the tunnels, as Jack is being hunted by the police. Together they escape their pursuers, and then split up to search the tunnels for Ira and Elsa. Shortly thereafter, the assistant DA arrives, followed by the police chief who confronts him. The assistant DA threatens the chief over being potentially involved in the ballooning scandal, to which the chief offers to make a deal. The assistant DA steps in to listen.Meanwhile, once caught up with Ira, Jack understands that Ira, still wearing his full combat gear, is suffering from uncontrollable flashbacks from the Battle of Okinawa. Cole then arrives and leads Elsa to safety, while Ira consents to let Jack shoot him dead to put him out of his misery. As the sewer begins to rapidly flood with torrential rainwater, the group manage to locate a manhole above them. Cole refuses to leave until he has helped everyone else climb out of the flooding tunnel, and then having no one left to lift him to safety, only looks up and says goodbye. He is then swept away by the water for good.At Cole's funeral, Roy, barely able to supress his snear, gives a speech full of phony condolences and tributes to the late Cole Phelps, as those Cole were his dear friend. Unable to stand it, Elsa jumps to her feet, curses Roy, and storms out in tears and disgust. The Chief of Police, the new DA, Roy, and the other conspirators comfortably disregard her. Biggs rises to go after her, and Jack can only sit and watch.After the credits end, a flashback plays depicting the fateful scene where Courney comes upon the idea of stealing the Army morphine to profit him and his unit, a group of men who otherwise have little to look forward to in civilian life. Courtney excitedly proclaims that the drug money will "give them the future they deserve". Jack is the only one among the group to reject the plot as betrayal of their honor, foreshadowing the eventual conflict that the drugs would bring, destroying nearly all of the men.Street Crimes - Unassigned CasesAlong with the Crime Desks that are explained above, players have the option to respond to radio calls that allow them to go to crimes in progress throughout the open-world environment. Some may remember this mechanic from the True Crime series. This allows players to take on extra side missions that can be completed while they are also heavily involved in the story. Each case is usually resolved within about 5 minutes and vary from shoot outs to chase sequences.Unlike the story cases, players are not graded according to performance, but just have to finish the case to gain 15 XP. All the cases can be done again in free roam and the different desk assignments have different cases. There are 40 unassigned cases in all. Cases can be replayed at any point and will remain on the map with a white street crime icon; but unplayed cases appear with a red icon. After completing all street crime cases on a desk while in Free Roam mode, a message will appear saying the desk is complete.Traffic DeskNameDetailsLocationImageAmateur HourBurglary829 Olive Street (Sillman's Jewelry Store)Army Surplus 540 West Ninth Street (Uncle Sam's Army Surplus)Boxing CleverBurglary267 South Main (Goldberg's Drug Store) Cosmic RaysDisturbanceSeventh and Flower StreetDeath from AboveShots FiredShatto and Valencia (Wilshire District)GangfightDisturbance1624 West Third StreetHotel BanditsArmed Robbery437 Eighnth Street (Bristol Hotel)Hung Out to DryBurglary536 South Figueroa (Hoelcher's Textile)Masked GunmanBurglarySixth and Ceres (Warehouse District)Pawnshop HoldupArmed Robbery333 South Main Street (Globe Loan and Jewelry)Shoo-Shoo BanditsArmed RobberyThird and Hill Street (Angels Flight)Theater RobberyArmed Robbery933 South Broadway (United Artist Theatre)Homicide DeskNameDetailsLocationImageBank JobArmed RobberySeventh and Olive (Bank of America)Bowling Lane RobberyArmed RobberyNinth and Grand (Rawling's Bowling Alley)Canned FishSuspicious Activity111 South AlmedaCop Killer ShotShot FiredSixth Street and Lindley PlaceDeath PlungeSuspicious ActivityEighth and Hope (First Methodist Church)Honey BoyDisturbance313 Bunker Hill AvenueKiller BanditsSuspicious Activity943 South Broadway (Levine's Liqour Store)MisunderstandingSuspicious ActivityUnion and Rockwood StreetRunning BattleArmed Robbery391 Broadway (Mallory's Cafe)Thicker Than WaterBurglaryLucas AvenueUnsuccessful HoldupArmed Robbery410 South Flower Street (Scott's Garage)Vengeful ExDisturbanceOlvera Street PlazaWould Be RobberPerson with a GunGrand between Fourth and Fifth StreetsVice DeskNameDetailsLocationImageAgainst the OddsTheftSunset and IvarBad DateHomicideUnion and SeventhCamera ObscuraLewd ConductFountain and BronsonCommiesArmed RobberyHollywood and Highland (Hollywood First National Gun)Daylight RobberyArmed RobberyThird and UnionFatal PlungeDisturbanceSeventh and CentralSecret KeepersSuspicious Activity6201 Santa Monica Boulevard (Southern California Auto Club)The Badger GameTheft3155 West Fourth StreetThe Blue LineSuspicious Activity1825 North Highland AvenueZoot Suit RiotShootout539 South Los Angeles Street (The Valor Tobacco Co.)Arson DeskNameDetailsLocationImageAccident ProneSuspicious ActivitySixth and AlvaradoBus Stop ShootingSuspicious ActivityBeverly and Union (Intersate Bus Station)Cafe HoldupArmed Robbery522 South Hill StreetHot PropertyBurglary38 North CatalinaPaper Sack HoldupArmed Robbery253 Main Street MissionsPatrol DeskUpon ReflectionArmed and DangerousWarrants OutstandingBuyer BewareTraffic DeskThe Driver's SeatA Marriage Made in HeavenA Slip of the TongueThe Fallen IdolHomicide DeskThe Red Lipstick MurderThe Golden ButterflyThe Silk Stocking MurderThe White Shoe SlayingThe Studio Secretary MurderThe Quarter Moon MurdersVice DeskThe Black CaesarThe Set UpManifest DestinyArson DeskThe Gas ManA Walk in Elysian FieldsHouse of SticksA Polite InvitationA Different Kind of WarCollectiblesLike Grand Theft Auto's hidden packages, L.A. Noire also has collectibles. There are 4 categories of collectibles: gold film canisters, landmarks, newspapers, and police badges, which is a Gamestop pre-order bonus.Newspapers:Newspapers are a vital source of information in Los Angeles in the era when L.A. Noire takes place.Newspapers give the player access to side missions, ambient events, and will report on gameplay events associated with player choices. Newspapers will also give the player a cutscene. There are 13 newspapers to collect in the game.Newspaper TitleCase Found InLocationSHRINK SAYS:"The Mind is the Final Frontier"Patrol:Upon ReflectionIn the Alleyway crime scene. On top of a crate to the right before the bloody door.ALIENIST FONTAINE:Provides Help to Troubled VetsTraffic:The Driver's SeatIn the Black's Residence on the dining table.SHRINK TO THE STARS:Promises Mental BreakthroughTraffic:A Marriage Made in HeavenInside Ray's Cafe on the bar near Dudley Lynch.DOPE FLOODS STREETS:Cops Chase War Surplus ContrabandTraffic:The Fallen IdolIn the Silver Screen Prop Store on the workbench near the shrunken heads in the storage alley.FAMILY BURNT TO DEATH:Cops Say House Fire Deaths Are SuspiciousHomicide:The Red Lipstick MurderRight in front of the door in the Henry Residence.MISSING MORPHINE:Cops Say: Goons Fighting Dope WarHomicide:The White Shoe SlayingOn a crate inside Stuart Ackerman's shack at the Hobo Camp.MICKEY COHEN:Heir Apparent to Bugsy SiegelVice:The Black CaesarInside Ramez Removal warehouse, across from the desk with the ledger.ALIENIST FONTAINE:Working Selflessly to Help the InfirmVice:The Set UpInside the American League Stadium on the training table in the locker room.LAPD VICE SCANDAL:Could Go All the Way to the TopVice:Manifest DestinyIn the alley near Haskell's Finest Men's Wear. Near the first dead gunmen.HOUSING DEVELOPMENT BURNS:Ex Servicemen Irate as GI Houses RazedArson:A Walk in Elysian FieldsOn the lawn to the right of the Morelli house fire, near the privacy fence.SUBURBAN REDEVELOPMENT:Fund Promises 10,000 New HomesArson:A Polite InvitationOn Leland Monroe's desk.CRUSADE AGAINST CORRUPTION:Peterson Pledges to Clean Up LAPDArson:A Different Kind of WarOn the front counter inside the Rapid Exterminators' store.THE FACE OF PROGRESS:Says Mayor of Developer Leland MonroeArson:A Different Kind of WarOn Harlan Fontaine's desk inside Doctor Fontaine's Surgery center.Police Badges:Police badges are exclusives to the Badge Pursuit Challenge, which was pre-order bonus at Gamestop/Game, but has since become DLC as well.Police Badges are hidden around L.A. Noire's beautiful recreation of 1947 Los Angeles. There are 20 police badges to find and collect. Finding all 20 badges will reward the player with the dapper Button Man suit which provides extra ammo for all weapons. Each badge also provides 5 additional XP, which will help further unlock intuition points.Landmarks:Landmarks are special types of locations in L.A. Noire. There are 30 landmarks to discover in the game. Finding landmarks grant players an intuition point per landmark. Finding all 30 landmarks earns the Star Map achievement/trophy.LandmarkLocationThe Mayfair HotelAlong 7th St., near Columbia Ave. and Witmer St.The Good Samaritan HospitalSouth of 6th St., between Witmer St. and Lucas Ave.Intolerance SetCorner of 8th and Francisco St.Christ Crown of ThornsSouth of 9th St. and west of Francisco St.LA Public LibraryAlong 5th St., between Flower St. and Grand Ave.Pershing SquareSouth of 5th St., north of 6th street and between Olive and Hill St.RKO TheatreCorner of Hill and 8th St.Los Angeles ExaminerCorner of 11th and BroadwayMain St TerminalOn 6th and Los Angeles St.The Bradbury BuildingCorner of 3rd and BroadwayAngels FlightOn 3rd and Hill St.Hall of RecordsAlong Broadway, east of 2nd St. Approximately one block northeast of the Central Police StationEl Pueblo de Los AngelesBetween Main and Los Angeles St. Easily found by it's distinctive circle on the mapUnion StationAlong Alameda St. Just south of El Pueblo de Los AngelesChinatownFar southeast of the map. Along BroadwayLA Cold Storage Cold Co.Between Central and Alameda Ave. South of 3rd St.4th Street ViaductOn the 4th St. bridge crossing the Los Angeles River.6th Street ViaductOn the Whittlier Blvd. bridge crossing the Los Angeles River.National Biscuit CompanyCorner of Industrial and Mateo St.MacArthur ParkOn Wilshire Blvd. between Park View and Alvarado St. Easily located by its big, distinctive squarePark PlazaCorner of 6th and Park View St. North of MacArthur ParkWestlake Tar PitsSouth of San Marino St.LA County Art MuseumOn Hoover St., south of 8th St.Bullocks WilshireCorner of Wilshire Blvd. and Westmoreland Ave.Brown DerbySouth of Hollywood Blvd. and west of Argyle Ave.Crossroads of the WorldAlong Sunset Blvd. and east of Las Palmas Ave.Musso  FranksAlong Hollywood Blvd. and southeast of Las Palmas Ave.Max Factor BuildingCorner of Hollywood Blvd. and Highland Ave.Grauman's TheaterAlong Hollywood Blvd., between Orchid and OrangeHotel RooseveltCorner of Hollywood Blvd. and Orange Dr.Gold Film Canisters:Gold film canisters are collectible items in L.A. Noire. There are 50 canisters scattered around Los Angeles, all of them with names of films from the 40s and 50s. Finding all of them reward with the Hollywoodland achievement/trophy.Movie NameDescriptionNotorious1946 thriller directed by Alfred Hitchcock starring Cary GrantDouble Indemnity1944 film noir directed by Billy Wilder starring Fred MacMurrayBody and Soul1947 film noir starring John GarfieldDetour1945 film noir starring Tom NealScarlet street1945 film noir directed by Fritz LangGun Crazy1950 film noir directed by Joseph H. LewisHouse of Bamboo1955 film noir that's in colorPickup on South Street1953 film noir directed by Samuel FullerLeave her to Heaven1945 film noir starring Gene TierneyKey Largo1948 film noir starring Humphrey BogartThe Maltese Falcon1941 detective film starring Humphrey BogartAngels with Dirty Faces1938 gangster film starring James CagneyStrangers on a Train1951 thriller directed by Alfred HitchcockThe Big Heat1953 film noir starring Glenn FordTouch of Evil1958 crime film directed by Orson WellesThe Asphalt Jungle1950 film noir directed by John HustonOut of the Past1947 film noir directed by Jacques TourneurThe Big Carnival1951 drama film starring Kirk DouglasMildred Pierce1945 drama film starring Joan CrawfordThis Gun for Hire1942 film noir directed by Frank TuttleRififi1955 french crime filmSweet Smell of Success1957 satirical film noir starring Burt LancasterMurder, My Sweet1944 film noir starring Dick PowellNight and the City1950 film noir directed by Gerald KershThe Big Clock1948 film noir directed by John FarrowThe Naked City1948 film noir on which the DLC is based off.Shadow of a Doubt1943 thriller film directed by Alfred HitchcockThe Killing1956 film noir directed by Stanley KubrickThe Set-Up1949 film noir on which the case of the same name is based off.Laura1944 film noir starring Gene TierneyThe Lady from Shanghai1947 fim noir directed by Orson WellesThe Third Man1949 british film noirThe Killers1946 film noir based off a short story by Ernest HemingwayM1951 thriller starring David WayneCrossfire1947 film noir starring Robert YoungThieves' Highway1949 film noir directed by Jules DassinWhite Heat1949 film noir directed by James CagneyThe Narrow Margin1952 film noir starring Charles McGrawSunset Boulevard1950 film noir directed by Billy WilderThe Woman in the Window1944 film noir directed by Fritz LangThe Spiral Staircase1946 thriller film starring Dorothy McGuireThe Night of the Hunter1955 thriller film starring Robert MitchumOdd Man Out1947 film noir starring James MasonIn a Lonely Place1950 film noir starring Humphrey BogartWhere the Sidewalk Ends1950 film noir starring Dana AndrewsGilda1946 film noir starring Rita HayworthThe Letter1940 film noir directed by William WylerBrute Force1947 film noir starring Burt LancasterNightmare Alley1947 film noir starring Tyrone PowerThe Big Sleep1946 film noir starring Humphrey BogartWeaponsThere are a total of nine weapons available to players. Using all nine weapons (excluding pre-order exclusive weapons) while killing bad guys, at least one guy per weapon, rewards with the Roscoe and Friends achievement/trophy.WeaponDescriptionColt M19171The Colt M19171 is the first weapon used by Phelps as an LAPD patrol officer. Use it on the Patrol case, Armed and Dangerous. In order to use this weapon, the player must drop the shotgun they take before entering the bank. The thugs here seem to also use M1917 revolvers, though with 'snub-nose' barrels instead of the version Cole Phelps uses.Colt M19171Star Model PThe Star Model P is the standard pistol Phelps uses as a detective.Star Model PIthaca 37 (Shotgun)The Ithaca 37 is the standard shotgun for LAPD officers. It is always accessed by opening the trunk, although times that players can open the trunk of the patrol car are restricted. Typically the trunk can only be opened during a hostile situation where shots have already been fired. The shotgun is the only weapon in the vehicle trunk unless the player downloads the Chicago Piano, which is free.Ithaca 37 (Shotgun)M1 GarandThe M1 Garand is a rifle used primarily in the army. It can be found in the street crime, "Death From Above" or in the Arson case, "A Different Kind of War". It is accurate, powerful, and probably the best choice for quick progression through the mission as it regularly kills with a single shot. Should it not, it is easy to follow up with a second shot, though a third shot is rarely, if ever, necessary. It has a clip capacity of eight rounds.M1 GarandM1A1 ThompsonThe M1A1 Thompson is a machine gun used primarily in the army. It is the most common sub-machine gun used by criminals and is also known as the "Tommy Gun". While being known as the "Tommy Gun", the name is more commonly used to refer to the iconic M1 Thompson with a Round Drum, made famous by mafia films.M1A1 ThompsonColt .45The Colt .45 is Jack Kelso's primary pistol. Use it in any case where the player gets to take control of Kelso.Colt .45M1 ThompsonThe M1 Thompson is basically the M1A1 Thompson with a round drum. It can be found in the Vice case, Manifest Destiny.M1 Thompson with barrelBrowning Automatic Rifle (BAR)The Browning Automatic Rifle can be found in the Arson case, "A Different Kind of War" and in the street crime "Army Surplus". It can be found during the "Cafe Holdup" street crime, but cannot be used there. In this street crime it is depicted as being incredibly powerful, killing Cole in a second when exposed. This is to stop players simply shooting the target from the ground - in other cases, the gun is not as absurdly powerful. It boasts a 20-round magazine capacity.Browning Automatic RifleFlamethrowerThe flamethrower can only be found and used in the Arson case, A Different Kind of War. Used by Jack Kelso, should the player choose the weapon. It is often the final weapon players need to use in order to attain the 'Roscoe and Friends' achievement, for killing an enemy with every weapon in the game. Ira Hogeboom also makes use of the M2 Flamethrower, to deadly effect.FlamethrowerChicago Piano GunThe Chicago Piano is a pre-order exclusive from HMV and Gamestop's PowerUp Rewards members. Visually, it shares a lot of similarities to the M1 Thompson, though is incorrectly depicted as having a magazine capacity of 100 rounds, despite using a 50-round drum. The Chicago Piano is available on both the PlayStation Store and the Xbox LIVE Marketplace for free, after Rockstar chose to release the weapon. It will be in the trunk of your patrol car, ready to be accessed when needed. It is generally much more useful than the Ithaca 37 due to its longer range of effectiveness.Chicago Piano GunNickel Plated PistolThe Nickel Plated Pistol is a pre-order exclusive from Best Buy / Zavvi, and visibly appears to be a Colt M1911 or another derivative of it. It becomes Cole's standard weapon when wearing the downloadable suit 'The Broderick'.Nickel Plated PistolVehiclesThere are 95 vehicles appears in the game. These are the usable vehicles.NameClassYearPowerTop SpeedAmerican LaFrance Fire TruckService1941-1946160 hp80 mphBuick 2DR Sedanette2 Door1947110 hp100 mphBuick AmbulanceService1947144 hp100 mphBuick Business Coupe2 Door193693 hp86 mphBuick Coupe2 Door1941125 hp95 mphBuick Custom2 Door1941125 hp110 mphBuick Eight Convertible2 Door1939141 hp105 mphBuick Eight Coupe2 Door1939141 hp105 mphBuick SuperPolice1947110 hp96 mphCadillac LaSalle Series 504 Door1935150 hp95 mphCadillac Series 614 Door1942150 hp95 mphCadillac Series 61 Touring Coupe4 Door1947150 hp95 mphCadillac Series 62 ConvertiblePolice1947150 hp95 mphCadillac Series 75 Limousine4 Door1942150 hp90 mphCadillac Town CarBonus1936135 hp93 mphCadillac V16 ConvertibleSport1934185 hp90 mphChevrolet Civilian VanService194960 hp80 mphChevrolet Coroner's VanPolice194985 hp90 mphChevrolet Fleetmaster 2DR2 Door194790 hp86 mphChevrolet Fleetmaster 2DR (Police)Police194790 hp96 mphChevrolet Fleetmaster ConvertibleSport194790 hp86 mphChevrolet PickupService194790 hp72 mphChevrolet Pickup #2Service194085 hp70 mphChevrolet Sedan4 Door194085 hp78 mphChevrolet Styleline2 Door194990 hp87 mphChevrolet Tow TruckService1947140 hp85 mphChevrolet VanService193785 hp70 mphChrysler Airflow4 Door1934115 hp90 mphChrysler Town and Country2 Door1946135 hp110 mphChrysler WoodyBonus1946  Cisitaalia CoupeBonus193969 hp109 mphCord 810 SofttopBonus1936170 hp130 mphCord Harptop2 Door1936115 hp92 mphDavis DeluxeBonus1948  Delage D8 120Bonus1937  Delage D8-120 S PoutoutBonus1937120 hp110 mphDelahaye 135MS CabrioletBonus1947  DeSoto 2DR Custom2 Door1946109 hp96 mphDeSoto Custom Suburban TaxiService194695 hp90 mphDeSoto Suburban4 Door1946109 hp92 mphDodge Fuel TruckService1939150 hp65 mphDuesenberg Walker CoupeBonus1934265 hp140 mphFord 2DR2 Door194790 hp90 mphFord AmbulanceService1948110 hp75 mphFord Business Coupe2 Door194060 hp80 mphFord Convertible2 Door193685 hp80 mphFord Custom2 Door194090 hp87 mphFord Deluxe ConvertibleSport193985 hp80 mphFord H BoyBonus1932130 hp115 mphFord Police SpecialPolice1947100 hp95 mphFord Tudor Convertible2 Door1947100 hp95 mphFord V8 Sedan2 Door194090 hp85 mphFrazer Manhattan4 Door1947112 hp106 mphGMC PickupService194793 hp76 mphHeil Colecto-PakService194795 hp70 mphHudson CommodorePolice1948129 hp91 mphHudson Super Six4 Door194792 hp88 mphInternational D SeriesService193982 hp75 mphInternational D Series Sedan4 Door193982 hp75 mphInternational KB5Service1946100 hp82 mphInternational KB6Service1946100 hp82 mphInternational KB8Service1946100 hp80 mphInternational KB8 (Polar Bear Ice Truck)Service194796 hp76 mphInternational Metro KB1MService194984 hp70 mphInternational Police WagonPolice1940110 hp75 mphLaSalle V8 Sedan2 Door1939125 hp88 mphLincoln Continental ConvertibleSport1946120 hp118 mphLincoln Continental Coupe2 Door1942130 hp118 mphLincoln Model K Convertible RoadsterSport1937150 hp122 mphLincoln Zephyr Touring4 Door1939110 hp95 mphMercury CustomSport1941110 hp105 mphNash Deluxe 600 ArmyService194299 hp90 mphNash La Fayette ConvertibleSport1939115 hp95 mphNash Super 6002 Door1948112 hp104 mphNash Super 600 (Police)Police1942112 hp98 mphOldsmobile Hydramatic 884 Door1948110 hp100 mphOldsmobile S98Sport1947110 hp100 mphOldsmobile Sedan4 Door1940110 hp92 mphPackard Clipper Eight2 Door1946165 hp120 mphPackard Clipper Eight (4 Door)4 Door1947130 hp102 mphPackard Clipper Six2 Door1948130 hp104 mphPackard Custom2 Door1940140 hp132 mphPhantom CorsairBonus1938  Pontiac Sedan Six4 Door1937105 hp92 mphPontiac Torpedo Six2 Door194190 hp84 mphPlymouth P54 Door193795 hp85 mphPlymouth Sedan4 Door193982 hp76 mphPlymouth Special Deluxe Six4 Door194795 hp89 mphStout ScarabBonus193685 hp75 mphStudebaker Commander2 Door194794 hp86 mphStudebaker Commander (Police)Police194794 hp90 mphTalbot GS26Bonus1948190 hp125 mphTucker TorpedoBonus1948166 hp120 mphVoisin C7Bonus193893 hp89 mphWillys Overland4 Door193961 hp55 mphOtherThese are non-usable vehicleCessna 195 AirplaneInternational Harvester TD-9 Crawler Tractor BulldozerPacific Electric Baldwin V-1000 LocomotivePacific Electric Railway StreetcarUnion Pacific EMD F3 LocomotiveWhite Model 798 BusOutfitsStandardBeat Cop UniformGolden BoySword of JusticeSunset StripThe OutsiderHawkshawBonusThere are 4 bonus outfits that are unlocked when purchased pre-order bonuses or downloadable content.The SharpshooterThe BroderickButton ManChicago Lightning Downloadable ContentL.A. Noire has a variety of DLC for purchase, from new cases, to alternate weapons  outfits.Released May 31, 2011The Naked City (Vice case)Slip of The Tongue (Traffic case)Broderick Detective SuitSharpshooter Detective Suit  GunChicago Piano Machine GunThe Badge Pursuit ChallengeReleased June 21, 2011Nicholson Electroplating Disaster (Arson case)Released July 12, 2011Reefer Madness (Vice case)"L.A. Noire Rockstar Pass"Rockstar is offering the "L.A. Noire Rockstar Pass," which allows players to buy all the DLC at once for a discounted price. If players purchased the pass by June 21st, the price was $10. After that, the Pass went up to $12, which is still less expensive than buying all the DLC individually.Pre-Order BonusesCertain major retailers offered different preorder bonuses. All of these items later became available to purchase as DLC:RetailersPre-Order BonusesWalmart (US)/Play.com (UK)The Traffic desk case "A Slip of the Tongue"Downloadable SoundtrackA Slip Of The Tongue CaseAmazonThe Broderick suit, which boosts your resistance to damage and the damage you cause during fist fights.The Broderick Detective SuitGameStop/EB Games/Game (UK)The Vice case "The Naked City"The "Badge Pursuit Challenge": the player must find 20 police badges around town. Each badge awards XP, finding all badges unlocks the "Button Man" suit, which provides extra ammo for weapons.The Naked City CaseBest Buy/Zavvi (UK)Pre-ordering from Zavvi or Best Buy results in receiving the Sharpshooter Detective Suit. The pack also includes the nickel-plated pistol, which will temporarily replace Cole's pistol until you select a different suit.The Sharpshooter Detective SuitRockstar WarehouseL.A. Noire T-ShirtL.A. Noire t-shirtL.A. Noire Official SoundtracksThe L.A. Noire soundtrack is full of 40's jazz and blues music. The official soundtrack was released on May 17, 2011.Recorded at Abbey Road by composer Andrew Hale, the soundtrack includes "modern takes on the classic torch songs of the period," as said by Rockstar's announcement of the soundtrack. Throughout the game itself, music helps notify players that clues are around; as they explore, players will hear more than 32 classic jazz tracks from musicians such as Billie Holiday, Dizzy Gillespie, Ella Fitzgerald, Louis Armstrong, and Thelonious Monk.Track No.TitleArtistLength1."Main Theme"Andrew Hale3:062."New Beginning, Pt. 1"Andrew Hale  Simon Hale1:063."New Beginning, Pt. 2"Andrew Hale  Simon Hale1:254."New Beginning, Pt. 3"Andrew Hale  Simon Hale3:185."Minor 9th"Andrew Hale2:506."Pride of the Job, Pt. 1"Andrew Hale  Simon Hale2:387."Pride of the Job, Pt. 2"Andrew Hale  Simon Hale2:328."Noire Clarinet"Andrew Hale2:339."Temptation, Pt. 1"Andrew Hale  Simon Hale1:1410."Temptation, Pt. 2"Andrew Hale  Simon Hale2:1211."Temptation, Pt. 3"Andrew Hale  Simon Hale0:5212."J.J."Andrew Hale  Fly1:3013."Redemption, Pt. 1"Andrew Hale  Simon Hale1:0714."Redemption, Pt. 2"Andrew Hale  Simon Hale2:2815."Redemption, Pt. 3"Andrew Hale  Simon Hale1:2116."Slow Brood"Andrew Hale  Simon Hale2:2017."Use and Abuse, Pt. 1"Andrew Hale  Simon Hale1:2618."Use and Abuse, Pt. 2"Andrew Hale  Simon Hale0:4919."Use and Abuse, Pt. 3"Andrew Hale  Simon Hale0:3820."Use and Abuse, Pt. 4"Andrew Hale  Simon Hale1:2121."Fall from Grace, Pt. 1"Andrew Hale  Simon Hale1:4422."Fall from Grace, Pt. 2"Andrew Hale  Simon Hale1:1323."Murder Brood, Pt. 1"Andrew Hale  Simon Hale2:3424."Murder Brood, Pt. 2"Andrew Hale  Simon Hale2:1825."Main Theme (Redux)"Andrew Hale1:2526."(I Always Kill) The Things I Love"Claudia Brcken  The Real Tuesday Weld2:5527."Guilty"Claudia Brcken  The Real Tuesday Weld2:1428."Torched Song"Claudia Brcken  The Real Tuesday Weld4:12Total length:55:21L.A. Noire: RemixedL.A. Noire: Remixed is a remixed EP of six jazz standards reinterpreted by modern DJs, producers and remixers.Track No.TitleArtistLength1.Stone Cold Dead in the Market (Ticklah Remix)Elle Fitzgerald  Louis Jordan4:162.Hey-Ba-Ba-Re-Bop (Midnight Sun Remix)Lionel Hampton  His Orchestra5:563.A Slick Chick (On the Mellow Side) (Maximum Balloon Remix)Dinah Washington2:574.Ain't Nobody Here But Us Chickens (DJ Premier Remix)Louis Jordan2:365.Sing Sing Sing (Truth  Soul Remix)Gene Krupa4:196.That Ol' Devil Called Love (Moodymann Remix)Billie Holiday4:15PC VersionL.A. Noire's PC version, titled L.A. Noire The Complete Edition, was released on November 8th and contains all the DLC released for the console version up to that point.System RequirementsOS: Windows 7 / Windows Vista Service Pack 1 / Windows XP Service Pack 3Intel CPUs: Core 2.2 GHz to Quad Core 3.2GHzAMD CPUs: Dual Core 2.4Ghz to Quad Core 3.2GhzRAM: 2GB to 8GBHard Disk Space: 16GBVideo Card: NVIDIA GeForce 8600 GT 512MB to NVIDIA GeForce GTX 580 1536MB or Radeon HD3000 512MB to Radeon HD 6850 1024MBSound: 100% DirectX 9 CompatibleAddition RequirementsInitial activation requires internet connection and Rockstar Social Club (13+ to register); software installation required including GameShield IronWrap  Patcher; DirectX, and Microsoft's Windows .NET Framework, and Microsoft Visual C++ 2008 SP1 Redistributable Package (x86).</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8804">Condemned: Criminal Origins</game><game id="21304">Heavy Rain</game><game id="20538">Mafia II</game><game id="15879">Mafia</game><game id="41524">Murdered: Soul Suspect</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/4/49957/1807787-la_noire_box_art.jpg</image></root>