<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21544</id><name>Hinterland</name><description>OverviewLoot, level, and build in this RPG/City Builder hybrid. In Hinterland, the objective is to lead a group of peasants to establish a new city in a fantasy kingdom. Players must select which peasants to send out into the wild, brimming with many creatures of myth and folklore, to collect much needed resources to expand their city. Careful decisions must be made, as even the loss of a simple farmer can result in a crisis when the city is in demand of food.GameplayWhen you start a game you customize the basics of your character you choose which class, starting stat, and starting characteristic.In the early game all you can hire are basic farmers but as you get more resources by killing all the enemies inhabiting or surrounding a mine or herb patch you can hire a blacksmith to use the ore from the mine, and a herbaologist to use the herbs. Once you get enough money you can upgrade certain buildings into more productive buildings either to produce more gold or to produce better weapons/potions. Once in a while the king will call unto you for an offering you can either accept the mission or decline it if you decline you lose fame, but if you accept you gain fame which in turn allows more people to visit your town letting you have a bigger selection of people also some people wont join your town unless you have a certain amount of fame.Later in the game you must set up guard posts to fight off the raiders who come and attack your village. Any character can fight but many are only armed with pitchforks making guards useful You lose the game when you run out of food and starve or your fame gets so low that the king loses faith in you and you get fired.The game comes without a tutorial or hint system which makes the first game you play basically a learning game as you learn by example and mistake.The graphics in the game are decent for the age it was build in. The resolution can be scaled up only to 1280 x 1024.FollowersNameDescriptionTrapperTraps food for the villagers.FarmerGrows food for the villagersGuardFights off enemies and makes a good adventuring ally.PriestHeals you , Damages enemies , or increases money made by the villagers.NecromancerSummons dead enemies to fight alongside you.HerbologistMakes potions for you and your adventuring companions to use.BlacksmithMakes weapons or armor for the adventurers and town militia.FletcherMakes bows for the town militia and adventurers.System RequirementsRecommended:Supported OS: Windows® XP or VistaProcessor: 1.8 GHz processor or higherSystem Memory: 512 MB RAM Windows XP® (1 GB for Windows® Vista)Video Card: 64 MB DirectX 8.1 compatible cardHard Disk: 350 MB uncompressed free hard drive space</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20803">Diablo III</game><game id="1119">Diablo II</game><game id="5985">Diablo</game><game id="4736">SimCity 4</game><game id="13760">SimCity 2000</game><game id="18443">SimCity 3000 Unlimited</game><game id="1628">SimCity Societies</game><game id="5559">Fallout 2</game><game id="11704">Fallout</game><game id="8638">Titan Quest</game><game id="13762">Titan Quest: Immortal Throne</game><game id="21594">Slaves to Armok II: Dwarf Fortress</game><game id="11345">Depths of Peril</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2614/203570-teaser10.jpg</image></root>