<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21551</id><name>The Precursors</name><description>OverviewThe Precursors is a role-playing game that blends the elements common to the genre with FPS action, Mech combat and even space simulation. The game takes place in an open world-universe, wherein the player can travel through space and explore a multitude of planets scattered throughout the universe.PlotThe player takes on the role of a young pilot of the humanoid Amarn race. Fresh from the academy, a virtual reality experience sent him to the single Amarn colony planet Goldin to serve his people. Captain Ridiger, a friend of the pilot's late father, becomes a mentor of sorts and offers him his father's old spaceship -- provided he can find a way to power it.Players choose to perform missions for either Ridiger, the civilians, or the bandits on Goldin to acquire the missing power cell for the spaceship, all the while talking and fighting in FPS/RPG hybrid style. With access to a variety of epic weapons and perks, the player and three teammates complete missions in order to uncover a secret of the Precursors, an ancient race that threatens to upset the natural balance of galactic powers.After completing several other missions, the pilot is sent on a more critical quest away from the planet, first to another planet called Gli. An avian race called the Clatz fight among themselves in two factions: the Clatz of the Nest, and the revolutionary Clatz. The next planet to visit is Reandore, which is actually a rocky moon. Here the Empire and Free Traders war against one another.The Precursors, a mythical race of ancient times, have since disappeared leaving behind odd pyramids on many planets and moons. A religious cult on Goldin worships the Precursors' pyramid, while on Reandore a laboratory tries to unluck the secrets of the pyramid.LevelsEach level leads the player on an exciting adventure to faraway, celestial bodies where missions include choosing sides while fighting in intergalactic wars.Geyser RockSandover VillageSentinel BeachForbidden JungleMisty IslandFire CanyonRock VillagePrecursor BasinLost Precursor CityBoggy SwampMountain PassVolcanic CraterSnowy MountainSpider CaveLava TubeGol and Maia's CitadelSystem RequirementsMinimumRecommendedOperating System: Windows 2000/XP/VistaProcessor: Pentium 4 @ 3 GHz Processor / AMD Athlon XP 3000RAM Memory: 1 GBVideo Card: nVidia GeForce 6600 / ATI Radeon x700Sound Card: DirectX 9.0c compatibleDirectX: 9.0cOperating System: Windows 2000/XP/VistaProcessor: Core 2 Duo E6600 2.4GHz Processor / Athlon 64 X2 Dual Core 4800RAM Memory: 1 GBVideo Card: nVidia Geforce 7600 GS / ATI Radeon X1600Sound Card: DirectX 9.0c compatibleDirectX: 9.0c</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21549">White Gold: War in Paradise</game><game id="8197">Boiling Point: Road to Hell</game><game id="18741">Star Wars: Knights of the Old Republic</game><game id="16909">Mass Effect</game><game id="21431">Oddworld: Stranger's Wrath</game><game id="22011">Zeno Clash</game><game id="17386">Vivisector: Beast Within</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/6/62890/1744259-precursors_cover.jpg</image></root>