<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21591</id><name>Combat Arms</name><description> Pre-Release and Final ReleaseCombat Arms got its start May 30th of 2008. Nexon, the games publisher, held a closed beta through FilePlanet that ran for only one week. There were a lot of limitations in the beta such as only having 4 maps and 30 weapons. A pre-open beta was released on June 26th. It was open to the entire public, but still had work to be done until the final release. The pre-open was used to help with the final product of the game. On July 11th, 2008, the game was finally released fully to the public in its final pre-patch form. It came with 4 game modes, and 6 maps.  GameplayCombat Arms is a free-to-play online first person shooter developed and published by Nexon. Players host and join games where they battle each other in a free for all or team-based match, completing objectives to earn experience for ranks and GP to use for updating their soldier with new gear from the shop. Combat Arms features several modes, maps, weapons, and even modifications that players may purchase to customize their gear however they see fit.     Game Modes  Elimination  Two teams face head-to-head racking up as many kills as possible.  One Man Army  Players face off in a free for all match.  Search  Destroy   One team tries to arm a bomb while the other team tries to stop the bomb from being armed.  Capture the Flag  Two teams try to capture the opposing team's flag and return it to their base while defending their own flag.  Snowball Fight  A significantly different mode from the other modes. This features lives although not per person. The team shares a certain number of lives and with each death you lose one. Once you die and your team is at 0 you cannot respawn. The mode can only be played on the two snowball stages, snow valley, and cold seed. You use default weapons given to you which are snowball launchers. Once your health goes down to one you are frozen. To kill someone you have to take out your melee weapon (they always give you the shovel) and beat them with it once to get the kill. Likewise you can thaw your teammates by hitting them. Each save counts as a mission point. Missions are basically a counter of how many times you do a certain thing per game. On capture the flag if you make the capture you get a mission. Mission points get you more exp. Because the system is like this there is a common glitch which is used. On a 2v2 game 1 person on each team shoots the wall and freezes them self repeatedly with their ally standing behind them hitting them repeatedly. This can get you about 300-400 missions per 16 minute match. The value of a mission has not changed because Nexon expected people to save rarely. Although once you pass 255 missions the counter resets to 0, the missions stack. with 300 missions you earn 1.9k experience and the same amount of gp per match. This mode was  terminated on 3/16/09.  Fireteam Mogadishu's military, the Sand Hog, is suspected of illegally supplying weapons to nearby countries and have been placed on the UAF's expulsion list. The local government has refused to take action until UAF headquarters provides concrete evidence. An infiltration team was sent in three days ago and signalled that they had obtained some vital Intel, but they failed to make it to the extraction point. They are believed to be captured or killed. Your mission is to infiltrate the mission area and gather the necessary Intel. If possible, find and rescue the infiltration team.Unlike other missions, this mission is a cooperative based mission. Your team, of up to 8 players, plays against computer controlled enemies. Fallen enemies will drop ammunition and health packs that you can pick up. Your health and ammunition will also be replenished by reaching checkpoints within the mission. If you die, you will respawn when your teammates to advance to the next checkpoint.     This mission unfolds in multiple stages. HQ will transmit information on your mission as it is needed. These transmissions can be seen on the lower middle part of the screen. Target indicators (which look like downward facing triangles) will also show up on your HUD to guide you to your objectives. Also, your current and completed objectives are summarized on the upper left corner of the screen. Mission and objective timers are displayed in the upper middle portion of the screen underneath your score counter. Complete all of the stages before the mission timer runs out in order to win the mission.  FIRETEAM MODE SAND HOG MAP   The Fireteam Mode Sand Hog Map is divided into 4 sectors:   • Sector 1 - Insertion route   • Sector 2 - The Temple   • Sector 3 - The Road   • Sector 4 - The Town   Sector 1 - Insertion route  Sector 2 - The Temple  Sector 3 - The Road  Sector 4 - The Town  Quarantine Mode The physiological stress and fatigue caused by the ongoing war has left soldiers deserting in droves and showing a lack of respect for their superior officers. In a controversial step to boost mercenary morale, high ranking officers authorized development of a stamina drug using a promising new organic sample. When the final product was being prepared for mass production, the first and only surviving test subject had an abnormal and untested dosage enter their bloodstream. The cause of the accident has yet to be determined, but shortly thereafter, the local security response team sent transmissions warning of a severe physical threat and potential outbreak situation. Before the transmissions were abruptly terminated, they alluded to the remainder of the drug sample left intact in the research centre. The research centre has been shut down by the Automatic Quarantine System, and an infiltration mission by Special Forces has been called upon in order to retrieve the drug sample.  At the beginning of the game, one or more players will be randomly selected as one of the Infected.  Infected Team:   Your mission is to infect as many humans as possible. Hit a human with a melee attack in order to infect them. Infect all humans to win the mission.   Human Team:   Your mission is to survive. You survive either when the mission timer runs out or you destroy all of the Infected.     Maps   Warhead  Pump Jack  Gray Hammer  Snow Valley  Junk Flea  Cold Seed  Two Towers  Brushwood  Waverider  Desert Thunder [Fireteam Only] Power Surge  Showdown Overdose [Quarantine Only]    Ranks    Players obtain experience by defeating opponents and completing game mode objectives. When players earn enough experience, they increase in rank. As a player's rank increase, more items from the shop are unlocked for players to purchase. Grunts  Trainee  Recruit  Private  Private First Class  Corporal  Sergeant  Field Officers  Staff Sergeant 1, 2 and 3  Sergeant First Class 1, 2 and 3  Master Sergeant 1, 2, 3 and 4  Command Sergeant Major 1, 2, 3, 4 and 5  Commissioned Officers   Second Lieutenant 1, 2, 3, 4 and 5  First Lieutenant 1, 2, 3, 4 and 5  Captain 1, 2, 3, 4 and 5 Command Officers   Major 1, 2, 3, 4 and 5  Major Colonel 1, 2, 3, 4 and 5  Colonel 1, 2, 3, 4 and 5  Generals   Brigadier General  Major GeneralOnly one hundred players may hold this rank.  Lieutenant GeneralOnly ten players may hold this rank.  GeneralOnly three players may hold this rank.      General of the Army         Only one player may hold this rank.  Gear   Players may purchase gear from the shop using GP earned from battle. There are five categories for which gear may be purchased for.   Primary Weapon  Secondary Weapon  Melee Weapon  Miscellaneous  Backpack   Primary Weapon The primary weapon slot includes assault rifles, machine guns, submachine guns and sniper rifles. Assault Rifles  M-16A3  AK-47  M4A1  G36E  MK16 SCAR-L  AUG-A1  AK-74U  K2  SCAR-L BLACK  M4A1 CQBR  AK-103  M14  FAMAS  M416  AK103  AK103 Gold Plated  M416 CQB  M4A1 SOPMOD  G36KE  G36D  Grenade Launcher [Specialist ONLY]    Machine Guns   M60  MINIMI  MK.48  K3  K3 SPW  M60 Steel Plated Submachine Guns   K1A  MP5A4  UZI  UMP  K7  MP5 RAS  MAC-10  P90 Sniper Rifles   M24  SR25  L96A1  MSG-90  M24 WOODLAND  L96A1 GHILLIE  SR25 SANDFIRE  L96A1 Super Magnum    Secondary Weapons  The secondary weapon slot includes pistols and shotguns.  Pistols   M92FS  G23  M1911 MEU  USP  K5  M92F SE  G23 SE  USP TACTICAL  ANACONDA BLACK Shotguns  M590 MILITARY  SPAS-12  R870  M590 CQB  SPAS-12 STOCK  SPAS-12  Stoke   Melee Weapon The melee weapon slot includes melee weapons.  Melee Weapons  M9  G.I. SHOVEL  SICKLE  Tomahawk   Miscellaneous The miscellanous slot includes grenades and support weapons.  Grenades   M67  XM-84  M-23F  G7A  M18  M69HE FRAG  Claymore [Specialist ONLY]  Support Weapons    SA-18  LAW  HB Detector  Sat Scan [Specialist ONLY]  Med KIT [Specialist ONLY]  HB SENSOR  Specialist on the June patch Combat Arms was introduced SpecialistSpecialist are special mercenarywith access to exclusive gear you unlock these once you hit 1st LT </description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22609">Soldier Front</game><game id="9993">Halo 3</game><game id="2600">Halo: Combat Evolved</game><game id="22218">WarRock</game><game id="2133">Call of Duty 4: Modern Warfare</game><game id="16866">Battlefield 2</game><game id="13029">Battlefield 2: Special Forces</game><game id="21646">Battlefield 2: Modern Combat</game><game id="11663">Half-Life: Counter-Strike</game><game id="5722">Counter-Strike: Condition Zero</game><game id="11339">Counter-Strike: Source</game><game id="24699">America's Army 3</game><game id="7334">Crossfire</game><game id="29463">Alliance of Valiant Arms</game><game id="20989">CrimeCraft</game><game id="40582">Mission Against Terror</game><game id="40583">Operation 7</game><game id="33265">Project Blackout</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2120431-box_carms.png</image></root>