<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21598</id><name>THE iDOLM@STER</name><description>OverviewThe Idolmaster, also romanized as THE iDOLM@STER, is a rhythm and simulation game by Namco Bandai originally released as an arcade game and later brought to the Xbox 360 platform. The entire game focuses around ten Japanese girls and their career as famous pop idols. Their career is in the hands of the player who takes the role of the producer for the fictional 765 Production Studio, who can be kind and protective of the girls (but also a little perverted if he so desires).Gameplay MechanicsAn Idolmaster PerformanceEach idol has different statistics, which are important for dealing with her personality or the style she will perform in. After choosing an idol to work with, the player is able to talk with the idol. The answers that are chosen can give a positive or negative effect on the attitude towards the player from the idols. After this, the game is divided by days, which in turn are divided in activities for the idol throughout the day. The first stage of every day is entirely optional, and involves sculpting the idol's image such as choosing songs to practice or changing her costume. Many types of clothes are available ranging from cute and girly, cool and sexy to cosmic and funny outfits. In addition, the player is able to accessorize the idol. The clothes and accessories the idol wears can have a major impact on her statistics, allowing her to perform better and feel more confident. After this, the idol can start her training which are a series of mini games to raise the idol's statistics.The most important part of the game are the auditions, which are composed out of another series of mini games. By performing well in the mini games, the player can improve the idol's performance and impress the judges. After the audition is completed successfully, the player is able to watch and record the entire performance.MusicTHE iDOLM@STER features many original Japanese pop tracks, each song can be sung solo or by up to three different idols. Because of the popularity of THE iDOLM@STER in Japan, several soundtrack CD's and collections have appeared on the market, such as THE iDOLM@STER Master Box, Drama CD's and a Christmas album. Each idol has its own solo album as well, featuring the idol's most favorite songs.PSP VersionsThe arcade version of the game will be ported to the PSP and released in 3 separate versions, each with their own exclusive characters. Perfect Sun has been fan-translated and is currently one of the few games in the series to be available in English (and the only one unofficially). Here's a list of what version contains which girls:The iDOLM@STER SP: Wandering StarYukiho HagiwaraIori MinaseAmi FutamiMami FutamiThe iDOLM@STER SP: Perfect SunHaruka AmamiYayoi TakatsukiMakoto KikuchiThe iDOLM@STER SP: Missing MoonChihaya KisaragiAzusa MiuraRitsuko AkizukiOther games for the PSP include the Shiny Festa games, which had been released in English on April 22nd, 2013 (although with different titles) on iTunes. Here's a list of what game contains each idol:The iDOLM@STER Shiny Festa: Rhythmic Record (Originally called "Funky Note") Ami FutamiMami FutamiYayoi TakatsukiIori MinaseHibiki GanahaThe iDOLM@STER Shiny Festa: Harmonic Score (Originally called "Honey Sound")Chihaya KisaragiHaruka AmamiRitsuko AkizukiAzusa MiuraThe iDOLM@STER Shiny Festa: Melodic Disc (Originally "Funky Note")Miki HoshiiYukiho HagiwaraMakoto KikuchiTakane Shijou</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="254">Moero! Nekketsu Rhythm Damashii Osu! Tatakae! Ouendan 2</game><game id="24131">Princess on Ice</game><game id="23814">Princess Maker 4</game><game id="23815">Princess Maker 5</game><game id="23769">Hatsune Miku: Project DIVA</game><game id="24976">Happy Dance Collection</game><game id="25500">Dream C Club</game><game id="25668">Rockin' Pretty</game><game id="29590">Lucky Star: Net Idol Meister</game><game id="30355">Hatsune Miku: Project DIVA 2nd</game><game id="30356">Hatsune Miku: Project DIVA Arcade</game><game id="32673">AKB1/48 Idol to Koishitara</game><game id="32854">Dream C Club Zero</game><game id="32699">Gal Gun</game><game id="41923">Kami Jigen Idol Neptune PP</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/112/759525-display.jpg</image></root>