<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21646</id><name>Battlefield 2: Modern Combat</name><description>OverviewBattlefield 2: Modern Combat is a modern military first-person shooter developed by DICE and published by EA for the Xbox and PlayStation 2 on October 24, 2005. The first game in the Battlefield franchise to be released on consoles, the game is based on Battlefield 2 for the PC (though it is not a straight port). Along with a new single-player campaign (the first Battlefield game to do so), Battlefield 2: Modern Combat supports online and LAN multiplayer for up to 24 players, with two game modes (Capture The Flag and Conquest) and 17 maps to choose from. All the maps are exclusive for the console game, they are not the same maps as in Battlefield 2 on PC.Similar to Halo 2, Battlefield 2: Modern Combat allows players to create and join clans, where clan leaders can customize their clan (name, tag, and motto), promote regular players to "co-leaders" for member management, and participate in clan battles (two-round matches that ties into a specialized "clan leaderboard").The game was later ported to the Xbox 360 on April 11, 2006, featuring graphical improvements and improved Xbox LIVE functionality. A PSP version had also been announced, but was cancelled to let DICE focus on the game's spiritual sequel, Battlefield: Bad Company.PlotThe singleplayer campaign focuses on a war between the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) and China which takes place in Kazakhstan. Propaganda is being broadcast which accuses both sides of war crimes, mean while the player is switching between sides fighting for each one. Eventually the player chooses a side to fight the war with who is then victorious in the war. A terrorist organization, named the Burning Flag, reveal that they were responsible for causing the war between NATO and China. The winning side of the war now must fight against the Burning Flag and stop Commander 31, the Burning Flag leader, from launching nuclear missiles.MultiplayerMultiplayer mode is similar to that of Battlefield 2 for the PC, it has two gamemodes; Conquest and Capture the Flag.Conquest ModeConquest is almost the same mode used in Battlefield 2. Both sides, the United States Marine Corps (USMC) and the Middle Eastern Coalition (MEC), have a ticket counter which starts at a set number. They must capture some of the several flags scattered across the map so that they run down the enemy team's ticket counter; the team who's ticket counter hits 0 first loses the round. Ticket counters are reduced by 1 for each time a player spawns after a death however there is also a reduction based on how many flags a team owns. If a team owns the majority of the flags, the enemy team's ticket counter will reduce faster then the team with more flags and vice versa; if both teams have an equal amount of flags then neither side's ticket counter will drop apart from player deaths. All vehicles are available from the start in Conquest mode.Player with a shotgun outMaps vary from who owns what control point at the beginning of the round. Some maps start with a team only in control of their own spawn point whilst other maps start with one team owning a permanent un-capturable control point however the other team start with all the other capture points.Capture the FlagCapture the Flag takes place on a smaller version of maps which means less vehicles and closer infantry combat. Each team holds a flag in their spawn point which the enemy team must capture to win. A player picks up a flag by walking over it, he must then carry it to his own base to receive a flag capture point. The flag is returned to a team's base by killing the person holding it and then walking over their own flag.SoundtrackBF Menu MusicHeadshotEnd of the LineBunker BustAir Traffic ControlHeavy TonnageZone 2 ChinaBig BangChina FinalChopper Catching FlakDefend the VillagesHelicopter ReconNATO FinalRiver MissionXbox 360 Game InstallationBattlefield 2: Modern Combat requires 6.6GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD.Xbox 360 Games on DemandOn November 3, 2009, Battlefield 2: Modern Combat became available on the Xbox 360's Games on Demand service. It costs $19.99 or 1600 Microsoft Points.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19654">Frontlines: Fuel of War</game><game id="18883">Enemy Territory: Quake Wars</game><game id="7747">John Romero's Daikatana</game><game id="22218">WarRock</game><game id="21912">Planetside: Core Combat</game><game id="7094">Star Wars: Battlefront II</game><game id="16711">Call of Duty 2: Big Red One</game><game id="21591">Combat Arms</game><game id="24949">Star Wars: Battlefront III</game><game id="1576">Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon: Jungle Storm</game><game id="4530">Greg Hastings' Tournament Paintball MAX'D</game><game id="7524">Call of Duty 3</game><game id="10228">Medal of Honor: European Assault</game><game id="16752">Medal of Honor: Rising Sun</game><game id="17246">TimeSplitters 2</game><game id="12311">Delta Force: Black Hawk Down - Team Sabre</game><game id="21116">MAG</game><game id="1986">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six: Vegas 2</game><game id="29221">Call of Duty: Modern Warfare Reflex Edition</game><game id="29463">Alliance of Valiant Arms</game><game id="16742">Wargasm</game><game id="2078">Mobile Forces</game><game id="38039">Call of Duty: Black Ops II</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1897517-box_bf2mc.png</image></root>