<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21688</id><name>Charlie's Angels</name><description>Overview Charlie's Angels is an action/adventure game developed by Neko Entertainment. It was released at the same time as the second   Charlie's Angels movie, Charlie's Angels: Full Throttle. The game features the likeness of Cameron Diaz as well as Drew Barrymore and Lucy Liu. Despite being licensed after the second movie in the Charlie's Angels franchise, the game's plot centers around the disappearance of the world's national monuments, starting with the Statue of Liberty. Gameplay The game is set in many different locations ranging from Alaska to Mexico across 18 missions. One of the game's key features is the ability to switch from angel to angel on the fly. By pressing start, you bring up a menu that lets you choose which angel you want to play as. This feature comes into play when solving puzzles and to defeat different enemies as each girl has different abilities. The game's combat system centers around combos, melee and ranged attacks. Melee centers around two buttons (X and Square on the PS2) letting you chain combos (combos that only become available after the first level). Shooting is done thanks to a lock-on system. Chaining combos lets you build up a focus meter which triggers bullet time. Levels are structured in the following way. First you enter an area where enemies spawn, this triggers the area being locked off by invisible walls. You defeat the enemies and leave the area which is locked off by invisible walls forcing you to move forward. You enter another area and the cycle repeats. Reception The game is infamous for its negative reviews and is considered as one of the worst movie licensed games ever. It was panned for its poor graphics and uninspired gameplay.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3777">Catwoman</game><game id="35555">Blackwater</game><game id="33280">Beverly Hills Cop</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2151942-box_cangels.png</image></root>