<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21705</id><name>DoDonPachi</name><description>OverviewDoDonPachi is a vertical scrolling shooting game (otherwise known as a shmup) created by the Japanese developer Cave. It was initially released for the arcades, but was ported to the Playstation and Saturn (In Japan only). It is also available on the Xbox 360 as an unlockable Kinect enabled bonus through Cave's visual novel Instant Brain.GameplayThe player fights against massive swarms of enemies and over the top bosses that fill the screen with stylized bullet patterns. To succeed at this game the player must expertly dodge the massive steam of bullets while chain killing the enemies for score. This chain killing mechanic is a central part of the game. Where a player must keep his Chain Counter Gauge full (in the top left of the screen) by constantly killing enemies and damaging bosses. Bonus Score is added based on constantly keeping this gauge filled. Achieving this bonus is necessary for high level play and to unlock the secret second loop.Ships  WeaponsWhen the player starts the game he has a choice of 3 different ships, each with their own unique main weapon (Activated by tapping the fire button).Ship Types:Type A (Red): Fires a concentrated stream of bullets that does more damage but has trouble dealing with very large groups.Type B (Green): Fires a stream of bullets forward but the edges of the stream also fires in the direction you are pointing the arcade stick.Type C (Blue): Fires in a fan shape that covers a large amount of the screen but does less damage then the other ships.In addition to the main weapons each ship can activate a narrow stream of fire that does more damage to a single target (Holding down the fire button). However it lowers the player's maneuverability considerably.Each ship also has a limited amount of bombs in case of emergency. If a player is using their main gun, the bomb clears all of the bullets and damages every enemy on the screen. When the player uses their narrow stream of fire, the bomb makes the narrow fire extremely powerful and gives the player a limited invincibility.LevelsThere are 6 levels to the game which can be looped if certain conditions are met:You don't Lose more then 2 Lives.You Complete the game with 1 Credit.Score atleast 50 million points by the end of the 6 Level.Collect all 13 bee power ups in 4 of the 6 levels.A maximum hit count depending of the ship type (Type A - 270 hits; Type B - 300 hits; Type C - 330 hits).The Second Loop has the same levels as before, however the enemies fire is greatly increased and is the only way to get the true ending of the game.</description><genres><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12069">Ikaruga</game><game id="413">Raiden III</game><game id="7474">R-Type Final</game><game id="20868">Castle of Shikigami III</game><game id="15508">Gradius</game><game id="22550">DonPachi</game><game id="22412">Dangun Feveron</game><game id="22919">Battle Garegga</game><game id="20755">19XX: The War Against Destiny</game><game id="25828">Ray Crisis</game><game id="30001">Espgaluda II Black Label</game><game id="28233">Progear</game><game id="30997">Ketsui: Kizuna Jigoku Tachi Extra</game><game id="32381">Pink Sweets ~Ibara Sorekara~</game><game id="33654">Vasara</game><game id="33655">Vasara 2</game><game id="33885">Muchi Muchi Pork!</game><game id="34237">Ketsui: Kizuna Jigoku Tachi</game><game id="34001">Crimzon Clover</game><game id="34268">Mushihime-sama Futari Black Label</game><game id="35611">Jamestown: Legend of the Lost Colony</game><game id="34222">Instant Brain</game><game id="37143">R-Shark</game><game id="29473">Batsugun</game><game id="42420">Raiden Fighters</game><game id="42421">Raiden Fighters 2</game><game id="42422">Raiden Fighters Jet</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14912/771855-dodonpachi.jpg</image></root>