<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21729</id><name>Cities XL</name><description>OverviewCities XL was a city builder patterned after SimCity and developed by now-defunct French studio Monte Cristo. The game was positioned as the first online city builder, and though it offered a single player mode, the subscription-based multiplayer mode called "Planet Offer" was necessary to unlock most of the gameplay.After poor sales and customer reaction, the game's servers were shut down on March 8, 2010. Monte Cristo itself went under in May of the same year. The game's code and IP were bought by fellow French publisher Focus Home Interactive, who went on to try to patch some of the game's online features out and rerelease the game, with some added art assets, as Cities XL 2011 and Cities XL 2012.ReceptionGarnering an unimpressive 69 at Metacritic, Cities XL was taken to task for its bland graphics, uninspiring gameplay, poor UI, incomplete features, and the inescapable online subscription fee. Giant Bomb itself did not give the game a review.Planet OfferThe subscription service included:Trading resources with other live players,Cooperating with other players to build huge "Mega Structures" from Blueprints won in lotteriesA web-based city and player profile page with messaging and trade contract management.Subscription Costs1 month - 7 Euros (approximately $10 USD)3 months - 5 Euros (approximately $7 USD per month)6 months - 4.5 Euros (approximately $6 USD per month)System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows XP SP3 or Windows Vista SP1Processor: Intel Pentium IV 2.5Ghz or AMD equivalent or betterRAM Memory: 1GB (XP), 1.5GB (Vista)Graphics Card: NVIDIA GeForce 6600 GT/ ATI Radeon X1600 or better, 256 MB RAMDirectX®: DirectX 9.0cHard Drive Space: 8 GBSound Card: DirectX 9.0c compatible</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4736">SimCity 4</game><game id="13657">City Life</game><game id="1628">SimCity Societies</game><game id="20960">SimCity Creator</game><game id="18443">SimCity 3000 Unlimited</game><game id="10733">SimCity 3000</game><game id="13760">SimCity 2000</game><game id="15035">SimCity</game><game id="19170">Caesar IV</game><game id="6645">Caesar III</game><game id="5652">Caesar II</game><game id="8592">Caesar</game><game id="17680">Pharaoh</game><game id="24980">Grand Ages: Rome</game><game id="23783">SimAnimals</game><game id="32401">Cities In Motion</game><game id="34703">Anno 2070</game><game id="18584">StarPeace</game><game id="38803">SimCity Social</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2452874-box_cxl.png</image></root>