<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21746</id><name>Dance Dance Revolution SuperNOVA 2</name><description>Song ListAnd Then We Kiss (Junkie XL Mix) - Britney SpearsAngelus - Hitomi ShimataniBeginning of the End - Klayton (Celldweller)Can't Stop the Rain - CascadaDream of Love - Kaori NishinaEternus - Sanxion7Every Little Step - Bobby BrownFaster Kill Pussycat - Paul Oakenfold featuring Brittany MurphyFevah - NightridersGot to be Real - Cheryl LynnHe Said She Said - Ashley TisdaleJust a Girl (Radio Edit) - Ian Van DahlLe Freak - ChicLove On My Mind (Radio Mix) - Freemasons featuring Amanda WilsonNumber 1 (Alan Braxe  Fred Falke Main Remix) - GoldfrappRock Your Body - Justin TimberlakeSay Goodbye - Chris BrownStrict Machine - GoldfrappSuddenly I See - KT TunstallTake On Me - AhaTemperature - Sean PaulThe Rockafeller Skank - Fatboy SlimThe World Around Me - DJ MicroUnbelievable - EMFUntil Forever - BeatdropUnwritten (Vicious Club Mix) - Natasha BedingfieldVolcano - Yasuhiro AbeWind It Up (Original Neptunes Mix) - Gwen StefaniA Thing Called Love - D-crew 2 USArrabbiata - Reven-G AlterativeDazzle - Kobo featuring KR:agueElectrified - SySF.Every Day, Every Night (NM Style) - Lea Drop featuring Ant JohnstonFire - Mutsuhiko IzumiFreeway Shuffle - DJ TakaMalacca  - NC featuring NRG FactoryMusic in the Rhythm  - NC featuring Electric TouchRaspberry♥Heart (English version) - Jun featuring Paula TerryStars★★★ (Re-tuned by Hal) (DDR Edition) - TerraVem Brincar - Caldeira feat.Téka PentericheBaby's Tears (Sky Girls Opening Theme) - Riyu KosakaBag - RevengBaila! Baila! - Dandy MineiroBallad For You - NM featuring Thomas HowardCalico Cat Rock - Anettai Maji-Ska BakudanCachaca - Mokky de Yah Yah'sCrash! - Mr. Brian  The Final BandDanDanDo (The True Man's Road) - Des-Row·UnitedDragon Blade - Kozo NakamuraE-motion - E.O.SFeelings Won't Fade (Extend Trance Mix) - SySF.Flowers - TerraHoney♂Punch - Riyu KosakaHunting for You - Togo Project featuring Megu  Scotty D.Hyper Eurobeat - Naoki featuring DDR All StarsKiss Kiss Kiss - Naoki featuring ShantiKonoko no Nanatsu no Oiwaini - AsakiLa Bamba - LH Music CreationMondo Street - Orange LoungeMorning Glory - BeForUNijiiro - DJ Yoshitaka featuring G.S.C LicenseOuter Limits - L.E.D.-GRainbow Flyer - DJ TakaSeduction (Vocal Remix) - NC featuring NRG FactorySilver Platform (I Wanna Get Your Heart) - U1 Reincarnates with LeahTrim - KoboUnder the Sky - Sayaka Minami (BeForU) with PlatonixFascination (Eternal Love Mix) - 2MBNGO - Keiichi NabeshimaUnreal - Black Rose GardenTrip Machine Phoenix - De-Sire AlterativeParanoia (Hades) - αType-300</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8743">Pump It Up : Prex 3</game><game id="7010">StepMania</game><game id="23219">Guitar Rising</game><game id="25024">Dance ManiaX 2nd MIX</game><game id="25047">Dance ManiaX 1ST MIX</game><game id="20403">Dance Factory</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2280555-box_ddnsn2.png</image></root>