<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21761</id><name>Metroid</name><description>OverviewMetroid is the first game to be released in the long-running  Metroid series. This game was released in August 1987 for the  Nintendo Entertainment System by  Nintendo RD1,  Intelligent Systems, and  Nintendo. The game was highly regarded for its non-linear, side-scrolling exploration, and spawned dozens upon dozens of imitators, including the well-known and long-running  Castlevania franchise (which helped inspire the term " Metroidvania").Famicom Disk System box artSince its release, Metroid has been ported to a variety of systems, including the  Virtual Console, a  Classic NES Series release on the  Game Boy Advance, a remake under the title  Metroid: Zero Mission, and a release on  3DSWare.The game follows the bounty hunter  Samus Aran, who has been employed by the  Galactic Federation to retrieve a shipment of a highly dangerous species known as " Metroids" after it has been stolen by  Space Pirates (an alien race led by the sentient " Mother Brain" creature). Metroid takes place on the planet of  Zebes, where Samus traverses the planet and manages to trigger the self-destruct function to destroy Mother Brain and escape the planet.Metroid was directed by  Gunpei Yokoi and  Satoru Okada, with music composed by  Hirokazu Tanaka. Other members of the team included  Hiroji Kiyotake,  Hirofumi Matsuoka, and  Yoshio Sakamoto.GameplayThe gameplay of the original Metroid is defined as very stiff, which makes the game very difficult. You can fire with B and jump with A, or the inner and outer buttons respectively. Samus can fire either up or sideways, which is very limiting; later installments allow you to fire in a third direction, directly down. Later installments allow diagonal firing as well. Instead of allowing players to fire down, one press down on the directional pad forces the player into Morph Ball mode, which is acquired at the very beginning of the game.Players can expand their arsenal through various upgrades picked up in the game. At the very beginning of the game you are very weak, and each power up makes you more powerful with items that let you increase how far you shoot, how high you jump, and how much damage you take. Metroid was one of the first games to provide players an open world with a side-scrolling perspective, which was very daunting since it provided very little in terms of direction. Most games at the time of its release had players move almost entirely horizontally or vertically and in a single direction. Metroid also has several areas of exploration, which adds further to first time players’ confusion. Each section is separated by a single elevator, and no more than two areas are connected at once outside of Brinstar.Metroid, at least in its North American and European releases, used a complex password system for saving data and progression. This led to some very famous passwords like the infamous Justin Bailey password alongside regular progression passwords that players got after each time they died. The Japanese version of the game for the Famicom Disk System, which was released later, had 3 separate save files akin to The Legend of Zelda and other minor enhancements such as less slowdown and input latency during busy scenes, slightly altered sound effects and improved music, and less predictable AI patterns for certain enemies.Abilities and Power-UpsWith almost every game, there are power ups and pickups. Metroid is no different, and each power up aids you along your quest. Morph BallMorph BallKnown as “Maru Mari”, this is the ability to curl up into a ball and traverse areas that are about half the size of Samus’ sprite in-game. This ability allows you to get around tight corners when falling down shafts as well, and is useful for bomb jumping which is hard to pull off due to the game’s stiff control nature.BombsThese are only usable in Morph Ball mode, and can be used by pressing the same button as the one to fire your arm cannon. Bombs in Metroid are pretty weak, and are only used to open up new areas for most players. In speed runs, they are used to perform bomb jumps, which are particularly tricky in this Metroid game due to the controls and physics in the game. Bombs can also be used to shake Metroids off of you if they become attached to you.High Jump BootsThese allow Samus to jump higher than normal. This allows players to reach areas that were otherwise unreachable, including the end area of the game, unless they are sequence breaking for speed runs. Screw AttackScrew AttackThe Screw Attack is a somersault move that damages enemies that come in contact with Samus while in midair. Samus also flashes colors rapidly while performing this attack. This attack does not damage Metroids and bosses, however. The Screw Attack remains a fan favorite to this day. Varia SuitThe Varia Suit gives the player a 50% boost in defense to all damage. In comparison to other Metroid games where it protects Samus against harsh environments, that is not the case in this game as environmental damage from heated rooms does not exist. The Varia Suit in this game has a white shade of color to it, unlike later Metroid games where it is more orange in color. MissilesThese are a secondary, but more powerful form of weapon that you pickup in the game. Missile packs are usually in groups of five and are scattered throughout the world. In Metroid, for beating the two main bosses, Ridley or Kraid, you are given 75 missiles a piece for defeating each one. Missiles are vital to defeating not only Metroids you meet in Tourian, but the final boss as well as no other weapon will allow you to damage either of these two enemies. Switching to Missiles changes Samus’ suit color to purple. In later games this does not happen, and the color purple is a signature color of the Gravity Suit. Long BeamLong BeamThis beam increases the distance in which Samus fires her beam weapon. Originally the Power Beam only goes about as far as Samus herself vertically, but this item extends that length considerably, making it not only easier to defeat enemies, but keep Samus from losing a lot of health at the same time as well. In later Metroid games, it is assumed you automatically have the Long Beam as your standard weapon. Ice BeamThis beam allows Samus to freeze enemies for a short period of time. This allows the player to use them as platforms or avoid them entirely. When used as platforms, players can use them to skip portions of the game that are otherwise required to beat the game. The Ice Beam is necessary to freeze Metroids in Turian in order to deal with them in a swift manner. Wave BeamThis beam changes the way in which Samus’ beam fires. Instead of a straight line, it becomes a curvy line, so it now has some verticality to it. In addition, it can also fire through walls and stacks on top of your previous beams. Energy TankEnergy TankThese increase Samus’ health by 100 for each one you pickup. Originally you start the game with only 30 health, even though your maximum health at that point in time is 99. Automatically refills health to maximum upon pickup. Getting these are vital to survival throughout the game as damage can be drained rather quickly by some enemies and hazards. There are eight of these tanks spread throughout the game.Areas on ZebesThere are total of five areas on Zebes in this game. The majority of the areas only have a single way in or out, except for Brinstar which acts as the game’s hub world per se. BrinstarThe complete mapThis is the opening area of the game, and is mainly blue in color. While not overly difficult to navigate, the majority of your useful power ups are located here, including the Long Beam, the Morph Ball, the Morph Ball Bomb, the Varia Suit, and the Ice Beam. NorfairThis is the game’s fire world, while it’s not that noticeable while playing the game, most of the environments are rock and lava based. There’s not much in terms of mechanical or man-made environments here. This area is mainly a pre-cursor to Ridley, where the second main boss is. Kraid's LairThis area is made almost exclusively for the purpose of facing the area’s boss, Kraid. Kraid is a tiny tortoise demon that shoots spikes. Kraid’s size is much, much smaller in comparison to later Metroid games where he is nearly two screens tall. While the area contains no meaningful upgrades besides a few Energy Tanks and Missile Packs, defeating the boss is one of the keys necessary to opening the path to the final area.RidleyThis area is made exclusively for the purpose of facing the area’s boss, Ridley. Ridley is a winged, fire breathing Purple Dragon that jumps up and down. Like Kraid, Ridley’s size is similar to Samus in this game, whereas in later games he is double to triple her height. This area once again provides no meaningful upgrades, and beating Ridley is the other key to progressing to the final area of the game, Tourian. TourianThis is the final area of the game, and it is very mechanical in nature. Besides the final boss, there are only 2 types of enemies here, and both are exclusive to the area: Metroids and Zeebeties. Zeebeties are the final boss’s main form of defense and can very easily knock you into a hazard pit if you are not careful, which can lead to a quick demise. Metroids are energy-sucking parasites that are your main enemy throughout this area until you reach the final chamber. Once the final boss is beaten, a self destruction timer starts and requires the player to race to the top of the next shaft to beat the game.BossesMetroid has a total of three bosses across the five areas of the game. All three bosses are required to beat the game unless a player is using sequence breaks to bypass both of the first two bosses. KraidKraid fires either two or three spikes at you at once, any of which will knock you back a good distance and, if not careful, into a hazard. After defeating Kraid, you will receive 75 additional missiles for your trouble. You can also get an Energy Tank hidden in the boss chamber. RidleyRidley jumps up and down and sends fireballs at you. This boss fight can be very hard or very easy depending on the tell enemies give you in the previous room. That room contains enemies that jump at a high or low distance. If they are jumping high, the fight with Ridley will be very easy. If they are jumping low, the fight with Ridley will be very hard. Mother BrainWhile this is the final boss in the game, it is more of an obstacle than anything. Only the Zeebeties are the main problem with this boss as they will constantly knock you back and forth, either delaying the inevitable or sending you to a hazard death at the feet of Mother Brain with no way to climb out. While coming in direct contact with Mother Brain will damage you, it is not that difficult. Due to the concurrent sprite limitations of the NES, freezing Zeebeties with the Ice Beam is highly effective as further Zeebeties will not spawn until the set amount already onscreen have exited, giving the Samus more breathing room to pump missiles into Mother Brain at will. Afterwards, you will have race to the top of the next chamber in order to beat the game. The only obstacle here is your ability to perform precision jumps, otherwise you have the potential to fall a very long way down.Other Characters Samus AranSamus AranSamus Aran is a bounty hunter sent by the  Galactic Federation on a mission to destroy the  Metroids and the  Space Pirates on their base of operations, Zebeth (or  Zebes as it is called in the later games). During her infancy, Samus's home planet K-2L was attacked by Space Pirates during a raid that killed her parents . She was orphaned until she was found by the  Chozo, a highly advanced race of bird-like creatures, who brought her up as a skilled athlete and infused her with Chozo blood. Her  Power Suit was designed specifically for her, which protects from a wide array of danger as well as granting Samus unprecedented offensive and athletic ability. Equipped with an  Arm Cannon which can fire self-powered beams of energy, Samus must find various upgrades to her suit during her mission, such as the Ice Beam or Missile Launcher. Other items include the Morph Ball, which turns her suit into a compact mobile sphere. This augment allows Samus to roll between gaps, duck below fire, and drop  bombs. Many  blocks can only be destroyed by bombs, which then can be rolled through to discover a new area. Samus must combine the uses of these and many other power-ups to stop the Space Pirates' plan to mass-produce the dangerous Metroid species and take over the galaxy. MetroidsMetroids are flying parasitic life-forms that originate from the planet  SR-388. They feed by latching onto other creatures and sucking life energy out, quickly killing the victim and enlarging the Metroid as a result. Metroids multiply quickly when exposed to beta rays, making them a very insidious species that poses a threat to the entire galaxy. Space Pirates seek Metroids due to their highly dangerous and destructive potential. Space PiratesSpace Pirates steal from ships under the command of their leader, Mother Brain. Ridley is a high commander of the Space Pirates, he is a dragon like creature that uses his tail to slash and also breathes  fireballs. In many cases, Ridley leads Space Pirates into a raid. Once he killed Samus' parents, he became Samus' arch enemy. He has been living on Zebeth, with the rest of the Space Pirates, and is one of two main  bosses. Kraid, who is also a high ranked Space Pirate, is the other boss in the game. Even though he is relatively small, his original design was to be very big, but because the NES had restricted pixels, this was not possible. In future games, like Super Metroid, he is much bigger, and takes up almost 2 full screens. Space Pirates themselves are human-like, but are reptile looking and have odd shaped hands. They use their hands as weapons, which fire two beams. Their appearance has changed over the course of the series.Speedrunning LegacyMetroid was one of the earliest video games to be released that gave players the freedom to explore a non-linear world. This was also one of the first games that led itself to having a following of people that wanted to beat the game as fast as possible. This continued throughout all of the Metroid games, and became the poster child of the speedrunning community with Metroid Prime. There are several sequence breaking elements in this game that allowed this to happen, and have made their way into other games in the series as well.Bomb JumpingIn Metroid, you could perform a bomb jump by laying a bomb then quickly getting out of Morph Ball mode. When the bomb explodes you will be sent slightly higher and you can perform a regular jump afterwards which will act like you have the High Jump Boots.Skipping BossesIt is entirely possible to only defeat a single boss in Metroid, that being Mother Brain. It involves the ice beam, morph ball mode and bombs, missiles and a stray enemy that must follow you into the progress room that normally forms a bridge for safe passage once both bosses are beaten. This will allow you to attempt freeze the enemy at the end of the platform and proceed to the next door.Freedom of ChoiceWhile the game prefers you defeat Kraid before Ridley, you can defeat Ridley before Kraid. This has led to routes claiming that doing this leads to faster times, although it is entirely dependent on the skill of the player.TriviaMetroid has been ported to the Game Boy Advance twice: as an unlockable in Metroid: Zero Mission and as an Classic NES Series standalone title.Metroid can be unlocked in  Metroid Prime on  GameCube by using the Game Boy Advance Link Cable with Metroid Fusion once it is beaten.In the  Wii Virtual Console version of Metroid, new passwords are useable exclusively in that version.Looking at the Game’s Map as a whole, Mother Brain in Tourian is directly above where you get the Morph Ball in Brinstar.</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14416">Ninja Gaiden II: The Dark Sword of Chaos</game><game id="15154">Kid Icarus</game><game id="14026">Mega Man 2</game><game id="8152">Zillion</game><game id="1850">Ninja Gaiden III: The Ancient Ship of Doom</game><game id="18041">Turrican II: The Final Fight</game><game id="19801">Mega Man X2</game><game id="7391">Mega Man 7</game><game id="16948">Mega Man X3</game><game id="15092">Turrican</game><game id="14216">Castlevania: Symphony of the Night</game><game id="2076">Ghoul School</game><game id="20975">Mega Man 9</game><game id="19934">Scurge: Hive</game><game id="8654">Castlevania: The Adventure</game><game id="24425">Rockman &amp; Forte: Mirai kara no Chousensha</game><game id="7860">Bionic Commando</game><game id="6630">Aquaria</game><game id="4778">Kid Icarus: Of Myths and Monsters</game><game id="4422">Burai Fighter</game><game id="7743">Metal Slug: 2nd Mission</game><game id="2664">Phantom 2040</game><game id="17825">Ninja Gaiden: Shadow</game><game id="8627">Super Star Wars: The Empire Strikes Back</game><game id="26706">Shadow Complex</game><game id="10395">The Goonies II</game><game id="6244">Dynowarz: Destruction of Spondylus</game><game id="14239">Ufouria: The Saga</game><game id="27681">Aztaka</game><game id="1432">Section-Z</game><game id="13711">Obliterator</game><game id="352">Gargoyles</game><game id="30876">FiNCK</game><game id="13132">Mutan Zone</game><game id="18884">Starquake</game><game id="33335">Eternal City</game><game id="12131">Getsu Fuuma Den</game><game id="34940">Terraria</game><game id="27375">Insanely Twisted Shadow Planet</game><game id="36869">UnEpic</game><game id="35147">LaserCat</game><game id="26561">Rygar</game><game id="38501">Poacher</game><game id="38695">The Iconoclasts</game><game id="22517">La-Mulana</game><game id="39609">Esper Boukentai</game><game id="39617">Youkai Yashiki</game><game id="40052">Cosmo Police Galivan</game><game id="20088">Cyborg Hunter</game><game id="25951">Layla</game><game id="40944">Full Bore</game><game id="41748">Space Hunter</game><game id="37673">Guacamelee!</game><game id="42797">Energy</game><game id="39548">Environmental Station Alpha</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2362064-nes_metroid.jpg</image></root>