<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21790</id><name>Gran Turismo 5</name><description>OverviewGran Turismo 5 is the fifth main entry in Polyphony Digital's racing simulation series. The first Gran Turismo for a high definition console, the underlying game engine was completely rewritten to take advantage of the more powerful hardware. The game launched with roughly a thousand licensed cars of all types from around the world, from sports cars and sedans to concept cars and go-karts.At E3 2009 during the Sony conference, Kazunori Yamauchi unveiled a trailer revealing NASCAR and WRC [World Rally Championship] logo, included with clips from both racing spectrums, implying that Gran Turismo 5 will have both NASCAR and WRC licenses included. Daytona International was an included track in Gran Turismo 5: Prologue and rally modes were available in both Gran Turismo 3 and 4.The game is known for its long production cycle and delays, including one final delay announced on October 13th 2010, which teased a "Holiday 2010" release date for a few weeks before finally settling for November 24, 2010.FeaturesGran Turismo 5 is set to feature over 1000 cars (200 premium cars and 800 standard cars) including NASCAR, Formula One, and go-karts20 locations with over 70 variations (including BBC's Top Gear test track)Cosmetic and mechanical damage for standard and premium cars, respectivelyFull interior modeling for premium carsArcade mode3D StereoscopyHead tracking using the PlayStation EyeGT mode (world map, my garage, car dealer, tuning shop, license tests, oil change/car wash)First-person walkabout photo modeGran Turismo TelevisionMuseumOnline - open lobby, text/voice chat, private rooms, online photo/replay albumsYouTube replay integrationCustom soundtracksDolby 5.1 and 7.1 supportOwners of Gran Turismo for PSP can import their cars for use in Arcade mode only.Day/Night cyclesWeather effects (For single player and online modes only.)Track GeneratorStunt ArenasSplit-screenIn-game message boardsPersonal profile pagePremium vs Standard carsPremium Cars200 Premium cars 832 standard 1032 all together.Premium cars will have highly detailed interiors to the point where everything works,Premium cars have two headlight settingsPremium cars have realistic damage including interiors, (Steel and carbon fibre bends and breaks realistically)Premium cars have the undercarriages modeled true to lifeStandard CarsStandard cars have a black silhouette interior view, and windows are tintedStandard cars can't change wheelsStandard cars only have small dents and scratches as visual damageStandard cars are less detailed compared to Premium cars,All CarsAll Cars will have mechanical damageAll cars will be able to roll overAll cars can be tunedSpecial EditionsCollector's EditionAnnounced at $99.99 (MSRP), the Gran Turismo 5 CE contains:Exclusive premium packaging a copy of the game1:43 scale die-cast Nissan GT-R Spec V model car (America only)300 page car guide on tuning/driving tips, future technologies and so fourthGran Turismo branded key chain (America only)Voucher for 5 "Chrome Line" edition carsNumbered certificate of authenticityDynamic PS3 theme5 collectible art cards (Europe only)Commemorative slip case (Europe only)This version is exclusive to America, Asia and Europe.Signature EditionAt a cost of €180.00, the Gran Turismo 5 Signature Edition includes:Sculpted metal box with a Mercedes-Benz SLS AMG "Obsidian Black" paint finish1:43 scale die-cast Mercedes-Benz SLS AMG model car300 page car guide on tuning/driving tips, future technologies and so fourthGran Turismo branded key chainVoucher for 5 "Chrome Line" edition carsVoucher for 6 "Stealth" edition carsGT branded USB keyDynamic PS3 theme (found on the USB key)Polyphony/Mercedes-Benz trailer (also found on the USB key)Coffee table book detailing the cars and tracks of Gran Turismo 5Gran Turismo branded leather walletCompetition entry card to win a real Mercedes-Benz SLS AMG super car*Entry into GT Academy**The Signature Edition is exclusive to Europe, Australia and New Zealand.*Participants of the competition must be over 18 and hold a full driving licence to enter.**Only open to UK, Ireland, Germany, Austria, France, Switzerland, Portugal, Spain, Italy, Sweden, Finland, Denmark, Norway, Greece, Czech Republic, Russia, Poland, Australia, New Zealand, South Africa, UAE and Saudi Arabia. Red Bull X1 PrototypeThe X1 PrototypeThe Red Bull X1 Prototype is a collaboration effort between Polyphony Digital and Red Bull Racing, specially aerodynamics expert Adrian Newey. The car was first hinted at the end of in the E3 2010 trailer, with Sebastien Vettel saying the car can "easily reach 400 km/h on straight away". The X1 Prototype was announced at TGS 2010, with complete pictures of the car have revealed in the November 2010 issue of Car Magazine. Sebastien Vettel drove a virtual lap on the Suzuka Circuit with the vehicle and set a world record on his first lap, clocking in at 1:11.540 (compared to the best lap time Vettel set at the 2010 F1 Japanese Grand Prix, which is 1:30.833). Adrian Newey created the car based on the idea of "If you built the fastest racing car on land, one that throws aside all rules and regulations, what would that car look like, how would it perform, and how would it feel to drive?".This is not the first time Polyphony Digital has collaborated with car manufacturers for real-life projects; the company worked with Nissan many times, namely the GT-R.SoundtrackFollowing the E3 2010 trailer, many fans of the game wanted to know the name of the song featured, yet the track was still untitled. Polyphony Digitial then decided to make a contest to find a name to the song, composed by Daiki Kasho. The winner was a fan from Argentina with "5OUL ON D!SPLAY". The intro song for the North American version is "Planetary (Go!)" by My Chemical Romance, while the theme of Gran Turismo, "Moon Over the Castle", is of course the song used for the intro of the Japanese version.Band of Skulls - "Patterns"Breakbot - "Penelope Pitstop"Calvin Harris - "I'm Not Alone (Deadmau5 Remix)"Camo  Krooked - "Climax"The Chemical Brothers - "Horse Power"Daiki Kasho - "5OUL ON D!SPLAY"DJ Fresh - "Talk Box (GT5 Edit)"Eagles of Death Metal - "I Want You So Hard (Boy's Bad News)"Emika - "Double Edge (GERM Remix)"Friendly Fires - "Hold On"Fuck Buttons - "The Lisbon Menu"The Fucking Eagles - "Gentlemen's Blues"Goose - "Words (Jester Dub) [GT5 Remix]"The Heavy - "No Time (Beats Mix)"Helsinki 78-82 - "Cruising"Hervé - "Blaze It (Reset! Remix)"The Hives - "Nasty Secretary"Hot Hot Heat - "Implosionatic"Jiro Vega - "Aqua (Miles Dyson Remix)"London Elektricity - "Just One Second (Apex Remix)"Lorn - "Cherry Moon"Kele - "Tenderoni"My Chemical Romance - "Planetary (Go!)"Noisia - "Yellow Brick (GT5 Remix)"Plasticines - "Pas avec toi"Pnau - "Baby (Breakbot Remix)"Pop Levi - "Police Sign"Queens of the Stone Age - "The Lost Ark of Keeping a Secret"Rusko - "You're On My Mind Baby"Scorpions - "The Sails of Charon"Scuba - "Latch"Sky Parade - "I Should Be Coming Up (But I Keep Coming Down)"Sub Focus - "Deep Space"Sub Focus - "Follow the Light"Sub Focus - "Rock It (GT5 Edit)"Sunchase - "Keyring"Two Doors Cinema Club - "Undercover Martyn"Them Crooked Vultures - "Scumbag Blues"Vitalic - "Poison Lips"We Are Wolves - "Holding Hands"Whitney - "Blah"Yeah Yeah Yeahs - "Heads Will Roll (Little Vampire Remix)"Besides the liscensed soundtrack, Chinese piano musician Lang Lang recorded classical songs for thegame. Those songs were included on the album "Gran Turismo 5 (The Official Game Soundtrack)", released on November 26th.Franz Linst - Liebestraum No. 1 "Hohe Liebe"Frédéric Chopin - Étude, Op. 10, No. 3 (Transcribed Version in A Major)Johann Sebastian Bach - Air on the G String from Orchestral Suite No. 3Gustav Holst - The Planets, Op. 32 "Jupiter the Bringer of Jollity"Piotr Ilich Tchaikovsky - The Nutcracker No. 14 Pas de deux "Var. II: Danse de la Fée Dragée"Frédéric Chopin - Polonaise, Op. 40, No.1 "Military Polonaise"Ludwig Van Beethoven - "Piano Sonata No. 17 in D Minor, Op. 31, No. 2 "Tempest": III. AllegrettoScott Joplin - "The Entertainer"Frédéric Chopin - Waltz in D-Flat Major, Op. 64, No. 1 "Minute Waltz"Sergei Prokofiev - Piano Sonata No. 7 in B-Flat Major, Op. 83: III. PrecipitatoJohann Sebastian Bach - "Jesus, Joy of Man's Desiring" Chorale from Cantata, BWV 147The game also supports custom soundtracks.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25225">Need for Speed: SHIFT</game><game id="24995">Forza Motorsport 3</game><game id="20936">Ferrari Challenge Trofeo Pirelli</game><game id="24513">DiRT 2</game><game id="20729">GRID</game><game id="33400">Forza Motorsport 4</game><game id="32253">SHIFT 2: Unleashed</game><game id="36993">Project CARS</game><game id="34542">F1 2011</game><game id="36977">RACE Injection</game><game id="27298">rFactor 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1794106-box_gt5.png</image></root>