<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2188</id><name>Knight Rider</name><description>PlotA U.S military base has been raided by terrorists and the player has to hunt them down and defeat them under a strict time limit.OverviewKnight Rider is a transcontinental racing game that also has enemy cars that the player can gun down with KITT's weaponry. At the end of each course is an boss battle encounter with the truck carrying the nuke; doing enough damage causes the truck to drive off. Michael and KITT also have to reach the end of each stage within a strict time-limit; a feature common to racing games at the time.Between stages Michael and his technician Bonnie can upgrade KITT with upgrade points that are occasionally found from friendly trucks on the road. These let KITT do more damage with his weapons, be more durable, be faster and so on. Unfortunately, the one thing KITT can't do in this game is speak.The course the terrorists (and, thus, the game) follows across the North American continent passes through the following cities:Los Angeles, CaliforniaSan Francisco, CaliforniaSeattle, WashingtonSalt Lake City, UtahDenver, ColoradoSt. Louis, MissouriChicago, IllinoisToronto, Ontario (Canada)Boston, MassachusettsNew York, New YorkWashington, DCMiami, FloridaHouston, TexasPhoenix, ArizonaLas Vegas, NevadaLos Angeles (again)TriviaAccording to Activision CEO Bobby Kotick, an intern in the Japanese office sold the rights for Knight Rider to a NES licensee for $400,000. The deal was they got to develop and publish the game in Japan, then Activision could sell that game to publishers everywhere else. The problem was Activision didn't own the rights for Knight Rider. They had to rush out and get after the deal had been made. (Game Informer, Issue 202, February 2010.)</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="36256">Cobalt</game><game id="38459">Spy Hunter</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2361931-nes_knightrider.jpg</image></root>