<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21952</id><name>Killer Instinct 2</name><description>StoryFight!               Eyedol's death at the hands of               Orchid in the previous game accidently set off a time warp sending everyone back 2000 years and allowed              Gargos to escape from Limbo. Now, 2000 years in the past, warriors that survived             Killer Instinct (1) and several new faces fight for the right to face the Demon Lord Gargos in combat. Some, like            T.J. Combo, just want to get home. Others, like Tusk, want to bring an end to Gargos and his reign of evil. This time there is no tournament or prize money, just a fight to the finish with the fate of the future hanging in the balance. One of the more unique aspects of the story was that the ending for your character changed depending on if you pull off a finishing move on any particular characters.  For example, Jago's ending will change depending on if you finish off either Fulgore or Orchid, both of them, or neither of them. GameplayKiller Instinct 2 was the surprise sequel to the obscure sleeper hit at the arcades known as Killer Instinct. All the character sprites and animations were re-done and were completely different from the original KI. Stage backgrounds were done using FMV graphics, and "animated" as characters moved around. It was a much different look than the first KI, and perhaps didn't quite look as good as the original.The game engine is a lot like the original Killer Instinct and certain improvements have added some depth to the gameplay. A new power meter was added to store energy for super moves and super linkers. The auto doubles have been included again, but there is now an option for manual combos. There are also many new moves and changes made to the old characters, although        Riptor,          Cinder, and          Chief Thunder did not return in the sequel. Its only console appearance was on the Nintendo 64 with           Killer Instinct Gold.  New Characters   While the release of Killer Instinct 2 saw the departure of     Riptor,     Cinder, and   Chief Thunder, it did see the addition of 4 new characters:          Kim Wu,         Maya,        Tusk, and       Gargos.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18484">Killer Instinct</game><game id="243">Street Fighter II: The World Warrior</game><game id="15743">Mortal Kombat</game><game id="1434">Mortal Kombat 3</game><game id="2178">Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3</game><game id="19200">Fatal Fury Special</game><game id="2396">Fatal Fury</game><game id="14929">Real Bout Fatal Fury 2: The Newcomers</game><game id="16444">Eternal Champions</game><game id="10614">Killer Instinct Gold</game><game id="22159">Samurai Shodown: Warriors Rage</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="8673">Fighter Destiny 2</game><game id="22362">Street Fighter II': Hyper Fighting</game><game id="21699">The King of Fighters '98 Ultimate Match</game><game id="21519">The King of Fighters XII</game><game id="2374">The King of Fighters Collection: The Orochi Saga</game><game id="20463">SNK Arcade Classics V.1</game><game id="5030">The King of Fighters XI</game><game id="4289">The King of Fighters 2006</game><game id="16200">The King of Fighters: Neowave</game><game id="18037">The King of Fighters '94 Re-bout</game><game id="193">The King of Fighters: Maximum Impact</game><game id="19799">The King of Fighters EX2: Howling Blood</game><game id="18240">The King of Fighters 2003</game><game id="449">The King of Fighters 2001</game><game id="7581">The King of Fighters 2002: Challenge to Ultimate Battle</game><game id="11976">The King of Fighters EX: Neo Blood</game><game id="15728">The King of Fighters 2000</game><game id="13352">The King of Fighters: Evolution</game><game id="6452">The King of Fighters: Dream Match 1999</game><game id="6872">King of Fighters R-2</game><game id="17540">King of Fighters R-1</game><game id="10621">The King of Fighters '98: The Slugfest</game><game id="4124">The King of Fighters '97</game><game id="8146">The King of Fighters '96</game><game id="18568">The King of Fighters '95</game><game id="4249">The King of Fighters '94</game><game id="10476">War Gods</game><game id="18423">ClayFighter 2: Judgement Clay</game><game id="21277">Ultimate Mortal Kombat</game><game id="42896">Killer Instinct</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/7661/658009-ki2logo.jpg</image></root>