<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21974</id><name>Shot Online</name><description>Overview:Shot Online, First and foremost is a fun and enjoyable Golf Sim.  However, you will be advancing your character by earning skill points and purchasing a variety of clubs, equipment and clothing to improve you character's performance on the course.Characters:Belzebuit: Male, 19 Years Old, English.Cold, rebellious but handsome and charismatic, he overwhelms other players despit young age. Because of this he earned his nickname Ice Prince.Erda: Female, 17 Years Old, Italian.Wise and calm. With excellence and modesty, everyone expects her to be the best of the best. Her nickname is Erda, meaning the goodness of wisdom.   Wotan: Male, 19 Years Old, Spanish.Reticent and sincere. His hard work ranks him as one of the top players, desite loss of his one eye in an accident.  His nickanme is Odin. Shaoring: Female, 15 Years Old, Chinese.Cute and outgoing. She usually acts carelessly, but not on the course. She is a lovely girl with a nickname LIttle Sprite.Zygmunt: Male, 18 Years Old, USA.Free-spirited and passionate. He is the only left-handed player in Shot Online.Modes:  Stroke Play:Stroke play is the most common scoring system and can be played with 1-4 players. Players record the sum of the strokes taken during the round. The player who records the lowest score wins.Match Play:In match play, the winner is determined by the hole. UP: wins the hole, DOWN: loses the hole, and HALF: ties the hole. The winner is determined by the player who records an UP by the end of the round. Match play requires 2 players.Scratch:The scoring system is equal to the stroke play, while each player gives or takes NG (Shot Online's Currency) depending on their strokes. Skins:In a skins game, players bet a certain amount of NG on each hole. The player that takes the least amount of storkes for that hole takes the prize NG. If the hole is a tie, the prize NG is carried to the next hole and the winner of that hole takes the accumulated prize money. A skins game requires 2-4 players.Foursome Match Play:Team vs. team match play. Each team has 1 ball and is composed of 2 players. This game requires 4 players.Four-ball Match Play:Team vs. team match play.  Each team is composed of 2 players and each player has a ball.  This game requires 4 players.Mastery Mode:To simulate playing on a real golf course, the TAB key (Indicator) will not work in mastery mode. This stroke game is exclusive to players who are Semi Pro and higher.CCSkins:In a skins game, players bet a certain amount of CC on each hole. The player that takes the least amount of strokes for that hole takes the prize CC. If a hole is a tie, the prize CC is carried to the next hole and the winner of that hole takes the accumulated prize money.   A skins game requires 2-4 players.</description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre><genre id="28">Golf</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9146/269132-f8ba_shot_online.jpg</image></root>