<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21989</id><name>My Pokémon Ranch</name><description>Overview My Pokémon Ranch is a game developed by Nintendo for the Wii's WiiWare service. In  My Pokémon Ranch, you take the role of a rancher who owns a    Pokémon ranch. To get pokémon, you can connect your Nintendo DS to your Wii and then transfer pokémon from  Pokémon Diamond/Pearl. Even if you don't have  Diamond,  Pearl, or even a Nintendo DS, there is a professor in the game who will give you 6 new Pokémon every day. VisualsThe visuals in  My Pokémon Ranch give the Pokémon a cute, almost blocky feel. It implements Miis as your rancher's face. Ranch LevelsIn  My Pokémon Ranch, you can level your ranch to a maximum of 25, which allows you to store a maximum of 1000 Pokémon.  You originally start with a maximum capacity of 20, and can level up your ranch by depositing a specific number of Pokémon that   Hayley, the main character of  My Pokémon Ranch tells you at various times.RewardsMy Pokémon Ranch does have its fair share of rewards based on the number of pokémon you bring to the ranch and bringing wanted pokémon to the ranch.  When the ranch reaches level 15, you can acquire a Phione from Haley by trading her a Leafeon.  At level 25, you can acquire a Mew from Hayley by trading her a pokémon egg. Price and Release My Pokémon Ranch was released on June 9 , 2008 on Wiiware in North America for 1000 Wii points. My Pokémon Ranch was released on March 25, 2008 on Wiiware in Japan. My Pokémon Ranch was released on July 4, 2008 on Wiiware in Europe and Australia.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2731">Mega Man Zero</game><game id="29768">Mega Man Zero Collection</game><game id="9824">Mega Man Battle Network 5: Double Team DS</game><game id="20539">Mega Man Star Force 2</game><game id="21403">Mega Man Star Force 3</game><game id="1476">Mega Man Star Force</game><game id="27178">Welcome Home! Chibi Robo!</game><game id="2866">Super Mario World 2: Yoshi's Island</game><game id="10347">Yoshi's Island DS</game><game id="15207">Yoshi's Story</game><game id="24009">Dragon Quest Monsters 1 &amp; 2</game><game id="31214">LittleBigPlanet 2</game><game id="25422">LittleBigPlanet</game><game id="20602">LittleBigPlanet</game><game id="24354">Magician’s Quest: Mysterious Times</game><game id="23375">Gangway Monsters</game><game id="20046">Yoshi Touch &amp; Go</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/11656/278315-everyonepkmnranch.jpg</image></root>