<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22002</id><name>TinStar</name><description>OverviewTin Star is an old West-style shooting game with     Robots. The main character of the game is a sheriff named    Tin Star sent to East Driftwood to clean up the town. Tagging a long is his trusty side kick named Mo Crash and his horse Aluminum. Tin Star goes to the town of East Driftwood to stop Black Bart, the leader of the Bad Oil Gang.     Gameplay  And keep 'em up.     Acts are replaced with days and in days there are levels called scenes. The game starts on Monday, and goes through until Sunday. At the start of every day is a shooting gallery   minigame. The training consists of trying to keep one or more jugs in the air for as long as possible by shooting the jugs. Every time a jug gets shot, the more more money you receive. The jugs also changes color if they are in the air long enough. If the player waits, the game will change and the player will instead try to juggle the bottles while shooting a target to gain money.   The game play is an  on-rails shooter that is either in first person view or in a 2d mode where you can see Tin Star, but you cannot control him. In this mode Tin Star moves independently, and you can only shoot a enemies on-screen. You will have to protect Tin Star from not only enemy robots, but other hazards like birds, dynamite and other objects. At the end of certain levels there are mini-bosses, which often appear more than once in the game.     One of the boss showdowns.     At the end of the day after several stages, there is a main boss fight which is a one-on-one showdown in the street. This fight consists of the player shooting a cylinder from a revolver from one of the four corners of the screen and then shooting the boss in the middle of the screen.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="35">Light-Gun Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1744">Lethal Enforcers</game><game id="12213">Lethal Enforcers II: Gun Fighters</game><game id="16218">Battle Clash</game><game id="13533">X-Zone</game><game id="2543">Super Scope 6</game><game id="3484">Metal Combat: Falcon's Revenge</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/13/137417/2364750-58_41915_0_tinstar.jpg</image></root>