<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22021</id><name>Star Soldier R</name><description>Overview Star Soldier R is a       vertical scrolling shooter for the      Wii, released through    Nintendo's     WiiWare service. It features two levels, a Quick Shot mode, and   leaderboards. The game was released on May 19, 2008, and is priced at 800 Wii Points ($8).Gameplay Star Soldier R, unlike other shooters, only features two levels which are split between two modes with two different time limits: two- and five-minutes. The former only has the first level due to the time constraint, while the latter feature both levels. Each level is relatively short, with hundreds of enemies coming at you constantly, and features a boss fight at the end of each level. Upon finishing (or dieing in) a level, your score -- which is increased by shooting enemies and whatever else can be shot -- is added up and is posted on the leaderboards. The best way to earn the highest score possible is by making a large chain of kills, which is done by simply shooting everything in sight -- as doing so adds to your combo, and thus earning you a higher score. This applies to the games other mode -- Quick Shot -- as well, to a certain extent. Rather than making your way through a level shooting enemies, this mode gives you twenty seconds to shoot as many objects as possible. However, this mode doesn't feature online leaderboards, and instead opts for an offline score board.</description><genres><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12069">Ikaruga</game><game id="413">Raiden III</game><game id="16952">Radiant Silvergun</game><game id="7474">R-Type Final</game><game id="75">Castle Shikigami 2</game><game id="20937">Gate of Thunder</game><game id="22550">DonPachi</game><game id="25828">Ray Crisis</game><game id="735">Summer Carnival '92: Recca</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/6384/287921-wiiware_starsoldierr.jpg</image></root>