<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22124</id><name>The Silver Lining</name><description>OverviewThe Silver Lining is a fan-created adventure game, continuing the story of King Graham and his family from the King's Quest series. The game is being produced in five free downloadable episodes. Episodes 1 to 4 were released in 2010 and 2011, with the fifth episode presumably being worked on.Main CharactersKing GrahamPrincess RosellaPrince AlexanderPlotKing Graham returns to adventuring after his children Rosella and Alexander fall under a curse. The story delves into the history of the Black Cloak Society which has had its hand in the villainy of most of the series.DevelopmentConceptionThe people behind The Silver Lining, Phoenix Online, have been and continue to be avid adventure fans, more specifically fans of the Kings Quest series. After being disappointed by The Mask of Eternity, the eighth installment of the series which neither stuck to the series' roots nor expanded the ever growing lore involved in the Kingdom of Daventry, they decided to create their own game that will wrap up the loose ends left by this abrupt ending.Legal TroublesOn September 30, 2005, the team was asked to cease production by Vivendi Universal Inc, the then-owners of the King's Quest franchise. After weeks of negotiations and with the support of their fans, on November 29, 2005, Vivendi granted the team permission to legally continue production on the game. They received a second "cease and desist" in February 2010. This time from Activision, the current owners of the King's Quest I.P. Activision eventually retracted the cease and desist order, and issued them a non-commercial license to release the game providing the following terms were met. They have to make it clear that it's not an official sequel or Activision product. That they do not make money from it and that the game is only hosted on their own website. The developers had never intended to go against any of these conditions in the first place so it would appear that they can now continue development unabated.System RequirementsWindows XP, Vista or 71GHz Intel or AMD Processor512 MB RAM (1GB recommended for Vista and 7)100% DirectX compatible video card with 256 MB video RAMDirectX 9.0c+</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9648">King's Quest</game><game id="14195">King's Quest II: Romancing the Throne</game><game id="1256">King's Quest III: To Heir is Human</game><game id="409">King's Quest IV: The Perils of Rosella</game><game id="16771">King's Quest V: Absence Makes the Heart Go Yonder</game><game id="2240">King's Quest VI: Heir Today, Gone Tomorrow</game><game id="10656">Roberta Williams' King's Quest VII: The Princeless Bride</game><game id="36860">Cognition: An Erica Reed Thriller</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/6875/313619-tsltemplate_logo.jpg</image></root>