<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2214</id><name>Nitemare 3D</name><description>Nitemare 3-D is a            re-imagining of the first game in the           Hugo series,  Hugo's House of Horrors. Just as before, when the lovely           Penelope goes missing after entering a supposedly haunted house, her boyfriend          Hugo ventures inside to rescue her. Unlike the original game, in which Hugo saved Penelope by using his wits to solve a series of puzzles, Nitemare 3-D  is a  first-person-shooter, in which Hugo must use violence to kill every monster who stands between him and his love. There are three different weapons to choose from, and unlike most shooters of the day, in which guns differed only in the amount of damage they did and how quickly they fired,  Nitemare 3-D's weapons were actually more or less effective on certain types of enemies.                        Plasma Gun - This experimental weapon, the first one Hugo finds, shoots bolts of pure energy, which do average damage to most kinds of enemies.                       Magic Wand - Although the sparkles it sends out may not look very dangerous, it causes excessive damage to magically-themed creatures like                     witches.           Revolver loaded with      silver bullets - the only               hitscan weapon in the game, the revolver is most useful when you're fighting certain supernatural enemies like                    vampires and                   werewolves. A fourth weapon, the  Auto-Repeat Plasma Gun, was also available, though it was identical to the Plasma Gun in every way (even using the same ammo) apart from being fully automatic.</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7694">Wolfenstein 3D</game><game id="6356">The Catacomb Abyss</game><game id="7326">Doom</game><game id="12274">Catacomb 3-D</game><game id="15567">I.M. Meen</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/17172/1169179-nitebox.jpg</image></root>