<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22156</id><name>Men of War</name><description>GameplayMen of War has very similar gameplay to the previous games from Best Way. Units in MoW are much more detailed than in other RTS games. Each soldier has an inventory, and can pick up weapons from other soldiers who have been killed. Cover is a key part of the gameplay, proving vital for both infantry and tanks. The game also has a physics engine, which allows the enviroment to be destroyed, allowing the creation and destruction of cover. Every vehicle has a weight, giving them momentum. Tanks and artillery pieces have the ability to chose the type of round loaded, depending on the situation. Armor piercing (AP) rounds are able to go through sections of cover or other vehicles and can glance off sloped armour while high explosive (HE) rounds explode on impact and can cause shrapnel damage. Vehicles have a damage system that allows precisely fired rounds to destroy weapons, damage wheels or tracks, knock off turrets and set engines on fire.Men of War brings back "Direct Control" mode. This mode allows players to take control of a single unit's actions. The mouse is used to aim while arrow keys control movement. This allows players to accurately line up important shots or deal with a problem in the AI. Singleplayer MissionsMen of War's singleplayer comprises of 3 campaigns and a set of bonus missions.Russia: The first campaign is from the Russian perspective, starting in 1941 and finishing in 1945. It follows two school friends through several different operations, including battles around Moscow and Sevestapol. It also looks at a selection of operation types ranging from small scale infantry missions, to large scale combined units operations.Germany: The second campaign focuses on the Germans. The missions all take place in the Mediterranean theater, starting with the invasion of Crete by German paratroops. It then proceeds into North Africa.US: The third campaign also takes place in North Africa but come at it from the American perspective. This campaign is more focused on small scale stealth missions MultiplayerMen of War includes a 16 person multiplayer game with a variety of different game modes. In all modes, 4 different sides (UK, USA, Russia and Germany) are can be chosen by the server host for the two sides in the match. Once ingame, each player buys his units with  money and is limited by the CP limit set by the host. More powerful units, like the King Tiger, costs more than light tanks or infanty units. Additionally, 2 units (the KV-2 and the Sturmtiger), are limited to one per player due to the two tanks powerful main gunsThere are 7 different modes:Combat: Effectively team deathmatch. At the end of the game, the team with the most points wins. Obviously, infantry men are worth less points than a tank.Free for All Combat: Combat, but its every man for themselves. Each individual player choses their army at the start. In this mode, it makes sense to find an area on the map and lock it down.Battlezones: Similar to conquest from the Battlefield series, in this mode there are several flag on the map (minimum is 3, but this number will increase if more players join). Team that has the most flag generates points quicker. At the end of the time limit, the side with the most points win.Victory Flag: King of the hill. Single flag in the centre of the map. The team who holds it gets the pointsValuable Cargo: Cargo spawns at several points around the map. Special vehicles based on the mine crawler are the only ones who can move it. Capture it and bring it back to score points. Destroying the crawler results in a new one spawing at the base, so blowing the tracks off it makes more sense. Effectively CTFFrontlines: One side attacks the other defends. Attackers have to capture a series of small flags to unlock a larger flag, which then opens a new area. Defenders can not recapture big flags. Attackers win once they have captured all the big flags. At the end of the game, the teams swap roles. One point to note is that both sides get different units. The defenders reccive lighter units, but have time to setup ambush pointsCooperative: All of the singleplayer missions can also be played in coop, with each player gaining the abilty to revive each others unitsAs well as the gameplay features, Men of War also uses Gamespy for its server browser. When hosting, the host can change a wide variety of options, including money, score limit, friendly fire and flora regeneration. The game also allows players to host games off several locally based servers rather than using their own pc. Additonally, mods are fully intergrated. Multiplayer Units List All sides can call in these infantry units:  Rifleman Squad SMG Squad Machinegunner Anti-tank rifle team (UK and USA cannot call in this unit) Rocket Launcher team Flamethrower Falshrimjaeger/Marines/Commandos/Rangers (Germany/Russia/UK/USA) Assault infantry Engineers (both AP and AT mine layers) Sappers Tank Crew Officer Scout SniperThe vehicles each side can call in are listed below. They are in the order presented on the buy screen.   Vehicle List         GERMANY   SOVIET UNION   UNITED STATES   UNITED KINGDOM     Transport or Procurement             BMW     R12          Kubel     VW82          Sdkfz     251/1          Opel     Blitz 3.6          Opel     Blitz 3.6 (Engineer)          Opel     Blitz 3.6 (Ammo)              M-72          Gaz-67B          M3A1          Zis-5          Zis-5     (Engineer)           Zis-5     (Ammo)              Willys     MB          Willys     AT          M3A1          GMC     CCKW-352          GMC     CCKW-352 (Engineer)           GMC     CCKW-352 (Ammo)              Willys     MB          Dodge     WC-55          M3A1          Bedford     OYD          Bedford     OYD (Engineer)          Bedford     OYD (Ammo)      Artillery             MG34          Flak     38          SGrw     34          Pak     35/36          Pak     40          SIG     33          Hummel          sFH     18          Raketen     Werfer           Panzerwerfer              DS-39     223          PKP     Heavy Machine Gun          BM-37          M-37          Zis-2          Zis-3          D1           Katysusha              .M2     .50 Cal MG          Oerlikon     20mm          M1     Mortar          M3          M8          M5          M7     Priest          M114          M4A3     Calliope              Vickers     MG          Oerlikon     20mm          M1     3" MII Mortar          QF     2pdr          QF     6pdr          QF     17pdr          QF     25pdr          BL     6" 26 CWT          Land     Mattress      Light Armoured Vehicles             Sdkfz     223          Sdkfz     222          Pzkpfw     I Ausf B          Pzkpfw     II Luchs          Sdkfz     7/1          Pz     III Sapper          Sdfkz     234 Puma          Wirbelwind              BA-64          T-26          BA11          T34-Sapper          BT-7A          T-60          T-70          ZSU-37              M20          M16          M8     Greyhound          M4A3     Crab       M19              Damiler     AC Mk1          Mk     VIII Tetrach          M4A3     Crab          Crusader     AA      Medium or Heavy Armoured Vehicles             Pzkpfw     III Ausf J          Pzkpfw     IV Ausf E          Pzkpfw     IV Ausf G          Pzkpfw     IV Ausf H          Pzkpfw     V Panther          Pzkpfw     VI Tiger          Pzkpfw     VI King Tiger              T34/76     ('40)          T34/76     ('43)          T-34/57          KV-1          KV-2          T-34/85          KV-85          IS-1          IS-2          IS-3              M5A1     Stuart          M3     Lee          M24     Chaffee          M4A1     Sherman          M4A2     Sherman          M4A3     E2 Jumbo          Sherman     (76) W          M26     Pershing          T29     (added to MP in 1.113 patch)              Mk     III Valentine          Mk     II Matillda          Mk     VI Crusader          Mk     VIII Cromwell          M4A1     Sherman          Mk     IV Churchill          M4A4     Firefly          Centurion     Mk II      Self Propelled Guns             Hetzer          Stug     IV Ausf G          Nashorn          Jagdpanzer     IV          Jagdpanther          Elefant          Jagdtiger          Sturmtiger     (added to MP in 1.113 patch)              SU-76          Zis-30          SU-85          SU-122          SU-100          ISU-152              M8     Scott          M18     Hellcat          M36     Slugger              Mk     I Bishop          Archer          Achillies     1C          A39     Turtle          System Requirements MinimumOperating System: Microsoft® Windows® XP SP3 / Windows Vista SP1 — This product does not support Windows 95/98/ME/2000/NT or XP x64/Vista x64!Processor: Intel® Pentium 4 3.0 GHz or AMD™ Athlon™ 64 3000 Memory: XP – 1 GB RAM / Vista – 2 GB RAMHard Disk Space: 6.5 GB   1 GB Swap FileVideo Card: 3D Hardware Accelerator Card Required – 100% DirectX 9.0c compatible 128 MB Video Memory. ATI® Radeon® 9600 or Nvidia® GeForce® 5900Sound Card: DirectX® 9.0c compatible sound cardDirectX® Version: DirectX® 9.0cNetwork: Internet(TCP/IP) or LAN play supported Internet play requires broadband connection and latest drivers LAN play requires network interface card with latest drivers RecommendedOperating System: Microsoft® Windows® XP SP3 / Windows Vista SP1 — This product does not support Windows 95/98/ME/2000/NT or XP x64/Vista x64!Processor: Intel® Core 2 Duo 2.33 GHz or AMD® Athlon® 4400 Memory: 2 GB RAMHard Disk Space: 5.5 GB   1 GB Swap FileVideo Card: 256 MB 3D Hardware Accelerator Card with Shader 3.0 support ** - ATI® Radeon® 2600 or Nvidia® GeForce® 8600Sound Card: DirectX® 9.0c compatible sound cardDirectX® Version: DirectX® 9.0cNetwork: Internet(TCP/IP) or LAN play supported Internet play requires broadband connection and latest drivers LAN play requires network interface card with latest drivers     Supported Mobile ChipsetsNVIDIA GEFORCE GO 7900 , NVIDIA GEFORCE GO 7950 and NVIDIA GEFORCE GO 8400    </description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2688">Faces of War</game><game id="6173">Soldiers: Heroes of World War II</game><game id="23293">Theatre of War 2: Africa 1943</game><game id="27937">Men Of War: Red Tide</game><game id="40891">Call to Arms</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1403/530218-men_of_war4976576x.jpg</image></root>