<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22178</id><name>Super Robot Wars A Portable</name><description>Featured SeriesBanpresto Originals* Super Electromagnetic Robot Combattler V Brave Leader Daimos Invincible Steel Man Daitarn 3 Metal Armor Dragonar Getter Robo Getter Robo G Shin Getter Robo  UFO Robot Grendizer Mobile Suit Gundam Mobile Suit Gundam: The 08th MS Team Mobile Suit Gundam 0083: Stardust Memory Mobile Suit Zeta Gundam Mobile Suit Gundam ZZ Mobile Suit Gundam: Char's Counterattack Mobile Fighter G Gundam New Mobile Report Gundam Wing: Endless Waltz Mazinger Z Great Mazinger Martian Successor Nadesico Super Electromagnetic Machine Voltes V Invincible Super Man Zambot 3  (*)Banpresto Originals, are as their name implies, mecha and characters designed by Banpresto themselves for the game.Since this was a remake there were no new series.Changes from Game Boy Advance versionBattle animations and audio (including voice acting) are on par with Super Robot Wars MX, although some graphical quirks from Original Generations are used as well. Most of the BGM is taken directly from MX, Alpha 3, and Original Generations. The Shield HP system is removed, as shields take on a more traditional role. Unique Full Upgrade Bonuses and Ace Bonuses are implemented from Original Generations. Several balance changes were made, including reworked Spirit Command lists, the removal of the V-Up item, and the removal of the Limit stat. The chosen main character no longer receives Gundam-based skills (Newtype/Cyber-Newtype for Axel/Lamia, respectively). Although attack lists are mostly faithful to the GBA version, a handful of new attacks are added, such as Gundam Ez-8's Full Burst and Zambot 3's Ion Cannon. Banpresto Original villain Lemon Browning now pilots her Weiss Saber from Original Generations.  New FeaturesThe game's random number generator has been changed so that repeatedly resetting and reloading the game will not change the outcome of a battle; it is often speculated that this was implimented in order to make the game more difficult. There are still ways around this feature, however. This is the first game that does not penalize the player for losing a unit (usually, the player is charged a "repair cost" at the end of the map). This feature would later be included as part of the "Negotiator" ability in Super Robot Wars Z. </description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23089">Super Robot Wars A</game><game id="3731">Phantom Brave</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/12421/313926-srtap_cover.jpg</image></root>