<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22181</id><name>Silent Hill Experience</name><description>OverviewWelcome to Silent Hill. The Silent Hil Experience takes viewers on a visually stunning and musically awe inspiring ride into the shadowy depths of SIlent Hill. Combining different forms of media including digital comics, music, and video, The Silent Hill Experience provides fans a unique look into the most terrifying video game franchise of all time. ContentsContained on the Silent Hill Experience UMD:Over 2 hours of Digital Comics based on the popular Silent Hill comics series, presented complete with haunting music. Includes the acclaimed comice series Silent Hill: Dying Inside, and a brand new Silent Hill Story, The Hunger. 20 Unforgettable music tracks selcted by the series' producer/sound track compser Akira Yamaoka. Exclusive interview with Christophe Gans, director of the live action Silent Hill film, and video interview with the series' music composer/producer Akira YamaokaRare video content from previous Silent Hill gamesSoundtrackTitle (Game Track Originates From)1. Silent Hill (Silent Hill 1)2. Tears of....(Silent Hill 1)3. Theme of Laura (Silent Hill 2)4. Null Moon (Silent Hill 2)5. Love Psalm (Silent Hill 2)6. True (Silent Hill 2)7. Promise (Silent Hill 2)8. Fermata in Mystic Air (Silent Hill 2) 9. Laura Plays the Piano (Silent Hill 2)10. Overdose Delusion (Silent Hill 2)11. You're Not Here (Silent Hil 3)12. Letter - From the Lost Days (Silent Hill 3)13. Dance With Night Wind (Silent Hill 3)14. Breeze in Monochrome Night (Silent Hill 3)15. Maternal Heart (Silent Hill 3)16. Never Forgive Me, Never Forget Me (Silent Hill 3)17. Cradle of Forrest (Silent Hill 4)18. Wounded Warsong (Silent Hill 4)19. Room of Angel (Silent Hill 4)20. Nightmarish Waltz (Silent Hill 4)</description><genres /><similar_games><game id="3070">Metal Gear Solid: Digital Graphic Novel</game><game id="19493">Silent Hill: Play Novel</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1149/325292-shexp.jpg</image></root>