<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22209</id><name>International Track &amp; Field</name><description>Overview International Track and Field is the fifth game in Konami’s International Track and Field franchise. The game allows players to ‘Try to become the world’s greatest athlete. You can compete in 11 events: the 100-meter dash, 110-meter hurdles, long jump, triple jump, high jump, pole vault, hammer throw, javelin, discus, shot put, and 100-meter freestyle swimming. If you are having problems qualifying in a certain event, use the Practice mode to improve your skills. No matter how you play, all of the competitors are rendered in 3D, and all of the events take place in highly detailed venues. An in-game announcer will make you think that you have stumbled upon a live broadcast of the World Championships. With a multi-tap and some friends, up to four players can compete at one time. Even if you can’t run very fast in real life, you can become a track star with INTERNATIONAL TRACK  FIELD.’ (Original box description) Pro Tips and TricksWhile it’s hard to become a world record breaker the following golden rules will help any budding athlete begin the long road to the gold medal and hopefully create a new generation of success stories:  100M DASH – Quickly tap the  two run buttons in succession to sprint to victory 110M HURDLES – As above  with occasional well-timed pushes of the jump button SWIMMING – See 100M Dash FREESTYLE SWIMMING – As  above but for longer LONG JUMP - Quickly tap the  two run buttons in succession to sprint followed by a well-timed push of  the jump button TRIPLE JUMP – As above with  three jumps instead of one SHOT PUT - Quickly tap the  two run buttons in succession to gain momentum, athlete turns once, throw  with jump button DISCUS - Quickly tap the  two run buttons in succession to gain momentum, athlete turns twice, throw  with jump button HAMMER THROW - Quickly tap  the two run buttons in succession to gain momentum, athlete turns thrice,  throw with jump button JAVELIN - Quickly tap the  two run buttons in succession to sprint, throw with jump button  POLE VAULT - Quickly tap  the two run buttons in succession to sprint, jump with jump button  New Audience...  International Track and Field was released onto the Playstation Network on August 21, 2008 amongst a hail of press coverage ready to capture the imaginations of a new audience.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="42">Track &amp; Field</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15205">Mario &amp; Sonic at the Olympic Games</game><game id="7309">Stadium Events</game><game id="25318">Mario &amp; Sonic at the Olympic Winter Games</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/7052/321532-51w9tx8rk6l__sl500_aa280_.jpg</image></root>