<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22215</id><name>V8 Supercars 2</name><description> Supercars LogoV8 Supercars 2 is the sequel to the popular V8 Supercars, from the creators of the TOCA touring cars series. V8 Supercars 2 adds an entirely new story mode, which allows gamers to follow the career of a new up and coming V8 Supercar driver. The story mode allows players to try out the wide variety of race types, from Formula Fords, Trucks, to the V8 Supercars themselves. The game can also be played in traditional modes across 15 different Racing types such as: V8 Supercars Series, Open Wheel Grand Prix, Super Truck racing, Stockcar Oval Racing, Rally, Rallycross, Ice-Racing, Formula Ford, Classic Racing, Convertible Racing, Street Racing, GT Racing, and Performance Cars. The Mighty HoldensRacing LocationsV8 Supercars 2 includes 10 real life locations. These are:  The most famous and best supercar track in the world. Bathurst Adelaide Phillip Island Oran Park Eastern Creek Pukekohe Surfers Paradise Sandown Hidden Valley Barbagallo  CarsV8 Supercars 2 includes a range of licenced vehicles, most notable the: Ford BA V8 FalconHolden VY V8 Commodore GTAston Martin VanquishJaguar XKRNissan SkylineAMG-Mercedes CLKGameplayUnlike some other realistic driving sims, V8 Supercars 2 does include damage physics and models, allowing licenced cars to take damage and wear over the course of a race. The damage taken by cars also impacts significantly on their performance and handling. Races are also customisable in the non-story mode so that gamers can choose if they want to race for a complete race length, or only a portion of these laps.  </description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="531">TOCA Race Driver 2</game><game id="12950">Gran Turismo 3 A-Spec</game><game id="17599">Forza Motorsport</game><game id="17872">TOCA Race Driver 3 Challenge</game><game id="2730">Formula One Championship Edition</game><game id="5881">Forza Motorsport 2</game><game id="17784">Gran Turismo 4</game><game id="24995">Forza Motorsport 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/13823/322820-v8_supercars_2__ps2_.jpg</image></root>