<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22262</id><name>Dracula Origin</name><description>Dracula: Origin is a new adventure game from Frogwares studio, that promises to re-transcribe Bram Stoker's world faithfully.StoryD:O reveals the origin of Dracula and his curse. Once the defender of his faith, he parts ways with God when his true love marries another. Dracula makes a deal with the devil and is turned into a vampire.Eventually Dracula discovers an ancient rite that could bring back a soul from the beyond. For this rite, he needs a host for the soul he intends to resurrect and he finds a young woman, Mina, to fit the bill.GameplayThe player in D:O takes the role of Professor Van Helsing, who's only mission in life is to take out Dracula. Van Helsing must prevent Dracula from performing the ancient rite in an adventure that spans from London to Egypt, Austria to Carpathian Europe, and, of course, into Dracula's home. The player moves through the story with traditional point and click game play. 150 vampire themed objects in the game to use or combine to complete your mission. The player meets over 40 characters to interact with to gain clues. The game also features a progressive help system of incremental hints that slowly give more and more of the answer away.GraphicsThe game uses a mix of 2d Scenery and 3d character models.Frogwares studio endeavors to use a rich variety of decors and locations as you hunt for clues in Europe, London, Transylvania via Vienna and Egypt.Main CharactersVan Helsing, the disciplined scientist fighting evil, the spiritual hero.Dracula, the insatiable vampire, inhuman and evil incarnate.Mina, the idealized reincarnation of Dracula's lost love.System requirementsRequired:Recommended:Pentium 4 1.5GHZ / Athlon XP 1500512 MB RAM3D video card with 128MB RAMCD Rom speed: 4x3 GB hard drive spaceWindows XP SP2/VistaDirectX 9.0cPentiuim 4 3.0GHZ / Athlon XP 30001 GB RAM3D Video Card with 256 RAMCD Rom speed: 8x3 GB hard drive spaceWindows XP SP2/Vista 32DirectX 9.0c</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8441">Sherlock Holmes: The Awakened</game><game id="574">Sherlock Holmes: Nemesis</game><game id="6870">Sherlock Holmes: Secret of the Silver Earring</game><game id="2111">The Mystery of the Mummy</game><game id="13274">80 Days</game><game id="8759">The Longest Journey</game><game id="2426">Dreamfall: The Longest Journey</game><game id="16965">Syberia</game><game id="1975">Syberia II</game><game id="2564">Overclocked</game><game id="12735">The Experiment</game><game id="6049">Sam &amp; Max Save the World</game><game id="7022">The Space Bar</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/29944/896378-drac_ori.jpg</image></root>