<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22305</id><name>Street Fighter III: 2nd Impact</name><description>OverviewStreet Fighter III: 2nd Impact is an update of     Street Fighter III: New Generation - it was released September 30, 1997.  The game adds new a gameplay feature known as "EX Specials." Street Fighter III: 2nd Impact also adds three more characters - one of them returning from the    Street Fighter II series. A brand new remix soundtrack and three more stages was also added to the game.Character Roster     Alex - An American fighter who fights with close-range wrestling and rush attacks. He enters the tournament to avenge his friend Tom, who was defeated by Gill.      Dudley - A British boxer who enters to retrieve an antique car which was stolen by Gill.      Elena- An African capoeira fighter who seeks new friends.      Ibuki - A Japanese ninja-in-training who enters the tournament as an exam.      Ken - An American fighter, Ken enters the tournament knowing his old friend and rival Ryu is entering, hoping to battle him once again.      Necro - A Russian man who was kidnapped and experimented on.      Oro - An immortal searching for someone worthy of inheriting his fighting style      Ryu - A Japanese fighter who enters seeking to fight powerful enemies to better his skills.      Sean - A Brazilian fighter being trained by Ken.      Yang - A Kung Fu expert from Hong Kong.      Yun - Another Kung Fu expert from Hong Kong.      Gill - The final boss, he is the leader of the Illuminati and wants to restore balance to the world.  2nd Impact Characters     Akuma - A Japanese fighter who killed his brother and teacher.    Hugo - A German wrestler influenced by Andre the Giant.      Urien - Gill's bitter young brother who wants to assume control of the Illuminati. </description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6421">Mortal Kombat 4</game><game id="10081">Tekken</game><game id="15584">Virtua Fighter</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="13753">Dead or Alive Ultimate</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="13875">Plasma Sword: Nightmare of Bilstein</game><game id="21948">Street Fighter III: New Generation</game><game id="707">Virtua Fighter 5</game><game id="243">Street Fighter II: The World Warrior</game><game id="10387">Tekken 2</game><game id="11189">Tekken 3</game><game id="14684">Tekken 4</game><game id="18753">Tekken 5</game><game id="20689">Tekken 6</game><game id="12411">Soulcalibur</game><game id="11822">Soulcalibur II</game><game id="9855">Soulcalibur III</game><game id="20678">Soulcalibur IV</game><game id="1434">Mortal Kombat 3</game><game id="21699">The King of Fighters '98 Ultimate Match</game><game id="10162">Tekken Tag Tournament</game><game id="5640">Capcom vs. SNK: Millennium Fight 2000 Pro</game><game id="5964">The King of Fighters '99</game><game id="35506">Fighting For One Piece</game><game id="34082">Skullgirls</game><game id="38196">Yatagarasu</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/29889/1152381-vstreet_fighter_iii_2nd_impact___giant_attack.jpg</image></root>