<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22324</id><name>Hit the Ice</name><description>OverviewHit the Ice hockey is an arcade hockey game released for the SNES by Taito, and see that sticker on the box, the one that looks like a quality seal?.. that's because it is and that's because this is a good game. Hit the ice hockey is a fast paced, no rules, arcade hockey experience from big hits to even bigger shots this game has it all, including performance enhancing drugs and crazy back flip slaps shots. What? you want team names? too bad developers never had time because they were having too much shooting the puck into the goalie, and making the goalie fly into the net and still scoring ( yes you can do that and apparently it's legal ). Well let's get into it because my fists hurt from random fights and no penalties. Gameplay: Hit the ice was a 1 player of 2 player ( Versus, or Co-op) Game and as you would expect is a fast moving hockey game with little to no rules and you would be right, players can do whatever they want to their opponents and often do what ever they like to the puck. The gameplay systems involved allowed players to pass the puck to other members on their team and allowed for the opposing team to intercept the puck by skating and breaking the straight line of passage between both of the passing team players. As well as shoot the puck, the game having your standard wrist shots and slap shots. The Game gets more arcade like when you learn about super shots. A player if left alone and unobstructed for long enough can charge up their shot, (their hockey starting to flash yellow) before releasing a shot, causing their own player to backflip and shoot the puck passed the goalie or into the goalie knocking the goalie into the net for the goal. The next super shot is what i would call the windmill. This shot more easy to pull of when playing with a friend mainly because of timing, one player skating behind the net and hitting the pass button when the player in front of the net's stick begins to glow, if done correctly the puck will be flipped over the net and the player in front will spin and bat the puck into the net. RULES?! RULES! THERE ARE NO RULES! Since the game was basically a hockey version of     Arch Rivals there were no rules, players would have special moves including, Elbows, Headbutts, Slashing, and A swift kick to the groin, all of which are illegal in the sport of hockey. Along with with no penalties comes fighting and lots of it, though random at times your players will fight, when in a fight you can dodge by holding away from the opposing player, punch and also uppercut, the loser of the brawl falling to the ice with birds flying over their head. With the Win of a fight there comes a few advantages, the player involved in the scuff will receive and speed boost and the chance to grab some tainted although very powerful water from the bench resulting in a zero time charge for a Super Shot, while the loser will stay sluggish in control for sometime after the fight, if an player loses to many fights in one period they are removed with an injury.  The Roster: Hit the ice hockey being no way connected the the NHL does not have any NHL players into the game thought the developers created some parodies and other characters to join the cast which include.   "Dicky" Fontaine "Gunner" Hall, spoof of Glen Hall  Pierre BourdoirPhil Bonker spoof of Phil Esposito   "Battleship" BoydDavid VolekIven Yakashev spoof of a Soviet player from 1972Willy Lindberg Tom Horyna Spoof of Tim Horton Al GiglianoHappy Goleck ("happy-go-lucky")Wayne Greatman Spoof of Wayne Gretzky Reggy MarshJonny NovakPetter Kidd, *"Bo" ClevelandBob DoverMike Barr</description><genres><genre id="39">Hockey</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11965">Tecmo Cup Soccer Game</game><game id="23274">Captain Tsubasa Vol. II: Super Striker</game><game id="11863">NHL Hitz 20-02</game><game id="19447">NHL Hitz 20-03</game><game id="22054">NHL Open Ice 2 on 2 Challenge</game><game id="10605">NHL Rock the Rink</game><game id="24738">3 on 3 NHL Arcade</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/13/137417/2364194-hit_the_ice__snes___na_.jpg</image></root>