<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2237</id><name>LMA Manager 2004</name><description>LMA Manager is the 2003/2004 iteration of the LMA franchise, the football (soccer) management game series. It was released on March 12, 2004 on both the PlayStation 2 and the Xbox. It features a handful of new features over LMA Manager 2003 including a new menu interface and a new Fantasy Team mode.New FeaturesNew and unique menu screen interface.New and updating match engine graphics. Player models are improved.A more realistic 3D Match Engine.New stats update for  the 2003/2004.Create individual tactics for each player on your team.Build your own custom club with the Fantasy Club mode.A new more difficult Expert Mode, for experinced players.More stats, attributes and hidden characteristics for players.A new "Football One" channel where players can watch highlights and get match reports.Shout orders to your players using Xbox Live Headset. (Xbox only)Advanced country, team and player scouting.Over 18,500, 785 clubs and 31 countries.New commentary from Barry DaviesFantasy Team ModeThe new Fantasy Team mode. A big new update with LMA Manager 2004 is the new Fantasy Team mode. This joins the Full Game, Quick Start  Expert modes and Challenge Mode. The player can create a name  for their new club, a country, a stadium, a kit and a full squad. The player then picks a league and is given the amount of funds that will balance with the league you pick. One lower level team is then removed from the league and you take their place and battle out to win some sliverware. Additional countries can be unlocked to be played by playing through some of the Challenge Mode challenges. The Fantasy Team mode is a feature that continues throughout the rest of the series as it turned out to be a popular new feature, even if the mode is quite difficult and requires a large time investment.LeaguesThe number of playable leagues continues to be the same from LMA Manager 2003, which was also the same for LMA Manager 2002. Currently this is the list of leagues that you can play:EnglandEnglish Premier LeagueEnglish Division OneEnglish Division TwoEnglish Division ThreeScotlandScottish PremiershipScottish First DivisionScottish Second DivisionScottish Third DivisionSpain1st Division2nd Division AItalySeria ASeria BFranceLigue 1Germany1st Bundesliga2nd Bundesliga</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="40">Soccer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8108">Championship Manager Season 97/98</game><game id="3753">FIFA Manager 07</game><game id="13578">Championship Manager 2</game><game id="27051">Championship Manager 2007</game><game id="10532">Championship Manager 3</game><game id="12974">Championship Manager 2: Scandinavian Leagues</game><game id="5444">Championship Manager 4</game><game id="20279">Championship Manager 5</game><game id="15731">Championship Manager 96/97</game><game id="16216">Championship Manager '93</game><game id="3248">Championship Manager: Season 1999/2000</game><game id="10275">Championship Manager: Season 00/01</game><game id="17370">Championship Manager: Season 01/02</game><game id="8563">Championship Manager: Season 02/03</game><game id="9111">Championship Manager: Season 03/04</game><game id="18153">Championship Manager: End of Season Edition</game><game id="1467">FA Premier League Football Manager 2000</game><game id="5605">FIFA Manager 06</game><game id="19272">FIFA Manager 07: Extra Time</game><game id="24888">FIFA Manager 09</game><game id="454">FIFA Soccer Manager</game><game id="1586">Total Club Manager 2003</game><game id="19086">Total Club Manager 2004</game><game id="15714">Total Club Manager 2005</game><game id="13818">Football Manager</game><game id="2662">Football Manager 2</game><game id="22117">Worldwide Soccer Manager 2006</game><game id="20784">Football Manager 2008</game><game id="23498">Football Manager 2009</game><game id="22169">Football Manager Live</game><game id="22593">Football Manager Handheld</game><game id="26944">Football  Manager Handheld 2009</game><game id="13826">Premier Manager 2</game><game id="5762">Premier Manager 3</game><game id="17239">Premier Manager 3 De-Luxe</game><game id="7009">Premier Manager 97</game><game id="13">Premier Manager 98</game><game id="6697">Premier Manager Ninety Nine</game><game id="8454">Premier Manager 2000</game><game id="10527">Premier Manager 2005-2006</game><game id="23500">Sky Sports Football Manager</game><game id="4805">Soccer Team Manager: English and Italian Leagues</game><game id="30751">Football Manager 2011</game><game id="33212">Football Manager 2012</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9089/326526-lma_2004.jpg</image></root>