<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22395</id><name>Copernicus</name><description>OverviewProject Copernicus (also known as Kingdoms of Amalur) was the code name of an MMORPG that was in development at 38 Studios since shortly after the company's founding, right up to its closing. Details on Copernicus were kept tightly under wraps throughout its development, save for the involvement of fantasy author R.A. Salvatore as lead writer and comic artist Todd McFarlane as concept artist. The Big Huge Games-developed single-player RPG Kingdoms of Amalur: Reckoning was set in the same universe as Copernicus, and was intended to establish familiarity with the Amalur universe leading up to the MMO's release.Copernicus is currently in limbo, and likely cancelled. On May 24th, 2012, it was announced that all employees at 38 Studios and Big Huge Games were laid off due to 38 Studios having incurred a significant debt and no longer having the funds to sustain operation. The rights to the game could theoretically be bought by another studio and development continued, but with the original development team since scattered to different jobs and different projects, as well as the incredible amount of media attention the game's failure received, prospects are grim for a Copernicus revival.On July 9, 2012, a rough cut of a trailer for Project Copernicus was leaked to Kotaku, revealing the game's final name - Kingdoms of Amalur - as well as its cartoonish art style, and several character models and environments. Nothing was shown of the game's actual gameplay, though, and many of the details about precisely what the game actually was are still shrouded in secrecy. Barring further leaks, this trailer might be the last that is ever seen of Project Copernicus.</description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10796">EverQuest</game><game id="5767">Ultima Online</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/81005/2209242-0.jpg</image></root>