<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22423</id><name>Wedding Dash</name><description>Overview    Wedding Dash is a strategy management game, created by PlayFirst. In Wedding Dash, you rush around delivering food to guests and keep everything running smoothly. Being a spin-off of the Diner Dash series, the main character of the Diner Dash series, Flo, makes quite a few appearances in Wedding Dash. She'll even show up to some weddings to help out, which is great integration for people who have played the Diner Dash games.  Story  The game starts off with the main character, Quinn, standing next to her friend who is trying on a wedding dress. Quinn is one of the bridesmaids and is helping her friend out. Suddenly, the bride receives a phone call that tells her the that many aspects of her wedding are falling apart. Quinn tells her friend that everything will be alright, and her friend says that Quinn is her answer, and that she should plan the wedding.   And thus starts Quinn's wedding planning career!  Gameplay There are five layers of levels in Wedding Dash. These levels are displayed in cake form before you choose to start on weddings. For example, there are twelve levels in the first layer of the cake. Then you move on to a new location and more of everything will be presented. More guests, more disasters and more extras. Use hints given in the letter to choose the best option in the following page.  Planning -     At the beginning of each wedding, you read a note from the bride and groom, hinting what sort of food, flowers, honeymoon spots, as well as other things, they want for their wedding. It's not essential that you get it right, it's basically some easy starter cash before each reception. Some of the goals are really high, and difficult to achieve, so anything helps. Reception -      The reception is where you actually play the game. You must seat the guests, take their gifts to the newlyweds and as well as feed them appetizers, a main dish, and finally cake. And you must do it all while taking care of any mishaps that may occur, and comply with where the guests want to sit. Of course there's a money goal you have to achieve before moving on to the next level. There's also an expert goal that can be achieved.Chains -   If you do things multiple times in a row, you create a chain. For example, if you place three guests in a row, each time after the first, more money is maid than usual. The first guest might give twenty, the second forty and the fifth sixty. This applies to everything you do, as long as it's the same action. If you place two guests, then take their gifts, then place two more, it won't start from the previous placing, it will reset. Mishaps -    There are some random problems that will occur during receptions. Only Quinn can fix these problems and a symbol will appear indicating that you need to click it to send her over, and solve whatever may be happening. More of them appear throughout the game, and Quinn hints at them at the start of the reception. You lose big money if the problem exists for too long, so always make sure to click those symbols right away. 'Bout to be a what? Girl Fight!  - Brawling Bridesmaids - Two bridesmaids appear near the DJ's booth who are in a bit of a cat fight. Send Quinn over immediately to solve. I told myself I wouldn't cry! - Choked-Up Aunt - Aunt Ethel can sometimes burst into tears. The thought of weddings just makes her so happy. Buzz buzz bye! - Beehive - Bees may appear in a swarm. They obviously weren't invited, so have Quinn shoo them off. If you can't take the he- *shot*                                      - Cooking Catastrophe - The Chef's cooking setup may go on the fritz.    People think they can bring their dogs everywhere these days....- Disruptive Dog - A dog belonging to one of the guests occasionally appears at the top left of the screen.  Get there quick! The five second rule doesn't apply to cake!- Bad Leg - The table charged with the significant job of holding the cake, is a little broken.  What did he say about Salisbury steak....? - Cut Off - Uncle Ernie can get a bit rowdy after a few drinks....   - Messed Music - The DJ's table might get messed up sometimes. Yo DJ! Bring the beat back!          Guest Types -     Each guest has a different personality. There are only so many though, and you will often end up with many of the same guest at once. Some guests are more patient than others. Some are more charismatic. You will be told about each guest before they're introduced at the start of the reception. So if there is a new guest type, Quinn will mention them, so you know what they're like before you seat them.  Every guest will have a thought bubble over their head when they enter the reception. This will tell you where they want, or do not want to go. Pay attention to this if you want the seating bonus.  Also, each guest has three varying qualities, depending on who they are.  Charisma - If they are charismatic, other guests will want to sit by them, if not, guests might come in asking not to sit by them. Eating Pace - How quickly a guest eats their food. Some scarf it all down, and some take their time. Patience - Guests with high patience don't need to be taken care of as quickly, they don't mind waiting as much, but some guests get irritated very quickly.   Uncle Al - Uncle Al - Al is a pretty average guest. Decently patient and charismatic. Average eating speed as well  Alison - Alison - Another pretty average guest.  Dereck   - Dereck - The last of the average guests.    - Chloe - Chloe is extremely charismatic but her patience and eating speeds are average. Chloe     Diane - Diane - Really patient, but a slow eater. Charisma is average.      - Auntie Ethel - Pretty average in the three areas, but she can randomly burst into tears. Auntie Ethel    Bob - Bob - Bob likes to eat his food really quickly so he can get to the dance floor. Otherwise he's pretty average.      Uncle Ernie - Uncle Ernie - Similar to Auntie Ethel, Ernie has his moments. Occasionally he can let the drinks get a hold of him. He's not very patient and eats a little quicker than most, and his charisma is lower than others, because of his drunkenness.  Betty   - Betty - Betty is very talkative, which annoys most of the other guests. Her charisma is lower because of this. Her patience is also low and her eating pace is normal.     Chuck  - Chuck - Chuck is very short on patience, and not many guests want to sit next to him, but he eats a normal speed.     Extras -    Throughout the game, there will be extra things you can do to help you beat the mad rush. Some are random, while others are brought by Quinn.You may choose, only one!- Bonuses - During certain points in the game, you will be asked which bonus you want for the rest of the tier of levels. These vary from making your waitress faster, to making the guests more patient, or making food worth more.- Champagne - Quinn sometimes brings in some bottles of champagne to pop. You'll start off with one to three bottles, once you get far enough, and each time you pop one, it makes the guests waiting to be seated patient again. So if their thought bubbles were becoming more hostile, this will reduce it temporarily. Poppin' champagne like we won a championship game! - Confetti Blaster - The confetti blaster is like the champagne, of the seated guests. It reduces their anger if they've been waiting long, but you can only use this when the red sphere on it flashes green. Other than letting it charge up, it has unlimited uses. Pew pew pew! Move! Move! Move!- Changing Seats - Sometimes a guest may wish to change seats, so they can sit next to someone else. This happens sometimes when you place a guest next to another, when they had requested a certain one. This doesn't break the chain if you have one going to change seats. That's my song!!! - Song Change - Like changing seats, some guests will bring music to give to the DJ. These are worth a pretty nice amount if you do it, and the chain doesn't break, so do it whenever you see it.Ah, what a fabulous 1889....- Wine - Yet another item for your waitress to serve. Random like the changing music, guests will sometimes want some wine. Get a nice amount of money for doing it to, and of course, no chain break. Modes  Career Mode -    In Career Mode, you basically play through the story. Keep the guests and newlyweds happy, and stop disasters while still trying to reach that ever growing goal.  Endless Reception -      Just as the title says, except for the initial planning which no longer happens, everything else is the same. During this mode, you're trying to keep everyone happy as usual, and the game will only end, if the bride becomes Bridezilla. </description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26713">Sally's Salon</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3614/378179-wedding_dash1.jpg</image></root>