<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22478</id><name>PowerUp Forever</name><description>GameplayNot much is known about this game except for what was said in its official press release.Gameplay of PowerUp Forever "Destroying elite enemies allows you to absorb their energy, transforming your ship’s size, shape and power. As your ship evolves and grows your world and its enemies shrink to insignificance, revealing even more massive and powerful enemies that were previously too large to see."FeaturesProcedurally Generated Environments – Never experience the same game twice as all of the enemy types and locations are procedurally generated Innovative Growth Mechanic – Adds a unique twist to the shooter genre and offers fun, exciting gameplay Power Up your weapons – Power up cool new weapons, such as lasers, shields and bombs, that boost your arsenal as you evolve High Definition Graphics – True next-gen graphical effects and an exciting abstract art-style provide eye-popping visuals Multiple modes of play  Survival Mode – Survive relentless waves of non-stop enemies Guardian Rush Mode – Defeat a series of guardians in the shortest length of time Defender – How long can you survive only using a shield? Overkill Mode – Unlimited weapons  </description><genres><genre id="31">Dual-Joystick Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21167">Geometry Wars: Retro Evolved 2</game><game id="1034">Asteroids</game><game id="13434">Asteroids Deluxe</game><game id="11099">Geometry Wars: Retro Evolved</game><game id="16151">Geometry Wars: Galaxies</game><game id="21118">Super Stardust Portable</game><game id="2707">Super Stardust</game><game id="793">Super Stardust HD</game><game id="9960">Everyday Shooter</game><game id="14615">Every Extend</game><game id="8887">Every Extend Extra</game><game id="2320">Every Extend Extra Extreme</game><game id="2027">Crystal Quest</game><game id="20600">Blast Factor</game><game id="20606">Nucleus</game><game id="24502">Evasive Space</game><game id="29759">Eclosion</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/13158/833684-gb.png</image></root>