<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22505</id><name>Tattoo Assassins</name><description>History and InformationNudality.There was a time when Fighting games dominated the local arcades, namely Street Fighter. With its popularity followed many clones, such as Mortal Kombat, and Killer Instinct, trying to cash in on the fad that dominated the arcade space. Then came the clones of the clones, and Tattoo Assassins was born. Made to deliberately cash in on the success of these franchises but took heavy "influence" from the Mortal Kombat franchise. It attempted to mimic MK's digitized art style and over the top violence advertising over 200 fatalities (it was the first fighting game to include "NUDEalities") for better or worse.At its heart Tattoo Assassins is a Mortal Kombat inspired knock off with bad graphics and horrible controls. You choose 1 of 9 playable characters and fight your way up the ranks through 3 sub-bosses leading up to a final encounter with the games villain Koldan. The story involves a guru named Mullah Abba discovering the secrets to a magical substance called "the ink of Ghize", described as a "magical living organism" which has the ability to bring life to its wearer's tattoos for short periods of time. Koldan wants all the ink for himself so he can create an army of tattooed warriors and enslave mankind. So, you are tasked to defeat the evil Koldan and save the earth.This game has a rather infamous story revolving around its inception. Apparently Joe Kaminkow (worked for DATA EAST pinball) and Bob Gale (co-creator of the back to the future trilogy) became friends after collaborating on the back to the future pinball game. Bob started sending Joe copies of his movie scripts and one of them happened to involve warriors who battled with magical tattoos. Apparently they both thought this was a great premise for a video game because production on Tattoo Assassins started shortly after.The team was quickly patched together and were put to task to create the game in only 8 months. A difficult task for any development team, especially considering the majority of the Tattoo Assassins team had little to no video game experience.There were stories of the team being forced to work 12 hour days, 7 days a week, and having their meals catered in so they wouldn't need to leave work. By most accounts from team members stated they all started to resent the long work hours and stopped caring about the quality of the game and just wanted it all to end.Only two working arcade cabinets were ever created; the first fell victim to a flood and was destroyed, and the second lives on in infamy at the company's headquarters as a monument to their failure.Thanks to the rise of emulators long forgotten digital brawlers like Jackie Chan Kung Fu Master, Blood Warrior, Survival Arts and Tattoo Assassins are now available to be played by the general public. Tattoo Assassins was never officially released and was destined to be just forgotten about but thanks to M.A.M.E. (and other emulators) people from all walks of life now have the chance to see what could have been and has gained cult status thanks to how shockingly "so bad that it's awesome" the game truly is.Character Bio'sThis information was taken directly from the game's attract mode.CharacterBioA.C. CurrentA.C. CurrentA.C. Current is a cyber mercenary who travels the net, cracking computer systems for the highest bidders. After being set up in an industrial espionage double-cross, A.C. is wanted by Interpol and by this former employers.Billy Two MoonsBilly Two MoonsBranded a renegade after taking arms against the U.S. bureau of land management over preservation of the burial site of his ancestors, billy has been a fugitive for many years, and he has had to dispatch numerous bounty hunters.Derek O'TooleDerek O'TooleDerek is an aspiring rock star who was falsely accused of taking part in terrorist activities in his home town of Belfast. He was forced to develop fighting skills to defend himself. he is now part of the underground club scene.Hannah HartHannah HartHannah was a world class strip club dancer, until a deranger killer started stalking the other dancers and murdered her best friend. She now prowls the night, in search of the man who ruined her life. her only desire is a cruel revenge.Karla KellerKarla KellerKarla was cheated out of her chance to compete in the Olympics when her rival Eva Gunther attempted to cripple her in a late-night ambush. Karla has sworn a vicious revenge and it practicing her martial arts for that day.Luke CordLuke CordLuke is a former Navy Seal who was stranded in Alaska after a secret operation against the soviets was compromised by a bureaucrat. he was been declared dead by the US Navy, but the CIA still has a contract on him because of his knowledge.MayaMayaMaya's father, a tribal chief, was killed by foreign land developers intent on taking over her tribe's land. Maya has taught her people to use guerilla tactics against the foreigners; now the developers want her dead as well.Tak HataTak HataTak is a former Yakuza assassin. When the governor's daughter was killed by the son of a powerful crime lord, Tak was framed for the murder. he is now wanted both by the Yakuza and the Japanese police.Truck DavisTruck DavisTruck is the last surviving member of the Holy Terrors biker gang. The Holy Terrors were ambushed by a rival gang, the Sore Losers, after they lost a drinking contest. Now Truck has a score to settle and the Losers want to finish the job.</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14900">Way of the Warrior</game><game id="4855">Shaq Fu</game><game id="244">CheetahMen II</game><game id="5047">Battle Monsters</game><game id="32525">Survival Arts</game><game id="21419">Time Killers</game><game id="32494">Timeslaughter</game><game id="11807">Xenophage: Alien BloodSport</game><game id="1434">Mortal Kombat 3</game><game id="39299">Dong Dong Never Die</game><game id="39751">Death Cargo</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8960/1428702-tatass.jpg</image></root>