<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22508</id><name>Super Robot Wars Z</name><description>Overview Super Robot Wars Z was the last      Super Robot Wars game to be released for the PS2, and the second game in the series to be published by Namco Bandai. Though the game at first appeared to be a standalone title, SRWZ would be followed by the Super Robot Wars Z2 duology (    Hakai-hen and    Saisei-hen) for the Playstation Portable.   Mechanics-wise, SRWZ is similar to the Super Robot Wars Alpha series, with the new Tri-Battle system taking inspiration from Alpha 2's and 3's Squad System. A new "Accuracy" robot stat is added, while the number of available Spirit Commands is reduced by one. Battle animations have also improved over Alpha: the robots are more accurately proportioned (like   Super Robot Wars MX), dynamic camera angles from  Original Generations returns, and attacks have different animations based on the attacker's and defender's positions.  This game adds a healthy number of debuting anime series. Newer series include Eureka Seven, Gravion, Genesis of Aquarion and Overman King Gainer, while the 80s is represented by Godsigma, Baldios, and Orguss. The movie version of Zeta Gundam and the ever-polarizing Gundam SEED Destiny, which both debuted in the Scramble Commander sub-series, make their first traditional appearance in SRWZ.StoryVarious dimensions have been merged together due to the detonation of the Space-Time Oscillation Bomb by fighter pilot       Kei Katsuragi in an event known as "Break the World." This chaotic world is controlled by a new Earth Federation, a super-alliance of the Universal Century world's Earth Federation and the Cosmic Era world's Earth Alliance, among other factions. In addition, other malicious groups such as the Hyakki Empire, the Shadow Angels, and the Guyzok roam this world. To battle this combined threat, a organization known as ZEUTH is formed; it consists of various groups such as the AEUG, ZAFT, and Gekko State.Featured Series A list of the anime series which are featured in the game. Series that premiered in the Super Robot Wars series in this game are marked with "(new)". Mobile Suit Zeta Gundam (A New Translation version)* Mobile Suit Gundam: Char's Counterattack After War Gundam X Turn A Gundam Mobile Suit Gundam SEED Destiny* Mazinger Z Great Mazinger UFO Robo Grendizer Getter Robo G Invincible Super Man Zambot 3 Invincible Steel Man Daitarn 3 Space Emperor God Sigma    (new)    Space Warrior Baldios    (new)    Combat Mecha Xabungle    Super Dimension Century Orguss    (new)    The Big O    The Big O: Second Season    (new)    Overman King Gainer    (new)    Super Heavy God Gravion    (new)    Super Heavy God Gravion Zwei    (new)    Genesis of Aquarion    (new)    Psalm of Planets Eureka Seven    (new)    Banpresto Originals (original characters created for the game)  *First appearance in a "traditional" SRW game. Tri-Battle SystemA combination of Super Robot Wars Alpha 2's Squad System and Original Generation's Twin-Battle System, Tri-Battle again lets the player place up to three robots into a single unit. However, the new Formation feature adds an extra layer of strategy, allowing the player to adapt to any situation.Tri FormationThe Tri Formation is built around the new Tri-Charge attack, which allows all robots in a squad to use their respective TRI weapons together as an ALL attack. Unlike normal ALL attacks, Tri-Charges do not suffer damage penalties when used against a 3-robot Squad; Tri-Charges also pierce enemy barriers. There will be special Tri-Charges for certain teams (such as Sting, Stella, and Auel from Gundam SEED Destiny).All members of the Squad receive defensive and evasion bonuses against ALL Attacks All members of the Squad are capable of Support Defending each other  The Platoon attack (PLA) is not available.  Center FormationApproximate to the Alphas' Squad System; the squad focuses fire on a single robot.Squad members can Support Defend squad leader. All members of the Squad share barriers. Squad leader receives defensive and evasion bonuses against ALL Attacks.  Wide FormationApproximate to OG's Twin Battle System; the squad fires on their respective enemies (Squad leader attacks enemy squad leader, left squad member attacks enemy left squad member, right squad member attacks enemy right Squad member). Unlike Center Formation, there are no penalties against this kind of attack.Support Defense is disabled. All members of the squad receive defensive bonuses when facing an enemy ALL attack.  New FeaturesTri-Battle System. See above. Robots now have an Accuracy stat. Attack Again. A new pilot skill that allows a robot to "Support Attack" itself if its pilot's skill rating is 20 points higher than the enemy's. To counteract the skill's high potential, it is the most expensive skill in the game; additionally, only extremely skilled aces (like Amuro Ray from the Gundam franchise and Kei Katsuragi from Orguss) receive the skill automatically. Animation has been improved in many areas. For example, several weapons now have separate animations for air-to-ground and ground-to-air situations. Animations on the map have also improved, with some events that would normally be depicted using static sprites or FMV (such as a Super Robot combining) being recreated entirely with moving sprites. </description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25708">SD Gundam G Generation Wars</game><game id="22983">SD Gundam G Generation Spirits</game><game id="22982">SD Gundam G Generation Portable</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/12421/392275-srwz_cover.jpg</image></root>