<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22562</id><name>Guitar Hero: Metallica</name><description>OverviewMetallica in 2008Guitar Hero: Metallica is the second Guitar Hero game with a focus on an individual band, the first being Guitar Hero: Aerosmith. The game's soundtrack features 28 Metallica tracks and 21 tracks from other artists such as The Sword, Foo Fighters, and Danzig. Tracks from each Metallica album, even the live album SM and the cover album Garage Inc are featured. While all versions of the game come with the track "All Nightmare Long" from their latest album, Death Magnetic, the rest of the album is available for download on the Playstation Network and Xbox Live Marketplace.In various interviews, Metallica has stated that they are pleased and honored that Activision is devoting an entire team to make a game entirely focused on their music. Lars Ulrich, the band's drummer and co-founder, said that it will be a treat for fans. Long time lead guitarist, Kirk Hammett, said that fans and even those who haven't discovered Metallica yet will fall in love with the game, because it gives players the feeling that they are really up on stage playing the songs and creating music.GameplayEnter Sandman in full-band modeCareer mode progression works similarly to the one found in Guitar Hero Aerosmith, while maintaining the gameplay found in Guitar Hero: World Tour. In the beginning, players take control of Metallica performing a two-song setlist. This triggers the story by inspiring a local band to follow Metallica on tour and play as an opening act. The band will follow Metallica around to key arenas which commemorate some of their most memorable gigs. This will include arenas such as the Tushino Airfield in Russia for where they played to a crowd of 500,000 people free of charge in 1991, as well as The Forum in Los Angeles.During career mode, the player alternates between playing as Metallica and the opening band, aptly named 'Tallica Jr. Players can choose to create their own rock star through the game's Create-a-Rocker editor, or choose from a variety of pre-existing characters (Whom include Guitar Hero staples Axel Steel, Johnny Napalm and Judy Nails). Following suit with the previously Neversoft Guitar Hero releases, players can also unlock celebrity rockers including Motorhead's Lemmy Kilmister and Mercyful Fate vocalist King Diamond (who appears with his trademark cross-bones microphone). When the player plays songs that are not by Metallica - with the exception of 'Ace of Spades' and 'Evil', generic Guitar Hero characters are used.Lemmy Kilmister makes an appearanceAside from the game's career progression style, the in-game interface remains largely unchanged from Guitar Hero: World Tour. One of the few key differences, however, is a box that goes over your note streak telling you how many stars (out of five) you have earned, similar to the system used in the Rock Band franchise. In addition to the in-game interface and set list changes, the menus of the game have been given a Metallica make-over, with everything from the start menu sporting Metallica inspired artwork.The online aspect of Guitar Hero: Metallica remains largely unchanged to Guitar Hero: World Tour, with the player being able to play in a four-player band, guitar and bass co-op, band vs band matches etc. The only key change resides in the game's guitar-exclusive battle mode, in which a new power up dubbed "Fade to Black" appears. The power-up is most used in sudden death matches, and when used completely blacks out the opposing player's fret board.FeaturesJames Hetfield performing in a motion capture suitMetallica put on motion-capture suits and did many of their signature moves from their live shows for the game. Among them were bassist Rob Trujillo's "braid spin" where, during the song "Seek and Destroy", he picks up his bass and spins around in a circle. The game features unlockable videos of the band in the suits, including a scene where Lars Ulrich is playing the band's song "The Shortest Straw" in the suit for the first time.In addition to the videos of the band in mo-cap suits, the game sports the "Metallifacts" video feature. Metallifacts is a pop-up video style feature that has the virtual band playing the song the player chooses, all the while displaying little known facts and details about the songs they pick. Some songs even feature bootleg performances taped by fans, included on the songs "Creeping Death", "Orion", "For Whom the Bell Tolls", and others.Expert PlusA new feature making its debut in Guitar Hero Metallica is the inclusion of Expert Plus, the highest difficulty a player may choose. Only available to Drummers, Expert Plus utilizes a second kickpedal that can be connected to all Guitar Hero World Tour and Band Hero drumkits via the ports on its back.ExportabilityOn September 28, 2010, 39 tracks (including all the Metallica tracks except those from Death Magnetic) from Guitar Hero: Metallica will be exportable to Guitar Hero: Warriors of Rock.Metallica's MusicEvery Metallica album is represented in the game's setlist. Metallica's Albums in chronological order:1983 - Kill 'em All1984 - Ride the Lightning1986 - Master of Puppets1988 - ...And Justice for All1991 - Metallica (The Black Album)1996 - Load1997 - ReLoad1998 - Garage Inc.1999 - SM2003 - St. Anger2008 - Death MagneticGuitar Hero: Metallica Setlist (Band**)Career TierSong TitleArtistYear1. The ForumFor Whom the Bell Tolls ***Metallica19841. The ForumThe Unforgiven ***Metallica19912. Tushino AirfieldTurn the Page (Live) ***Bob Seger19762. Tushino AirfieldMother of Mercy ***Samhain19862. Tushino AirfieldNo ExcusesAlice in Chains19942. Tushino AirfieldTuesday's Gone ***Lynyrd Skynyrd19732. Tushino AirfieldDemon Cleaner ***Kyuss19943. Metallica at TushinoNothing Else Matters ***Metallica19913. Metallica at TushinoEnter Sandman ***Metallica19913. Metallica at TushinoKing Nothing ***Metallica19963. Metallica at TushinoSad But True ***Metallica19913. Metallica at TushinoNo Leaf Clover ***Metallica19994. Hammersmith ApolloStacked ActorsFoo Fighters19994. Hammersmith ApolloToxicitySystem of a Down20014. Hammersmith ApolloArmed and ReadyMichael Shenker Group19844. Hammersmith ApolloAlbatrossCorrosion of Conformity19944. Hammersmith ApolloThe Boys are Back in Town ***Thin Lizzy19764. Hammersmith ApolloOrion ***Metallica19864. Hammersmith ApolloFade to Black ***Metallica19844. Hammersmith ApolloThe Memory Remains ***Metallica19974. Hammersmith ApolloWherever I May Roam ***Metallica19914. Hammersmith ApolloWelcome Home (Sanitarium) ***Metallica19865. Damaged Justice TourHell Bent for LeatherJudas Priest19785. Damaged Justice TourThe Black River ***The Sword20085. Damaged Justice TourMommy's Little Monster (Live) ***Social Distortion19985. Damaged Justice TourWar Inside My HeadSuicidal Tendencies19905. Damaged Justice TourAce of Spades ***Motörhead20085. Damaged Justice TourFuel ***Metallica19975. Damaged Justice TourFrantic ***Metallica20035. Damaged Justice TourOne ***Metallica19885. Damaged Justice TourAll Nightmare LongMetallica20085. Damaged Justice TourHit the Lights ***Metallica19836. The MeadowlandsAm I Evil? ***Diamond Head19826. The MeadowlandsBlood and Thunder ***Mastodon20046. The MeadowlandsStone Cold CrazyQueen19746. The MeadowlandsMercyful Fate ***Metallica19986. The MeadowlandsSeek  Destroy ***Metallica19836. The MeadowlandsCreeping Death ***Metallica19846. The MeadowlandsMaster of Puppets ***Metallica19866. The MeadowlandsBattery ***Metallica19967. Donington ParkBeautiful Morning ***Machine Head20077. Donington ParkWar EnsembleSlayer19907. Donington ParkEvil ***Mercyful Fate20087. Donington ParkThe Shortest Straw ***Metallica19887. Donington ParkWhiplash ***Metallica19837. Donington ParkDyer's Eve ***Metallica19887. Donington ParkDisposable Heroes ***Metallica19867. Donington ParkFight Fire with Fire ***Metallica19848. The Ice CaveThe Thing That Should Not Be ***Metallica19869. The Stone NightclubBroken, Beat  Scarred *Metallica20089. The Stone NightclubCyanide *Metallica20089. The Stone NightclubMy Apocalypse *Metallica2008* = These songs are exclusive to the Wii and PlayStation 2 version of the game, although they are available as DLC for Xbox 360 and PlayStation 3.** = The setlist for single instruments varies from this list. All the songs do appear on those setlists (except for the instrumental Orion on vocals).*** = Exportable to GH:WoRDownloadable ContentThe entire Death Magnetic album a unique version of Suicide  Redemption is available as DLC for both Xbox 360 and PlayStation3.Song TitleArtistYearThat Was Just Your LifeMetallica2008The End of the LineMetallica2008Broken, Beat  ScarredMetallica2008The Day That Never ComesMetallica2008All Nightmare LongMetallica2008CyanideMetallica2008The Unforgiven IIIMetallica2008The Judas KissMetallica2008Suicide  Redemption J.H. ( James Hetfield's solo)Metallica2008Suicide  Redemption K.H. ( Kirk Hammet's solo)Metallica2008My ApocalypseMetallica2008Trivia and Other StuffOriginal Box Art MisspellingThe "Lynyrd Skynrd" misspellingIn February 2009 the original box art for Guitar Hero : Metallica was released and had a big misspelling on it. Instead of the famous band name "Lynyrd Skynyrd", the box art read "Lynyrd Skynrd".DemoA demo for Guitar Hero: Metallica was released on Xbox Live Marketplace on 20th March, 2009. It included the four following songs:No Excuses - Alice in ChainsSad But True - MetallicaSeek and Destroy - MetallicaStone Cold Crazy - QueenLaunch Bundles  Pre-order BonusesIn the United Kingdom and Australia, a limited guitar bundle was distributed. The bundle contains the game, a Guitar Hero: World Tour guitar, a Metallica faceplate and some exclusive stickers.Pre-order bonuses were also offered by retailers. In Australia, EB Games offered a bass pedal, GAME offered a set of black drumsticks with a printed Guitar Hero: Metallica logo and JB Hi-Fi offered a Guitar Hero: Metallica t-shirt. In the United States, GameStop offered a new bass pedal and Hollywood Video and GameCrazy offered the above mentioned drumsticks.</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23939">AC/DC Live: Rock Band</game><game id="29439">Green Day: Rock Band</game><game id="25536">Guitar Hero: Van Halen</game><game id="27919">Rock Band 3</game><game id="32905">Singstar Guitar</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2491501-box_ghm.png</image></root>