<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22574</id><name>Melty Blood</name><description>OverviewMelty Blood is 2D fighting game by Type-Moon based on the characters in the visual novel, Tsukihime and was originally released on Windows PCs. Later the game was ported to arcades and the PlayStation 2 as Melty Blood: Act Cadenza. The original game contains 14 playable characters.StoryMelty Blood's story takes place approximately one year after Tsukihime. A series of murders occur in Misaki and Shiki Tohno attempts to search for the murderer. During his travels he meets Sion Eltnam Atlasia, an alchemist who attempts to capture him. She explains that she is attempting to find a cure for vampirism.ReleasesMelty Blood was released in December 2002 on the PC and went through subsequent patches, the first of which Re-Act was released in May 2004 and Re-Act Final Tuned was released in July 2005.Re-ActRe-Act included an Arcade Mode, set shortly after the events of the main storyline. Many characters were re-balanced and new movesets were introduced.Re-Act: Final TunedRe-Act: Final Tuned added configuration options for controllers and fightsticks, as well as four new colours for each character.</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21863">Melty Blood: Act Cadenza</game><game id="19278">Guilty Gear XX #Reload</game><game id="800">Guilty Gear XX Λ Core</game><game id="243">Street Fighter II: The World Warrior</game><game id="21367">Sengoku Basara X</game><game id="22812">Battle Fantasia</game><game id="22362">Street Fighter II': Hyper Fighting</game><game id="26032">Million KNights Vermilion</game><game id="27723">Vanguard Princess</game><game id="34218">Chaos Code</game><game id="35030">Akatsuki Blitzkampf</game><game id="38196">Yatagarasu</game><game id="35513">Phantom Breaker</game><game id="44008">Dengeki Bunko: Fighting Climax</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/208/404480-meltyblood.jpg</image></root>