<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2260</id><name>Sonic R</name><description>OverviewSonic R is a 3D racing game for the Sega Saturn that was developed by Sonic Team and Traveller's Tales, and is the third Sonic racing game to be created in the franchise, the first two being Sonic Drift and Sonic Drift 2 for the Sega Game Gear. Other racing games based on the Sonic franchise include Sonic Rivals, Sonic Rivals 2, Sonic Riders, Sonic Riders: Zero Gravity, Sonic Free Riders and more recently Sonic  Sega All-Stars Racing.Sonic R was also released on the PC and within the game compilation Sonic Gems Collection for the Gamecube and PS2 (Japan only).GameplayUnlike Sonic Drift, the main characters of Sonic R, with the exception of Amy Rose and Dr. Robotnik, do not drive a car, but instead run through the stages. The stages themselves are more epansive than traditional racing courses and offer many different routes through each level, leading to hidden short cuts and areas which can be explored. These hidden areas also contain collectable items, such as finding special emblems and Chaos Emeralds which unlock extra characters and stages.As in most Sonic games, rings are an important element of Sonic R. As well as offering protection, rings are used to open up gates that lead to hidden areas and Chaos Emeralds, and are also used on speed boosts to increase the player's speed. Power ups are also a key feature of Sonic R, such as the lightning shield and water shield from Sonic the Hedgehog 3.There are multiple game modes within Sonic R. Most notably is the Grand Prix, where all four stages can be played in order. There is also a Time Attack mode and a host of multiplayer options including a standard versus race, a tag style race where player's must chase after each other and capture them, and a balloon game, where the player must find and pop five balloons before their opponent.CharactersThere are four playable characters available at the start of Sonic R, with five more that can be unlocked. Each character has their own strengths and weaknesses, such as increased speed or the ability to run or glide over water. The playable characters are:Sonic the HedgehogSonic is the fastest of the characters available at the beginning, with quick acceleration at the expense of handling. He has the ability to perform a double jump.Miles "Tails" ProwerTails has fairly good speed and acceleration and also retains his trademark ability of flight, enabling him to reach areas other characters may not.Knuckles the EchidnaKnuckles is an all round character with decent speed and acceleration. He also retains his trademark ability of gliding, allowing him to create his own short cuts.Amy RoseAmy is one of the characters that uses a car to race, which can float over water. Her car is quite slow but has the ability to boost.Dr RobotnikDr Robotnik is the other character that uses a car to race, which is slow with poor acceleration but can float over water. He has the ability of shooting missiles. He is one of the unlockable characters.Metal SonicThe Metal Sonic is a robotic version of Sonic that can jump higher than other characters. He is one of the unlockable characters.Tails DollThe Tails Doll is a robotic version of Tails that can float over water without slowing down. He is one of the unlockable characters.EggRoboThe EggRobo is a robotic version of Dr Robotnik with similar abilities and speed. He is one of the unlockable characters.Mecha KnucklesThe Mecha Knuckles is a robotic version of Knuckles which is slightly faster than Knuckles. He is one of the unlockable characters.Super SonicSuper Sonic is arguably the best character of the game and also the hardest to obtain, as he requires all of the Chaos Emeralds. Super Sonic is the fastest of all the characters and can run across water. He is one of the unlockable characters.StagesThere are four initial stages within Sonic R to choose from, whilst the final stage is unlocked when all four stages are completed in first place. Those stages are:Resort IslandA traditional tropical stage based around the beach and mountains with a waterfall at the beginning of the stage.Radical CityA city at night based around old Sonic leves such as Casino Night. Within the middle of the stage is a pinball-style area.Regal RuinA ruined Egyptian themed stage at sunset, which contains imagery similar to Angel Island from Sonic the Hedgehog 3.Reactive FactoryA futuristic factory, similar to the fortresses of Dr Robotnik's lairs of previous Sonic games.Radiant EmeraldA beautiful stage set in space with a transparent ground, this is the longest of the stages and must be unlocked.SoundtrackThe music in Sonic R was composed by Richard Jacques and features pop-heavy songs performed by the British singer, TJ Davis. Those songs include:Can You Feel the Sunshine?- For Resort Island.Living in the City- For Radical CityBack in Time- For Regal RuinWork it Out -For Reactive FactoryDiamond in the Sky- For Radiant EmeraldSuper Sonic Racing- The Sonic R main theme and course track for Radiant Emerald if playing as Super SonicNumer One- The Sonic R Ending Theme and CreditsPlus two extra bonus tracks:Super Sonic Racing - X-Tra Club MixWork it Out - Red Raw MixEach stage also has an instrumental version which can be switched on and off within the game options menu.The Tails Doll LegacyBuy the Gamecube version to induce 60 pains per second.Tails Doll, one of the unlockable characters in Sonic R, evolved into an internet meme shortly after the release of Sonic Gem Collection, as the collection was the first to introduce many players to Sonic R. If players select Tails Doll in Sonic R the track "Can You Feel The Sunshine" plays regardless of the track selected. At all times Tails Doll floats lifelessly, eyes wide with a face void of any expression. These factors contribute to Tails Doll becoming an internet icon of evil and the perpetual myth that Tails Doll has the ability to curse players.Easter EggPutting the game disk into a standard CD player would play the in game soundtrack. This is possible because the in game music was stored as standard CD audio tracks on the game disk.Game CreditsExecutive Producer - Shoichiro IrimajiriProduct Manager - Youji IshiiProducer - Yuji NakaGame Design Directer - Takashi IizukaHead Artist - James CunliffeLead Artist - Dave BurtonGraphic Advisor - Naoto OhshimaLead Programmer - Jon BurtonCharacter Designer - Yuji UekawaMusic  Sound Producer - Richard JacquesMusic Vocals - T.J. DavisMap Design Director - Hirokazu YasuharaAdditional Artwork - Shigeru OkadaAdditional Artwork - Sean NadenArtwork - Bev BushTerrain System Programming - John Hodskinson</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15550">Kirby Air Ride</game><game id="20645">Mario Kart Wii</game><game id="11656">Rockman Battle &amp; Chase</game><game id="4902">Mad Dash Racing</game><game id="4236">Rayman Rush</game><game id="13772">Ostrich Runner</game><game id="26657">Sonic &amp; Sega All-Stars Racing</game><game id="19071">Super Mario Kart</game><game id="18757">Mario Kart: Double Dash!!</game><game id="15242">F-Zero</game><game id="18808">F-Zero X</game><game id="46">F-Zero: Maximum Velocity</game><game id="10084">Mario Kart 64</game><game id="31747">Mario Kart 7</game><game id="14113">Sonic Gems Collection</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1870233-box_sonicr.png</image></root>