<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22607</id><name>Super Robot Wars Alpha 2</name><description>Featured SeriesA list of the anime series which are featured in the game. Series that premiered in the Super Robot Wars series in this game are marked with "(new)".Mobile Suit Zeta Gundam Mobile Suit Gundam ZZ Mobile Suit Gundam: Char's Counterattack Mobile Suit Gundam 0083: Stardust Memory Mobile Suit Gundam F91 Mobile Suit Crossbone Gundam (new) Mobile Suit Gundam Wing: Endless Waltz Mazinger Z Mazinkaiser (Banpresto Original version) Great Mazinger Getter Robo G Shin Getter Robo (manga version) Steel Jeeg (new) Demon Sky Dragon Gaiking Super Electromagnetic Robot Combattler V Super Electromagnetic Machine Voltes V Brave Leader Daimos Demon God of War GoShogun King of Braves GaoGaiGar (new) Brain Powerd (new) Banpresto Originals (original characters created for the game)  This game, with the inclusion of Crossbone Gundam, is the first SRW to utilize a manga series' plot. Since Crossbone Gundam doesn't have an equivalent anime, its BGM is taken from the SD Gundam G Generation video game series. New FeaturesSquad System. A massive change to the traditional Super Robot Wars formula, each unit on the map now represents up to four robots. The general concept of this system has been used in every PS2 Super Robot Wars game since (with the exception of MX).ALL Attacks attack all members in a certain squad. Platoon Attacks allow each squad member to use an attack before the squad leader performs their attack. Support Defense is now carried out amongst squad members. Combination Attacks can still be carried out between two (or more) squad leaders; however, the player may now place the necessary robots in a single squad and perform a Combination Attack without needing to be adjacent to another unit.   Dynamic Kill. Usually, after a fatal attack, the enemy returns to a neutral state and says a line before exploding. However, attacks with Dynamic Kills have alternate animations for fatal hits which depict the enemy being destroyed mid-attack. The concept of extra animation for a fatal hit has existed before (as far back as Super Robot Wars 4), but this is the first game to use the modern, more well-known definition.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14489">Fire Emblem: Radiant Dawn</game><game id="222">Fire Emblem: Path of Radiance</game><game id="1121">Fire Emblem: Fuuin no Tsurugi</game><game id="12309">Fire Emblem: Monshou no Nazo</game><game id="20805">Fire Emblem: Ankoku Ryu to Hikari no Tsurugi</game><game id="18005">Fire Emblem: Seisen no Keifu</game><game id="14915">Fire Emblem Gaiden</game><game id="18540">Disgaea: Hour of Darkness</game><game id="2652">Disgaea 2: Cursed Memories</game><game id="9532">Disgaea: Afternoon of Darkness</game><game id="22722">Disgaea DS</game><game id="8721">Final Fantasy Tactics Advance</game><game id="12869">Tactics Ogre: The Knight of Lodis</game><game id="771">Front Mission 4</game><game id="6052">Front Mission</game><game id="17836">Front Mission 2</game><game id="13524">Front Mission 5: Scars of the War</game><game id="12489">Front Mission 1st</game><game id="17595">Front Mission 3</game><game id="3731">Phantom Brave</game><game id="451">Makai Kingdom: Chronicles of the Sacred Tome</game><game id="5580">Spectral Souls: Resurrection of the Ethereal Empires</game><game id="20613">Spectral Force 3</game><game id="831">Rhapsody: A Musical Adventure</game><game id="21355">Soul Nomad &amp; the World Eaters</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2504/407427-2nd_super_robot_wars_alpha_coverart.jpg</image></root>