<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22629</id><name>Rage of the Dragons</name><description>OverviewRage of Dragons story is about the master of the Black Dragon who plans to take over the world. It's the job of whatever characters you chose to stop him, before it's too late. The game has 15 characters to chose from. All the characters, except Abubo, fight in pairs with each character having a personal motivation for fighting, which you discover in the games endings.GameplayRush ComboRage of Dragons features tag-team gameplay. The object in a tag-team match is to defeat both characters to win. Your team of two characters each have a heath bar and you can switch between your two characters. You can also perform tag attacks like combo rushes and counter attacks that replace one character with the other. Your character also has a power meter that can perform individual specials attack when full. Your single character can perform their own combos that require a sequence of button presses to complete. Another gameplay element is the ability to knock your opponent against an object on either side of the screen to do even more damage. The game has a mini boss and a final boss. Each boss character has much more health and power than average.Giga-PowerNeo-Geo games in the late 1990's into early 2000 made games using the so-called Giga-Power. These games would feature improved graphics and sound that maximized the capability of the arcade console. It was also mostly a response to their rival Capcom's CPS-3 technology. Rage of Dragons features bright and fluid characters sprites. The game has an entire punk rock and rave theme to it that is clear in the character designs and the backgrounds. The music in the game is also mostly techno based, with a few differences in a couple of stages.Ports?Rage of Dragons would only get ported to the Sega Dreamcast, and only in Japan, as the Dreamcast in the United States died before the game came out.Playable Characterschoose your tag-teamBilly LewisJimmy LewisLynn BakerSonia RomanenkoAnnie MurakamiRadelPupa SalgueiroPepe RodriguezOniJae-Mo KangMr. JonesElias PatrickCassandraAlice CarrolAbubo (Sub Boss)Johann (Final Boss)</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9309">Marvel Super Heroes Vs. Street Fighter</game><game id="11156">X-Men vs. Street Fighter</game><game id="2612">Marvel vs. Capcom 2: New Age of Heroes</game><game id="13999">Kizuna Encounter: Super Tag Battle</game><game id="18240">The King of Fighters 2003</game><game id="15491">Double Dragon V: The Shadow Falls</game><game id="8605">Marvel vs. Capcom: Clash of Super Heroes</game><game id="2760">Art of Fighting</game><game id="13327">Art of Fighting 2</game><game id="8867">Art of Fighting 3: The Path of The Warrior</game><game id="7111">Savage Reign</game><game id="18554">World Heroes</game><game id="16064">World Heroes 2 JET</game><game id="10827">World Heroes Perfect</game><game id="19626">World Heroes 2</game><game id="10162">Tekken Tag Tournament</game><game id="5692">Samurai Shodown</game><game id="16407">Samurai Shodown II</game><game id="4363">Samurai Shodown IV: Amakusa's Revenge</game><game id="3387">Samurai Shodown V</game><game id="6538">Samurai Shodown V Special</game><game id="23535">Samurai Shodown VI</game><game id="21699">The King of Fighters '98 Ultimate Match</game><game id="5030">The King of Fighters XI</game><game id="617">NeoGeo Battle Coliseum</game><game id="20728">Tatsunoko vs. Capcom: Ultimate All Stars</game><game id="21519">The King of Fighters XII</game><game id="16400">Aggressors of Dark Kombat</game><game id="30940">Voltage Fighter Gowcaizer</game><game id="17631">Groove on Fight: Gouketsuji Ichizoku 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4737/533411-rageofthedragons.jpg</image></root>