<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22696</id><name>The Dishwasher: Dead Samurai</name><description>OverviewPlayers control a young man referred to as "The Dishwasher", who rose from the grave to seek bloody revenge. The Dishwasher is armed with two cleavers at first and builds his arsenal throughout the course of his adventure.Players hack and slash enemies until they are stunned and are susceptible to a finishing move by the simple press of a button. Players can use a strong or a quick attack, or alternatively opt for a grab move.  Game Modes  Story ModeThere are 14 levels of story mode and 5 difficulties: EasyNormalNinjaSamuraiTourney The levels are listed below.Note: During story mode there is a Guitar mini game in where you must press the correct button as it hits the middle box. Getting over 70% will earn you a pick, which is used in upgrades. Arcade ModeArcade Mode is comprised of 50 levels.  Each includes a number of rooms featuring a set number of enemies.  Each has  its own theme and equips you with two specific weapons and one magical power. These rooms can be played cooperatively with two or three people (however three person coop is unranked).  Additionally, according to the Ska Studios founder James Silva the Arcade rooms will sometimes employ certain modes such as:  Vampire:  Your health is constantly being drained, but monsters give more health when killed.Bullet Time:  All monsters move at half speed.Aerials:  Monster are only damaged while airborne. Learn those air combos!Instakill:  Everything deals 4x damage, so baddies turn into red mist pretty quickly. In the Arcade modes you do not play as the Dishwasher but as one of two Cyborgs Hunters. Thought at this stage to be called Loïc (the blue guy) and Hargreaves (the red guy). At this stage it is  unknown who or what the third co-op character is. The levels are listed below.Practice ModePractice your moves here.  Dish Challenge Fight off wave after wave to compete for the highest score.  This is sort of like the standard game arena, ranking overall score and a weekly rush score. This one is all about combos.  The way scoring works is a bit like Tony Hawk–the more hits and kills you get, the higher your multiplier is. Your multiplier is accumulated while you keep a combo running.  How can you tell a combo is running?  There’s a little red progress bar under your combo count that let’s you know–once the bar runs out, your combo ends and the combo score x multiplier is added to your current score. This leads to some super-addictive game play–the challenge for Dish Challenge is not to survive the level (well, it isn’t a cakewalk either) but to do it as one long combo. Weapons Melee WeaponsAll unlocked weapons in the game can be upgraded via the Halperbotshop. Each weapon has it's own version of the combos.  Meat Cleavers: The weapons you start the game with, the Dishwasher dual wields them. Using the right stick or holding LT and using the Left stick makes the Dishwasher do rolling dodges.Shift Blade (The Samurai Sword): The Dishwasher obtains this from the first boss in the game. The weapon grants teleporting abilities which replace rolling dodges when using the right analog stick. Uses Shadow Samurai Technology.Kama (The Scythes): Similar to the cleavers as they are duel wielded. Possibly replacing the meat cleavers in later levels. Uses Blade Frenzy.Chainsaw: A chainsaw with Ultimate Destructive Capabilities.   Long Range Weapons  Machine Gun/Shotgun : Regular attack uses the sub machine gun while heavy attack uses the shotgun.   Dish Magic  The Dishwasher can use magic by the use of green skulls. LevelsStory ModeFoghorn CafeIvy TrailGray FortressSt. Crux CemeteryNord TrainyardDrome RailL'Opera DramatiqueMeatron DistrictGrave ChapelMono CatacombsCam RooftopsCam LobbyIn ProcessingCam CoveArcade ModeGet Your Feet WetSwatfed!The PittBridge To NowhereOgremania!Robot Death CubeSkavoovie!Rooftop JocksJet SmashersNight At The OperaAlley RumbleFlying Cleaver StylePaybill RevengeZombie Smashers Yo!If You Were A Tree...Stone CuttingOne Way TicketRooftop RampageEnter The CatacombsFreaks And GeeksHostile TakeoverTricky NarrowsProcess This!Skyscraping!Fear The TechnologyShotty CreepsSwat SyrupL'Opera RobotiqueSkulls Of FrustrationCommandos, Living And DeadVulkies And VikesIt's Raining ZombiesBack To The StreetCemetery ManThe Killing YardDeath Is Coming!Ranting At The OperaGreen Skull VengeanceBoardroom BloodbathAltered StatesDoc's Last StandUbertanked!Zombies From Space!The LabyrinthVikings Don't Do DishesRobot RampageIt's Gray!I 3 HalloweenBoardroomblitzFinal Showdown</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6959">God of War</game><game id="20553">Ninja Gaiden II</game><game id="6681">Devil May Cry 4</game><game id="18122">Streets of Rage 2</game><game id="25714">Explodemon!</game><game id="890">Devil May Cry 3: Dante's Awakening</game><game id="13072">Devil May Cry</game><game id="16741">Devil May Cry 2</game><game id="21876">Ninja Gaiden</game><game id="11314">God of War II</game><game id="8112">Viewtiful Joe 2</game><game id="20922">Afro Samurai</game><game id="25637">Shank</game><game id="20710">Bayonetta</game><game id="26344">ZSX4 Guitarpocalypse</game><game id="26343">ZP2K9</game><game id="15148">Splatterhouse</game><game id="35887">They Bleed Pixels</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1858018-box_tdds.png</image></root>