<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22717</id><name>Mobile Suit Gundam: Federation vs. Zeon</name><description>GameplayAction can get intense. Mobile Suit Gundam: Federation Vs. Zeon is a third-person action-based mech game. It is in a very arcade like style, as you choose what "character" or rather which mech and which side to play on. You may choose mecha from either the Earth Federation or the Principality of Zeon. You may use a variety of weapons based on the mecha being used, ranging from laser canons to beam sabers. There are a variety of environments such as desert landscapes, large cities, and outer space. You can choose from a rather large selection of Mobile Suits and choose to complete one of around 200 of the game's missions. MultiplayerYou may choose from many a Gundam.There is a multiplayer option in which each player may choose a Mobile Suit to duke it out with over a split-screen.  In multiplayer mode you may choose any map and any Mobile Suit after you have unlocked in through the story mode. There is only one multiplayer mode, a simple deatmatch in which both players attempt to destroy their enemy's Mobile Suits. HistoryMobile Suit Gundam: Federation vs. Zeon is actually a port from a Japaenese arcade game, with some enhancements, to the Playstation. The arcade game, from the  Gundam Vs. series was originally named Kidou Senshi Gundam Federation Vs Zeon, also serving as the name of the Japanese release of the console game. The arcade game was hugely popular in Japan and never made it to North America, though the console port did. The Japanese release of the console version had made number one best-seller; Though the popularity of the North American version had not made such noise in the Video Game market.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8843">Mobile Suit Gundam: Zeonic Front</game><game id="16703">Gundam 0079</game><game id="21439">Gundam Side Story 0079:  Rise from the Ashes</game><game id="22513">Mobile Suit Gundam: Crossfire</game><game id="22604">Mobile Suit Gundam: Gundam vs. Zeta Gundam</game><game id="14084">TransFormers</game><game id="22533">Another Century's Episode 3: The Final</game><game id="26731">Mobile Suit Zeta Gundam: AEUG vs. Titans</game><game id="26122">Mobile Suit Gundam: Encounters in Space</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2421673-box_msgfvz.png</image></root>