<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22879</id><name>Mega Man 2: The Power Fighters</name><description>OverviewPromotional artworkMega Man 2: The Power Fighters was released for the arcade in 1996. It is a spin-off of the Mega Man franchise, and the sequel to Mega Man: The Power Battle. The game was developed and published by Capcom. It was later released on GameTap in 2006. The game was also part of the Mega Man Anniversary Collection for the PlayStation 2 and Nintendo GameCube. Mega Man 2: The Power Fighters and Mega Man: The Power Battle were both released in Rockman: Power Battle Fighters for the PlayStation 2. The game's story is quite simple; it involves Dr. Wily resurrecting his old Robot Masters and wreaking havoc.GameplayEach stage is a match between Mega Man and a Robot Master.Mega Man 2: The Power Fighters has four playable characters. The three characters from Mega Man: The Power Battle (Mega Man, Proto Man, and Bass) make a return, as well as one addition: Duo. Again, the game has a two-player mode (although only one of the two gets the Robot Master's weapon). As in Mega Man: The Power Battle, there are three paths that can be taken, each with different bosses and power-ups. The three paths are: searching for Dr. Wily, going to save Roll, or recovering stolen parts. Unlike the previous game, Mega Man 2: The Power Fighters allows players to select which Robot Master they wish to fight next.The game also has several other new features. One such is the ability to perform a special move. Each character has one, that is activated by releasing a fully charged shot while holding up on the joystick. Mega Man has the special move Mega Upper, which is a powerful uppercut. Proto Man has Proto Strike, a powerful energy blast. Bass has Crescent Kick, which is a rotating kick. Duo does an uppercut like Mega Man, but if the button is quickly pressed again, then Duo jumps up and slams the enemy to the ground.SoundtrackThe soundtrack.The soundtrack for Mega Man 2: The Power Fighters was released on September 21, 1996. It was called Rockman 2: The Power Fighters.OpeningPlayer SelectCourse SelectVs. - Stage StartPlant ManBubble ManHeat ManGyro ManCentaur ManShadow ManStage ClearGet WeaponCut ManDive ManStone ManRoll RescueElec ManShade ManSlash ManRankingNapalm ManGemini ManGuts ManReclaiming of the Neo PartsAir ManQuick ManPharaoh ManVs. - WilyMad GrinderYellow DevilMecha DragonWily MachineWIly CapsuleContinueGame OverEscapeRockman: Ending 1Rockman: Ending 2Blues: EndingForte: Ending 1Forte: Ending 2Duo: Ending 1Duo: Ending 2S.E. Collection</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10323">Metroid Fusion</game><game id="8605">Marvel vs. Capcom: Clash of Super Heroes</game><game id="20728">Tatsunoko vs. Capcom: Ultimate All Stars</game><game id="2612">Marvel vs. Capcom 2: New Age of Heroes</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/7465/463408-megaman2.png</image></root>