<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2288</id><name>Blood II: The Chosen</name><description>OverviewBlood II: The Chosen, much like the original Blood, is an ultra-violent horror FPS with a humorous tone. The game was once again developed by Monolith Productions and published by GT Interactive in 1998. In this game, the player once again controls Caleb or one of the Chosen and an arsenal of seventeen different weapons to take out hordes of enemies.In single player, the player can choose his character among one of the four Chosen (Caleb, Gabriella, Ishmael or Ophelia Price). However major plot holes occur if any other character other than Caleb is selected, such as in-game cinematics are not shown and the story does not develop properly. Each of these Chosen have different abilities. The game is divided into chapters, each of which is accessible only if the previous one is complete. PlotThe game takes place in the year 2028. Caleb, the protagonist, has spent the last century since the events of the first game searching for a way to resurrect his comrades, The Chosen, who were killed in the previous game by the Cabal, a cult dedicated to the worship of the evil god, Tchernobog. The Cabal, in the meantime, has spent the century since Tchernobog’s death by Caleb's hands turning the cult into a global mega-corporation called CabalCo, which uses its economic influence to control the world’s populace, all thanks to Gideon, the Cabal's current leader who has been raised to restore Tchernobog and destroy Caleb, now called the “Great Betrayer”. MultiplayerAlthough Blood II is primarily focused on the single player experience, it also features a multiplayer component. it's deathmatch component is the aptly titled "Bloodbath" mode for better reflects the game's title. Each player can choose one of the four Chosen to control during the match - Caleb, Gabriella, Ishmael and Ophelia. Since every character has different abilities, the weaponry they receive at the beginning of the game varies. LegacyAn expansion pack was released in August 1999 that provided background information on Caleb, Gabriella, Ishmael, and Ophelia as narrated by the deceased Gideon. As the Chosen continue to walk home to their world from the invading reality, they encounter a psychic beast known as the Nightmare. The Nightmare captures Caleb as a result of the Chosen attracting it by telling scary stories in which the player then has to relive some of the most horrific moments of the Chosen's lives. The expansion adds new enemies and re-introduces old ones and two new weapons - the combat shotgun and the flayer. The game also added new multiplayer modes and models, most of which were created during the development of Blood II, but never made it into the final project until the release of the add-on. Minimum System RequirementsWindows XP / Vista1.8 GHz processor512MB RAM (1 GB recommended)3D graphics card compatible with DirectX 7 (compatible with DirectX 9 recommended)2GB HDDMouseKeyboard</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11940">No One Lives Forever 2: A Spy in H.A.R.M.'s Way</game><game id="8569">KISS: Psycho Circus - The Nightmare Child</game><game id="15716">SiN: Wages of Sin</game><game id="20425">Painkiller: Battle Out of Hell</game><game id="6730">Painkiller</game><game id="13600">Painkiller: Overdose</game><game id="15660">Hexen II</game><game id="3061">Will Rock</game><game id="18837">Postal 2: Apocalypse Weekend</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1824021-box_blood2.jpg</image></root>