<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22956</id><name>Ibara</name><description>Ibara is a vertical bullet hell shoot 'em up developed by Cave and released in 2005. A port for the Playstation 2 was released in 2006. The game's main programmer was Shinobu Yagawa, the man behind Armed Police Batrider and Battle Garegga.StoryIbara takes place in an alternate version of the 20th century. The steam-powered engine has recently been invented, and the Northern European country Edelweiss is at the forefront of the technological and industrial development. However, a great threat appears: the insane Dr. Theresa Rose has decided that the human race is filthy and needs to be exterminated to make place for a beautiful rose garden, and her very first target is none other than Edelweiss. She and her five daughters (Lace, Shasta, Kasumi, and twin sisters Midi and Meidi) wreak havoc across the country under the name Rose Garden, leaving the Emperor with no choice but to send out his finest: the "negotiators" Bond and Dyne, to defeat the Rose Garden and save the country.ShipsShipPlayerFeaturesPlayer 1 - BondModerately fast, with narrow shotPlayer 2 - DyneSlower with wide shotVoice ActorsRose GardenTeresa - Chiharu KomineLace - Nami AokiShasta - Maiko MoriKasumi - Kumiko IshiharaMidi - Mao ShimuraMeidi - Asako NaitoNegotiatorBond - Daisuke MatsumotoDyne - Akira WakabayashiSpecial FormationsWide : Get 6 option items back-to-back.Search : Get 5 bomb-chips back-to-back then get option itemRolling : Get 5 symbols back-to-back then get option itemBack : Get 5 small shot items back-to-back then get option itemTechnical Info (Arcade Board)CPU: Hitachi SH-3 CPU, 133 Mhz ClockSound: Yamaha YMZ770C-FPlayers: 2Control: 8-way Joystick2 Button Control: 『A』 Shot, 『B』 Bomb</description><genres><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21341">Raiden Fighters Aces</game><game id="29473">Batsugun</game><game id="21928">Touhou 06 - The Embodiment of Scarlet Devil</game><game id="21929">Touhou 07 - Perfect Cherry Blossom</game><game id="21877">Touhou 08 - Imperishable Night</game><game id="21326">Touhou 10 - Mountain of Faith</game><game id="21327">Touhou 11 - Subterranean Animism</game><game id="25577">Touhou 12 - Undefined Fantastic Object</game><game id="22919">Battle Garegga</game><game id="33885">Muchi Muchi Pork!</game><game id="33886">Muchi Muchi Pork! &amp; Pink Sweets</game><game id="31088">Armed Police Batrider</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2291751-box_ibara.png</image></root>