<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22992</id><name>Super Robot Wars</name><description>StoryDeep in outer space, the evil monster known as Gilgilgun is born. Obsessed with destruction, it travels across the galaxy, destroying every planet that it comes by. The monster eventually reaches the Super Robot homeworld, and begins to use mind control to take possesion of the planet's denizens. Fortunately, some are able to elude its grip, and are now faced with the task of rescuing their friends and destroying Gilgilgun.Featured Series  A list of the anime series which are featured in the game. Most of these series would become mainstays in the SRW franchise.Mazinger Z Great Mazinger Getter Robo Getter Robo G Mobile Suit Gundam Mobile Suit Zeta Gundam Mobile Suit Gundam ZZ Mobile Suit Gundam: Char's Counterattack Mobile Suit Gundam F91 Starting Units Mazinger Team:        Mazinger Z, Aphrodite A, Diana A,        Great Mazinger, Venus AGetter Team:   Getter Robo,  Getter Robo G, Getter Q, Texas MackGundam Team:      Gundam, Guncannon,     Zeta Gundam, Hyaku Shiki, ZZ Gundam,    Nu Gundam, Gundam F91  GameplayAfter the game's opening, the player is asked which franchise he or she would like to play as ("Gundam Team", "Mazinger Team", or "Getter Team"). The player is then asked which robot they want as their team leader; this robot is considered the main character of the game, and although they gain 5 extra attribute points to be added to their stats, the game is over if they are destroyed. Finally, the player is asked which other characters that they want to add to their team, and the main game starts.Super Robot Wars is a strategy RPG; the player's force moves across grid-based battlegrounds to confront the enemy force, with the ultimate goal of capturing the enemy's main Tower. Along the way, the player may attempt to convince enemy robots, converting them into allies. Likewise, should the enemy destroy one of the player's robots, it may appear in a later stage as an enemy. This continues until the final stage, where the player's force faces off against the monster Gilgilgun.FeaturesExclusive to this GameTowers. There are towers scattered throughout the various battlefields in the game. Once a player unit reaches the Tower, the structure is captured; this yields an item and becomes a space for robots to recover their HP. Capturing a special tower causes the stage to end.Multiplayer Mode. This is the only single SRW to feature a two-player mode. (Super Robot Wars XO has multiplayer, but it is not SRW's traditional SRPG gameplay)Franchise MainstaysSpirit Commands. Known as seishin in Japanese, these are support "spells" that improve the robot's status (or occasionally hnder the enemy's). The modern Spirit Command system would not be introduced until Super Robot Wars 2; in this game, only the main character can use Spirit Commands, and the selection is randomized. In this game, SP represents the number of times the main character can look for a seishin to use; even if the player chooses none, SP is still lost.Items. Equippable items appear in every game in the SRW series (with the exception of Super Robot Wars 2G). However, this game allows the player to equip weapons onto robots, a feature which would only be used again in the Original Generation line of games.Convincible Characters. In every game in the series, characters who aren't quite evil can be convinced by a certain player unit depending on the situation. Usually, this leads to the enemy character joining the player's side. However, in this game, every enemy can be convinced by the player.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="39590">Zoids: Chuuou Tairiku no Tatakai</game><game id="40761">Out Live</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/16/160705/2261417-srwboxart.jpg</image></root>