<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23041</id><name>Super Robot Wars Compact 2 Part 2: Cosmoquake</name><description>Overview Super Robot Wars Compact 2 was the second         Super Robot Wars strategy RPG to be released on the WonderSwan. Like        Super Robot Wars F/      F Final before it, Compact 2 is split into multiple parts:   Part 1 and Part 2 occur simultaneously, while     Part 3  continues from Part 2. Using the WonderSwan's internal memory, players  can send their clear data to each successive game; several events are  altered based on the player's previous save, gained items are carried  over to Part 3, and a special final scenario can be unlocked by clearing  the entire trilogy within 777 turns. The game, like    its predecessor,  borrows almost all of its gameplay mechanics from F/F Final; however,  it introduces the "Support System" which immediately became a core  mechanic of the SRW franchise.   Earth Crisis introduces Ninja  Senshi Tobikage and Hyper Combat Unit Dangaioh, while Cosmoquake  features the debut of Machine Robo: Revenge of Cronos.   The entirety of Compact 2 was remade into  Super Robot Wars Impact for the PlayStation 2.Featured Series A list of the anime series which are featured in the game. Series that premiered in the Super Robot Wars series in this game are marked with "(new)". Special Note: As the events of SRW Compact 2-1 and Compact 2-2 occur  simultaneously, many robots will appear in a game, only to later  disappear from the roster completely; therefore, this list only covers  units that are available at the end of the game. For a more complete  series list, see           SRW Compact 2-3 or          Super Robot Wars Impact. Mobile Suit Gundam Mobile Suit Gundam 0083: Stardust Memory Mobile Suit Zeta Gundam Mobile Suit Gundam ZZ Mobile Suit Gundam F91 Mazinger Z* Great Mazinger* UFO Robo Grendizer Brave Raideen Invincible Super Man Zambot 3 Invincible Steel Man Daitarn 3 Super Beast Machine God Dancougar Machine Robo: Revenge of Chronos (new) Banpresto Originals (Original characters created for the game)   *Depends on a choice that the player makes in SRW Compact 2-1.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/16207/503703-srwc22.jpg</image></root>