<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23052</id><name>Super Robot Wars F Final</name><description>Featured SeriesA list of the anime series which are featured in the game. Series that premiered in the Super Robot Wars series in this game are marked with "(new)".  Mobile Suit Gundam Mobile Suit Gundam 0080: War in the Pocket Mobile Suit Gundam 0083: Stardust Memory Mobile Suit Zeta Gundam Mobile Suit Gundam ZZ  Mobile Suit Gundam: Char's Counterattack Mobile Suit Gundam F91 Mobile Fighter G Gundam New Mobile Report Gundam Wing New Mobile Report Gundam Wing: Endless Waltz (new) Mazinger Z Mazinkaiser (Banpresto Original version, new) Great Mazinger Getter Robo Getter Robo G Shin Getter Robo (manga version) Super Electromagnetic Robot Combattler V Invincible Steel Man Daitarn 3 Space Runaway Ideon (new) Aura Battler Dunbine Demon God of War Goshogun  Heavy Metal L-Gaim Super Beast Machine God Dancougar Aim for the Top! Gunbuster (new) Neon Genesis Evangelion Banpresto Originals (original characters created for the game) Masoukishin - Lord of Elemental (Banpresto Original storyline)  New FeaturesIde Gauge. Exclusive to the Ideon, the Ide Gauge increases as Ideon is placed in danger and decreases as enemies are destroyed. As the gauge increases, Ideon gains more abilities and weapons such as infinite EN and the Ideon Sword, with the strongest upgrade by far being the Ideon Gun MAP attack (with a base attack of 9999 and an infinitely expanding range, it is often considered the most powerful attack in the entire SRW franchise). However, if the gauge is raised too far, the Ideon goes beserk and attacks friend or foe. This system returns in Super Robot Wars Alpha 3, though without the beserker catch.Changes from Super Robot Wars 4Near the end of Super Robot Wars 4, Londo Bell (the protagonist group) decides that the Guests are a greater threat than the Divine Crusaders and fights them until the end of the game. In Super Robot Wars F Final, however, the choice is left up to the player, affecting the latter missions of the game. </description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23047">Super Robot Wars F</game><game id="3731">Phantom Brave</game><game id="23087">Neo Super Robot Wars</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/16207/505491-srwff.jpg</image></root>