<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2308</id><name>WWE Day of Reckoning</name><description>Roster Featured wrestlers                           Batista                         Big Show                        Booker TCharlie Haas                       Chavo Guerrero                      Chris Benoit                     Chris Jericho                    ChristianDanny BashamDoug Basham                   Eddie Guerrero                  EdgeGarrison Cade                 Hardcore Holly                John Cena               Kane              Kurt AngleLance StormMark Jindrak             Matt HardyMolly Holly            Randy Orton           Rey MysterioRhyno          Ric Flair         Rob Van Dam        Shawn Michaels       Shelton Benjamin      Stacy Keibler     The Rock    Triple H   Trish Stratus  Undertaker Val VenisVictoria Legends                                André the Giant                                Bret Hart   Brutus Beefcake   Greg Valentine                                Roddy Piper   Match TypesNormalHardcoreLadderTableTLC (Tables, Ladders, and Chairs)Steel CageHell in a CellBra  PantiesIron ManTag TeamTriple ThreatFatal 4 WayHandicapRoyal RumbleArenas    Raw   SmackDown!   WWE Heat   Royal Rumble 2004   No Way Out 2004   WrestleMania XX   SummerSlam 2003   Unforgiven 2003    No Mercy 2003   Survivor Series 2003   Armageddon 2003   House Show    Storyline A created superstar starts off as a new wrestler signed to a WWE developmental contract trying to work his way up to the main roster. After developmental comes a stint on Sunday Night Heat before the wrestler finally joins the main roster. You get to choose which brand your superstar enters (RAW or SmackDown!), which also chooses the stable they will enter for the story (                               Triple H's  Evolution for Raw,                                The Undertaker's New   Ministry for SmackDown!). While the created superstar works his way up the roster, the leader eventually becomes the shows' world champion, then starts kicking people off the team as they fail him or (as in the case of the created superstar) become a threat to his championship. The final battle is an iron-man match at   WrestleMania XX for the championship. The story is continued in the sequel,                                WWE Day of Reckoning 2, though under the assumption that the superstar chose Raw (which was essentially necessary because both brands end up being involved).</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="10">Wrestling</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12592">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2008</game><game id="20680">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2009</game><game id="6">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2007</game><game id="4315">WWE Crush Hour</game><game id="15815">WWE SmackDown! Here Comes the Pain</game><game id="3732">WWE WrestleMania X8</game><game id="13445">WWE Raw 2</game><game id="7552">WWE SmackDown! Shut Your Mouth</game><game id="487">WWE WrestleMania 21</game><game id="20723">WWE Legends of WrestleMania</game><game id="14912">WWE Road to Wrestlemania X8</game><game id="16374">WWE WrestleMania XIX</game><game id="30637">Lucha Libre AAA Heroes del Ring</game><game id="28430">WWF Royal Rumble</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2139891-box_wwedor.png</image></root>