<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23083</id><name>Super Robot Wars D</name><description>Overview Super Robot Wars D is the fourth Super Robot Wars game for the GBA. Unlike its (traditional) predecessor,  Super Robot Wars R, D offers a more diverse selection of anime series, getting rid of mainstays like G Gundam, Gundam 0083, Zambot 3/Daitarn 3 and Combattler V/Voltes V for debuting series like Daltanius, The Big O and Megazone 23.   Featured SeriesThis is a list of series that are featured in Super Robot Wars D. Debuting series are marked with "(new)." Mobile Suit Zeta GundamMobile Suit Gundam ZZMobile Suit Gundam: Char's CounterattackMobile Suit Victory GundamNew Mobile Report Gundam WingMazinger ZGreat MazingerUFO Robo GrendizerGetter Robo Armageddon (new)Future Robo Daltanius (new)Six God Combination GodmarsMegazone 23 (new)Macross 7 (new)The Big O (new)New FeaturesCombo Attacks. Some attacks (marked with "C" on the weapons menu) can strike multiple adjacent enemies. This feature would return in Super Robot Wars J and would be refined in Super Robot Wars W.Song System. The main characters of Macross 7 do not use traditional weaponry, instead they use the Song System. Songs mostly give stat boosts to allies, but can function as normal attacks against the Protodevilin (the antagonists of Macross 7, who reduce non-song damage by 50%). This system remains in Super Robot Wars Alpha 3, and Mic Sounders the 13th (from GaoGaiGar) uses a somewhat similar system in his appearances in the SRW franchise.Tsume Supa Robo. A set of side missions that ask you to complete certain objectives to obtain money and items. It returns in Super Robot Wars J.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21355">Soul Nomad &amp; the World Eaters</game><game id="14489">Fire Emblem: Radiant Dawn</game><game id="771">Front Mission 4</game><game id="13524">Front Mission 5: Scars of the War</game><game id="22982">SD Gundam G Generation Portable</game><game id="22475">Tear Ring Saga</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/10588/513512-1_2.jpg</image></root>