<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23082</id><name>Super Robot Wars R</name><description>OverviewSuper Robot Wars R is the second   Super Robot Wars game for the Game Boy Advance. The game adds no new mechanics to the franchise, and is identical to   its predecessor in many ways, including the usage of "static" sprites, much of the anime roster, and general interface. The game does, however, implement many of the changes introduced in   Super Robot Wars Alpha and   Alpha Gaiden that were not present in Super Robot Wars A.R removes the original Gundam series, Gundam 0083, Daimos, the classic Getter Robo series and Dragonar, and replaces them with Gundam X and the debuting Gear Fighter Dendoh, Shin vs. Neo Getter Robo, and Nadesico: Prince of Darkness.The story follows the Excellence Team, including main character   Raul or   Fiona Gureden (depending on  the player's choice), as they find themselves caught in the middle of the events of Nadesico: Prince of Darkness or Mobile Suit Gundam: Char's Counterattack. After an ambush by a mysterious entity, the Excellence Team is thrown into the past.Featured SeriesA list of anime featured in the game. Series that make their SRW debut in this game are marked with (new).Mobile Suit Zeta GundamMobile Suit Gundam ZZMobile Suit Gundam: Char's CounterattackMobile Fighter G GundamNew Mobile Report Gundam Wing: Endless WaltzAfter War Gundam XMazinger ZGreat MazingerUFO Robo GrendizerShin Getter Robo vs. Neo Getter Robo  (new)Super Electromagnetic Robo Combattler VSuper Electromagnetic Machine Voltes VInvincible Super Man Zambot 3Invincible Steel Man Daitarn 3Martian Successor NadesicoMartian Successor Nadesico: Prince of Darkness  (new)GEAR Fighter Dendoh  (new)</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14489">Fire Emblem: Radiant Dawn</game><game id="21355">Soul Nomad &amp; the World Eaters</game><game id="12489">Front Mission 1st</game><game id="771">Front Mission 4</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/10588/513413-2.jpg</image></root>