<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23139</id><name>Divinity II: Ego Draconis</name><description>StoryThe story begins several years after its predecessor,     Beyond Divinity, and the land of Rivellon has not fared well. After the apocalyptic wars of the previous games, the land lies fractured and shattered. And now the proud race of dragons has been corrupted by Damian, the child of chaos, in order to kill the Divine One. To defend the land, dragon slayers were trained to fight the dragons that plague the land, but the fight goes ill. You play a young dragon slayer initiate seeking to rid Rivellon of the dragon scourge, but you have been cursed with the ability to become that which you despise most -- a dragon.GameplayAs the cursed dragon slayer, you have the ability to fight as either human or dragon, including skills trees and weapons for both. The game also includes a complex quest system that includes quests that may be completed in multiple ways, each having its own consequences to the gameplay and storyline.      Battle in Divinity 2: Ego Draconis.     The game is played as a third-person hack and slash RPG with the choice  between either melee, ranged and magic attacks. Experience points are gained through quests and combat with players able to take on a  variety of side missions. Upon finishing quests, in addition to the awarding of XP and gold, players can also choose an additional reward such as more XP or various items. Mindreading also features, where in exchange for XP, you can attempt to read the mind of an NPC. This can reveal hidden secrets and information which can often lead to finding special items and other loot. Armour and weapons can also be upgraded. Charms offer fixed and  permanent improvements, while enchantments can be applied and removed as required, although the requisite enchantment formula is required to create it. The ability to morph into a Dragon allows the player access to otherwise unreachable locations and features heavily during the second half of the game. Your dragon form can also be improved by special dragon armour and a variety of skills.   Flames of Vengeance / Dragon Knight SagaContinuing the story of Ego Draconis, an expansion titled     Flames of Vengeance was released for the PC. It features a new campaign, an upgraded graphics engine and additional items.    The Dragon Knight Saga is a compilation of both a remastered version of Ego Draconis (including new content and updated graphics) and the Flames of Vengeance expansion. The Dragon Knight Saga was released on both PC and Xbox 360. PC System Requirements Minimum System Requirements OS: Windows XP / Vista Processor: 1.8Ghz Intel Dual Core (or better)Memory: 1GB (XP) / 2GB (Vista) HDD: 9GB of free hard disk space Video Card: 256MB DirectX 9.0c with 3.0 shader model support (Nvidia 7600 / ATI Radeon X1600) Sound Card: DirectX 9.0 compatible sound card DirectX: 9.0c (XP) / 10 (Vista) Installation: DVD-ROM  Recommended System Requirements   OS: Windows XP / Vista Processor: 2.6Ghz Intel Dual Core (or better)Memory: 2GB HDD: 9GB of free hard disk space Video Card: 512MB DirectX 9.0c with 3.0 shader model support (Nvidia 8800 / ATI Radeon X3800) Sound Card: DirectX 9.0 compatible sound card DirectX: 9.0c (XP) / 10 (Vista) Installation: DVD-ROM  </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20901">Sacred 2: Fallen Angel</game><game id="10473">The Witcher</game><game id="7753">Gothic 3</game><game id="20238">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion</game><game id="14759">Two Worlds</game><game id="23081">Risen</game><game id="1804">Gothic II</game><game id="1982">Gothic</game><game id="17367">The Elder Scrolls III: Morrowind</game><game id="30939">Crusade of Destiny</game><game id="33129">Divinity II: The Dragon Knight Saga</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1825079-box_div2ed.png</image></root>