<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23229</id><name>Wurm Online</name><description>Overview   Wurm Online is a First Person MMORPG in which the players have no set goals or objectives.  Players are free to pursue whatever they're interested in, be it creation of infrastructure(Houses, villages, towns, docks, roads etc are all made by the players), fighting monsters or other players, or being a merchant supplying hard to find materials from around the world.    Gameplay     The basic gameplay consists of gathering materials and combining them into various tools and objects that are more useful, or used to create even more advanced items.  Along with just the basic building of items, players need to be concerned with their health, water, food and stamina levels.  Players can also train weapon and combat skills for use in hunting or in PvP combat on the PvP enabled servers.  Finally, religion mechanics allow players to worship specific deities and learn spells and enchantments.     Players start with only the very basic tools needed to survive in the world and must make everything else from necessities(food) to luxuries or more permanent items to make their mark on the world.  Most players start out making a few simple items, mainly clay jars for water transportation and bowls for cooking in to sustain themselves for longer journeys or tougher projects.  Gathering materials can range from easy to near impossible depending on your current location and the item you need, adding an incentive to trade with other players.   Monsters complicate the system by making some areas less accessible or far more dangerous to travel.     Every action taken is based on a skill system.  By digging a ground tile you increase your digging skill, allowing you to dig on more sloped surfaces, and the more clay items you make the better you skill becomes in that area allowing more complex and higher quality items to be crafted.  The World     One of the more impressive aspects of Wurm Online is the way players are able to shape the world.  Through massive terra-forming efforts and lots of time players have created large roads into the wilderness and large settlements in which to live and work.  The world on each server is very large (Over 512 sq Km according to the developer), and this gives players ample room to live and create their character's homes.  From single home settlements, to larger villages and market hubs, all of the players can create what they wish and carve out their small portion of the world.       Scattered throughout the world are different types of resources used in crafting all of the items you see.  From trees and forrests for wood, grass tiles for forraging berries and nuts, and all the way to iron and gold deposits mined underground, everything is player gathered and created into every item you see as you travel the world.    Paid Subscription Model     Wurm online has a PvE server open to free accounts as well as paid accounts allowing new players to experience the world as its created by higher level characters.  Free accounts have their skills capped at 20 (out of a possible 100) locking them from creating some of the more advanced items (stone walls most notably).  PvP and Kingdom vs Kingdom servers are paid accounts only. </description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7109">Stranded II</game><game id="20239">Tail of the Sun</game><game id="27224">Roma Victor</game><game id="31934">Xsyon</game><game id="37435">Haven &amp; Hearth</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/22191/775472-logo_small.jpg</image></root>