<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23289</id><name>Robotica</name><description> GameplayRobotica plays like a lot of shooters did at the time. There are 30 levels, most of them having a maze like design. Sometimes, a light swich must be found in the level before it is completely visible. Additionally, a computer can be found in each level that will reveal the full map, and each level can only be completed when a key is collected. There are a number of guns and sub weapons in the game. Main Weapons Arm Punch - Melee attacks an enemy. Vulcan - The weakest gun. Laser - Stronger then the Vulcan but fires at a slower rate. Missile - The strongest weapon, but the ammo is limited.Sub WeaponsBlaze Lazer - Terminates all enemys that are currently on screen.Hover Jet - Moves forward at a fast speed. Power Booster - Increases attack power. Plasma Barrier - Increases defence. Re Fresh - Revives health. All 3 of the the normal guns can be upgraded, either with an item or using a cheat system. Enemy TypesQuattro: Will run into you and explodeArobit: A Hovering robot that will shoot at you with lasers, it is stationaryVolcano: Ground unit that fires a Vulcan cannonGriffith: Stronger version of the Volcano, has two Vulcan cannonsCurve-Goon: Similar to the Arobit, but it can move and uses a powerful Head-mount Cannon   ReceptionAt the time of it's release, Robotica was praised for it's music and, then impressive visuals, but was criticized for it's repetitive nature.</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7694">Wolfenstein 3D</game><game id="3407">Duke Nukem 3D</game><game id="621">Doom II: Hell on Earth</game><game id="750">Final Doom</game><game id="16788">Doom 64</game><game id="10469">Heretic</game><game id="42403">The Starship Damrey</game><game id="1921">Marathon 2: Durandal</game><game id="20232">Marathon</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/6087/555597-g06827yfed3.jpg</image></root>