<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2328</id><name>Singstar 90s</name><description>TracklistsInternational TracklistAll Saints - Never Ever Aqua - Barbie Girl B52's - Love Shack Barenaked Ladies - One Week Billy Ray Cyrus - Achy Breaky Heart The Cardigans - Lovefool The Cranberries - Zombie Crash Test Dummies - Mmm Mmm Mmm Mmm The Cure - Friday I'm In Love Divinyls - I Touch Myself EMF - Unbelievable Gins Blossom - Hey Jealousy Lisa Loeb - Stay (I Missed You) MC Hammer - U Can't Touch This Meredith Brooks - Bitch M-People - Movin' On Up Natalie Imbruglia - Torn New Kids On The Block - Step By Step Nick Cave  Kylie Minogue - Where The Wild Roses Grow Poison - Unskinny Bop Radiohead - Creep R.E.M. - Everybody Hurts Roachford - Only To Be With You Savage Garden - I Want You Seal - Kiss From A Rose Sir Mix A Lot - Baby Got Back Spice Girls - Wannabe Spin Doctors - Two Princes Technotronic feat. Felly - Pump Up The Jam Wet Wet Wet - Love Is All Around  American Tracklist Arrested Development - Tennessee Boyz II Men - Motownphilly Chumbawamba - Tubthumping Color Me Badd - I Wanna Sex You Up Divinyls - I Touch Myself En Vogue - Free Your Mind Extreme - More Than Words Gin Blossoms - Hey Jealousy Hootie And The Blowfish - Only Wanna Be With You Jesus Jones - Right Here, Right Now Len - Steal My Sunshine MC Hammer - U Can’t Touch This Natalie Imbruglia - Torn Nirvana - Lithium Paula Abdul - Opposites Attract Poison - Unskinny Bop R.E.M. - Everybody Hurts Santana feat. Rob Thomas - Smooth Savage Garden - I Want You Seal - Kiss From A Rose Sir Mix A Lot - Baby Got Back Sixpence None The Richer - Kiss Me Soundgarden - Black Hole Sun Spin Doctors - Two Princes Technotronic feat. Felly - Pump Up The Jam The Cranberries - Zombie Vanilla Ice - Ice Ice Baby Wilson Phillips - Hold On  </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21171">Lips</game><game id="15661">Karaoke Revolution</game><game id="23524">SingStar: Queen</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/495/273668-box.185.1180350206.jpg</image></root>