<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2332</id><name>Continuum</name><description>Published by Data East in the United States and Infogrames elsewhere (where the game was called Alpha Waves), this early 3D platformer is actually  one of the first fully polygonal games.  It is an abstract puzzle-solving game with two different modes.  One, a free exploration mode called Emotion, allowed you to traverse the many rooms of the game without limit (with some restrictions), while Action timed your progress, forcing players to figure out how to exit a room before the time limit expired.  Players explore the environment using one of several vehicles, each with different performance statistics.  Some bounce higher more easily, while others turn quicker or move faster. Each room has its own set of challenges, with certain polygonal creatures sometimes obstructing or attacking, and platforms that the player vehicle has to bounce on in order to reach the exit doors.  Some exit doors in the game are blocked forcing players to find ways around them or unlock them.     Each cube represents a room.  Dream is the largest section, and where you start in Action mode.  Each section, or emotion, has several rooms, and an accompanying mood  (conveyed by colors and difficulty) and a different musical score, which  you can sample in the selection screen (right):   The ultimate goal is elusive; most will simply explore the rooms, trying to stay alive for as long as possible (or in the case of the Emotion mode, eventually run out of places to explore).        According to designer     Christophe de Dinechin, there IS a way to beat the game.  There are several stars scattered throughout the worlds which, if collected individually, give you extra time in Action mode.  If you collect ALL of the stars from all of the zones though, you win.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5933">Virus</game><game id="13417">Vaxine</game><game id="8214">Pyrotechnica</game></similar_games><image>NONE</image></root>