<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23401</id><name>Shakugan no Shana</name><description>Plot SummarySakai Yuuji, a normal high school student, finds out he's dead. On his way home, he witness a shocking image as the world suddenly froze: a monster resembling a doll was engulfing blue flames that emanated from people Just as the monster was about to consume Yuuji, a sword-wielding girl with flaming red eyes and hair saves him from the monster. The girl called herself a "Flame Haze" people who hunt the "Guze no Tomogara", creatures from another world. As Yuuji notices a blue flame in his chest, she calls him a "Torch", a temporary replacement, saying that the "real" Yuuji's existence had already ended. Unfazed, Yuuji befriended the strange girl, named her "Shana", and joined her fight against Tomogara and other Flame Hazes.  Gameplay   Shakugan no Shana is a visual novel, an interactive anime game using static graphics, with a battle system and dating sim elements. The game follows the events of the first season, allowing series veterans to predict what will happen. The choices made throughout the game determine which of the five endings the player receives at the end of the game.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22554">Suzumiya Haruhi no Yakusoku</game><game id="23358">Suzumiya Haruhi no Tomadoi</game><game id="23402">Zero no Tsukaima: Shouakuma to Shunpuu Concerto</game><game id="23403">Hayate no Gotoku! Boku ga Romeo de Romeo ga Boku de</game><game id="23422">Hayate no Gotoku! Ojousama Produce Daisakusen Boku Iro ni Somare!</game><game id="23595">Zero no Tsukaima: Muma ga Tsumugu Yokaze no Gensoukyoku</game><game id="23948">Zettai Karen Children DS: Dai-4 no Children</game><game id="24247">Dengeki Gakuen RPG: Cross of Venus</game><game id="24471">Nanatsuiro Drops</game><game id="33549">Ore no Imouto ga Konna ni Kawaii wake ga Nai Portable</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/112/573040-boxart.jpg</image></root>