<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23452</id><name>Angelique</name><description>OverviewAngelique is a dating sim otome game developed by Ruby Party, a division of Koei consisting fully of females. It was originally released on September 23, 1994 for the SNES, and has since been ported countless of times, often including additional features. Version DifferencesAngelique SpecialAngelique Special was the first port of the game. It was originally released on December 22, 1995 for PC-FX, and was later ported to PC, Sega Saturn, and PlayStation on March 29, 1996. It adds to the game voice acting by several big-name voice actors, in addition to new animated cutscenes. The PC version is said to be extremely hard to find.  Angelique Voice Fantasy Angelique Voice Fantasy was released on the very same day as Angelique Special, and adds all of the voice acting found in Angelique Special to the original SNES game using a CD and an add-on deck called Voicer-kun.  Angelique Duet  Angelique Duet is the latest revision of the Angelique game. It was originally released on July 30, 1998 for Sega Saturn and PlayStation, and later ported to the Nintendo DS on April 6, 2006. The biggest addition to the game is the option to play as not only our usual heroine Angelique Limoges, but also her rival Rosalia de Catargena.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23440">Princess Debut</game><game id="23472">Tokimeki Memorial Girl's Side: 2nd Kiss</game><game id="23429">Tokimeki Memorial Girl's Side</game><game id="23967">Hiiro no Kakera DS</game><game id="24349">Harukanaru Toki no Naka de: Yume no Ukihashi</game><game id="24137">Arabians Lost: The engagement on desert</game><game id="24350">Harukanaru Toki no Naka de</game><game id="24343">Otometeki Koi Kakumei Love Revo!!</game><game id="24355">Hoshizora no Comic Garden</game><game id="41592">Sweet Fuse: At Your Side</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/112/581901-587862_4977_front.jpg</image></root>