<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23559</id><name>Priston Tale</name><description>ClassesThe classes of Priston Tale are split by two factions; Morion and Tempskron. The difference between these two are starting location and class availability and each class is tied to a specific gender that cannot be changed.TempskronTempskron Mechanician (Male) : The main tank class in the game primarily wielding claw weapons and shields. Fighter (Male): The class best excelling in close proximity battles dealing huge damage albeit with slower attack speed.Pikeman (Male): The spear/pike wielding class that has the longest range of all melee classes with a higher critical hit ratio.Archer (Female): A long range damage dealer that can be accompanied by a falcon which periodically attacks the target for additional damage.Morion Morion  Knight (Male): The "Paladin" class of the game who specialized in holy attacks primarily giving damage bonuses to the undead.Atalanta (Female): The class with a mix of melee and range abilities with use of spears or javelins accompanied by shields.Priestess (Female): The only healing class in the game and the most physically weakest, using various magic spells such as Divine Lightning to defeat enemies.Magician (Male): The only pure spell-casting class in the game using various elements such as fireball and summoning elementals to do his bidding.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16614">Ragnarok Online</game><game id="22542">Ragnarok Online 2: The Gate of the World</game><game id="18603">World of Warcraft: The Burning Crusade</game><game id="20701">World of Warcraft: Wrath of the Lich King</game><game id="2268">RuneScape</game><game id="18547">EverQuest II</game><game id="1036">RYL: Path of the Emperor</game><game id="22187">Flyff - Fly For Fun</game><game id="22085">CABAL Online</game><game id="9641">Age of Conan: Hyborian Adventures</game><game id="20666">Warhammer Online: Age of Reckoning</game><game id="1119">Diablo II</game><game id="15589">Diablo II: Lord of Destruction</game><game id="22228">Helbreath</game><game id="23571">Scions of Fate</game><game id="23583">ROSE Online</game><game id="22087">Silkroad Online</game><game id="25615">Ys Online: The Call of Solum</game><game id="24482">Husky Express</game><game id="24448">Luna Online</game><game id="26467">Dragonica</game><game id="29110">Dream Of Mirror Online</game><game id="27070">Mu Online</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/481/600222-ptlogo.png</image></root>