<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23583</id><name>ROSE Online</name><description>Stat pointscharacter obtains stat points as they progress in their adventures. There are six unique stats in total: Strength, Dexterity, Concentration, Sensibility, Intelligence and Charm. Strength, Dexterity and Concentration mainly benefit melee characters, while Sensibility and Intelligence benefit more to the magic type characters, Charm is beneficial equally to all classes, There are no restrictions on which stat points players can add to their characters. Below you will find descriptions and effects of each stat point:Character status.Strength (STR): Increases your maximum hit points, damage of melee weapons, defensive abilities and also increases your maximum inventory weight.Dexterity (DEX): Increases dodge rating, movement speed, damage done with katars and long ranged weapons.Intelligence (INT): Increases your maximum mana points and your magical offensive and defensive abilities.Concentration (CON):Increases health and mana recovery speed, crafting success rate, accuracy and attack power with guns and launchers.Charm (CHA): Increases the reward bonus gained after completing quests.Sensibility (SEN): Increases chance to deal a critical strike and increases the chance for the overall quality of your item to be increased while crafting.System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows XPMemory: 1 GB RAMGraphics: GeForce2 MX 400/Radeon 7000DirectX®: 9.0Hard Drive: 3 GB HD spaceOther Requirements: Broadband Internet connectionRecommendedMemory: 2 GB RAMDirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 5 GB HD spaceOther Requirements: Broadband Internet connection</description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16614">Ragnarok Online</game><game id="22542">Ragnarok Online 2: The Gate of the World</game><game id="23559">Priston Tale</game><game id="23572">Priston Tale 2</game><game id="22228">Helbreath</game><game id="21958">MapleStory</game><game id="22187">Flyff - Fly For Fun</game><game id="22085">CABAL Online</game><game id="23571">Scions of Fate</game><game id="22087">Silkroad Online</game><game id="24801">Angels Online</game><game id="25460">Conquer Online</game><game id="25615">Ys Online: The Call of Solum</game><game id="24482">Husky Express</game><game id="21707">Fury</game><game id="24448">Luna Online</game><game id="26467">Dragonica</game><game id="21909">Atlantica Online</game><game id="29110">Dream Of Mirror Online</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3257/607020-roseonlnelogo.jpg</image></root>