<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23619</id><name>Dynasty Warriors: Gundam 2</name><description>Overview Dynasty Warriors: Gundam 2 is the sequel to 2007's Koei-Bandai mash up. The new installment dramatically increases playable mobile suits.  Also, an original mode has been changed to mission mode where pilots not only have story missions but other various missions to gather items or gain relationships. Official Mode As in the first game, this mode lets the player select a mobile suite and play its missions like how they play off in the anime. When the player first start the game, only Amuro Ray, Char Aznable, Kamille Bidan, and Judau Ashta are available to play. Once the player beats a character, a new character will be unlocked.Mission ModeWhen the player first starts off, only Kira Yamato, Athrun Zala, Shinn Asuka, Seabook Arno, Uso Ewin, Domon Kasshu, Master Asia, Heero Yuy, Milliald Peacecraft, and Rolan Ceahack are available to play but more will be unlocked once the character is completed. Story Mission In this mode the player plays missions base off a original story.Free Mission Like the title, this mode allows players to choose a level freely and play it. tutorials missions are also located here.Friendship Mission In this mode, the player will interact with other pilots and different options on how to respond will be presented to the player and there response determines how the other pilot will interact with the player. Keeping the pilot alive in battle also raises the friendship level, the latter also occurs if the pilot is defeated. Some missions here can not be played until the pilot's friendship level is at a certain point. Collection Mission Here the player chooses a mission and fights only one type of enemy for the sole purpose of collecting parts to complete a "grunt" suit.License Mission This mode is directly related to the Collection mode. Once a player a player has completed a "grunt" suit, they can not use it right away. The player must first pass a License mission to activate the suit playable.Extra Mission These are missions that are unlocked when certain variable are meant while playing through levels.Mobile Suit Lab This area allows the player to combine parts found in battle to form a "grunt" suit.Lounge Here the player can check license or relationship info. Also the player can change the skills the player wants to have. Terminal Here the player can interact with other characters. Interactions consist of RPG like dialogue where the player must choose from a list of responses to answer the character. Depending on how the player responds, the character will ether be friendly to the player (possible invitation to his or her army) or will be hostile.  MultiplayerThere is offline and online multiplayer in the game that supports up to 4 players. A player can select any suit and play one of 3 modes on any map.   War Mode In war mode the first player to finish the mission objective or reach 1000 points is the winner  Sudden Death Mode This is an all-out brawl where the player with the most points wins  Hunting Mode Each player is designated as a hunter or target. A hunter gets points for destroying a target, and a target gets points for evading a hunter. Game PlayMobile Suits (Playable):RX-93 Nu Gundam MSN-04 Sazabi ZGMF-X20A Strike Freedom ZGMF-X19A Infinite justice ZGMF-X42S Destiny Gundam F91Gundam Formula 91 LM314V21 Victory Gundam WD-M01 Turn A Gundam XXXG-01W Wing Zero Gundam  YMS-15 Gyan GF13-017NJ II God Gundam MSZ-010 ZZ Gundam MSZ-006 Z Gundam RX-78-2 Gundam ZMT-S33S Gottrlantan Concept-X 6-1-2 Turn X Gundam MS-14S Gelgoog Commander Type RB-79 Ball RX-77-2 Guncannon MS-07B Gouf MSN-03 Jagd Doga (Gyunei Guss Version) MSN-03 Jagd Doga (Quess Paraya Version) MSN-00100 Hyaku Shiki RX-178 Gundam Mark II (AEUG Version) RX-179 Gundam Mark II (Titans Version) PMX-003 The O AMX-004 Qubeley RX-139 Hambrabi PMX-001 Palace Athene PMX-002 Bolinoak Sammahn AMX-004-2 Qubeley Mark II AMX-004-3 Qubeley Mark II AMX-107 Bawoo GF13-001NHII Master Gundam OZ-13MS Gundam Epyon Musha Gundam  Musha Gundam Mark II MS-07H Gouf Flight Test Type MSM-07 Z'Gok MS-06V Zaku Tank RMS-099 Rick Dias RGM-79GS GM Command Space Type NRX-055 Baund Doc RGZ-91 Re-GZ RGM-89 Jegan MSN-02 Zeong RX-160 Byarlant   Mobile Armors:MA-08 Big Zam MRX-009 Psyco Gundam MRX-010 Psyco Gundam Mk-II NZ-000 Quin Mantha NZ-333 Alpha Azieru JDG-00X Devil Gundam  Grunt Suit Creation A "Grunt" suit can only be created if all of its parts are collected. To collect parts, the player must complete missions (the parts are acquired in game but will be lost if the player losses the level). Once the player acquires the parts necessary, the player must enter the "Mobile Suit Lab" under "Mission Mode". Here the player can select what parts the player wants to combine into a suit. There are 5 different parts the player must acquire in order to complete the suit. Body, Left Arm, Right Arm, Left Leg, Right Leg. Each part has a level and extra stats. There are 4 levels of parts but the stats associated to them are created at random.  GalleryThere is a gallery section in the game that showcases All the characters that are in the game, including a bio. There is also a mobile suit and ship viewer. If the player has fought alongside or against anyone, then they will appear in this mode to be viewed. In the gallery section the player can also cycle through all of the music on the disk.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23198">Samurai Warriors 2</game><game id="26645">Trinity: Souls of Zill O'll</game><game id="37103">Sengoku Basara 3 Utage</game><game id="6513">Bladestorm: The Hundred Years' War</game><game id="38478">Sengoku Basara HD Collection</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1820022-box_dwg2.png</image></root>