<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23631</id><name>Snow Sakura</name><description>OverviewSnow Sakura was first developed and released as 雪桜 (Japanese: Yukizakura) for the Windows PC in Japan by D.O. Corp on November 28, 2003. It was later translated ad released in the USA by G-Collections on December 13, 2007.PlotMy name is Yuuji Tachibana, a regular student with no particular plans for the future - until my parents left for Hawaii on a business trip last fall, leaving me in the care of my uncle in the wintry countryside of Hokkaido.Small-town life on Japan's northern island didn't have time to get dull, as from the moment I got there I was reunited with my cousin and childhood friend Saki. She's pretty demanding, but when I'm hanging out with her and her school friends I don't mind; as I get close to them I feel like I'm finding meaning in life that I didn't know I was looking for.Legend says there is a flower that blooms here in the depth of winter... as the twilight deepens and a snowflake melts in the palm of my hand, I stand with a beautiful girl by my side. Will we be able to uncover its mystery in this fleeting moment?HeroinesMisaki Souya - Younger sister of Misato and best friend of Kozue. Cheerful but shy and airheaded.Kozue Hiyama - Close friend of Misaki and idolizes her. Observant and meticulous but has an inferiority complex.Saki Tachibana - Cousin of Yuuji Tachibana. Energetic, critical, and violent.Rei Kisaragi - Third year student and a shrine maiden. Intelligent and studious.Misato Souya - A teacher and older sister of Misaki. Hard-working but extremely clumsy and airheaded.GameplaySnow Sakura is a visual novel that features a non-linear branching narrative which requires players to make choices of up to 3 options that will lead to one of the different story lines focusing on one of the 5 heroines which their own endings.The story diverges roughly at halfway point. One feature of Snow Sakura is that it will present a intermission screen featuring the portrait of the heroine who currently has the highest intimacy with the player. As such, a blank intermission screen signifies either 2 or more girls with equal intimacy level or insufficient intimacy with any girl to properly advance the story.CreditsCharacterVoice ActorMisaki SouyaAsakura SuzuneKozue HiyamaShion MiyabiSaki TachibanaAoyama YukariRei KisaragiTakazuki SakuraMisato SouyaAya UranSumiyoshi ItouHamada HiroshiTakeaki TachibanaTaida NikudanYuuji TachibanaShimazaki Hiro</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12166">Bible Black -La Noche de Walpurgis-</game><game id="14699">The Sagara Family</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/112/703745-snow_sakura_package.jpg</image></root>