<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23669</id><name>Code Geass: Hangyaku no Lelouch</name><description>     This is a game classic RPG/adventure format exclusively for the  Nintendo DS system and published by  Namco Bandai. based on the popular anime series Code Geass Lelouch of the Rebellion. The series is the original creation of the anime's director, Goro Taniguchi  the writer, Ichirou Ohkouchi. Produced by the Sunrise company that created the ever popular Gundam franchise. The game roughly follows the basic plot of the first season of the anime, and ends with the same story points as the series. Though, it takes liberties in several segments to create certain          boss fights that never occurred in the anime.  One of the more publicized functions of the game was from the use of the DS's built in mic. Much as with the popular  Ace Attorney series, Code Geass implemented context sensitive voice commands. The player will take on the role of the commander of battles and could give voice commands for who should attack. With proper timing, this could initiate certain combos. The game was released in Japan on October 25th 2007. No U.S. release date has ever been established and after several years of waiting. It seems unlikely the game will ever officially reach the the Western shores in any way other than imports of the Japanese version. Rather peculiar given the popularity the series had when it aired.PlotThe story takes place in an alternate-history        Earth of 2017 where the American Revolution either never occurred or failed. The Britannian Empire eventually attacks and conquers the nation of   Japan for it's resources. As part of their attack, they used mechs called the Knightmare Frames (KMF). Basically, bipedal mobile tanks of great power and maneuverability.Britannia strips the island nation of it's name and calls it Area 11. Even the people are reclassified as Elevens. A young-cast way Britannian prince,         Lelouch Lamperouge, was living in secret  with his crippled sister Nunnally for seven years in Area 11 . His life is drastically changed when he literally stumbles into an attack by Japanese rebels. In the commotion, he comes across a mysterious, green-hair young girl named       C.C. who grants him a power called Geass. With this power, he can command the wills of others, and he plans to use this ability to destroy the Empire and it's leader, his own father. To accomplish this plan. Lelouch gathers the strength left in Japan under the guise of the masked leader Zero, and he forms an army of his own called the Black Knights. This includes a fellow classmate of his named      Kallen Kozuki, who is a half-blood of Japanese and Britannian descent. Kallen is the ace pilot of the deadly Knightmare Frame called the Guren Mk-II. The only force standing in their way is Lelouch's childhood friend     Suzaku Kururugi. Despite being Japanese, he wishes to change Britannian from within, and is unaware that Lelouch is Zero. He is the pilot of Britannia's most powerful KMF, the Lancelot.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23621">Super Robot Taisen OG Saga: Endless Frontier</game><game id="11881">Xenosaga I+II</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/238/624360-code_geass_hangyaku_no_lelo.jpg</image></root>