<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23689</id><name>Penny Arcade Adventures: On the Rain-Slick Precipice of Darkness - Episode Two</name><description>OverviewPenny Arcade Adventures: On the Rain-Slick Precipice of Darkness: Episode Two was released on October 29th on Xbox Live Arcade, PlayStation Network, and PC. It costs $14.95 or 1200 Microsoft Points. Even though this is the second episode of the series, the game allows you to start a brand new character or continue with the character you started in Episode One. The game takes place in mostly the same areas as the first game, but changes them up a bit in order to give them a fresh feel. It was also developed and published by Hothead Games.StoryThe story begins after a short break between the first episode where Gabe and Tycho are continuing fighting Fruit Fuckers and searching for Fruit Fucker Prime. They end up crashing their truck into the your (the Player’s) new home after having your first home destroyed in Episode One . Gabe and Tycho ask you to rejoin them in searching for the giant Fruit Fucker. The party visits Anne-Clare who informs them that she has discovered the creator of the Fruit Fuckers: Dr. Crazoir. He is being held at the sanatorium that Tycho’s father and grandfather were held in. Anne-Clare also requests that the group bring her materials for an experiment. She requires silk thread, a golden bolt, an engine, and a molecule of Energite.You, Gabe, and Tycho arrive at the sanatorium and meet Dr. Crazoir. He explains that he is not insane and that he needs documents to free him. In return, he will give the group materials regarding his research and a robot monkey card. They give the receptionist flowers, chocolate, and jewelry before they are allowed access to the building. The party confronts the owner of the sanatorium, Dr. Wolfington, who gives them an ink blot test which results in them being classified as insane.You must then perform a minigame with the aid of Twisp and Catsby in order to fight off the injections causing you to become insane. Once you regain consciousness, you find Gabe and Tycho locked in cages. You set them free and release large spiders containing the silk that you need. After confronting Wolfington a second time, you engage him in combat. Once he is defeated you take the release papers for Crazoir as well as Wolfinton’s diary. The group then returns to your destroyed home and find the truck engine.The party returns to Crazoir who reveals that he was asked a favor by “M” to make the Fruit Fuckers. M’s address is given and the group head off to his apartment. They are met by Charles DuBois who is looking for an apartment at the same time you are. You fight Charles for the available room during a “wimpy boss fight” while Tycho investigates M’s apartment. He finds several demonic artifacts and returns with them after Gabe accidently sets the building on fire while baking a pie.Gabe, Tycho, and you then head off to the Symposium On the Future of Man where you must get an autograph of Dr. Lars Krangle for Anne-Claire. In order to gain access to the Symposium, you must gain credentials by winning a robotic monkey fight. The group uses Mr. Tails (who Gabe is extremely affectionate toward) and gives him three monkey cards in order to win. The prize for winning is a trophy that contains a molecule of Energite. You receive a bolt from one of the doctors which you cover in gold in order to make it slightly heavier. Dr. Lars Krangle gives a keynote speech only to be then crushed by Fruit Fucker Prime who is being controlled by Mordo von Mundo. He proceeds to kill everyone except your party and Dr. Blood. Dr. Blood explains that the Fruit Fuckers run on Darksteam and gives you a ticket to the World’s Fair.Fruit Fucker Prime wrecks his way to the World’s Fair where he begins to fornicate a giant orange dome. You, Gabe, and Tycho discover that Anne-Claire is no longer in her room and proceed to pursue Mundo. After you activate a train that crashes into the orange dome, the party faces Fruit Fucker Prime on the rooftop. During the fight, he is able to heal himself completely from all of the damage he is inflicted. Suddenly, Anne-Claire arrives in a giant doll robot which was the result of her experiment. The giant doll defeats Fruit Fucker Prime and the group finds the Necrowombicon. Dr. Blood reveals himself to be Dr. Raven Darktalon Blood and the third verse of the Quartet for the Dusk of Man is read.System RequirementsPCMinimumOS: Windows® 2000/XP/Vista™ with latest updatesProcessor: Pentium® III, AMD Athlon™ 1.0 GHz or betterMemory: 512 MB of available system memoryGraphics: ATI Radeon™ 9500 or better, NVIDIA GeForce™ FX 5200 or better, Intel® GMA 950 or better with 64 MB of video memory (shared or dedicated)Sound: OS-supported sound cardHard Drive: 350 MB of available hard drive space (185 MB installed)Input Devices:  OS-supported keyboard and mouseNote: All video cards require latest drivers supporting OpenGL®.RecommendedProcessor: Pentium® IV, AMD Athlon™ 1.5 GHz or betterMemory: 768 MB of available system memoryGraphics: ATI Radeon™ or better, NVIDIA GeForce™ or better video card with 128 MB of video memory*Sound: 16-bit stereo- or surround-capable sound card with latest driversMacMinimumOS: Mac OS X 10.5 or later with latest updatesProcessor: Intel based Mac 1.5 GHz or betterMemory: 1 GB RAMGraphics: ATI Radeon x1600 or better, NVIDIA GeForce 9400 or betterHard Drive: 350MB</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20587">Strong Bad's Cool Game for Attractive People Episode 1: Homestar Ruiner</game><game id="6049">Sam &amp; Max Save the World</game><game id="21670">Wallace &amp; Gromit's Grand Adventures Episode 1: Fright of the Bumblebees</game><game id="2426">Dreamfall: The Longest Journey</game><game id="32304">Costume Quest</game><game id="34211">Hector: Badge of Carnage</game><game id="6479">Freedom Force</game><game id="8894">Freedom Force vs The 3rd Reich</game><game id="36978">South Park: The Stick of Truth</game><game id="32108">Faery: Legends of Avalon</game><game id="41569">Mario &amp; Luigi: Dream Team</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2891/625549-precipice2.jpg</image></root>