<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23727</id><name>Iji</name><description>StoryEarth is under attack by evil aliens called "Tasen". It's up to the cyborg Iji to save the remaining people of the planet. She is guided by her brother Dan through loudspeakers that are placed throughout the levels. Dan convices Iji to call on an alien taskforce consisting of a different alien race, the Komato, to help Iji wipe out the Tasen. But the Komato are not the salvation that Dan and Iji thought they were. In actuality they, also, try to destroy the Earth and all its inhabitants, because their sworn enemies the Tasen are there - fleeing from the ruthless Komato.GameplayThe combat in Iji is real time, each enemy has a Nano-shield that can be taken down a number of ways before the actual enemy can be defeated, once the enemy is defeated Iji can assimilate the remnants of their nanoshield to gain experience.Iji can access 8 basic weapons unlocked through skill points and these weapons can be combined to create new more powerful weapons provided that Iji's crack stat is high enough.e.g. combining the Shotgun and Machine gun will give you the Buster gun, a more powerful automatic shotgun which uses machinegun ammo.InfluencesDaniel Remar, creator of Iji, has admitted that System Shock 2 was a major influence, despite the game being almost nothing like System Shock 2.The game also has echoes of Castlevania and Metroid and utilizes some basic cover mechanics from games like kill.switchSoundtrackThe music for Iji was done by Chris Geehan and Dan Byrne McCullough with the exception of Further by VNV Nation.The music for Iji also had some contributions from Tom Mauritzon and Daniel Remar.Make Your Mind Up - Chris Geehan  Dan Byrne McCulloughKinda Green - Chris Geehan  Dan Byrne McCullough3 Cans Later - Chris Geehan  Dan Byrne McCulloughWelcome to the Party, Pal - Chris Geehan  Dan Byrne McCulloughFor Stronger Bones - Chris Geehan  Dan Byrne McCulloughSeven Four - Chris Geehan  Dan Byrne McCulloughFace to Face - Tom MauritzonTor - Chris Geehan  Dan Byrne McCulloughFurther - Composed by VNV Nation (Covered and performed by LifeForce; edited for length by Daniel Remar)Main menu - Men And You - Chris GeehanLevel Clear - Chris Geehan  Dan Byrne McCulloughDark Stroke - Chris Geehan  Dan Byrne McCulloughLightstroke - Light Stroke - Chris Geehan  Dan Byrne McCulloughAll That Can Wait - Chris Geehan  Dan Byrne McCulloughHade Shade - Chris Geehan  Dan Byrne McCulloughGlass Soldier - Chris Geehan  Dan Byrne McCulloughAsha - Chris Geehan  Dan Byrne McCulloughGame Over - Chris Geehan  Dan Byrne McCulloughHero (Wretched8 Remix) - Composed by Machinae Supremacy (Covered by Captain Goodnight)Doom - Chris Geehan  Daniel Remar½ fabrikat - Internal SFX sequence player by Daniel RemarLinksOfficial Website</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1066">Flashback: The Quest for Identity</game><game id="8292">Super Metroid</game><game id="9530">Seiklus</game><game id="20124">Cave Story</game><game id="39476">The Hive</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/25515/950112-iji_2009_04_09_21_25_30_07.jpg</image></root>