<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23769</id><name>Hatsune Miku: Project DIVA</name><description> Release  Hatsune Miku: Project DIVA was released in Japan on July 2nd 2009. The game is yet to be released overseas, but due to the Vocaloid software being a Japanese voice synth tool, popularity outside of Japan is little in comparison.   Those that ordered the special edition of the game received a petit nendoroid figurine of             Hatsune Miku.   Gameplay  As with typical rhythm games, points are earned by hitting notes to the beat of the music. Notes in Project DIVA come in two halves:  Static Notes: These will be the first to appear on the screen. They come in four different shapes, matching the            PSP buttons. The notes also come with a ticker hand, starting at a 12 o’clock position and turning clockwise until again reaching a 12 o’clock position. It is at this point that the correct shape should be pressed.  Moving Notes: These will fly from off-screen and land on their respective static note counterpart. They are timed so that they will overlap perfectly when the ticker on the static notes reaches a 12 o’clock position. Pressing the correct button completes the note and you are awarded points accordingly.   The more accurate you are, the more points you will receive. This ranges from 0 (for a miss) to 500 points. The combo metre will also increase your score. Missing a note or pressing the wrong button will reset your combo.   In the bottom left of the screen is a sphere with a music note. This acts as a life meter of sorts, rising and emptying depending on how well you play. The song will end should the sphere deplete.  Songs  The game ships with 39 songs split by different colour tags. The following songs are listed by their tag colour and their Japanese, Rōmaji  and English names.   Songs that seemingly only have an English name are called the same for all three.   Pink Tag Songs  ワールドイズマイン  - Warudo Izu Main - World is Mine  ひねくれ者  – Hinekuremono - The Rebel  恋は戦争  - Koi wa Sensou - Love is War  その一秒スローモーション  - Sono Ichibyuo Suroumoushon - That One Second Slow Motion  メルト  – Meruto – Melt   Blue Tag Songs Far Away  ストロボナイツ  – Sutorobonaitsu - Strobo Nights Star Story Last Night, Good Night Packaged   Orange Tag Songs  雨のち Sweet*Drops - Ame Nochi Sweet*Drops - Sweet*Drops After the Rainミラクルペイント  - Mirakuru Peinto - Miracle Paintフキゲンワルツ  - Fukigen Warutsu - Bad Mood Waltzマージナル  – Maajinaru - MarginalDreaming Leaf - ユメミルコトノハ - - Dreaming Leaf - Yumemiru Kotonoha - - Dreaming Leaf -Dreaming Words-  Yellow Tag Songs  荒野と森と魔法の歌  - Kouya to Mori to Mahou no Uta - Song of Wastelands, Forests, and Magic  荒野と森と魔法の歌 ( レン ver.) - Kouya to Mori to Mahou no Uta (Ren ver.) - Song of Wastelands, Forests, and Magic (Len ver.)  荒野と森と魔法の歌 ( リン ver.) - Kouya to Mori to Mahou no Uta (Rin ver.) - Song of Wastelands, Forests, and Magic (Rin ver.)  ハト  – Hato - Pigeon moon  みくみく菌にご注意 ♪  - Mikumiku-kin ni Gochuui ♪  - Beware of Miku Miku Bacteria ♪   いのちの歌  - Inochi no Uta - Song of Life  いのちの歌 ( レン ver.) - Inochi no Uta (Ren ver.) - Song of Life (Len ver.)  いのちの歌 ( リン ver.) - Inochi no Uta (Rin ver.) - Song of Life (Rin ver.)   Sky Blue Tag Songs  The secret garden Dear cocoa girls  天鵞絨アラベスク  - Birodo Arabesuku - Velvet Arabesque  ラブリスト更新中 ？  - Rabu Risuto Koushinchuu? - Updating Your Love List?  桜ノ雨  - standard edit - - Sakura no Ame - standard edit - - Rain of Cherry Blossoms - standard edit –   White Tag Songs  恋スルＶＯＣ ＠ ＬＯＩＤ  - Koi Suru VOC@LOID - VOC@LOID in Love Ievan Polkka  あなたの歌姫  - Anata no Utahime - Your Diva  えれくとりっく・えんじぇぅ  - Erekutorikku Enjyeu - Electric Angel  初音ミクの消失  - Hatsune Miku no Shoushitsu - The Disappearance of Hatsune Miku  金の聖夜霜雪に朽ちて  - Kogane no Seiya Sousetsu ni Kuchite - Golden Holy Night Rotting into the Frost and Snow  みくみくにしてあげる ♪ 【してやんよ】 - Miku Miku ni Shite Ageru ♪ (Shite Yanyo) - I'll Make You Do the Miku Miku ♪  (You'll Do It)              Collectables  As a reward for completing songs, players are often given items to decorate Miku's room with. These include furniture, instruments and wallpapers. It is also possible to unlock new costumes (or modules) when certain conditions are met. While there are regular clothes included, changing costume can in some cases change your character to another Vocaloid. There are also special costumes from other       Sega games, notably         Valkyria Chronicles and        Space Channel 5.  Downloadable Content  On the Japanese      Playstation Network, you can purchase a content pack that adds nine new songs, PV’s, a mini-game and more. The new songs are accessed through the song creation menu rather than the regular game, so you will not see them in the same list as the original 39 songs.   Sequels      Hatsune Miku Project DIVA 2 is scheduled to be released in Japan on the 29th of July 2010. This will also be for the PSP console, and promises to add new features such as eight notes instead of four, new music and new game modes. An    arcade version has also been announced. </description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21598">THE iDOLM@STER</game><game id="25668">Rockin' Pretty</game><game id="25028">DJMAX Trilogy</game><game id="17021">DJMAX Portable</game><game id="21232">DJMAX Portable 2</game><game id="24424">DJMAX Portable: Clazziquai Edition</game><game id="24618">DJMAX Portable: Black Square</game><game id="30577">K-On! After School Live!</game><game id="40015">Megpoid the Music</game><game id="36393">Hatsune Miku and Future Stars: Project Mirai</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/112/1091238-front.jpg</image></root>