<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23833</id><name>Tekken 6: Bloodline Rebellion</name><description>OverviewJin and his father KazuyaTekken 6: Bloodline Rebellion is an updated version of Tekken 6 (originally being an Arcade exclusive). Bloodline Rebellion retains all features introduced in Tekken 6 (the bound and rage systems, as well as item moves), and all of the characters in Tekken 6 are set to return. Two brand new characters, Lars Alexandersson and Alisa Boskonovitch will also be included.Console ReleaseTekken 6: Bloodline Rebellion was released in Japanese and North American arcades on the 18th of December 2008, with a home console release confirmed by Namco Bandai themselves at a pre-Tokyo Game Show event. On October 8th, 2008, it was revealed by Katsuhiro Harada that Namco will release Tekken 6: Bloodline Rebellion on the Playstation 3 and Xbox 360 in Fall 2009 with more content than the arcade version. The release was later set at October 27, 2009. Previous to this announcement, it was announced by Namco during a press conference that Tekken 6.0 would not be appearing on any console, and that Tekken 6 Bloodline Rebellion would replace it. There are rumors that console exclusive characters similar to the vein of the Soul Calibur franchise's approach would happen for the console versions. Namco themselves relieved their interest in doing this, however they stated that it would be difficult as Sony and Microsoft would be reluctant to agree to have the two versions be different.Portable ReleaseA screenshot of the PSP versionOn April 28, it was reported from Namco Bandai's Gamers Day conference that Tekken 6: Bloodline Rebellion would be appearing on Sony's Playstation Portable, alongside the already announced Xbox 360 and PS3 versions. However it's release was moved back to November 24, 2009, as opposed to October 27 for the consoles. Namco also stated that there would be additional content, such as additional stages and customization options, although it is unknown if they are reffering to the content added to Bloodline Rebellion expansion, or if the PSP version will get content that the console versions will not. Also confirmed, is Ad-Hoc multiplayer.AdditionsApart from the two new characters (Alisa Boskonovitch and Lars Alexandersson) there are various things that have been added to Tekken 6 with the Bloodline Rebellion update. A total of six new stages have been added, including the "Electric Fountain", "Tunnel Disaster", "Anger of the Earth and "Lightning Storm" stages that were shown when the Bloodline Rebellion update was announced.Two other stages have since been found through the games release in Japanese arcades, including a grassy meadow with sheep in the background (reminiscent of Jun Kazama's Tekken 2 stage) called "Hidden Retreat" and a fiesta stage called "Fiesta del Tomate" (these two stages can only be selected by choosing random on the stage select menu before a fight.).Hidden Retreat StageAdditionally new ranks have been confirmed (such as the "Swallow in Flight" rank) as well as lots of new moves and countless new customizations for each character.GameplayThe two new characters duking it outGameplay features introduced in Tekken 6 return in Bloodline Rebellion. First and foremost the rage system, where a player will turn into rage mode when they have 5% or less remaining health in their health bar, making their attacks much stronger. As well as the bound system, where the opponent will bounce off the floor upon being hit by certain moves during a juggle, thus enabling the player to continue their combo. Bloodline Rebellion also features new item moves, such as Bryan's gatling gun, Miguel's guitar, Raven's projectile blades and Xiaoyu's wand. There are various new fighting styles and moves.Other ChangesOn November the 6th to November the 9th 2008 Namco held a location test on Tekken 6: Bloodline Rebellion two arcades in Japan. Reports from players who played the near-final build of the game (if not the final build) indicate that most of the changes to the characters involve nerfing instead of buffing (characters have been weakened instead of being made stronger). For example, Kazuya's "Electric Wind God Fist" attack, which is considered to be one of the most powerful attacks in the game, has been slowed down from 13 frames to 16 frames (meaning Kazuya's "CH d/f 2 EWGF" launch can now not be performed, and also that the move is now much easier to counter). Other characters have been similarly nerfed, with Bob's d/f 2 now not launching on normal hit and now only on critical hit and Jin's hop kick only launching on critical hit. Some characters however have been buffed, such as Heihachi and Lili.Additionally, wall damage has been reduced, with the opponent slumping on the wall for a much shorter amount of time, reducing the amount of possible wall hits. The low parry system has also changed, with the player being parried going straight into the bound position.StoryJin salutes his army, as he continues to wage his war against the WorldAt the conclusion of The King of Iron Fist Tournament 5, Jin Kazama defeated his great grandfather and tournament sponsor Jinpachi Mishima and won the tournament, as well its its grand prize - the Mishima Zaibatsu. Jin immediately changed the direction of the company, beginning various programs within the company and converted the Tekken Force into a spy project. People began suspecting darkness in the president of the Mishima Zaibatsu, which lead to increased tension, fighting and eventually a full-scale war with the entire world drawn into the confilict. With nations beginning to lose power, war became a profitable option for the Mishima Zaibatsu, which lead to Jin announcing the Zaibatsu as an independent nation, declaring war on the entire world.Initially, the Mishima Zaibatsu proved to be a formidable enemy, but then the G Corporation, lead by Jin's father Kazuya Mishima, rose to become the Zaibatsu's main opposition. The world saw G Corporation as its savior, and endorsed them completely in their attempt to suppress the Zaibatsu. G Corporation claimed that the president of the Mishima Zaibatsu was the root cause of the war, and announced that they will pay an immense amount of money to anyone who can capture Jin Kazama dead or alive. G Corporation's current CEO and chairman, Kazuya Mishima, took over the company after killing those within it who betrayed him just after The King of Iron Fist Tournament 4. As if the Mishima Zaibatsu anticipated this move, the Mishima Zaibatsu announced the opening of The King of Iron Fist Tournament 6.Meanwhile, among the ranks of the Tekken Force, a young soldier named Lars Alexandersson has begun a rebellion to slowly dismantle the Mishima Zaibatsu and G Corporation in order to put an end to the war. During an operation, Lars stumbles across a sleeping female cyborg, identifying her as Alisa Bosconovitch. G Corporation forces attack, starting a fight and causing an explosion that kills almost everyone present at the scene and leaves Lars with amnesia. Lars escapes with Alisa and the two begin a journey to discover their origins, meeting and fighting several previous Tekken characters. Jin along with his top subordinates, Nina and Eddy, learn this and issue a manhunt for Lars.During the journey Lars reunites with his lieutenant, Tougou, and the two keep in touch. Gradually, Lars begins to recover from his amnesia and remembers that he is the illegitimate son of Heihachi Mishima. Who is now living in solitude but still plotting to retake the Zaibatsu from Jin. Lars locates and confronts Heihachi, prepared to kill him, but relents at the last minute and leaves, turning down Heihachi's proposal that they work together to defeat Jin. Lars eventually comes into contact with Lee Chaolan who serves as an aid and contact for Lars after Lars rescues Lee's friend, Julia Chang, from a G Corporation facility. At the same time, Kazuya hears of Lars's exploits and sends his men to kill him.Lars and Alisa's journey eventually leads them to G Corporation, where they are confronted by a squadron of armed soldiers. Tougou and his men arrive to provide back-up for Lars while Lars and Alisa confront and defeats both Anna and Kazuya. Lars and Alisa manage to escape, but Tougou is killed in battle, and Lars vows to avenge him. They then hijack a Zaibatsu subway train to get to the Mishima Zaibatsu's Central Tower, although they are ambushed along the way by Nina and a squadron of Tekken Forces. Despite the odds, Lars defeats the soldiers and kicks Nina off the train.Lars and Alisa reach the tower and confront Jin, aided by Nina who survived the fall. In a plot twist, Jin reboots Alisa's memory bank and sets her on Lars, revealing that she was built the whole time to protect him and that he has been using her to monitor Lars's actions, although the G Corporation attack was not part of Jin's plan. Lars fights and manages to defeat Alisa, who flees the scene. Raven suddenly arrives having been tailing Lars and Alisa throughout their journey and offers help, and as he saw Jin heading for the desert, Lars accepts.Lars and Raven locate an abandoned temple in the middle of the desert said to be the home of the demon known as Azazel, or the Rectifier. Inside the temple Lars and Raven find and confront Kazuya once again, Kazuya learning, to his disgust, that Lars is his half-brother. After the fight Kazuya leaves the temple with Anna. Lars and Raven reach the heart of the temple and locate Azazel. During the fight, Azazel tells Lars that he is merely a creation of man, and that it is time for him to destroy humanity to make them atone for their sins, but as he is too injured to continue fighting, Azazel apparently self-destructs. Lars and Raven flee the temple as it collapses.Once outside, they are confronted by Jin once again, who sets Alisa on them. Lars and Raven defeat Alisa, who reverts to her old self and shares a brief, tearful reunion with Lars before expiring. Jin insults Alisa which enrages Lars and starts another fight. It is then that Jin finally reveals his intentions: having known about Azazel for a long time since Zafina's story, Jin knew that the only way to awaken Azazel was to fill the world with negative emotions, and the best way was starting a war. Jin also tells Lars that Azazel is not yet dead and can only be destroyed by someone who carries the Devil Gene, so Jin can be freed from the Gene, saving the worlds from the Gene's schemes and revive all many peoples who became a victim of the war, even Tougou. Indeed, Azazel, now much stronger, suddenly erupts from the rubble, but Jin, powering himself up with the Devil Gene, approaches Azazel being immune to his attacks, punches his fist straight through the beast's chest and sends the both of them plummeting to their apparent deaths. Nina appears and contemplates Jin's selfless act and leaves. Lars and Raven take Alisa's body to Lee who promises to repair her as soon as possible. Lars bids farewell to Raven, before Raven leaves, he gave Lars his Rebel badge after the revived Tougou gave it to Raven. Lars then receives a call for a new job, the conversation left a mystery to the player.A post-credits scene shows that Raven and his colleagues have found Jin's half-buried body in the desert. Whether he is dead or alive is left ambiguous, although the latter is more likely, as the Devil Tattoo is still visible on Jin's arm indicating that Azazel's demise has apparently not freed him of the Devil Gene. In the morning Alisa was successfully revived in Violet System Lab because Lee promised his younger brother Lars to repair her.Note: It is Rumored that Kazuya's ending is Canon due to him being in the middle of the cover that and he is the only one that fights Devil Jin.This proves that Kazuya might have won the tournament and possibly defeats Lars, Heihachi, and Jin/Devil Jin but it is yet to be confirmed. But the Devil Orb might be apart of it as well.New CharactersLarsLars AlexanderssonAs the Mishima Zaibatsu waged war on the world, its soldiers, the Tekken Force, began a worldwide coup d'etat. G-Corporation, lead by Kazyuya Mishima, rose to power and was their main opposition, leading to worldwide conflict. The mastermind behind the coup d'etat was Lars Alexandersson, a young, charismatic Tekken Force officer with incredible physical ability and intellect. Most importantly, he is the son of Heihachi Mishima, and no one, save for Lars himself knows this. Not even Heihachi himself.AlisaAlisa BoskonovitchDeep within a lush and thriving forest lies a heavily defended research facility. This facility was a research institute named after its director, Bosconovitch. This facility was very important, as it was here that the Mishima Zaibatsu's most sensitive military equipment was developed.Located at the core of the researcher center was a room that kept its most prized possession: a clear capsule, in which a young girl slept soundly. Her name: Alisa Bosconovitch.Returning CharactersFrom Tekken 6:BobLeoMiguel Caballero RojoZafinaAzazel (unplayable)NANCY-MI847J (unplayable)From previous games:Anna WilliamsArmor KingAsuka KazamaBaek Doo SanBruce IrvinBryan FuryCraig MardukChristie MonteiroDevil JinEddy GordoFeng WeiGanryuHeihachi MishimaHwoarangJack-6 (Jack)Jin KazamaJulia ChangKazuya MishimaKingKumaLee ChaolanLei WulongLiliLing XiaoyuMarshall LawMokujinNina WilliamsPandaPaul PheonixRavenRoger Jr.Sergei DragunovSteve FoxWang JinreiYoshimitsuStagesAzazel's Chamber (Final Boss stage)Cemetery (Multi-tier)City After DarkFallen Colony (Multi-Tier)Fountain (new to Bloodline Rebellion)Gargoyle's Perch (sub-boss Jin Kazama's stage)High Roller's ClubLightning Storm (new to Bloodline Rebellion)Manji ValleyMystical ForestNancy-MI847J's Stage (stage has no official name, but is a bonus stage)Noh TheaterRustic AsiaTemple GroundsTemple of Earth (new to Bloodline Rebellion)Tunnel Disaster (new to Bloodline Rebellion)Urban War ZoneRankingsRankings are titles earned by IC-Card possessing users at arcades by defeating a certain amount of opponents. Defeating opponents earns you points (which are not shown) and when a player amounts a certain amount of points, he will be given a promotion chance. As you rank up, you must earn more points in order to earn a promotion chance. This ranking system will also be in the home console version of Tekken 6: Bloodline Rebellion (as it was in Tekken 5 and Tekken 5: Dark Resurrection) where the game will use the same point system (although it is much easier to rank up in home versions than it is the arcade versions).The ranking system is quite simple, players who are of similar ranks will earn more points from defeating there opponent. For example, if two players on 3rd Dan play each other, the victor will earn more points than if he defeated someone 3 ranks above or below him (it is a common misconception that defeating higher ranked players will earn you more points). Players also lose points when they lose matches, and similarly, losing to a similarly ranked opponent makes you lose more points than you would losing to a player who is not of a similar rank. After a certain amount of points is lost, the player will earn themselves a "Demotion Risk", wherein if they lose the match, they will go down one rank.Bloodline Rebellion Rankings:Beginner9th Kyu8th Kyu7th Kyu6th Kyu5th Kyu4th Kyu3rd Kyu2nd Kyu1st Kyu1st Dan2nd Dan3rd Dan4th DanMentorMaster飛燕 Rogue餓狼 Brawler猛虎 Marauder飛龍 Berserker剛拳 Warrior狂拳 Avenger魔拳 Vindicator滅拳 Juggernaut修羅 Vanquisher羅刹 Destroyer羅漢 Conqueror羅将 Survivor夜叉 Champion紅蓮 Overlord無双 Sage拳聖 Legend朱雀 Suzaku風神 Fujin雷神 Raijin鬼神 Yaksa戰神 Raksasa武神 Asura龍王 Dragon Lord鐵拳王 Tekken Lord鐵拳大帝 Tekken Emperor鐵拳霸皇 Tekken God</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7792">Dead or Alive 4</game><game id="20456">Street Fighter IV</game><game id="20449">Mortal Kombat vs. DC Universe</game><game id="20749">Virtua Fighter 5 R</game><game id="30364">Ys vs. Sora no Kiseki: Alternative Saga</game><game id="28865">Naruto Shippuden: Clash of Ninja Revolution 3</game><game id="25042">Mortal Kombat</game><game id="20831">Castlevania Judgment</game><game id="36412">Dead or Alive 5</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1887909-box_tekken6.png</image></root>