<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23882</id><name>DJ Hero</name><description>OverviewAfter many rumors, DJ Hero was finally confirmed to be in development on January 20, 2009.  Developed by                  FreeStyleGames and published by                  Activision, DJ Hero allows the player to experience the life of a club DJ using a wireless turntable                  peripheral. The controller is split up into two sections. The first is the turntable, which has a replica disc with three buttons on it, capable of full 360-degree spinning movement. The mixer portion contains a cross-fader, euphoria button, an effects dial, and a panel which, when opened, reveals the D-Pad, face and home buttons. Gameplay A rendering of the turntable controllerGameplay features a similar highway of traveling notes reminiscent of the                  Guitar Hero games. Players must hit the corresponding button as its' designated color note travels down the screen. The formula is mixed up as players must move the crossfader into certain positions, and scratch the record when prompted to.  In the game’s easy/medium difficulties, players are free to scratch in whatever direction when the designated scratch notes appear. As the difficulty moves up, scratches become notes that must be scratched in specific directions as related to the song (For example, the game may ask you to scratch forward twice, then backwards).The game's Euphoria button (equivalent to Guitar Hero's Star Power) is used to double the players' scores while the Effects dial (similar to the Whammy bar) allows players to put a personal touch on the pre-mixed songs. A Rewind feature is also included that allows players to rewind a specific part of the song, used to further boost point scores.DJ Hero has seven multiplayer modes including the standard array of face-off options. A co-op mode is present where one player can use a guitar controller to play guitar in 10 or so of the game's 94 song setlist. DJ Hero Soundtrack DJ Hero boasts a soundtrack of more than 85 songs that create a setlist of 93 custom mixes. The majority of the tracks are "mash-ups": custom mixes of two songs done by DJs, such as DJ Shadow and DJ Z-Trip. The rest of the setlist is comprised of individual tracks mixed by contributing DJs. Setlist    2Pac - "All Eyez On Me" vs. The Aranbee Pop Orchestra - "Bittersweet Symphony (Instrumental)" 50 Cent - "Disco Inferno" vs. David Bowie - "Let's Dance" 50 Cent - "Disco Inferno" vs. InDeep - "Last Night A DJ Saved My Life" Afrika Bambaataa - "Zulu Nation Throwdown" vs. Freedom Express - "Get Down" Beastie Boys - "Here's A Little Somethin' For Ya" vs. DJ Shadow - "The Number Song (2009 Version)" (Produced and mixed by DJ Shadow) Beastie Boys - "Intergalactic" vs. Blondie - "Rapture" Beastie Boys - "Lee Majors Come Again" vs. Daft Punk - "Da Funk" (Produced and mixed by Cut Chemist) Beck - "Where It's At" vs. DJ Shadow - "Six Days (Remix ft. Mos Def)" Bell Biv DeVoe - "Poison" Beat Juggle Bell Biv DeVoe - "Poison" vs. Beastie Boys - "Intergalactic" (Produced and mixed by DJ AM) Bell Biv DeVoe - "Poison" vs. Cameo - "Word Up!" Benny Benassi - "Satisfaction" vs. Tiësto - "Elements Of Life" Billy Squier - "The Big Beat" vs. N.E.R.D. - "Lapdance" * Black Eyed Peas - "Boom Boom Pow" vs. Benny Benassi - "Satisfaction" Bobby "Blue" Bland - "Ain't No Love In The Heart Of The City" vs. 2Pac - "How Do You Want It" Bobby "Blue" Bland - "Ain't No Love In The Heart Of The City" vs. Connie Price  The Keystones - "Fuzz And Them" Boogie Down Productions - "Jack Of Spades" vs. David Bowie - "Let's Dance" (Produced and mixed by DJ Shadow) Chuck Brown  The Soul Searchers - "Bustin' Loose" vs. The Zombies - "Time Of The Season" (Produced and mixed by DJ Shadow) Chuck Brown  The Soul Searchers - "Bustin' Loose" vs. Young MC - "Bust A Move" Common - "Universal Mind Control (U.M.C.)" vs. Masta Ace - "Jeep A** Gutter (Aaron LaCrate  Debonair Samir " (Produced and mixed by The Scratch Perverts) Cypress Hill - "Insane In The Brain" vs. Classics IV - "Spooky" Cypress Hill - "Insane In The Brain" vs. David Axelrod - "The Edge"  Daft Punk - "Around The World" vs. Young MC - "Bust A Move" Daft Punk - "Da Funk" vs. N.A.S.A. - "Strange Enough ft. Karen O, ODB  Fatlip" Daft Punk - "Megamix 1" Daft Punk - "Megamix 2" Daft Punk - "Robot Rock" vs. Hashim - "Al Naafyish (The Soul)" (Produced and mixed by The Scratch Perverts) Daft Punk - "Robot Rock" vs. Queen - "We Will Rock You" Daft Punk - "Short Circuit" vs. Boogie Down Productions - "Jack Of Spades" Daft Punk - "Technologic" vs. Gary Numan - "Cars" Daft Punk - "Television Rules the Nation" vs. No Doubt - "Hella Good" David Axelrod - "The Edge" vs. Eric B.  Rakim - "Eric B. Is President" Dizzee Rascal - "Fix Up, Look Sharp" vs. DJ Shadow - "Organ Donor (Extended Overhaul)" Dizzee Rascal - "Fix Up, Look Sharp" vs. Justice - "Genesis" DJ Shadow - "Six Days (Remix ft. Mos Def)" vs. D-Code - "Annie's Horn" Eminem - "My Name Is" vs. Beck - "Loser" Fedde Le Grand - "Put Your Hands Up For Detroit" vs. Sandy Rivera and David Penn - "I Can't Stop (David Penn Remix)" Foo Fighters - "Monkey Wrench" vs. Beastie Boys - "Sabotage" * Foreigner - "Juke Box Hero" vs. DJ Z-Trip ft. Murs - "DJ Hero" (Produced and mixed by DJ Z-Trip) Foreigner - "Juke Box Hero" vs. DJ Z-Trip ft. Murs - "DJ Hero" (DJ-Guitar mix, produced and mixed by DJ Z-Trip) Gang Starr - "Just To Get A Rep" vs. Mobb Deep - "Shook Ones, Pt 2" (Produced and mixed by J. Period) Gorillaz - "Feel Good Inc." vs. Blondie - "Atomic" Grandmaster Flash's - "Boom" vs. "Tap" (Produced and mixed by Grandmaster Flash) Grandmaster Flash, DJ Kool, DJ Demo - "Here Comes My DJ" vs. Gary Numan - "Cars" (Produced and mixed by Grandmaster Flash) Gwen Stefani - "Hollaback Girl" vs. Gorillaz - "Feel Good Inc." Gwen Stefani - "Hollaback Girl" vs. InDeep "Last Night A DJ Saved My Life" (Produced and mixed by DJ AM) Gwen Stefani - "Hollaback Girl" vs. Rick James - "Give It To Me" Herbie Hancock - "Rockit" Beat Juggle Herbie Hancock - "Rockit" vs. N.E.R.D. - "Lapdance" (Produced and mixed by Grandmaster Flash) InDeep - "Last Night A DJ Saved My Life" vs. Cameo - "Word Up!" Jackson 5 - "I Want You Back" vs. Gang Starr - "Just To Get A Rep" (Produced and mixed by DJ Yoda) Jackson 5 - "I Want You Back" vs. Third Eye Blind - "Semi-Charmed Life" * JAY-Z feat. Pharrell - "Change Clothes" vs. 2Pac - "All Eyez on Me" JAY-Z - "Izzo (H.O.V.A.)" vs. Eminem - "My Name Is" JAY-Z - "Izzo (H.O.V.A.)" vs. Jackson 5 - "I Want You Back" JAY-Z - "Excuse Me Miss" vs. Rick James - "Give It To Me" Jean Knight - "Mr. Big Stuff" vs. Masta Ace - "Born To Roll" Jurassic 5 - "Jayou" vs. Billy Squier - "The Big Beat" Jurassic 5 - "Jayou" vs. Herbie Hancock - "Rockit" Kid Cudi - "Day 'N' Nite" vs. Black Eyed Peas - "Boom Boom Pow" Kool Moe Dee - "How Ya Like Me Now" vs. Reel 2 Real featuring The Mad Stuntman - "I Like To Move It" Little Richard - "Tutti Frutti" vs. Shlomo - "Beats" (Produced and mixed by DJ Yoda) M.I.A. - "Paper Planes" vs. Eric B.  Rakim - "Eric B. Is President" (Produced and mixed by The Scratch Perverts) M.I.A. - "Paper Planes" vs. Wale - "Lookin' At Me" Marvin Gaye - "I Heard It Through The Grapevine" vs. David Bowie - "Let's Dance" Marvin Gaye - "I Heard It Through The Grapevine" vs. Gorillaz - "Feel Good Inc." Motörhead - "Ace Of Spades" vs. Noisia - "Groundhog" * N.A.S.A. - "Strange Enough ft. Karen O, ODB  Fatlip" vs. Isaac Hayes - "Theme From Shaft" Noisia - "Groundhog" Beat Juggle (Produced and mixed by The Scratch Perverts) Paul van Dyk - "Nothing But You" vs. Sandy Rivera and David Penn - "I Can't Stop (David Penn Remix)" Public Enemy - "Shut 'Em Down" vs. Beck - "Where It's At" Public Enemy ft. Zakk Wylde - "Bring The Noise 20XX" vs. Justice - "Genesis" (Produced and mixed by DJ Z-Trip) Public Enemy featuring Zakk Wylde - "Bring The Noise 20XX" * Q-Tip - "Good Thang" vs. Billy Squier - "The Big Beat" (Produced and mixed by J. Period) Queen - "Another One Bites The Dust" vs. Beastie Boys - "Brass Monkey" (Produced and mixed by DJ Z-Trip) Queen - "Another One Bites The Dust" vs. Daft Punk - "Da Funk" Rihanna - "Disturbia" vs. Kid Sister - "Control" Rihanna - "Disturbia" vs. The Killers - "Somebody Told Me" * Rihanna - "Disturbia" vs. The Trammps - "Disco Inferno" Shlomo - "Beats" vs. Billy Squier - "The Big Beat" Street Sweeper Social Club - "Fight! Smash! Win!" vs. Beastie Boys - "Intergalactic" * Tears For Fears - "Shout" vs. DJ Shadow - "Six Days (Remix ft. Mos Def)" Tears For Fears - "Shout" vs. Eric B.  Rakim - "Eric B. Is President" (Produced and mixed by DJ Jazzy Jeff) Tears For Fears - "Shout" vs. Eric Prydz - "Pjanoo" The Aranbee Pop Orchestra - "Bittersweet Symphony (Instrumental)" vs. LL Cool J - "Rock The Bells" (Produced and mixed by DJ Jazzy Jeff) The Scratch Perverts Beats and Pieces (Produced and mixed by The Scratch Perverts) The Killers - "Somebody Told Me" vs. Eric Prydz - "Pjanoo" Vanilla Ice - "Ice Ice Baby" vs. MC Hammer - "U Can't Touch This" Vanilla Ice - "Ice Ice Baby" vs. Paula Abdul - "Straight Up" Wale - "Lookin' At Me" vs. Black Eyed Peas ft. Tippa Irie - "Hey Mama" Weezer - "Beverly Hills" vs. Evidence, The Alchemist, Aceyalone, Rakaa  88 Keys - "Fresh Rhymes And Videotape" * Wild Cherry - "Play That Funky Music" vs. Gang Starr - "Just To Get A Rep" * *Song is compatible with a Guitar Hero guitar controller  Appearing Mix DJs*  Cut Chemist Daft Punk** DJ AM** DJ Jazzy Jeff** DJ Shadow** DJ Yoda DJ Z-Trip** Grandmaster Flash** J.Period The Scratch Perverts    *Mix DJs will be contributing the Mixes found in the game  **these mix artists are represented as in-game avatars in addition to contributing some of the game's mixes     DJ Hero Renegade EditionThe "Renegade Edition" is a special edition package of DJ Hero that includes the following:  DJ Hero game. Renegade turntable controller featuring premium gold metal finish on the cross-fader, edge on the turntable, on the effects dial  on the propes underneath the controller  Renegade Edition Turntable. Hardshell turntable carrying case that converts to performance-ready DJ stand. Exclusive JAY-Z and EMINEM 2-CD pack featuring unreleased tracks and collectible case designed by artist Shepard Fairey.The package is known as the Renegade Edition, named after a song by Jay-Z and Eminem of the same name.The bundle is priced at an RRP of US$199.99/£169.99.     Downloadable Content Like most other games in Activision's "Hero" franchise, DJ Hero supports                  downloadable content in the form of downloadable song packs, which add new mixes to the game's playable soundtrack. DLC songs are only available in packs and cannot be purchased separately (with the exception of the Nintendo Wii version).  Extended Mix Track Pack 01  Public Enemy - "Can't Truss It" vs. Gorillaz - "DARE" 50 Cent feat. Mary J. Blige - "All of Me" vs. Queen - "Radio Ga Ga" David Guetta Mix Pack 01  David Guetta feat. Kelly Rowland - "When Love Takes Over David Guetta feat. Akon - "Sexy Chick David Guetta feat. will.i.am  apl.de.ap - "Once The Dance Floor"  Jay-Z vs. Eminem Mix Pack 01  Eminem - "Shake That" vs. Jay-Z - "Show Me What You Got" Eminem - "Without Me" vs. Jay-Z - "Encore" Jay-Z feat. Ja Rule and Amil - "Can I Get A..." vs. Eminem - "Lose Yourself"  Domination PackDarude - "Sandstorm" vs. Josh Wink - "Higher State of ConsciousnessWolfgang Gartner - "Wolfgang's Fifth Symphony" (Beat Juggle)Danny Byrd - "Red Mist VIP" (Beat Juggle) DJ Hero 2 Promotional Single Lady  Gaga - "Just Dance" vs. Deadmau5 - "Ghosts 'n' Stuff"  Dance Party Mix Pack Lady  Gaga - "Poker Face" vs. Duran Duran - "Girls on Film"The Pussycat Dolls - "Buttons" (Beat Juggle)Rhianna - "SOS" (Beat Juggle) Trivia  Artists Flavor Flav (of Public Enemy) and Natalia "MC Tali" Scott appear in the game as vocal sample sets. The Wale song Lookin' At Me is known as Chillin' on his debut album Attention: Deficit. The song also features artist Lady Gaga singing the chorus (uncredited in the game).  When first announced, the game was said to include a mash-up of Nirvana's All Apologies and Rick James' Give it to Me Baby to be mixed by DJ Shadow. This mix did not end up in the final build of the game for unspecified reasons.  When the box art was first revealed for the game, it listed that the game would include a total of 94 mixes. The box art was then revised and the game's soundtrack was set to have a total of 93 mixes in all.  When the audio is extracted, four mixes are present that are not playable in the game.  Ludacris - "Stand Up" vs. Red Hot Chili Peppers - "Suck My Kiss" (Labeled as Ludacris vs. RHCP - "Ludakiss" in the .xml tracklist) Aceyalone - "Lost Your Mind" vs. Bob - "Unknown Song" (Bob is used in the .xml tracklist, but is not further specified). Bliss n Eso - "Party At My Place" vs. Unknown Artist - "Unknown Song" (No further information is given in the .xml tracklist). Though unspecified, the lyrics used in the mix are from the song "Party Hard" by The Perceptionists feat. Camu Tao and Guru. Queen - "Another One Bites The Dust" vs. Beastie Boys - "Brass Monkey" (Alt. Version)    </description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21543">beatmania IIDX</game><game id="20714">Rock Band 2</game><game id="20673">Guitar Hero World Tour</game><game id="24025">Scratch: The Ultimate DJ</game><game id="2951">beatmania</game><game id="21171">Lips</game><game id="27000">DJ Mix Tour</game><game id="26554">Armin van Buuren - In the Mix</game><game id="24711">Guitar Hero 5</game><game id="25536">Guitar Hero: Van Halen</game><game id="4031">Guitar Hero III: Legends of Rock</game><game id="25521">Guitar Hero: Smash Hits</game><game id="14916">Guitar Hero II</game><game id="6311">Guitar Hero</game><game id="12241">Guitar Hero Encore: Rocks the 80s</game><game id="5307">Make My Video: Marky Mark and the Funky Bunch</game><game id="36981">Crackin' DJ</game><game id="24517">beatmania</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1887884-box_djhero.png</image></root>