<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23897</id><name>Supercars II</name><description>Produced by Magnetic Fields, Super Cars 2 is a top down racer, published by Gremlin Graphics Software Ltd in 1991 on the Amiga and Atari STThis game went to be the basis for Supercars International on the PC. It is linked to other Magnetic Fields games including: Lotus Esprit Turbo Challenge, Lotus Esprit Turbo Challenge 2, Lotus Esprit Turbo Challenge 3 and Super CarsSuper Cars 2 took the formula of its previous incarnation and changed it emphasis from a power up based system to one more suited to learning the handling style of the vehicle used.Super Cars 2 took the original games weapons and engine upgrades and expanded on them with higher level upgrades. some weapons include Front and Rear Missiles and Front and Rear Homing MissilesThe game had a few thing happen before it had finished loading, there was an anti piracy feature...during the start up sequence you are presented with a race track layout and are requested to look for it in the game manual, when you have found said track you enter the corresponding page number to continue loading the game. Old School SecurityAlso during the start up sequence you are presented with an early form of in game advertising for the Early Drive program that Brands Hatch Race Track ran in the UK.The Early Drive program was a way for under age drivers to learn how to drive before they were allowed on UK roads.Finally during the start up you are shown a splash page promoting Magnetic Field previous games Lotus Esprit Turbo Challenge and Super Cars, also there is a teaser on this page promoting Lotus Esprit Turbo Challenge II.Early In Game AdvertisingLotus Esprit Challenge II Teaser As with other games that Magnetic Fields had created the driver roster was populated with Pun Names based on Formula 1 drivers some of these names include:Nijel Mainsail    =    Nigel MansellAyrton Sendup    =    Ayrton SennaNelson Pickets    =    Nelson PiquetMickey Louder    =    Niki LauderCrashhard Banger    =    Gerhard BergerAlain Phosphate    =    Alain ProstT. Hairy Bootson    =    Thierry BoutsenDriver Roster</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="29358">Slicks</game><game id="4531">Super Skidmarks</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/889/683526-super_cars_2_splash.jpg</image></root>