<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23939</id><name>AC/DC Live: Rock Band</name><description>This is your doorway to Rock.AC/DC LIVE: Rock Band Track Pack is a standalone game available for the Xbox 360, PlayStation 3, Playstation 2 and WIi.  The Xbox 360 and PlayStation 3 versions have a key printed on the back of the manual that allows the user to download all 18 songs for use in Rock Band 1 or 2. This key is unique and can only be used once, so beware purchasing the game pre-owned with the intention of importing the tracks into your Rock Band library. The key included with a used copy of the game has almost certainly been used by the previous owner.  The 360 version contains achievements worth 250 points for doing tasks similar to those in other Rock Band games, like hitting every note in a song or keeping a long note streak going. Unlike later Rock Band games, the PlayStation 3 version does not  contain trophy support. This is because the game uses a stripped-down version of the Rock Band 1 engine, which was built before Sony standardized the trophy system.  AC/DC is a band notorious for not licensing their music for digital distribution or use in video games. Notable exceptions include Rock Band 2, in which "Let There Be Rock" was available as part of the setlist. This track pack is be the first video game dedicated to the Australian rockers, and the first to include many of their popular songs.   For the first year of its release (Nov. 2008 - Nov. 2009), the AC/DC Live track pack was only available new in Wal Mart and Sam's Club stores in the United States. This was due to it being part of a much larger merchandising campaign between Wal Mart and AC/DC management to promote AC/DC CDs, DVDs, and books in to hype the band's new album "Black Ice." Since the campaign has ended, AC/DC Live Rock Band Track Pack has been released in other stores across America. The game is also available used at retailers such as GameStop, but as noted above the import codes often have already been cashed in, rendering the songs playable only from the standalone disc. The entire track list is below, and all of the songs are recorded from their famous live set at Castle Donington in 1991.  Following the track names are the difficulty levels for each instrument (Band, Guitar, Drums, Vocals, Bass), with 0 being the easiest and 6 being the hardest:    "Thunderstruck" - (2, 4, 3, 2, 0) "Shoot to Thrill" - ( 2, 3, 3, 4, 1)  "Back in Black" - ( 1, 3, 0, 3, 0)  "Hell Ain't a Bad Place to Be" - (0, 1, 0, 3, 0)The gameplay and interface is based off the original Rock Band.  "Heatseeker" - ( 3, 3, 2, 5, 1)  "Fire Your Guns" - ( 4, 4, 4, 4, 1)  "Jailbreak" - ( 2, 3, 3, 3, 1)  "The Jack" - ( 1, 1, 0, 5, 1)  "Dirty Deeds Done Dirt Cheap" - (3, 5, 3, 1, 1)  "Moneytalks" - ( 0, 1, 0, 0, 0)  "Hells Bells" - ( 1, 3, 1, 2, 1)  "High Voltage" - ( 3, 5, 0, 5, 3)  "Whole Lotta Rosie" - ( 3, 4, 3, 4, 3)  "You Shook Me All Night Long" - (1, 0, 2, 3, 0)  "T.N.T." - ( 1, 3, 0, 1, 0)  "Let There Be Rock" - ( 5, 5, 5, 5, 2)  "Highway To Hell" - ( 1, 4, 0, 2, 0)  "For Those About to Rock (We Salute You)" - (4, 4, 4, 2, 3)  Xbox 360 Game InstallationThe AC/DC Live track pack can be installed to the Xbox 360 hard drive, using 2.6 GB of HDD space. This method will not integrate the songs into your Rock Band library however, you will still have to play it as a stand-alone game. This should not be confused with the import feature mentioned earlier.</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20673">Guitar Hero World Tour</game><game id="4031">Guitar Hero III: Legends of Rock</game><game id="14916">Guitar Hero II</game><game id="22562">Guitar Hero: Metallica</game><game id="23009">GuitarFreaks</game><game id="23219">Guitar Rising</game><game id="25871">Tap Tap Revenge: Coldplay Edition</game><game id="21102">Guitar Hero On Tour: Decades</game><game id="20639">Guitar Hero: On Tour</game><game id="23524">SingStar: Queen</game><game id="1420">Amplitude</game><game id="20635">Rock Revolution</game><game id="32905">Singstar Guitar</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14036/837728-acdc_cover.jpg</image></root>