<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23953</id><name>Another Code: R - A Journey into Lost Memories</name><description>Overview Another Code R: A Journey into Lost Memories follows the 16-year old   Ashley once more as she explores Lake Juiliet. Ashley remembers a vague time where she visited before, just before her mother's death when she was 3 years old. Players solve puzzles and gather clues to try and unlock the past - finding out what's so significant about the lake.  GameplayA large portion of the game plays like a visual-novel where you cycle through text occasionally making choices which affect the conversation. However, in between conversations, you move Ashley round the camp and its surrounding areas in a 2D plane (i.e. left and right) though it allows you to change this plane at certain junctions on the path.  Throughout the game, the player come across a variety of puzzles. Some require the use of a virtual DSi (known in-game as the DAS or "Dual Another System") to take pictures and manipulate them. You also use a Wii remote like device to open door-locks by entering codes which get steadily more complicated throughout. In addition to these, there are puzzles that use neither of these in-game objects and, instead, require you to use the Wii Remote as if you are manipulating Ashley's movements (the most publicized would be the use of a water acidity testing kit where you tilt and shake the Wii remote like the chemicals and the test tube).</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20522">Harvey Birdman: Attorney at Law</game><game id="17544">Broken Sword: The Shadow of the Templars</game><game id="9345">Zack &amp; Wiki: Quest for Barbaros' Treasure</game><game id="24237">Again</game><game id="32606">Gyakuten Kenji 2</game><game id="28028">Ghost Trick: Phantom Detective</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/7439/962241-anothercode.jpg</image></root>