<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23966</id><name>Sin &amp; Punishment:  Star Successor</name><description>  Gameplay  Fighting  enemies during a level.Sin and Punishment: Star Successor plays with the Wii Remote pointed to the screen as a gun, where you aim and shoot at your enemies and targets. You control your character's movement with the analog stick of the Nunchuck. When you approach an enemy close-range, you can use a sword your gun has equipped to slice your target with ease.   Like the first game, you play the game as two characters, Isa Jo and  Kachi, but instead of alternating between them throughout the levels,  you choose your character at the start of the game and they have  different firing styles instead of playing the same. When playing as  Isa, you can lock on to enemies manually to automatically aim at enemies  as you could in the original whereas Kachi will automatically lock on  to enemies close to your reticle. In addition to this, each character  has their own charge shot. Isa's charge shot explodes when it hits an  enemy and covers a large area while Kachi's charge shot allows you to  lock on to up to 8 enemies and shoot them all simultaneously. The game plays similarly to the                        Star Fox series, you go forward on-rails, but you can control yourself to avoid obstacles or get to different paths. The game is much more cinematic than Star Fox, having action pieces and story points evolve on-screen as you control your character. For those who want to, the game also supports the                       Classic Controller and the                      Gamecube controllers. Similar to            Super Mario  Galaxy, a second player can join in to destroy  enemies but, instead of  having two characters on screen, the second  player is just a reticule,  only able to shoot. After completing a level  for the first time or  setting a new high score, you can upload your  score to          Nintendo  Wi-Fi Connection where you can see the top scores  for all the  difficulties and see how you rank.     Plot    In the middle of an epic firefight.     Set a number of years after the original game, Sin and Punishment: Star Successor takes place in a universe where space is divided between two factions at war, the Inner-Space and Outer-Space. To defend themselves from the Outer, the Inner created multiple planet Earths and inhabited them with humanity. Occasionally, the humans would try to be friends with the Outer instead of fighting with them like the Inner wanted them to. Whenever they did this, the Inner would wipe the planet clean and start humanity again.  Shortly before the start of the game, the Inner wiped the fourth Earth clean of humanity. Seeing an opportunity, the Outer sent an advance guard disguised as a girl to the Earth to gather information on the humans. When she arrived on the planet, however, she lost all her memories and instead of gathering intel on the Inner defences, she simply became interested in humanity and began searching the planet in search of them.  Knowing that the Outer had infiltrated the planet, the Inner sent Isa Jo (Son of        Airan and         Saki from the original game) to eliminate the vanguard. After they met, Isa empathised with the feelings she had about not being entirely human due to the ruffian blood he inherited from his parents and, instead of killing her, he helped her look for traces of humanity. Enraged by this betrayal, the Inner contacted the humans of the fifth Earth (Known as the Nebulox) and offered them greater rights for them in the Inner-Space faction if they kill both Isa and the vanguard (Who took on the name Kachi after meeting Isa).  The game begins with Isa and Kachi trying to escape the Nebulox by leaving the planet. History  The main characters adopt vehicles during an  action scene.The original                            Sin and Punishment, an                           N64 game only released in Japan, was one of Nintendo's last big games for the system, but due to timing, it was never released outside their home country due to the proximity of their next-gen console, the                          Gamecube. Developed by genre-masters     Treasure, the game was critically acclaimed.         A decade later, the game was re-released by Nintendo on the                         Wii Virtual Console, the first time it has been released on a non-Japanese speaking country. The game was an unexpected smash hit, causing Nintendo to greenlight the sequel a few months later with Treasure again at the helm. </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2727">Star Fox Assault</game><game id="5765">Burning Rangers</game><game id="26878">Zombie Panic in Wonderland</game><game id="31734">Kid Icarus: Uprising</game><game id="21800">Planet Harriers</game><game id="32567">Saber Rider and the Star Sheriffs</game><game id="35811">Big Town Shootout</game><game id="7393">Sin &amp; Punishment</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/27239/1298274-sin_punishment_star_successor_us_box_art_revealed_20100309101625845_000.jpg</image></root>