<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23977</id><name>Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles: Echoes of Time</name><description>Overview The gameplay layout for the DS version of Echoes of Time is largely the same, despite numerous updates and changes. As well as new weapons and armour (which can now level up), the game introduced a new weaponry system in which all tribes may use a variety of weapons, as well as abilities which range from 2-3 types of weapons. The ability-equip system from    Ring of Fates was also discarded in favour of a jewel system, in which players can add jewels to weapons to add extra abilities. The game also boasted a revamped magic system which consumed   MP as opposed to Magicites.  The Wii version of the game is ultimately the same and the only major difference is from a hardware perspective: Because the DS has two screens, and a Wii is only portrayed on one screen (a single television) the action will be split into two screens on the television itself, as if to emote a DS on the television. Aside from this, the only other difference is that the Wii version of the game came with a trailer for the upcoming  Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles: The Crystal Bearers. Story  The main character comes back from a great battle which was held in a forest to celebrate a ceremony. But there he stumbles upon a young girl, Eriru, who has a disease, suffering from crystal sickness. The hero then offers to help and sets out on a journey to find a cure for the disease. But little does he know, that the crystals that he seek, are a thing of the past and no longer exist. </description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21448">Kingdom Hearts 358/2 Days</game><game id="9471">Children of Mana</game><game id="22044">From the Abyss</game><game id="24232">Ragnarok DS</game><game id="21633">Soma Bringer</game><game id="23777">Phantasy Star Zero</game><game id="24225">Destiny Links</game><game id="25152">Blue Dragon: Awakened Shadow</game><game id="24050">Monster Hunter Tri</game><game id="21636">Dungeon Explorer: Warriors of Ancient Art</game><game id="27893">Cross Treasures</game><game id="27199">Rune Factory 3: A Fantasy Harvest Moon</game><game id="20615">Summon Night: Twin Age</game><game id="28324">Shounen Kininden Tsumuji</game><game id="29232">Lufia: Curse of the Sinistrals</game><game id="31644">Kingdom Hearts Re:coded</game><game id="30580">Monster Hunter Portable 3rd</game><game id="35479">Heroes of Ruin</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/112/888307-front.jpg</image></root>