<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24063</id><name>428: In the Blocked City, Shibuya</name><description>Introduction428: Fuusa Sareta Shibuya de (428 封鎖された渋谷で) is a sound novel developed by Chunsoft. It was released in 2008 for the Wii and in 2009 for the PSP and PS3. Like most Chunsoft sound novels, it uses photos to show the scenes described in text, but it drops the classic blue silhouettes for the characters used in Kamaitachi no Yoru or Imabikisou. 428 is considered by some Japanese fans as the spiritual successor of Machi.SummaryThe plot resolves around a kidnapping in Japan Shibuya district, the game takes place between 10 AM and 6 PM in the lives of five different characters:Kano (a derective), Achi (a punk/ex gang leader), Tama (a girl wearing a cat costume), Minorikawa (a journalist), and Oozawa (the kindapped girl's father).The game can be divided in several chapters, each chapter takes an hour in the lives of the characters, in order to progress in the story the player needs to lead all the characters to the end of the chapter, if the player finish the chapter then the story will move to the next hour in the game.The gameplay in 428 its quite different from other sound novels, its impossible to beat the game without using all the characters, since the decisions made with one character may affect every other protagonist in the story. For instance, in one portion of the game two yakuzas are looking for a building and ask directions to one of the main characters, if the player tells them where the building is it will lead another protagonist story to a bad ending, when one of the main characters gets a bad ending the player have to go back in time using the time chart and correct the decisions.Depending on the player's choices, a number of new scenarios become available, which ultimately lead to different outcomes and endings. The game has up to 85 different possible endings.Reception428: Fuusa Sareta Shibuya scored a perfect 40/40 in Famitsu magazine. </description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="27266">999: 9 Hours, 9 Persons, 9 Doors</game><game id="29700">Misshitsu no Sacrifice</game><game id="17132">Machi</game><game id="30817">Time Travelers</game><game id="39522">Imitation City</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14945/1113879-428ps3boxart.jpg</image></root>