<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24094</id><name>Planet Pachinko</name><description>IntroductionWiiware title published by Allied Kingdoms. The game offers a 2 player co-op modeStory"Can you survive the temples of Planet Pachinko? In the future of the future, an ancient civilization has sealed away their riches in elaborate temples dedicated to the game of pachinko. Now the Robot family must fight through the dangerous temples in search of their lost puppy. Using their rockets, lasers, grenades, and slime launchers, will they be able to survive the challenges?  They aren't the only ones adventuring through the temple. The pirate Vile Vill and his minions are looking to loot the temples, and take on the Robot family as well."GameplayBeware of Fascist Robots. You are inside of a pahinko machine and your goal is to destroy the pachinko balls before they fall into the cups at the bottom of the machine, if you so manage to do so you will be rewarded in the "intergalactic currency" of "Space jelly". However does a ball happen to to fall into one of the cups it will transform into a enemy.The balls go through platforms and only interact with the pins in the machine whereas you only interact with the platforms and not the pins. The basic idea is to use this in your advantage and race towards the falling balls and destroy them either with a melee attack or with one of your weapons (which all interact with the pins and platforms in a different way). You will get hurt if one of the balls falls on you. The enemies that are created by the balls falling in the cups do not rewards you with any space jelly when you destroy them so it is better to try and destroy the balls before they can transform.The game also has a anti-camping mechanism that will release turrets on you if you stay still for too long.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3715/748503-planetpachinko.png</image></root>