<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2410</id><name>Def Jam: Vendetta</name><description>OverviewDef Jam Vendetta is a fighting/wrestling video game published by Electronic Arts. It features a wide range of characters from the world of hip-hop, and is named for the Def Jam record label, of which almost all of the artists in the game were signed on at the time of release. It was released for the PS2 and Gamecube. It uses the AKI engine made famous with the pro wrestling games on the N64.StoryIt's rough in the underground street fighting world.In Def Jam: Vendetta, you first choose one of four characters (Briggs, Proof, Tank or Spider) to play as in the story mode. You are an up-and-coming underground street fighter ready to make it big. As you fight your way to the top, the owner of the clubs in which you fight, D-Mob, takes a notice to your abilities and ambition. A violent world of shady business unfolds itself as a result. Eventually you are no longer fighting for the money and the women, but you are fighting to survive.CharactersThe game features a wide variety of characters from the hip-hop world such as Method Man, Redman and Ludacris. Included in the game are also a handful of created characters that serve as allies, enemies, girlfriends and opponents throughout story mode.Featured Artists/Celebrities (Playable in Exhibition matches)CaponeChristina Milian (Non-playable, voices Angel story character)Christopher Judge (voices D-Mob story character)Dabo (Japanese version only)DMXFunkmaster FlexGhostface KillahJoe BuddenKeith MurrayLudacrisMethod Man as The GoochN.O.R.E.RedmanScarfaceS-Word (Japanese version only)WCPlayable Story Mode CharactersBriggsProofTankSpiderConkerGirlfriends (Playable in Exhibition/Cat Fight Story mode Matches)CarlaDejaPennyT'ai MoniquePlayable Exhibition CharactersAriiChukklezCruzDan GDeeboDrakeHeadacheHouseIcebergMannyMasaMosesNyneOmarOpalPeeweePocketsRazorRuffneckSketchSnowmanZaheerSoundtrack List1. DMX - Intro2. Dabo - It's My Turn (Fight!)3. DMX - Party Up4. Keith Murray - Yeah Yeah You Know It5. C-N-N feat. M.O.P. - Stompdash6. N.O.R.E. - Nothin7. WC feat. Snoop Dogg - The Streets8. Comp - Do Sumptin9. Ludacris - Saturday10. Scarface - in Cold Blood11. Christina Milian Feat. Ja Rule - Get Away12. Method Man - Uh Huh!13. Keith Murray - Oh My Goodness14. Redman - Smash Sumthin15. Comp - Stick Em16. Joe Budden - Focus17. Method Man - Bring the Pain18. Onyx - Throw Ya Gunz19. Public Enemy - Fight the Power20. DMX - X Gon' Give It to Ya21. Def Jam - OutroSequelsThe success of the original Def Jam: Vendetta resulted in the sequels Def Jam: Fight For New York and Def Jam: Icon. A Def Jam game was also released for PSP entitled Def Jam Fight For New York: The Takeover.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="10">Wrestling</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14809">MTV Celebrity Deathmatch</game><game id="10872">Wu-Tang: Shaolin Style</game><game id="3667">WWF Wrestlemania 2000</game><game id="11394">WWF No Mercy</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="721">Ehrgeiz: God Bless the Ring</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="9855">Soulcalibur III</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4647/837848-562455_front.jpg</image></root>