<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24115</id><name>Ikki Tousen: Eloquent Fist</name><description>Overview Ikkitousen: Eloquent Fist is a side-scrolling beat em' up released in 2008 for the PlayStation Portable, the game was developed and published by Marvelous Entertainment Inc.The game contains a large number of playable characters from the Ikkitousen series and includes bonus unlockable costumes, along with an image gallery for each playable character.  Game Modes The game consists of two game modes, arcade and story.Story sections in the game are fully voiced. Arcade mode allows the player to select one of a number of characters, and play through the various stages in the game. The character will also level up at the end of stages which unlocks various bonus' for that specific character. Story mode has the player select one of three different stories, each having it's own roster of characters. The story mode mainly differs from the arcade mode in two areas, one being the character for a particular stage is preselected from the roster in relation to the story. The second is the visual novel style of story telling before and after stages, which involves static character images and text with voice overs. Gameplay Gameplay in Ikkitousen: Eloquent Fist takes the form of a typical side scrolling brawler. Sticking to this formula the player works their way through the stage defeating opponents, where at points progress is halted until the set amount of combatants are beaten, after which a familiar “GO!” instruction is issued and progress can continue. At the end of a stage the player squares off one on one with a boss character which is also one of the playable characters. Generally there is only one boss battle per stage although some stages have two back to back boss fights. The attacks used in the game fall into three general areas, light attacks, heavy attacks and special moves which require the player to fill a special gauge to a certain amount. The light and heavy attacks, when done in certain combinations form different combos that differ with each character, although each character has a fairly low amount of combos individually the number of playable characters gives players a fairly diverse set of moves overall.Unleash a special attack! Specials when performed halt the action for moment and are followed up by a close up of the character with one of several voiced phrases, after which the action resumes with the special being executed. Should the player finish a boss with a special the boss is shown with clothes ripped away in precarious places for a brief moment, otherwise if the boss is finished with normal attacks, a clothes intact representation is displayed instead. ReleasesIkkitousen: Eloquent Fist has two different releases, one being a standard PSP game release along with a limited edition set that includes the game along with the following.  Two PVC figures  Desktop calendar for 2008-2009  A Kanu Unchou Holographic flick-action card    </description><genres><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20436">Streets of Rage</game><game id="23308">Ikki Tousen: Shining Dragon</game><game id="29779">BlazBlue Calamity Trigger Portable</game><game id="29483">Dead or Alive: Paradise</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/238/758353-eloquent_fist_wall__2_.jpg</image></root>