<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24126</id><name>Furcadia</name><description>Furcadia is a massively multiplayer online social game. It's a virtual world where you can roleplay with others in an animated realm where, well, anything is possible. Players, called "furres" here, engage in both socializing and roleplaying. The public areas, called maps, are themed and specify whether they are intended for free-form roleplaying or chat-room-style interactions with players from all over the world (the standard language is English). Furcadia offers user-created content. Player-mode maps, called "dreams", cover a very wide range of themes and topics. Maps have age- and content-focused ratings that define the expected behavior and the limits. CharactersIn Furcadia you are a Furre, and you play in this continuity that Furcadia has set up. This continuity is off the many hub worlds in Furcadia itself. Though the law of thisMany types of furres in one placecontinuity is never enforced. Also each character depending on which furre you make gets a portrait for that species. Though if you pay, you can put your own personal picture in your portrait for use anywhere you go. Also each character gets there own area to give a description for their character, so when someone clicks on you, they can read whatever information you would like for others to see about your character. Anyways, you choose your character who would be an animal which stands on both legs(well, if you pay, there's some that stand on 4 legs). Here are the initial free animal types to choose from:Feline (Cat)Canine (Dog)Lapine (Rabbit)Equine (Horse)Musteline (Weasel)Sciurine (Squirrel)Rodent (Mouse)Bovine (Bull/Minotaur)Ursine (Bear)The most commonly used furres are the Feline, and the Canine. Its also good to note, that you can be 1 of 3 genders. Male, Female, and Unspecified. This will change your portrait, but not your character model.WorldsIn Furcadia there are several different hub worlds you can just warp to at any moment. Hub worlds are used to harbor Dreams, and such. Each Hub world is designed to Harbor a broad selection of dreams, though it's the owner of the dreams choice to put it anywhere he wants.Naia Green, intended to be Furcadia's community center. Many Beekin volunteers gather here to help answer user questions.Challenges, a game-oriented area that includes boards for chess, checkers, "pillow wars," and others.Acropolis, an area for out-of-character socializing and dream uploads.Furrabian Nights, a Mature 16 environment. User-created content follows guidelines set in the new dream standards and is of a mature(Ex. Sex, Slavery, etc.) nature.Hawthorn (replacing Haven), a Mature 16 environment dream meant for the harsher, more savage side of Furcadia. It employs the same basic layout as Haven did, with darker patching and other content-related changes.Allegria Island, a popular location for dream uploads.Meovanni Village, an area intended for persona play (a form of simplified roleplay).Imaginarium, an area intended for deeper roleplay. Most roleplay-oriented dreams are uploaded here.The Wylde, a main map for Ferians which includes thirteen different biomes with habitats upon which players can upload their dreams.Vinca Nexus, the central hub connecting the rest of the main maps, as well as your destination if your character is ejected from another map or dream.Secondary WorldsThese Secondary worlds are only reachable by finding the entrance, you can't just teleport to them at any time like the other worlds. The following is an incomplete list of these worlds:Welcome Map, a tutorial area where new players learn about the game. The Pineapple Resort is the companion zone to this area.Naia Green, a family friendly map for socializing and making friends, often also frequented by newer players. A Help Center is located here.Beekins' Aerie, a map designed for volunteer staff; beekin classes and meetings held here.Theriopolis, a roplaying map. Magic here is weak and barely exists.Goldwyn, a roleplaying map. Magic here is more prevalent.Dusk 2 Dawn, a dark, Mature 16 map.Town Meeting, a temporary dream where an annual "Town Meeting" is held, accessible only to Silver Sponsors.Silver Sponsorship Showcase, a scenic map where Silver Sponsors can upload on special portals, but anyone can visitZephiroth, a flying island-themed map that only winged players or those summoned by winged players can visit.Olde Town, a recently added socializing map for adult players looking to meet other adults, without exposure to typically "mature" content.The five annual festival dreams, Jujinka's Spring Festival, M'Rill's Festival of the Sun, Jemmion's Rameen Festival, Wolf Howl, and Danival's Winter Festival.DreamsThe primary focus of Furcadia is user-created content. To this end, the Furcadia game download includes an art editor and a map creating program. Users are encouraged to create their own virtual worlds, called Dreams, using these tools. These worlds can be uploaded to the Furcadia server and used for a variety of purposes, examples being role playing, a place to hang out with friends, or a number of other purposes. Dreams remain open to theRoleplaying in a Western style Dream.public area in which they are uploaded, so long as it is inhabited, and, if unoccupied, it is eventually unloaded automatically. Dreams can include the useof audio files in the WMA, Ogg, MOD, S3M, WAV, and MIDI(.mid) formats, to name a few.Most Dreams take advantage of a relatively user-friendly coding language known as DragonSpeak, or "DS". DragonSpeak allows users to develop interactivity into their dreams, ranging from a simple action like opening a door, to far more complex uses, such as a complete game of chess or lazer tag.Dream owners are allowed to make and use bots to accomplish things that DragonSpeak cannot, but these are not officially supported by Furcadia.Dreams run off several file types. ".MAP" files hold the main Dream layout, ".DS" files hold the DragonSpeak code, and ".FOX" (replacing the older ".FSH" format) and PCX files hold patch art for Furcadia. Every aspect of the Furcadia interface can be customized with Furcadia skins. Skins are made with a "marbled.pcx" file that is used for the background, two ".FOX" files (buttons.fox and the customizable dsbtns.fox), a settings file (skin.ini) and several fonts.Many popular types of dreams are build-a-homes (where you can buy a temporary house from staff for free and decorate it with items, but is usually deleted after you leave the dream), hangout dreams (Usually featuring a bar or café area) and roleplay dreams. Furcadia hosts a wide variety ofThere is no end to creativityroleplaying dreams, ranging from strict-continuity roleplay (In which the dream is its own independent world) to persona play (Roleplay that is light and is governed by few rules). Roleplaying dreams also come in a myriad of different forms, ranging from feral (Feral wolf and horse dreams are immensely popular, concentrated in the Northeast region of the popular 'main map', Allegria Island) to furre to human. Many dreams revolve around fantasy plots and themes, based on popular books, television programs and even ancient mythology; some dream ideas are created entirely out of the minds of their creators.Furcadia itself is basically made up of several dreams, the ones made by its users, and the main maps.DevelopmentFirst opened to the public onDecember 16, 1993Furcadia is developed by Dragons Eye Productions inc.(DEP). Its engine was developed in 1994, originally for a preliminary graphical MUD project called Dragonspires, which featured very simplistic real-time combat, and used a DOS-based client limited to the 16 EGA colors. At its public release, Furcadia featured a graphical improvement: art with a 256 color VGA palette. New support for 24-bit non-remappable portraits (the first art to extend beyond 256 colors), and Windows Vista support were implemented in the April 6, 2007 "Kitterwing Edition." On December 16, 2006 Furcadia became the first-ever MMORPG to celebrate ten years of continual service.Furcadia was originally designed and programmed by Dr. Cat (known as Felorin in-game) and Talzhemir. Two additional people have since been credited as part of the creative team for their work: game producer Katie Bazor (known as Emerald Flame), who developed (and still coordinates) the Beekin volunteer staff project, and Aleksi Asikainen(known as sanctimonious), who created the game's editors and is now involved in coding the client and the server as the game's lead programmer.The developers continue to release several updates to the code per year. Major updates to the code (such as the addition of new character avatars or improved Dragonspeak commands) occur approximately twice per year. A successful Kickstarter fund raising campaign in December 2012 provided the necessary means to start the development of a web client (Flash, later intended to be ported to HTML5). As of 2013, the game remains in a public beta development stage.  Business modelDownloading and playing Furcadia is free of charge. DEP has publicly stated that Furcadia will remain free of mandatory playing charges. To fund staff and cover the costs of running Furcadia's servers, DEP sells several game-enhancing products, known in the game as Digos, sold in an online store known as the Digo Market(named after an in-game location). Possession of these game enhancements can last anywhere from one day to 'life' (an indefinite amount of time), depending on the product and package one purchases.These Digos include premium avatars, in-game wings of several types, the ability to upload custom in-game character portraits, in-game roses, and small images, such as cupcakes or even engagement rings, that display in a character's profile (known as Desctags). Additionally, players may purchase 'Silver Sponsorships', which provide a number of game-enhancing abilities and features.DragonScales are an in-game currency that may be used to purchase Digos. DragonScales may be purchased in the Digo Market, or received in-game as competition prizes or gifts.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre><genre id="15">Compilation</genre><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="36">Text Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21958">MapleStory</game><game id="2268">RuneScape</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/19821/755966-mainlogo.jpg</image></root>