<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2416</id><name>Gran Turismo</name><description>Gran Turismo was produced by Japanese based studio          Polyphony Digital and published in         Japan in 1997. It went on to become one of the most successful console racing games ever made. GameplayAt the time of release, many        PC racing games featured realistic, simulation style handling but there were few such titles for systems like the       Playstation. Gran Turismo was one of the first games to bring a realistic style of car physics and handling to a home console. This was made possible by the increased computing power brought about by the Playstation generation of hardware.The player competes in competitions to earn money, which is then spent on new vehicles or upgrades to already purchased ones. A competition consists of a number of discrete races, and depending on a player's finishing position a trophy is awarded.  In addition, more mundane changes were possible, such as changing a  vehicle's wheel design or oil. These changes remained available in later  Gran Turismo titles as well.The game features 178 cars and 11 race tracks including two real world locations. It also featured a robust car modification system that allowed players to upgrade their car's performance in a number of key areas:  Engine Exhaust Gearbox Aerodynamics Weight  License TestsGrand Turismo included a unique      tutorial to introduce players to the style of driving necessary, which was unusual in console racing games at the time. The player was required to earn "Licenses" in game, in order to unlock more advanced races. The licenses (B, A and International A) are each achieved by completing eight sections of increasing difficulty, which serve to introduce driving techniques and ensure players are proficient enough in them to pass. These license tests were completed with varying trophy grades depending on the finish times. Gold trophies are by far the hardest to attain, but completing a license with all gold trophies tends to unlock a reward car which can be kept and used in races. Typically the Silver times proved challenging, though Bronze was the minimum that could be achieved.Car Manufacturers  The original Gran Turismo featured mainly Japanese cars, with a few big-name brands from the US and UK: Acura Aston Martin Chevrolet Dodge Honda Mazda Mitsubishi Nissan Subaru Toyota TVR  The range of cars in the game is broad, hatchbacks, wagons, sedans and sports cars all being available for use, though the more eclectic brands such as Dodge and TVR only featured high-end automobiles. Depending on the game's region (eg. NTSC and PAL), the cars contained may have different information. For example, Acura appeared only in NTSC copies of the game, while it was listed as Honda in PAL copies. This was due to the fact that Acura is not marketed in European regions, acting as Honda's American division. Some of the cars are limited only to Arcade mode instead of Simulation Mode, while some of the cars in the game simply are not meant to be seen for various reasons.  Another key example of the manufacturers and regional differences is with the Toyota GT-ONE Le Mans car. In PAL copies the car features a red and white livery with the Esso branding running across it. In NTSC copies the Esso branding is replaced with Exxon, though the other decals present on the car remain constant. Minor differences like these can be noted in the game throughout. CarsToyota  Starlet Glanza V             Corolla Levin BZG            Sprinter Trueno BZG          Celica GT-Four               Mark II '92 Tourer V           Mark II '92 Tourer S         Chaser Tourer V             Chaser Tourer S              Soarer '95 2.5 GT-T          Soarer 2.5 GT-T VVT-i        MR2 G-Limited                MR2 GT-S                  Supra '95 SZ-R               Supra SZ-R               Supra RZ                  MA70 Supra GT Turbo Limited  JZA70 Supra Twin Turbo R    AE86 Corolla Levin GT-APEX   AE86 Sprinter Trueno GT-APEX  Nissan  Fairlady Z ver.S 2 by 2    Fairlady Z TwinTurbo 2 by 2 Fairlady Z ver.S 2-seater   Fairlady Z ver.S TT 2-seater R32 Skyline '89 GT-R        R32 Skyline '91 GT-R         R32 Skyline GT-R Vspec       R32 Skyline GT-R Vspec II    R32 Skyline GT-R NISMO       R32 Skyline GTS-t Type M     R32 Skyline GTS25 Type S     R32 Skyline GTS4           R33 Skyline GTS25t Type M    R33 Skyline '95 GT-R         R33 Skyline '95 GT-R Vspec   R33 Skyline GT-R             R33 Skyline GT-R Vspec       S14 Silvia Q's               S14 Silvia K's               S14 Silvia '95 Q's           S14 Silvia '95 K's           S13 Silvia '91 Q's 2000cc    S13 Silvia '91 K's 2000cc    S13 Silvia '88 Q's 1800cc   S13 Silvia '88 K's 1800cc    Primera '90 2.0Te            Primera '95 2.0Te           180SX '95 Type X             180SX Type X                 180SX Type S    Mitsibishi       Pulsar '91 GTi-R            GTO '92 SR                   GTO '92 Twin Turbo           GTO '95 SR                  GTO '95 Twin Turbo           GTO '95 MR                  GTO SR                      GTO Twin Turbo               Galant VR-G Touring         Galant VR-4                  Eclipse GT                   FTO '94 GR                   FTO '94 GPX                FTO GR                       FTO GPX                      FTO GP version R             Lancer EvoIII GSR            Lancer EvoIV GSR  Honda      Mirage Asti RX               Mirage '92 Cyborg R           Prelude '93 Si               Prelude '94 VTEC           Prelude                      Prelude SH                   Civic Sedan                 Civic 3-Door                 Civic (racer)                del Sol '93 S                del Sol '93 Si               Civic '91 CR-X Si            Civic '93 3-Door Si          Civic '93 Sedan              Accord Sedan              Accord Wagon                 NSX '91                      NSX '93                      NSX                          NSX Type S                   NSX Type S Zero              Integra GS-R                 Integra Type R           Mazda  E unos Cosmo 13B Type-SCCS    Eunos Cosmo 20B Type-ECCS    Lantis Coupe 2000 Type-R     Eunos Roadster '89 Normal    Eunos Roadster '90 V-special Eunos Roadster '92 S-special Eunos Roadster Normal        Eunos Roadster V-special     Eunos Roadster S-special    FD Efini RX-7 '91 Type-R   FD Efini RX-7 Type RZ        FD Efini Rx-7 Type RB        FD Efini Rx-7 Touring-X      FD Efini Rx-7 A spec       FC Savanna RX-7 GT-X       FC Savanna RX-7 Efini III    Demio GL-X                    Demio GL                      Demio LX-G package         Subaru   Alcyone SVX Version L        Legacy Touring Sedan RS     Legacy Touring Wagon GT-B    Legacy '93 Touring Sport RS  Legacy '93 Touring Wagon GT  Impreza WRX-Sti Type-R       Impreza '96 Sedan WRX       Impreza '96 Sed. WRXSti vIII Impreza '96 Wag. WRXSTi vIII Impreza '95 Sed. WRXSTi vII  Impreza '95 Wag. WRXSTi VII  Impreza '94 Sedan WRX         Impreza '94 Wagon WRX      Aston Martin    DB7 Coupe                    DB7 Volante    Dodge            Viper RT/10                 Viper GTS        TVR           Cerbera                      Griffith 500                Griffith 4.0          Corvette       Camaro Z28                   Corvette '96 Coupe         Corvette '96 Grand Sport        Tracks Autumn RingAutumn Ring Mini Clubman Stage Route 5  Deep Forest Raceway  Grand Valley Speedway  Grand Valley Speedway East  High Speed Ring  Special Stage Route 5  Special Stage Route 11  Test Course  Trial Mountain CircuitUpgrades and TuningPolyphony's racer has an extensive level of simulation and physics emulation. This allows for a robust tuning system, making it possible to adjust or even completely overhaul a car's handling and power. Dependent on what upgrades are installed, a car's characteristics may be altered in a multitude of ways. From ride height and tire composition, to gear ratios and boost timings, Grand Turismo had no parallel on consoles of the time.  Music List  "Autonomy" - Cubanate   "Industry" - Cubanate   "Oxyacetalene" - Cubanate   "Skeletal" - Cubanate   "Everything Must Go (Chemical Brothers Remix)" - Manic Street Preachers   "High" -   TMF   "Lose Control" - Ash   "Sweet 16" - Feeder  "As Heaven is Wide" - Garbage  </description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8437">TOCA 2: Touring Car Challenge</game><game id="19563">Sports Car GT</game><game id="17599">Forza Motorsport</game><game id="453">Need for Speed: High Stakes</game><game id="8779">Sega GT 2002</game><game id="15965">Sega GT</game><game id="5869">TOCA Touring Car Championship</game><game id="8831">Need for Speed: Porsche Unleashed</game><game id="941">Project Gotham Racing</game><game id="2279">Project Gotham Racing 2</game><game id="19809">Project Gotham Racing 3</game><game id="7019">Ridge Racer V</game><game id="5977">Need for Speed III: Hot Pursuit</game><game id="7777">Juiced</game><game id="10124">Midnight Club: Street Racing</game><game id="17872">TOCA Race Driver 3 Challenge</game><game id="12282">World's Scariest Police Chases</game><game id="13535">GT Pro Series</game><game id="1052">Super PickUps</game><game id="15558">Lotus Challenge</game><game id="25225">Need for Speed: SHIFT</game><game id="24373">Motorhead</game><game id="13338">Andretti Racing</game><game id="38254">Running High</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1794102-box_gt.png</image></root>