<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24295</id><name>Mall Maniacs</name><description>A game set in different themed ICA stores. ICA is one of the bigest chains of supermarkets in sweden. The game contains products from many companies and the game was given with the purchas of some of them. Most copis of the game probably found there way to the consumer from Macdonald's who had a prominent roll in the game, in every ICA there was a Macdonals were the player could get a hamburger that bosted the players speed. The player could choose from different characters who all had different stats such as speed and handling. The player could unlock new characters on each level, many of the unlockable characters followed the theme of the level it was from, like Kajsa Komet who was dressed like an astronaut, she was unlocked on the last level that had a space theme.There were 3 different modes of play, Race, Foodfight and Quiz.The race mode is a standard race, you raced thru the supermarket with your shopping-cart following flags trying to get to the finish, the cash register, before the computer opponents.In Foodfight the object off the game is to get to a product first, the PA system will tell you what product to get and you try to get there first, the first player to get 5 and gets to the cash register wins, to get the product you have to let go off the cart and then throw the product in it, opponents can try and bash your cart away when you let go of it, to slow you down.In the Quiz mode you play alone, you get a list of products to collect and you try to do it as fast as you can. To get a product you have to answer a question regarding one of the products in the game.Fun fact one of the products that sponsord the game is Gott  blandat one of the types of candy that Grin brought to the bombcast.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21905">PickUp Express</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4485/777190-mallmaniacs.jpg</image></root>