<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2433</id><name>Kunio-kun no Nekketsu Soccer League</name><description>Overview in this  game you take charge of one player of your choosing to captain a team of 6 players to be chosen out of 12 available . other players are AI controlled, however; you can command them to pass or shoot if  your team posses the ball or to defend when your team loses the ball. Each player has a unique strike or shot that varies in power and effectiveness. The game tries to infuse some strategy by allowing players to choose  style of offense and defense. players and their position is subject to change since all players can play in every position including the goalkeeper.      Strategies Game modes include N.league, Match, and Penalty. N.league you try to lead the Japanese team (only one available in this mode) to victory over teams from four different leagues each one includes 3 national teams: Asia League (Korea, Thailand and Mongolia); Africa League (Cameroon, Guinea, and Senegal); South America League (Argentina, Brazil, Mexico); and Euro League (England, Italy, and Germany) this mode available for 1 or 2 players. Match mode is a single friendly match where up to four players can compete versus each other or on the same team. in this mode you     lineup     are free to choose any country but unlike the Japanese team where each player has his own trademark shot, the entire team has one shot that only the captain can preform. Finally Penalty mode where a player vs AI or a player vs a player compete in penalty shootouts. all these modes available on three difficulties: Easy, Medium or Hard.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="40">Soccer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6718">Mario Strikers Charged</game><game id="15288">FIFA Street</game><game id="9592">FIFA Street 2</game><game id="20785">FIFA Street 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/4/48222/1374100-5b8cb56d87d940eca0ad3540ddc65664.jpg</image></root>