<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24362</id><name>Company of Heroes: Tales of Valor</name><description>OverviewCompany of Heroes: Tales of Valor is the second standalone expansion in the                 Company of Heroes  franchise which returns to the western front in France during    WW2; it  contains three new campaigns, new multiplayer gamemodes and maps , new  units and evolved gameplay mechanics. CampaignsEpisode 1: Tiger AceControl the          tiger  tank "Tigergruppen" against the British 7th Armored Division on D-Day  in one of the most famous tank battles of WWII.  This campaign tells the  story of The Battle of Villagers Bocage.  The battle takes place in  1944 when the Allied forces push ashore from the beaches.  The player  will take direct control of your lone Tiger where you can invest command  points in your tank crew to unlock new abilities.  This campaign shows  off the new feature "Direct Fire" where you can point where you want  your tank turret to point and shoot bringing you closer to the  battlefield and closer to your troops.Episode 2: CausewayTake  command of an American paratrooper unit who have been deployed a few  hours after the beginning of the D-Day landings.  This campaign follows  the 82nd Airborne's fight for La Fiere Causeway.  The player will take  command of Able and Baker squads to accomplish the mission.  Able squad  is led by Sgt. Wilson and Baker squad is led by Sgt. Craft.  The  gameplay revolves around these two squads and their distinct abilities  and specialty upgrades.  The Causeway campaign also employs the new  "Direct Fire" feature to better enhance the squads separate play styles.   Able squad is better at storming into battle equipped with Sub  Machine-guns while Baker squad wields Recoilless Rifles to neutralize  enemy vehicles.  Each squad can earn different upgrades, to having more  ammo for Able squad or equipping Baker squad with another Recoilless  Rifle.  A new feature introduced in this campaign is "Field Dressing".   Field Dressing is a special ability Able and Baker squads have to be  able to patch up a fallen soldier on the battlefield.Episode 3: Falaise PocketTake command of the  Wehrmacht army as you try and hold off an allied advance.MultiplayerThe  well praised Company of Heroes multiplayer mode returns with three new  gamemodes and alternate units to use in classic matches.Operation: StonewallThe  first of the new multiplayer gamemodes places four players into a  scenario in which they must defend a town against countless waves of AI  attacks and they must hold out as long as possible.  AI attacks increase  in strength over time from basic infantry to full armored vehicle  assaults.  Controlling certain points within the town is the key to  victory.  Aside from the usual cover specific buildings such as the  Church will heal nearby units and the Manor will grant a population cap  increase.  The Garage will give engineers a repair bonus and holding the  Bank will give you a bonus to your manpower income.  If  you survive  long enough eventually you will earn special abilities such as a Bombing  Run. This operation supports 1-4 Players Operation: PanzerKriegThis  new multiplayer mode tests players skills in tank vs. tank combat.   Each of the six tanks on the battlefield can be fielded for the Axis  and Allied powers have a unique role and their own command tree to  unlock unique abilities.  Victory is achieved by reducing the enemy's  points to zero and this is done by either holding the majority of the  Victory Points, causing them to slowly tick down, or by destroying the  enemy's tanks. The heavier the tank the more points awarded . Each  Victory Point on the map will also allow certain abilities to be used.   The radio point will grant the player access to support abilities such  as map reveals and artillery, the infantry point gives you AI controlled  infantry to defend an area, and the mortar point lets you own the  mortar bunker on the map. The radio and infantry points give you access  to stronger call-ins the longer you hold onto them. This operation supports 2-6 Players and uses the new "Direct Fire" ability on all the tanks.Operation: AssaultA  take on the classic DoTA mod, this mode pits two AI controlled enemy  forces against each other, throwing streams of soldiers at one another's  bases. The relatively equal forces will tangle with eachother and if  one side makes a breakthrough they will end up running into machine gun  nests so not much progress will be made by the AI alone. This is where  you come in controlling a single super powerful hero of your choice to  counter the enemy forces, remove the enemy MG nests holding up your  soldiers and eventually destroying the mortar bunker strong points.  Doing so not only stops mortar rounds from falling but it also causes  it's defenders to surrender and removes a spawn point for the enemy  forces and heroes. Each side has three defensive lines of 3 mortar  bunkers each, and ends with a large fuel depot that when destroyed will  spell defeat for it's owner. As the battle rages on each side will start  spawning stronger forces.At the start of the game you choose  one of seven heroes to start with and as you destroy the enemy forces  you gain experience to level up with, each level lets you enhance the  strength of either your weapon, your armor or your grenades. Whenever  your hero dies you can choose to spawn from the same selection after a  short wait, but no matter which you pick it will retain the same level  and upgrades.This mode supports 1 - 6 players. Alternate VehiclesIn standard matches owning Tales of Valor will unlock 2 new vehicles for each faction, and completing the Tiger Ace campaign will unlock Wittman's Tiger for the Wehrmacht. All of these units replace a normal unit when used.American Units American Units  M18 Hellcat (300 manpower 55 fuel)  Replaces the M10 Wolverine (300  manpower 55 fuel)  A similar tank destroyer with a similar price.  While somewhat lacking in speed and armor penetration compared to the  M10, it does have a couple unique additions. The first is a .50 cal  upgrade that is identical to the others available to U.S. armor, but in  this case is the only dedicated anti-infantry weapon available for it.  An M10 or a Hellcat without the upgrade has to rely on either lucky  shots with it's cannon or simply running the infantry over to deal with  them.The other add-on for the M18 is the ability to camouflage  itself, rendering it invisible (but stationary) and giving it a first  strike bonus when it fires from camouflage. The bonus attack will  increase penetration and damage but breaks the camouflage.    T17 Armored Car (280 MP 40 fuel)   Replaces the M8 Greyhound (280  MP 30 fuel)The T17 trades the M8's minedrop ability for a white  phosphorous round that can be used on any enemy vehicle to stun it.  This completely halts the vehicle, keeping it from moving or firing for a  few seconds, opening up all sorts of possibilities and making the T17 a  more active player in the late game when tanks are commonplace. Unlike  the Greyhound the T17 has no purchasable upgrades, but when it gets it's  first level of veterancy it gets a large bundle of sandbags tied around  it, a similar benefit to the M8's armored skirts. If you can survive  long enough to make those kills you can consider yourself up one free  upgrade.   British Units  Staghound Armored Car (280 Manpower 45 Fuel)  Replaces the Cromwell  Command Tank(300 Manpower 50 Fuel)The British  Armored Car may be a T17 by another name, but it's location in the tech  tree gives it a very different meaning. As a unit on it's own it's a  pretty standard armored car with the ability to buy a .50 cal turret  gunner, added to the normal firepower of the coaxial and hull machine  guns along with it's main cannon, giving it serious anti-infantry power,  but only mild anti-armor. The main interest of it is the fact  that it replaces the Cromwell command tank, which can give out  veterancy, but has almost no firepower of it's own. If you don't plan to  have a massive armor force, or your building Kangaroos which won't  benefit from tank veterancy, it might be more beneficial to have another  attacking unit. Note that even if you pick the Staghound you still have  to buy at least one to unlock Fireflies.    Kangaroo Carrier (240 Manpower 10 Fuel)  Replaces the  Cromwell Tank (400 Manpower 70 Fuel)A converted tank  with it's turret removed, the Kangaroo lets your infantry attack from a  mobile armored position. The 'Roo fits 15 individuals, with room for 6  to be firing out the top at once, whoever has the best weapon for the  situation will likely be the one shooting. The men inside will take no  damage until the Kangaroo is destroyed, but are free to continue to  fighting afterward.   Wehrmacht Units  Schwimmwagen Type 166 (240 MP) Replaces the Motorcycle (180 MP)   This unique vehicle largely outclasses the motorbike at higher  cost. With it's amphibious design the Schwimm can move through any map's  flooded areas without the usual high movement penalty, and being a car  as opposed to a bike, it can drive in reverse giving it greater  maneuverability. Additionally the Schimmwagen can sustain more damage  than it's counterpart, but it is not without it's disadvantages as it  has a slower top speed and takes longer to build.    Geschutzwagen (280MP 55 Fuel)  Replaces the StuG IV  (340 Manpower 40 Fuel)Where the StuG is a harden battering ram,  the Gewagen is more of a catapult. It contains a seriously powerful  anti-tank gun, and a turret gunner manning an MG42 to hold off infantry.  It's chassis puts out some serious horsepower giving it a very high top  speed on open ground, but with very slow turning, and with no rotating  turret that can be a serious liability. It's armor is quite weak as far  as tanks go, but with it's incredible range, and the ability to pay 50  munitions to double it's fire rate, you can do all the damage you need  before they can strike back if you engage at distance.   Tiger Tank "205"  Replaces the Tiger This reward for  completing the Tiger Ace campaign allows you to field the same         Tiger  commanded by Wittman in place of the usual Tiger. Unlike all of the  other replacements this is merely a change in look and voice, it will  function the same on the battlefield. Panzer Elite Units  Schwimmwagen Type 128 (165 MP)   Replaces the Kettenkrad (165  MP)As it is mostly the same unit but with amphibious travel, it  all comes down to the doctrine abilities. Scorched Earth will yield  incendiary traps for 15 munitions, placed like any normal mine but will  only trigger on infantry. Instead of exploding they ignite a large area  around it in flames, doing damage over time.Luftwaffe allows  your Schwimm to mark an enemy target. This ability can be used on any  enemy vehicle or infantry that isn't garrisoned. Marking a target will  increase the accuracy of any of your units firing upon it, and will also  allow you to see the unit after it dissapears into the fog of war,  especially useful for tracking down snipers. The effect lasts about 20  seconds and can be used every 10 seconds.Tank Destroyer gives you a  standard mine drop ability for 35 munitions a peice.   Hotckiss Light Tank (280 MP 45)  Replaces the Panzer IV Infantry  Support Tank (420 MP 60 Fuel)A lightweight tank, the Hotckiss  has very thin armor, and a small cannon with no machine guns. For 75  munitions you can give it a Long Barreled 37mm to up it's anti armor  capabilites, and for 150 munitions you can outfit it with a 4 tube  Walking Stuka indirect rocket launcher. Although not as strong, it can  be more versatile than the Panzer IV, and is much cheaper to put out.  System RequirementsOperating System: Windows® XP or Vista  Processor: SSE capable processor, 2.0 Ghz Intel Pentium IV  or equivalent or AMD Athlon XPMemory: 512 MB RAM. 1GB MB RAM required for Vista  Graphics: DirectX 9.0c compatible 64MB video card with  Pixel Shader 1.1 support or equivalentSound: DirectX® 9.0c compatible 16-bit sound card </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21175">Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War II</game><game id="3537">Conflict Zone</game><game id="26487">Order of War</game><game id="30367">Order of War: Challenge</game><game id="33907">APOX</game><game id="31579">Men of War: Vietnam</game><game id="39305">Wargame: AirLand Battle</game><game id="16537">COPS 2170: The Power of Law</game><game id="41044">9th Company: Roots of Terror</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1894703-box_cohtov.png</image></root>