<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24396</id><name>Grand Slam Tennis</name><description>EA's Grand Slam Tennis is the company's first foray into the tennis genre. The game sports an art style intended to appeal to a younger audience, and is one of the first games to employ the use of Wii MotionPlus. Though the game was built bottom-up with the Wii in mind.Grand Slam Tennis utilizes MotionPlus in such a way that the player can play the shots they want. It can recognize when players hit balls with top spin or slice, or when they want to play lobs, drop shots, or flat shots. EA claims that it "takes the authentic one-to-one motion to a new level."VenuesThe game is the first licensed tennis game since Top Spin 2 to feature Wimbledon. All four Grand Slams can be played, and each Slam comes with some of the unique courts that accompany them in real life. These include Rod Laver Arena and Hisense Arena (Australian Open), Court Philippe Chatrier and Suzanne Lenglen Court (French Open), Centre Court, Court One, and Court Three (Wimbledon), and Arthur Ashe Stadium, Louis Armstrong Stadium, and Court No. 9 (US Open).RosterGrand Slam Tennis includes the following players: Men John McEnroeBjorn BorgPete SamprasStefan EdbergBoris BeckerRoger FedererRafael NadalAndy RoddickNovak DjokovicAndy MurrayPat CashMichael StichKei NishikoriLleyton HewittJo-Wilfried TsongaWomen Chris EvertMartina NavratilovaJustine HeninLindsay DavenportVenus WilliamsSerena WilliamsMaria SharapovaAna Ivanovic</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="25">Tennis</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20578">Sega Superstars Tennis</game><game id="13328">Wii Sports</game><game id="15398">Mario Power Tennis</game><game id="25294">Virtua Tennis 2009</game><game id="10676">Virtua Tennis</game><game id="19443">Virtua Tennis 3</game><game id="9908">Virtua Tennis: World Tour</game><game id="20857">Top Spin 3</game><game id="32594">Top Spin 4</game><game id="19029">Top Spin</game><game id="17111">Top Spin 2</game><game id="32369">Virtua Tennis 4</game><game id="14977">Tennis 2K2</game><game id="21098">Wii Sports Resort</game><game id="30349">Sports Champions</game><game id="10903">Wimbledon Championship Tennis</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1824037-box_gst.png</image></root>