<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24415</id><name>Afterfall: InSanity</name><description>OverviewAfterfall: InSanity is a post-apocalyptic third person shooter/survival horror game. It originally started development as an RPG by Polish fans of games like Fallout and S.T.A.L.K.E.R. before it was professionalized under Intoxicate Studios in mid-2008 and got turned into a survival horror game.The game was released by Nicolas Entertainment Group on November 25th worldwide via digital distribution on PC while a boxed version was available in Poland (including a Collector's Edition). Initially, Xbox 360 and PlayStation 3 versions were announced but only the Xbox 360 version seems to be still in development.After initially launching only on gamersgate, the title now made its way onto other digital distribution platforms - namely Impulse and Origin. An "Extended Edition" was announced for release in Q3 of 2012 on PC and Xbox 360.StoryImagine, that one tiny detail changed the course of the whole history. Imagine, that there are no more malls, popcorn, cinemas and Sunday father-and-son strolls in the park.Civilization turned out to be a brittle behemoth that finally collapsed. The source of this tragedy was an almost fanatic obsession with money and power, which took on the proportions of a religion. People spent their lives chasing careers, only to die alone, aware of the fact that they just wasted the last 60 years of their lives. This was coupled with fanaticism and television that indoctrinated its viewers, telling them how to live and how to fulfill the “American Dream.” A crippled child begot by this deadly couple was frustration that ate away humanity from the inside. That was when the bombs fell.That is why you are sitting now in a small 4-man room with steel walls on an iron-hard bunk identical to 20.000 other occupied beds in this shelter. Not once in your life have your eyes seen sunshine. They have also been bereft of the sight of meadows stretching to the horizon, violent mountain streams and the forests surrounding them. You saw all of this in your mind’s eye, while listening to the stories told by the oldest inhabitants. But soon all this will change. The zero hour has come. The measuring systems send a clear message. The message generations were looking forward to the vault doors are opening.LevelsSheltered LifeNo DayLight In The ShelterInterrupted TransmissionOne Way TicketBackstage of GloryEdge of HumanityEscapeRaise The CurtainCity of LightLaw of the FistExtended EditionIn March 2012, Intoxicate announced a "2.0" edition of the game with significant changes to be released in Q3 2012. This update, dubbed "Extended Edition" would be distributed via a free patch to owners of the PC version while the first time Xbox 360 release will be available at the same time with all the changes already implemented.Most notable changes include (taken from the game's official website):New dynamic combat systemImproved cutscenes (camera, sound, animations)More elements of psychosis (FearLock)Improved facial expressionsImproved environment and character-audioBetter optimizationNew weapon(s)New automatic save points (checkpoints)New AI variantsNew lighting/special effectsNew and improved sound effectsNew balancing of gameplayChanges in the narration styleTechnical and gameplay improvementsThe $1 CampaignBefore there was the Kickstarter craze, there were clever marketing ideas. Developer Intoxicate Studios took to the web on October 9th, 2011 to announce a risky plan: They wanted 10 Million people to donate $1 in the form of a pre-order with 10% going to charity. This meant gamers would pay $1 and receive the full game upon release. If they failed, they would donate all the money the received to charity while the game would be sold at regular price. Since the goal was unrealistically high, the campaign failed and the game launched on PC on November 25th, 2011. Those who participated in the $1 campaign were given download codes for the game's soundtrack as well as a 50% off code for the game to be redeemed only on gamersgate.com.PC System RequirementsMinimumRecommendedOperative System: Windows XP SP 2 / Windows Vista / Windows 7Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo 2Ghz / AMD Athlon 64 x2 2GhzRAM Memory: 2 GB (XP), 3 GB (Vista and Win 7)Video Card: 256 MB, DirectX 9.0c i Shader 3.0 (GeForce 8600GT / ATI equivalent or better)HDD Space: 7 GBOperative System: Windows XP SP 2 / Windows Vista / Win 7Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo 2Ghz / AMD Athlon 64 x2 2Ghz or betterRAM Memory: 3 GBVideo Card: GeForce 8600 GT or Radeon HD 4550 or equivalentHDD Space: 7 GB</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20800">Dead Space</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2381666-pc.jpg</image></root>