<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24417</id><name>Snoopy Flying Ace</name><description>Overview  Snoopy Flying Ace is a flight combat game developed by                   Smart Bomb Interactive and published by                 Microsoft Game Studios for the Xbox Live Arcade. It is the sequel to                  Snoopy vs. the Red Baron and features online gameplay for up to 16 players. Along with a mission-based campaign; it features a leveling system that sees you unlocking new things such as weapons, planes and characters as you gain experience points by destroying enemy planes.   Features Players 1-2Co-op  1-2HDTV 1080pIn-game Dolby DigitalOnline Multiplayer  2-16Co-op 1-2Content  DownloadsLeaderboardsVoiceCharactersThere are a wide variety of characters from the Peanuts universe that the player can choose from when beginning a game. Whichever character is selected will not affect gameplay beyond aesthetics. The available characters include:              Snoopy         Charlie BrownSchroederSallyRerunPigpenPeppermint PattyMarcie       Lucy        Linus      FranklinRed Baron     Player's Avatar VehiclesThere are also a number of airplanes to choose from when selecting a character. Unlike the characters, these planes differ in their handling, health, and speed statistics. Through these, the planes fall into a light, medium, and heavy classifications. A light plane can outmaneuver a medium or heavy plane, but will be easily shot down. On the flipside, a heavier plane will have more difficulty maneuvering but can stand up to heavy gunfire. Experimenting with different plane types depending on the mission, map, and opponents is key to obtaining victory.  WeaponsAfter selecting a character and airplane, the player must then select two secondary weapons to go along with standard mounted machine guns. The choices are:  Blunderbuss   Basically, a mounted shotgun. This weapon is only effective at very close range, but it is devastating when it can get   close enough. Comet Rockets   These are basically cluster missiles. They are fairly effective at medium range when they can establish a lock on the   target. EMPLlike an EMP in other games, the EMP disorients other players, damaging them and throwing them off course. Leech   This rocket, when it homes in on an enemy, attaches itself to the enemy plane and explodes a few seconds later. The   ensuing explosion is usually a one-hit-kill but the leech can be shaken off with a maneuver. Molten Flail   These medieval-esque spiked balls hang below the plane, but can be activated to catch on fire and start spinning.   Devastating if rammed into an opponent. Rain Maker   Another set of machine guns to complement the other machine guns. The work best if fired in tandem with the other   machine guns. Squitos   Aerial mines that hang out where they were dropped and pelt any opponent that gets too close to them. Swarm   Similar to the Comet Rockets, but with poison. They cause progressive damage but do less immediate damage upon   impact than the Comet Rockets. Tarpedo   A sticky bomb, remote detonated. Wingman   Essentially, a homing missile, but it can go after another target once it finds its first target. Silver Bullet   Fires a massive bullet straight ahead. No homing capabilities, but it will destroy whoever it hits and keep on going   through them. B.A.M.  Another aerial mine, but it is to be used defensively: when dropped it will attract homing weapons.    Big Bang   Similar to the Silver Bullet, it fires several weaker fireballs straight ahead.      Multi player maps    There are a total of eight multi player maps that come with the game with two new maps released for 80 Microsoft points.ToulonSand SphinxIce GrottoCity of LightsDesert TracksLost IslandFrozen FjordL'BarrageAces Airway  - DLCKaiser's Spike - DLC DLCTwo New Airplanes  Whirlybird w/ Sniper Rifle weaponDragonfly w/ Jammer WeaponAvatar Awards  There are 2  avatar awards to be earned.  Charlie Brown's T-Shirt - Obtain at least one medal in each mission. Red Baron Suit - (Achievement:  Flying Ace) Reach the Flying Ace rank in Xbox Live public matches.       </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20458">Warhawk</game><game id="12911">Crimson Skies: High Road to Revenge</game><game id="13712">Blazing Angels: Squadrons of WWII</game><game id="17131">Crimson Skies</game><game id="31457">Dogfighter</game><game id="31188">Tom Clancy's H.A.W.X. 2</game><game id="32364">Top Gun</game><game id="36073">SkyDrift</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1839038-box_sfa.png</image></root>