<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2445</id><name>Galaxian</name><description>OverviewOriginally released in 1979, Galaxian was one of the early arcade games that is still considered a classic. Developed by Namco and released by Midway, it is a fixed shooter arcade game, and is characteristic of the genre, which was created by the release of Space Invaders a year earlier. Galaxian stays true to the formula established by Space Invaders, in that you control a spaceship at the bottom of the screen and must destroy groups of ships at the top of the screen by means of shooting. The main gameplay addition offered by Galaxian to the Space Invaders formula is the kamikaze like behavior of enemy ships. The rate of shooting is relatively slow, however your weapon is reloaded immediately upon a successful hit. Once a wave is conquered, another one, with increased difficulty, would replace it.Galaxian also offered multi colored animated sprites (including explosions), theme music, background music, and representative icons to indicate number of lives left. These were not brand new additions to video games, however Galaxian's use of them would influence game development over the next several years.The game was considered a success and spawned the even more successful sequel, Galaga, in 1981. Galaxian's success drove the development of several versions for various home consoles, and can found collected in various Namco Museum collections for modern day consoles. GameplayThe objective is destroy endless 'waves' of enemies. The enemy ships are arranged in a formation at the top of the screen. At regular intervals enemy ships on the sides of the formation swoop down and shoot at the player. There are 4 different types of enemy ship, each type behaves differently on its attacking run. The player must destroy all ships in a wave to complete it. With a minor exception that one yellow ship may dissappear after a bombing run and will appear as an extra yellow ship in the following wave. The yellow ships attack in a formation with two red ships, the order these three are destroyed determines the points awarded for destroying the yellow. The maximum is 800 points if the two reds are destoyed first. Once a wave has been completed a red flag is added to the bottom of the screen. When 10 flags are accumulated they are replaced by a larger flag. The player has 3 lives at the beginning of the game. A bonus life is awarded when the player reaches a score of 7000 points. Once all lives have been lost the game ends. The player can only have one shot on screen at one time. This means if the player misses he must wait until the shot leaves the top of the screen to fire again. This makes accuracy very important.   High score The current world record score for Galaxian is  1,653,270 points.</description><genres><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5099">Space Invaders</game><game id="7451">Moon Cresta</game><game id="13292">Wavy Navy</game><game id="21465">Retro Game Challenge</game><game id="13036">Gorf</game><game id="15784">Galaga</game><game id="15941">Demon Attack</game><game id="3196">Phoenix</game><game id="8975">Pleiads</game><game id="23221">Phoenix</game><game id="1157">Centipede</game><game id="2773">Millipede</game><game id="9694">Megamania</game><game id="12834">Alien Invaders - Plus!</game><game id="14030">Demons to Diamonds</game><game id="23504">Vector Vaders</game><game id="12744">Chicken Invaders</game><game id="8125">Astrosmash</game><game id="13424">Cheesy Invaders</game><game id="1293">CHAMP Invaders</game><game id="20776">Radar Scope</game><game id="23877">Annihilator</game><game id="18283">Warplock</game><game id="11031">Better Dead Than Alien!</game><game id="24551">Tail Gun Charlie</game><game id="14772">Sneakers</game><game id="30655">Galactic Invasion</game><game id="34482">Arcadians</game><game id="34735">Battle Vader</game><game id="14693">CHAMP Galaxia</game><game id="41629">UniWar S</game><game id="42466">MonkeyRoids</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3413/215157-galaxian.jpg</image></root>