<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24513</id><name>DiRT 2</name><description>DiRT 2 was developed by Codemasters, the makers of DiRT and, more recently, GRiD, which was released in June, 2008. The game carries on the McRae legacy despite both his, and his son's, untimely death in September of 2007.DevelopmentOne of the first games to use DX11 on the PCThe game is built on the third-generation EGO engine, which improves on the lighting, damage-modeling, and textures found in GRiD. The game also features an improved system to handle environmental hazards such as dust kicked up by other drivers, pools of water, and more. The game also improves on the series standard driver's-seat view, and incorporates the rewind feature found in GRiD, which allows people a limited amount of attempts to re-do missed turns, spin outs, et cetera. Also improved is the online-multiplayer experience, which includes both tour and quick races, leader-boards, frequent tournaments (which also allow players to win prizes), and an improved matchmaking system, by which players gain "fame" (the game's version of experience) as they drive in online-races.ReleaseDiRT 2 was released on September 8th in North America and September 11th in the United Kingdom. This was only for consoles and portable game devices. The PC version of Dirt 2 was released in North America on December 8th. 2009 and was one of the first games to take advantage of new DirectX 11 features found in only the newest graphics cards.Career ModePlayer's Garage and Tour BusThe main game-play mode in DiRT 2 is the DiRT World Tour. This mode takes players from their first race, in London, to tracks all across the world as they gain fame and level up. Players will be able to form friendships with other drivers, which in turn allows them to qualify for team-events. Any event the player races in, gains them both: fame - the game's form of experience; and money, which can be used to buy new cars, as well as upgrade existing ones. World Tour Mode takes players all across th e world, from Baja California and London, to Malaysia, China, Japan, and more. Players are also able to take part in X-Games, which give them a chance to own bonus money and fame, as well as exclusive cars.As players gain more fame and level up, they can compete in more events, in more locations. As players move up the tree from Rookie to All-Star, they take on harder opponents in faster cars. More fame and money can be earned on higher career skill-levels, but the difficulty of the A.I. increases and the number of "rewinds" given decreases from five on the easiest to none of the most difficult setting.Game Modes  Track List"My Rides"DiRT 2 comes with eight standard game modes, each with their own custom track layouts and default vehicle restrictions. These vehicle restrictions (or vehicle sets are they are called in game) are based on the size and nature of the tracks and the corresponding game mode. It's to make sure players pick the right car for the circuit and also to maintain parity across the field. Once a vehicle set is picked, players can only pick cars from that particular set so it avoids situations where someone might end up racing the nimble Mitsubishi Evo against the bulkier Hummer. The Career mode has all these modes sprinkled in equal quantity throughout the campaign.In addition to the following list, players can also create their own custom tracks and mix-n-match game modes with different vehicle sets in multiplayer. However, the game gives you a fair warning against mixing extreme cases like racing a Bowler on a RallyCross track.RALLYThe classic Rally mode, where drivers make a point to point run with the option of a co-driver for instructions. Driver with the quickest time is the winner. The vehicles are the limited to the Rally specification only. Here are the standard tracks available for Rally mode:LocationTrack LayoutsBaja California, MexicoSpillway Long, Spillway ShortMalaysiaLadang Sprint, Ladang Mine Run, Ladang LongMoroccoKasbah Run, Ait Benhaddou, TamdaghtChinaLi River, Li River Hillclimb, Li River DescentCroatiaHairpin Run, Chapel Run, Mali Alan PassRALLYCROSSThe closest thing to a standard race format, RallyCross puts 8 drivers on a half-asphalt, half-off-road circuit. The first driver to complete a set number of laps wins. The vehicles are limited to RallyCross specifications only. The standard tracks for this mode are:LocationTrack LayoutsLondonBattersea Bridge, Battersea Bridge B, Battersea AirJapanShibuya, Shibuya BLos AngelesMarina Air, Marina Sprint, Stadium SprintTRAILBLAZERSimilar to the standard Rally format, players have to set their quickest time on a point to point track. The twist here is that players don't get the help of any co-driver and nearly everyone is on the track at the same time, split by a few seconds through staggered starts. As a result, it's possible to overtake others (or be overtaken) in this mode. Only cars under the Trailblazer vehicle set are allowed. The standard tracks for this are:LocationTrack LayoutUtahKane Creek, Hurrah PassMoroccoOunila Descent, Ounila ValleyChinaYu Yong, Yu Yong B, Yu Yong Sprint, Yu Yont Sprint BLANDRUSHSet across off-road tracks, Landrush pits eight drivers in an all out race to the finish. The terrain features massive jumps, drops and water traps. The vehicles are limited to Trophy Trucks, Stock Baja, Raid T1 and Class 1 Buggies. Here is the standard track list for this mode:LocationTrack LayoutMalaysiaTanamera, Tanamera FallsMoroccoHammada Circuit, Hammada SprintBajaEnsenada, Ensenada SprintRAIDA point to point race on an off-road track with all-terrain vehicles. These tracks are wider than normal and feature multiple splits (or shortcuts). Like Landrush, it's limited to Trophy Trucks, Stock Baja, Raid T1 and Class 1 Buggies. The standard tracks for this are:LocationTrack LayoutBajaPeninsula Run, SpillwayCroatiaNovigradMalaysiaRawang TrailMoroccoKasbah TrailLAST MAN STANDINGThe closest thing to an elimination mode in DiRT 2. Players drive around a closed circuit, as the last man is eliminated after every 30 secs. Terminal damage to the car also knocks you out and resets the timer. This mode allows almost all the vehicle sets. Here is the standard track list for this mode:LocationTrack LayoutLondonBattersea Air, Battersea Bridge, Battersea Bridge BBajaEnsenada, Ensenada SprintJapanShibuya, Shibuya BMalaysiaTanamera, Tanamera FallsLos AngelesMarina Air, Marina Sprint, Stadium SprintMoroccoHammada Circuit, Hammada SprintGATECRASHERA twist on the standard Rally mode, drivers race across a track smashing through as many gates as possible. Each gate gives the driver 2 extra seconds and the driver with the most time wins. This mode is restricted to Rally cars only.LocationTrack LayoutBajaSpillway ShortMalaysiaLadang Sprint, Ladang Mine RunMoroccoAit Benhaddou, TamdaghtChinaLi River Hillclimb, Li River DescentCroatiaHairpin Run, Chapel RunDOMINATIONIn Domination, a circuit is split into multiple sectors. Drivers get points based on their sector times. At the end of their alloted laps, the driver with the most points wins. This mode is open to nearly all the vehicle sets.LocationTrack LayoutLondonBattersea Bridge, Battersea Bridge B, Battersea AirJapanShibuya, Shibuya BBajaEnsenada, Ensenada SprintMalaysiaTanamera, Tanamera FallsMoroccoHammada Circuit, Hammada SprintLos AngelesMarina Air, Marina Sprint, Stadium SprintCar ListDiRT 2 features a large selection of licensed vehicles, from rally cars to buggies, and sees the return of the trucks from the original DiRT, albeit downsized to a large degree. There are a total of seven separate classes of vehicles that the player gets to drive on the game's large variety of tracks, which take place all over the world; in Africa, Asia, Europe, and the United States.The cars are segregated into the following vehicle sets:Rally, Rallycross and TrailblazerSubaru WRX STINote: Cars have different statistics under each sub-set.BMW Z4 Coupe MotorsportColin McRae R4Mitsubishi Eclipse GTMitsubishi Lancer Evolution IXMitsubishi Lancer Evolution XNissan 350zPontiac Solice GXPSubaru Impreza WRX STISubaru Impreza STI Group NStock BajaHonda RidgelineDodge Power WagonHonda RidgelineHummer HXToyota FJ CruiserRaid T1Mitsubishi Racing LancerBowler NemesisHummer H3Mitsubishi Racing LancerVolkswagen (VW) Race Touareg 2Trophy TrucksChevy SilveradoChevrolet Silverado CK-1500Dodge Ram Trophy TruckKincaid Ford F-150 Trophy TruckWest Coast Choppers Stuka TTClass 1 BuggiesPorter PRC-1Brian Ickler BuggyDeJong MXRHerbst Smithbuilt BuggyPRC-1 BuggySoundtrackBiffy Clyro - MountainsBlack Stone Cherry - Blind ManBlack Tide - ShoutBlakfish - Jeremy Kyle Is A Marked ManBloc Party - HelicopterBloc Party - TalonsDeichkind - Ich Betaeube MichDie! Die! Die! - Sideways Here We ComeDinosaur Pileup - All Around The WorldEagles Of Death Metal - Wannabe In LAElbow - Ground For DivorceFranz Ferdinand - UlyssesFriendly Fires - In The HospitalFriendly Fires - LovesickGlamour Of The Kill - A Hope In HellHollow Earth Theory - TransmissionIglue  Hartly - Violent  YoungKram - Good LoveLadyhawke - My DeliriumMadina Lake - Never Take Us AliveMSTRKRFT - Work On YouProceed - Treading WaterProdigy - Warriors DanceQemists - Lost WeekendQueens Of The Stone Age - Little SisterRise Against - InjectionSantogold - Say AhaScars On Broadway - They SaySilversun Pickups - There'e No Secrets This YearSteadlur - Bumpin'Templeton Pek - Red Lights FlashThe Automatic - Steve McQueenThe Cribs - Men's NeedsThe Futureheads - Radio HeartThe Hot Melts - EdithThe Rakes - 1989The Stone Roses - This Is The OneThe Subways - I Won't Let You DownThe Temper Trap - Science Of FearThe Walkmen - The RatTommy Sparks - I'm A RopeUnkle ft Josh Homme - RestlessWhite Denim - Let's Talk About itWhite Lies - To Lose My LifeYou Me At Six - Save It For The BedroomYeah Yeah Yeahs - Y ControlSupported controllers and steering wheels (PC)KeyboardKeyboard ControlsControl PadsDiRT 2 can be configured to use almost any PC controller, however it is recommended to use one the following controllers for the best experience:Official Xbox 360 ControllerLogitech Cordless RumblePad 2 USBThrustmaster T-Wireless 3 in 1 Rumble ForceThrustmaster Run’N’Drive WirelessThrustmaster Run'N'Drive Wired Rumble ForceThrustmaster Dual Trigger Rumble ForceThrustmaster Dual Analog 3Steering wheelsDiRT 2 provides default configurations for all of the below, meaning that you should be able to plug-and-play, without tweaking.For some wheels (e.g. Logitech MOMO, Fanatec Porche) it is important that the pedals are on separate axes, rather than combined. From the Windows Control Panel, choose 'Controllers' and click 'Properties' for the wheel you will be using. Click 'Settings' and ensure that the 'Combined' or 'Single Axis' setting is unticked.Logitech G25 Racing WheelLogitech G27 Racing WheelLogitech Driving Force ProOfficial Microsoft Xbox 360 WheelThrustmaster Ferrari 430 Force Feedback Racing WheelThrustmaster RGT F/F Pro (with and without Clutch models)Logitech MOMO WheelLogitech MOMO ForceFanatec Porsche 911 Turbo Wheel (PWT)Thrustmaster Ferrari GT WheelPC System RequirementsMinimum Requirements:OS: Microsoft Windows XP, Vista or Windows 7Processor: - Intel Pentium D 3.0Ghz or AMD Athlon 64 X2Memory: 1GB (2GB for Windows Vista)Graphics: ATI Radeon X1500 or NVIDIA GeForce 6800DirectX®: 9 and 11Hard Drive: 10GBController Support: XBox 360 controller supportOther Requirements: Online play requires log-in to Games For Windows - Live.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20729">GRID</game><game id="23461">FUEL</game><game id="20451">MotorStorm: Pacific Rift</game><game id="25424">MotorStorm: Arctic Edge</game><game id="24793">MotorStorm</game><game id="20132">Sega Rally Revo</game><game id="22490">Sega Rally 3</game><game id="1101">Ridge Racer 7</game><game id="941">Project Gotham Racing</game><game id="2279">Project Gotham Racing 2</game><game id="19809">Project Gotham Racing 3</game><game id="23116">Ridge Racer 2</game><game id="11607">Ridge Racer Revolution</game><game id="1880">Ridge Racer 64</game><game id="11625">Ridge Racer DS</game><game id="7019">Ridge Racer V</game><game id="2453">R4 Ridge Racer Type 4</game><game id="6499">RalliSport Challenge 2</game><game id="8944">RalliSport Challenge</game><game id="12950">Gran Turismo 3 A-Spec</game><game id="17784">Gran Turismo 4</game><game id="20597">Gran Turismo 5 Prologue</game><game id="21790">Gran Turismo 5</game><game id="16191">Sega Rally 2</game><game id="7510">Need for Speed: V-Rally</game><game id="6829">Need for Speed: V-Rally 2</game><game id="10791">Beetle Adventure Racing!</game><game id="12194">GT Advance 2: Rally Racing</game><game id="24995">Forza Motorsport 3</game><game id="12976">Need for Speed: Most Wanted</game><game id="31982">WRC: FIA World Rally Championship</game><game id="34427">Sega Rally Online Arcade</game><game id="34757">Test Drive V-Rally</game><game id="36993">Project CARS</game><game id="37743">F1 2012</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1891339-box_dirt2.png</image></root>