<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24527</id><name>beatmania THE FINAL</name><description>New SongsGenreSong NameArtist TEKNO12.4 RAM  TECHNO 2.14.23dj nagureo  UK GARAGEAin't It GoodTomoki Hirata  DRUM'N BASSAll is vanity good-cool  RAVEASK RAM  HIPHOPBadboy flygirl Miss Monday  Gury  LATIN POPBAILA! BAILA! DANDY MINERO  2STEPbirdman NM feat. TIME  UK GARAGEBODY Tomoki Hirata  EURO GROOVEBRILLIANT 2U NAOKI  J-RBcalling for distiny NM feat. NAPPO  CANDY POPCANDY☆LUV UNLIMITED  CYBER PUNKCAT MAN CALF  DRUM'N BASSCLOUDY MUSIC SLAKE  MIXTURALCOREDESAT Des-ROW  DISCODANCE THE NIGHT AWAY KAZ SENOO feat. MANNY MENDEZ  DANCE POPDr. LOVE baby weapon feat. Asuka M  TRANCEEAST MEETS WEST RAM  BROKEN BEATS蝶の羽 (Chou no Hane)SLAKE feat. ANCTEA  HOUSEfeeling of love Youhei Shimizu  EPILOUGEfellows dj TAKA feat. Sana  BREAKBEATS TRANCEFIRE WIRE PINK PONG  BIGBEATGAMBOL SLAKE  GAMELAN TRANCEGamelan de Couple TOMOSUKE  DRUM'N BASSgentle stress DJ Swan  GUITAR PUNKHappy Man Mutsuhiko Izumi  HIPHOPHIT'N'SLAP ASLETICS  GOA TRANCEImplantation TOMOSUKE  WARP HOUSEJam  Marmalade FinalOffSet  GUITAR PUNKJET WORLD Mutsuhiko Izumi JAZZ HIPHOP Keep On Liftin' dj nagureo  HYPER EUROBEATKISS KISS KISS NAOKI feat. SHANTI  BOSSA LOUNGELa Brise d'ete Orange Lounge  HOUSELive together good-cool  HAPPY HARDCORELOVE D RIVE D-Crew  KONAMIXMGS2 mission R L.E.D. (original by NORIHKIHO HIBINO) J-GARAGE POPMiracle MoonTogo Project feat. SanaJAZZ HOUSEmnemoniqYouhei ShimizuPERCUSSIVE西新宿清掃曲 (Nishi Shinjuku Seisou Kyoku)SIMON MANNU JAZZNURUHACHIASLETICSBROKEN AMBIENCEone seekpositive MA feat. AKINOEURO BEATOverwhelminggood-coolPSYCHADELICperfect sunriseMIRAK feat. Brian SmithTRANCEPURE DREAMPINK PONGPSYCHEDELICQuickeningdj TAKADISCO TRANCERE-ROOTSNAPAKICKEXPERIMENTAL赤カーテン (Aka Curtain)mur.mur.kurotohHIPHOPRest my minddj nagureo feat. DoublecheeseBREAKBEATSRETROFUTUREDJ SIMONDUB POPSAVIORreo nagumo feat. Lala MooreJ-POPShake it downgood-coolDRUM'N BASSSHOXRAMTRANCE TECHNOspecial energyDJ FXGARAGE HOUSEStay with medj nagureo feat. Robbie DanzieEURO GROOVESYNTH 1997e.o.s.RADA TECHNOtaulanaewnmur.mur.kurotohPROGRESSIVETHE LEAST 100 SEC.Sasaki HirofumiEUROBEATTwin Bee -Generation X-FinalOffSetTECHNOULTRARAMMIXTUREVOIDDDDes-ROW feat. Kevin VecchioneHIP ROCK大見解 (Daikenkai)Des-ROW feat. TSUBOI from ALPHA</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25988">Cool Cool Jam</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/23793/814887-bm_thefinal.jpg</image></root>