<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24590</id><name>Exodus From The Earth</name><description>StoryThe game takes place in 2016. Mankind reckons it'll be five billion years before the Earth starts to die. However, in reality it turns out that the Earth is living its last twenty years. According to the current studies, the Sun is to become an ever-increasing “Red Giant” burning everything on its way and turning the Earth into a lifeless hell.So, mankind has been beset with a monumental task which is to either adapt human beings for living in extraterrestrial conditions, or to find an Earth-like planet where people can live.The A.X. Corporation, which is the largest genetic and space military engineering company, has undertaken to conduct the research. After a while, the Corporation, with Mr.Crizby at the head, offered the technology that could allow human beings to survive in any alien extraterrestrial environment. On a distant planet they found a mineral from which they could produce a vaccine that would allow human beings to live in any environment. The Corporation’s proposal was to inject their vaccine into every person and then move to some other planet beyond the solar system.The Intelligence Agency is not likely the idea of being entirely dependent on the Corporation and furthermore, nobody knows how the mineral will influence human organisms. Moreover, according to their information there was an astronaut, John Rick, who had supposedly found a so-called “Second Earth” which was a planet with an Earth-like environment. Based on secret information, John Rick returned from his space expedition and disappeared. The Intelligence Agency suspected the Corporation of removing John Rick in order to subordinate all of mankind for their financial interests.The Intelligence Agency has commissioned the main hero whose name is Frank, to find out what is happening inside the Corporation’s confines and to get the information about the Earth-like planet if it really exists.System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Windows® XP or Windows® VistaProcessor: Intel® Pentium™ 1,8 GHz or AMD Athlon™ XP 1.8Memory: 512 Mb RAMGraphics: 3D Video card with 128 Mb memory supporting DirectX® 9.0c, PS 2.0 (starting from NVIDIA GeForce FX 5700 or ATI RADEON 9600) with the latest driver installedDirectX Version: DirectX® 9.0 (included)Hard Drive: 7 GB free space for the game additionally for saved gamesSound Card: 16-bit sound card, fully compatible with DirectX® 9.0cInput: Mouse, Keyboard, Controller Pad, Xbox 360 ControllerRecommended:OS: Windows® XP or Windows® VistaProcessor: Intel® Core™ 2 Duo E6600 or AMD Athlon™ 64 X2 4200 (or other dual core processor of at least such performance level)Memory: 2048 Mb RAMGraphics: 256 Mb video card ATI Radeon X1950Pro, GeForce 7950GT or analogue supporting pixel shaders 2.0 and DirectX® 9.0c compatible with the latest driver installedDirectX Version: DirectX® 9.0 (included)Hard Drive: 7 GB free space for the game additionally for saved gamesSound Card: Creative sound card of X-Fi series</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1987/818637-exodus_header.jpg</image></root>