<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24739</id><name>Trine</name><description>StoryTrine is set in a fantasy kingdom, which was once beautiful and prosperous, but has since fallen into ruin due to an undead army that attacked the kingdom. Trine starts with three adventurers, a knight named Pontius, a thief named Zoya, and a wizard named Amadeus, who simultaneously stumble upon an ancient artifact called the Trine. All three touch the Trine at the same time, which magically fuses all three souls into one body. They each maintain their individual voices  consciousnesses, but can only inhabit the single body one at a time. Luckily, they are able to transform into any one of the three characters at any time they choose.The trio are reluctant to work together, but in order to find a way to counteract the Trine and separate their souls from each other, they are forced to battle their way through the kingdom and the undead armies to find a cure. The Wizard is able to decipher some ancient inscriptions, and they soon discover that the Trine is one part of a trio of ancient artifacts, representing the mind, the body, and the soul. The three artifacts are scattered through the kingdom, but the Wizard theorizes that if these three artifacts are brought together, it may free them from the Trine.As the adventurers battle their way through the kingdom, they eventually do bring the three artifacts together, which indeed unbinds their souls from the Trine. Reuniting the artifacts also has the fortunate side effect of liberating the kingdom from the undead armies, and Pontius, Amadeus and Zoya are hailed as heroes.CharactersThe characters in Trine are very much lighter versions of the archetypal definition of three very famous fantasy classes:Amadeus, the WizardAmadeus is an "old" wizard still "studying" at the Astral Academy. Through a series of accidents, he's left behind in the castle when the undead army approaches. Usually, at Amadeus' age, wizards would have graduated and left, but Amadeus never quite passed the wizarding exams. He's never even learned the fireball spell, having always been more interested in flirting with the girls and going to great lengths to pretend that he's a magnificent wizard. However, this traditionally only leads to failure.Abilities: Despite not having learned the fireball spell, Amadeus knows still a few useful spells. He can summon Boxes and Planks and he can also levitate objects. Through the course of the game, he will learn to cast Boxes and Planks in larger quantities.Amadeus, the WizardPontius, the KnightPontius isn't really a Knight, but he does dream of joining the King's army and what better way to do that than to battle against the undead and prove himself worthy of knighthood? The problem is that Pontius doesn't really know what "undead" means, and he thinks he's the only one staying behind to face the enemy in the castle. Pontius is a large individual and enjoys a fine dose of meat at every hour or so. He's a friendly, happy fellow, and thinks good of everything and everyone. Unless he's hungry, of course. Pontius is a bit on the slow side, though -- he never gets a joke, and doesn't quite understand all the magic business going on around him.Abilities: Pontius has an impressive arsenal of melee weapons. His strength also comes in handy when it comes to lifting heavy objects, or throwing them upon your enemies. Pontius also has a shield that he can use to block attacks. He cannot swim in his armor, though.Pontius, the KnightZoya, the ThiefZoya is from a distant land. She heard there was an ancient object with tremendous value in the castle and realizing that the Undead army marching towards the castle had already done half the job for her by leaving the castle abandoned, she feels that the time is right to break in and steal the precious treasure. Zoya is a great thief and has a soft spot for all things shiny, but not much else is known about her. She keeps to herself and doesn't like anyone asking her any questions. She's not one to reveal any kind of secrets about her.Abilities: Zoya is an amazing archer. Her ranged attacks are great for hitting enemies at a long distances. Zoya also carries a grappling-hook that she can attach to wooden surfaces. She can then grab onto them and swing herself over ledges and climb up or down with the rope.Zoya, the ThiefGameplayTrine bills itself as a "physics-based action game", and focuses on platforming, combat, and simple puzzle solving. The player uses the knight, the thief, and the wizard to work their way through this 2D side scrolling environment, and can switch between the characters throughout the game at any time. Each character has their own individual abilities that can be used to solve various conundrums faced by the player.The Thief navigates the forests of TrineThe Knight uses a heavy sword, and can lift, carry and throw heavy objects, and can lift his shield to block attacks. The Thief can use a grappling hook on wooden surfaces and use her bow and arrow to kill enemies and activate remote switches. The Wizard is unique in that he has the ability to summon physical objects, such as boxes and planks, which can be used as a stepping stone for higher jumps, to drop on enemies, or to block projectiles. Each character has their own health and energy bar as well which adds a layer of management to the game's equation.Leveling UpThere are two ways to gain experience in Trine:Killing enemies and taking the "auras" or "souls" they leave behindBy finding green potions scattered and hidden throughout all the levelsThe latter creates interesting mini-challenges as you go, as these potions are often hidden or just apparently out of reach, causing the player to use creative problem solving to retrieve the potion. Once the player recovers a certain amount of green potions or enemy "souls", they are allowed to level up one of the characters, granting upgrades like increased damage and new attacks. The secret treasure chests are generally hidden much more discreetly and requires the player to get creative in order to find  reach their location. Treasures grant the characters other special abilities, and while some can be swapped between more than one character, others are character specific.Local Co-OpThe game has local co-op multiplayer, allowing up to two other players to join your game. This adds a new element to the gameplay, by allowing new ways to overcome obstacles by combining each characters abilities. To play the game co-op on the PC, you may now use any PC gamepad (including the Xbox 360 controller), or multiple keyboards and mice. Each player may also assign their own controls if they wish.Trine designer and Frozenbyte CEO, Lauri Hyvärinen has said they plan to add online multiplayer at a later date, but this seems less likely of possibility as time passes.Inventory ItemsThroughout the course of the game, the player -- if adventurous enough -- can find a series of items inside of treasure chests (some of them hidden away from the game's main path) that will make his/her journey through the world of Trine a lot easier.ItemItem DescriptionBuffsUsable ByAmulet of Energy GainIncreases the effect of energy potions by 5%EnergyAnyAmulet of the KingsIncreases maximum health by 15%HealthAnyAmulet of SacrificeUses health as a substitute for energy if energy has run outEnergyAnyBlue MasterstoneIncreases number of boxes or arrows by 1AbilityWizardThiefEnergy Vial (inventory)Restores 30% of energy when energy is depleted. Reloads at checkpoint.EnergyAnyWolfgang's Music BoxIncreases number of boxes by 2AbilityWizardRing of SpellcasterIncreases maximum energy by 5%EnergyAnyStatue of the EagleReduces energy cost of levitationEnergyWizardEnchanted Energy CrystalIncreases effect energy vials by 5%EnergyAnyOrb of EnergyIncreases maximum energy by 10%EnergyAnyPendant of the GuardianIncreases maximum energy by 15%EnergyAnyHealth Vial (Inventory)Restores 25% health when health drops below 25%. Reloads at checkpoint.HealthAnyBracersReduces damage hitting armsArmorAnyGem of ResurrectionAllows the bearer to resurrect, once per level.AbilityAnyLeggingsReduces damage hitting legsArmorAnyNecklace of PowerIncreases damage by 25% for weapons that use energyAbilityAnyNecklace of LifeIncreases maximum health by 5%HealthAnyScales of FishUnderwater breathingAbilityAnyRed MasterstoneIncreases number of planks by 1 (Wizard) or health by 10% (Knight)AbilityHealthWizardKnightBottle of PoisonIncreases damage from basic sword or basic arrowsWeaponsKnightThiefPrism of Light25% more health and energy from checkpoints.HealthEnergyAnyAmulet of FortitudeIncreases maximum health by 10%HealthAnyEnchanted Health CrystalIncreases the effect of health potions by 5%HealthAnyPendant of Life StealingRestores 2 points of health per killed monster when the owner is inactiveHealthAnyBootsReduces damage from spikes and hazardous surfacesArmorAnyVictor's CrownIncreases number of planks by 2AbilityWizardLevelsLevel No.LevelTotal Potion ExperienceTotal Enemy ExperienceSecrets1Astral Academy (tutorial)10002Academy Hallways302023Wolvercote Catacombs201524Dragon Graveyard252025Crystal Caverns352526Crypt of the Damned252027Forsaken Dungeons302028Throne of the Lost King252029Fangle Forest3020210Shadowthorn Thicket2015211Ruins of the Perished3520212Heartland Mines3020213Bramblestoke Village3520214Iron Forge4025215Tower of Sarek10152PSN Delay  ControversyAlthough released for PC on July 2, 2009, the release for the PlayStation Network was delayed, likely in order to optimize it for the PS3 platform. In mid-July, a Frozenbyte employee posted on the game's official forums saying that the game would be released on July 30. However, on July 29 the same Frozenbyte employee wrote, "Unfortunately, Trine isn't coming to PSN this week, and this time it's our fault as there was discovered yet another small bug, which needed to be fixed."Some cited the release of Sony's Fat Princess, also scheduled for release on July 30, as the reason for the delay. They hypothesized that Sony must have forced Frozenbyte to push back the release of Trine, fearing low sales due to competition. However, that theory seemed less and less likely as more time passed without a Trine release.Trine was eventually released on PSN in Europe on September 17th 2009, and on October 22nd in North America. One of the advantages of buying the game on PSN was supposed to be that it would be $10 cheaper than the PC version, but the price of the PC version dropped $10 before the PSN release, leaving that advantage unrealized.Free DLC...and Hint of a SequelMore Trine to come?On April 19th 2010, Frozenbyte released a free DLC level for the PC titled "Path to New Dawn" (the level was later released on the PSN on August 3rd, 2010 for $0.99). The level becomes available upon completion of the game and features 10 unique items for players to collect.Upon completing the level, an image of a dragon appears on screen with a note reading "The story has just begun...". While this teased that this might not be the end of the Trine storyline, the sequel for the game, Trine 2, wasn't officially unveiled until E3 2010.SoundtrackTrine's Soundtrack Album ArtThe soundtrack for Trine was composed by Ari Pulkkinen. The main theme can be downloaded for free at the musician's website.Track No.Song TitleRunning Time01Astral Academy04.0402Academy Hallways04.1603Wolvercote Catacombs05.0404Dragon Graveyard04.0105Crystal Caverns04.3006Crypt of the Damned03.3807Forsaken Dungeons04.0708Throne of the Lost King04.3609Fangle Forest04.1910Shadowthorn Thicket04.1211Ruins of the Perished04.0812Ruins of the Perished II04.1513Heartland Mines04.3014Bramblestoke Village04.0015Iron Forge04.0316Tower of Sarek02.5417Trine Main Theme01.4418Trine Trailer Theme01.23PC System RequirementsMinimum system requirementsProcessor: 2.0 GHz CPUOperating System: Windows XP / Windows VistaSystem Memory: 512 MB (XP), 1 GB (Vista)Hard-Disk Space: 1 GBSound Card: (not required)Video Card: Radeon X800 or GeForce 6800 or betterRecommended system requirementsProcessor: Dual-Core CPU or betterOperating System: Windows XP / Windows VistaSystem Memory: 2 GBHard-Disk Space: 1 GBSound Card: DirectX compatible soundcard.Video Card: Radeon HD 3800 series or GeForce 8800 series or betterOther: Gamepad(s) for co-op playUseful LinksOfficial Website:http://trine-thegame.com/site/Official Forums:http://frozenbyte.com/board/viewforum.php?f=15Soundtrack:http://www.aripulkkinen.com/projects/project-trine/</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20716">Braid</game><game id="5429">The Lost Vikings</game><game id="4134">Norse by Norse West: The Return of the Lost Vikings</game><game id="20602">LittleBigPlanet</game><game id="20483">Bionic Commando Rearmed</game><game id="26706">Shadow Complex</game><game id="29426">Bob Came In Pieces</game><game id="30625">Rush'N Attack: Ex-Patriot</game><game id="30945">Bionic Commando Rearmed 2</game><game id="34034">Rochard</game><game id="35173">Tesla: The Weather Man</game><game id="36999">Pid</game><game id="38390">The Cave</game><game id="39254">Stained</game><game id="5269">Oddworld: Abe's Oddysee</game><game id="32314">Dustforce</game><game id="37756">A-Men</game><game id="39484">Giana Sisters: Twisted Dreams</game><game id="37971">Party of Sin</game><game id="40887">Towers of Oz</game><game id="2561">Prince of Persia</game><game id="30074">Blade Kitten</game><game id="44033">Giana Sisters: Twisted Dreams - Rise of the Owlverlord</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3699/1839753-trine.jpg</image></root>