<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24787</id><name>Fear &amp; Respect</name><description>BackgroundOn September 23, 2004, Midway announced the game Fear  Respect. It was described as being a third person action game taking place in South Central L.A. You would play the role of an  "O.G." (Original Gangster) of a gang, fighting rival gangs in the area, raising fear and earning respect.    Hollywood director John Singleton was involved in the project. He is best known for directing films such as Boyz N the Hood, The Fast and the Furious, and Baby Boy. Rapper Snoop Dogg was set to star as Goldie in the game, the playable main character.  GameplayThe game was to star Goldie (voiced by and modelled after Snoop Dogg), a 22 year old gang member. The game had a RESPECT system, where your interactions with other gangmembers,  your appearance and your actions would earn you "Respect" while at the same time making enemy gangmembers fear you.  The game would have had a large collection of real life weapons including pistols, rifles,and shotguns. Also, the game map was to be a realistic, accurate rendering of Los Angeles. The game would have been an open world freeroam experience. Film AdaptationThe very next day after the game was announced, Paramount Pictures announced it acquired the film rights to the game. This announcement came a month after Paramount announced a film based off the game Area 51, which would have starred Marylin Manson and David Duchovny. Both movies were never actually made.  Trailer and ScreentshotsIn February 2006, Midway released a set of 13 screenshots and a trailer for the game. This is the only media that was released for Fear  Respect.   The trailer takes place in South Central Los Angeles during a Summer heat wave.  Snoop Dogg's character Goldie is riding in a car, a fellow gangmember is in the backseat with a loaded gun. The Snoop Dogg song "Drop It Like It's Hot" begins to play on the radio. As the car drives down a street, rival gangmembers block the car by standing in front of it and begin firing their weapons. The car charges down the street and ends up crashing. Goldie and his fellow gangmember then get out of the car with their weapons ready. The trailer then shows a montage of actual gameplay footage.   CancelledOn March 1, 2006 the game was cancelled. Midway didn't give a particular reason for the cancellation, but it was most likely due to the crowded genre of  crime-themed open world games. According to Midway, they still want to work with Snoop Dogg and John Singleton.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4647/833633-jancov.jpg</image></root>