<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24783</id><name>Dragon Quest X: Mezameshi Itsutsu no Shuzoku Online</name><description>OverviewDragon Quest X: Mezameshi Itsutsu no Shuzoku Online (The Wake of the Five Tribes Online) was revealed by Square-Enix during a Dragon Quest conference on September 05, 2011.  The game is an MMORPG released for both the Wii and the Wii U.The Wii version of the game was released in Japan on the 2nd of August 2012 with a basic subscription fee of 1000 yen for 30 days. The Wii U version is expected in Japan in 2013.Features:3DS Streetpass would also be involvedIt can be played with a Wii Remote and Nunchuck, Classic ControllerUSB keyboard can be usedThe game uses a USB device of some kind for data management.Some cross platform play with Wii and Wii UPlotThe protagonists are a mischievous pair of orphaned human siblings in the small village of Etene. Etene is also the home of residents Shini, a calm and reliable boy, and his grandmother Aba, a feisty shrine maiden.After an initial portion of the game played as a human, the player character is reborn as a monster race. The player may choose from five races which their character will play the main part of the game as.RacesThe game has five playable tribes, each with a different continent in the world of Astordia.OgresOgres are tall, horned, red humanoids known for their strength and courage. They come from the continent of Ogreed (or Ogrelead). Ogreed has varied terrain types, including a snowy tundra-like area and an arid desert.PukuripoPukuripo are small, greenish, cheerful creatures with jester-like outfits. They come from Pukuland, a forested area with mountains, windmills, and a carnival-like atmosphere.WediWedi are blue, finned humanoids. They come from Wena Island, which is a coastal area with a wide variety of climates; cold blue lakes, resort-like beach villages, and leafy tropical forests can all be found here.ElvesElves are small, pink, large-eared humanoids who honor nature. Their homeland, Eltona (or Eldona), has a heavy Asian influence, with pagodas and cherry-blossom trees.DwarvesDwarves are small, dark-olive humanoids with prominent round ears who value craftmanship and wealth. They come from Dwachakka, a very mountainous area with thin vegetation.GameplayHousing systemEach of the five continents has an area where the player can buy a plot of land and build their own house with a House Kit. The interior layout is customizable, and furniture and crafting equipment can be set up inside.Artisan systemThe player can begin crafting items by registering at a guild (as a clothes specialist, weapon smith, etc.). Once the player has the required items, they can craft objects through a minigame.MultiplayerPlayers can communicate between preset phrases and gestures, or they can use free-text input with a USB keyboard.Players can invite others to join their party's with a preset message, whereupon both players will agree on a length of time that they'll play together.If players spot another group fighting, they can use a support command which causes the group's tension to rise.There are also AI characters which the player can recruit at a pub. They'll behave like the party members in Dragon Quest 9 and will use whichever tactics you set out for them. The player can also turn themselves into an AI character, so when they're offline someone else can recruit their AI controlled character. When the player comes back, they will retain the experience they earned as an AI.ClassesSwitching classes works a lot like Dragon Quest 9. The player goes to the Branch Office of Dharma's Shrine to switch classes. Some skills carry over between classes, others do not. The level of the player's previous job is retained in case they want to switch back.WarriorMonkMonks have low health and attack stats, but they're very adept with recover magic. They can use spears, clubs, and staffs.MageAlong with their natural magic ability, mages can wield the dual-handed staff, dagger, and whip.ThiefThieves wield daggers, claws, and whips. They also learn a few spells.Martial ArtistMinstrelPricing/Payment ModelIn Japan, the game has a monthly subscription fee of 1,000 Yen (about $12). However, to accommodate for the Dragon Quest series' younger audience, players will have two hours of free time every day. The free game time is only available during specific hours, namely 4 to 6 p.m. on weekdays and 1 to 3 p.m. on weekends.This was decided based on customer feedback during demo events. Players will be notified before their free game time ends and those without money in their account will have their game saved before the session gets terminated. Supposedly, these terms are subject to change and Square Enix emphasized that they intended the free time solely for younger children.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/82063/2321879-955322_115848_front.jpg</image></root>