<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24804</id><name>100 Classic Books</name><description>Introduction100 Classic Book Collection is a      Nintendo DS game that, as the title suggests, contains one hundred of the world's greatest literary works. All books contained in the game are their original versions, and footnotes are provided to help readers understand some of the language used that is no longer common today.  In an unusual move, 100 Classic Books is unrated in all regions.  Because the title is simply a literature compilation and not an actual game of any sort, Nintendo did not deem a content rating necessary and was not required to submit it to content ratings boards such as the ESRB, whose rating process is voluntary.Features100 Classic Book Collection provides a certain number of features that make the reading and selecting of books easier: All the books are displayed on a bookshelf in which you can scroll through to select the title you are interested in. Every book has a small summary and a little biography of the author.  In order to keep track of which books you have finished, a small "r" will appear on the spine of the book when you finish reading it. Two different font sizes. You can look up books either by scrolling through the bookshelf or by using the search feature that will let you type in the name of either the book or author. A special quiz mode will suggest titles to read depending on how you answered a short number of questions. Bookmarks that  you can lay down to save your place. You can use up to 3 different ones per book.   Wireless and Online Features  The game allows the player to download new books via    Nintendo WFC and to update the so-called rankings (completion rate of the percentage of the total books read by your friends). It is also possible the receive and send downloaded books via local Wi-Fi. The game also allows the player to send a demo version to someone who does not own the game.ControlsThe game can be entirely "played" using only the DS stylus, though the button set-up is fully customizable to fit your way of reading. In order to turn pages using the touch controls, you slide your stylus over the page, either to the right for the next page or to the left for the previous one. The menu is brought up by simply tapping the screen. Books available in the gameLouisa May AlcotLittle Women  Jane AustenEmma Mansfield Park Persuasion Pride and Prejudice Sense and Sensibility  Harriet Beecher StoweUncle Tom's Cabin   R.D. BlackmoreLorna Doone The Tenant of Wildfell Hall Jane Eyre The Professor Shirley Villette  Emily Bronte  Wuthering Heights  John Bunyan The Pilgrim's Progress  Frances Burnett  Little Lord Fauntleroy The Secret Garden  Lewis Carroll Alice's Adventures in Wonderland Through the Looking-Glass  Wilkie Collins The Moonstone The Woman in White  Carlo Collodi  Adventures of Pinocchio  Arthur Conan Doyle The Adventures of Sherlock Holmes The Casebook of Sherlock Holmes  Joseph Conrad  Lord Jim  Susan Coolidge What Katy Did  James Fenimore Cooper Last of the Mohicans  Daniel Defoe Robinson Crusoe  Charles Dickens Barnaby Rudge Bleak House A Christmas Carol David Copperfield Dombey and Son Great Expectations Hard Times Martin Chuzzlewit Nicholas Nickleby The Old Curiosity Shop Oliver Twist The Pickwick Papers A Tale of Two Cities  Alexandre Dumas The Count of Monte Cristo The Three Musketeers  George Eliot Adam Bede  Middlemarch The Mill on the Floss  Henry Rider Haggard King Solomon's Mines  Thomas Hardy Far From The Madding Crowd The Mayor of Casterbridge Tess of The D'Urbervilles Under the Greenwood Tree  Nathaniel Hawthorne The Scarlet Letter  Victor Hugo The Hunchback of Notre Dame Les Miserables  Washington Irving The Sketch Book of Geoffrey Crayon  Charles Kingsley Westward Ho!  D.H. Lawrence Sons And Lovers  Gaston Leroux The Phantom of the Opera  Jack LondonThe Call of the Wild  White Fang  Herman Melville Moby Dick  Edgar Allen Poe Tales of Mystery and Imagination  Sir Walter Scot Ivanhoe Rob Roy Waverley  Anna Sewell Black Beauty  William Shakespeare All's Well That Ends Well Antony and Cleopatra As You Like It The Comedy of Errors Hamlet Julius Caesar King Henry the Fifth King Lear King Richard the Third Love's Labour's Lost Macbeth The Merchant of Venice A Midsummer-Night's Dream Much Ado About Nothing Othello, the Moor of Venice Romeo and Juliet The Taming of the Shrew The Tempest Timon of Athens Titus Andronicus Twelfth Night The Winter's Tale Kidnapped  Robert Louis Stevenson The Strange Case of Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde Treasure Island  Jonathan Swift Gulliver's Travels  William Thackeray  Vanity Fair  Anthony Trollope Barchester Towers  Mark Twain Adventures of Huckleberry Finn Adventures of Tom Sawyer  Jules Verne Round the World in Eighty Days 20,000 Leagues Under the Sea  Oscar Wilde The Importance of Being Earnest The Picture of Dorian Gray </description><genres><genre id="8">Educational</genre><genre id="15">Compilation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26993">Story Hour: Adventures</game><game id="26994">Story Hour: Fairy Tales</game><game id="29757">Flips: Percy Jackson</game><game id="30172">Flips: Terror in Cubicle Four</game><game id="31102">Flips: Artemis Fowl</game><game id="31103">Flips: Cathy Cassidy</game><game id="31104">Flips: Enid Blyton - Faraway Tree Stories</game><game id="31105">Flips: Enid Blyton - The Adventure Series</game><game id="31106">Flips: Mr. Gum</game><game id="31107">Flips: Too Ghoul for School</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/27239/1317467-500x_100_classic_books.jpg</image></root>