<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24858</id><name>Darkest of Days</name><description>OverviewIn Darkest of Days, the player controls Alexander Morris, a soldier fighting in General Custer's army during the Battle of Little Big Horn (also known as Custer's Last Stand) a the beginning of the game. After General Custer is killed and Morris is wounded in battle, suddenly, a man in futuristic armor appears and takes Morris through a strange portal. Morris then awakens in the headquarters of KronoteK, an organization that has managed to develop time travel technology, the same technology that brought you to the future, that they have been developing and researching to protect key people in history.A KronoteK higher-up know only as "Mother" tells Morris that the organization's founder has gone missing and disturbances have started appearing through history, causing individuals that have played key roles in history to be placed in danger. "Mother" then tasks Morris with helping KronoteK to restore history.GameplayThe game includes over 20 weapons both from the original time period of each battle and from the future. The game also contains vehicles although it is not clear in what capacity the player will interact with them.They never were good at taking coverBattles are large-scale. The engine was designed with the capability to handle 300 enemies in a single battle. Each battle can be fought from either side of the conflict.The goal of the game is not necessarily to kill everyone you see but to preserve soldiers marked with a blue aura. These soldiers are those who survived the battle and must not be killed to avoid creating a paradox.If it happens that you kill a character that you were supposed to save, the world freezes and enemy agents come out of portals to kill you.After you manage to fight off their attack, the world will un-freeze again and you will be able to try rescuing the highlighted person again. Since searching for the one chosen person on a huge battlefield would be an immense pain on your own, the developers provide the main character with a device called "seekers".These are tiny spheres that would not only find the chosen person for you, but even shock them and carry them back to you. The problem is that you only have a limited amount of seekers and they can also get shot down.Since having such a huge amount of troops on the field at the same time could risk having them making lots of stupid mistakes, their AI was customized to work in units of 5 people. They will be working with each other, and if the situation gets very bad (AKA everyone in their unit dies), they will probably flee from the battle.PC System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Windows XP SP2/VistaCPU: Intel 2.0 GhzRAM: 768 MBHDD: 5 GB free disk spaceGraphics: 128 MB Graphics CardSound Card: DirectX 9 CompatibleDirectX: Version 9.0cRecommended:OS: Windows XP SP 2/VistaCPU: Intel dual core 2.0 GhzRAM: 2 GBHDD: 5 GB free disk spaceGraphics: 256 MB Graphics CardSound Card: DirectX 9 CompatibleDirectX: Version 9.0cSupported Graphics Cards:Minimum:nVIDIA® GeForce™ 6600 or ATI Radeon® 9800Recommended:nVIDIA® GeForce™ 8800 or newer/ATI Radeon® 3000Macintosh PortOn December 06, 2010, Virtual Programming ported this title to the Macintosh PlatformMacintosh Platform Hardware Requirements:Mac OS 10.6.5 or higherIntel CPU, 2.16 GHz or faster1 GB RAMGeForce 8600, Radeon X1600 or newer, 128 MB5 GB Hard Disk spaceInternet connection for product registrationMovieIn February 2010 it was reported that the screenwriters Douglas Cook and David Weisberg, who's previous work includes The Rock and Double Jeopardy, were attached to write a screenplay based off the game. Creative Artist Agency (CAA), one of the most prominent entertainment agencies in Hollywood, is engaged in efforts to sell the project to a major studio.</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14229">The History Channel: Civil War - Great Battles</game><game id="3522">Civil War: A Nation Divided</game><game id="6626">Robert E. Lee: Civil War General</game><game id="10000">Civil War</game><game id="2566">The Civil War</game><game id="16897">1914: The Great War</game><game id="4240">WWI: The Great War</game><game id="11257">Gods and Generals</game><game id="12098">Turning Point: Fall of Liberty</game><game id="17246">TimeSplitters 2</game><game id="12621">TimeSplitters</game><game id="6338">TimeShift</game><game id="25887">History Channel: Civil War - Secret Missions</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1836580-box_dod.png</image></root>