<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24871</id><name>Fieldrunners</name><description>OverviewFieldrunners is a simple tower defense game. Starting a game allows you to select mode, difficulty(easy, medium, hard), and map. The three modes are classic, extended, and endless, classic uses only 4 towers and will end after 100 rounds. Both extended and endless allow use of 6 towers. The only difference between them is that extended ends after 100 rounds. There are currently five maps available. It is good to know that on Crosslands, enemies always go toward the opposite exit from where they entered, so place your towers and make a path accordingly. Land units will always follow the shortest path to their exit which allows Juggling. Air units will fly straight across all defenses to the exit, so it is important to place a lot of heavier damage turrets closer to the middle of the map.Fieldrunners was initially released for the iPhone, but overtime additional platforms came available.TowersEach tower can be upgraded twice for increased damage and range. All towers can attack both land and air units.Gatling Tower - Continuous attack, short range. (Cost: $5, Upgrade: $4, Sell: $3*level)Goo Tower - Slows enemies, medium range. (Cost: $10, Upgrade: $5, Sell: $3 $4*level)Missile Tower - Splash damage, long range. (Cost: $20, Upgrade: $15, Sell: $4 $11*level)Ice Tower - Slows enemies, replaces Goo Tower in Frostbite, short range. (Cost: $20, Upgrade: $15, Sell: $4 $11*level)Laser Tower - Damages all enemies in a straight line, replaces Tesla Tower in Skyway. (Cost: $40, Upgrade: $30, Sell: $23 $67*level)Flame Tower - Area of effect damage, short range. (Cost: $50, Upgrade: $40, Sell: $7 $30*level)Tesla Tower - Massive damage, medium range. (Cost: $70, Upgrade: $50, Sell: $14 $38*level)Mortar Tower - Massive splash damage, exclusively long range. (Cost: $120, Upgrade: $90, Sell: $23 $67*level)MapsThe "Availability" column only refers to the iPhone release of Fieldrunners; all maps are included in the PSP and DSiWare releases.NameEntrancesExitsObstaclesAvailabilityGrasslands11NoIncludedCrossroads22NoIncluded (Unlockable)Drylands33NoIncluded (Unlockable)Skyway11YesIn-game purchaseFrostbite22YesIn-game purchasePC System RequirementsOS: Microsoft Windows XP or laterProcessor: 1.6 GHz ProcessorMemory: 512 MB RAMHard Disk Space: 285MB Free Hard Drive SpaceVideo Card: hardware and driver support for OpenGL 3.0DirectX®: 9.0cMac System RequirementsOS: OS X version Snow Leopard 10.6.3, or later.Processor: Mac IntelMemory: 512 MB RAMHard Disk Space: 285MB Free Hard Drive SpaceVideo Card: hardware and driver support for OpenGL 3.0</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="27091">geoDefense</game><game id="29428">PixelJunk Monsters Deluxe</game><game id="23102">South Park Let's Go Tower Defense Play!</game><game id="29551">Savage Moon: The Hera Campaign</game><game id="35786">Tower Defense: Lost Earth</game><game id="35878">Army of Darkness Defense</game><game id="42643">TUG</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3699/2299543-fieldrunners.jpg</image></root>