<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24920</id><name>Guitar Hero On Tour: Modern Hits</name><description>IntroductionThe third installment of the Guitar Hero franchise on the DS, Guitar Hero On Tour: Modern Hits builds on predecessors  Guitar Hero: On Tour and  Guitar Hero On Tour: Decades.  Setlist Guitar Hero on Tour: Modern Hits will feature a total of 28 songs (comprised from new tracks  songs from Guitar Hero III's setlist  DLC). As With  Guitar Hero: On Tour Decades the setlist was localized for the US, UK  the EU with each having 9 exclusive tracks to that reagion (the EU version shares 6 of the exlusive track with the UK version with having 3 tracks that are not avalible in the UK or the US Version as thses are forein language songs). the set lsit is as follow (with exclusive tracks notes where needed):  "Adrenaline" By 12 Stone (US Exclusive)  "All My Life" By Foo Fighters **"Always Where I Need  To Be" By The Kooks  "The Bitter End" By Placebo (EU/UK Exclusive)  "Bohemian Like You" By The Dance Wahols (EU/UK Exclusive)   "Call To Arms"  By Angels  Airwaves (US/UK Exclusive)    "Chelsea Dagger" By The Fratellies  "DashBoard" By Modest Mouse (US Exclusive)    "Do The Panic" By Phantom Planet (US/UK Exclusive) "Everybody Get Dangerous"    By Weezer  "The Fallen" By Franz Ferdinand "Falling Down" By Atreyu  (US/UK Exclusive) "Golden Skans" BY The Klaxons  (EU/UK Exclusive) " I Wanna Be Your Man" By Endeverafter (EU Exclusice)"In The Shadows" By The Rasmus  (EU/UK Exclusive)*" Lassoo" By The Duke Spirt  (US/UK Exclusive) "Lights And Sounds" By Yellowcard  (US Exclusive) "The Metal" By Tenacious D ****"Miss Murder" By AFI ****" Napoleon Says" By Pheonix  (EU Exclusive)  "On Call" By KIngs Of Leon  (EU/UK Exclusive)  "Our Velocity" By Maxïmo Park (EU/UK Exclusive) "Paralizer" By Finger Eleven  (US Exclusive) "Que No" By Deluxe (EU Exclusive)  "Reptilia" The Stokes ****"Ruby" By The Kaiser Chiefs **** "Scream Aim Fire" By Bullet For My Valentine  (EU/UK Exclusive)*** "Shockwave" By Black Tide (EU/UK Exclusive) "Still Waiting" By Sum 41 "Sweet Sacrifice" By Evanescence "This Ain't A Scene, It's An Arms Race" By Fall Out Boy "Unconditinal" By The Bravery (US Exclusive)  "Via Le Mani Dagli Occhi" By Negamaro (EU/UK Exclusive) "Violet Hill" By Coldplay "What Do I Have To Do" By The Donnas  (US Exclusive) "When You're Gone" By Avril Lavigne (EU/UK Exclusive) "Are We Runnin'?" By Lenny Kravitz    * appears as DLC For  Guitar Hero World Tour ** appears as DLC For  Guitar Hero III *** appears in the setlist of  Guitar Hero World Tour **** Appears in the set lsti for  Guitar Hero III Game Modes Single Player:The Single Player mode is broken into the Career mode and a Quickplay mode. The Quickplay mode has all the songs unlocked from the get go. Where as in the Career mode, you rock your way through different concerts in pursuit of more fame and a larger fan base. In addition to  the normal "beat the song, move forward" kind of gameplay, you need to finish challanges or "Fan Requests" in order to get more fans. You can only unlock new concerts if you have a specific set of "Fans". The requests could be anything from beat the song using a base guitar, to getting a set amount of star powers in a song.   There is also a Training mode with several tutorials, and a practice mode where you can play any section of a song without losing playing as either a lead guitarist or with a base guitar.    Multiplayer: You can either host or join a two player game where you can play a Face-Off, Pro Face-off or a Co-op match.   Guitar Hero World TourThe menu theme song Called "S.U.P.R.A.H.U.M.A.N. "  for Guitar Hero: On Tour Modern Hits was featured as free DLC for  Guitar Hero World Tour,  Guitar Hero 5 and  Band Hero.</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21102">Guitar Hero On Tour: Decades</game><game id="25421">Rock Band Unplugged</game><game id="31764">DJ Hero 3D</game><game id="38479">Jam Sessions 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2491504-box_ghotmh.png</image></root>