<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24969</id><name>Tokobot Plus: Mysteries of the Karakuri</name><description>OverviewBolt is an apprentice Treasure Master working at Mr. Canewood's laboratory. With the help of mysterious Tokobots, he will explore many prehistoric ruins to find ancient relics that will put him one step further on his path to be a Treasure Master and find his father. However, he will also change his destiny in other ways.Tokobot FormationsWith the press of a button, Bolt can put his collection of Tokobots into special formations. Each has its uses both within combat and for platforming purposes.U formation: This formation puts Tokobots on both sides of Bolt, four to his left and four to his right.Circle formation: All eight Tokobots surround Bolt.V formation: The Tokobots line up directly behind Bolt and follow in a vertical line.CharactersBoltA young boy who dreams of becoming a Treasure Master. His father is a legendary Treasure Master, but was always off exploring ruins and never got to spend any time with his son. With the Tokobots and his childhood friend Ruby, Bolt plans to become a Treasure Master and reunite with his father. He is voiced by Christina Pucelli.The TokobotsNot much is first known about these strange robots Bolt accidentally discovers within a prehistoric ruin. They are quirky and seem to share a hive mindset, forming ladders and attacking all at once to defeat a specific enemy. Bolt came up with their namesake based on their small, adorable appearance.Mr. CanewoodMinister of the kingdom, as well as the man (robot?) responsible for bringing Bolt and the Tokobots together. He created Canewood's Lab to research ancient civilization from the clues found in ruins. He is both very knowledgeable and absentminded, making it difficult to determine how serious he is about his life's work. He is voiced by Barry Dennen.RubyBolt's childhood friend and the communications operator at Canewood's Lab. Via a transceiver, Ruby is able to give Bolt advice and updates when he's exploring ruins. Can be a bit spacey. She is voiced by Kari Wahlgren.Dr. ViolaChief of the Analysis Room in Canewood's Lab, which is the place to go for upgrades to the Tokobots. She can also appraise unknown items Bolt finds in the ruins and exchange them for rewards. She is voiced by Tara Platt.FuelUsed to be a commander in the army, but is now an instructor at Canewood's Lab for young Treasure Masters. Gives out mission advice for Bolt. He is voiced by Michael Benyaer.FlamesBartTajiA young boy who is hostile to Bolt.</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2405">Pikmin</game><game id="2480">Pikmin 2</game><game id="11667">Ape Escape 2</game><game id="19388">Ape Escape 3</game><game id="4618">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Going Commando</game><game id="18309">Ratchet &amp; Clank</game><game id="4966">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Up Your Arsenal</game><game id="14623">Jak and Daxter: The Precursor Legacy</game><game id="11470">Scaler</game><game id="11407">Vexx</game><game id="13169">Ty the Tasmanian Tiger</game><game id="19188">Ty the Tasmanian Tiger 3: Night of the Quinkan</game><game id="159">Ty the Tasmanian Tiger 2: Bush Rescue</game><game id="18926">Malice</game><game id="12209">Spyro: A Hero's Tail</game><game id="8420">Spyro: Enter the Dragonfly</game><game id="20908">The Legend of Spyro: Dawn of the Dragon</game><game id="6134">The Legend of Spyro: The Eternal Night</game><game id="3883">The Legend of Spyro: A New Beginning</game><game id="5235">Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time</game><game id="25720">Jak and Daxter: The Lost Frontier</game><game id="22042">Tokobot</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2367526-box_tokobotp.png</image></root>