<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24962</id><name>Full Throttle: Payback</name><description>Full Throttle 2: Payback would have been the official sequel to the original game, the story would have continued where the original left of. Tim Schafer had already left LucasArts when the game got into the development stage, this lead to Larry Ahern becoming the project lead and William Tiller to become the art director.The game development went well for a long time, about 25% of the levels where completed and 40% of the preproduction was done and just started on 3D models when things started to look dark. According to Tiller disagreements started to arise over the game style the game had between the productive team and a very influential person within the management. This "Mucky muck" as he called him, had read the game design and said that he did not like it. When Tiller asked for more precise criticism the person answer that the he didn't think that the Cave Fish Gang (or the Cone Fish as the person called them) belonged in the Full Throttle universe.PlotThe story/plot of the game would close resemble the story of the first game. it would revolve around a large corporation making a deal with the local governor to replace the asphalt roads into hover roads so that they could sell all the hover vans and family oriented cars that would be "faster and safer". The biker community did not like how things were starting to change and had started a rebellion against the company, but this did not sit well with the governor who hired the Rotwheelers to assassinate the Father Torque who was the leader of rebellion. Ben is however in hiding from the media who has not given him a break after he was acquitted of Ripburger's murder.The first part of the game would revolve around Ben trying to stop the assassination of Father Torque, and in the second half he would be joined with a persistent undercover female reporter to bring down the government.LocationsThe game would also feature now locations that the players would visit:Abandoned Power PlantRuined Freeway under constructionA damA trainGated communityThe territorial capitalThe capitol buildingA RefineryPolice StationNew motel/barThe Cave Fish colonyGrave yard</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13230">Grim Fandango</game><game id="5729">The Curse of Monkey Island</game><game id="3019">The Secret of Monkey Island</game><game id="6728">Zak McKracken and the Alien Mindbenders</game><game id="4372">Maniac Mansion: Day of the Tentacle</game><game id="11852">Sam &amp; Max Hit the Road</game><game id="6049">Sam &amp; Max Save the World</game><game id="14748">Indiana Jones and The Last Crusade: The Graphic Adventure</game><game id="21174">Full Throttle</game><game id="23322">Full Throttle: Hell on Wheels</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8884/848022-full20040719111312.jpg</image></root>