<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25065</id><name>Mini Ninjas</name><description>Story For over 300 years the empire has been at peace, this was due to the banishment of the Evil Samurai Warlord, the structures that were built under his time were now left abandoned and was slowly turning into ruins. But one day this all changed. Storms and natural disasters not seen for many hundred years started to become a frequent sight. The Ninja Master who resided at the Ninja Mountain could feel that something evil had awakened. The Evil Samurai Warlord had once again awakened and was using his forbidden Kuji magic to transform innocent animals into mindless samurai warriors so that he can take over the world. The larger his army was the more violent the storms are. The Ninja Master did not know what was causing all of this but he had a feeling that it was something evil. He sent his best ninja to scout and discover the truth behind the growing storms but the ninja never returned, growing ever so worried Ninja Master sent out another ninja who also never returned. Soon only two ninjas remained, Futo and Hiro. Gameplay Mini Ninja is a third-person action/adventure game that is aimed to a maybe more younger audience then you would think when you hear the word Ninja. You will not find any blood or gore in this game, instead you when you defeat your foes they will turn back to animals (because that’s what they are created from). Throughout the game the players will be tasked to save their ninja friends, once a player has acquired a new character they can switch between characters at will. Other than just having this feature in the game without any context players will actually be using this if they want to get the most out of the game, some enemies will be taken down faster with a specific character. Each of the character that are available for the players have their own Primary Attack, Block Breaker Attack (Stun Block), and a Power Attack, The Power attack is what differentiates the characters the most and these attacks will use up Unstable Ki energy that players can find throughout the world and when defeating enemies. Through the game players will have to locate Ki Shrines for new spells/powers to be unlocked, if a player misses out on a shrine on a level then that power will no longer be available for the player (unless the level is replayed). There are also more ninja like stuff that can be done in the game, players will be able to hide in bushes, run up walls and run across wires. They do however have special Ninja power, and this is to take control of a nearby animal. Each animal also has a special “power”, some animals can take more damage, some run faster and some will help you locate items you can pick up. These items can then be mixed to make potions, smoke bombs or other helpful items. Characters Hiro -   The main character of the game, his weapon of choice is a Katana. He is the only playable character that can use the Kuji magic. Futo – Hiro’s best friend who has a hammer as a weapon. Futo is a heavy hitter in the game whose attack might be slow but powerful.Suzume – Female ninja whose weapon of choice is a flute, the flute can be used both in close combat and long rage when used as a blowgun.Tora – Fast and nimble that can attack at the speed of light, but he’s weak against the spearmen.Kunoichi – The ninja who is specialized with the spear.Shun – The archer who likes to stay out of harm’s way.System Requirements Minimum:OS: Windows XP and VistaProcessor: PIV/Athlon 3.2ghz or higher processorMemory: 512MB system RAM (1GB Vista)Graphics: ATI Radeon X1300 or higher / Nvidia Geforce 6600 or higher (shader model 3 required) graphics cardHard Drive: 5.85GB free spaceSound: DirectX 9 compatible sound cardRecommended:OS: Windows XP and VistaProcessor: Intel/Athlon Dual Core ProcessorMemory: 1024MB system RAM (2GB Vista)Graphics: ATI Radeon X1300 or higher / Nvidia Geforce 6600 or higher with 512MB video RAM (shader model 3 required)Hard Drive: 5.85GB free spaceSound: DirectX 9 compatible sound card    </description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9533">Kung Fu Chaos</game><game id="1605">I-Ninja</game><game id="1391">Rag Doll Kung Fu</game><game id="20640">Kung Fu Panda</game><game id="22801">Ninjatown</game><game id="21220">Battlefield Heroes</game><game id="18162">Team Fortress 2</game><game id="20602">LittleBigPlanet</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3699/1790552-mini_ninjas_cover.jpg</image></root>