<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25078</id><name>Super Robot Wars K</name><description>Overview Super Robot Wars K is the third SRW for the DS and is the sequel to   Super Robot Wars W. Like most SRWs, it doesn't radically change the traditional SRPG gameplay, but introduces the Partner Battle System, which attempts to bring the Squad System of the console entries to handhelds.  Almost all of W's cast list is discarded; only a handful of units from Gundam SEED use animations from previous SRW. The roster largely consists of newer series; in fact, only Mazinger Z and Dangaioh predate the year 2000. Godannar makes its SRPG debut in this game (it previously appeared in Super Robot Wars Scramble Commander the 2nd), and the Zoids franchise makes its first appearance with Zoids Genesis.  Virtual On Marz's Dramatic Mode is incorporated into the game's story, making it the first video game to have plot relevance in a traditional Super Robot Wars game.Featured Series A list of the series which are featured in the game. Series that debuted in the SRW franchise in this game are marked with "(new)".Mobile Suit Gundam SEED Mobile Suit Gundam SEED Destiny Mobile Suit Gundam SEED C.E. 73: Stargazer  (new) Mazinger Z Haja-Taisei Dangaioh  Overman King Gainer         Cyber Troopers Virtual On: MARZ Shinkon Gattai Godannar!! (debut into traditional SRW) Shinkon Gattai Godannar!! Second Season (debut into traditional SRW)  Fafner of the Azure  (new) Zoids Genesis  (new) Gun X Sword  (new) Gaiking: Legend of Daikuu Maryuu  (new) Steel God Jeeg  (new)  New FeaturesPartner System. Somewhat similar to the Twin Battle system of         Original Generations, a single unit can represent either a solo robot (as usual) or a team of robots, with one being the leader and the other being the support. The support robot can take hits for the leader, as well as provide a Support Attack. However, unlike the PS2 games, the team leader determines all of the team's movement qualities (if the support robot is incompatible with the terrain, it cannot support).Attack Combo System. Multi-target combos can now target any enemies in it range, as opposed to Super Robot Wars         D's and         J's method (targeting in a straight line) and Super Robot Wars         W's method (targeting any enemies that are adjacent to each other). Only robots without support can use Combos.  Music PlagiarismUpon Super Robot Wars K's release, it was discovered that some music was more or less lifted from past games unrelated to Super Robot Wars: namely, the BGM commonly played after enemy reinforcements is "The One Who Will Save the Earth" from        Lufia II and the final stage BGM is "Battle with Magus" from       Chrono Trigger.     Namco Bandai issued a public apology regarding the issue and mentioned that a settlement had been reached with      Square Enix (implying that legal action was taken by the latter).</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21244">Super Robot Wars W</game><game id="27921">Mage Knight: Destiny's Soldier</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14945/869140-srwkbox.jpg</image></root>