<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25127</id><name>Space Invaders Extreme 2</name><description>Overview Space Invaders Extreme 2 is       Taito's second game in the series set to re-imagine the      iconic arcade franchise. Sporting a new soundtrack as well as new Fever Time minigames, among other features, the game largely makes incremental upgrades and changes upon the formula set out by its predecessor. The game features a number of modes in which to partake, including online multiplayer modes that take advantage of    Nintendo Wi-Fi Connection. Gameplay The core gameplay remains unchanged: you, as a lone ship, are tasked with defeating multiple waves of incoming invaders to earn points. Unlike the original arcade game, however, there's no cover to hide behind. It's just you and the invaders.  The invaders are always lined in columns and get slowly closer to you  with each time they reach the sides of the screen. As you progress, new types of invaders are introduced. Some possess special abilities such as shields that reflect or absorb shots, and vary in size.   Power-Ups A returning feature from the first Space Invaders Extreme are power-ups, which are obtained by defeating a certain number of enemies of the same color. The types of power-ups available are:   a large blue laser that destroys multiple columns of enemiesan upgraded version of the standard cannon that has a wider reach explosive shots that eliminate all enemies with in the blast radius, and a shield that protects you from enemy shots for a limited time.</description><genres><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="24378">Big Bang Mini</game><game id="5057">Lumines: Puzzle Fusion</game><game id="32607">Pac-Man Championship Edition DX</game><game id="33617">Crossfire 2</game><game id="22414">Atari Classics Evolved</game><game id="10958">Activision Hits Remixed</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5911/1099408-space.jpg</image></root>