<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25130</id><name>Dystopia</name><description>Dystopia was released on Steam in February 2009. The game places the player into tense team combat situations in a high tech world spanned by computer networks. As either Punk Mercenaries or Corporate Security Forces the player will fight through the physical world to gain access, via jack-in terminals, to cyberspace in aim to complete certain objectives specified by the map.Gameplay Meatspace and CyberspaceCyberspace is a three dimensional representation of the world's network. Inside cyberspace players will launch programs to hack into systems linked to the physical world (known as meat space) while fighting off enemy hackers and defending critical systems. Gameplay progresses through inter-linked physical and cyberspace objectives, some are completed in either the physical world or cyberspace, others only by a well timed combination of the two.Player LoadoutsThis quick firing gun is the side arm of all players.A variety of different player loadouts are available to choose from before the player spawns. Different choices of class type, weapon and augmentations can lead to different play styles ranging from a quick and stealthy killer to a heavy damage machine or somewhere in the middle depending on player preference.Setups range from a 3 different class types ranging from Light to Heavy each having their own different types of weapons plus pros and limitations ranging from augmentation capacity, speed to the amount of hits they can take.The weapons in Dystopia are fairly distinct from one another and each have their own different alt fire mode. Weapons can range from a futuristic assault rifle, to a cyberpunk'd katana, a guided missile launcher to even a robotic spider which acts like a grenade for the heavy loadout.Augmentations which are powered by an energy meter are also selectable choices when you spawn. Augmentations can range from stealth camouflage, thermal vision, the ability to heal others and even jumping higher to reach alternative map paths.Art DirectionNote the use of colours in both players and map.Dystopia hosts a cyberpunk art direction with every map taking place at night time with contrasting light sources such as neon lights or reactors giving an art style akin to the cyberpunk genre. Some maps take place in cold corporate futuristic office spaces with intervals of roof top areas in which more of the mass cityscape can be seen. Other maps take place in secluded facilities out of the city sometimes in factory outskirts or even a huge cavernous area but still retain a futuristic theme with complicated looking machinery and wiring running throughout. The player models have a futuristic feel and the red and blue team colours are intergrated within their own combat armour aiding in the gameplay but keeping art integrity. Sound is used effectively with static noises and beeps matching the electronic warfare of EMP Grenades and battles fought in cyberspace. The game also includes a playlist but by default uses Cyberpunk themed electronic music throughout the gameplay which creates atmosphere.Overall the art style in both visual and sound creates an oppressive environment which suits the dystopian attitude of the Corp team but also justified the undercover nature of the Punk mercenary team.</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1539">Half-Life 2</game><game id="25345">Eternal Silence</game><game id="13948">System Shock</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/904/869866-dys.jpg</image></root>