<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25144</id><name>GameCenter CX: Arino no Chousenjou 2</name><description>OverviewGame Center CX: Arino no Chousenjou 2 is the sequel to Retro Game Challenge. Similarly to Retro Game Challenge it is based around the Japanese television show Game Centre CX, and features games based on games released on the NES. Unlike the original it features games based on SNES, Game Boy, Game Boy Color, Game  Watch and the MSX.Some are sequels or remakes of games in the Original Retro Game Challenge, while others are new IP's. It received a Japanese release on the 26th of February 2009. Releases in western territories have yet to be confirmed.GamesGame Center CX 2 features 9 games through the main campaign.Wiz-ManWiz-Man is similar to Pac-Man, in which you control a man around a maze who must collect pellets. In a twist to the classic Pac-Man formula, there are separate coloured pellets, and Whiz-Man can only collect one colour at a time. He can change the colour he is able to collect by collecting the wand of that colour.Demon ReturnsDemon Returns is a platforming game similar to Super Mario Bros with influences from other NES platformers. It also features a new gameplay mechanic, the ability to knock enemies upside down, and then ride on top of them onto other enemiesMutekiken Kung FuMutekiken Kung Fu is a side scrolling beat-em-up similar to Double Dragon. It also features a two player Vs. mode.Detective Kacho Part 1This is a text adventure with graphical aids in which you play as a detecive investigating crimes. It is based on Famicom Detective Club, a game only released in japan for the Famicom Disk System.Detective Kancho Part 2A sequel to Detective Kancho Part 1. It continues the storyline, and features the same style gameplay.Guadia Quest SagaGuadia Quest Saga is a sequel to Guadia Quest, which was in the original Game Center CX. It is designed to be a "Game Computer Mini Colour" game, the Game Center CX universes version of the Game Boy Color. It takes the core formula of Guadia Quest, but adds new features, such as a leveling system and the ability to control multiple Guadias (Creatures that can join with the player).GunDuelA top down sci-fi shooter which features the option for two players to play at once.Super Demon ReturnsThe sequel to Demon Returns. It is presented as an SNES game, whereas the original was an NESgame.TriotosToritos is a puzzle game for the Game Boy, featuring aspects from Tetris and Puyo Puyo.Rare GamesSimilar to the TV show Game Center CX, the player can visit a shopping district and buy additional games to play. These games, referred to as "Rare Games" are often remakes or enhanced versions of games from the original Retro Game Challenge.Cosmic Gate (MASA-X Version)A version of Cosmic gate (which featured in the original Retro Game Chalenge) for an MSX like system, called the MASA-X.Rally King ExA version of Rally King featuring a time trial mode.Star Prince SA (Score Attack Version)A version of Star Prince SA in which the players goal is to score the maximum number of points in 3 or 5 minutesof play.Ninja Super Robot Haggleman: Koume VersionThis is Ninja Super Robot Haggleman, but you control a female ninja known as Koume.Triotos DXAn SNES version of Triotos, featuring extra gameplay elements over the original.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="30174">G.G Series Collection Plus</game><game id="10555">Retro Atari Classics</game><game id="15915">Konami Classics Series: Arcade Hits</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/97089/2196547-b.png</image></root>