<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25152</id><name>Blue Dragon: Awakened Shadow</name><description>OverviewThe events of Blue Dragon: Awakened Shadow takes place two years after the original  Blue Dragon game. You create the main character and can customize their gender, appearance, voice, emblem and name. The main character awakens in the same ancient ruins as the two main antagonists, Jyun and Ganda, who bear a resemblance to the previous games' antagonist  Nene.  With no memory of how he/she got there or of their past, the main character leaves the ruins and begins their adventure.The game features a 3D overhead world with a rotatable camera fixed in eight directions. There are occasional FMV sequences as well as voice acting but the majority of dialogue is text. There is a crafting system where you combine different objects to make new items or make existing items more powerful.Beyond changing the appearance of the main character during creation, armor and weapons also change his/her appearance. The emblem you create has no bonus effects but other emblems can be earned which change your stats and other effects.The main character and party members do not level up but the shadows they wield do, gaining stat increases and new powers.  There is multiplayer when you and up to two friends can join together to face more difficult bosses in the cube world. Combat Combat is much different than in either  Blue Dragon or  Blue Dragon Plus and is real-time action based.  The player has a basic attack, charge-up skills and can block or roll for defense. You can have up to two other party members but have no control over their actions. The combat utilizes positioning and encourages flanking your opponents for extra damage.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23977">Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles: Echoes of Time</game><game id="22015">Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles: Ring of Fates</game><game id="9471">Children of Mana</game><game id="21633">Soma Bringer</game><game id="21448">Kingdom Hearts 358/2 Days</game><game id="24232">Ragnarok DS</game><game id="23777">Phantasy Star Zero</game><game id="22044">From the Abyss</game><game id="24225">Destiny Links</game><game id="27199">Rune Factory 3: A Fantasy Harvest Moon</game><game id="20615">Summon Night: Twin Age</game><game id="29232">Lufia: Curse of the Sinistrals</game><game id="27893">Cross Treasures</game><game id="31644">Kingdom Hearts Re:coded</game><game id="35479">Heroes of Ruin</game><game id="24354">Magician’s Quest: Mysterious Times</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1875180-box_bdas.png</image></root>