<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25161</id><name>Spore Galactic Adventures</name><description>OverviewNew, player-made missions.Spore Galactic Adventure is an expansion pack for the game Spore. It is a major new upgrade to the Space Phase (Space Phase is the only phase affected by the expansion), and instead of receiving pre-made missions from the AI Empires scattered throughout the Galaxy, you can make up missions to play in game (With unprecedented amount of customization) for yourself and other players. There are two modes you can access your missions: Ingame, in the Space Phase (By selecting a star with a special "flag" icon over it), or you can go to the Sporepedia and surf other player's custom missions. You can also rate and comment on missions created by other players.Missions are rated by 3 icons, a smiley face, a bar, and a "total times played" counter. The smiley face is how well rated the adventure is, the bar (with a 1-5 measurement on it) rates the difficulty (It sees the difficulty by how many times a player dies on a mission), and the "total times played" counter really needs no formal presentation. It just counts how many people played.The editor is a shining example of how something simple can create something complicated there are many ways to create a mission, you can include ANY sort of creation in the Sporepedia and make it part of an adventure. All sorts of adventures can be created, from Destruction, Puzzle, Guard, Templates, to even Story. Anything can be created and edited.System RequirementsSupported OS: Microsoft Windows XP Service Pack 2   Windows Vista Service Pack 1  Processor: 2.0 GHz P4 Processor or equivalent  Memory: (XP) 512MB (Vista) 768 MB  Graphics: 128MB Video Card with support for Pixel Shader  2.0  Hard Drive: At least 2GB of hard disk space without  creations  DirectX9®: DirectX 9.0c  For computers using built-in graphics chipsets under Windows,the game  requires at least: Intel Integrated Chipset, 945GM or above  2.6 GHz Pentium D CPU, or 1.8 GHz Core 2 Duo, or equivalent  768 MB RAM </description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23985">WarioWare D.I.Y.</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4938/922183-339463ps_500h.jpg</image></root>