<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2520</id><name>Donkey Konga</name><description>OverviewDonkey Konga BongosDonkey Konga by   Namco is the first in the Donkey Konga trilogy. The game includes the Donkey Konga Bongos, which consist of two small plastic bongo drums that sense when they are hit, when the player claps, or when the player makes any other high-pitched noise. Hit these Bongos and clap in time with the scrolling colors on screen to receive points.GameplayDonkey Konga consists of modes: Street Performance, Mini-games and Multiplayer.Street Performance    The main mode in Donkey Konga, Street Performance allows players to choose any song they like and then rewards them with in-game coins should they perform the song accurately. The in-game interface consists of a horizontal bar on which colored notes scroll from right to left. When the notes reach the target on the far left side of the bar the player must respond with the corresponding action: Red = Right Bongo | Yellow = Left Bongo | Pink = Both Bongos | Star = Clap.The player receives a higher accuracy rating depending on where the note is in the target when they hit the bongo, the ratings pop up on screen after each note as hit, they are things such as "Great!" or "Bad!" etc. Players can also gain a note streak should they go for long without missing any notes.There are three difficulty's in Donkey Konga: Monkey (easy), Chimp (medium) and Gorilla (hard). These difficulty's offer a variety of challenges (Gorilla especially) where the player will be confronted by long strings of notes and erratic changes in timing. The harder the difficulty, the more coins the player will be rewarded with, so that they can unlock new songs and mini-games.Mini-games    Mini-games are unlocked after being bought in DK town (the games virtual store). The three main mini games include Vine Climbing Racing, Banana Juggling and Donkey Konga's variation on Whack'a'mole. All the mini-games use the Donkey Konga Bongos, but they are usually very simple and only provide a quick distraction.Multiplayer    Donkey Konga's multiplayer consists of 3 different modes. Co-op, in which 2 players can pick songs and play them together in an attempt to collect coins. The Battle mode however, pits two players against each other to see who can achieve the higher score. This mode includes 2 new icons: Pow - Takes away a chunk of your opponents score, and Slot Machine - if hit correctly will reward the player with extra points. The more casual mode, Jam mode, removes any point or coin earning and allows up to 4 players to simply play the game.Track List     Donkey Konga features a wide variety of songs, some stranger then others.All the Small Things by Blink-182Bingo by UnknownBusy Child by The Crystal MethodCampfire Medley by UnkownDancing in the Street by Martha and the VandellasDiddy's Dities by NintendoDK Rap by NintendoDonkey Konga Theme Song by NintendoHungarian Dance #5 in G Minor by Johannes BrahmsI Think I love You by The Partridge FamilyKirby: Right Back at Ya! by NintendoLike Wow by Leslie CarterLouie, Louie by Richard BerryOn the Road Again by Canned HeatOye Como Va by Tito PuentePara los Romberos by Tito PuentePokemon Theme Song by NintendoRight Here Right Now by Fatboy SlimRock Lobster by he B-52'sRock this Town by Stray CatsShining Star by UnknownSing Sing Sing (With a Swing) by Louis PrimaStupid Cupid by  Connie FrancisSuper Mario Bros. Theme Song by NintendoThe Impression That I Get by The Mighty Mighty BosstonesThe Legend of Zelda Theme by NintendoThe Loco-Motion by Little EvaTurkish March by BeethovenWe Will Rock You by QueenWhat I Like About You by The RomanticsWhip It! by DevoWild Thing by The Wild OnesYou Can't Hurry Love by The Supremes</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9860">Rock Band</game><game id="24117">Meccha! Taiko no Tatsujin DS: 7-tsu no Shima no Daibouken</game><game id="21099">Wii Music</game><game id="18157">Um Jammer Lammy</game><game id="10051">PaRappa the Rapper 2</game><game id="25988">Cool Cool Jam</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2267065-box_dka.png</image></root>