<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25229</id><name>AaaaaAAaaaAAAaaAAAAaAAAAA!!!: A Reckless Disregard for Gravity</name><description>StoryAaaaaAAaaaAAAaaAAAAaAAAAA!!!: A Reckless Disregard for Gravity can loosely be described as a BASE jumping simulator. According to the game, in the year 1982, 'polystructures' fell from space and became stuck in the atmosphere; by the year 2011 cities had been built in the sky, far above the surface of the planet. The player plays as a BASE jumper in one of these cities, making dangerous leaps off of tall buildings. While you fall, the citizens of your city can be seen traversing walkways, hover cars can be seen flying through the air and very large billboards hawk their wares all over the place, often displaying unusual imagery and messages.GameplayYou start at the top of each level with the buildings of the city below you. After jumping downwards you can move near to a building to score a "kiss", worth 1000 points (any wall segment you kiss will turn blue) and stay near a building you have kissed to earn hugs, each worth 100 points. On the left side of the screen your speed meter is shown, while on the right side of the screen there is a meter which shows your proximity to the nearest building. At the bottom of every level there is at least one platform which you must land on at a suitable speed to successfully finish the level. To reduce your speed you can deploy your parachute fins which slow your fall but make it harder to control your movement, and disables the ability to earn points.Hitting a building or platform from above at a high speed or falling past the landing platform(s) at the end of the level will result in you failing the level. Smashing into the side of buildings will also cause you to temporarily spin out of control. On some levels there are scoring plates which you can crash into as you fall which will award you with the amount of points displayed on them and points can also be scored by hitting flying objects such as birds. Other objects may be found in midair which will advantage you in gameplay such as teleporters which will jump you back to a higher area of the level or plates that will speed you up. On the landing platforms at the bottom of the levels there may also be specifically marked out areas which will increase your score by a certain percentage if you land in them.Upon the completion of a level, the game displays your score and gives you a rating out of five stars based on it. Setting a new record for the number of stars you achieve on a certain level will result in you being rewarded with a large amount of the game's currency, teeth. The more stars you gain upon breaking your record, the more teeth you will be rewarded with, although you will still receive a small number of teeth if you manage to match your previous record on a level. Teeth can be used to buy new levels or buy special items for use in the levels, such as 'the power of caffeine' which will slow down time or the 'flip-it glove' which allows you to gain points by giving the thumbs up to your fans and obscene gestures to protesters.There is also a meditation level in the game which uses sound and imagery to help you relax, while there is an anti-meditation level which will presumably do the opposite.DevelopmentAccording to Dejobaan games, the idea for AaaaaAAaaaAAAaaAAAAaAAAAA!!! first came about when their level designer sent YouTube videos of BASE jumping to their programmer. Dejobaan then prototyped the original concept for the game in just 3 days.The free demo of the game included 10 levels and a single unlockable item. Pre-ordering the full game allowed customers to download an unfinished version of the game including 30 levels and 2 unlockable items. The full game includes 80 levels.PC System RequirementsOS:Windows XP/VistaProcessor:1.5 GHz processorMemory:1GBGraphics:3D card with 128MB video memoryDirectX®: 9.0c</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14727">Pilotwings</game><game id="33373">1...2...3...KICK IT!: Drop That Beat Like an Ugly Baby</game><game id="33143">Ninja Escape</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1373250-dd_aaa.jpg</image></root>