<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25225</id><name>Need for Speed: SHIFT</name><description>OverviewShift's cockpit view.The next instalment in the long-running    Need For Speed franchise will be developed by      Slightly Mad Studios (formerly     Blimey! Games). Slightly Mad Studios has a great sim-racing background, previously working on             GT Legends and             GTR 2. Shift is being developed to go after the hardcore simulation gamer segment, parting from the arcade racing style of the previous titles.  Shift will feature a cockpit view which will allow players to look freely around the cockpit. The new HUD will mimic driver head movement, responding to g-force to increase the realism factor.Driver ProfileEarn points for that clean corner.Shift allows the player to earn points for certain manoeuvres, such as cornering, overtaking, and even ramming competitors. Upon reaching the point threshold, the player will receive a level and a badge in the appropriate category. Depending on the type of badges the player earns, a title will be bestowed, 'Machine,' 'Wrecker,' or 'Dominator.' These badges are viewable by opponents and give them insight into your driving style.CarsOn May 29, 2009, the full car and track list for NFS Shift was revealed. There will be 67 cars and 18 tracks. 2006 Aston Martin DBR9  2009 Audi R8 LMS  2008 Audi R8  2008 Audi RS 4  2007 Audi S3  2007 Audi TT 3.2 quattro  2006 Audi S4  BMW M3 E36  BMW M3 E46  BMW M3 E92  2008 BMW 135i Coupé  2009 BMW M3 GT2  2007 BMW Z4 M Coupé  2008 Bugatti Veyron 16.4  2006 Dodge Challenger Concept  2008 Dodge Viper SRT10  Falken Tire 2010 Ford Mustang GT  2010 Ford Shelby GT500  2007 Ford Focus ST  2006 Ford GT  2006 Need For Speed Shelby Terlingua  1996 Ford Escort RS Cosworth  2009 Chevrolet Camaro SS  2006 Chevrolet Cobalt SS  2006 Chevrolet Corvette Z06  2006 Honda Civic Si  2000 Honda S2000  2006 Koenigsegg CCX  2008 Lamborghini Gallardo LP560-4  2007 Lamborghini Murciélago LP640  2007 Lamborghini Reventón  2006 Lotus Elise 111R  2007 Lotus Exige S  2005 Maserati MC12 GT1  2008 Mazda MX-5  2006 Mazda RX-8  1995 Mazda RX-7  1994 McLaren F1  2007 Mercedes-Benz SLR McLaren 722 Edition  2007 Mercedes-Benz SL65 AMG  2008 Mitsubishi Lancer EVOLUTION  2006 Mitsubishi Lancer EVOLUTION IX MR-edition  2003 Infiniti G35 (V35)  1997 Nissan 200SX (S14)  2009 Nissan 370Z (Z34)  2006 Nissan 350Z (Z33)  2009 Nissan GT-R SpecV (R35)  2008 Nissan GT-R (R35)  2000 Nissan Silvia (S15) spec.R AERO  1999 Nissan Skyline GT-R (R34)  1972 Nissan Skyline 2000GT-R  1992 Nissan 240SX (S13)  2006 Pagani Zonda F  2010 Pagani Zonda R  2008 Porsche 911 GT2  2009 Porsche 911 GT3 RSR  2006 Porsche 911 GT3 RS  2004 Porsche Carrera GT  2007 Porsche Cayman S  2008 Renault Mégane RS  2007 SEAT Leon CUPRA  2006 Subaru Impreza WRX STi  2007 Lexus LF-A Concept  2008 SCION tC  1986 Toyota Corolla GTS (A86)  2008 Volkswagen Scirocco  2006 Volkswagen Golf GTI  Tracks Alpental  Autopolis International Racing Course  Ambush Canyon  Brands Hatch  Dakota  Ebisu Circuit  Glendale  Hazyview  Mazda Raceway Laguna Seca  London  Miytomi  Nordschleife  Road America  Rustle Creek  Silverstone  Circuit de Spa Francorchamps Tokyo  Willow Springs  Soundtrack Buraka Som Sistema feat. Pongolove: Kalemba (Wegue-Wegue)Chase And Status feat. Plan B: PiecesDeadmau5: Ghosts N StuffEagles Of Death Metal: Anything 'Cept the TruthFort Knox 5 feat. Asheru: Insight (The Nextmen Remix)Gallows: I Dread The NightIn Case Of Fire: This Time We StandJamal: Pull UpKanye West: Paranoid (Part 2)Kasabian: UnderdogThe King Blues: The Streets Are OursMala Rodriguez: Te ConviertoMando Diao: Mean StreetMSTRKRFT feat. E-40: Click ClickN.A.S.A. feat. Spank Rock, MIA, Santigold and Nick Zinner: Whachadoin?The Prodigy: Run With The WolvesThe Qemists feat Mike Patton: Lost WeekendRegular John: TransmitterRootbeer: Under ControlShinichi Osawa: Electro 411 (Lies In Disguise Mix)Spoon Harris  Obernik: BaditudeTOKIO: DogonimTwisted Wheel: Oh, What Have You Done?Two Fingers feat. Sway: High Life  StoryAlthough it probably cant be called an official story, when you first start the game there will only be two options: Story, and Options. When you first enter this "story" mode you will be put into a BMW M3 with no assists on and run a hot lap. Based on that hot lap the game will configure its settings and assists to fit your driving style for a well rounded experience. You will then race on the same track with the same car with your specific game adjustments. This race will determine your beginning currency for the game, however it will only be a difference of about 10,000 no matter what position you get. PC System Requirements OS: Windows XP (Service Pack 3) / Windows Vista (Service Pack 1) / Windows 7CPU: Intel Core 2 Duo 1.6 Ghz or fasterRAM: 1GB RAM (Windows XP) / 2 GB RAM (Windows Vista / Windows 7)HDD: 6 GB free disk spaceGraphics: 256 MB or higher (Pixel Shader 3.0, PCIe)DirectX: Version 9.0cInternet Connection Required  SUPPORTED VIDEO CARDS ATI Radeon X1800 XT 512 MB or better NVIDIA GeForce 7800 GT 256 MB or better</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20729">GRID</game><game id="14858">GTR 2: FIA GT Racing Game</game><game id="13734">TOCA Race Driver 3</game><game id="275">GT Legends</game><game id="23526">GTR: Evolution</game><game id="19809">Project Gotham Racing 3</game><game id="22693">RACE Pro</game><game id="531">TOCA Race Driver 2</game><game id="12136">Pro Race Driver</game><game id="17599">Forza Motorsport</game><game id="5881">Forza Motorsport 2</game><game id="24995">Forza Motorsport 3</game><game id="2416">Gran Turismo</game><game id="8100">Gran Turismo 2</game><game id="12950">Gran Turismo 3 A-Spec</game><game id="17784">Gran Turismo 4</game><game id="20597">Gran Turismo 5 Prologue</game><game id="21790">Gran Turismo 5</game><game id="23062">Sega Super GT</game><game id="10124">Midnight Club: Street Racing</game><game id="20418">Midnight Club II</game><game id="5875">Midnight Club 3: DUB Edition</game><game id="20927">Midnight Club: Los Angeles</game><game id="21114">Midnight Club: Los Angeles Remix</game><game id="23517">GTR Evolution</game><game id="33400">Forza Motorsport 4</game><game id="36993">Project CARS</game><game id="34542">F1 2011</game><game id="27298">rFactor 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1891352-box_nfsshift.png</image></root>