<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25318</id><name>Mario &amp; Sonic at the Olympic Winter Games</name><description>GameplayWii One of the new events in the Wii version, Dream Ice Hockey. The Wii version of the game features various co-op and competitive modes, including boss battles and Festival Mode.  Festival Mode allows the player(s) to play through an Olympic competition from opening to closing ceremony.   The game offers Wii Balance Board support. DS The DS version of the game offers Adventure Tour mode, in which the player tries to stop Dr. Eggman and Bowser from ruining the Olympic Games.  The game also features Wi-Fi multiplayer as well as Download Play.Events Real Events Alpine Skiing (Downhill) Alpine Skiing (Downhill /Giant Slalom)Figure SkatingMogulsBobsleighBiathalon (DS)Ski JumpingSnowboard Half-Pipe (Wii)Speed Skating 500mShort Track 500mShort Track 1,000m Ice HockeySnowboard CrossLugeSkeletonNordic CombinedWii Dream Events   Dream Ski Cross Dream Ski CrossDream Ice HockeyDream Ski JumpingDream BobsleighDream Figure SkatingDream Snowball FightDream Hang glidingDream CurlingDream Alpine  DS Dream Events Extreme Snowboarding Curling Bowling Curling BowlingBlazing BobsleighIntense Short TrackSupersonic DownhillDeluxe Halfpipe Ski ShootingUltimate Figure SkatingSki Cross RacingRocket Ski Jumping Fever Hockey Fever HockeySnow Machine FightCharacters   Team Mario                 Mario                Luigi               Peach            Daisy Yoshi Yoshi             Wario    Waluigi   Bowser  Donkey Kong  Bowser Jr.Team Sonic        Sonic           Dr. Eggman       Tails          Knuckles  Shadow     Blaze  Silver the Hedgehog  Amy Rose Vector the Crocodile Vector the Crocodile  Metal SonicPlayers can also play as their Mii in the Wii version.  The game features customizable gear and clothing for players' Miis.  The game will also feature various supporting characters and bosses from or inspired by the Mario and Sonic universes.  Game Modes Single Match Shopping (Wii)Festival Mode (Wii)Party GamesAdventure Tour (DS)Multi-Round Match (DS)</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre><genre id="33">Snowboarding/Skiing</genre><genre id="39">Hockey</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20471">Beijing 2008: The Official Video Game of the Olympic Games</game><game id="14096">Nagano Winter Olympics '98</game><game id="8749">Winter Olympics: Lillehammer '94</game><game id="20619">New International Track &amp; Field</game><game id="22209">International Track &amp; Field</game><game id="17259">Athens 2004</game><game id="24411">Party Pigs: Farmyard Games</game><game id="27099">Winter Challenge</game><game id="25572">Vancouver 2010</game><game id="26102">Sled Shred featuring the Jamaican Bobsled Team</game><game id="34986">Mario &amp; Sonic at the London 2012 Olympic Games</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2112209-box_msog2010.png</image></root>