<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25313</id><name>Venetica</name><description>Overview  Scarlett sets out.In Venetica, Death becomes embodied and serves the ancient secret council known only as Corpus. Every generation Corpus chooses Death's successor, but when they unknowingly choose a necromancer, they disobey Corpus law and throw the balance of the world into chaos. It is known that no mortal can kill a necromancer, and that is where Scarlett steps in. With no knowledge of her past, she begins her adventure; She finds out she is the daughter of Death incarnate and is blessed with his ultimate powers. As she progresses, her powers become stronger, and her mind sharpens. These are all things she will need to defeat the evil that threatens to destroy the world and ultimately save her father.Gameplay Being Death's daughter has its advantages in battle.Venetica is a third-person action-RPG set in and around a fictional version of Venice. The game is largely melee based, with access to swords, hammers, axes, spears, shields, and scythes. Enemies are automatically targeted by being the closest to the front of Scarlett. Players can use a variety of techniques to aid them in combat, such as rolling and blocking. As an RPG, Venetica rewards players with XP for discovering new locations, defeating enemies and completing quests. Levelling up provides points to improve not only Scarlett's attributes but to learn and develop both physical and mental (magic) skills. Attributes can be improved there and then, skills can only be gained through use of various trainers who can be found throughout the game world. Death also plays a unique role in Venetica, through use of the 'Twilight World'. Scarlett is able to obtain Twilight energy by killing enemies with her 'Moonblade' scythe, and if she has enough energy when you die, she can be revived with all her hit points restored. When this happens, you enter a sort of 'bullet time' and are also able to move Scarlett to a better position when the game resumes. The 'Twilight World' can also be accessed through normal play via specific mental skills to discover hidden locations and passageways. Venetica also has a number of RPG staples such as lock picking and interacting/trading with NPCs. The game also features a reputation system with which you can gain reputation points for completing certain quests and lose points for committing various crimes such as stealing.PC System RequirementsMinimumOperating System: Windows XP SP2 or VistaProcessor: Pentium 4 with 2.4 GHz or comparable processorGraphics Card: Geforce 6600 GT or comparable graphics card (min 256 MB)RAM Memory: 1 GB (XP) / 1.5 GB (Vista x86) / 2 GB (Vista x64)Hard Disk Space: 10 GBRecommendedOperating System: Windows XP SP2 or VistaProcessor: Core 2 Duo E8200 (2.67 GHz) or comparable processorGraphics Card: Geforce 8800 GT or comparable graphics card (min 512 MB)RAM Memory: 2 GB (XP) / 3 GB (Vista)Hard Disk Space: 10 GBXbox 360 InstallationVenetica requires 4.8GB of hard disk space.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3264">Fable</game><game id="27878">Fable III</game><game id="14759">Two Worlds</game><game id="23081">Risen</game><game id="28178">The Witcher 2: Assassins of Kings</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1828918-box_venetica.png</image></root>