<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25383</id><name>School Days</name><description>PlotMakoto Itou, is just an average high school student, at Sakakino Gakuen.  While on the train to school, he notices a beautiful girl, wearing the uniform of the same school he attends, reading a book.  Over time, he always finds himself staring at her, with their eyes meeting every one in a while.  One day, after hearing about a charm that will make the one you like return your feelings if you take a picture of them and use it as your cell phone background for three weeks without anyone finding out, Makoto snaps a picture of this girl with his cellphone.  That same morning, before class begins, the girl sitting next to him, Sekai Saionji, sees Makoto staring at his phone, and sees the picture of a girl, on his screen.  She grabs his phone, causing the two to get to know each other more.  After communicating to each other through the passing of notes, Sekai vows to help Makoto get with this girl, who she informs him that the girls name is Katsura.  Eventually, with Sekai's help, the Makoto and Katsura begin dating, however Sekai soon grows jealous, as she has also developed a love for him.  EndingsIn School Days there are 21 possible Endings.  16 of which are "good" endings, where Makoto ends up with one of the girls, 2 endings where Makoto ends up with multiple girls.There are also 3 bad endings, which School Days is notorious for including.  In one ending, Katsura murders Sekai in broad daylight, on a bridge while Makoto watches, frozen in fear.  The second "Bad" ending is when, Makoto finally ignores Katsura again, she jumps off a building, with her head hitting the pavement right infront of Sekai, causing the two to break up from the memories of that incident.  The 3rd and Final "Bad" ending occurs when Makoto is murdered by Sekai, for leaving her in favor of Katsura, by the beach, where Makoto dies a slow, dramatic death.School Days LxHSchool Days LxH, after removing the H scenes, adds new plot relations and 5 new endings.  In these new endings, Makoto dies in one, Katsura dies in another, and Sekai dies in 2 of them.  The final new ending is both Sekai and Katsura's deaths.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22256">Shuffle!</game><game id="24128">Kimi ga Nozomu Eien</game><game id="23887">Higurashi no Naku Koro ni: Onikakushi-hen</game><game id="24251">Chäos;HEAd</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/29333/896282-schooldays.png</image></root>