<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25400</id><name>SingStar Pop Edition</name><description>New FeaturesWireless MicrophonesWireless SingStar MicrophonesAlthough Microsoft's Lips was the first karaoke game to be packaged with wireless microphones, these SingStar microphones had been in development some three years beforehand, intended for release with the original SingStar. Issues occurred with latency between the console and the microphone, using two simultaneously, and keeping costs reasonable for the consumer. They have improved audio quality over the wired microphones, and are also be compatible with the PlayStation 2.Voice-ControlVoice-controlled menus have also been incorporated, allowing players to use the microphone to select tracks or browse through the SingStore.TracklistAlphabeat - 10,000 Nights Of ThunderAmy Winehouse - RehabBack Kids - I'm Not Going To Teach Your Boyfriend How To DanceBon Jovi - Livin' On A PrayerChris Brown - With YouChris De Burgh - Lady In RedCyndi Lauper - True ColoursThe Feeling - RoseGloria Estefan - Rhythm Is Gonna Get YouJordin Sparks feat. Chris Brown - No AirKaiser Chiefs - Never Miss A BeatKate Nash - MouthwashThe Killers - HumanKings Of Leon - Sex On FireKlaxons - Gravity's RainbowLittle Jackie - The World Should Revolve Around MeN.E.R.D. - Sooner Or LaterP!nk - So What!The Police - Every Little Thing She Does Is MagicQueen - Bohemian RhapsodyRobbie Williams - AngelsRobyn - Be MineRockwell - Somebody's Watching MeSam Sparro - Black and Gold The Script - The Man Who Can't Be MovedSolange - I DecidedSugababes - GirlsWill Young - Changeswill.i.am feat. Cheryl Cole - HeartbreakerYazoo - Don't Go</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21171">Lips</game><game id="20714">Rock Band 2</game><game id="20673">Guitar Hero World Tour</game><game id="30022">Lips: Party Classics</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14741/958195-340664ps_500h.jpg</image></root>