<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25413</id><name>Lost Planet 2</name><description>OverviewWelcome to the jungle.Ten years have passed since the events that took place in           Lost Planet. The planet           E.D.N. III was completely covered in snow and ice, and humans were struggling to colonize the frozen world. Since then, the planet E.D.N. III has undergone massive climate changes that have revealed new jungles, awakened new creatures, and reveal the new "Snow Pirates."          Capcom says that they have taken many players' wishes into consideration and claim that users will be very pleased with the results. For example, many users said they wished they could take on           Akrid enemies (and bosses) in co-op mode, and Capcom have made this available in Lost Planet 2.Also, in some areas your thermal energy will not be effected as much. If you are in a icy environment, then your thermal energy will begin to go down. But say you are in a jungle or a warmer environment, you will lose little or no thermal energy in those places. This is different from the first game, where you were losing energy constantly. Your thermal energy is used to heal your character when injured and there are locations to replenish your energy. Also some weapons are based on your character's current thermal energy, if you run out of energy the weapon may no longer fire.In an interview with the game's producers, they stated that one of the things they looked at when building the sequel was the Halo franchise. They saw how Halo could appeal to a hardcore audience, but seem inviting to a casual audience, and use that as a basis for a lot of ideas in the game.StoryInstead of focusing on a single character like in           Lost Planet: Extreme Condition, the story now follows different factions from ex-military and various other types of snow pirates. The 5 factions include Rounders, Fight Junkies, Snow Pirate Elite, NEVEC Black Ops, and Femme Fatales. Not all of them are represented in the story or playable, some are just shown as enemies in passing but all of them can be used in multiplayer matches.The story revolves around a giant akrid known as an over G. The actions done in the game are set around similar time frames yet bounce back and forth so throughout the story characters will be acting out different sections of the story that are occurring at the same time as one of the other missions the player has done or will do.FeaturesSplit-screen Co-opThe game engine that Capcom will be using is an updated version of Capcom's very own MT-Framework engine used in Lost Planet. The updated engine is called MT-Framework 2.0.The game will feature four player online co-op where you can team up with friends and finish mission objectives and the main campaign mode.The game also includes two player split screen local co-op.Environments now include deserts and jungles as well as snow areas that were seen in the first game.Players can customize their characters in various ways and can be used in multiplayer as well as the main campaign after it has been completed.Data posts, on top of giving energy and radar information, can now be used as spawn points and give 500 points that add to the team battle gauge.Customizable items can be unlocked through various means. From using credits that are gained from boxes dropped by completed mission objectives and killing enemies and gaining career points which every few career levels unlocked new parts.The game contains a perk style system with different abilities such as higher defense for less damage or starting a level with more T-Energy.CustomizationCharacter Parts - Obtained through gaining career levels for the respective faction. These are cosmetic changes only and include 4 options, Head, Upper Body, Lower Body, and Thermal Pack. Color can also be changes, each part has 4 options.Weapons - Unlocked using credits that can only be acquired by faction multiplayer, training, and the campaign. The credits are used in a slot machine and the chances of getting a gun is randomized with other customizations. Guns are not so much upgrades but rather other forms of a similar weapon or function. As a shotgun is mainly damage, Shotgun 2 has only a 2 shot cartridge and uses plasma so it freezes VS and enemies in place allowing for tactical retreats, flanking or healing.Abilities - These are a sort of perk system, the player has 2 slots and these are unlockable with the slot machine. The each have various effects and some have negative effects that carry with them such as the Defense increases your defense yet sacrifices the players attack power and damage. Some also use both slots on a single ability.Emotes - Gained by using the slot machine with credits. These are just cations that can be mapped to buttons. These actions include kissing, dancing, celebrating, whistling, and dramatic team based poses.Noms De Guerre - Obtained through the slot machine using credits. Noms De Guerre is basically a label or nickname that appears as a sort of comment or nickname such as I Suck At Games, Schools Out For Summer, Glasses Make The Girl, Outlaw, Avenger and others. Some are also unlocked by doing certain actions. If you kill an enemy that is killing your team mates then you can possibly gain the Avenger.Character Selection - Selects a faction, these are all unlocked from the beginning. This is more so a selection of which faction do you want your character to have traits from as far as cosmetics go.Faction UnlockablesThis list contains all the Unlockables you can unlock as you level up each faction (Note: if you Unlock the Item via the slot machine you will not unlock it again or anything new in its place)RounderLv.01 - Mercenary A Model PartsLv.10 - Waysider A Model PartsLv.20 - Mercenary B Model PartsLv.30 - ShurikenLv.40 - Mercenary C Model PartsLv.50 - Hand Cannon SPLv.60 - Waysider B Model PartsLv.70 - Gun Sword SPLv.80 - Rounders Full Customization UnlockedLv.90 - Waysider Leader Model PartsLv.99 - Mercenary Leader Model PartsFight JunkiesLv.01 - Jungle Pirate A Model PartsLv.10 - Sandraider A Model PartsLv.20 - Vagabundo A Model PartsLv.30 - Jungle Pirate B Model PartsLv.40 - Sandraider B Model PartsLv.50 - Vagabundo B Model PartsLv.60 - Sandraider C Model PartsLv.70 - Jungle Pirate C Model PartsLv.80 - Fight Junkies Full Customization UnlockedLv.90 - Vagabundo Leader Model PartsLv.99 - Jungle Pirate Leader Model PartsSnow Pirate ElitesLv.01 - Crimson Pirate Model PartsLv.10 - Carpetbagger A Model PartsLv.20 - Mountain Pirate Model PartsLv.30 - Hunter Model PartsLv.40 - Sea Dog Model PartsLv.50 - Akrid Launcher SPLv.60 - Carpetbagger B Model PartsLv.70 - Bug Rancher Model PartsLv.80 - Snow Pirate Elites Full Customization UnlockedLv.90 - Carpetbagger Leader Model PartsLv.99 - Crimson Pirate Leader Model PartsNEVEC Black Ops:Lv.01 - Ex-NEVEC Model PartsLv.10 - NEVEC A Model PartsLv.20 - NEVEC B Model PartsLv.30 - Plasma Gun SPLv.40 - NEVEC C Model PartsLv.50 - Plasma Cannon SPLv.60 - NEVEC D Model PartsLv.70 - V-Device SPLv.80 - NEVEC Black Ops Full Customization UnlockedLv.90 - Nevec Leader Model PartsLv.99 - Nevec Leader 2 Model PartsFemmes Fatales:Lv.01 - Carpetbagger Femme Fatale Model PartsLv.10 - Jungle Pirate Femme Fatale Model PartsLv.20 - Waysider Femme Fatale Model PartsLv.30 - FirecrackerLv.40 - Sandraider Femme Fatale Model PartsLv.50 - Shotgun SPLv.60 - NEVEC Femme Fatale Model PartsLv.70 - Energy Gun SPLv.80 - Femmes Fatales Full Customization UnlockedLv.90 - Sandraider Femme Fatale Leader Model PartsLv.99 - Carpetbagger Femme Fatale Leader Model PartsCapcom Game save UnlockablesIn Lost Planet 2 having a game save from another Capcom game allowed for a special unlock for the player, as well as, for some reason,     Marcus Fenix and      Dominic Santiago from the  Gears of War franchise.Character Skins Albert Wesker - Have a  Resident Evil 5 save on your HDD (360/PS3) Frank West - Have a  Lost Planet: Extreme Condition save on your HDD (360/PS3)       Servbot Head - Have a  Dead Rising save on your HDD (360/PS3)Marcus and Dom - Beat the game once on any difficulty (360)Noms de GuerreLegendary Warrior - Have a Lost Planet save on your HDD (360/PS3)Decorated Soldier - Have a Lost Planet Colonies save on your HDD (360)I Love LP - Have both of the above saves on your HDD (360)Played The Demo - Have a Lost Planet 2 Online Mulitplayer Demo save on your HDD (360/PS3)Street Fighter - Have a Street Fighter IV save on your HDD (360/PS3)BSAA - Have a RE5 save on your HDD (360/PS3)Devil May Cry - Have a Devil May Cry 4 save on your HDD (360/PS3)I've Covered Wars - Have a Dead Rising save on your HDD (360)Capcommaniac - Have any three of the above saves on your HDD (360/PS3)WeaponsMachine Gun SP - Have a Lost Planet 2 Online Mulitplayer Demo save on your HDD (360/PS3)Shield SP II - Have a Lost Planet save on your HDD (360/PS3)*Info obtained from the Lost Planet 2 forums. Big thanks to BTHR Zero X for the work put into this list*GameplayLost Planet 2 contains many similarities with the first game, but one difference is the ability to go through the story in 4 player co-op. The game has a variety of weapons and new uses for Thermal Energy such as healing yourself, opening containers, firing energy weapons and keeping the player from taking damage in extreme conditions. The weapons range from assault rifles to a shield that can turn into a giant cannon when used with a teammate. The game also contains an anchor, a grappling hook type of device that is integral to the gameplay. The player can use this to zipline to close locations as the length of the wire is a bit short, yet they can also use it to repel and hang off cliffs and walls.Something important to note as well is that in the previous game Thermal energy was constantly being drained. As this game has new environments then the characters do not need it to sustain survivability from the world around them, but rather use it for direct healing purposes.The game contains a huge amount of progression and collection. The player has a career level which is used for unlocking customization parts which are purely cosmetic. The parts are usually unlocked in intervals of 10 levels. Aside from this, credits can also be collected. Credits are obtained by achieving mission objectives or killing enemies efficiently such as head shots, punching, and using the weak points. These are displayed as drops in box form with question marks. The boxes contain a random number of credits and sometimes contain Nom De Guerre which is a sort of nickname/ label.Weapons and GrenadesUnlike           Lost Planet: Extreme Conditions, which preferred actual character development, Lost Planet 2 prides itself in putting ugly bling on generic avatars. One of the customizable factors is the weapons. Ranging from a basic fully automatic Machine Gun to a Bolt Action Rifle. Lost Planet 2 features a lot of weapons and grenades for all types of players. Below is a list of all the unlockable weapons in the game.Human WeaponsStandardMachine GunMachine Gun IIEnergy GunGun SwordMachine Gun SPEnergy Gun SPGun Sword SPShort RangeShotgunShotgun IIRevolverFlamethrowerShotgun SPGold RevolverAkrid LauncherLong RangeRifleRifle IIPlasma GunPlasma Gun IIRifle SPGold RiflePlasma Gun SPHeavyRocket LauncherRocket Launcher IIHand CannonPlasma CannonRocket Launcher SPHand Cannon SPPlasma Cannon SPSupportShieldInjection GunInjection Gun IIV DeviceShield SPShield SP IIV Device SPOtherHandgunGrenadesNormalHand GrenadeIncendiary GrenadeBuster GrenadeHand Grenade IIHand Grenade IIIGumGum GrenadeSpark GrenadeChameleon GrenadeGum Grenade IIGum Grenade IIIDiscDisk GrenadeGrenade Energy GrenadeShurikenDisk Grenade IIDisk Grenade IIIReleaseDummy GrenadeBalloon GrenadeFirecrackerDummy Grenade IIDummy Grenade IIIPlasmaPlasma GrenadeRegen GrenadeWarp GrenadePlasma Grenade IIPlasma Grenade IIIVital SuitsVital Suits (VS's for short) are mechs that the player  enemies can pilot throughout the game. They have their own life bar, and drain thermal energy at a much faster rate than if the player were on foot. The benefit is that they can move while reloading the VS weapons, and can dual wield them.VS TypesBattle NeegalDongo GearGAB-25M Codename CaktiGAH-41BSL Codename BaylidGAH-42BS Codename BleedGAF-14 Codename FastreyGAF-14D Codename DrionGAF-15D Codename DrionGAN-A04SD Codename CyclopsGAN-3AM Codename TriseedGAN-34 Codename GranseedGAN-36 Codename OspreyGAN-37 Codename X-SeedGTB-22 Codename FazeGTF-11 Codename DrioGTF-13F Codename VensaGTF-13M Codename EvaxGTN-A01 Codename TurntableGTN-A01N Codename Turntable Type 2GTN-A03C Codename ZebetGTN-A03M Codename ZebetGTT-01 Codename NidaPTX-140R Codename HardballerTencale 8CameosDelta Squad joins the fight.The PS3 version of Lost Planet 2 will receive the Rathalos Armor skin from           Monster Hunter, and 2 different           Helghast skins.The Xbox 360 will come with           Marcus Fenix and           Dominic Santiago skins.Both consoles will receive           Albert Wesker and           Frank West skins.There are separate ways to unlock the characters on each console. In the PS3 version, the Helghast will be free           DLC, but you must beat the game to unlock other characters. On the 360 version, Wesker and Frank           can be unlocked by having a           Resident Evil 5 and           Dead Rising save data, respectively.PC SpecsLost Planet 2To support "NVIDIA GeForce 3D VISION"SpecMinimumRecommendationMinimumRecommendationOSWindows XPWindowsWindows 7Windows XPWindows 7WindowsWindows 7CPUIntel Core 2 Duo ProcessorAMD Athlon x2 ProcessorIntel Core2 Quad ProcessorAMD Phenom x4 ProcessorIntel Core 2 Duo ProcessorAMD Athlon x2 ProcessorIntel Core2 Quad ProcessorAMD Phenom x4 ProcessorMemoryWindows XP ： 1GBWindows Vista ： 2GBWindows XP ：2GBWindows Vista ：3GBWindows Vista ： 2GBWindows Vista ： 3GBHDD13.0GB13.0GB13.0GB13.0GBResolution640×480 or over1280×720 or over640×480 or over1280×720 or overVideo CardDirectX 9.0c / Shader 3.0No guarantee on running it on board or by sharing it with a main memoryNVIDIA GeForce 7800 Series or laterATI Radeon HD 2400 ProVRAM ：256MB 0No guarantee on running by sharing it with a main memoryNVIDIA GeForce 9800 Series or laterATI RadeonTM HD4800 Series or laterVRAM ： 512MB or overNo guarantee on running by sharing it with a main memoryNVIDIA GeForce 8800 Series or laterVRAM ： 512MB or overNo guarantee on running by sharing it with a main memoryNVIDIA GeForce GTX260 Series or laterVRAM ： 512MB or overNo guarantee on running by sharing it with a main memorySound CardDirectSound SupportDirectX 9.0c or overDirectSound SupportDirectX 9.0c or overDirectSound SupportDirectX 9.0c or overDirectSound SupportDirectX 9.0c or overInput DeviceMouse, KeyboardGaming Pad ： Xbox 360 Controller for WindowsMouse, Key boardGaming Pad ： Xbox 360 Controller for WindowsDVD SizeDVD9 x 2DVD9 x 2</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20662">Gears of War 2</game><game id="20497">Dark Sector</game><game id="20470">Bionic Commando</game><game id="20655">Battlefield: Bad Company</game><game id="25246">Battlefield: Bad Company 2</game><game id="7338">Earth Defense Force 2017</game><game id="19654">Frontlines: Fuel of War</game><game id="20516">Fracture</game><game id="270">Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon: Advanced Warfighter 2</game><game id="2397">Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon: Advanced Warfighter</game><game id="16909">Mass Effect</game><game id="13629">Giants: Citizen Kabuto</game><game id="29903">Vanquish</game><game id="30544">Conduit 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1974395-box_lplanet2.png</image></root>