<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25448</id><name>Magical Date EX - Sotsugyou Kokuhaku Daisakusen</name><description>OverviewAn arcade game in which the player picks one of 3  girls to go out on a date with (presumably a magical one), and proceeds  to complete a number of tasks in order to win her affections. 2 players  can compete against one another for the affections of the same girl on  a love-triangle stricken 3-way date.Tasks take the form of  minigames and quizzes, which play out upon landing on various spaces on  a virtual board game. The minigames take various themes, including such  accurate dating metaphors as one-on-one 2D frog fighting and quickly  identifying polygonal letters from odd angles. Succeeding in these  challenges will reward the player with the chance to pick an outfit for  their girl and take photos of her from an almost free-roaming camera on  a date at a number of wholesome locations; including the carnival,  tennis court, beach and Casino.HistoryThe  game was developed and published by Taito in Japan in 1996 under the  name of Magical Date - DokiDoki Kokuhaku Daisakusen (まじかるで～と　ドキドキ告白大作戦.  Literally, "Beating Heart Battle for Confession"). A minor version  update was released in 1997 in Japanese arcades as Magical Date EX -  Sotsugyou Kokuhaku Daisakusen (まじかるで～と　卒業告白大作戦. Literally, "Battle for  Confession Graduation"). The former version was released on the  Playstation on the 20th of November 1997, with this same release now  being available for purchase as a download from the Japanese  Playstation Store GameArchives (ゲームアーカイブス), made available on the 13th  of August 2008.DatesThe player may pick one of 3 dates, each with their own personalities, favourite locations and outfits to discover.Ayumi Ichijouji (一乗寺 愛弓 - いちじょうじ あゆみ)School: Sabrina Girls' Academy - 3rd YearBirthday: 9th September (Virgo)Blood type: AThree sizes: B 89 / W 59 / H 88Rin Midorikawa (緑川 鈴 - みどりかわ りん)School: Seira Girls' School - 1st YearBirthday: 17th April (Aries)Blood Type: BThree sizes: B 78 / W 56 / H 80Kasumi Fuyuno (冬野 霞 - ふゆの かすみ)School: Amatsuki Academy - 2nd YearBirthday: 23rd November (Sagittarius)Blood Type: ABThree sizes: B 82 / W 58 / H 83</description><genres><genre id="14">Trivia/Board Game</genre><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="39939">No-Ri-Ko</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/12985/904561-0001.png</image></root>