<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25486</id><name>Zen Bound</name><description> OverviewTie off on the high-lighted nail to endZen Bound is a relaxed puzzle game which revolves around covering wooden figures with paint by wrapping a rope around them. The gameplay concerns covering the largest portion of each wooden figure as efficiently as possible. Your goal in Zen Bound is to cover the wood with as much paint as possible. There are no time limits and the rope can be unwound from the figure, as needed. Once you have covered enough area, one of three cherry blossoms will flower, signifying that you've completed the puzzle and can finish playing by tying the rope off on a highlighted nail placed somewhere in the wood.  GameplayYou rotate a wooden shape by pinching and twisting it with your fingers on the multi-touch display. The rope always hangs down on the screen and is controlled by the  accelerometer. LevelsThe current version of Zen Bound consists of three types of puzzles, each organized into "trees."   The tree of reflection consists of carved animal shapes like birds, snakes, whales, and bears, while the Tree of Challenge consists of geometric puzzles that prove to be pretty tricky.  An additional tree, called the tree of Nostalgia, was later added in an update, featuring further wooden figures modeled after toys. By causing the cherry blossoms to flower, upper branches of the trees become unlocked. As you climb the tree, the shapes become progressively more difficult to cover efficiently, with varying contours, sizes, and allowed rope measurements. Later stages provide challenging twists such as numerous wooden blocks, along with oddly shaped ones.ReceptionGet that BullThe critical response for Zen Bound was almost entirely positive. It received a 9.5 from IGN's Levi Buchanan and was highlighted by many sites as one of the best iPhone Apps of 2009. Zen Bound is often praised for making better use of the iPhone than the majority of the games on the platform.  Due to the game's critical success and high number of sales in the App Store, Zen Bound 2 has since been announced for the  iPad.</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/7303/909571-zen_iphone.jpg</image></root>