<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25485</id><name>Test Drive Unlimited 2</name><description>Overview       Test Drive Unlimited 2 is an                  open-world racer developed by                              Eden Games, published by                              Atari and released on February 8, 2011. Test Drive Unlimited 2 features the new island of Ibiza, with more than 2,000 miles of road, as well as the Hawaiian island of Oahu from the first                    Test Drive Unlimited game. Other new features include                 dynamic weather effects, a                day/night cycle, and improved               vehicle damage, along with a plethora of new cars, including a new class of off road vehicles and motorcycles to collect, race, cruise and crash.     The game features the same seamless integration between online play and single player as the first TDU, and has been described by the developer as being "always live" with updates being downloaded automatically during gameplay. Players are able to customize their vehicles and purchase in-game properties and clothing for their driver, leaving their own unique mark on the online world. This is part of a light story progression featured in the game.        Test Drive Unlimited 2 opens with you choosing your own character, and, unlike the more open nature of the first game, initially locks you into a series of events keyed together by a mild story. As a dopey valet who falls asleep at the wheel of a Ferrari California, you find yourself challenged by its owner to take place in a series of televised races that she is the host for. Licenses are required for progressing in these loose story events, and each class of race has a named driver that will taunt you for the duration of the event. The game opens up early on, but the story element remains in place until the end. During the course of the game's story, your character rarely speaks, leaving them devoid of a personality beyond what you define. Progression In TDU 2, players earn experience by reaching driving milestones and completing certain challenges, and use this experience to unlock new portions of the game. Additional cash can be earned by driving dangerously and performing stunts through the game's F.R.I.M. (Free Ride Instant Money) system, reminiscent of the Kudos system from                    Project Gotham Racing, or the boost meter in the              Burnout series. After each level of FRIM you earn, you have a few seconds to 'cash out' your earnings. Additional levels will increase your relative winnings ($100, $200, $350, $500, etc) but hitting anything with your car will reset the entire meter.  Progression is displayed as a level for each player, visible in their own pause menu as well as beside their Gamertag when racing online. The maximum level attainable is 70, and your levels accumulate from four different categories - Challenges, Discovery, Collection, and Social. Each of these categories has 15 levels of their own and points are earned by small achievement-like challenges, from winning a set number of races to owning a certain number of cars or houses, or driving over a set percentage of roads. You can also add to your Global Level via the Casino DLC, with ten additional levels to attain. Within the standard game there are sixty levels - the additional ten bolsters the system to its final figure of seventy.   ChallengesChallenges consist mainly of races in the game, which are divided into different classes and subclasses that  restrict your choice of car - C (classic) races, A (standard) races, and B (off-road) races, with decreasing numbers for each indicating the relative speed of the cars in question. A class ranges from 1 to 7, with 7 being the slowest cars such as the Volkswagen Golf GTi or Alfa Romeo MiTo.  The races consist of the same variants found in the first Test Drive Unlimited - point to point or circuit races against opponents, speed trap races where you hit the speed traps as fast as possible, time trials, and overall speed challenges, where points are earned gradually for every mile over a set speed you drive for a given period of time.   The challenge group also includes character challenges and licenses. Licenses are earned for each of the aforementioned car classes and doled out as the story progresses. Character challenges are found at set places around the map and only show up for a set period of time each day in-game. These involve ferrying a person from their location to another, holding a certain speed for a daredevil, trailing a guy's girlfriend, and more. The most common are the taxi-like missions, and they have different requirements depending on the person - some people have a time limit, some people like being driven slowly because they have weak stomachs, and some tolerate you hitting traffic or driving off the road more than others.   CollectionCollection is also divided up into a number of categories - cars, houses, furniture, clothing, and hairstyles/makeup. Points are earned for collecting a set number of each, although acquiring higher level clothing and hairstyles requires your discovery level to be reasonably high, as it's linked to item unlocks and car performance upgrades. Simply purchasing cars and houses, and customizing both of them will attain some of these points. Collection points also restrict the availability of different content for customizing your avatar. Some clothing and hairstyles are locked until you reach a certain level, whereupon they can be purchased. DiscoveryThe Discovery category relates entirely to driving around the island. Points can be attained for discovering new roads around the islands, finding different locations, finding photo spots, and finding wrecked cars. These all contribute to your Discovery level, which defines what can b purchased from the tuning shops in the world. The Discovery levels do not apply in different regions of the two islands. Content cannot be bought in Area 1 of Ibiza if a player only has a high enough Discovery level in Area 2. Wrecked cars also contribute to this overall level - there are ten wrecks hidden in each of the island areas, and you can earn six cars via finding these wrecks. These cars cannot be attained in any other manner.  Social Social level pertains to the level of sociability you personally have in the game, though it does not decrease. These points can be earned for playing with friends or being part of a racing club in the game. Partaking in multiplayer races and challenges also contributes to one's overall Social rating. If a player joins in a police pursuit with another player this provides a further boost to Social experience.   Available in the game is a social network of sorts, called MyTDULife. The system apes popular networking sites such as Facebook and MySpace, allowing players to post status updates and set their mood, as well as customize a profile other gamers can browse with images and other information about how they like to play. DLCCasinoUpon launch of Test Drive Unlimited 2, Atari released the Casino as content. This download unlocks a casino area, where players can gamble on games of poker and roulette, as well as play on slot machines. The Casino also comes with an exclusive track where players can race the cars available on the island, which are exclusively unlocked via the casino. Among these cars is the Audi R8 Roadster, which is notoriously difficult to acquire. At launch the Casino was plagued with many issues and Atari took it down, though it has since been returned in a more usable state. The Casino also came as a bonus with some retail copies of the game. Exploration PackReleased in May 2011, the Exploration Pack came as free content from Atari. The pack adds gameplay improvements, new content, bug fixes, and 3D capabilities with both the PC and PlayStation 3 versions of the game. The pack comes with twenty new events, and two new event types. These new event types are Extreme Convoy, and Timed Convoy. They play in the same manner as regular convoy events, except causing any damage during Extreme Convoy results in a failed mission. Timed Convoy simply adds a timer to the existing Convoy mission style. With each of these events completed a new wreck is discovered. Upon completing all these events players unlock two cars: the 1969 Dodge Charger, and the Lancia Stratos Rallye. Three new 'Discovery' levels can also be gained, with new clothing tied to them. New races are also available in Multiplayer mode, though they are exclusive to the Lancia Stratos. Accessible via the television, a help channel becomes available.   Bug fixes and gameplay improvements are detailed below:Gameplay improvements:Players can sell their cars in the used car dealer (including cars won in duels)Effect of collisions with rocks and trees is now less severeInstant challenges have been tweaked to exclude very short or very long racesCruising as a passenger now unlocks roadsLower car-road impact soundsNew restrictions on MP races (to stop the prevalence of top end cars in all races)Session lost messages are now more descriptiveKoenigsegg CCXR performance tweaked to be competitive with Bugatti VeyronsY axis inversion option addedAdditional race restrictions added to avoid Bugattis having complete dominanceLobby: Club cars are now allowed in multiplayer and solo modesWe scrutinize savegames for specific hacks and take measures when they are detectedNat info text displayed on the Start screen if a potential network configuration problem is detectedLobby: « With/Without collisions » info addedLobby: « Inner club »  « club vs club » info icons addedPlayers can now cancel on the search games loading screen[PC] Chat window moved and positioned according to the game mode[PS3] Mic  Voice IP options added[X360] It is now impossible to join a ranked match once it has started[X360] Rich presence is now more descriptive, based upon what players are doing in the gameBug fixes:Cars can be launched into the air by glitches in the roadCars can end up in the sky if the player goes to the map while their car is fallingPossible to get through walls/scenery by going in and out of map modeUnable to enter sessions with a co-driverCars sometimes turn invisibleUnable to start a multiplayer race with the Caterham Superlight R500Unable to play club races with club carsThe Final Cup can be repeated to earn the grand prize an unlimited number of timesMissing car door interior when switching to some low-res modelsStickers not appearing when in a friend’s garageInvisible avatars immediately after a club upgradeHawaii – collision problem on the “Hydro House”Collisions problems in many sectorsInfinite loading in sticker shop when no more storage space is availableCrash when loading a photo in MyTDUHouseCrash at the end of chase mode onlineCrash at end of a duelCrashes in chase mode  freerideCrash when exiting a championship challengeOther random crashesSticker shop: Matt paint available twice, replacing metallic as an optionMylife Info : Incorrect number for clothes (collector box)  road unlocked (cruising box)Pause menu: MyLife and Player info incorrect for levels higher than 60Gameplay icons not removed when you press start on the results screenWrecks: Instant Challenge invites still active when opening wrecks popupMap : Players sometimes displayed at the top-west corner of the map, in the seaNews: Not possible to delete news itemsClub member list not updated when the president fires someone (members not notified)Disappearing GPS road sections on HawaiiLogitech on-wheel LED not accurately representing RPM and engine danger zoneUnable to sell pre order and DLC cars in game[PS3] Logitech wheel issues[PS3] Possible to get stuck in an invalid session[PS3] The Ranked Matches search results not correct[X360] Problems caused by changing devices[X360] Players can get kicked out of sessions for no reason[X360] Crash when selecting a challenge icon very quickly on the mapCasino: Rankings not appearing correctlyCasino: Roulette exploitCasino: Crash on slot machines when another player wins a jackpot and leaves the roomCasino: Crash at level 10 cut-sceneCasino: Crash when you use back on track at the entrance to the Casino in HawaiiCasino: Changing profile when you win a car makes it impossible to win or purchase cars CarsAC  1967 AC 427    Alfa Romeo 2010 Alfa Romeo MiTo Quadrifoglio Verde 2005 Alfa Romeo Brera Italia Independent 2007 Alfa Romeo 8C Competizione  2009 Alfa Romeo 8C Spider  Ariel 2006 Ariel Atom 300 Supercharged  Ascari2007 Ascari A10 2005 Ascari KZ1 R Limited Edition  Aston Martin 2010 Aston Martin V12 Vantage Carbon Black Edition 2008 Aston Martin DBS Coupe 2010 Aston Martin DBS Carbon Black Edition 2010 Aston Martin One-77 2009 Aston Martin V12 Vantage 2007 Aston Martin DB9 Coupe 2007 Aston Martin DB9 Volante 2008 Aston Martin V8 Vantage  Audi 2010 Audi R8 Spyder 5.2 FSI Quattro 2010 Audi Q7 V12 TDI Quattro 2008 Audi Q7 V12 TDI Quattro - TDU2 Inuit Edition 2010 Audi TT-RS Roadster 2009 Audi S3 2010 Audi RS5 Coupe 2010 Audi R8 5.2 FSI Coupe 2010 Audi TTS Coupe 2010 Audi RS6 Avant 2010 Audi S5 Coupe  Bugatti  2010 Bugatti Veyron 16.4 Centenaire 2010 Bugatti Veyron Super Sport 2010 Bugatti Veyron 16.4 Grand Sport Sang Bleu 2010 Bugatti Veyron 16.4 2010 Bugatti Veyron 16.4 Grand Sport  Caterham 2010 Caterham Superlight R500 2008 Caterham CSR 260  Chevrolet 2010 Chevrolet Camaro 2SS 1957 Chevrolet Corvette (C1) 2010 Chevrolet Camaro LS Cynergy Green Edition 2010 Chevrolet Camaro 1LT  Citroen  1967 Citroen 2 CV  Dodge 2006 Dodge Charger SRT8 2008 Dodge Viper SRT101969 Dodge Charger  Ferrari 1985 Ferrari 308 GTS Quattrovalvole 2010 Ferrari 458 Italia 2010 Ferrari 599 GTB Fiorano 2010 Ferrari 599 GTO 2010 Ferrari 612 Scaglietti 2010 Ferrari California 2004 Ferrari Enzo 2009 Ferrari F430 Scuderia 2009 Ferrari F430 Scuderia Spider 16M 2009 Ferrari FXX Evoluzione 2007 Ferrari 612 Sessanta 2009 Ferrari 599 GTB Fiorano China Edition 1973 Ferrari Dino 246 GTS  Ford 2005 Ford GT 1968 Ford Mustang Fastback 2011 Ford Mustang GT 2010 Shelby GT500  Ginetta 2010 Ginetta F400   Gumpert 2008 Gumpert Apollo Sport  Hummer 2007 Hummer H3  Jaguar 2010 Jaguar XKR Speed Pack / Black Pack 2010 Jaguar XKR  1955 Jaguar D-Type 1968 Jaguar E-Type  Koenigsegg 2008 Koenigsegg CCXR Edition  Lancia 1993 Lancia Delta HF Integrale Evoluzione II Lancia Stratos version Rallye   Land Rover 2010 Land Rover Range Rover Sport HSE Lotus 1981 Lotus Esprit S3 2010 Lotus Evora 2008 Lotus 2-Eleven  McLaren 2011 McLaren MP4-12C  Mercedes-Benz 2009 Mercedes-Benz ML 63 AMG 1954 Mercedes-Benz 300 SL GullWing 2010 Mercedes-Benz SLR McLaren Stirling Moss 2010 Mercedes-Benz SLK 55 2009 Mercedes-Benz SLR 722 S Roadster 2009 Mercedes-Benz CLK 63 AMG Black Series 2010 Mercedes-Benz SLS AMG  Nissan 2009 Nissan 370Z Optional Parts 2007 Nissan GT-R R35 2009 Nissan 370Z  Pagani 2008 Pagani Zonda Cinque  2010 Pagani Zonda Tricolore Coupe 2005 Pagani Zonda F 2007 Pagani Zonda F Roadster 2002 Pagani Zonda C12S Roadster   RUF 2010 RUF RT 12  2006 RUF RK Spyder 2005 RUF RGT 2000 RUF RTurbo  Shelby 1965 Shelby Cobra Daytona Coupe  Spyker 2010 Spyker C8 Aileron 2010 Spyker C12 Zagato 2010 Spyker C8 Aileron Spyder 2010 Spyker D8 Peking-to-Paris  Subaru 2006 Subaru Impreza WRX STI Sedan  TVR 2006 TVR Sagaris   Volkswagen 2009 Volkswagen Touareg V10 TDI 1967 Volkswagen Beetle 2010 Volkswagen Golf GTI   Weismann 2003 Wiesmann Roadster MF3   PC System RequirementsFactorsMinimumRecommended Operating System Windows XP SP2Windows 7  Processor Intel Core 2 Duo @ 2.2GHz / AMD Athlon X2 4400Intel Core 2 Duo : 2.2GHz / AM Athlon X2 4400 RAM 2GB2GB GraphicsNvidia GeForce 8800 / ATI Radeon HD 3870 Nvidia GeForce GTX 280 / ATI Radeon HD 4870 DirectX DirectX 9.0cDirectX 9.0c Hard Drive Space 14GB14GB Sound DirectX 9.0c compatibleDirectX 9.0c compatible Peripherals Keyboard / Mouse / Controller Controller Other RequirementsBroadband connection / Microsoft .NET 3.5 Broadband connection / Microsoft .NET 3.5Test Drive Unlimited 2 is unique in the fact that it requires 2GB of RAM as a minimum. Making an attempt to run the game with less than 2GB of RAM will present an error dialog to alert a user that they cannot run the game without upgrading their RAM.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25226">Need for Speed World</game><game id="5977">Need for Speed III: Hot Pursuit</game><game id="12976">Need for Speed: Most Wanted</game><game id="20741">Need for Speed: Undercover</game><game id="18095">Need for Speed: ProStreet</game><game id="8844">Need for Speed: Carbon</game><game id="32253">SHIFT 2: Unleashed</game><game id="31634">Driver: San Francisco</game><game id="37648">Forza Horizon</game><game id="39714">WRC 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2139880-box_tdu2.png</image></root>