<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25578</id><name>NCAA Basketball 09 March Madness Edition</name><description>OverviewNCAA Basketball 09: March Madness Edition is an exclusive XBox Live Arcade release that has all of the same gameplay as NCAA Basketball 09, but only presents the NCAA Tournament mode with the 2009 NCAA Tournament Bracket.  There is no quickplay, season, or dynasty mode, and does not support online multiplayer.  NCAA Basketball 09: March Madness Edition does support multiplayer on the same system, but the only match-ups that can occur are the ones that actually occur within the tournament bracket.  There are a total of 65 teams in the tournament, acurate statistics and player number designations, and actual venues of the tournament, such as the Final Four in Detroit, Michigan.2009 NCAA Tournament TeamsMIDWESTLouisville CardinalsMichigan State SpartiansKansas JayhawksWake Forest Demon DeaconsUtah UtesWest Virginia MountaineersBoston College EaglesOhio State BuckeyesSiena SaintsUSC TrojansDayton FlyersArizona WildcatsCleveland State VikingsNorth Dakota State BisonRobert Morris ColonialsAlabama State HornetsMorehead State EaglesSOUTHNorth Carolina Tar HeelsOklahoma SoonersSyracuse OrangemenGonzaga BulldogsIllinois Fighting IliniArizona State Sun DevilsClemson TigersLSU TigersButler BulldogsMichigan WolverinesTemple OwlsWestern Kentucky HilltoppersAkron ZipsStephen F. Austin LumberjacksMorgan State BearsRadford HighlandersEASTPittsburgh PanthersDuke Blue DevilsVillanova WildcatsXavier MusketeersFlorida State SeminolesUCLA BruinsTexas LonghornsOklahoma State CowboysTennessee VolunteersMinnesota Golden GophersVCU RamsWisconsin BadgersPortland State VikingsAmerican EaglesBinghamton BearcatsEast Tennessee State BuccaneersWESTConnecticut HuskiesMemphis TigersMizzouri TigersWashington HuskiesPurdue BoilermakersMarquette Golden EaglesCalifornia Golden BearsBYU CougarsTexas AM AggiesMaryland TerripansUtah State AggiesNorthern Iowa PanthersMississippi State BulldogsCornell Big RedCal State-Northridge MatadorsChattanooga Mocs</description><genres><genre id="22">Basketball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21317">College Hoops 2K8</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1811158-box_ncaab09mme.png</image></root>