<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25579</id><name>Star Trek: D-A-C</name><description>Overview Lots of flashy laser beams.  Star Trek: D-A-C is an arcade style top down space combat simulator for Xbox Live Arcade, PlayStation Network and PC. The game was released May 13th 2009, to coincide with the release of the new Star Trek movie. It is not a retelling of the movie's storyline, but the battles are inspired by the ones depicted in the movie. Senior Producer of the game, Ben Hoyt, has compared the game to other top down space shooters such as          Geometry Wars and          Subspace, but claims that it has more "strategic depth". The subtitle is derived from the game's three play modes: Deathmatch, Assault, and Conquest. The players can choose to be Federation or Romulan, and then choose from three different ship classes: Bomber Fighter Flagship (The Federation Flagship is obviously the  U.S.S. Enterprise, while the Romulan Flagship is meant to resemble the future starship from the film, the  Narada.) Star Trek D-A-C scatters health and special orbs around the maps. Special orbs grants the player various power-ups such as:  MissileCloakingShieldMake a copy of yourselfArea effect energy blast that hits all enemies within a radiusGame Modes  Huge energy blast.  Star Trek: D-A-C features three modes- single player, co-op and versus: The single player and co-op allows the player to take command of the U.S.S. Enterprise in space battles against various enemies, including the main enemies from the film, the          Romulans.  Versus mode has 12-player multiplayer, featuring 2 teams of 6, with AI filling in any empty spots. The Federation and Romulans use their array of gunships to destroy the enemy, and the first team to reach 50 kills wins. All the game modes have a 10 minute time limit for each of their levels before moving on to the next. </description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="31">Dual-Joystick Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21167">Geometry Wars: Retro Evolved 2</game><game id="11099">Geometry Wars: Retro Evolved</game><game id="16151">Geometry Wars: Galaxies</game><game id="18381">SubSpace</game><game id="4576">Battlestar Galactica</game><game id="20833">Shred Nebula</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/13158/1010019-gb.png</image></root>