<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25645</id><name>Call of Duty</name><description> OverviewCall of Duty for the Nokia N-Gage follows  a similar story and mission path as the original Call of Duty for PC  and Mac, but in a drastically reduced form. What levels have been ported  over have been streamlined to force more straight-forward progression  and to compensate for the limited field of view. The game has  generated notoriety for its technical shortcomings, such as its single  digit framerate, three-frame reload animations, tight field of view, low  draw distance and AI quirks in addition to interface oddities leading  some reviewers to speculate that the game wasn't completely finished  prior to shipping.Missions11 missions comprise the  single player campaign and are split across three different countries  (USA, Great Brittan and the Soviet Union). Additionally, there is one  secret level only obtainable via the use of the level select code.American Brecourt - Originally placed as the fifth  mission in the PC version of Call of Duty, Brecourt has the player  running along trenches of Brecourt Manor during Operation Overlord.  Based on the Brecourt Manor Assault as depicted in Band of Brothers'  second episode, "Day of Days".Burnville - Based on the  second mission of the PC version of Call of Duty and takes place  chronologically prior to the Brecourt Manor Assault, just after midnight  June 6, 1944. The 101st parachutes into a field outside of of a small  vilage and must make their way through the vilage and disable the  anti-aircraft guns behind the church.Foy - An entirely  original urban-based mission, Foy takes places in the Belgium city of  the same name. The level must be cleared out of German troops through  close quarters fighting and then their flak cannon must be destroyed.BunkersBritishCapture The BridgeThe DamAirportV2  RocketsRussianRed  SquarePezenskaiaReichstagHiddenTank AssaultReception Call  of Duty for the N-gage  received mixed reviews and garnered a   metacritic score of 58. </description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4946">Ashen</game><game id="1576">Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon: Jungle Storm</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14912/702079-callofduty_ngage_cover.png</image></root>