<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25659</id><name>Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles: My Life As a Darklord</name><description>Development  ReleaseAfter the release of the well recieved     Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles: My Life as a King,    Square Enix decided to focus upon a direct sequel, with My Life As a Darklord being the result. My Life As a Darklord was revealed alongside another Square Enix published   WiiWare title,  Final Fantasy IV: The After Years, at the 2009 Games Developers Conference. The game was met with decent reviews, which although not as enthusiastic as My Life as a King, still proved positive. The game currently holds a 71.78% rating on GameRankings.StoryChapter 1:...Chapter 2:...Chapter 3:...After defeating the enemy forces the enemies leader kneels down before Mira and reveal herself to be      Princess Fiona of Alfitaria the biggest kingdom of the world. Fiona who had heard about Mira's half Clavat lineage tells Mira that she came to see her since she believes that Mira can be the link that will restore peace between the monsters and the other races. Mira tells Fiona that monsters are destined to fight and that that is what she intends to continue to due, then she walks of not finishing off her opponent. Chapter 4:After her conversation with Fiona Mira locks herself up in her room for several days. In the mean time      Slitzkin a wandering      Moogle who seems befriended with Tonbetty visits the tower. While discussing what happened to Mira with Tonbetty Mira burst out of her chamber and dropkicks Tombetty for speaking with a Moogle. Tombetty's head falls of and it is reveal that Tonbetty is actually a      Selkie in costume. Fiona enraged by the situation is interrupted by her Tonberry troops who tell her that      Sir Hugh Turg a famous Lilty knight wants to face her. Mira then decides to head straight for the challenge and to deal with Tonbetty and Slitzkin afterwards. Downloadable contentUpon release 5700 points worth of DLC were made available for the player to download much like My life as a King. CostumesBeloved Wardrobe:  Launch DLC, ? PointsRadiant Dress: A dress similar to the light side of Mira's normal dress, having it equipped allows the player to cast Cure once a battle. Dark Dress: A dress similar to the dark side of Mira's normal dress, equipping it grant the player an extra 50 NP at the start of every battle. Prim Dress: A dress modeled after      Chime from      My Life as a King her dress, when equipped the player can cast Hard Slash, a light physical attack once a battleDesigner Wardrobe: Launch DLC, 600 PointsCat dress: A dress inspired by the dress Sherlotta wears in      Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles: Echoes of Time, equipping it grants the player an extra 50 NP at the start of every battle.Mystic Dress: The dress  Ryona wears in      Final Fantasy IV: The after years, equipping it allows the player to cast Fire (light fire damage) once a battle. Puffy Dress: A dress that looks like the one  Poron wears in Final Fantasy IV: The after years. Having it equipped allows the player to cast Cyclone (light generic damage) once a battleMonstersDarklord Special Forces: Launch DLC, ? PointsOgre:Ahriman:Sahagin:Coeurl:Chimera:Lamia:Darklord Elite Forces: Launch DLC, ? PointsGigas:Abaddon:Tentacle:Dark Knight: Little Pirate:Kain: Launch DLC, 200 PointsPalon: Launch DLC, 200 PointsFloorsBedroom Set, Launch DLC, 300 PointsVoid FountainSummon MirrorDrain chestLiving Room Set, Launch DLC, ? PointsPurgatory PressAbyss CraneHypno BoxItemsDarklord Armory: Launch DLC, 400 PointsShockwaveBlastArrowFiraQuakeCuraVile Ribbon: Launch DLC, 200 PointsOwning this item will grant the player plus 50 NP at the start of every battleNightmare Tiara: Launch DLC, 200 PointsOwning this item will grant the player plus 50 NP at the start of every battleFatal Earings: Launch DLC, 200 PointsOwning this item will grant the player plus 50 NP at the start of every battleGloomy Armband: Launch DLC, 200 PointsOwning this item will grant the player plus 50 NP at the start of every battleWailing doll: Launch DLC, 200 PointsOwning this item will grant the player plus 50 NP at the start of every battleStage collectionsWanted on Vaction: Launch DLC, 400 PointsAn extra chapter that plays after the final chapter of the gameA Fatefull Clash!: Launch DLC, 400 Points...</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7274">ActRaiser</game><game id="17123">ActRaiser 2</game><game id="1861">Dark Cloud</game><game id="10007">Dark Cloud 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3715/940097-jaquette_final_fantasy_crystal_chronicles_my_life_as_a_darklord_wii_cover_avant_g.jpg</image></root>