<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25651</id><name>R.U.S.E.</name><description>OverviewR.U.S.E. (which doesn't actually stand for anything) is a Real-Time Tactical game set in World War II. The game has a bright and clean art style unlike many other WWII games that go for a grimy, guerilla look, setting R.U.S.E. apart visually. It runs on the IrisZoom engine which allows the developers to create huge expansive maps that are reportedly the most detailed levels any RTS has ever attempted.The story centers around a fictional character named Joe Sheridan. Sheridan is a US Army rising star who aspires to be a full general. As the player, you control his forces from the deserts of North Africa; to sun scorched Italy; rustic France, Belgium, and Holland; and the final assault on Nazi Germany.A free, open, public beta of R.U.S.E. was available on Steam without need of any sort of activation key from March 9th to April 12th.MultiplayerMultiplayer consists of 4 different online game types. There is...1) Unranked 1v12) Unranked 2v23) Unranked 3 or 4 player Free For All4) Ranked 1v1 or 2v2There is also a "Battles" game type, where you can fight against the AI in either 1v1, 2v2, or 3-4 player Free For All.RUSE stands out from other WWII RTT's by a few innovative features.- Gameplay essentially forces the player to gather Intelligence on the enemy, or to hide your own units through the use of RUSE's.- Highly detailed maps that cover immense areas of land and various landscapes.- Most WWII games opt for a grimy, dirty look. But RUSE has a vibrant art style that is also highly detailed.- RUSE is compatible with the Playstation Move and Touch Screen Computers, offering a new level of depth o the battlefield.The fundamental difference of this game compared to other RTT titles is IrisZoom technology, which enables the ability to watch over the battlefield from every possible camera angle.The RUSEsDeception is the essence of R.U.S.E.’s gameplay, just as it is the core of warfare: deception techniques such as espionage, decoys and radio silence played an essential role during World War II and continue to figure in modern conflicts. R.U.S.E. features deception cards - also known as ruses – that let you apply a deception technique to a specific sector in the map. The ruses are split into three categories :- Reveal : these ruses such as the Spy Plan or Decryption are useful in order to understand or uncover your enemy’s actions.- Hide : the Radio Silence or Camouflage Net will let you hide your troops or buildings from your opponent’s radar.- Fake : the last category of ruses is used to trick your enemy, to make him believe what you want him to believe. The Decoy Offensive simulates an attack to confuse your adversary.Decoy ArmySpyDecoy BuildingDecryptionBiltzRadio SilenceFanaticismCamouflage NetTerrorReverted IntelUplayUplay is a service where you earn points and use them to unlock bonus items. Here is a list of Actions (achievements) and Rewards for this game.ActionsPointsFirst ContactComplete first mission.10UFrom Cover to CoverCapture the Italian secondary HQ by moving from cover to cover.20UDeath from AboveComplete Operation Market Garden.30UVeteranReach the Veteran League.40URewardsCostR.U.S.E. Theme (Wallpaper)Download the exclusive UPlay Theme (Wallpaper) for R.U.S.E..10USuper PershingUnlock the ability to upgrade your Pershing heavy tanks to Super Pershings! Available in Battle and Multiplayer matches.20UGolden ChipsGrants you the ability to use restricted Golden Chips in place of the basic ones! Available in Battle and Multiplayer matches.30UThe Battle of the CotentinThe entire Cotentin map is available for battles against the AI! Available in the Battle section.40UDLC:Eugen Systems released a DLC pack for RUSE in December of 2010. The DLC pack is called "The Manhattan Project pack." It provides 3 new maps, and 2 new game modes called Total War and Nuclear War.3 New maps: The new maps are: "Twilight of the Gods" (a large map overlooking a river delta in Holland at night). "Vesuvio" (another large map, takes place in Italy with a volcano in the center; the belligerents bases are located on opposite sides of the volcano). "Guns 'N Tulips" (a medium sized map that takes place in North Africa with a river running through the denter of the map).2 New game modes:Total War - This game mode starts all belligerents in the 1939 time period, but progresses after a set time to 1942, and finally advances to 1945. When changing time periods, all weapons will automatically be researched and will phase-out the older weaponry. This game mode offers a unique experience to enter combat on the same level as your opponent(s) without the need to research any time period correct weaponry.Nuclear War- As it states, Nuclear War allows all belligerents the ability to build a nuclear artillery factory. For a high price, one can manufacture the factory and for a nearly equal high price can produce the nuclear artillery. Nuclear artillery moves is quite cumbersome, has a slow rate of fire, and is very fragile. But, it can destroy a building in a single shot and can decimate troops within its blast radius.PC System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Windows® XP (with Service Pack 3) or Windows Vista® (with Service Pack 2) or Windows® 7Processor: 2.8 GHz Intel® Pentium® 4 or AMD® Athlon™ 64 3000 or higherMemory: 1 GB for XP / 2 GB for Vista and Win7Graphics: 128 MB DirectX® 9.0c-compliant video card (ATI® Radeon X1000/GeForce® 6 Series or better)DirectX®: DirectX 9.0c (included)Sound: DirectX 9.0c-compliant sound cardRecommended:OS: Windows® XP (with Service Pack 3) or Windows Vista® (with Service Pack 2) or Windows® 7Processor: 3.5 GHz Intel® Pentium® D or AMD® Athlon™ 64 3500 or higherMemory: 2 GB (XP / Vista / Win7)Graphics: 256 MB DirectX® 9.0c-compliant video card (ATI® Radeon X1900 series / GeForce® 7800 or better)DirectX®: DirectX 9.0c (included)Sound: DirectX® 9.0c-compliant sound card</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20739">Tom Clancy's EndWar</game><game id="20660">Command &amp; Conquer: Red Alert 3</game><game id="17551">Command &amp; Conquer 3: Tiberium Wars</game><game id="20674">StarCraft II: Wings of Liberty</game><game id="18930">Company of Heroes</game><game id="4750">Company of Heroes: Opposing Fronts</game><game id="1901">Supreme Commander</game><game id="7489">Act of War: Direct Action</game><game id="2478">Act of War: High Treason</game><game id="24079">StarCraft II: Legacy of the Void</game><game id="9659">Panzer Tactics DS</game><game id="29046">Panzer General: Allied Assault</game><game id="6164">World in Conflict</game><game id="25235">Under Siege</game><game id="35658">Wargame: European Escalation</game><game id="39305">Wargame: AirLand Battle</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1849088-box_ruse.png</image></root>