<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25673</id><name>Ratchet &amp; Clank Future: A Crack in Time</name><description>OverviewRatchet  Clank Future: A Crack in Time is the 9th installment in the Ratchet  Clank franchise, and the third and last game in the "Future" trilogy. It brings new improvements to the platforming aspects with new gadgets and mechanics, and keeps the combat fresh with new weapons and enemies.The game features more Clank gameplay than the other games in the series, with his newfound time manipulation abilities. Also, Captain Qwark gets more screen time, due to his absence from Quest for Booty. The end of the trilogyRatchet  Clank Future: A Crack in Time is the end of the "Future" trilogy, wrapping up the story set in motion by Ratchet  Clank Future: Tools of Destruction.The game answers some of the biggest questions about the franchise: Ratchet's origins, the Zoni, and what has happened to the Lombax race. The Future storyline is also the first time Ratchet  Clank games have had a story arc going across multiple games.The story so far...The first game in the trilogy, Ratchet  Clank Future: Tools of Destruction, began with the brave duo living peacefully in Metropolis, when they received a message from Captain Qwark saying that, once again, he is in trouble. They responded by running to his rescue. They soon realize that the city is being attacked by heavily-armed robotic commandos that work for a evil mastermind Emperor Tachyon. Tachyon wants to kill all the Lombaxes in the universe, and he has tracked down Ratchet who is the last of the Lombax race. Ratchet and Clank manage to escape from him and fly away into space. Then they go through the galaxy looking for Tachyon who is trying to take over the galaxy.Along the way, they meet many characters who play important roles throughout the trilogy.Some of the more important characters are:Talwyn Apogee - The daughter of a famous explorer who helps Ratchet on his journey.Captain Slag and Rusty Pete - Two space pirates that want to catch RatchetThe Smuggler - A mysterious smuggler who provides ratchet with new gadgets and builds weapons.The heroes eventually learn that Emperor Tachyon is a Cragmite, who are the sworn enemies of the Lombaxes. Ratchet also finds out that Tachyon wants to use the Dimensionator to bring back the Cragmites, who were thrown into another dimension by the Lombaxes. Ratchet eventually manages to defeat Tachyon and stop the Cragmites from taking over the galaxy.But as Ratchet is busy with his own adventure, Clank meets mysterious creatures called the Zoni, who give Clank control over time and other abilities. Unfortunately, Clank is the only one who can see the Zoni, so Ratchet doesn't believe that they exist. The true intentions of the Zoni are unknown in Tools of Destruction; however, at the conclusion of the game, the Zoni kidnap Clank and the game ends with a cliffhanger.The story is continued in Ratchet  Clank Future: Quest for Booty, the second entry in the trilogy. In Quest for Booty, Ratchet fights against space pirates alongside Talwyn to find out where the Zoni have taken Clank. At the end of the game, Ratchet finds out that the Zoni are somehow connected to Dr. Nefarious, the villain of Ractchet  Clank: Up Your Arsenal, who is back for revenge.PlotIn Ratchet  Clank Future: A Crack in Time, Ratchet meets another Lombax named Alistair Azimuth; disproving that Ratchet is the last Lombax. General Alister Azimuth was a once-revered Lombax leader, and a friend of Ratchet's father. Alister desperately wants to rescue the other Lombaxes and will do so at any cost. While Ratchet is working his way towards the Great Clock, Clank learns of his past and where he came from. All the while Dr. Nefarious is attempting to use the clock to turn back time so the villains always win and Ratchet always loses. In the end, Ratchet and Clank are left with very important decisions to make that will effect their own futures, along with the future of their friendship.GameplayThe gameplay is still identical to the previous games in the series, with minor tweaks. One of the new features is the Hover Boots. These boots let Ratchet hover through the air and speed through the levels faster. They are also included in platforming puzzles as a substitute for the absent Clank. Another new aspect is the sense that this game is a little more open world than the previous ones. Traveling between planets now has Ratchet flying his ship and landing on smaller planets and moons to further explore and upgrade his arsenal.Aside from the Ratchet adventure, Clank now has his own storyline to follow. It is a simple platformer with a bit of a time twist. Clank must maneuver his way through the Great Clock and his own mind by solving time puzzles. These have him creating recorded versions of himself to unlock doors, raise platforms, and more.WeaponsRatchet  Clank Future: A Crack in Time has 19 weapons in total--including Ratchet's OmniWrench--and each one (except the wrench) can be upgraded five levels, making it incrementally stronger. On other play throughs, while in Challenge Mode, each weapon will have an "Omega" version which can be leveled up another five times. Bringing the total of each weapon up to level 10.Buzz BladesFirst Located - Vorselon's Warship, Korthos SectorInitial Cost - 48,000 Bolts (24,000 if discounted)V5 Name - Doom BladesDescription - The Buzz Blade is an pistol-like weapon that shoots out deadly sharp buzzsaw blades which can ricochet off of walls and floors. When one of the blades strikes an enemy it bounces off and circles back for multiple hits.Chimp-o-MaticFirst Located - Agorian Battleplex, Korthos SectorInitial Cost - Win the "Overkill" challenge of the Raritanium CupV5 Name - ChimpositronDescription - The Chimp-o-Matic is the latest in the long line of Ratchet  Clank weapons that turns enemies into adorable animals. As the name the Chimp-o-Matic turns foes into huggable lovable monkeys.Constructo BombFirst Located - Zolar Forest, Planet QuantosInitial Cost - 1,000 BoltsV5 Name - Mega Constructo BombDescription - The Constructo Bomb is much like the Bomb Glove of earlier Ratchet  Clank games. It launches a small ball which creates a massive explosion with a huge area-of-effect. It is one of three "Constructo Weapons" in the game, players can attach special mods to the gun to give it different abilities.Constructo PistolFirst Located - Begin Game With itInitial Cost - FreeV5 Name - Mega Constructo PistolDescription - The first game players have access to in the game, the Constructo Pistol is little more than a regular pistol at first. It however is also one of three "Constructo Weapons," and with certain mod attachments it gains the ability to shoot more rounds quicker, or slower more powerful shots. Making it one of the most versatile guns in the game.Constructo ShotgunFirst Located - Agorian Battleplex, Korthos SectorInitial Cost - Win the Gold CupV5 Name - Mega Constructo ShotgunDescription - The third of the "Constructo Weapons" in the game, the Constructo Shotgun is incredibly powerful up-close. It has mods that will affect the types of shells it shoots, the firing speed and spread, as well as added bonus effects.CryoMine GloveCryoMine GloveFirst Located - Tombli Outpost, Planet ZanifarInitial Cost - 41,000 BoltsV5 Name - Blizzard Mine GloveDescription - The CryoMine Glove shoots out small mines which move towards enemies and instantly freezes them solid for a short amount of time. Once frozen, enemies can be shattered with the OmniWrench or a powerful blast from a different weapon.Dynamo of DoomDynamo of DoomFirst Located - Torren IVInitial Cost - 16,000 BoltsV5 Name - Dynamo of DevestationDescription - The Dynamo of Doom shoots a giant electric orb which electrifies enemies. The player can roll around the electric orb directly using the PlayStation 3 controller's Sixaxis function. If the Sixaxis isn't used the orb will roll forward automatically.Groovitron GloveFirst Located - Agorian Battleplex, Korthos SectorInitial Cost - 22,000 Bolts (11,000 if discounted)V5 Name - Groovibomb GloveDescription - The Grooviton Glove is one of the most unique and fun to use weapons in all of "Ratchet  Clank." When used a ball shoots out and turns into a disco ball complete with music, which forces enemies to dance uncontrollably for a short time. When upgraded to the Groovibomb it plays hard rock instead of disco.Mag-Net LauncherFirst Located - Valkyrie Citadel, Planet VapediaInitial Cost - 40,000 Bolts (37,000 if discounted)V5 Name - Mag-Net CannonDescription - The Mag-Net Launcher shoots a batch of small ionized raritanium orbs which are wrapped in an electromagnetic net. When it hits an enemy it wraps around them, locking them into place temporarily while dealing damage to them.Mr. ZurkonFirst Located - Vorselon's Ship, Phylax SectorInitial Cost - 6,000 Bolts (3,000 if discounted)V5 Name - Zurkon the DestroyerDescription - Mr. Zurkon is a smart-mouthed, cocky, synthenoid, combat partner. When summoned he will fight alongside players with a mounted laser blaster. Zurkon also possesses a deadly sadistic sense of humor which terrify his enemies.NegotiatorThe NegotiatorFirst Located - Agorian Battleplex, Korthos SectorInitial Cost - Win the "Bros Before Foes" challenge of the Bronze CupV5 Name - JudicatorDescription - A gigantic rocket launcher which shoots a deadly explosive rocket. Once the rocket is fired, it travels in a spiraling motion before blowing up its unfortunate target.OmniWrench Millennium 12Omni-WrenchFirst Located - Begin Game With itInitial Cost - FreeV5 Name - N/ADescription - The wrench that Ratchet uses for all of the "Future" games, the OmniWrench Millennium 12 is a big heavy wrench which is good for hitting enemies. In addition to acting as a melee weapon, the wrench also has a bunch of other abilities, like grabbing and throwing objects, turning bolts, and acting as a kinetic tether.Plasma StrikerFirst Located - Krell Canyon, Planet LumosInitial Cost - 33,000 BoltsV5 Name - Plasma SlayerDescription - The Plasma Striker is a high powered crossbow that shoots bolts of high powered plasma. It also functions as a sniper rifle as it has a high tech bioscope which not only zooms in, but also highlights enemies weak points.Rift Inducer 5000Chimp-o-MaticFirst Located - Nefarious Space StationInitial Cost - 91,000 BoltsV5 Name - Rift Ripper 5000Description - One of the most powerful weapons in the game, the Rift Inducer 5000 is a quick and easy way to dispose of a large number of foes. When fired, the Rift Ripper 5000 opens a portal to an alternate dimension where an inter-dimensional tentacle monster named "Fred" lives. Fred proceeds to grab enemies, pull them into his world and eat them alive.RYNO VRYNO VFirst Located - Axiom City, Planet TerachnosInitial Cost - Find all nine pieces of Holo-PlanV5 Name - Mega RYNO VDescription - Unarguably the most powerful weapon in the game, the RYNO V is the latest in the popular line of the "Rip Ya a New One" line of weaponry. Firing a barrage of high-powered missiles, the RYNO V has the speed of a machine gun, the accuracy of a pistol, and the power of multiple rocket launchers.Sonic EruptorFirst Located - Zolar Forest, Planet QuantosInitial Cost - 4,000 BoltsV5 Name - Super Sonic EruptorDescription - The first weapon of the series to utilize an actual creature for power, the Sonic Eruptor attached a small slug-like creature known as a Xenegote to the end of a device which would cause the creature to emit it's powerful mating call. The more the creature breathes in before firing, the stronger the blast.Spiral of DeathSpiral of DeathFirst Located - Argonian Battleplex, Korthos SectorInitial Cost - Win "Triumvirate of Terror" challenge of the Silver CupV5 Name - Spiral of CarnageDescription - The Spiral of Death is a gun which charges up kinetic energy into a deadly spiral which is shot at enemies. Once shot the spiral tears through foes, once reaching a certain distance the spiral curves and returns to the gun--much like a boomerang--allowing for multiple hits.Tesla SpikesFirst Located - Axiom City, Planet TerachnosInitial Cost - 19,000 BoltsV5 Name - Storm SpikesDescription - The Tesla Spikes could be called the ultimate defensive weapon. Throw one spike down and it acts like a short range turret, shocking anything within its perimeter. Throw down multiple Tesla Spikes and an electric charge flows between each one creating a barrier, as well as increasing their power.Other EquipmentRatchet now has Holo-Armor, which allows him to turn off his armor when he doesn't need it. Thus eliminating the problem many fans had with previous games, in that high end armor sets would cover Ratchet's face, making him look like a robot.Another new gadget that he has is the OmniSoaker, which absorbs things from the environment and shoots it out again. For example, he can absorb nectar from plants, and use it to distract deadly bugs.You can also receive discounts on some of the weapons from Tools Of Destruction in A Crack in Time if you have a save from Tools of Destruction.LevelsThe pause menu..Krell Canyon - The Agorians have brought in heavy artillery. Work with General Azimuth to destroy the Hydra Tanks and save the Vullard settlement! -The description of on of the missions in the level.Axiom CityAxiom City - Home of the Terachnoids, Ratchet journeys here to search for more information regarding Clank.The Great ClockThe Great Clock - Located directly in the center of the galaxy (give or take 50 feet), the Great Clock is a mysterious place and also the location where Dr. Nefarious is holding Clank. The place itself controls the flow of time and is drastically important to the story..Pre-order BonusesRatchet  Clank Future: A Crack in Time had an extensive amount pre-order bonuses. Before the game's launch, you could find these items at retailers like Amazon.com, Best Buy, Game Crazy, GameStop, and other participating retailers.Discovery Packagethe Discovery PackageExplore the Insomniac Moon, a special level that resembles the layout of the Insomniac Games’ offices!Scattered through this museum-like level, you will discover a moon’s worth of extra content that didn’t quite make it into the game.Power Packagethe Power PackageThe Power package includes an exclusive weapon skin for one of Ratchet’s weapons. You will also start the game with extra hit points, and Ratchet’s brand new Cryo-Mine Glove, a weapon that freezes enemies!Bolt Packagethe Bolt PackageThe thrifty gamer will find lots to love in this exclusive Bolt Package! Start the game with two of Ratchet’s most bolt-centric power-ups; the Bolt Magnetizer and Box Basher, and you will discover your galactic bank account has already been loaded with 5,000 bolts when you start the game.Space Packagethe Space PackageThe Space Package offers an exclusive hot-rod skin for Ratchet’s ship, the Aphelion. You also will start with 5,000 bolts as well as an exclusive Ratchet  Clank PlayStation Home avatar skin!Collector's EditionCollector's Edition (PAL exclusive)A Collector's Edition of Ratchet and Clank: A Crack in Time is available only in Europe, and contains:A 3D lenticular cover - Something of a hologram, where the cover image appears to have depth as you look at it from side to side.An art book with concept art from the game.A PSN voucher with a code to unlock the Insomniac Moon level, equivalent to the Discovery pre-order package.A Crack in Time Patch 1.20A number of people had encountered a bug when finishing the game that essentially corrupted the game's save file. The bug essentially happened when players were given the option to continue playing the game as it is or go into challenge mode to earn more bolts,and upgrades. The save would load and the game would freeze after a short while. The patch also addresses an issue some encountered with the Smuggler while attempting to get the Good Samaritan trophy. If you are one of the affected and still have the corrupted file, load it and press the following: Up, Up, Down, Down, L3, square, circle, square, circle, R3. The game will restart in challenge mode with all earned bolts, weapons, and upgrades, and you should be able to play through your second time with no real issues.SoundtrackDisc One1."A Crack in Time (Theme)"2."Unused Preview Theme"3."Main Menu"4."The Caretaker's Awakening"5."Chase in The Clock"6."Zolar Forest"7."Weapon Upgraded!"8."Trouble with the Fongoids"9."The Missing Children"10."Minor Mission Complete"11."Vongoid Village Music"12."Vorselon's Invasion"13."Infiltrating Vorselon's Ship"14."Into The Ship"15."Fighting The Troops"16."Vorselon Confrontation"17."Polaris Classical; Space Wander 1"18."Fixing The Great Clock"19."Clank's Subconscious"20."The Hypersonic Brainwave Scrambler"21."Polaris Classical; Space Wander 2"22."Molonoth Fields"23."Major Mission Complete"24."Chase Down Azimuth"25."The General's Pupil"26."Axiom City"27."Battle in Neurox Plaza"28."Bypass the Security System"29."General Mission Complete"30."The VX-99"31."Fixing Anomalies"32."Please Don't Go"33."Tetramite Swarm"34."The Agorian Riders"35."The Hydra Tanks"36."Agorian Air Support"37."The Freed Colony"38."The Consequences of Time"39."Pride of The Battleplex"40."My Blaster Runs Hot: The Game"41."My Blaster Runs Hot - Score Tally"42."The Bronze Tournament 1"43."The War Grok"44."The Silver Tournament"45."The Elite Hydra Tank"46."The Gold Tournament"47."Battleplex Victory"Disc 248."Infiltrating Tombli Outpost"49."The Dead Planet"50."Freeing the Fongoids"51."A Peaceful Village"52."Inside The Outpost"53."The Lombaxes Escape"54."Entering The Orvus Chamber"55."The Outer Islands"56."Dance with The Valkyries"57."Rotator Rings Death Trap"58."Battery Bot Drop Death Trap"59."Duel with Cassiopeia"60."The Nafarious Space Station"61."Meeting 'Shanon'"62."To a Wonderful Smell"63."They Didn't Fall For It"64."The Battle for Gimlick Valley"65."Riding The Morklon Vines"66."Confronting Commander Argos"67."The Battle for Time"68."The End?"69."No More Than Six Minutues"70."Heroes Collide"71."The Clock Breaks"72."Azimuth's Remorse"73."The Last Lombax"74."A Crack in Time (Credits)"Disc 3 ( Groovitron Groove Tunes )1."Disco Napoli"2."Electro Boost"3."Flying to Space"4."Flying to Space (Vocals)"5."Restless Dancer"6."Teknokrat"7."Chain Free"8."Checkered Flag"9."Girl Rules"10."Girl Rules (Vocals)"11."Metal Future"</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10384">Jak II</game><game id="9669">Jak 3</game><game id="8006">Metal Arms: Glitch in the System</game><game id="14623">Jak and Daxter: The Precursor Legacy</game><game id="20586">Banjo-Kazooie: Nuts &amp; Bolts</game><game id="10920">Banjo-Kazooie</game><game id="2871">Banjo-Tooie</game><game id="16094">Super Mario Galaxy</game><game id="31304">Ape Escape Move</game><game id="29405">Transformers: War For Cybertron</game><game id="34833">Sonic Generations</game><game id="35545">Fuse</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1832155-box_racfacit.png</image></root>