<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25689</id><name>Bonsai Barber</name><description>PlotThe villagers are hungry for the latest in foliage fashion, and it's up to you to fix the foliage. Use the tools like: scissors, clippers, spray can, buzzer, paint brush and more. You could call this game a "first-person-groomer" game. In this game you are a barber, cutting and styling tree's "hair". There are a variety of different styles to cut and unlock. You can also practice your own style on your "practice bush".GameplayEach day, 5 of the games 12 characters will come into your shop and ask for the perfect haircut. It's up to you and your trimming tools to get the job done right. Using the Wii Remote, you can shape and mold the customers hair into their desired style. Each of the plant patrons will tell you what style the want before each session, and it's up to the player to get that style right. The player is rated with stars on how well they're doing. Each haircut has a template to show the player what it looks like, the closer the player matches the template, the higher rating they get. The players have many tools available to get the job done just right, even a water bottle to help the hair grow back if you make a mistake. After you've given your foliage friends the perfect cut, you can choose the mallet tool to bang on a gong, signaling that your work is finished. Each day you play the game you are only allowed five cuts, and the more you play, the more hair styles you will unlock. If you miss an appointment with one of your customers, they'll send messages to your Wii Message Board making sure that you know they are not happyTriviaThis game was created by Martin Hollis, who originally worked at Rare and on Goldeneye 007InfoPlayers: 4Wii Points: 1.000</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21804">Root Beer Tapper</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/7439/943430-bonsai_barber.png</image></root>