<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25721</id><name>Cloudy With a Chance of Meatballs</name><description>Movie StoryFlint Lockwood is a scientist that wants to prove himself to his father. In order to do so, he decides to resolve hunger issues around the world by inventing a machine that turns water into food, named the Flint Lockwood Diatonic Super Mutating Dynamic Food Replicator, or FLDSMDFR for short. But everything does not go as expected, and soon the machine becomes sentient and causes many disasters on the planet. Flint then tries to fix the situation and save the world.  Game StoryThe game follows the plot of the movie and starts up right when the FLDSMDFR has started wreaking havoc on the world. You control Flint and a second player can join in co-op controlling Steve (the monkey), whom you guide through 5 Acts made up of 18 levels. Each level consists of an overall goal, such as saving someone from a horde of gummies, and along the way you destroy food stuffs using various weapons. Destroy 30 food stuffs per level and you acquire a blue print piece which serves as the games collectable portion and also is necessary to achieve the "true" game ending. GamePlayThe game is a standard modern platformer. You guide flint through each level solving puzzles and defeating enemies. It is a kids game so is relatively light on challenge though in order to find and destroy all 30 pieces of food on each level will require a little problem solving. Each level gives you one to three weapons to utilize, though the selection is predetermined. The weapons are used to solve various puzzles, defeat enemies, and destroy food stuffs.   The weapons are:  Hot Enougher - A large hair dryer like tool used to melt things.Forkamajigger - A spear like weapon with a fork for an end. Used to spear things along with a few other uses in puzzlesUpsucker - A sort of vacuum that also expels what it sucks up. Used to solve numerous puzzles in the gameBigacious Pow - A boxing glove on a spring essentially. Used to punch and break things.Chopper-er - A large blade used to cut things, surprisingly enough. Also there are times where you make use of Flint's vehicle, the Outtasighter. It works as a giant vacuum along with a way to remove certain giant food pieces. ReceptionThe game received a rather wide range of reviews and currently stands in the upper 60s on metacritic (depending on platform). Most reviewers thought the game was a decent kids game though the criticisms leveled at it ranged from being too short to being a bit repetitive in gameplay and voice samples.  System Requirements Minimum:OS: Windows XP SP3 / Vista SP1Processor: Pentium 4 / Athlon XP equivalent to 2GhzMemory: 512MB for XP / 1GB for VistaGraphics: 64MB – 64Bit bus width DirectX 9.0c compatible video cardsDirectX®: DirectX 9.0cHard Drive: 3.5 GB freeSound: Any DirectX 9.0c compatible sound card Recommended:OS: Windows XP SP3 / Vista SP1Processor: Pentium 4 / Athlon 64 equivalent to 2.8GhzMemory: 1GB for XP / 2GB for VistaGraphics: 128MB – 128Bit bus width DirectX 9.0c compatible video cardsDirectX®: DirectX 9.0cHard Drive: 3.5 GB freeSound: Any DirectX 9.0c compatible sound card</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="24700">Monsters vs. Aliens</game><game id="18492">Bee Movie Game</game><game id="34990">Kung Fu Panda 2: The Video Game</game><game id="42289">The Smurfs 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1824031-box_cwacomb.png</image></root>