<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>259</id><name>Grandia III</name><description>Overview Grandia III is an RPG for the PS2 made in 2006. The Gameplay was very similar to past Grandia games with the battle system's fastest-character-goes-first, wheel turn-based gameplay.Story You follow Yuki, a young boy who wants to be a pilot , who gets mixed into saving 2 worlds when he meets a "communicator" called Alfina. Alfina is being chased by her brother and his companions, an incompetent brute Kornell, the wicked yet beautiful Violetta, and La-Illim, an undead monster who summons undead dragons to fight for him. On his adventures Yuki makes invaluable friends, Ulf, a dragon rider who shares his love of the sky, Alfonso, the powerful fisherman who believes in dreams, Hect, a silent, almost lifeless girl, Miranda, Yuki's mother and a great cook and finally Dahna a tribe leader and fortune-teller. Together they travel around the world attempting to stop the evil Xorn and protect the Guardian spirits before Emelious destroys them all.Gameplay Special gameplay elements include a multitude of equipment including "mana eggs" which increase magical potency according to elements. Powerful spells can be extracted from mana eggs. Each character has different skill sets for you to learn and level up.   The main form of transportation in the game is by plane. MusicNoriyuki Iwadare, who composed all prior installments of the Grandia series, returns. The game features the theme song "In the Sky" by Japanese recording artist Miz.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12099">Star Ocean: Till the End of Time</game><game id="4328">Chrono Cross</game><game id="20336">Xenosaga: Episode I - Der Wille zur Macht</game><game id="11093">Xenosaga: Episode II - Jenseits von Gut und Böse</game><game id="8600">Xenosaga: Episode III - Also Sprach Zarathustra</game><game id="18304">Xenogears</game><game id="18991">Suikoden IV</game><game id="19152">Suikoden V</game><game id="11434">Enchanted Arms</game><game id="15050">Atelier Iris: Eternal Mana</game><game id="1959">Atelier Iris 2: The Azoth of Destiny</game><game id="7197">Dragon Quest V: Hand of the Heavenly Bride</game><game id="12349">Shadow Hearts: From the New World</game><game id="20128">Wild Arms Alter Code: F</game><game id="4822">Wild Arms 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2080536-box_grandia3.png</image></root>