<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25913</id><name>Ski-Doo Snowmobile Challenge</name><description>OverviewSki-Doo Snowmobile Challenge is a racing game released for the Xbox 360, PS3 and Wii. The game was developed by Coldwood Interactive and published by Valcon Games. As well as having a career mode, there is also a single race mode, split-screen multiplayer and online multiplayer for up to 12 players; as well as four separate race types. During races you can perform tricks and landing them successfully will build your adrenaline meter, which when full, will give you boost. The career mode has a standard method of progressing. From the onset there are only a few events opened up but as you complete these more and more unlock. Winning events will give you money which you can spend on upgrades for your snowmobiles; there are also unlockable outfits and promotional videos from Ski-Doo. The game uses Ski-Doo snowmobiles exclusively.Event TypesCross Country Cross Country races are set in a more open environment, while still retaining the familiar lap structure common in most racing games. These often cross over frozen ponds and streams.Snowcross Snowcross races are essentially motocross races with snowmobiles. Here there are shorter laps with big jumps and sharp turns.Hill Cross Hill Cross races start at the bottom of a hill or mountain with the goal being to reach the top in first place.Freestyle In a freestyle event, your goal is to score 3000 points as quickly as possible. There are three of these in the game and are set in a closed environment filled with jumps.SoundtrackTriple Cobra - Lazerbird Triple Cobra - Trash Fight the Quiet - June Fletch - Still Alive Last Conservative -  Learning to Stand The Juliet Dagger - Taking it Back Ones and Zeros - Hide Yourself Immigrant - V.I.P. Hello Operator - Take Me Away From the Darkness, Light - Who Told You (inst)Xbox 360 HD Installation The optional installation requires 2.5 GB of hard drive space.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9320">Kawasaki Snowmobiles</game><game id="6147">Ski-Doo X-Team Racing</game><game id="20936">Ferrari Challenge Trofeo Pirelli</game><game id="19890">Sno-Cross Championship Racing</game><game id="26585">Polaris SnoCross</game><game id="27918">Sled Storm</game><game id="41554">Snow Moto Racing</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1820040-box_skidoo.png</image></root>