<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25963</id><name>Age of Pirates 2: City of Abandoned Ships</name><description>ShipsNamePhotoInformationDescriptionTartaneTartaneClass: 7Hitpoints: 90Sail: 100Speed: 7,75Mobility: 46Beydervind: 8.25Cargo hold: 48Crew: 0-5-15Weapon: noneTartan first appeared in the Mediterranean. Originally it was a small fishing boat with triangular sail, but the good handling characteristics have made a very popular ship. It is used for coastal voyages and trade between the closely spaced settlements.BarkasBarkasClass: 7Hitpoints: 225Sail: 100Speed: 13.00Mobility: 65Beydervind: 7.50Cargo hold: 225Crew: 0-2-25Weapon: 12/8Barkas a large boat, which set the small gun. A major ship will never be, but for piracy or smuggling attacks is widely used around the world.LuggerLuggerClass: 6Hitpoints: 600Sail: 100Speed: 16.00Mobility: 62.50Beydervind: 10.45Cargo hold: 550Crew: 0-8-50Weapon: 16/12Lugger small ship designed for the transport of goods and protection of small convoys. Despite the fact that the armed lugger - the weak, and the team - a small, it is specifically designed for trade and for the battles. Many captains appreciate the lugger for his speed and agility. Small size does not allow him to make long sea voyage.SloopSloopClass: 6Hitpoints: 950Sail: 100Speed: 15.25Mobility: 40Beydervind: 8.15Cargo hold: 850Crew: 0-15-80Weapon: 12/16Sloop has a shallow draft and excellent driving characteristics. It is, they are a highly effective intelligence ship, suitable for coastal patrol and trade.BarqueBarqueClass: 5Hitpoints:1500Sail: 100Speed: 8.3Mobility: 22.5Beydervind: 4.5Cargo hold: 1850Crew:0-20-85Weapon: 12/16Bark is a ship that is adapted for long voyages. With a cargo space, and sufficient firepower, bark is considered one of the best ships in its class. However, the large size did not allow him to develop a high speed and to maneuver quickly, so the bark loses driving characteristics lighter ships of its class.SchoonerSchoonerClass: 5Hitpoints: 1250Sail: 100Speed: 12.50Mobility: 35.00Beydervind: 7.5Cargo hold: 1300Crew: 0-30-125Weapon: 16/20Schooner fast merchant vessel with a large cargo hold. Can carry fewer goods than the caravel, but the schooner could easily get away from the big ships of piratesCaravelCaravelClass: 5Hitpoints: 2250Sail: 100Speed: 10.00Mobility: 30.00Beydervind: 5.00Cargo hold: 2750Crew: 0-45-200Weapon: 16/30Caravel ship with a large cargo space capable of carrying large loads over long distances. But it is easy prey for piratesBarkentineBarkentineClass: 5Hitpoints: 3100Sail: 100Speed: 14.50Mobility: 52.00Beydervind: 6.75Cargo hold: 2300Crew: 0-35-155Weapon: 16/16When the Spanish negotiators understood that become easy prey for pirates in the Caribbean, they were massively converted their galleons in the barkentine. Due to the mixed barkentine sailing arms can quickly move in any direction.BrigantineBrigantineClass: 5Hitpoints: 3100Sail: 100Speed: 14.50Mobility: 52.00Beydervind: 6.75Cargo hold: 2300Crew: 0-35-155Weapon: 16/16Brigantine is a legendary type of sailing ships.FleutFleutClass: 4Hitpoints: 3200Sail: 100Speed: 11.50Mobility: 37.50Beydervind: 5.00Cargo hold: 3350Crew: 0-30-175Weapon: 16/18Fleut - ship a solid and large for long voyages, however to use it for military purposes is unreasonable. Flute is good as a commercial vehicle, as the size of the hold and strength of body opponent flute in his class is hard to find.BrigBrigClass: 4Hitpoints: 3000Sail: 100Speed: 15.50Mobility: 50.00Beydervind: 5.75Cargo hold: 2000Crew: 0-35-140Weapon: 16/16Brig is often used as a merchant ship, but more often - as a warship. High speed and maneuverability make it one of the most harmonious ships.GaleonGaleonClass: 4Hitpoints: 4000Sail: 100Speed: 11.00Mobility: 35.00Beydervind: 3.50Cargo hold: 3500Crew: 0-50-350Weapon: 16/20Galleon most famous type of ship in history. A similar relative of the caravel, a galleon - a clumsy and reliable ship, the sailors who served for two hundred years. Easy prey for real pirate.СorvetteСorvetteClass: 3Hitpoints: 3400Sail: 100Speed: 17.50Mobility: 55.00Beydervind: 5.50Cargo hold: 2300Crew: 0-30-300Weapon: 16/32Corvette was designed as ship that has a powerful weapon: but at the same time as a quick and easy. As a consequence, Corvettes have a weak body, but they can overtake the lighter ships and lead a successful battle with the heavier. Typically, the corvette was used as a patrol vessel, as well as support warship.Heavy GalleonHeavy GalleonClass: 3Hitpoints: 5750Sail: 100Speed: 8.25Mobility: 27.50Beydervind: 3.00Cargo hold: 5000Crew: 0-55-425Weapon: 32/36Heavy Galleon - is a powerful warship. The guns of large caliber, a robust housing, and numerous team provide protection for any cargo.PinnacePinnaceClass: 3Hitpoints: 3750Sail: 100Speed: 14.00Mobility: 30.00Beydervind: 6.50Cargo hold: 4500Crew: 0-40-300Weapon: 24/18Pinas, is big enough and strong for long sea voyages, the capacity of its hold can transport a large amount of cargo, and Equipment: hard enough. However, in a fight he really did not have enough agility and speed of this warship.FrigateFrigateClass: 2Hitpoints: 4500Sail: 100Speed: 14.50Mobility: 40.00Beydervind: 4.00Cargo hold: 3000Crew: 0-35-375Weapon: 16/46Fast and maneuverable frigates like so many of its high quality running and firepower. The squadron of frigates could destroy the fort and pillage the city.WarshipWarshipClass: 2Hitpoints: 6100Sail: 100Speed: 12.00Mobility: 31.50Beydervind: 2.00Cargo hold: 4780Crew: 0-50-425Weapon: 32/56Warship, surpassing the number of guns frigate, losing his speed and agility. However, by strengthening the body and increase the size of the ship on some military ships can put the most powerful weapon.BattleshipBattleshipClass: 1Hitpoints: 8000Sail: 100Speed: 13.00Mobility: 33.00Beydervind: 1.25Cargo hold: 6000Crew: 0-100-550Weapon: 32/80Battleship is development of a warship by increasing the size and enhance the body. A huge and unwieldy, it carries a several batteries of heavy guns and maintained a large team.Linear shipLinear shipClass: 1Hitpoints: 7250Sail: 100Speed: 12.00Mobility: 32.50Beydervind: 1.50Cargo hold: 5500Crew: 0-75-600Weapon: 32/66....................................................Linear ship is a formidable force. Armed with the most powerful and long-range guns, with a very strong body, he is able to successfully resist any ship at sea and destroying coastal fortifications.Man-of-WarMan-of-WawClass: 1Hitpoints: 10500Sail: 100Speed: 10.00Mobility: 25.00Beydervind: 1.00Cargo hold: 7500Crew: 0-175-750Weapon: 42/102Man of war is the most powerful of all human-made vessels. At its three decks, he is a hundred heavy guns, and his body is almost impenetrable to the nuclei. Unfortunately, the huge size and displacement limit the use of large naval battles and the bombing of the forts.Brig "Sea Wolf"Brig "Sea Wolf"Class: uniqueBrig 'Sea Wolf' is a piece-work master Alexus, made ​​by order of the Jackman! High speed and maneuverability, a good move in the close-hauled make the brig is great. A nine guns on each side make this boat a dream.Soleil-RoyalSoleil-RoyalClass: uniqueRoyal First Class battleship. Terrifying firepower combined with a refined decoration of body and an impressive driving characteristics. The greatest ship of all time.Xebec "Blue Bird"Xebec "Blue Bird"Class: uniqueXebec is unusual for this region the ship. This xebec 'Blue Bird' has the highest rate. Fully sail skew gives a maximum in the course of close-hauled. This super-maneuverable sailboat. For eight guns on each side and four bow guns make this an ideal xebec in the attack.CorvetteCorvetteClass: uniqueCorvette, the likes of which can not be found. Outstanding work of shipbuilding. Strong body, capable of carrying a large team and a 32-pounder guns, excellent sail, close-hauled course in a magnificent, 16on board, 4 nasal and 4 fodder guns - this is an incomplete list of the advantages of the corvette.Frigate "Arabella"Frigate "Arabella"Class: uniqueFrigate "Arabella" is a former "Cinco Lyagas." That says it all ...Flying DutchmanFlying DutchmanClass: uniqueThe horror of all who go sailing ...</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16331">Sid Meier's Pirates!</game><game id="22771">X3: Terran Conflict</game><game id="2572">X³: Reunion</game><game id="37043">X3: Albion Prelude</game><game id="41179">Caribbean!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14741/959375-4514.jpg</image></root>