<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25985</id><name>F1 2010</name><description>OverviewFormula One 2010 is developed by Codemasters as the their first next-generation multiplatform Formula One release following their acquisition of the license which had previously been held by Sony. Because the game is now multiplatform it is the first F1 game on the Xbox 360; the first truly next generation F1 game on the PS3 (as the previous F1: Championship Edition game was developed on Playstation 2 hardware) and the first officially licensed F1 game on the PC for over a decade. The PC version of F1 2010 will be a Games for Windows Live game.Previously, Codemasters had announced that this game would be released in 2009 as F1 2009, but this was scrapped and F1 2009 was brought out as a Wii and PSP release.On September 27, 2010 it was announced via the Codemasters' forum that a patch was in process of development and would be released soon.EGO EngineFormula One 2010 is developed on Codemasters own EGO Engine, which has powered other Codemasters racing games such as Colin Mcrae: Dirt 1  DiRT 2 , Race Driver: GRID and the Wii version of F1 2009, as well as other Codemasters developed games like Operation Flashpoint: Dragon Rising and Bodycount.The EGO engine has been improved specifically for F1 2010, unofficially dubbed 'EGO 1.5'.Teams and DriversFormula One 2010 includes the real life cars and drivers of the 2010 Formula One season, letting you drive any of the 12 teams cars as any of the 24 drivers of the season. The line up features the following teams and drivers:MclarenJenson Button (2009 Formula One Drivers Champion)Lewis HamiltonMercedes Grand Prix (2009 Formula One Constructors Champion as Brawn GP)Michael SchumacherNico RosbergRed BullSebastien VettelMark WebberFerrariFernando AlonsoFelipe MassaWilliams-CosworthRubens BarrichelloNico HulkenbergRenaultRobert KubicaVitaly PetrovForce IndiaAdrian SutilVitantonio LiuzziToro RossoSebastien BuemiJamie AlguersuariLotus RacingJarno TrulliHeikki KovalainenHispania Racing Team *Karun ChandhokBruno SennaBMW Sauber **Pedro De La RosaKamui KobayashiVirgin RacingTimo GlockLucas Di GrassiNotes:* Sakon Yamamoto and Christian Klien are not availble as drivers for Hispania Racing Team even though Yamamoto has replaced Chandhok and Senna during the 2010 FIA Formula One Championship.** BMW Sauber are actually powered by Ferrari engines and only have the BMW name due to having to take over the old BMW Sauber team name when the team changed ownership at the start of the season. Also Nick Heidfeld is not a driver on the BWM Sauber team even though he replaced De La Rosa during the actual season.CircuitsThe game will feature all 19 circuits that are on the official F1 2010 calendar which are:Bahrain InternationalBahrain International Circuit , Sakhir, BahrainLaps: 49Track Length: 6.2kmAlbert ParkAlbert Park, Melbourne, AustraliaLaps: 58Track Length: 5.3kmSepang InternationalSepang International Circuit, Sepang, MalaysiaLaps: 56Track Length: 5.5kmShanghai InternationalShanghai International Circuit, Shanghai, ChinaLaps: 56Track Length: 5.4kmCircuit de CatalunyaCircuit de Catalunya, Montmelo, SpainLaps: 66Track Length: 4.6kmCircuit de MonacoCircuit de Monaco, Monte Carlo, MonacoLaps: 78Track Length: 3.3kmIstanbul ParkIstanbul Park, Istanbul, TurkeyLaps: 56Track Length: 5.3kmCircuit Gilles VilleneuveCircuit Gilles Villeneuve, Montreal, CanadaLaps: 70Track Length: 4kmValência Street CircuitValencia Street Circuit, Valencia, SpainLaps: 57Track Length: 5.4kmSilverstoneSilverstone Circuit, Silverstone, Great BritainLaps: 52Track Length: 5.8kmHockenheimringHockenheimring, Hockenheim, GermanyLaps: 67Track Length: 4.5kmHungaroringHungaroring, Budapest, HungaryLaps: 70Track Length: 4.3kmSpa-FrancorchampsCircuit de Spa-Francorchamps, Spa-Francorchamps, BelgiumLaps: 44Track Length: 7kmAutodromo di MonzaAutodromo di Monza, Monza, ItalyLaps: 53Track Length: 5.7kmMarina Bay Street CircuitMarina Bay Street Circuit, Singapore (night race)Laps: 61Track Length: 5kmSuzukaSuzuka Circuit, Suzuka, JapanLaps: 53Track Length: 5.8kmKorean InternationalKorean International Circuit, Mokpo, South KoreaLaps: 55Track Length: 5.6kmInterlagosAutodromo Carlos Pace (Interlagos), Sao Paulo, BrazilLaps: 71Track Length: 4.3kmYas MarinaYas Marina Circuit (twilight race), Abu Dhabi, UAELaps: 55Track Length: 5.5kmCareer ModeLike previous Codemasters racing games, Formula One 2010 features a career mode. The career mode is similar to that of GRID, where it's based around the experience of being a race driver. Because of this, the career mode emphasizes the importance of out performing your own team-mates like a real F1 driver, as well as racing for team based targets. Beating your team mates will allow you to become more popular and to be seen as a better driver, thus enabling you to move up to better teams as you progress through the career mode.Formula One 2010 features different career lengths that will affect the start of your career:If you choose to do a 3 season career you can choose to start with one of the top teams (McLaren or Ferrari, for example)If you choose to go for a medium long career (5 seasons), you will have to start with one of the smaller teams, though not the worst ones, and try to work your way up to the bigger teams via meeting team objectivesIf you choose to compete in the 7 seasons long career, you'll be assigned to one of the generally considered worst teams on the paddock, thus not being expected for you to win the championship anytime soon. Instead, and just like on the medium long career mode, you're given modest set goals to achieve, something that your bosses feel you can realistically achieve with the car you're currently driving. Meet or surpass the given goals and you'll be able to transfer to a bigger team, and hopefully reach one of the top ones before the 7 seasons go by.MultiplayerFormula One 2010 features online multiplayer on all three platforms; over Xbox Live on the Xbox 360; Play Station Network on the PS3; and through Games for Windows Live on the PC.Real Time Damage and Dynamic Weather EffectsFormula One 2010 features a more advanced simulation of damage than previous racing games. Similar to Codemasters' own DIRT and GRID; damage is calculated in real time, giving a much more naturalistic look to the cars when they are damaged, as well as in how the car will handle when damaged.F1 2010 also features what Codemasters are claiming as the most advanced weather effects of any racing game to date. Like the damage in F1 2010, Weather is also calculated in real time as well as being dynamic. This leads to a much more realistic simulation of how an F1 car handles in the rain around a circuit. Some of the different weather effects the game is calculating are:'Rain' FilterIn-game example of the rain filterWhen racing in the wet in "F1 2010" a filter is applied to the players camera in order to simulate rain that would be hitting the camera or similar to the rain hitting the drivers visor. This will make driving in the wet much more of a challenge than any other racing game as it will be harder to see the track clearly due to the globules and drops of water that block your vision.Procedural WaterA dry line forming due to the games procedural waterStanding water on the track can be dispersed or 'moved' by the car. An example of this in racing is when a 'dry line' is developed by the constant movement of the cars going around the circuit lap after lap; the tires pushing the water away from the contact point of the rubber tire and tarmac surface. This technology is not only aesthetic, but will also affect the handling of the car is a way that is representative of real life racing.Water CoolingStanding water in the game has the ability to cool off your tires. If you are in a situation where your wet tires are gathering too much heat due to a dry line forming, you can drive off-line in the laying water which will cool down the tires to prevent overheating and grip loss.TriviaFormula One test driver Anthony Davidson was the technical adviser for Codemasters for the development of F1 2010. Anthony is an experienced F1 test driver for Honda and Brawn and has also raced in F1 competitively for a small stint in 2007 for Super Aguri. He has also driven competitively for the Peugeot Sport Team in the 24 Hours of Le Mans and the 12 Hours of Sebring.Official Licensed SoundtrackThe tracklist for the in-game F1 2010 licensed music can be found at the end of the user manual.ArtistSong TitleChase and Status feat. Plan BEnd CreditsDelphicClarion CallGoldhawksRunning AwayIan BrownF.E.A.R. (Uncle Remix)KasabianFireKids In Glass HousesThe Best Is Yet to ComePendulumWatercolourSub Focus feat. CocoSplashThe DatsunsEmperor's New ClothesThe QemistsOn the RunZico ChainAnaemiaPC System RequirementsMinimum RequirementsOperating System: XP / Vista / Windows 7Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo @ 2.4GHz or Athlon X2Memory: 1 GB RAM (2 GB Vista / Windows 7)Hard Disk Space: 12.5 GBGraphics Card: GeForce 7800 / Radeon X1800Sound: DirectX Compatible Sound Card or Motherboard audioDirectX: DirectX 9.0cRecommended RequirementsOperating System: XP / Vista / Windows 7Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo @ 2.66GHz or Athlon 64 X2 Dual Core 4200Memory: 2 GB RAMHard Disk Space: 12.5 GBGraphics Card: GeForce 9800 GT / Radeon HD 4850 or aboveSound: DirectX Compatible Sound Card or Motherboard audioDirectX: DirectX 9.0c or aboveOther Requirements: Online play requires log-in to Games For Windows - Live.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8595">Formula 1</game><game id="29496">Formula 1 '97</game><game id="8792">Formula 1 '98</game><game id="4939">Formula One 99</game><game id="20248">Formula One 2000</game><game id="12773">Formula One 2001</game><game id="11266">Formula One 2002</game><game id="9056">Formula One 2003</game><game id="22194">F1 Career Challenge</game><game id="16884">F1 Championship Season 2000</game><game id="7432">Formula One World Championship: Beyond the Limit</game><game id="2730">Formula One Championship Edition</game><game id="23103">Formula One 2009</game><game id="26638">Michael Andretti's Indy Car Challenge</game><game id="9609">Grand Prix 2</game><game id="14919">Grand Prix Challenge</game><game id="33400">Forza Motorsport 4</game><game id="36993">Project CARS</game><game id="38434">NASCAR The Game: Inside Line</game><game id="27298">rFactor 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2333753-box_f12010.png</image></root>