<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26008</id><name>Front Mission Evolved</name><description>Overview and infoFront Mission Evolved is a third-person shooter and that allows players to control giant battle mechs known as Wanzers. Front Mission Evolved is an addition to the Front Mission Franchise however this time it is being published by a western developer, Double Helix. Notably this game departs from the traditional grid based strategy the series is known for, for a more general 3rd person style shooting experience.The game features a story driven single-player campaign and online multiplayer in an immersive world, state the developers. Like previous installments Double Helix stated that customization will continue to play a part in the core gameplay. The customizability is expanded upon by featuring the option to change ammo shot type such as EMP or Corrosive and additionally hands and shoulder parts will now too be open to swapping around.In a Wanzer, players have to watch out for damage done to their various mech modules as getting them damaged has specific impeding effects, for example damage in the leg parts will impare your movement speed.CustomizabilityThis part specific targetting can also be applied to enemy mechs. This is a standard in the Front Mission franchise.A notable new feature is "Edge mode" which slows the game down and highlights various enemies whilst increasing your damage done. Similar to bullet-time. This "Edge mode" couldn't really be feasable in the previous game due to the turn based nature. However, one can draw a comparison between "Edge mode" and "Battle Skills" or "Links" seen in Front Mission 3 and 4. A special modifier in battles.In Front Mission Evolved there are also moments in game where you find your character interacting with the world outside of a Wanzer mech, such as on foot base exploration (like Front Mission Online) and even combat parts.MultiplayerDomination is one game mode. The jist of domination is teams of Wanzers have to dominate turrets (similar to control points in general multiplayer modes). When a player captures a turret it will shoot the opposing team until it is destroyed.Multiplayer in Front Mission Evolved is an amazing experience because of the variety of wanzers and weapons that you can use to build your wanzer loadout. This variety of options allows you the experiment with many different strategies and battle tactics. And with multiplayer, there is even more depth because you have to consider not only how to best customize your wanzer, but how to create a wanzer that best complements your teammates.- David Varfai | Development blogWanzer customization and Voice chat is supported in multiplayer.Visual and SoundsThe music for Front Mission Evolved comprises of an orchestral score made up of over fifty musicians.As for the visuals of the game, illistrative designer Skan Srisuwan aimed to keep the general design of the mechs similar to the previous installments.Zenith kept its traditional lookI know FRONT MISSION from the pixelated version in FM1 to low polygon look in FM2-3, more polygon FM4-5 in PlayStation 2 graphic and now I have to design the wanzer for next gen console. As a designer and drop-dead fan, I want all the good feelings from 1995 to be carried through to 2010 .... I have to admit that I did not want to change much of the original look or create “something totally new” like Hollywood usually do to many films. My intention in designing all wanzers is to serve a feeling of the good old days for adult fans and to tell the new generation that there’s such a good feeling like this in the old days and it never dies. - Skan Srisuwan | Development blogStoryThe development blog revealed that the joint operation between Double-Helix and Square Enix has allowed the opportunity for Square Enix to have their input on how the story is presented.Story BriefFront Mission Evolved takes place in the year 2171 A.D. after humanity has once again reached the stars. The global powers of the world have began a space race building orbital elevators to seize control of the unconquered space region. The game will take place around a terrorist attack in Manhatten which is apparently linked to this 'cold war' like space feud.EmergenceFront Mission Evolved was teased in a May 2009 issue of the Official Xbox Magazine, keeping the title of the teased game secret, but revealing that Square Enix was creating a new game based off an existing IP involving mechs and that the game's franchise rhymed with "Brunt Fission". On April 30, 2009 an official teaser site went up for the game depicting the same futuristic city-like images displayed in the teaser in OXM, however not actually revealing it's a teaser site for Front Mission Evolved, instead titling the website "NEW GAME".On May 29, the game's official website was launched revealing the title will be a third person shooter being developed by Double Helix Games, to be released on PLAYSTATION 3, Xbox 360, and PC.More information was then shed light via the development blog.TrailersE3 2009 Trailer (05.31.09) - The debut trailer for Front Mission Evolved.TGS 2009 Teaser Trailer (09.23.09) - This trailer shows more CGI Footage and notes "World Wide Release".TGS 2009 Story Trailer (09.23.09)System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Windows XP, Vista, Windows 7Processor: Intel Pentium D 1.8 GHz or AMD Athlon 64 x2 1.8 GHzMemory: 1GB RAM (XP), 2GB RAM (Vista/7)Graphics: 512MB NVIDIA GeForce 7800 series graphics card or equivalentDirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 11 GB Free SpaceSound: DirectX® 9.0c compatible sound cardController Support: Mouse, Keyboard, Xbox 360 ControllerRecommended:OS: Windows XP, Vista, Windows 7Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo 2.4 GHz or AMD Athlon 64 x2 2.4 GHzMemory: 2GB RAM (XP), 3GB RAM (Vista/7)Graphics: 512MB NVIDIA GeForce 8800 series graphics card or betterDirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 11 GB Free SpaceSound: DirectX® 9.0c compatible sound cardController Support: Mouse, Keyboard, Xbox 360 Controller</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10225">Zone of the Enders: The 2nd Runner</game><game id="17675">Armored Core 4</game><game id="22133">Armored Core: for Answer</game><game id="4609">Armored Core 2: Another Age</game><game id="934">MechWarrior 4: Mercenaries</game><game id="13931">MechWarrior</game><game id="1407">MechWarrior 2: 31st Century Combat</game><game id="17438">MechAssault</game><game id="11350">Zone of the Enders</game><game id="16656">Armored Core</game><game id="25601">Mobile Suit Gundam: Battlefield Record U.C.0081</game><game id="34304">Iron Brigade</game><game id="29753">Armored Core V</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2492904-box_fme.png</image></root>