<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2614</id><name>The Dig</name><description>OverviewThe Dig is a science fiction point and click adventure game built on the SCUMM engine, as were other LucasArts adventures of the time such as The Secret of Monkey Island. It gives you what you would expect from an adventure game: items, puzzles, and a story-driven adventure. The story concept was written by Steven Spielberg and was originally planned to be a movie. However, the budget required was quickly deemed too excessive, plus the CG technology of that time was not mature enough to create the asteroid Attila or the many unusual location and creatures. Ultimately, the concept was rolled over into a computer game. Around the time of release, a novelization of the game was also created, penned by veteran science fiction writer Alan Dean Foster.The game suffered a long production time. It started in 1989 and had four different project leaders, Noah Falstein, followed by Brian Moriarty, then Dave Grossman, and finally Sean Clark. The game was finally released in July, 1995, to mixed reception.The Dig went through many different incarnations. At first it was going to be set in the future, with characters crash landing on an unknown planet and having to find a way off it. The game was initially designed to be much more violent, with blood and gore in a lot of scenes. The violence was toned down because LucasArts felt it was too graphic for younger gamers. Some of this violence is kept in the novelization, most notably a detailed scene involving one of the characters' head injury.The game proudly displayed the fact that actor Robert Patrick, antagonist from Terminator 2: Judgment Day, lent his voice for commander Boston Low. The Dig was re-released via Steam on July 8th, 2009 for $4.99.StoryThe Dig has you following commander Boston Low through his mission to save the planet from an asteroid that would destroy Earth. But then he has to save his crew, when they are transported to a faraway planet with only their space suits and a few tools such as a shovel. Commander Low and his crew, reporter Maggie Robbins and scientist Dr. Ludger Brink, must explore the strange planet, dubbed "Cocytus", to find a way home and dig up a few discoveries along the way.ScoreThe Dig's score was composed by Michael Land, who also composed for other LucasArts titles, such as the Monkey Island series. For The Dig's score, he gathered a lot of inspiration from Wagner, using many chords from Wagner's works. The majority of the score was played on a K2000 synthesizer, with other live instruments occasionally mixed in. A full interview with Michael Land, conducted by The Dig Museum, can be found here.Secrets/Easter EggsIf you mouse over Boston (when not in Outer Space) and hit Ctrl B, Boston will flex his muscles.After examining the communicator a few times Boston will say, "It's a T-1000 model," a reference to the fact that the Boston's voice-over work was performed by Robert Patrick, who played the T-1000 in Terminator 2: Judgment Day.In the control room, if you type "SWAN" you will see Boston taking a swim outside the window. This can only be done before completing the "Exploding Alien Turtle" puzzle.In the tomb, on the ground on the left side of the screen, you will find a faint outline of Max the rabbit.The planet the astronauts are marooned on is nicknamed "Cocytus", after the circle of Hell which contained the only exit, by Ludger Brink. However, the dialogue in which he does this was removed from the final game, and it remains nameless throughout. The back of the CD case does retain the text "Greetings from Cocytus", though, and the novelization leaves the dialogue intact.Originally, there were meant to be four astronauts lost on Cocytus, not three. This is still reflected in the cover art for the game's soundtrack. The removed character is Toshi Olema, a Japanese businessman who funded the Atilla project on the condition that he be allowed to go into space with the crew. Olema was meant to die a gruesome death in an also-removed chamber where acid dripped from the ceiling, reflecting the more graphic nature of the game's early design. The unceasing nature of the acid flow would also mean that it would be impossible for the player to resurrect Toshi with Life Crystals, since Low would die if he attempted to get close to Olema's body. It is unknown whether Olema would have been resurrected at the end of the game when the Cocytans were freed from Spacetime Six.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4084">Broken Sword II: The Smoking Mirror</game><game id="17544">Broken Sword: The Shadow of the Templars</game><game id="10915">Beneath a Steel Sky</game><game id="21914">A Vampyre Story</game><game id="2845">Gabriel Knight 3: Blood of the Sacred, Blood of the Damned</game><game id="1353">The Beast Within: A Gabriel Knight Mystery</game><game id="14075">Gabriel Knight: Sins of the Fathers</game><game id="2634">Space Quest 6: Roger Wilco in the Spinal Frontier</game><game id="11508">Space Quest: The Sarien Encounter</game><game id="3633">Indiana Jones and the Fate of Atlantis</game><game id="23532">Nikopol: Secrets of the Immortals</game><game id="22111">The Whispered World</game><game id="23778">Strong Bad's Cool Game for Attractive People Episode 3: Baddest of the Bands</game><game id="21667">Gray Matter</game><game id="2800">The Shivah</game><game id="19852">The Blackwell Legacy</game><game id="20430">Beyond Shadowgate</game><game id="10927">Loom</game><game id="19438">The Orion Conspiracy</game><game id="39355">Primordia</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4938/609591-the_dig_box_front_6570x8280.jpg</image></root>