<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26181</id><name>Red Orchestra 2: Heroes of Stalingrad</name><description>OverviewRed Orchestra 2: Heroes of Stalingrad is a tactical first person shooter and is the sequel to Red Orchestra: Osfront 41-45 . An enhanced version of the Unreal 3 Engine is being used for Red Orchestra 2.GameplayThe gameplay of Red Orchestra: Heroes of Stalingrad is based on that of the original Red Orchestra, but adding several new features and improvements to the original.New features include: A new health and bleeding system, destructible environments, a first person cover system, realistic weapon ballistics, squad command and a suppression system.The game features new game modes in addition to classic ones, and new maps.Persistent stat tracking and leaderboards also included.Gameplay ModesTerritory - The classic game mode from Red Orchestra in which players are either tasked with attacking or defending a set of objectives, new features include a "Lock Down" timer which gives attackers less time to take beginning objectives. When the first objectives are taken the timer opens up to whatever time was remaining instead of adding new time to the clock.Countdown - A one live variant of Territory. Both teams fight over one objective (as opposed to two or three in territory) and only have one life to take it, if attackers are successful the map shifts focus to a new objective and both team re-spawn. If defenders are successful the defenders are successful then the sides flip and attackers now defend and vice versa. In this mode commanders are able to call in reinforcement waves that re-spawn dead players to continue fighting, however the commander only has two waves per match.Firefight (Team Deathmatch) - A simple kill the enemy mode with no class limits.Skirmish - An offline/online mode in which players are tasked with clearing out a map of enemy AI.Co-op - Can play skirmish mode in co-op, against the AI. Can also play the campaign in co-op.The Multiplayer Campaign - A Mode around 4 hours of play time. Players vote on which sector to attack, from within the specific campaign. Losing a sector, results in a loss of 'resources'. It is suggested that less resources, removes the ability to attack certain sectors. A campaign is broken down to ~10 sectors.WeaponsSovietPPSh-41Mosin-NagantScoped Mosin-NagantSVT-40AVT-40DP-28PTRS-41TT-33M1895Pulemyot Maxim M1910GermanMP40MKb 42(H)K98kScoped K98kG41(W)MG-34PzB 784(R)P38C96VehiclesSovietT-34GermanPanzer IVAdditional vehicles will be available as free post-release DLC.MapsGrain Elevator - A recreation of the Grain Elevator in which Soviet troops were held up in and defended well, was important to both sides during the battle.StationFallen FightersSpartanovkaApartmentsCommisar's HouseRed October FactoryPavlov's HouseBarracksGumrakAchievementsThe game has 79 Steam Achievements.SoundtrackThe original score for Red Orchestra 2: Heroes of Stalingrad was composed by Sam Hulick, of Mass Effect fame.System RequirementsMinimumRecommendedOS: Windows XP/Vista/7Processor: Dual Core 2.3 GHz or betterRAM Memory: 2 GBGraphics: 256 MB SM 3.0 DX9 Compliant NVIDIA® GeForce 7800 GTX or better ATI® Radeon® HD 2900 GT or betterDirectX®: DirectX 9.0cHard Drive: 8 GB free hard drive spaceSound: Windows Supported Sound CardOther: Broadband Internet Connection requiredOS: Windows XP/Vista/7Processor: Quad Core 2.6 GHz or betterRAM Memory: 3 GBGraphics: 512 MB SM 3.0 DX9 Compliant NVIDIA® GeForce GTX 260 or better ATI® Radeon® HD 5750 or betterHard Drive: 8 GB free hard drive spaceSound: Sound Blaster Audigy or better</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="24023">Insurgency</game><game id="12716">Battlefield 1942</game><game id="2347">Call of Duty 2</game><game id="1629">Call of Duty</game><game id="38374">Iron Front Liberation 1944</game><game id="31362">Red Orchestra: Rising Storm</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2348980-cover.png</image></root>