<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26390</id><name>Star Wars The Clone Wars: Republic Heroes</name><description>Story This is a brand new story-line neither in the movies or cartoon series. The player follows many characters in the Star Wars universe in an adventure to stop a mysterious techno assassin's evil plot against the republic. It also bridges the gaps between the cartoon series' seasons one and two.  GameplayYou can control as Jedi Knights, clone troopers, and other characters in combat in 40 missions. The game was developed with co-op in mind so the player is always paired with an AI and is never fighting alone. There is also puzzle solving gameplay and an upgrade system based on collecting "force orbs" throughout the different levels.  CharactersThe player can control both characters from the series and new characters introduced just for the game. Some other characters make appearances but are not playable. Playable: Anakin SkywalkerObi-Wan KenobiAhsoka TanoMace WinduKit FistoAayla SecuraLuminara UnduliPlo KoonCaptain RexCommander CodyCommander GreePondsCommander BlyPrivate SwitchSergeant BoomerSergeant Kano Appearance: Count DookuGeneral GrievousAsajj VentressPadme Amidala System Requirements OS: Windows XP or Windows VistaProcessor: Intel P4 3.0GHz AMD XP 3000  or higherMemory: 1GB Ram, 2GB for Windows VistaGraphics: Nvidia 7300 GS or better, ATI X1600 or better* *Requirement of 256MB or more video memoryDirectX®: DirectX 9.0cHard Drive: 8GBSound: 100% DirectX 9.0c compatible audio DeviceController Support: YesOther Requirements: Requires login to Games for Windows - LIVE.</description><genres><genre id="31">Dual-Joystick Shooter</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21023">Star Wars: The Clone Wars - Lightsaber Duels</game><game id="21021">Star Wars: The Clone Wars - Jedi Alliance</game><game id="11120">LEGO Star Wars: The Complete Saga</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5150/1123620-swrh.jpg</image></root>