<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26433</id><name>DoDonPachi Dai Ou Jou Black Label EXTRA</name><description>DoDonPachi Daioujou Black Label Extra is an updated version of Cave's 2002 vertical bullet hell shoot 'em up DoDonPachi Daioujou. 5pb handled the porting and the game was released on February 19, 2009 exclusively for the Xbox 360. Pre-orders for the game also included a guidebook. At the time of release, the game suffered from glitches and long load times. The reason for this was that 5pb had, without permission, used the source code from the highly regarded port of Daioujou for PS2. Cave, Microsoft and 5pb along with significant assistance by Ichirou Mihara who was primarily responsible for the PS2 port collaborated to create a patch addressing some of the issues. The patch which was repeatedly delayed was finally released on January 19, 2011. Modes DoDonPachi Daioujou Arcade - Old Version The original DoDonPachi Daioujou.  DoDonPachi Daioujou Arcade - New Version A rebalanced version of DoDonPachi Daioujou. In this mode, the player can enter the second loop at will.  DoDonPachi Daioujou Black LabelA heavily altered version of DoDonPachi Daioujou. Changes: The player retains his lives when he enters the second loop.The boss patterns in the second loop have been changed.The chain counter has 5 digits rather than 4.DoDonPachi Daioujou X-Mode A beginner mode with new systems and no second loop. A new character named Piper is also available in this mode.  Other Features   A gallery feature which includes concept art for the game is also included.</description><genres><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="30001">Espgaluda II Black Label</game><game id="28233">Progear</game><game id="30997">Ketsui: Kizuna Jigoku Tachi Extra</game><game id="32344">DoDonPachi Resurrection</game><game id="32381">Pink Sweets ~Ibara Sorekara~</game><game id="33885">Muchi Muchi Pork!</game><game id="34237">Ketsui: Kizuna Jigoku Tachi</game><game id="34001">Crimzon Clover</game><game id="34268">Mushihime-sama Futari Black Label</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2291730-box_ddpdojble.png</image></root>