<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26452</id><name>MX vs. ATV: Reflex</name><description>GameplayMX vs. ATV Reflex uses the all new Reflex engine which allows for greater control over the riders movement. As usual, the left analog stick is used to steer, but now, the right analog stick is used to shift the riders weight allowing for more precise jumping and landing. For instance, pulling the right stick back just before a jump and then pushing it forward at the exact moment the bike is leaving the ground enables the rider to jump farther. Then, when about to land the right stick can be used to adjust the way the bike is landing, making it easier to make sharp turns or land tricks effectively. The right stick is also used to do tricks while in the air. When in the air, holding down the trick button and moving the right stick in specific directions will make the rider do tricks such as windmills and back flips.  Another new feature the Reflex engine brings is the ability to make ruts in the ground where you are riding. This gives the terrain the potential to change over the course of many bikes riding in the same spot, and it also allows the player to see where it is the AI controlled riders are riding if they are having trouble with a certain part of the track. More than anything though, the ruts make the game feel and look more realistic than previous entries in the series.  Motocareer MX vs. ATV contains motocross, supercross, omnicross, waypoint, and champion sport racing modes as well as a trick focused mode called freestyle, and a free roam mode.  Every race has three possible medals which are bronze, silver, and gold. MotocrossMotocross is the basic motobike racing in off-road terrain. There are some variations on the simple lap race throughout the motocross series that include 1v1 racing as well as a mode where the player will start in last and have to finish the race in first after a set amount of laps. There are three different motocross series in motocareer: National Series 1 which contains four races, National Series 2 which contains four races, and National Series 3 which contains eight races.  Supercross Supercross is the indoor tighter style racing with sharper turns and jumps which require more precision than the regular motocross races. There are also some variations in the supercross mode other than normal races including an elimination mode in which the racer to finish last at the end of every lap gets eliminated until there is only one racer left. There are three supercross series in motocareer: Supercross Series 1 which contains four races, Supercross Series 2 which contains four races, and Supercross Series 3 which contains eight races.  Omnicross Omnicross is similar to the regular motocross in that it takes place in open outdoor terrain, but is different because any vehicle can be chosen for the races. One of the variation races in omnicross is a type of checkpoint race where the rider that has the fastest times between multiple flag sets. There are three supercross series in motocareer: Omnicross Series 1 which contains four races, Omnicross Series 2 which contains four races, and Omnicross Series 3 which contains eight races.  Waypoint Waypoint races are races that are simply a race to specific points instead of a lap race. There are two basic variations to the waypoint race. The first is a race against others to get to all the points before anyone else, and the second is a race against time in which time is added when crossing a waypoint. There are three supercross series in motocareer: Waypoint Series 1 which contains three races, Waypoint Series 2 which contains three races, and Waypoint Series 3 which contains four races.  Champion Sport Champion Sport is the main series for the larger vehicles except for the last race in every series which is for only MX bikes and ATVs. Basic races are the main mode for champion sport but it also contains some variations of the special races in the other series. There are three champion sport series in motocareer: Champion Sport Track S1 which contains three races, Champion Sport Track S2 which contains three races, and Champion Sport Track S3 which contains six races.  Freestyle Freestyle is the series that focuses entirely on tricks. The tricks you do are rated in four different ways and you then receive an overall score at the end to determine your placement in the series. The four ratings are difficulty, flow, variety, and execution. Difficulty is how deter minded by how many trick combos you can string together and whether those tricks are difficult or easy. Flow is determined by how well you use the entire course. Using all the ramps instead of just one or two is a good way to score the maximum amount of points for each trick. Variety is simply determined by whether or not you repeat the same tricks in a run. Finally, Execution is determined by whether or not you are wrecking, as well as how clean you are landing. Wrecking often and getting shaky landings can greatly hurt an overall score. There are three freestyle series in motocareer: Freestyle Series 1 which contains three events, Freestyle Series 2 which contains three events, and Freestyle Series 3 which contains five events.  Free Ride Free ride open world race series that gives the player a gaint area to explore as well as do specified tasks. There is only one free ride series that contains three events, and in each even there are four different goals to complete. In each area there is a checkpoint race, a target hitting race, a mountain climb, and certain number of flags to collect.  Rides and RidersThere are seven different types of rides in the game and each has many different vehicles to buy and customize. Vehicles and customization options are purchases with money earned from completing races.  MX Lite MX Lite is the slower less powerful MX bike. There are ten MX Lite bikes: Blaze 125sBlaze 250FDakumoto 125Dakumoto 250KTM 125 SXKTM 250 SX-FShima 125RShima 250FTakashi 125RTakashi 250F MXMX is the faster more powerful MX bike. There are ten MX bikes: Blaze 250RBlaze 450FDakumoto 250SDakumoto 450FKTM 250 SXKTM 450 SX-FShima 250RShima 450FTakashi 250RTakashi 450F ATV ATVs are slower than bikes but easier to control and harder to wreck. There are nine ATVs: Blaze 450Burst 450FXDakumoto 400Dakumoto 450KTM 450 SXRaven 450SShima 450Striker 450Takashi 450R UTVUTVs are faster and more powerful than ATVs but significantly slower and weaker than the buggies and trucks. There are twelve UTVs: Black RhinoBlaze Riot650, FadeBlaze Riot650, LinesBlaze Riot650, RainbowBlaze Riot650, TearBlaze Riot650, VividDragon FireRaven CLAW, CamoRaven CLAW, FlameRaven CLAW, FlareRaven CLAW, RainbowRaven CLAW, Stripe  Sport TruckSport trucks are a little bit slower and less powerful than buggies and sport 2 trucks but are very balanced. There are ten sport trucks: Burst 200 CurvesBurst 200, 3ToneBurst 200, ArchBurst 200, ScallopBurst 200, StockDakumoto GTG 200, SwayDakumoto GTG 200, LineDakumoto GTG 200, RainbowDakumoto GTG 200, SplatDakumoto GTG 200, Wave Sport Buggy Sport buggies are fast and easier to steer than sports trucks. There are ten sport buggies: Burst XL 1600, RainbowBurst XL 1600, StepBurst XL 1600, StripeBurst XL 1600, SwirlBurst XL 1600, WaveStriker Impact, AngleStriker Impact, FlameStriker Impact, RainbowStriker Impact, StripeStriker Impact, Tick Sport 2 Truck Sport 2 Trucks are the fastest and most powerful vehicles in the game. There are ten sport 2 trucks: Burst 600, CircleBurst 600, FadeBurst 600, LinesBurst 600, RainbowBurst 600, SwooshDakumoto Spark 4x2, FlamesDakumoto Spark 4x2, HalftoneDakumoto Spark 4x2, RainbowDakumoto Spark 4x2, StripesDakumoto Spark 4x2, Tear RidersOther than the players rider there are five riders in the game: James StewartJeremy McGrathJosh GrantRicky CarmichaelRyan Villopoto</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20957">Pure</game><game id="19001">ATV Offroad Fury 2</game><game id="19032">ATV Offroad Fury</game><game id="22064">ATV Offroad Fury 3</game><game id="24793">MotorStorm</game><game id="20451">MotorStorm: Pacific Rift</game><game id="25424">MotorStorm: Arctic Edge</game><game id="30986">Nail'd</game><game id="35577">MotionSports Adrenaline</game><game id="37323">Insane 2</game><game id="37598">MUD: FIM Motocross World Championship</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2210192-box_mxvsatvr.png</image></root>