<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26492</id><name>0 Story</name><description>How our friendly protagonist winds up as a stalker love ghost.0 Story (or Love Story) is an  adventure            full motion video based game developed by           General Entertainment and published by           Enix, released exclusively in         Japan on April 27, 2000. It was the first Enix game published on the           PlayStation 2 and, in conjunction with           Sony, was used extensively to promote the release of the console in Japan .Plot SummaryContrary to the title of the game, 0 Story does in fact have a story. The player takes the role of a recently deceased           man killed in a           motorcycle  accident. He is sent back to           Earth by the           Angel of           Love who tells him that he will be resurrected if he gains the love of a woman named Lina within six short days. Keep in mind that this game was created in Japan. Gameplay 0 Story is different from most games, in that it was based around the idea that the game plays like an           interactive movie, shown to the player through continuous        full motion videos. The player can make various actions at specific moments which result in slightly different paths and scenes, although the direction of the story remains basically the same. It's like a Choose Your Own Adventure book, just that it's a video game...and you can't lose! Other things do occur, such as events similar to           quick time events, which were considered unique at the  time. In conjunction with this, the player can also shoot "love           arrows" (imagine  Cupid, just           dead and  Japanese) which nudge Lina into doing various actions which help you in your ultimate goal of her falling in love with you. Godforsaken        mini-games are also present in 0 Story, including the much-adored  rhythm-based games, which were also considered unique back in the day. All of these games and actions contribute, based upon the outcome of each event, positively or  negatively on the "Love Meter". If the Love Meter reaches 100% by the sixth day, the player wins the game...and Lina's heart! How adorable! DevelopmentIn late August of 1999, Kouichi Hasegawa announced publicly that a number of titles were in development for the, at the time, unreleased      Playstation 2.  0 Story was showcased in February 2000 at the   PlayStation Festival in           Tokyo, as part of Sony's campaign to promote the  soon-to-be-released PlayStation 2. As this was     Enix's second attempt at making a decent    FMV-based game, the cast recruited for 0 Story includes Japanese actresses,           television personalities, and models. A           game demo was given to video game          journalists a month before the game was to be released. The game was also showcased a second time at the           Tokyo Game Show, where it was one of the most visited Enix attraction's after           Dragon Quest VII. </description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25932">12Riven: The Psi-Climinal of Integral</game><game id="26491">7 Blades</game><game id="3915">Ace Lightning</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5434/1029688-cover_art.jpg</image></root>