<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>265</id><name>CSI: Crime Scene Investigation - Hard Evidence</name><description>OverviewAs in all the previous CSI games, the player has five cases to lay his hands on and investigate. The goal of each case, of course, is to find the culprit and discover the truth as led by the evidence. To solve the case, the player has a handful of crime scene investigation tools (i.e. rubber gloves to collect basic, big pieces of evidence, tweezers for bullets found in walls from gun fights and fingerprint powder for, if you haven't already figured it out, collecting fingerprints.) at his disposal. If the player gets somehow stuck in a case, there's always going to be the partner to come and ask for some advice. Each case the player gets a new partner, eventually getting to see and ''work'' with every main character from CSI: Vegas. At the end of each case, the player gets an evaluation score based on how well he's collected and followed evidence and if the player has asked any advice to his partner.The voice acting is done by the show's original cast with exceptions of Catherine's and Sara's characters who are voiced by Edie Mirman and Kate Savage respectively.CSI CrewFor each case you undertake you'll be backed up by another CSI member who will help you asses the crime scenes, interview witness, and offer their insights into the evidence. These CSI staff members are:Gil GrissomGil Grissom, the head of the LVPD CSI graveyard shift. He'll pop in from time to time in order to check up on your progress on the current case. He often has valuable, though sometimes cryptic, advice to offer and usually provides you with an alternative way to look at the situation or evidence.Catherine WillowsCatherine Willows, a Level 3 CSI and sometimes Acting Shift Supervisor. She also stops in from time to time to offer sound advice, though you'll be working with her on a specific case this time.Nick StokesNick Stokes, a level 3 CSI for the LVPD, originally from Dallas. He is your first partner when you arrive as a new CSI and works with you to put away a murdering arsonist.Sara SidleSara Sidle, one of the newer team members, this time around she helps out more from headquarters rather than partnering directly with you on a case.Warrick BrownWarrick Brown, a level 3 CSI from Vegas. He partners with you on your third case.Greg SandersGreg Sanders, a junior member of the CSI team. After proving your abilities, he "shadows" you on the fourth case.Captain Jim BrassCaptain Jim Brass is the police front man for all your investigations. Anything legal you need taken care of or any legwork you need, he'll make happen. From obtaining warrants to having his men enact searches for missing evidence, you just ask and he'll make it happen.Dr. Al RobbinsDr. Al Robbins, the Chief Medical Examiner for the LVPD. He will perform all autopsies on your victims as well as provide you with any specific medical information you might need relative to your victim.Tools and EquipmentThis time around you have a number of tools and equipment at your disposal for combing crime scenes and then properly processing and analyzing the evidence.System RequirementsOS: Windows 2000 / XP / Vista (only)Processor: 2 GHz processor or better (3.0 GHz Pentium 4 or equivalent recommended)Memory: 512 MB (1 GB recommended)Graphics: 64 MB DirectX 8.1-compliant video card (128 MB recommended) (see supported list*)DirectX®: DirectX 8.1 or higher (included)Hard Drive: 2.3 GB freeSound: DirectX 8.1-compliant sound cardSupported Video Cards:- NVIDIA GeForce 2 / 3 / 4 / FX / 6 / 7 / 8 families- ATI Radeon 9000 / X families- Laptop versions of these cards are not fully supported.Xbox 360 Game InstallationCSI: Hard Evidence requires 3.4GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6049">Sam &amp; Max Save the World</game><game id="5804">Broken Sword: The Sleeping Dragon</game><game id="4084">Broken Sword II: The Smoking Mirror</game><game id="3141">Still Life</game><game id="25685">Miami Law</game><game id="26608">Case Closed: The Mirapolis Investigation</game><game id="29347">Casebook</game><game id="36434">NCIS</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2285638-box_csihe.png</image></root>