<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26539</id><name>The Lord of the Rings: Aragorn's Quest</name><description>StoryAfter the War for the Ring,  Aragorn returns to the  Shire to visit the  Hobbit's and pay visit to his friends after many years without seeing them. Aragorn tells stories of his valiant battles to to the  Shire as well as his time as a Strider. You will play as  Aragorn reliving his most memorable battles from all three of the major books/films. You must help defend  middle-earth from  Sauron's evil forces using any sort of weapons that become available to you. A level up system is present which allows you to upgrade you abilities to suit your play style. Not only that, a Morale system is present in which Morale is generated when you deal damage to your foes. GameplayCombat is much like other modern Action-Adventure games. When wielding his  sword,  Aragorn has a quick attack and a power attack which can be stringed together to perform combos. He can also block, which if timed correctly will stun the enemy.  Aragorn also wields a bow which can be charged up by holding down the button.  Special attacks are granted on level up and consume Morale, which is generated when dealing damage. These abilities include a speed boost, a fire arrow, and a lunging sword attack. Aragorn has 6 slots for equipment, including his  sword and  bow. Each piece of equipment has three basic stats:  Sword (increases sword damage),  Bow (increases bow damage), and Defense (decreases damage taken). A piece of equipment may also have a fourth bonus such as increasing Morale.  DevelopmentAragorn's Quest was first announced when Entertainment Software Association leaked the list of games that were going to be shown at  E3. The game was then officially announced on May 28, 2009 in a press release made by  Warner Bros Interactive. It's the first title in it's franchise, this is because  Warner Bros Interactive just recently obtained the licence for "Lord of the Rings" games after  EA owning it for years.  The press release stated that the game would be available for Wii, Playstation 2, Nintendo DS and the PSP and would be released around Q3/Q4 of 2009. Later on in the year, the publishers announced that the game will have to be delayed until Q1/Q2 of 2010. Several months after and still no release, on March 10, 2010 the publishers then announced it would be available on the Playstation 3 and would include full  Playstation Move compatibility, further pushing the release back until Q3/Q4 for all platforms.</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="32416">DeathSpank: Thongs of Virtue</game><game id="6447">The Lord of the Rings: The Battle for Middle-earth II - The Rise of the Witch-King</game><game id="22997">The Lord of the Rings Online: Mines of Moria</game><game id="17686">The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King</game><game id="4867">The Lord of the Rings: The Battle for Middle-earth II</game><game id="4157">The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring</game><game id="8643">J.R.R. Tolkien's The Lord of the Rings, Vol. I</game><game id="28357">The Lord of the Rings Online: The Siege of Mirkwood</game><game id="21334">The Lord of the Rings: The Two Towers</game><game id="20965">The Lord of the Rings: Conquest</game><game id="7701">The Lord of the Rings: The Battle for Middle-earth</game><game id="23201">The Lord of the Rings: The White Council</game><game id="15954">J.R.R. Tolkien's The Lord of the Rings, Vol. II: The Two Towers</game><game id="12376">The Lord of the Rings Online: Shadows of Angmar</game><game id="17677">The Lord of the Rings: War of the Ring</game><game id="30767">The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring</game><game id="5219">The Lord of the Rings: Tactics</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2276086-box_tlotraq.png</image></root>