<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26563</id><name>Magic Johnson's Super Slam Dunk</name><description>GameplayScoringMagic Johnson's Super Slam dunk is a basic basketball game. Magic Johnson himself appears before every game and gives commentary as to which team has the advantage and why. The game has all the teams from the NBA at the time, but no NBA liscence. Therefore, there are no team logos and the teams are only referenced by the city name. The last names of the players for the actual NBA teams are used as well.Game StatsThe game primarily uses an isometric viewpoint. During the face-off the view is from the side of the court, and after the face-off the camera moves around to face the net. When the other team gains possesion and moves the ball out of their zone, the camera moves around again so as to face the other net. Basic statisitcs are tracked during the game and since player names are used you know who scored the most over the course of the game.Game ModesIntense Playoff ActionIn Super Slam Dunk there is no option to play an entire season, only a single exhibition game or a playoff showdown. In the playoffs, there are 8 teams. You start by choosing a team and playing against the rival. Whether you win or loose, you next pick another team to play from in one of the other matchups. You continue to do this through the quater finals, semi-finals and final. This means there is a strange system where you can be playing as one team in the quater-final, only to turn around and choose to play against that team in the semi-final. There is no best of 7 series, only single games are played. A password system is used to save your progress.Game OptionsGame OptionsSuper Slam Dunk has relatively sparse options. The game can be played 1 player, 2 player, or autoplay, where the computer plays itself. The period length can be set to 2, 5, 8, or 12 minutes. Finally, fouls and the music can be turned on or off.</description><genres><genre id="22">Basketball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16685">Jordan vs. Bird: One-on-One</game><game id="1725">Magic Johnson's Fast Break</game><game id="38745">Super Dunk Star</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/931/1032818-9721.jpg</image></root>