<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26611</id><name>Tournament of Legends</name><description>Tournament of Legends has you play as characters of Roman mythology, in a mostly standard fighting game. The gameplay has been described as a cross between the Soul Calibur and the Fight Night Franchises.Players use the Wiimote and the Nunchuk to initiate the attacks, and will let players use Wii motion plus to add varying attacks.Each fighter in Tournament of Legends features a unique weapon (which other characters can later take to copy their fighting styles) and different narratives depending on choices players make as they progress through the game. Other creatures will be unlocked as you play through the game.The game features offline split screen multiplayer, with no online multiplayer.CharactersMarcus "Hero of Rome"MarcusSpecialsRain of Arrows (Up  A) -1 EnergyDinner Time! (Right  A) -2 EnergyGotcha! (Left  A) -1 EnergyWeight Class; RuggedMovement; StandardStrength; MediumEnergy Gain; AverageJupiter "King of the Gods"JupiterSpecialsJupiter's Lightning (Up  A) -1 EnergyJupiter's Storm (Right  A) -2 EnergyJupiter's Thunder (Left  A) -1 EnergyWeight Class; MassiveMovement; SlowStrength; StrongEnergy Gain; LowKara "She Who is Born of Battle"KaraSpecialsThor's Fury (Up  A) -1 EnergySky Strike (Right  A) -1 EnergyTempest (Left  A) -1 EnergyWeight Class; LitheMovement; FastStrength; WeakEnergy Gain; HighAkki  Goryo "Slave and Master"Akki  GoryoSpecialsDark Portal (Up  A) -1 EnergyDemon's Blood (Right  A) -1 EnergySucker! (Left  A) -1 EnergyWeight Class; RuggedMovement; StandardStrength; MediumEnergy Gain; AverageBravehoof "Defender of Nature"BravehoofSpecialsRampage (Up  A) -1 EnergyNature's Spear (Right  A) -1 EnergyBerserk (Left  A) -1 EnergyWeight Class; MassiveMovement; SlowStrength; StrongEnergy Gain; LowBast "Eye of Ra"BastSpecialsNine Lives (Up  A) -1 EnergyInferno (Right  A) -1 EnergySolar Strike (Left  A) -2 EnergyWeight Class; LitheMovement; FastStrength; WeakEnergy Gain; HighVolcanus "The Astounding Bronze Automaton"VolcanusSpecialsClockwork Missiles (Up  A) -1 EnergyField Repair (Right  A) -1 EnergyPiston Punch (Left  A) -2 EnergyWeight Class; MassiveMovement; SlowStrength; StrongEnergy Gain; LowNarcia "Accursed Gorgon"SpecialsPetrify (Up  A) -2 EnergySnake Swarm (Right  A) -2 EnergyVenom (Left  A) -1 EnergyWeight Class; LitheMovement; FastStrength; WeakEnergy Gain; HighDevelopmentOriginally Tournament of Legends went under the name Gladiator A.D. and was going to be a mature rated gladiatorial combat game designed to use the Wii MotionPlus exclusively. Due to publisher concerns about the potential audience for the title, the gladiator characters were redesigned to be based off mythological beings like Valkyries and minotaurs. The gameplay was scaled back to allow support for Classic Controller and the standard Wii remote, while the game does allow for Wii MotionPlus support, it is not 1:1. The game was released at a budget price of US$29.99 ("A Legendary Value"). Tournament of Legends uses an updated version of the Quantum3 engine. The same engine used in The Conduit.</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6399">Bushido Blade</game><game id="20452">Fight Night Round 4</game><game id="12411">Soulcalibur</game><game id="29790">Deadliest Warrior: The Game</game><game id="11822">Soulcalibur II</game><game id="31127">Swords</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1871444-box_tol.png</image></root>