<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26622</id><name>Bust-A-Move Plus!</name><description>GameplayThe objective of the game is to remove all the bubbles off a stage. Do not let the bubbles go underneath the line. Types of BubblesHurry up! Shoot it!Normal Bubbles: There are no special qualities on what these bubbles can do. Just pop 3 or more bubbles of the same color to free the characters that are inside. Star Bubbles: Shoot this special star bubble at a normal bubble to cause all the bubbles that are alike in color to pop! However, if you shoot it at another star bubble, it will have no effect whatsoever. Don't shoot it that way!Rainbow Bubbles: If you happen to pop a normal bubble that is touching a rainbow bubble, the rainbow bubble will turn into the color of the bubble that just popped. However, if you shoot it at another rainbow bubble, you will not get any results. Metal Bubbles: This very special and mighty bubble eliminates any bubbles that are in its way. Sadly, it pops when it touches ceilings and blocks. Fire Bubbles: This bubble explodes when it comes in range of a normal bubble, which also destroys everything surrounding it. Types of Blocks You think you can pop them all?Hinder Blocks: These blocks are a nuisance because they can be wedged in between other bubbles, and the way to free of them is by simply making them drop. The good thing though is that you don’t have to clear all the hinder blocks to clear a stage. These bubbles will just drop and the stage will not end if touches beneath the line. Support Blocks: These are the blocks that grasp bubbles, and the only way to get rid of them is to eliminate all the bubbles surrounding it. If the support block touches beneath the line, the stage will end.  Downloadable Content There are 2 additional level packs containing 135 classic levels each. Each pack costs 200 Nintendo Points, and takes 1 block of memory. One of the packs includes stages from the 1995's    Bust-A-Move 2, and the other pack has selected levels from   Bust-A-Move 3 and    Super Bust-A-Move.</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25945">Bubble Bobble Neo!</game><game id="14228">Bust-A-Move</game><game id="1263">Bust-A-Move 4</game><game id="7091">Bust-a-Move DS</game><game id="13468">Bust-A-Move Millennium</game><game id="19017">Super Bust-A-Move</game><game id="4484">Bust-A-Move '99</game><game id="18594">Bust-A-Move 2</game><game id="8208">Bust-A-Move 3 DX</game><game id="16739">Bust-a-Move Deluxe</game><game id="28037">QuantZ</game><game id="7395">Pokémon Trozei!</game><game id="19154">Pokémon Pinball</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/28533/1076221-_jap__cover.jpg</image></root>