<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26641</id><name>Ultima Online: Stygian Abyss</name><description>New Playable Race: Gargoyles Players may now create gargoyle characters as members of the Gargoyle Race.  Gargoyles are unable to ride mounts.  Some locations in Ter Mur   and the Stygian Abyss Dungeon  are only reachable via flight.  When flying, gargoyles move at mounted speed.   Gargoyles cannot wear Leather/Plate/Chain/Studded armor, only new Gargoyle Armors.  Gargoyles cannot equip most weapons (War Fork, Katana, Staff, etc.)  Gargoyles cannot learn Archery or use bows.   Gargoyles instead use the long-ranged skill Throwing.          Berserk - In situations of great danger, a Gargoyle's natural ferocity will take over, granting speed and power at the cost of defenses.                    Master Artisan - A strong cultural emphasis on art and craftsmanship grants the Gargoyles an increased chance to imbue, enhance, and unravel magical items.                    Deadly Aim - All Gargoyles are trained from childhood in the skill of Throwing, giving them a basic competence with missile weapons.                    Mystic Insight - Gargoyles have an intuitive understanding of Mysticism, allowing them to cast basic Mysticism spells without further training.     New Game Client   Stygian Abyss Client  Redesigned and improved isometric 3D client built upon the Kingdom Reborn  client's tech, with a combination of KR and the old classic 2D graphics.      New Skills Imbuing - A new crafting skill that allows players to manage the properties added on a crafted weapon or armor piece. This will also include the ability to harvest magical properties from existing items.  Mysticism - A Gargoyle form of spell casting complete with it's own set of spells. First Circle- Nether Bolt - Fires a bolt of nether energy at the Target, dealing chaos damage.- Healing Stone - Conjures a Healing Stone that will instantly heal the Caster when used. Second Circle- Purge Magic - Attempts to remove a beneficial ward from the Target, chosen randomly.- Enchant - Temporarily enchants a weapon with a hit spell effect chosen by the Caster. Third Circle - Sleep - Puts the Target into a temporary Sleep state. In this state, a Slept Target will be unable to attack or cast spells, and will move at a much slower speed. -  Eagle Strike - Conjures a magical eagle that assaults the Target with its talons, dealing energy damage. Fourth Circle-  Animated Weapon - Conjures and animates a weapon that selects a Target to attack based off its combat strength and proximity.-  Stone Form - Infuses the Caster with the essence of solid stone, giving a bonus to physical attacks and damage resistance, but reducing the Caster's movement, spell casting, and attack speed.Fifth Circle-  Spell Trigger - Allows the Caster to store a Mysticism spell in a Spell Stone. When the Caster uses the Spell Stone, the stored spell is instantly cast.-  Mass Sleep - Puts one or more Targets within a radius around the Target's Location into a temporary Sleep state.  Sixth Circle-  Cleansing Winds - Soothing winds attempt to neutralize poisons, lift curses, and heal a valid Target.-  Bombard - Hurls a magical boulder at the Target, dealing physical damage.   Seventh Circle-  Spell Plague - Inflicts a terrible curse on one or more Targets in its area of effect. Each time a Spell Plagued Target hits with a harmful attack or spell, the Target may suffer a backlash of fire damage.-  Hail Storm - Summons a storm of hailstones that strikes all Targets within a radius around the Target's Location, dealing cold damage.  Eighth Circle-  Nether Cyclone - Summons a gale of lethal winds that strikes all Targets within a radius around the Target's Location, dealing chaos damage. In addition to inflicting damage, each Target of the Nether Cyclone temporarily loses a percentage of mana and stamina.-  Rising Colossus - Summons a colossal stone titan that selects a Target to attack based off its intelligence and proximity.   Throwing  - A new ranged weapon skill utilizing throwing weapons and consumes no ammunition. Can only be learned by Gargoyles. There are 3 throwing weapons: Boomerang, Cyclone and Soul Glaive.  New Features  Basket Weaving  - A new sub-skill that allows tinkers to create colored baskets.  Staining  - A new system that allows gardeners, cooks  and alchemists  to turn player-grown plants into special dyes.  Custom Carpets  - Complete a quest to gain access to a carpet vendor.  Battle Chicken Breeding  - Raise the perfect chicken and send them into battle.  Snake Charming  - Using specially made instruments, command serpents to do your bidding.  Pet Resurrection  Changes - NPC's can now raise dead pets for a fee.  Scroll Binder  - Combine power, stat and transcendence scrolls into more powerful ones.  Gargoyle Architecture - Nine new housing tile sets showing off the style of Gargoyles.     41 New Creature Types </description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4791">Vanguard: Saga of Heroes</game><game id="545">Asheron's Call</game><game id="13869">Istaria: Chronicles of the Gifted</game><game id="24336">Fiesta</game><game id="27896">World of Warcraft: Cataclysm</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9261/1119834-stygian.png</image></root>