<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26657</id><name>Sonic &amp; Sega All-Stars Racing</name><description>OverviewSonic  Sega All-Stars Racing is a kart racing game featuring several characters from Sega's library of games. Released on February 23, 2010, this is the second game from Sumo Digital Ltd. to feature Sega characters in a sports game, the first being Sega Superstars Tennis. It supports up to four players offline, up to eight online on the console versions, and six on the Nintendo DS version. The PC version is not online-enabled.In 2011, Sega produced an arcade version of the title, featuring only 13 playable characters and 13 tracks. Game modes include Grand Prix, Single Races and Time Trials. Up to eight cabinets can be linked together for multiplayer modes. Optional kits can be added onto cabinets for ticket redemption for at least 5 tickets for players finishing first in races multiplied by human players who are playing the game. Cabinets run on Sega's Ringwire hardware, which produces a graphical fidelity resembling the lower definitions of the game such as the Wii version and PC version's low graphic definition mode.On April 30th 2012, Sega announced a sequel for the game called Sonic and All-Stars Racing Transformed, which was released on November 16th later that year.GameplayDr. Eggman racing on Whale Lagoon.Playing strongly similar to the Mario Kart series of Nintendo fame, the game has eight different racers driving around a track for 3 to 5 laps. Each track is laid out with various sharp turns, jumps, and shortcuts. When taking on a sharp turn, the player may drift by pressing and holding the Drift button as they turn. While holding the Drift button, the player may also rapidly press the Accelerate button to make their turn even sharper. As the player drifts, they will build up a turbo-boost which will give the player a small burst of speed when they let go of the Drift button. The longer the player drifts, the longer the boost will be, with there being three levels of turbo-boost. If you bump into anything while drifting, you will lose any turbo-boost accumulated from that drift. Pressing the Drift button in mid-air after launching from a jump will have your character perform a trick from their kart. Successfully finishing the trick will result in a turbo-boost upon landing. Much like drifting, you may perform up three tricks to build up to three levels of turbo-boost, with each character having different tricks, some will be able to perform theirs faster than others, with those who have longer tricks are given longer boosts as opposed to those with shorter tricks. If the player lands in the middle of performing a trick, no turbo-boost is given, though they retain the speed they were driving at.NiGHTS as the referee of the game, waving the checkered flag to start and end the race.Also strewn about the track are a multitude of item bubbles, turbo pads, and obstacles, all for the racers to use to their advantage. Item bubbles give the racer one of 11 random items to use from. Depending on what place you're in will also alter the odds of which item you will receive. For example, a racer in seventh place is more likely to receive a Giant Rocket or an All-Star, while a racer in first place is more likely to receive a Mine or a K.O. Glove. Driving over a turbo pad will give you a short burst of speed. Driving into an obstacle will cause your racer to spin out and slow down greatly. If you are in the middle of a speed boost, you may drive into certain obstacles with no consequence.Racing Commentator/Announcer (Consoles Only)All throughout the races in the console versions, there is a racing commentator that gives running commentary, where he talks about the current track information, counts down to the start of the race, talks about a racer's certain position, announces which lap it is, tells the racers when someone has received and initiated an All-Star Move, and announces the winner. This feature can be turned off in the settings menu. The only version that doesn't have the commentator feature is the DS version.CharactersThere are currently 24 characters in all, some being exclusive to certain platforms. Each character has their own unique vehicle and special weapon known as their "All-Star Move." As of April 1, 2010, more characters has been added only available through purchased downloadable content.All the playable characters, excluding the console exclusive characters.Sonic the HedgehogOrigin: Sonic the HedgehogVehicle: Speed StarAll-Star Move: Super SonicMiles "Tails" ProwerOrigin: Sonic the Hedgehog 2Vehicle: Tornado RacerAll-Star Move: Tails TornadoKnuckles the EchidnaOrigin: Sonic the Hedgehog 3Vehicle: Land BreakerAll-Star Move: Emerald PowerDr. Ivo "Eggman" RobotnikOrigin: Sonic the HedgehogVehicle: Egg MonsterAll-Star Move: Missle MadnessAmy RoseOrigin: Sonic CDVehicle: Pink CabrioletAll-Star Move: Piko HammerShadow the HedgehogOrigin: Sonic Adventure 2Vehicle: Dark RiderAll-Star Move: Super ShadowBig the CatOrigin: Sonic AdventureVehicle: Green HopperAll-Star Move: Giant FroggyAiAiOrigin: Super Monkey BallVehicle: Blazing BananaAll-Star Move: Super Monkey RollAmigoOrigin: Samba de AmigoVehicle: Sun BuggyAll-Star Move: Samba de PartyRyo HazukiOrigin: ShenmueVehicle: Naoyuki's MotorcycleAll-Star Move: Working ManBeatOrigin: Jet Set RadioVehicle: De La Custom GGsAll-Star Move: Tag JammingAlex KiddOrigin: Alex Kidd in Miracle WorldVehicle: Sukopako MotorcycleAll-Star Move: PeticopterBilly HatcherOrigin: Billy Hatcher and the Giant EggVehicle: Racing RoosterAll-Star Move: Egg RodeoZobio  ZobikoOrigin: The House of the Dead EXVehicle: Hotrod of HorrorAll-Star Move: Run-a-Way LoveUlalaOrigin: Space Channel 5Vehicle: Astro GliderAll-Star Move: Tension BlastJacky Bryant  Akira YukiOrigin: Virtua FighterVehicle: Red LightningAll-Star Move: Virtua FightB.D. JoeOrigin: Crazy TaxiVehicle: Crazy TaxiAll-Star Move: Crazy BoostMobo  RoboOrigin: Bonanza Bros.Vehicle: Get-a-Way WagonAll-Star Move: Blimp StrikeOpa-OpaOrigin: Fantasy ZoneVehicle: Opa-OpaAll-Star Move: Fantasy ThornChuih, ChuBei, ChuPea,  ChuBachOrigin: ChuChu Rocket!Vehicle: ChuChu RocketAll-Star Move: Cat-WalkerBanjo  KazooieOrigin: Banjo-KazooieVehicle: Bolt BucketAll-Star Move: Jiggy RainNote: This racer is exclusive to the Xbox 360 version.AvatarOrigin: Xbox LiveVehicle: Ava-Car 720All-Star Move: Party PowerNote: This racer is exclusive to the Xbox 360 version.MiiOrigin: Nintendo WiiVehicle: Super ZoomerAll-Star Move: Parade PowerNote: This racer is exclusive to the Wii version.Ryo-FOrigin: ShenmueVehicle: ForkliftAll-Star Move: Working ManNote: This racer is exclusive to the PS3 and 360 versions through DLC.Metal SonicOrigin: Sonic CDVehicle: Metal BoosterAll-Star Move: Maximum OverdriveNote: This racer is exclusive to the PS3 and 360 versions through DLC.TracksWhale LagoonAll tracks originate from various levels of classic Sega games.Sonic the HedgehogSeaside HillWhale LagoonLost PalaceOcean RuinCasino ParkRoulette RoadPinball HighwayBingo PartyFinal FortressTurbine LoopDark ArsenalThunder DeckDeath Egg Zone*Egg Hangar*Billy Hatcher and the Giant EggBlizzard CastleIcicle ValleyRampart RoadDino MountainLava LairSamba De AmigoCarnival TownSunshine TourJump ParadeRocky-CoasterStudio Amigo***Sun Fair***Jet Set Radio FutureTokyo-ToShibuya DowntownRokkaku HillHighway ZeroCurien Mansion**Curien MansionOuter ForestSewer ScrapesDeadly RouteSuper Monkey BallJumble JungleTreetopsDetritus DesertSandy DriftsPirates OceanMonkey Target*These tracks are exclusive to the PS3 and 360 versions through DLC.**These tracks are all based on the House of the Dead franchise, but are labeled as "Curien Mansion".***These tracks are exclusive to the DS and mobile versions of the game.Arena TracksIn addition to the race tracks, there are additional arena tracks made for the split-screen multiplayer mode.House of the Dead/Curien MansionGrave HardSuper Monkey BallRumble RampsSonic the HedgehogSeaside SquareMusic ListEach track theme features music that is played during gameplay. Unlocking songs from the SEGA Store gives you more track to choose from.Sonic the HedgehogSeaside HillSeaside Hill [Sonic Heroes]Palmtree Panic (Present) [Sonic CD]Can You Feel the Sunshine? [Sonic R]A New Day [Sonic Rush]Windy and Ripply [Sonic Adventure]Casino ParkCasino Park [Sonic Heroes]Back 2 Back [Sonic Rush]Bingo Highway [Sonic Heroes]Super Sonic Racing [Sonic R]Be Cool, Be Wild and Be Groovy [Sonic Adventure]Final FortressFinal Fortress [Sonic Heroes]Metal Scratchin' [Sonic Rush]What U Need [Sonic Rush]Crank the Heat Up!! [Sonic Adventure]E.G.G.M.A.N. (Insturmental) [Sonic Adventure 2]Death Egg ZoneCosmic Fall - [Shadow the Hedgehog]General Offensive - [Sonic Adventure]Never Let it Go - [Sonic the Fighters]Egg Fleet - [Sonic Heroes]Space Gadget [Shadow the Hedgehog]Billy Hatcher and the Giant EggTumbling XylophoneBossa Nova of Briny AirJack-in-the-Box!Volcanic OrchestraBilly's CourageSamba De AmigoSamba De Janeiro [Samba De Amigo]CarnivalBum BumVamos a Carnaval [Samba De Amigo ver. 2000]Mambo De Verano [Samba De Amigo ver. 2000]Party Time*Super Samba*Super Monkey BallMonkey Island [Super Monkey Ball - Banana Blitz]Party Game 1 [Super Monkey Ball - Banana Blitz]Party Game 2 [Super Monkey Ball - Banana Blitz]Ultra Heaven [Super Monkey Ball - Banana Blitz]Monkey Race [Super Monkey Ball]House of the Dead/Curien MansionHope With Doubt [House of the Dead 4]Into the Dark [House of the Dead]Aura of Dread [House of the Dead]Theme of the Magician [House of the Dead 2]Restoration of Terror [House of the Dead 4]Jet Set Radio FutureThe Concept of Love [Jet Set Radio Future]Sneakman (Toronto Mix) [Jet Set Radio Future]Funky Dealer [Jet Set Radio Future]Let Mom Sleep (No Sleep Remix) [Jet Set Radio Future]Fly Like a Butterfly [Jet Set Radio Future]*These music tracks are available in gameplay only on the Nintendo DS version.Split Screen Multiplayer Game ModesSplit screen multiplayer features several game modes besides the regular racing game. These game types are not available online.RaceBeat your rivals in a mad cap dash to the finish line!BattleUse weapons and pickups to eliminate all your rivals!Capture the ChaoGrab the Chao and take it to your base to score!GrabGrab the Chaos Emeralds and try to hold on to them to score!King of the HillBe the only racer in the zone to score!KnockoutBetter speed up! Every 15 seconds the racer in last place is knocked out!ItemsAlong the tracks, you can drive into item bubbles to receive one of various items to aid you in the race.ShieldCreates an energy shield that surrounds you for a limited amount of time. Withstands one attack.Rolling BombShoots out a bomb in front of you, exploding upon impact.Giant RocketLaunches a rocket down the center of the track. Pressing the Item button again detonates the rocket.RainbowDrops behind you. Anyone who drives into it has their view temporarily obstructed with a wavy rainbow effect.K.O. GloveShoots forward a giant boxing glove that ricochets off walls.MineShaped like an orange traffic cone, these are placed behind you that either explodes on contact or after a certain amount of time has passed.Manual RocketLaunches a homing rocket at the nearest racer ahead of you.High Speed ShoesGives a temporary speed boost.Confusion StarTargets the nearest racer and flips their screen upside down.Mega HornEmits a blast of sound damaging those near your vehicle.All-StarAllows the chosen character to use their All-Star Move. The further down you are in positions, and depending on your gameplay performance, the more likely you will receive your All-Star.TriviaHis vehicle would've been a Sega Saturn.Among the planned characters that did not make it into the game, whether for legal or time issues, were ToeJam  Earl, Gilius Thunderhead of Golden Axe, Vyse of Skies of Arcadia, and Segata Sanshirou. Some of these characters were later used in the sequel, Sonic  All-Stars Racing Transformed.Originally, Mario was considered as a Wii-exclusive character, however Sega decided against the idea so as to differ itself from the Mario  Sonic series.Pre-ordering the game in the UK came with a code that changed Ryo Hazuki's vehicle to a forklift. This was later released everywhere else as DLC.The Arcade version has two buttons for firing, however they do not allow players to adjust their firing direction due to the lack of a joystick.On the Wii and PC versions of the game, one of the playing cards on the track Roulette Road shows a picture of Sonia, Sonic's sister from the cartoon Sonic Underground, taken from fanart by artist RianaLD. This was evidently mistaken for official artwork. Sonic Team did notice the error and requested it fixed, though they were unchanged upon release. Apologies has been offered to RianaLD and plans are already being made to fix it on the PC version. The Wii version, due to lack of an update feature, cannot be altered.PC System RequirementsMinimum System Requirements:OS: Windows XP/VistaProcessor: Pentium 4 @ 3.2 GHz/Athlon 64 3000+ or EquivalentMemory: 1 GB (2 GB on Vista)Hard Drive: 6 GB FreeVideo Memory: 256 MB (NVIDIA GeForce 7600/AT Radeon X1300)Sound Card: DirectX CompatibleDirectX: 9.0cKeyboard and MouseDVD Rom DriveRecommended System Requirements:OS: Windows XP/Vista (SP1)Processor: Intel Core 2 DUO @ 2.4 GHz/Athlon 64 X2 4200+Memory: 1.5 GB (2 GB+ on Vista)Hard Drive: 7 GB FreeVideo Memory: 512 MB (NVIDIA GeForce 8800/ATI Radeon HD 3800)Sound Card: Creative Sound Blaster X-Fi Sound CardDirectX: 9.0c or 10Keyboard and MouseDVD Rom Drive</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20645">Mario Kart Wii</game><game id="3165">SEGA SuperStars</game><game id="20578">Sega Superstars Tennis</game><game id="19043">Fighters Megamix</game><game id="26792">Kinect Joy Ride</game><game id="2260">Sonic R</game><game id="8422">Sonic Drift</game><game id="30168">Spongebob's Boating Bash</game><game id="6196">Crash Team Racing</game><game id="11656">Rockman Battle &amp; Chase</game><game id="25227">Need for Speed Nitro</game><game id="18757">Mario Kart: Double Dash!!</game><game id="22373">Mario Kart Arcade GP</game><game id="1316">R.C. Pro-Am II</game><game id="24866">OutRun Online Arcade</game><game id="689">Jak X: Combat Racing</game><game id="12544">Wacky Wheels</game><game id="32225">Crash Bandicoot Nitro Kart 2</game><game id="21205">Crash Bandicoot Nitro Kart 3D</game><game id="36675">DreamWorks Super Star Kartz</game><game id="31747">Mario Kart 7</game><game id="37441">LittleBigPlanet Karting</game><game id="39998">Hugo Bukkazoom!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2090574-box_sasasr.png</image></root>