<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26702</id><name>FIFA 10</name><description>Overview Ronaldinho FIFA 10 is the second latest iteration in the                 FIFA series(the first being 2010 FIFA World Cup South Africa),                 EA Sports' popular football franchise, developed by                 EA Canada and licensed by the Federation Internationale de Football Association (FIFA). As with previous versions of the game, this latest installment features licensed teams from major football leagues throughout the world. It evolves on the gameplay established by its predecessors, using the same engine but building on many of the modes debuted in                 FIFA 09 and                 FIFA 08 and refining the gameplay. The biggest change to how the game plays is the introduction of 360 degree dribbling, instead of the eight-way control that has been prominent since the beginning of the FIFA games. It also adds a new Virtual Pro that lets the player import a GameFace that represents a real-life face from the EA Sports Football website. The game was released in European regions on October 2nd and the US on October 20th, 2009. As of December 2009, FIFA 10 has sold more than 4.5 million copies and is the fastest selling sports game ever with 1.7 million copies sold in its first week. It is also the overall top-selling game of 2009 in Europe.  Despite the 2010 FIFA World Cup in South Africa taking placing during the months of June and July in 2010, FIFA 10 does not feature the worldwide football tournament. Instead, EA Sports released a separate stand-alone game,         2010 FIFA World Cup South Africa. New Features   Set pieces in the arena  Many new features and improvements to established features have been put into the game. Some of them are listed below:   There has been a refinement of the ball physics The defensive line will usually be deeper  The AI's goalkeeping, positioning, and defending have all received tweaks 360 degree dribbling gives the player a new sense of control over the ball, and the dribbling is generally more responsive Players can import their face from the EA Sports Football website and use it on their created player Alternatively, they can use the             PlayStation Eye or            Xbox Vision cameras to put their face inside the game instead  The ability to take quick free kicks has been added Referees will also show cards quickly to speed the continuation of the game up Players cover spaces left by team mates The practice arena has been improved with new options that let players set up practice matches and set pieces The ability to change stadium names and assign them to teams has been added  Game Modes     Quick Match - Quick Match allows the player to get straight into a match straight away without having to go through the menus. By default, the match is between the player's favored team and the team's main rivals. Exhibition - This mode allows the player to set up a friendly match between two teams. Tournament Mode - Custom or preset tournaments and leagues can be set up and played. A lot of individual settings can be tweaked, like the number of substitutes, whether the away goal rule is in effect, and the number of games a player misses through suspension.Manager Mode - This standard career mode has undergone a few significant changes, notably with transfers and experience points completely revamped. Kit numbers can also be edited at any time, effectively fixing the problem in previous FIFA games where newly bought players were assigned unusual numbers. Virtual Pro - A new addition to FIFA 10, players can create their own footballer with the ability to add a scan of their face. Completing specific challenges allows players to improve particular stats, and this player carries across to all of the different game modes. Be a Pro Seasons - Players choose a single footballer (their Virtual Pro is also an option) and complete a season playing solely as that player. Staying in the primary squad requires the fulfillment of set challenges, which also improves your footballer's stats. Lounge Mode - Lounge Mode is a relaxed and more unrealistic way of playing FIFA 10. Players earn points and badges depending on how well they play in a match and meet certain criteria. Badges can be used before a match to give your team an edge or impede your opponent. Examples include ensuring that the offside rule does not affect you and distributing bookings to the opposing team. Head-to-Head - Head-to-Head is the traditional online mode that pits two players against each other using teams of their choosing. League Mode - With this mode, players can start a new league and invite friends to it. Participants play each other at any time, and the standings update according to the results. Be a Pro Online - Up to twenty players can take part in one match, with everyone assuming a different single footballer. Only the goalkeepers cannot be controlled.  Gameplay Criticisms  The main criticisms of FIFA 10's gameplay have pointed towards the effectiveness of goalkeepers in certain situations. Goalkeepers are particularly susceptible to chip shots due to advancing far off their goal line and not reacting to the chip.    Downloadable ContentEA Sports has put more focus on downloadable content compared to previous years. There is an in-game store that lets players purchase and download extras. Real Madrid's stadium, the              Estadio Santiago Bernabéu, was released as free                DLC to coincide with the game's launch date, while temporary stat boosts for Virtual Pros and extra commentary are also available.  Live Season 2.0  Live Season 2.0 is an updated version of                 FIFA 09's Adidas Live Season and allows in-game updates to player stats and statuses depending upon their real world performance, injuries, and transfers, among other things. Updates are released every Wednesday, and it is available for 6 leagues within the game: the Premier League, Ligue 1, Serie A, Bundesliga, Liga BBVA, and Primera División. It also allows players to play their chosen team's real-life season with the same line ups, and compare their results and performances alongside reality. Without sponsorship from Adidas this year, it is paid DLC and costs $3.99/400 MS points per individual league or $7.99/800 MS points for all six leagues.  FIFA Ultimate Team   Arranging your team     EA Sports' popular post-release piece of DLC that featured in FIFA 09 returned for FIFA 10, costing $4.99/400 MS points. The mode is based on card collection where players are able to buy card packs with in-game money or via PSN / MSP in order to build and improve their own team. Not only do the cards include individual players but also managers, coaches, physios, stat boosts, kits, balls and stadia. The player's team can then be taken into online or single-player tournaments to earn more money. This time, the mode features regularly updated new challenges, tournaments, and rewards.  The other big change is team chemistry, which has been redesigned to play a much bigger part in matches. Each individual player has a chemistry value dependent on a number of factors. A player forms relationships with his teammates, and if his nationality or the league he plays in is the same as those nearby, he receives a boost in chemistry. Likewise, if he is playing in his favoured position, or if the formation is one that he likes, he will find it easier to gel in the team.Additionally, the add-on provides access to an additional 250 achievement points on           Xbox Live.  Cover Athlete Each region's version of FIFA 10 features a different set of players on the cover:   United Kingdom and Republic of Ireland -                  Theo Walcott,                  Frank Lampard and                  Wayne Rooney Australia - Wayne Rooney and                  Tim Cahill Germany - Bastian Schweinsteiger and Wayne Rooney Italy -                  Ronaldinho and Giorgio Chiellini France - Steve Mandanda, Karim Benzema, and Guillaume Hoarau Spain - Karim Benzema and Xavi Poland - Wayne Rooney and Robert Lewandowski Portugal - Frank Lampard and Simão Russia - Sergei Semak Hungary - Wayne Rooney and Balázs Dzsudzsák North America - Frank Lampard, Cuauhtémoc Blanco and Sacha Kljestan Commentators FIFA 10 provides localised commentary. You will generally only get a few commentary pairs with the game depending on where you live, but the rest can be downloaded from the store. Below are the list of commentators that appear in the game:  English - Martin Tyler and Andy Gray English (Alternate) - Clive Tyldsley and Andy Townsend French - Herve Mathoux and Franck Sauzée Italian - Giuseppe Bergomi and Fabio Caressa German - Tom Bayer and Sebastian Hellman Spanish (Spain) - Paco González and Manolo Lama Spanish (Mexico) - Enrique "el Perro" Bermúdez and Ricardo Peláez Dutch - Evert ten Napel and Youri Mulder Portuguese (Portugal) - David Carvalho and Hélder Conduto Portuguese (Brazil) - Nivaldo Prieto and Paulo Vinícius Coelho Hungarian - Richard Faragó and István B. Hajdú Russian - Vasiliy Utkin and Vasiliy Solovjov Swedish - Glenn Hysén and Henrik Strömblad Czech - Jaromír Bosák and Petr Svěcený Polish - Włodzimierz Szaranowicz and Dariusz Szpakowski  Soundtrack The FIFA 10 soundtrack features songs from 42 up-and-coming bands from a variety of different countries:   Adiam Dymott - Miss You Afrobots - Favela Rock Alex Metric - Head Straight Auletta - Meine Stadt Balkan Beat Box feat. Tomer Yosef and Saz - Ramallah-Tel Aviv BLK JKS - Lakeside Bomba Estéreo - Fuego The BPA feat. Ashley Beedle - Should I Stay or Should I Blow Buraka Som Sistema feat. Pongolove - Kalemba (Wegue - Wegue) CasioKids - Fot I Hose Children Collide - Skeleton Dance Crookers feat. The Very Best, Two Fingers  Marina Gasolina - Birthday Bash Cut Off Your Hands - Happy as Can Be Dananananaykroyd - Black Wax Datarock - Give It Up Fabri Fibra - Donna Famosa Fidel Nadal - International Love Los Fabulosos Cadillacs - La Luz Del Ritmo Macaco - Hacen Falta Dos Major Lazer - Hold the Line Marcio Local - Soul Do Samba Matt  Kim - Daylight (Troublemaker Remix feat. de la Soul) Metric - Gold Guns Girls Mexican Institute of Sound - Alocatel Nneka - Kangpe Passion Pit - Moth's Wings Peter Bjorn and John - Nothing to Worry About Pint Shot Riot - Not Thinking Straight Playing for Change - War / No More Trouble Rocky Dawuni - Download The Revolution Royksopp - It's What I Want Soshy - Dorothy The Answering Machine - It's Over! It's Over! It's Over! The Enemy - Be Somebody The Temper Trap - Science of Fear Tommy Sparks - She's Got Me Dancing The Whitest Boy Alive - 1517 Wyclef Jean - MVP Kompa Zap Mama - Vibrations Demo A demo was released to the public on the Xbox Live Marketplace and the PlayStation Network on October 2, 2009. It featured three difficulty levels, the arena (doubling as a loading screen), and the Exhibition mode. Players could choose from six different teams in the demo and play matches of three minutes per half. If both teams were tied after ninety minutes, penalties decided the match. The six teams included:    Olympique Marseille Chelsea Juventus Chicago Fire Bayern Munchen                 FC Barcelona </description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="40">Soccer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20959">Pro Evolution Soccer 2009</game><game id="13165">Pro Evolution Soccer 2008</game><game id="21242">Winning Eleven: Pro Evolution Soccer 2007</game><game id="2100">Pro Evolution Soccer 5</game><game id="7540">Pro Evolution Soccer 4</game><game id="783">Pro Evolution Soccer 3</game><game id="8000">ISS Pro Evolution 2</game><game id="10340">ISS Pro Evolution</game><game id="9790">International Superstar Soccer 64</game><game id="19165">Sensible World of Soccer</game><game id="13969">Sensible Soccer: European Champions</game><game id="10022">Sensible World of Soccer '96/'97</game><game id="16250">International Sensible Soccer</game><game id="19558">Sensible Soccer '98: European Club Edition</game><game id="8951">Sensible Soccer 2006</game><game id="9951">UEFA Champions League 2006-2007</game><game id="2629">UEFA Euro 2000</game><game id="3517">UEFA Euro 2004 Portugal</game><game id="1630">UEFA Champions League 2004-2005</game><game id="27148">Let's Make a Soccer Team!</game><game id="25791">Pro Evolution Soccer 2010</game><game id="31024">SFG Soccer</game><game id="31571">Crazy Soccer Mundial</game><game id="30203">Pure Futbol</game><game id="31217">Pro Evolution Soccer 2011</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2266507-box_fifa10.png</image></root>