<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26733</id><name>Mobile Suit Gundam SEED Destiny: Rengou vs. Z.A.F.T. II</name><description>A sequel to   Mobile Suit Gundam SEED: Rengou vs. ZAFT; Rengou vs ZAFT II improves upon its predecessor with the inclusion of more mobile suits, and balance tweaks to existing suits. The Playstation 2 version also included a Challenge mode as well as P.L.U.S mode, a mission mode featuring    Shinn Asuka as the protagonist based on Gundam SEED Destiny events.  Gameplay  Like its predecessor, RvZ2's gameplay involves a 2v2 battle between suits. Both teams have a single "power gauge", which depletes as a team's mobile suits are destroyed. Players choose from a wide array of suits, each having their own power value, which dictates how much of the power gauge is lost when the mobile suit is destroyed. More powerful suits, such as Gundams, carry a higher value, therefore being a high risk to the power gauge if they are indeed killed; while weaker units will prolong the power gauge at the cost of lower performance.  The power values suits are assigned are broken up into tiers, 590, 560, 450, 420, 280, 270, and 200.The game is played from a 3rd person perspective behind the unit. There is auto-targeting, which causes suits to strafe around their opponent. Switching between targets is possible. The suits can also jump, and double tapping and holding jump performs a boost dash, which continues until the boost gauge is depleted. Double tapping in one direction performs a "step", which is a small dash that can be used to quickly avoid attacks.   There are two attack buttons, generally one for long range attacks, such as using a beam rifle or machine gun; and one for melee attacks (although some suits do not have melee, and instead performing a melee will just result in another long range attack). Some suits also have a sub weapon, and "special" melee and distance attacks, which can be done by pressing that attack button with the jump button simultaneous.   Awakening Mode  As units take and deliver damage, the awakening gauge builds up. Like the first game, activating the gauge (done by pressing the jump, and both attack buttons simultaneously) gives the suit certain effects for a certain amount of time. Different from the first game though is the inclusion of two new awakening modes, which can be chosen before the battle begins. RUSH Mode: The player's weapon ammo is completely replenished, and regenerates at a very fast rate, allowing for rapid, consecutive shots. Defense is also increased, and weapon charge and delay is decreased as well.  A blue aura surrounds the player when this effect is on.SPEED Mode: This mode increases the player's speed and any attacks the player performs can be canceled by a boost dash or a step. Attack delay is also decreased. This player is covered by a larger blue aura when this effect is on.POWER Mode: The player's attacks cause more damage in this mode at the cost of defence and speed. The player also does not flinch from enemy attacks. A orange aura surrounds the player when this effect is on.  Game Modes P.L.U.S Mode Added to the Playstation 2 Version of the game, P.L.U.S Mode is a mission mode that outlines the events that occur in Gundam SEED Destiny. The player takes controls of one pilot,    Shinn Asuka, and performs the missions as they open up. At first, Shinn can only pilot a low value suit, such as the GINN. Through gaining levels and at certain plot points in the story, the player gains more mobile suits to pilot. The same is true for the other characters Shinn will encounter in P.L.U.S Mode.Every mission is associated with a certain character from the series, and this is where a relationship system is utilized. Two kinds of missions can be done for each character, a co-op mission or a vs. mission. Completing such missions either sours or strengthens your relationship, the latter granting use of that character and their suits if the player decides. Characters that the player has positive relationships with can also be chosen to assist in missions that allow more than one pilot to enter, in which AI will control them in most circumstances. Mission objectives vary and include simple deathmatch involving the power gauge, to target missions; where a certain suit/pilot must be killed, timed missions, and collection missions.The leveling system in P.L.U.S Mode is based on the points a player scores in each mission, as well as being affected by the mobile suit the player uses, and if he/she chose any allies before starting. Depending on the strength and value of the suit, multiplier values are put on the experience gained. For example, the Destiny Gundam has a multiplier value of 1, while a weaker suit, such as the GINN, has a multiplier of 3. Choosing allied pilots to help in a mission also cuts your experience gain by a percentage, and it is also important to note these allies gain levels much faster than the player.   Arcade Mode The only mode for the arcade version of the game, this mode involves 9 "phases" that the player must emerge victorious. The player has the choice of various "routes", and there are several different endings depending on the route chosen and the player's performance. The stages are simple deathmatch style, where the player must empty the enemy's power gauge to zero before theirs does. The player is scored and given a rank at the end of each phase, either E,D,C,B,A,S, or Destiny rank. Acheiving Destiny Rank also awards a "FAITH" Badge. If a player receives a FAITH Badge on a any other than the final phase, then the player moves on to a EX version of the next phase, which is a more difficult version of the phase. If a player manages to accumulate 5 FAITH badges over the course of the 9 phase, then after the final phase, the player is given the chance to partake in the FINAL PLUS stage, a very difficult stage that has a special ending regardless of whether the player manages to win or not (the player cannot continue in FINAL PLUS).  In the Playstation 2 Version, beating the arcade mode a number of times unlocks new content, such as new routes, and special mobile suits.  Versus Mode Either one of two players customize a battle to be fought of 2-4 suits. The player/s choose their suit and pilots, and can adjust some game settings, such as the amount of boost, awakening, time, power gauge, and damage that is done in the battle.  Mobile Suits The game boasts an incredible roster of mobile suits and mobile armors, around 60 . Almost every suit used in the Gundam SEED and its sequel are playable, as well as some mobile suits from Gundam SEED's spinoffs, Astray and Stargazer. Notable suits included are the Strike Freedom, Legend, Destiny, and Infinite Justice. Only these 4 suits carry a 590 power value, and as in the series, are very powerful.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26732">Mobile Suit Gundam SEED: Rengou vs. Z.A.F.T.</game><game id="23032">Mobile Suit Gundam: Gundam vs. Gundam</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/16207/1041251-avz2p.jpg</image></root>