<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26735</id><name>The Simpsons Pinball Party</name><description>The TableThe Simpson's Pinball Party is a noteworthy table for a multitude of reasons:  It has two floors or playfields; a lower or main field, and an upper more minor field with two small flippers, located in the top left of the table.  The game also introduces Pinball's first tricolor information display which it actually puts to great use to display a lot of important information in a very small space;  it is designed as the classic Simpsons TV set that you see during the opening of every show with the Show's creators' names.  It also included a floating Homer head that would move, light up, and talk during the game.  Aside from the aforementioned, the game featured some pretty awesome gadgets that were put to good use to, relate to and help make references to the Simpson's show.  For instance, there is the famous Simpson's couch which is used to unlock multiball play.  The couch locks the balls into the cushions like they are little silver people and it has a pretty cool look to it design-wise.  The game also features the snide remarks of CBG (that's Comic Book Guy for those not in the know) who works sort of as the game's rule system... in a sarcastic way.  Scattered abound you will find many different characters, locations and objects from the show, many which are interactive.  This would include the power plant where Homer works, the Simpson's family's malfunctioning garage door which you must "bang" open with a ball, and a skating, daredevil Bart that you can hit to make him "Skate" for points and to complete one of the many challenges.   The table was created during the show's 14th Season and was an exceptionally ambitious table for its time because of the many devices (not to mention how advanced they were) that the board was able to cram into its limiting space.  It also manages to have a rather fair and forgiving "dead zone" (the area where you will lose the ball no matter what unless you 'tilt' the machine - but tilting can cause the machine to lock up temporarily as well, so be careful!)  Overall the Simpson's Pinball Party has been claimed to be one of the most innovative and enjoyable tables out there.  Demand is high and maintenance is laborious due to the advanced gadgets.  The cost of one of these tables today can run, on average, at $3,500 and as high as $5,000 for a well-maintained machine.    This table has also been a favorite for pinball modders (yes, they exist).  These modders have managed to add even more devices as well as change/fix some of the default workings of the game.   Super Duper Mega Extreme Wizard ModeIt is worth noting the Super Duper Mega Extreme Wizard Mode.  This mode required the player to complete 6 challenges or tasks (which should be noted that most were of extreme difficulty to complete if they were timed events) then you were to shoot the ball into any hole during single-ball play (which is simply 'non-multiball-play) and this would initiate the Super Duper Mega Extreme Wizard Mode which very few have ever gotten to witness.  It is named partly after Pinball Wizard by The Who with the loaded adjectives in place to really drive home the fact that this is the cream of the cream in terms of pinball achievements.  Upon reaching this, you are given five (yes, 5!) balls to shoot around the table and scores are amped up rather generously.</description><genres><genre id="30">Pinball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22525">The Addams Family</game><game id="27329">Baywatch</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/10/103881/1782842-spp.jpg</image></root>