<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26754</id><name>Crysis 2</name><description>OverviewCrysis 2 was announced on June 1st of 2009, and was in development since 2007. Crysis 2 is the sequel to 2007's Crysis which was lauded for its impressive visuals. German based studio Crytek GmbH, developers of the first game, was the lead developer of the sequel along with help from Crytek UK, formerly Free Radical. It is the first game using the new CryENGINE3 engine.The game is also available in stereoscopic 3D on all platforms.PlotNew York isn't doing too well.The year is 2023, three years after the events of the original Crysis, and humanity is losing the fight against the Ceph aliens awakened on Lingshen Island. Major cities across the world including London and Rio de Janeiro have been destroyed, and an alien virus is sweeping across Manhattan. Martial law has been declared, and the Crynet Enforcement  Local Logistics force (C.E.L.L.) is trying to control what's left of New York..A former Crynet doctor, Nathan Gould, is trapped on Long Island, and a Marine unit is sent in to retrieve him, though they are quickly ambushed by the Ceph. One marine, named Alcatraz, barely survives, rescued by Prophet, the squad leader from the first game. Prophet has been infected with the alien virus, however, and he gives Alcatraz his powerful Nanosuit before committing suicide. The Nanosuit, while making Alcatraz unbelievably powerful, is also the only thing keeping him alive, and regularly shows Alcatraz Prophet's memories.Not knowing Prophet is dead, C.E.L.L. hunts Alcatraz and the Nanosuit, believing Prophet is inside and branding him a biohazard. Alcatraz receives instructions and directions from Dr. Gould via radio, though Dr. Gould is also not aware that it is not Prophet in the suit. After retrieving some alien tissue samples, which upgrade the suit, Alcatraz finds Dr. Gould, who is dismayed to discover that Prophet is dead. But Gould realizes that the Nanosuit, after contacting the alien tissue, may contain what's needed to stop the Manhattan Virus. Alcatraz and Gould are ambushed by C.E.L.L. forces, led by Commander Lockhart and Tara Strickland (the Major from the original Crysis' daughter), but a Ceph attack releases a bio-weapon into the area, killing most of the C.E.L.L soldiers and nearly destroying Alcatraz.Alcatraz's Nanosuit gets a reboot from Jacob Hargreave, the inventor of the Nanosuit, who speaks to Alcatraz from an unknown location. Hargreave seems to have a great deal of knowledge about the Ceph, and guides Alcatraz to a massive alien spire to try and network with the alien's communication systems. The plan fails, and Marines are sent in by the Pentagon to destroy Manhattan's flood barrier and flush out the aliens, nearly drowning Alcatraz.Alcatraz is rescued by a group of Marines that includes his former squadmate Chino (seen briefly in the introduction to the game), and Alcatraz assists the Marines in evacuating civilians from Manhattan. Meanwhile, the Nanosuit is rewriting its code, via the alien tissue samples, to be able to talk to the alien's technology.Another alien spire rises high into the air out of Times Square, and Alcatraz is now able to enter and interface, reprogramming the spores and killing all Ceph nearby. Alcatraz heads to Roosevelt Island to find Hargreave, killing Commander Lockhart along the way. He finds Hargreave, who is revealed to be nearly 200 years old and living suspended in life-sustaining liquid, aware for many years that the Ceph were going to invade. He has Alcatraz captured and attempts to remove the Nanosuit, but the suit resists and Alcatraz is rescued by Tara Strickland, who explains that she is an undercover CIA agent. Hargreave knows the Ceph are about to invade Roosevelt Island, and gives Alcatraz a final suit upgrade before destroying the island and himself.Alcatraz, Stickland, and Gould learn that the Pentagon has authorized a nuclear strike on Manhattan. Meanwhile, a Ceph ship long buried beneath Central Park rises from the ground, lifting most of the park high into the sky. Alcatraz gains access to the ship and fights his way to the spire at the ship's core. He releases the spire's spore bio-weapon over all of New York City, killing all remaining Ceph and averting the nuclear strike.The memories of Prophet, stored in the suit, inform Alcatraz that the Ceph have buildings beneath major cities all over the world and that more work is yet to come. Prophet's memories are finally fully combined with those of Alcatraz, and when asked for his name via radio by Karl Ernst Rasch, co-founder of the Hargreave-Reach corporation, Alcatraz responds, "They call me Prophet."GameplayNanosuit 2.0Nanosuit 2.0The suit powers from the original return with the addition of a tactical mode that gives detailed information about enemy weaknesses, data about the environment, and a boost to the audio of nearby enemy conversations. Suit modifiers themed around the different suit powers include X-ray vision, directional bullet trails, and bullet deflection.The suit's enhanced parkour abilities also introduces more verticality.The updated Nanosuit now has two Primary and two Secondary modes, which work in tandem:Primary Modes - When activated, these modes drain the suit's power and provide temporary boosts.Armor - Diverts all damage to the suit, depleting shield power in lieu of user health.Stealth - Drains all the suit's power to cloak the user and silence all movement sounds.Secondary Modes - These modes are passive and turned on at all times. They can be activated simultaneously with the primary modes.Tactical - Replacing the binoculars from the first game, the tactical mode highlights all objects of interest in the world (like enemy targets, weapons, ammo etc.).Power - Drains the suit's energy to perform feats like power jump, power slide or power sprint.Nanovision - Allows the user to track hidden enemies and to see in dim-lit environments.Upgrading the NanosuitThroughout the game, Alcatraz collects Nano Catalyst from the Ceph he kills, which the player can use on buying upgrades for the suit.Tactical UpgradesThreat Tracker - Allows the player to see the route of incoming projectiles.Proximity Alarm - Gives the player a audible warning when a enemy is near.Cloak Tracker - Allows the player to see cloaked enemies.Armor UpgradesArmour Enhance - Armor mode drains energy slower.Nano Recharge - When not using a suit mode, energy and health recharge faster.Deflection - Deflects many enemy bullets, allowing for more hits before health loss.Power UpgradesMobility Enhance - Increases ledge grab speed and slows running and jumping energy drain.Air Friction - Gives the player better control when falling.Air Stomp - Gives the player a powerful ground pound ability.Stealth UpgradesCovert Ops - Softens the sound of the player's footsteps.Tracker - Highlights enemy paths.Stealth Enhance - Allows the player to enter and leave stealth much faster. Heavily reduces drain of power in stealth mode.Each enemy drops a different amount of Nano Catalyst:Alien Tick - 20 CatalystAlien Grunt - 100 CatalystAlien Grunt Commander - 300 CatalystCeph Devastator - 500 CatalystCeph Pinger - 2,000 CatalystCeph Stalker - 5,000 CatalystNote: Upgrades collected in first playthrough along with collected catalyst are carried over to future playthroughs.Multiplayer ModesCrash SiteCeph drop pods are periodically launched by overhead dropships. Two teams must race to each pod and defend it from the opposing team. Points are earned by guarding the pods wherever they land.Team Instant ActionCrysis 2's standard team deathmatch mode. Defeat as many foes as possible with the powers of the Nanosuit while minimizing player deaths.ExtractionOne team is on offense, trying to obtain two bio-ticks that will give boost to stealth and armor and will then try to reach a helicopter extraction point. The defenders must stop them.AssaultOne team is on offense, trying to download critical data from five different data-posts and are clad in Nano suits but have limited weaponry. The defenders must stop them, and get superior weapons but no Nano suit. Four rounds with teams switching sides after each one.Capture the RelayA Capture the Flag spin-off mode where two teams vie for control over two data relays. Matches usually span around ten minutes and requires three capture points to win.Instant ActionA basic free-for-all deathmatch mode. The player with most kills by the end of the round wins.Multiplayer RanksLevel 1 - CadetLevel 2 - Cadet IILevel 3 - Cadet IIILevel 4 - Recruit ILevel 5 - Recruit IILevel 6 - Recruit IIILevel 7 - Private ILevel 8 - Private IILevel 9 - Private IIILevel 10 - Trooper ILevel 11 - Trooper IILevel 12 - Trooper IIILevel 13 - Private First Class ILevel 14 - Private First Class IILevel 15 - Private First Class IIILevel 16 - Specialist ILevel 17 - Specialist IILevel 18 - Specialist IIILevel 19 - Ranger ILevel 20 - Ranger IILevel 21 - Ranger IIILevel 22 - Guard ILevel 23 - Guard IILevel 24 - Guard IIILevel 25 - Operative ILevel 26 - Operative IILevel 27 - Operative IIILevel 28 - Corporal ILevel 29 - Corporal IILevel 30 - Corporal IIILevel 31 - Sergeant ILevel 32 - Sergeant IILevel 33 - Sergeant IIILevel 34 - Veteran ILevel 35 - Veteran IILevel 36 - Veteran IIILevel 37 - Major ILevel 38 - Major IILevel 39 - Major IIILevel 40 - Enforcer ILevel 41 - Enforcer IILevel 42 - Enforcer IIILevel 43 - Colonel ILevel 44 - Colonel IILevel 45 - Colonel IIILevel 46 - General ILevel 47 - General IILevel 48 - General IIILevel 49 - Group CommanderLevel 50 - Force CommanderSoundtrackCrysis 2 OST Cover.The soundtrack was composed Borislav Slavov, with the main theme being written by Hans Zimmer.TracklistInsertion - 03:10Battery Park - 03:26New York - 02:44Aftermath: No Escape - 02:31Close Encounter - 02:00SOS New York - 02:05Chase - 02:28Under Assault - 02:01Crynet: Shoot Him Down! - 02:07Sneak and Shoot - 03:45Gate Keepers - 02:18Rampage - 01:54Nanosuit 2 - 01:13Rising Spear - 01:18Dead Man Walking - 02:04Contamination - 02:24Sinister Breed - 02:02Where Is The Exit? - 01:17Dystopian Nightmares - 02:06Catastrophic Beauty - 02:04Semper Fi - 01:58Flooded Streets - 01:32Aquarium In Obscurum - 02:20Devastation - 01:39Shadowzone - 02:27Alien Suite - 02:05Unsafe Haven - 01:55Terminal Escape - 00:57Under the Clock - 01:51Morituri - 02:23Intersection - 01:32Times Square Evacuation - 01:58Burning Night - 01:27Resolution (Reprise) - 02:05Eye of the Storm - 02:28New York Theme - 02:36Our Only Hope - 02:04Out of the Ashes - 01:59Alien Logo - 00:44The End of the Beginning - 02:01Walk in the Park - 02:01Epilogue - 03:17Limited and Nano EditionsPC Nano Edition.The Limited Edition of Crysis 2 was released at the same price as the regular version and is a part of EA's Project 10 Dollar. It included bonus experience points in multiplayer, early access to the "SCAR Hologram Decoy," a "SCAR Weapon Skin," and an in-game Platinum Dog Tags that displays multiplayer rank and stats.The Nano Edition cost $149.99 at launch and includes the Limited Edition of the game, a steel case, an 11 inch statue of the main character on top of a NYC taxi, and an art book, all contained inside a backpack designed to look like the nanosuit.PC System RequirementsMinimumRecommendedOperating System: XP / Vista / Windows 7Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo 2Ghz, AMD Athlon 64 x2 2Ghz or betterMemory: 2 GB RAM (3GB in Windows Vista)HDD Space: 9 GBDVD ROM: 8xGraphics Card: NVIDIA 8800 GT 512MB Ram or ATI 3850 512 MB or betterDirectX: 9.0cSound Card: DirectX 9.0c compatiblePeripherals: Keyboard and mouse or Microsoft Xbox 360 controller for WindowsOperating System: XP / Vista / Windows 7Processor: A dual core processor 2.6 GHz or aboveRAM Memory: 3 GB (4 GB in Windows Vista / 7)HDD Space: 9 GBDVD ROM: 8xGraphics Card: NVIDIA GeForce 280 GTX or Radeon HD 4870 X2 or betterDirectX: 11Sound Card: DirectX 9.0c compatiblePeripherals: Keyboard and mouse or Microsoft Xbox 360 controller for Windows</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20665">Far Cry 2</game><game id="14782">Far Cry</game><game id="30185">Blacklight: Tango Down</game><game id="2133">Call of Duty 4: Modern Warfare</game><game id="35129">Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 3</game><game id="36230">Blacklight Retribution</game><game id="39691">Killzone Trilogy</game><game id="38740">N.O.V.A. 3: Near Orbit Vanguard Alliance</game><game id="29510">N.O.V.A.</game><game id="29021">Resistance 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3661/1618079-81910_crys2genpftnorating_jpg_jpgcopy.jpg</image></root>