<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26776</id><name>Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 1: Launch of the Screaming Narwhal</name><description>Overview Tales of Monkey island Chapter 1: Launch of the Screaming Narwhal is the first in a five part episodic series by telltale, continuing the Monkey Island franchise approximately nine years after the previous instalment, Escape from monkey island, was released. LucasArts had discontinued development of its adventure game franchises due to dwindling sales in the early 2000s. Later in the decade, Telltale Games (founded by a number of former LucasArts employees) had revitalized the genre by creating episodic downloadable adventure games, leading to ToMI's creation and development.Plot  The tale begins with        Guybrush Threepwood Mighty Pirate™ sailing the seas to rescue his wife,        Elaine Marley who has been captured by the        Zombie Pirate LeChuck. He arrives at LeChucks Ship equipped with instructions to create The Cursed Cutlass of Kafflu, to kill LeChuck forever. Unfortunately, Guybrush drops the bottle of Root Beer required and is forced to improvise using roots from a plant, and        Grog. His improvisation fails to kill LeChuck, but turns him human, and infects Guybrush's left hand with LeChucks evil energy, The Pox of LeChuck, which gives his hand a mind of its own. An explosion then hurls Guybrush from the ship.We next find our hero on an unknown beach where he is greeted by        Davey Nipperkin, a local reporter, who informs Guybrush that he is now stranded on        Flotsam Island, a mysterious island which the winds are always pointing inwards, making leaving impossible. He is informed about "Deep Gut" who is the only person who may know how to escape the island, but Davey insists on Guybrush helping him by creating some pirate news for Davey's newspaper before revealing Deep Gut's location. After seizing the local ship, The Screaming Narwhal, finding buried treasure, and starting a bar fight, Guybrush is told to go to a shack to the north of the island, and use a codeword to gain entry.Upon entering Deep Gut's shack, Guybrush discovers that Deep Gut is in fact the        Voodoo Lady, who Guybrush has met before. The Voodoo Lady is unfamiliar with the causes of the in-blowing winds, but informs him that to remove the Pox of LeChuck infecting his hand he must find La Esponje Grande (or The Big Sponge). Guybrush also obtains a map, in a glass bottle, which may reveal the secrets of the islands winds.Guybrush's infected hand prevents him from accessing the map within the bottle, and he seeks advice from the local doctor, Marquis De Singe. Upon arriving, Guybrush discovers that Marquis De Singe was the first inhabitant of the island, after being condemned there by the King of France. After being tied to an operating table, Guybrush's hand is injected with a numbing agent, and the Marquis plans to remove the hand to study it. After escaping from the table, Guybrush gains access to the map due to his newly numbed hand.Following the map, Guybrush discovers a large wind controlling machine, which the Marquis is using to strand pirates on the island, giving him patients. Despite the Marquis best efforts to prevent him, Guybrush manages to deactivate the wind machine using several controls hidden across the island. This allows Guybrush to set sail in his seized ship, The Screaming Narwhal. An unfortunate side effect of deactivating the wind machine is that The Pox of LeChuck begins to spread outwards from the island, possibly leading to the infection of other locations in the Tri-island area.After setting sail to The Rock of Gelato to find Elaine, Guybrush discovers Elaine and LeChuck on his ship he used during his first rescue attempt of Elaine. He sees Elaine being wooed by LeChuck, before suddenly being held at sword point by an unknown attacker.  Gameplay The basic gameplay involves the player taking control of Guybrush and solving puzzles in order to progress in the storyline. The control system involves the player clicking on Guybrush and dragging the mouse to make him walk in that direction, and clicking on items in order to perform actions. The WASD keys on the keyboard can also be used to move Guybrush. The player also has an inventory which can be used to select items to use on the environment, or even combine two items to form a new, better item.  When Guybrush is tied to Marquis De Singe's operating table he loses the ability to move freely, and can only rotate 90 degrees at a time, and use items within his reaching distance from the table.  PC Requirements Operating System: Microsoft® Windows® XP/Vista/Windows 7Processor: 2.0 Ghz or better (3 GHz Pentium® 4 or equivalent recommended)Memory: 512 MB RAM (1GB recommended)Hard Disk Space: 310 MBVideo Card: 64 MB DirectX® 8.1 compliant video card (128 MB recommended)Sound Card: DirectX® 8.1 sound deviceDirectX® Version: DirectX® Version 9.0c or better (DirectX updater included)Controller Support: Yes    No internet connection required to play         </description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6049">Sam &amp; Max Save the World</game><game id="21670">Wallace &amp; Gromit's Grand Adventures Episode 1: Fright of the Bumblebees</game><game id="21174">Full Throttle</game><game id="13230">Grim Fandango</game><game id="14164">The Legend of Kyrandia: Malcolm's Revenge</game><game id="21350">Jack Keane</game><game id="30008">Sam &amp; Max Episode 301: The Penal Zone</game><game id="30370">Sam &amp; Max Episode 302: The Tomb of Sammun-Mak</game><game id="30374">Sam &amp; Max Episode 305: The City That Dares Not Sleep</game><game id="4889">Rent-a-Hero</game><game id="30372">Sam &amp; Max Episode 303: They Stole Max's Brain</game><game id="30373">Sam &amp; Max Episode 304: Beyond the Alley of the Dolls</game><game id="7344">Sam &amp; Max Episode 5: Reality 2.0</game><game id="32592">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 1: It's About Time</game><game id="33414">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 2: Get Tannen!</game><game id="33415">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 3: Citizen Brown</game><game id="33416">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 4: Double Visions</game><game id="33417">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 5: OUTATIME</game><game id="40100">Chaos on Deponia</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4938/1076091-1.png</image></root>