<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26833</id><name>Golden Sun: Dark Dawn</name><description>Pre-Release InformationAnnounced during Nintendo's press conference at E3 2009, Golden Sun DS marks the return of the classic 2D RPG franchise previously exclusive to the Game Boy Advance. Slated for a 2010 release, it will be Camelot's first traditional turn-based fantasy RPG since the release of Golden Sun: The Lost Age in 2003.E3 2009The E3 2009 demo showed 2D character sprites on top of dynamic 3D environments, similar to the Dragon Quest IV and V remakes. Battles take place on the bottom screen and will have black bars on the top and bottom of the screen, just like in the original games (giving battles a cinematic look). Stylus controls are included and may possibly be mandatory with no option for traditional controls. The demo also revealed familiar summons, protagonists, enemies and level design, hinting that Camelot's next project will be full of nostalgic treats for fans of the Game Boy Advance games.E3 2010A trailer was released at E3 '10 showing off more of the 3D environment, and the use of the touch controls with psynergy, and also button mapping. New summons were shown, and the names of the main characters were revealed to be Matthew, Karis and Tyrell, who resemble Isaac, Ivan and Garet , respectively. the E3 Demo showed what looked like a demo of the touch controls, and some new abilities, such as the ability to climb trees. Djinn from the first 2 games are also shown to make a return in battle, which is now fully 3D.PlotDark Dawn takes place 30 years after the previous games in the series. The world has changed due to the effects of the Golden Sun, unleashed at the end of The Lost Age. Alchemy has been restored to the world, saving it from its slow decay, but not all is well. Along with these changes, Psynergy Vortexes have begun to spread across the world, absorbing all Psynergy they come across. The children of the previous protagonists band together to solve the mystery of the vortexes and save the world of Weyard once again.The game centers around Matthew, the son of Isaac and Jenna. While Jenna, Ivan, and many other citizens of Vale (destroyed by the "Golden Sun Event") live in the merchant city of Kalay, Isaac, Matthew, Garet, and Tyrell, Garet's son, live on the newly up heaved Goma Plateau, watching over the remains of Mount Aleph and the Sol Sanctum, the place where Isaac and Garet's quest began.At the beginning of the adventure, Tyrell takes a Soarwing, a device that allows Jupiter Adepts to fly, from Karis, ivan's daughter. He breaks it, and to fix it, Isaac and Garet need a feather from a very rare and dangerous bird, a Mountain Roc. Matthew, Garet, and Karis embark on their journey across the continent of Angara to recover this feather. However, in the process, they discover something far more sinister.CharactersMatthewThe hero of the story, Matthew is the son of Isaac, leader of the legendary Warriors of Vale who saved the world a generation ago. After an unfortunate incident, he sets off on an adventure with Tyrell and Karis. Matthew is an Earth Adept just like his father was when he started his adventures 30 years ago. He is a person of few words, but strong convictions.TyrellThe son of Garet, Isaac's oldest friend, takes after his heroic father in many ways. Tyrell has great courage and curiosity...and perhaps too much of both. A Fire Adept, he plans to follow in his father's footsteps.KarisThe daughter of Ivan, another of the Warriors of Vale, is the most levelheaded of the trio. Mature for her age and quick-witted, Karis is relied upon by Matthew and Tyrell for a great deal. A Wind Adept, she has inherited her father's indomitable spirit and powers of observation.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22703">Dragon Quest IV: Chapters of the Chosen</game><game id="7197">Dragon Quest V: Hand of the Heavenly Bride</game><game id="19425">Dragon Quest VI: Realms of Revelation</game><game id="21463">Final Fantasy III</game><game id="20829">Final Fantasy IV</game><game id="24200">Sands of Destruction</game><game id="9249">Chrono Trigger</game><game id="21240">Black Sigil: Blade of the Exiled</game><game id="23936">7th Dragon</game><game id="25435">Dragon Ball Z: Attack of the Saiyans</game><game id="24394">The Wizard of Oz: Beyond The Yellow Brick Road</game><game id="23478">Suikoden Tierkreis</game><game id="21666">Dragon Quest IX: Sentinels of the Starry Skies</game><game id="2094">Final Fantasy II</game><game id="26932">Glory of Heracles</game><game id="27186">Final Fantasy: The 4 Heroes of Light</game><game id="23987">Nostalgia</game><game id="5827">Final Fantasy Legend II</game><game id="25150">Summon Night X: Tears Crown</game><game id="23904">Ni no Kuni: Shikkoku no Madoshi</game><game id="4338">Final Fantasy Anthology</game><game id="9896">Beyond the Beyond</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2478660-box_gsdd.png</image></root>