<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26847</id><name>Final Fantasy XIV Online: A Realm Reborn</name><description>OverviewFinal Fantasy XIV takes place in the new world of Hydaelyn.Final Fantasy XIV: A Realm Reborn is the second MMORPG to be released as a part of Square Enix's Final Fantasy series, following in the footsteps of Final Fantasy XI. It is a fully redesigned relaunch of the original version of Final Fantasy XIV, which was released in 2010. A Realm Reborn was released on August 27, 2013 on PlayStation 3 and PC. A PlayStation 4 version has been announced, but not yet dated.The game was initially announced at Sony's E3 2009 press conference, where it was announced that in addition to its release on PCs, the game would see an exclusive console release for the PlayStation 3.The game takes place in the fantasy world of Hydaelyn. Players begin their adventures in the region of Eorzea , which is comprised of the continent of Aldenard and its surrounding islands. The region contains several city-states, including Limsa Lominsa, Ul'dah, Gridania, and Ishgard. Limsa Lominsa is a bustling port with a strong naval tradition, Ul'dah is a mining city located in the desert, Gridania is found deep in an ancient forest, and Ishgard is in the high mountains.Original Release and ReactionFinal Fantasy XIV began its first stage of alpha testing on March 10th, 2010, and entered the second stage on June 10th, 2010. Closed beta testing began on July 13th, 2010, and the game's open beta started on September 2nd, 2010. The game launched with a Limited Collector's Edition on September 22nd, 2010, and the standard edition launched on September 30, 2010 worldwide on Windows PC platforms. The game was not released as a part of Square Enix's PlayOnline service that Final Fantasy XI operates under, but under a new "Square Enix Account" system planned for use with all future Square Enix online titles.Upon its release, Final Fantasy XIV was savaged by critics and players alike for dull, tedious, and outdated gameplay. The response was so severe that Square Enix president Youichi Wada publicly apologized for the game's quality. The game's development team was reorganized and the free trial period was extended while the company made efforts to improve the title.The PlayStation 3 version of the game was put on indefinite hold, while the title's many faults were addressed.A New Producer/Director and A Realm RebornOn December 10, 2010, a massive shakeup occurred amongst the development and planning teams of Final Fantasy XIV, in wake of the game's extremely negative launch.Naoki Yoshida, a relative unknown amongst fans of Square Enix titles, stepped in to the role of both Producer and Director, replacing the positions held by Hiromichi Tanaka and Nobuaki Komoto respectively. With this and other staff changes made at key positions, an air of change began in the development of the title. Yoshida opened lines of communication with the players through players polls, and new official forums. This kind of communication with players was unheard of in the series' previous MMO, Final Fantasy XI. Player feedback has became a top priority, and since his arrival, many game mechanics that players found arduous and non-friendly were removed (Fatigue system, Physical levels, etc.) or given totally new roles (Guildleves changing from the main crux of the game's content, to being a method of easier solo-play).While many of the changes to the original game were welcomed by the game's player base, there were many other changes that the team could not implement due to limitations in the original game engine and servers. So, it was announced in late November 2011 that the game would be completely rebuilt from the ground up, and become an entirely new client. This project was originally named Final Fantasy XIV: Version 2.0.The introduction of Version 2.0 brought numerous elements into play that were not possible in the original game. These include, but are not limited to:A completely new game engine based off of Square Enix's Luminous engine, allowing for better scaling of graphics, and therefore lowering the games' high PC requirements.Completely new geography to the maps, eliminating the original maps' repetitive nature.New party search feature to allow for cross-server play.New player estates, including linkshell/guild housing.New main scenario.New UI for PC and a controller friendly UI for PlayStation 3, including the support of add-ons for both versions.Player vs. Player content.Delivery Services via moogles.Players being able to jump while traveling on foot, or on chocobos.On November 11th, 2012, the original version of the game was shut down, and a CG trailer showed the conclusion of the "Seventh Umbral Era" storyline which is being used to explain the massive changes in the world coming with the game's relaunch. Now labeled "Final Fantasy XIV: A Realm Reborn", the new game client will be in the final testing period for Windows and PlayStation 3 as of August 16, 2013.Unlike the original release's beta test, where nearly no feedback was taken into account, the game has undergone a great many changes while in beta testing due to player feedback. While the changes cannot be specified due to the game's NDA, it would seem that feedback is playing a very important role to help ensure the title's success.A Realm Reborn is expected to go on sale August 27, 2013 for Windows and PlayStation 3 in Japan, North America and Europe simultaneously. All current and former players who have purchased the original Final Fantasy XIV for Windows will get A Realm Reborn at no additional cost in the form of a new client download. Users will also be able to play their characters on both PC and PS3 on the same servers, but will need to purchase the PS3 version separately. The game servers/data centers will be regional, but there will be no restriction on which server players choose to join. Languages supported are Japanese, English, French and German, and an in game auto-translation feature allows for communication between users of those languages. Though not available at launch, support is being considered for Spanish, Italian and Russian as well.A Chinese version of the Windows client will be made available in late 2013. This version will be run on separate servers to those of the other regions due to Chinese law. Official LaunchFinal Fantasy XIV: A Realm Reborn launched on August 27th, 2013. Early access was granted 2 days prior if you pre-ordered the game.The launch was less than spectacular with problems ranging from login restrictions to instance ("duty") server issues and just World/server crashes in general. Most of the time the game was unplayable because Square Enix had to limit the amount of users able to even log in so as not to crash the game for those that actually were able to..This drove players to stay logged in 24/7 which made the need for login restrictions even worse. Square Enix released a patch on September 11th which imposed a 30 min AFK timer which kicks AFK players offline. Digital sales and activation were even put on hold as to keep the players already attempting to play working.As of September 4th, after the first maintenance, the game has been mostly stable. Square Enix released data claming 200,000+ concurrent users were playing FFXIV:ARR during peak times. The ArmouryA BlacksmithThe Armoury is a system vaguely reminiscent the job system used in previous Final Fantasy games. Rather than gaining experience and levels, however, this class system is tied to weapons. Each weapon type represents a different character class (for example, if your character picks up a one-handed sword, he becomes a Gladiator). Selecting a weapon will grant you basic abilities for the class tied to it. As you fight with that weapon and use the class abilities it grants, your skill with the weapon will increase, granting you new abilities. At any time, you can change your weapon, switching classes in the process. For example, you've been carrying a staff since the start of your adventuring career and you've earned powerful skill as a Conjurer. Deciding to learn the way of the sword, you put your staff away and pull out a longsword. Now you can use your sword for basic attacks, and as you increase in skill, learn more powerful sword-based attacks. And, while using your sword, you can still cast most spells you learned as a Conjurer. Put the sword away and take out your staff, and you're once again a Conjurer.DisciplinesDisciplines are the different paths of activity and skill that an adventurer may devote himself to. Using the Armoury system, one may switch between classes under all disciplines.Disciples of WarArcher (Job Advancement: Bard)The Archer is a ranged combat specialist, highly skilled with the bow and able to fall back on slings and rocks if they run out of arrows. Traditionally, the Elezen and Miqo'te are considered to be the most skillful Archers. Effectiveness with this class will depend on a player's expertise in positioning and arrow-type selection.Lancer (Job Advancement: Dragoon)The Lancer is a melee fighter skilled at using polearm weapons such as lances and pikes. Able to attack from a relatively safe distance due to the length of their weapon, lancers are also skilled at throwing javelins at long range. These abilities make them an ideal combat support class.Gladiator (Job Advancement: Paladin)Gladiators are skilled in the use of all one-handed blades, including both melee weapons and throwing knives. They can either use shields in their off hand or focus all their energy on their sword arm. A Gladiator is a great front-line fighter and defender, with the ability to hold an enemy's attention.Marauder (Job Advancement: Warrior)A combat specialist focusing on the two-handed great-axe, the marauder is a fearsome fighter who is able to supplement their arsenal with throwing axes. Brute force is their greatest attribute, and timing and distance will be essential to their effectiveness in combat.Pugilist (Job Advancement: Monk)This master of close-combat is formidable even when unarmed, but they are known to use different types of fist weapons to augment their arsenal. The Pugilist can alter their stance to focus on either attack or defense, and counter their lack of range with excellent maneuverability.Disciples of MagicConjurer (Job Advancement: White Mage)Conjurers use a combination of healing spells and elemental magic attacks. They use wands or canes to focus energy from the world around them and weave it into spells. Their intimacy with all types of elemental energy enables them to easily switch between offensive and defensive magic.Thaumaturge (Job Advancement: Black Mage)A Thaumaturge uses the power of darkness to buff allies and enfeeble enemies along with doing great darkness magic damage. They draw on the energy within themselves and channel magic through scepters and staffs. Their powers of destruction can rival even the Disciples of War.Arcanist (Job Advancement: Summoner and Scholar)Armed with grimoire books, and faithful sidekick Carbuncle by their side, Arcanists use gemstones to set their elemental alignment, and can cast power spells.Disciples of the LandBotanistThe Botanist is a master of procuring resources from all forms of plant life. They use a hatchet to harvest from trees, grasses, and other plants, and many other disciplines rely on them for supplies.MinerAlong with being able to harvest valuable minerals, a Miner can also throw rocks and debilitate their enemies with mineral compositions. Their main tool is the pickaxe, and they are able to take on a broad spectrum of jobs, from small- to large-scale.FisherFishers use a fishing rod to harvest the realm's aquatic creatures, and sell them to those in other disciplines. Many factors influence how successful they will be in different areas, and the dangerous spots they may need to travel to fish necessitates protection from more combat-oriented classes.Disciples of the HandAlchemistAlchemists are masters of both science and nature, capable of distilling ordinary materials into wondrous concoctions. They use an alembic to distill and combine materials into various powerful and trans-formative substances.BlacksmithBlacksmiths smelt metal ingots and use them to craft armor, weapons, and even guns. This work is always in high demand all over Eorzea due to the need for all fighters to keep their weapons in good repair. They have many tools related to crafting and repairing weapons.CulinarianCulinarians use a vast array of ingredients to cook delicious meals that help adventurers maintain their strength on the battlefield. Their main tool is the skillet, which they use to fulfill many different recipes.LeatherworkerTanners are able to boil and dye pelts and skins, and use them to craft leather armor and clothing. There is a large demand for these products, and the Leatherworker uses a headknife for many of these processes.WeaverWeavers make threads and use them to make various types of clothing. Their main tool is the needle, and they must keep up with current trends in clothing to stay successful.ArmorerAn Armorer's main skill is crafting many pieces of metal armor, whether plate or chain, and their main tool is the raising hammer. There is enough specialization in requisite techniques to separate this profession from Blacksmithing.CarpenterThe Carpenter's main tool is the handsaw, which they use to create various wares. They are attuned to the fine differences between types of wood, and bring these traits out in any craft they produce.GoldsmithGoldsmiths use precious metals and gems to craft accessories and decorate weapons, armor, and tools. Their main tool is the chaser hammer, and they must constantly watch economic trends to make sure they get a return on their investment in expensive materials.JobsAn evolution of the Armoury system, the Job System is where any of the Disciples of War or Magic classes, when meeting certain requirements, can complete quests to become classic jobs in the Final Fantasy series.The jobs currently available are:Warrior - Unlocked through MarauderMonk - Unlocked through PugilistWhite Mage - Unlocked through ConjurerBlack Mage - Unlocked through ThaumaturgeBard - Unlocked through ArcherDragoon - Unlocked through LancerPaladin - Unlocked through GladiatorSummoner - Unlocked through ArcanistScholar - Unlocked through ArcanistJobs are all linked to the class that they are obtained through. Meaning that when you are a level 50 Gladiator, you are also a level 50 Paladin. Changing roles is as simple as equipping the "Soul Crystal" for the job.When playing as a job, you will have access to both the actions of base class as well as those of the job in question. You will also be able to equip certain actions belonging to other classes, though these are limited. Job-specific actions are acquired by completing job quests.Currently Arcanist is the only known class that branches off into multiple jobs, although ultimately other classes will follow this trend.Other classic Final Fantasy jobs being considered for implementation are Red Mage, Ninja, Samurai, and Dark Knight.RacesFinal Fantasy XIV has five playable races to choose from in character creation. The races will have very minor attribute differences, and these differences will not be as exaggerated as in Final Fantasy XI. In regards to gender, there are no attribute differences between male and female characters of the same race.ElezenThe Elezen are nomadic people whose race used to lay total claim over the land of Eorzea and predated all the other races onthe lands of Eorzea. Beleiving this prominence to be ordained by the gods, they came to develop an esteemed sense of honor and pride. The Elezen are a characteristically tall, sporting slim physiques and large ears, which are so sensitive they can discern the squeak of a field mouse from several malms out.Elezen players will be able to choose between the "Wildwood" and "Duskwight" factions.Elezen are essentially Elves.LalafellThe diminutive Lalafell were originally a group of agriculturalists that used to live in the south seas. Thanks to transmarine commerce they found their way through the trade routes of Eorzea." Their race now is one of the most populated races in the region of Eorzea. Lalafells are extremely agile and are able to travel long distances due to their legs. Many of the Lalafells are also very intelligent and highly developed individuals. This race continues to be one of the friendliest races welcoming any outsider.Lalafell players will be able to choose between the "Plainsfolk" and "Dunesfolk" factions.Lalafell are similar to the Tarutaru race from Final Fantasy XI.HyurThe Hyur traveled across the sea to Eorzea from neighboring continents. Three massive migratory waves gave this race the highest population in the land of Eorzea. The Hyur brought massive amounts of technology to Eorzea and drove the cultural and technological progress for all those that reside in Eorzea. They also brought a very complex ethos. The Hyur are extremely focused on the individual and this initially caused a large conflict with the Elezen. Hyur can be found mainly among the Highlanders in the mountainous areas and the Midlanders who live in the lower elevations.Hyur players will be able to choose between the "Midlanders" and "Highlanders". Players who choose the Highlander faction will only be able to play as a male character.Hyur are Human in all but name.RoegadynThe Roegadyn are found in the northern areas of Eorzea. This is where they came from when they landed on the shores ofEorzea and remain a maritime people. Members of the race have a large muscular build and highly value competitiveness and unflinching courage. Most Roegadyn remain seaman located in the Limsa Lominsa area. Many have adventured out into the world to become bodyguards, mercenaries and even pirates by trade. Some Roegadyns have moved high up into the mountains of Ul'dah and become known as the Hellsguard, Roegadyn that have mastered magical arts.Roegadyn players will be able to choose between the "Seawolf Tribe" and the "Hellsgaurd Tribe" factions.Roegadyn are similar to the Galka race from Final Fantasy XI.Beginning in A Realm Reborn, female Roegadyn characters were introduced, and are a playable variation of the race.Miqo'teThe Miqo'te originated from hunting tribes that found Eorzea's seas turning the "Age of Endless Frost". At that time the land was covered by ice and passage between the islands was possible, which lead to an influx of foreign fauna which were hunted by the descendants of the Miqo'te. The Miqo'te belong to two different groups, the Seekers of the Sun and the nocturnal Keepers of the Moon. Both groups share an olfactory sense and powerful leg musculature which evolved from their past hunting andpredation. This race chooses to be very isolated and avoids contact with the other races even when they reside in the large populated cities.Miqo'te players will be able to choose between the "Seekers of the Sun" and "Keepers of the Moon" factions. Players who play as Miqo'te will only be able to play as a female character, however, Square Enix has stated that male Miqo'te do exist in the lore of Final Fantasy XIV.Miqo'te are basically nekomata, popularly known outside of Japan as "catgirls".Beginning in A Realm Reborn, Male Miqo'te were introduced, and are a playable variation of the Miqo'te race.City-StatesUl'dahFar to the South, in the deserts of Aldenard, lies the bustling commercial hub of Ul'dah. Many walls and fortifications have been built up aroundUl'dah bannerthe characteristic dome-shaped citadel at its center. The city is a well-known center of wealth, and as such, gambling and recreational activities form a large part of daily life. The sultan serves as a sort of figurehead for the city's leadership, but it is the Syndicate, a group of six powerful merchants, who wield the real political power.Limsa LominsaLimsa Lominsa bannerLimsa Lominsa is located off the southern coast of the island of Vylbrand, under the shadow of ancient cliffs carved by the relentless Rhotano Sea. The city is actually placed on many different islands or man-made formations known as sea stacks. Bridges span across each island in a kind of latticework pattern; a sight so beautiful, bards have named it "The Navigator's Veil." The goddess Llymlaen is said to have blessed Limsa Lominsa because she took pity on the sailors of a great armada that had to flee from battle. The rocks destroyed their ships and with no means to travel and no home to return to they settled in the islands using the remaining vessels that they had to begin construction. The people of Limsa Lominsa did not forget their old ways, but merely gathered strength to rebuild and adventure out again. Their influence soonspread throughout the five seas of Eorzea. These legends formed the backbone of their society and their country's leader is referred to as "Admiral."The shipping industry is key to Limsa Lominsa's financial success. The Knights of the Barracuda secure the safety of mariners and ensure the safety and reliability of shipping route's. However, piracy, reaving and pillaging still runs rampant and other nations believe that the Knights of the Barracuda are actually working with local bandit pirates and are trying to make a profit off unwary travelers.GridaniaGridania bannerGridania is located in the Eastern reaches of the continent, and is nestled among the great woodlands of the area. The architecture blends seamlessly with the surrounding natural beauty, and the inherent natural harmony of the setting has lead to Gridania's prominence in trades such as forestry, carpentry, and agriculture. Gridania is also home to many skilled leather-workers, and the fate of the city is governed by the will of the forest's elementals.IshgardBastion atop the mountains. A forest city-state located in Eorzea. A story in Eorzean history, "Tales of Bridges," describes Ishgard.TravelAetheryteThe Aetheryte is the name placed upon the large crystal shards found in the crystallized aetheric mist. They were precisely cut and fused to arcane machinery. These crystals are at the backbone of all everyday teleportation and are found throughout the realm, mainly in the individual city-states in which they are managed and operated. The origins and functions of these crystals is still very much a mystery. It is not known who constructed these crystals or what they were originally used for. Even though they are commonly used for teleportation, the actual process remains unknown. However, some have theorized that when a sentient presence approaches the crystal, it triggers the aether of the crystal and the body resonates with the crystal, breaking down into simple mass which then flows through the invisible aetheric streams of the planet. The person's soul is what actually guides the particles to the pre-determined destination and the crystal reconfigures the mist back into its original form. This is all instantaneous and this make easy travel to the far reaches of the world. However, one may only use the crystal so much as when the body is broken down to the aetheric level, a great toll is taken on one's body. Distance and use is the biggest factor when using the Aetheryte to travel and if one uses it too much in a sort span of time, irreversible damage can take effect.AethernetThe Athernet is made up of smaller scale Aetheryte crystals inside a city. They are used for quick travel between locations inside the city. As with the larger Aetheryte crystals, you have attune yourself to an Aethernet crystal in order to be able to teleport to that crystal's location. However unlike Aetheryte crystals, teleporting within a city using the Aethernet is not limited by your anima.ChocobosOne of the character mascots of the Final Fantasy series, Chocobos are available as player mounts within the word of Eorzea. You can either rent a chocobo within the three city-states for 80 gil, or you can get your own personal chocobo. You must attain an enlisted rank within one of the three Grand Companies of Eorzea, and have 1,000 Grand Company seals in order to purchase a Chocobo Whistle, which can be used thereafter to call upon your own personal "horsebird".When you have your Grand Company Chocobo, you can consume the "Gyshal Green" item and your chocobo will fight alongside you as a companion.GoobbueHulking giant monsters with dozens of teeth, these mounts see the player sitting atop them on a rug, legs crossed, while traversing the environment. These beasts run at the same speed as chocobos. Available to players in January 2012, the Goobbue mount was a thank you gift given to all players who played during the period from billing start on January 6, 2012, until August 13, 2012. There are no plans for this mount to be made available again.Magitek Armor and Future MountsUpon the launch of A Realm Reborn, Magitek Armor (Previously featured in Final Fantasy VI) will be available as a mount to players, though the method of acquiring it has not be determined yet. There will also be other mounts available in the future. Some ideas discussed have been Courels (Preorder bonus), Ahriman (Veteran Reward), Drakes, and more.Character CreationMaking a character involves selecting one's race, physical appearance, and world server. Among the options for customizing are various face and hair styles, eye color adjustments, and characteristics such as battle scars, tattoos, bust size for females, muscle tone for males, voice type, etc. Each character must be equipped with a first and last name, the latter of which is mandatory.PC System RequirementsThe following are the PC specs required for Final Fantasy XIV: A Realm Reborn.Minimum System RequirementsOSWindows® Vista 32/64bit, Windows® 7 32/64 bitCPUIntel® Core™2 DuoMemory2GB (4GB recommended for 64bit OS)Available space on hard disk/SSD20GBGraphics CardNVIDIA® Geforce® 8800 or higher, ATI Radeon™ HD 4770 or higherScreen Resolution1280x720InternetPersistent broadband internet connection requiredSound CardDirectSound® compatible sound card (DirectX® 9.0c or higher)DirectX®DirectX® 9.0c or higherRecommended System RequirementsOSWindows® 7 64 bitCPUIntel® Core™ i5Memory4GBAvailable space on hard disk/SSD20GBGraphics CardNVIDIA® Geforce® GTX 660 or higher, AMD Radeon™ HD 7950 or higherScreen Resolution1920x1080InternetPersistent broadband internet connection requiredSound CardDirectSound® compatible sound card (DirectX® 9.0c or higher）DirectX®DirectX® 9.0c or higher* NVIDIA® SLI™ and AMD CrossFire™ support will be available at release.Subscription Information and PricingFinal Fantasy XIV: A Realm Reborn is a pay-to-play MMORPG, in much the same way as Final Fantasy XI and World of Warcraft. With the purchase of A Realm Reborn, players receive a thirty-day free trial.The following pricing structure will go into effect at launch:MembershipMonthly Price(Total Price)Max Charactersper serverMax Characterson AccountSub. LengthLegacy$9.99 / £6.89 / 9.99 €84030 daysStandard$12.99 / £7.69/ 10.99 € ($71.44 / £46.14 / 65.94 €)840180 days$13.99 / £8.39/ 11.99 € ($41.97/ £25.17 / 35.97 €)84090 days$14.99 / £8.99/ 12.99 €84030 daysEntry$12.99 / £7.69/ 10.99€1830 days* All subscription fees are subject to change in accordance with the terms of the FINAL FANTASY XIV User Agreement.Legacy MembershipThis is a program which provides several benefits for those who subscribed to the original version for at least 90 cumulative days during the time the game required a subscription fee to play.Legacy members will be able to play at a specially discounted subscription price.Legacy members will receive an exclusive in-game Chocobo mount.Legacy members can request that their name be displayed in the credits.Legacy members will receive early access to A Realm Reborn.Veteran RewardsVeteran Rewards are special in game item bonuses that are awarded to players based on how long they've had an active subscription.RankRewardRank 1 (30 Days)- Wind Up Cursor Minion- Phial of Fantasia (Allows for character appearance to be changed)Rank 2 (60 Days)- Black Chocobo Chick Minion- Cascadier Uniform Voucher (Voucher to obtain black swimwear)Rank 3 (90 Days)- Beady Eye Minion- Voidal Resonator (Ahriman Mount)Rank 4 (120 days) and onwardRewards for longer periods will be announced at a later date.Rewards are granted based on the number of days subscribed, not time played. For example, if you pay for 90 days of service at once, you will receive the 30, 60, and 90 day rewards all at once on the first day, and not on day 30, 60, and 90 respectively.Payment MethodsThe following methods can be used to pay A Realm Reborn's subscription fees.Credit Cards or Debit CardsAccepted are VISA, MasterCard, American Express, DISCOVER, and JCB from directly within the SQUARE ENIX Account system.Square Enix CrystaCrysta can be added to a Square Enix account using a payment method such as a credit card, PayPal, or Ultimate Game Card (PayPal and UGC available through the "UltimatePay/PlaySpan option) and then used for various services such as subscription fees.Prepaid Time CardPrepaid time cards will also be available upon game launch at retailers. They will offer 30 or 60 days of play time for the appropriate price in each region the game is available.* Additional payment options may be introduced in the future.Preorder/Collector's Edition BonusesA Realm RebornPreorder BonusesBy preordering either the Collector's or Regular package of A Ream Reborn, you will receive:Early Game Access beginning August 24, 2013Two In-Game Items: Cait Sith Doll Minion and a Mog CapCollector's EditionThose who purchase the Collector's Edition of A Realm Reborn on either PC or PS3 will receive 7 additional bonuses:Exclusive box art by Yoshitaka Amano"The Art of Eorzea - A Realm Re-imagined" - 80 page art book by Akihiko Yoshida"The Waning of the Sixth Sun" - DVD showcasing the stories leading up to the destruction of the original game world.Four In-Game Items -Players will receive the Helm of Light, a Coeurl Mount, Behemoth Barding for their Chocobo, and a Baby Behemoth Minion pet."Sounds of Eorzea" - A Special soundtrack CD with music from the cities and fields of Limsa Lominsa, Ul'dah and Gridania.Art Card Set - Five art cards featuring art by Square Enix Visual Works.Themed Security Token - An "A Realm Reborn" themed Security Token which can been used to make your account more secure.* Players will be able to upgrade their standard accounts to Collector's Edition status after game launch for $19.99/¥2,300 (EU Pricing not yet available). This purchase will give players the CE In-Game items only.Version 1.0The Collector's Edition, released a full eight days prior to the release of the standard edition, contained the following in addition to those items included with the standard edition:Early AccessBehind-the-Scenes DVDSecurity TokenTravel JournalRight of Passage - A personalized certificate with a unique serial numberBuddy Pass - Lets a friend play free for a limited timeLinksOfficial Players Website: http://lodestone.finalfantasyxiv.com/pl/index.htmlOfficial Promotional Website: http://www.finalfantasyxiv.com/</description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18547">EverQuest II</game><game id="12149">Dark Age of Camelot</game><game id="12376">The Lord of the Rings Online: Shadows of Angmar</game><game id="24057">Demon's Souls</game><game id="32295">EverQuest: House of Thule</game><game id="26770">Rift</game><game id="17494">Guild Wars</game><game id="11082">Guild Wars: Nightfall</game><game id="8474">Guild Wars: Factions</game><game id="21223">Guild Wars 2</game><game id="23702">Guild Wars Bonus Mission Pack</game><game id="18110">Guild Wars: Eye of the North</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/99864/2533964-678050_272308_front.jpg</image></root>