<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26913</id><name>Watchmen: The End is Nigh Part 2</name><description>OverviewWatchmen: The End is Nigh Part 2 is the sequel to the Watchmen: The End is Nigh, a downloadable game released to tie in with the movie. Part 2 was released around four months after the first, with the downloadable version coming July 30, 2009 and the disc compilation release coming out July 21, 2009. Like the first it was developed by Deadline Games and published by Warner Bros. Interactive Entertainment.  StoryWhereas the first game took place in 1972 with Nite Owl and Rorschach hunting down one of their arch enemies, this game takes place in 1977. Rorschach has received a film reel of an underage girl (Violet Greene) in what appears to be a pornographic film being mistreated. The duo set out after realizing where the film was shot and begin their search for the girl. Nite Owl believes the film was shot near a pier where a strip club is located. They infiltrate said strip club while beating up on thugs. Here they realize that Twilight Lady is behind it, an old flame of Nite Owl's. As soon as they hit the streets heading for her mansion, they realize the streets need to be cleaned up a little. Once they get to Twilight Lady's mansion, they find her as well as Violet Greene. To their surprise, Violet is 18 years old and perfectly fine with this line of work, as she "makes more money then her deadbeat father." Nite Owl reluctantly decides to drop the matter but Rorschach has other plans. He wants to get Twilight Lady; in his eyes she is filth and should be eliminated. They chase her towards to the roof of the mansion were Nite Owl and Rorschach ultimately fight. Depending on who wins the ending of the game is different.Xbox 360 HD Installation The optional installation requires 2.2 GB of hard drive space.  </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10026">300: March to Glory</game><game id="34">Batman Begins</game><game id="6722">Final Fight</game><game id="922">Final Fight: Streetwise</game><game id="21559">Marvel Ultimate Alliance 2</game><game id="5614">Spider-Man 3</game><game id="20258">Spider-Man: Friend or Foe</game><game id="20034">Spider-Man &amp; Venom: Maximum Carnage</game><game id="20436">Streets of Rage</game><game id="16206">The Warriors</game><game id="15532">Urban Reign</game><game id="24747">X-Men Origins: Wolverine</game><game id="20762">Spider-Man: Web of Shadows</game><game id="30469">Kick-Ass</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1858026-box_wteinp2.png</image></root>