<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26921</id><name>Pokémon Rumble</name><description>GameplayYou can control your own Toy Pokemon through dungeons and arenas in melee based combat. The player starts out with a low level common pokemon and grinds through battles with wild pokemon where you can collect coins which allow you to buy new attacks or recruit new pokemon. Eventually when the player obtains a high enough level pokemon, the Battle Royale arena opens. In the Battle Royale arena, the player can take on dozens of pokemon at once and must defeat them all to rank up, while facing stronger and stronger pokemon along the way.   Stages are broken up into several segments, always ending in a boss battle with a large version of a pokemon. Once the boss is defeated, he may be recruited.  The game supports up to four players at once in both co-op and competitive modes. It also has a password system for unlocking new pokemon.    Special TraitsPokemon Rumble introduced "special traits" for certain pokemon. The special trait is something individual pokemon can possess. These pokemon will sparkle different colors when defeated. Some of the traits include stat altering traits which give the pokemon a higher attack power or more HP. Other traits include "guard" traits which make the pokemon resistant to certain types of enemy attacks.   Release TicketsIf a player releases a pokemon, an release ticket can be picked up. Releasing five of the same type of pokemon will give the player a ticket for the next stage of evolution. Releasing five of the highest stage of evolution will give the player a ticket for the basic form of pokemon. Pokemon without any evolution forms will not produce tickets. Some combination of tickets redeemed at a special building in the game will result in rare pokemon tickets.   These are the ticket combinations for the US version:   Five Mothim = Burmy Trash/Sandy/Plant Cloak Ticket Pidgeot, Fearow, Jynx, Lapras = Articuno Ticket Dragonite, Bastiodon, Garchomp, Lucario, Magnezone = Dialga Ticket Gyarados, Empoleon, Garchomp, Blastoise, Dragonite = Palkia Ticket Heat Rotom, Wash Rotom, Cut Rotom, Frost Rotom, Spin Rotom = Darkrai Ticket Five East Sea Shellos = West Sea Gastrodon Ticket Dragonite, Gengar, Spiritomb, Garchomp, Dusknoir = Giratina Ticket Dialga, Palkia, Giratina = Mewtwo Ticket Three Phione = Manaphy Ticket Magmar, Pidgeot, Fearow, Charizard = Moltres Ticket Vaporeon, Lapras = Phione Ticket Five East Sea Gastrodon = West Sea Shallos Ticket Rotom, Jolteon = Spin Rotom Ticket Rotom, Vaporeon = Wash Rotom Ticket Rotom, Glaceon = Frost Rotom Ticket Rotom, Flareon = Heat Rotom Ticket Rotom, Leafeon = Cut Rotom Ticket Charizard, Arcanine, Arbok, Kangaskhan, Bastiodon = Shaymin Land Form Ticket Five Grass Cloak Burmy = Wormadam Trash/Sandy/Grass Cloak Ticket Electabuzz, Raichu, Pidgeot, Fearow = Zapdos Ticket Five West Sea Shellos = East Sea Gastrodon Five West Sea Gastrodon = East Sea Shellos  Passwords If you head over to the recruitment building and enter these passwords in the terminal, you can get special Pokemon. These are for the US Version of the game only.    1589-3955 = Venusaur 7540-5667 = Cherrim Positive Form 0511-0403 = Eevee 9580-1423 = Blastoise 9561-8808 = Mew 8672-1076 = Turtwig 7968-4528 = Charizard 9849-3731 = Shiny Rattata 8322-3706 = Giratina (Origin Form) 5468-6284 = Shaymin (Sky Form) 5575-2435 = Shiny Bidoof 7927-6161 = Charmander 6824-2045 = Squirtle 8109-8304 = Chimchar 9900-2455 = PiplupCards: There was also promotional cards featuring rumble pokemon.</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23375">Gangway Monsters</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5150/1192251-500x_pokemon_rumble_logo.jpg</image></root>