<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26967</id><name>Lemonade Tycoon</name><description>IntroductionSell, sell, sell and be the envy of the block. Lemonade Tycoon, is a business simulation game. Remember profit is king.Game-playBasic Rules of the GamePlayers manage many aspects of owning their very own business; while selling as much lemonade as possible.Choosing recipes, set prices, and sell lemonade in a variety of locations, are important factors in advancing in the game.The money the player earns from selling lemonade is used to replenish supplies (lemons, sugar, water and cups) and spend on advertising, which increases the potential number of customers you can have in a day.Players can also buy upgrades to aid them such as ice makers, and employees such as a cashier or clown, which reduce wait time and increase patience.Other FactorsLocation also plays a factor, there are a total of five different locations a player can set up a stand at, each costing a certain amount of money for rent. Each location has its own popularity and satisfaction stats, which are based on the players' performance.Changing weather and news are some of the things the player must compensate for. Players have a variety of upgrades to buy in order to overcome some factors, such as long lines and stock.Game ModesThere are three game modes in Lemonade Tycoon1. Career ; play for as long as you want.2. Challenge; 30 day limit to sell your lemonade.3. Champion.Using the money they earned from selling lemonade, players will have to buy supplies such as lemons, cups, sugar and water. Money can also be spent for advertisement,Other Information about the GameInitially released as Lemonade Inc., Lemonade Tycoon is a Shockwave-based game. A limited, but free version is available for online play at many sites. The full version with no time restrictions can be purchased online.The game saw releases on a variety of platforms including PC, Palm devices, and various mobile phones. An iPhone version of the game was released in 2009 by Electronic Arts.</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17392">Lemonade Stand</game><game id="23173">Plant Tycoon</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4647/1048710-lemonade_tycoon_big.jpg</image></root>