<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27025</id><name>NHL 2K10</name><description> NHL 2K10 Feature ListNew Game Features 2K Share (Allows you to share sliders, rosters, player dna's, draft classes etc.)Wii Motion Plus (Enhanced Wii Remote control scheme)Mii Superskills (New Mii integration in a set of mini-games based on the all star skills events)Classic Controller Support on the Wii version this yearNew Uniform editing suite for created teams, that can be taken into franchiseImproved Graphics (brand new player models and faces)Playoff / International Tournament ModeNew Team Budget system in franchise that has owners setting new salary restrictions year to year based on team performanceFantasy Drafts (Franchise Mode)New unique arena intros for all 30 teams    New Gameplay FeaturesStumble ShotsImproved AIOvi-Dekes1on1 and Power MovesStick Lifts  New Online FeaturesFranchise games are now playable onlineTeam Up Mode allows you to create a uniform or persistent identity for your teamFranchise BloggingWii version now playable online this yearWii version supports Wii Speak    NHL 2K10 Soundtrack 1901 - Phoenix Skeleton Boy - Friendly Fires Feel.Love.Thinking.Of - The Faunts Time to Pretend - MGMT Too Fake - Hockey Take My Everything - War Stories Superstar - Lupe Fiasco feat. Matthew Santos Blue Day - Darker My Love Crowd Chant - Joe Satriani The Stuff - Tin Foil Phoenix The Victim - 2nd Day Crush Anything At All - Fono Take it Back - 20 Pound Shovel Future Releases of NHL 2K series This will be the last game (in the foreseeable future) that will be released on the Xbox 360 and Playstation 3, Take-Two announced they would only be releasing a Nintendo Wii version in 2010 (NHL 2K11). </description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="39">Hockey</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26458">NHL 10</game><game id="24738">3 on 3 NHL Arcade</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2222543-box_nhl2k10.png</image></root>