<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27063</id><name>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Turtles in Time Re-Shelled</name><description>OverviewTeenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Turtles in Time Re-Shelled is a remake of the arcade version of                Turtles in Time. The game has newly retooled 3D graphics, but very similar gameplay of the original. Along with the graphics, the game includes new music and voice acting done by the cast of the 2003 animated series. The price was originally 1200             Microsoft points ($15), but was lowered to 800 points ($10). As of July 1, 2011, Turtles in Time Re-Shelled was pulled from Xbox Live Arcade and Playstation Network along with the XBLA version of TMNT: 1989 Arcade.Modes of Play    Re-Shelled adds another dimension of movement from the original game.     All of these modes feature both local and online multiplayer up to four players. The modes can be played on either easy, medium, hard, or hardcore difficulties. There is also an online leader-board. Story ModePlay through the nine stages of the game. Your amount of starting lives depends on the difficulty you choose.Quickplay ModePick and play any level that you've previously completed. Your amount of starting lives depends on the difficulty you choose.Survival Mode See how long you can last against            Shredder's wrath! This is essentially just story mode, except everyone starts with only a single life. Why Isn't This Like the One I Remember?It's because the one you remember is most likely the           SNES version. Or maybe the Genesis-related release of                Hyperstone Heist. This game is a remake of the arcade version, which came out a little before the SNES version, and has a few differences.Levels and Bosses (Arcade vs. SNES)          Tokka and         Rahzar are the bosses of the Skull and Crossbones level in place of the SNES version's        Bebop and       Rocksteady.Punching Robots are some of your enemies, rather than the Roadkill Rodneys. The      Rat King is not the final boss of the 3rd stage. There is no final boss.There is no     Technodrome level like in the SNES version, meaning no additional Shredder boss. Cement Man is the boss of the Prehistoric Turtlesaurus level in place of the SNES version's    Slash. There are no Foot Soldiers disguised as curtains in the stage Bury My Shell at Wounded Knee.The Neon-Night Riders stage is played from a tradition side-scrolling 2D perspective, rather than from the SNES's behind-the-back perspective.Shredder is the final boss of the final stage in place of the SNES version's Super Shredder.Gameplay Differences (Remake vs. Arcade/SNES)Attacks can now also be dealt  vertically and diagonally as opposed to previous versions which only allowed you to attack left or right.A   double jump can be executed in the remake, compared to only a single jump with older versions.You can't continuously front flip across the screen like in the SNES version.Using  special attacks no longer takes away some of your life bar.</description><genres><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20733">Castle Crashers</game><game id="14351">Golden Axe</game><game id="20717">Spyborgs</game><game id="20436">Streets of Rage</game><game id="18122">Streets of Rage 2</game><game id="15924">Streets of Rage 3</game><game id="6722">Final Fight</game><game id="14608">Final Fight 2</game><game id="8241">Final Fight 3</game><game id="5231">Final Fight CD</game><game id="27973">Penalty of Heroes</game><game id="20754">Double Dragon Advance</game><game id="29491">Scott Pilgrim vs. The World: The Game</game><game id="39520">Crisis Heart Brawlers: Clash at Otakon</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1797246-box_tmntrs.png</image></root>