<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27113</id><name>Record of Agarest War</name><description>OverviewRecord of Agarest War (also known as Agarest: Generations of War) is an RPG that was initially released for the PlayStation 3. An updated port of the game was made for North America on both the Xbox 360 and Playstation 3 (via PSN). The game is also set to be released for PC via Steam on October 3, 2013.StoryThe story follows Leonhardt, a man of noble birth with the misfortune of being the last member of a disgraced house. Leonhardt turns his back on the war and his country to save an elven girl and in doing so he is mortally wounded by the Dark Knight, he then swears that he and all his descendants will be a spirit vessel for a mysterious woman called Dyshana, if she will grant him power so he can protect the elven girl.GameplayFighting plays out like a strategic RPG where each character can perform various moves, characters can perform collaborative attacks if they are in the extended area of another character and as the battle progresses the player builds up SP which can be used to pull off 'extra skills' which allow you to deal large amounts of damage. When the game progresses, you will be able to adjust the field of battle prior to beginning the fight.The game includes dating sim elements through its "Soul Breed" system. As the player progresses through the game they can pursue one of three heroines. At the end of the generation, you will be able to pick one of heroines if their affection level is high enough. You will then have a child with the chosen character, the appearance, stats and abilities will vary depending on which heroine chosen. There are over 1000 combinations for the child's stats and abilities. You will then take control of the fully grown version of your child and continue the story. This happens four times in the game, totaling five generations of characters.There is also a moral choice system that influences the story.Limited EditionNaughty Limited Edition.The 360 exclusive "Really Naughty Limited Edition" includes:Yearning Ellis pillowcase (pillow not included)Sensual Vira-Lorr mouse padRecord of Agarest War SoundtrackNaughty Collectors Box to protect your girls$59.99 USDDownloadable ContentRecently the Xbox 360 has added DLC including these packs. Keep in mind all purchases are non refundable, thus information on what is contained in all packs are listed. The stats for these items have also been listed so you know exactly what you're buying.General purpose Pack - 80 Microsoft points and includes:1 Magic Blade, 1 Partisan, 1 Battle Frame, 1 Bracelet of Feicui, and 1 Item Drop Rate Up, as well as 2 Shiny Fangs, and 2 Advanced Heals.Item NameATKDEFMAGRSTHITAVDMOVSTRVITAGIINTLUKAPRGBRKMagic Blade3240342810000300501190Partisan44201340100000000012126Battle Frame1224008000010000000Bracelet of Feicui0200020000000000100Magic-Fighter Pack - 80 Microsoft points and includes:1 Vajra Rod, 1 Magic Hand, 1 Madu, 1 Ymir's Claw, and 1 Hidden Seeker.*Unknown Stats For Vajra Rod And Hidden Seeker*Item NameATKDEFMAGRSTHITAVDMOVSTRVITAGIINTLUKAPRGBRKMagic Hand235051781501600008541114Madu48011240090000900021156Ymir's Claw3760376014012002000031102Offense-defense Pack - 40 Microsoft Points and includes:1 Adaka, 1 Shield Sword, 1 Bird Eye, 1 Magic Frame, 1 Critical Hit, and 2 Seeds of Happiness.Item NameATKDEFMAGRSTHITAVDMOVSTRVITAGIINTLUKAPRGBRKAdaka20712138100900030000186Shield Sword2125162010590060000143Bird Eye016801121212000100000Magic Frame(Resists HP Drain)0112616800000010000Tonight's dinner pack - 160 Microsoft points and includes:1 Carrot Sword, 1 Chicken Emblem, 1 Chicken Ring, 1 Hiyoko Charm, and 1 Float.*Unknown Stats For Carrot Sword and Hiyoko Charm*Item NameATKDEFMAGRSTHITAVDMOVSTRVITAGIINTLUKAPRGBRKChicken Emblem0150015000000000100Chicken Ring000000000000000Additional Points pack 1 - 80 Microsoft points and includes:10,000G, 100PP, 250TP, and 500EP.Additional points pack 2 - 160 Microsoft points and includes:100,000G, 5,000EP, 250PP and 500TPBasic pack - 40 Microsoft points and includes:1 each of Resurrect, Capture, and Resist Direction, 2 each of Heal and Refresh, and 5 Vessels of Life.F-Fishy Pack 1 - 80 Microsoft points and includes:1 Marble Beast Claw, 1 Blood Fang, 1 Scarlet Claw, 1 Large Marble Claw, 1 Large Blood Fang, and 1 Scarlet Fang.Flower Pack - 40 Microsoft points and Includes:1 Lucky Charm, 1 HP Up, 1 Resist Ailments, 1 Restore HP 15%, and 1 Restore AP , as well as 2 Moonlight Flowers, and 3 Tree Spirit Souls.Jack Pack - 80 Microsoft points and includes:1 Mugen's Craw, 1 Sarnga, 1 Soul Sucker, 1 Sanctuary, 1 Extra Heal, 1 Resurrection, 1 HP Up , and 1 Resist AilmentsRecovery-Skill Pack - 40 Microsoft points and includes:2 Light Heals, 2 Harvest Heals, and 2 Cure All's, as well as 1 Prayer, 1 Gospel, and 1 Counter.Upgrade Pack 1 - 80 Microsoft points and includes:10 STR Up, 10 VIT Up, 10 AGI Up, 10 INT Up, 10 LUK Up and 10 Max HP Up, and 1 Resist HP Drain and 1 Resist HP Break.Upgrade pack 2 - 80 Microsoft points and includes:10 STR Up , 10 VIT Up , 10 AGI Up , 10 INT Up , 10 LUK Up , and 10 Max HP Up , as well as 1 Magic Up and 1 Resist Magic Up.Versions DifferencesThe North America release on both platforms has added content such as extra voice acting, a gallery to view CG and a change to the art used in game, compared to the original PS3 release in Japan.SoundtrackThe music for the game was composed by Kenji Kaneko. The "Really Naughty Limited Edition" version released on the 360 came with a soundtrack CD with this tracklist:Agarest War SuiteAwakeningThe 1st Generation ThemeAn Adventure StoryDon’t Wait For MePantheonWith Light StepsThe Eye7th Ave.Breeze Of TimeChoose The WayWild LifeThe PriestMain EventFrom The DepthsPasswordTension And AngerWheel Of FortuneVisionaryThe HuntCity LifeShall I Help?The OracleCalm ForestThe Earth MemoriesXxxplosionPC System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows XPProcessor: 1.7GHz i3Memory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: DirectX 9.0c compatible graphics card with 64Mb RAM and support for v3 shadersDirectX: Version 9.0cHard Drive: 5 GB available spaceSound Card: DirectX 9.0c compatible sound cardRecommendedOS: Windows XP or laterProcessor: 2 Ghz i5 ProcessorMemory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: DirectX 9.0c compatible graphics card with 128Mb RAM and support for v3 shadersDirectX: Version 9.0cHard Drive: 5 GB available spaceSound Card: DirectX 9.0c compatible sound card</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20939">Disgaea 3: Absence of Justice</game><game id="18253">Phantasy Star III: Generations of Doom</game><game id="32698">Disgaea 4: A Promise Unforgotten</game><game id="23693">Cross Edge</game><game id="19864">Final Fantasy Tactics</game><game id="31284">Hyperdimension Neptunia</game><game id="28333">Record of Agarest War Zero</game><game id="35687">Rainbow Moon</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2188519-box_roaw.png</image></root>