<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27139</id><name>Worms 2: Armageddon</name><description>OverviewWorms 2: Armageddon is a turn based strategy game released on Xbox Live Arcade on July 1 2009 and is priced at 800MS points. No release date or price has been announced for the PC and Mac versions.Weapons and UtilitiesNew Weapons: • Gas Pump• Poison Strike: Give them a does of Worm flu. • Super Bunker Buster: Massive underground charge.Returning Weapons:• Air Strike• Armageddon: It's in the title so it's gotta be good! • Banana Bomb• Baseball Bat: Whack those enemy Worms right out of the ballpark (or at least into the water)!  • Bazooka: Bazooka.• Buffalo Of Lies: The Donkey’s nemesis. It's full of lies and explosives. Acts like the Mad Cow. • Bunker Buster: Dropped out of the sky. Digs through the terrain to attack enemy Worms that are hidden beneath.• Cluster Bomb: Grenade x5.• Concrete Donkey: The Donkey's back and ready to kick some worm tail (Do worms even have tails? Well, it'll kill them anyway). • Dragon Ball: Can you say 'Kamehameha'?• Dynamite: And BOOM! Goes the dynamite.• Earthquake: Don't be near any edges when this thing goes off or you might find yourself sliding down into a watery grave. • Fire Punch• Grenade• Holy Hand Grenade: Have faith in it. Hallelujah! • Homing Missile• Kamikaze• Lightning Strike: Raises Worms from the dead. Also heals alive ones!• Mine: A mine, detonates if you walk near it.• Napalm Strike: I love the smell of burning Worms in the morning! • Petrol Bomb: All you need is; Petrol, a Bottle and a rag and buddy, you got yourself a genuine Worm roasting weapon! • Sentry Gun: Helps defend a position by automatically firing towards enemy movement. "Sentry goin' up!" • Sheep: A kamikaze sheep that hops around.• Shotgun: You don't wanna be in it's firing path.• Super Sheep: A flying, fully controllable, kamikaze sheep. 'nuff said.• Uzi: Just your regular good'ol Uzi.New Utilities:• Electromagnet: Attract or repel metallic explosives.   • Emergency Teleport: Beam us up, Scotty. Returning Utilities:•  Blow Torch: Tunnel through the map.•  Jet Pack: Makes you fly.•  Ninja Rope: Swing, like a Ninja!•  Parachute: Ever lost a Worm to a bad rope jump? Sure you have. This will help you though!   •  Pneumatic Drill: Get up-close and personal with those underground or hard to get to Worms.  •  Prod: Poke.•  Teleport: Beam me up, Scotty.•  Girder: Gives you protection.•  Bridge Kit: Protection x5.•  Skip Go: Skip your turn.•  Surrender: Loser.New Additions:  • 5 all new landscapes including: Medieval England, Cheese Moon, Construction site and more. • 130 base landscape styles (compared to just six on original) for diverse play levels.• Vertical Levels. Play on tall, narrow strips or caverns rather than the traditional 'wide’ levels.• Mix combination of landscape type, style and your own game rules to create tons of new levels!• Fort Mode! Start teams on your own bases.• Rope Racing mode.• Fire. Eats and burns away the landscape and well as any Worms that get in the way!• Unlockable items. Win tokens in the new 30 chapter single player campaign unlock prizes in the game shop including new new landscapes, voices, hats and more.• More customization for your Worms.  Battle Pack DLCAs of 7th July 2010, a downloadable content pack for Worms 2 Armageddon is available via Xbox live.  The pack costs 400 Microsoft Points. Contents: 30 New single player levels. Body Count mode. 6 New weapons and utilities. 10 new fort maps. Customization for player units.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4153">Bomberman Live</game><game id="24008">Battle Zone</game><game id="24430">Bomberman Ultra</game><game id="2430">Bomberman</game><game id="20715">Rocket Riot</game><game id="16885">Hogs of War</game><game id="15697">Gunbound</game><game id="13773">Soldat</game><game id="12653">Scorched Earth</game><game id="30602">War Pig</game><game id="30148">Worms Reloaded</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1798135-box_worms2a.png</image></root>