<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27147</id><name>Color-Changing: Tingle's Balloon Trip of Love</name><description>Color Changing Tingle's Love Balloon Trip  ( いろづきチンクルの恋のバルーントリップ  Irozuki Chinkuru no Koi no Barūn Torippu? ,  "Ripening Tingle's Balloon Trip of Love") is an adventure video game developed by          Vanpool and published by          Nintendo for the         Nintendo DS.  It is a sequel to the game        Freshly-Picked Tingle's Rosy Rupeeland and was released in Japan on August 6, 2009.  As its predecessor, the game focuses on       Tingle, a character from   The Legend of Zelda series. Game PlayThe player has to solve many puzzles that require the wise use of the  different abilities of Tingle's three partners. Kakashi lacks  intelligence, but is small and therefore able to get into small places.  Buriki is very intelligent, but heartless, and can cleverly solve  puzzles Tingle's other partners won't be able to do so. The party's last  member, Lion, is more powerful than the other two partners, but  cowardly. Many of the actions in the game are performed via the stylus.  Another central gameplay element is the romantic interaction with five  different female characters. The player has to find the right words  during the dialogues and to give Tingle's love interests the best  fitting items in order to win their favor. This is necessary for  continuing the adventure. In order to complete the game, Tingle must  have some degree of a relationship with all of the girls. Unlike its  predecessor, Color Changing Tingle's Love Balloon Trip is completely touch screen controlled. PlotThe game's storyline starts with an ordinary 35-year-old man who watches  a direct sales program on television.  He orders a book that is said to  make its readers popular among women.  When the man opens the book, he  gets sucked into a picture book world.  In this world, he becomes  Tingle, wearing a green costume.  Tingle meets three characters that  accompany him on his journey to escape the world:        Kakashi the        scarecrow,        Buriki the robot, and        Lion the lion.  These characters are inspired by the        Scarecrow, the        Tin Woodman, and the        Cowardly Lion from        The Wonderful Wizard of Oz, respectively.  </description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="38549">Nintendo Land</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/97089/2491706-untitled.png</image></root>