<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27182</id><name>Gary Grigsby's War in the East</name><description>A turn based strategy game that allows players to fight either a large campaign or smaller specialized scenarios. The starting years for the campaigns are 1941, 1942, 1943 and 1944. There are 10 different scenarios that last anywhere from 10 to 25 turns. An interesting feature is that new units must be trained behind the front line before they are sent to the front, adding another dimension to the game's strategy. There are around 4000 units in the game and the player can create various unique units as well. There are also 500 historically accurate military commanders for the player to assign to various units. Unit commanders can be killed in action, and the player can dismiss, fire, or execute commanders at will. The attributes of military commanders are divided between military and political prowess.A major point of appeal for War in the East is the accurate representation of the Soviet industrial migration that occurred during the first year of the Great Patriotic War. The Soviet player suffers from heavy production penalties and delays representing the reconstitution of factories east of the Urals. The player must keep track of various spreadsheets outlining unit ammunition, battle fatigue, and strength. Although units are presented at the division level the various brigades that comprise a division are susceptible to varying degrees of damage, meaning that the player must allocate supplies and reinforcements to the most worn-out units.System RequirementsOS: Windows XP/Vista/7CPU: 1.5GHz+RAM: 1GBVideo Card: 128MB DirectX 9+ CompatibleSound Card: 16 bit DirectX 9+ CompatibleHard Drive Space: 1.5 GB FreeDirectX 9.0c</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4563">Field Commander</game><game id="31929">Hearts of Iron III: Semper Fi</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4647/1068338-wite_frontshot_800px.jpg</image></root>