<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27210</id><name>Sengoku Basara: Samurai Heroes</name><description>OverviewSengoku Basara: Samurai Heroes is the latest game in Capcom's Sengoku Basara series. The first game in the series to be released outside Japan with the names and historical references intact. Crowd-clearing hack-and-slash play remains the same, with an expanded roster. The opening theme is "Naked Arms" by T.M. Revolution, closing is "Gyakkou" by Ishikawa Chiaki. Missions contain hidden objectives, and the ability to vary story progression by focusing on certain ones like attacking specific officers allow branching story.Due to schedule cuts, certain aspects like online play and alternate dubs have been cut, but local co-op for certain modes is an option.LocalizationSengoku Basara: Samurai Heroes is the first game in the series to see a western release with its historical references in tact. Previous entries in the series were rebranded under the name Devil Kings. In both cases, all characters were renamed and the scenarios no longer referenced the Warring States era of Japanese history.CharactersReturning CharactersOichi - her old naginata is replaced with "black aura hands"Yukimura Sanada - twin yariYoshihiro Shimazu - great axeMasamune Date - continues to wield his sets of katanaMotochika Chousokabe - boat anchor and chainIeyasu Tokugawa - bare-fisted brawlingTadakatsu Honda - drill-like pikeKotaro Fuuma - kodachi short bladesKeiji Maeda - odachiMotonari Mouri - hoop bladesNew CharactersMitsunari Ishida - katanaYoshitsugu Outani- strung orbsKanbe Kuroda - ball and chainMagoichi Saiga - various firearmsTsuruhime - bowNPCsKenshin UesugiSourin Outomo - Zabii tankKasuga - kunaiKojuurou Katakura - swordsHideaki Kobayakawa - frying panSasuke Sarutobi - hand held shurikenMuneshige TachibanaTenkai - dual scythesUjimasa Houjou - multiple pointed spearToshiie Maeda - tridentMatsu - naginataYoshiaki Mogami - rapier</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10139">Samurai Warriors</game><game id="23198">Samurai Warriors 2</game><game id="25051">Warriors Orochi Z</game><game id="33151">Samurai Warriors 3Z</game><game id="33150">Samurai Warriors 3: Xtreme Legends</game><game id="37019">Dynasty Warriors Next</game><game id="35700">Saint Seiya: Sanctuary Battle</game><game id="39884">Senran Kagura Shinovi Versus: Shōjo-tachi no Shōmei</game><game id="40315">Hakuoki: Warriors of the Shinsengumi</game><game id="34360">Bleach Soul Resurrección</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1988894-box_sbsh.png</image></root>