<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27264</id><name>Calling</name><description>OverviewCalling is a Wii-exclusive horror-adventure from Hudson Entertainment. It was released in North America on Marth 9, 2010. In the game, the player takes control of several characters as they unearth the mystery behind "The Black Page," a mysterious website that supposedly allows its visitors to contact the dead. The game's style is heavily influenced by the Japanese horror genre of film. Gameplay The use of cell phones is integral to the gameplay.Calling is played from a first-person perspective using the Wii Remote and Nunchuk. In each chapter, the player must explore the environment and search for clues to escape the predicaments that they have been caught up in. At the center of the gameplay is the use of a cell phone. At times, the player will receive calls and must hold the Wii Remote to his or her ear in order to hear the incoming message. After acquiring phone numbers, the player may also make phone calls. The cell phones can also receive text messages. The Wii Remote is used to look around, examine, and interact with the environment. It can be used to open drawers, cabinets, and doors by pressing a button to grab the handle and either pulling or pushing the remote in order to pull or push the door open and closed. The on-screen cursor will change its state to indicate items that can be interacted with and how they can be manipulated. For example, if an item can be moved or collected, the cursor will become a hand, and if there is a gap in a doorway, it will become an eye, indicating that the player can peek to examine anything visible on the other side. At certain points in the story, the player character will enter a "caution mode." When this occurs, the player character will remain stationary until they examine the environment and discover the source of their cautious urge. You'll need to get good at shaking off ghosts if you want to see the end.Occasionally, the player character will be attacked by ghosts that will latch on and attempt to scare the character to death. In order to escape a ghost's clutches, the player must shake the Wii Remote and press a button prompt when it appears on screen. If the player does not press the button fast enough, he or she must continue shaking the remote until they can escape. Failure to escape will cause the player's panic to rise, indicated by a heartbeat chart. If it rises to high, the player character will succumb and the game will end.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21139">Fatal Frame IV: Mask of the Lunar Eclipse</game><game id="25888">Ju-On: The Grudge</game><game id="22605">Cursed Mountain</game><game id="25707">Silent Hill: Shattered Memories</game><game id="33374">Night of Sacrifice</game><game id="37561">Project Zero 2: Wii Edition</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5150/1263481-51f7uhhjhil.jpg</image></root>