<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27339</id><name>Gloom</name><description>Gloom was originally released in 1999 by Team Reaction.   The original Quake 2 engine was used and heavily modified with new textures and player models to make the game appear as if Gloom was a stand alone game.  In the game players joined one of two sides; aliens or humans.  Each team had individual defensive and offensive structures they could build with teleporters being the most important.  The teleporters allowed players to spawn in to the game, and once a team's teleporters were destroyed and their remaining teammates were killed the game was over.Gloom awarded points to players who killed members of the opposing team.  These points could be used to upgrade to more advanced classes which had better capabilities and generally did and withstood more damage.Gloom was developed by Team Reaction (TrXN) which had other notable Quake 2 mod releases such as Jailbreak and QPong.  Team Reaction was originally lead by Dave "White Noise" Wallin, who was the primary programmer for Jailbreak, Qpong and Gloom.  After his eventual departure from the group, Aaron "Lifer!" Gilmore (a mapper from Gloom) took over the reigns of the team and began work on a version of Gloom for Quake 3 which never materialized.Classes of GloomAlienBreeder - The Breeder was capable of creating defensive and offensive structures for the alien team.Hatchling - The most basic offensive class, the hatchling was not able to take much damage but was capable of jumping to high heights and crawling along walls.Drone - An upgraded class which could jump to incredible heights and swipe with its two claws.Wraith - A medium sized alien that had the ability to fly and spit acid.Kamikaze - a modified Hatchling which could explode on command, causing area of effect blast damage.Stinger - A scorpion like alien that could attack with its tail.Guardian - A large, cumbersome alien that could stealth and become completely invisible to the opposing team.Stalker - The largest, most armored and damaging alien class.HumanEngineer - The Engineer was capable of creating defensive and offensive structures for the alien team.Grunt - The basic marine for the humans.  The grunt had a machine gun and did minimal damage.Shock Trooper - An upgraded marine with a shotgun and protective suit which protected him from alien bio weapons. Biotech - A female marine with the ability to heal members of the human team.Heavy Trooper - An upgraded marine with a rocket launcher that devistated alien structures.Elite Commando - A specialized marine with an uzi and a batch of grenades which were effective for eliminating aliens and unit structures.Exterminator - A battle suited human with a pulse rifle and grenades.Mechanize Unit - A robotic, heavily armored robot with dual laser rifles and the ability to squash smaller aliens by walking on them.Gloom's official homepage can still be found at http://teamreaction.planetquake.gamespy.com/gloom/index.htm.  As of this writing, Gloom still has 4 active servers and a community site at http://www.planetgloom.com.</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>NONE</image></root>