<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27344</id><name>Bit.Trip Void</name><description>OverviewBit.Trip Void is the third installment of the six part Bit.Trip series of rhythm games. In this installment, you're tasked with grabbing black beats using a large black ball called the "void," that grows as you grab black beats, while avoiding the white beats that litter the playing field.StoryNot much is known about the games story just yet, but according to developer Gaijin Games, this installment will mark the end of the first chapter in the Bit.Trip series.GameplayVoid places you in control of a black ball called the void. The goal is to absorb as many black beats as possible while avoiding their hazardous white counterparts to earn points. As you do this, the void become progressively bigger, as each black beat you grab increases the size of the void. And as you grow, the void's movement speed is slowed, making it harder to both avoid, and collect beats.However, this can be fixed by shrinking the void down to its original size. This also saves all the points you've accumulated by adding them into the overall total. But if you want to achieve the highest possible score, you have get the void as big as you can before shrinking it, as the more beats you grab, the more points you'll earn. This adds a risk-versus-reward element to the game, that adds a lot more challenge, in some ways.CheckpointsVoid marks the first game in the series to include checkpoints. Each level contains three checkpoints, and start you off with only one credit (or continue). But more can be obtained by gaining a high number of points.System RequirementsPCOS:Windows XP SP3Processor:2.0+ GHzMemory:512 MB RAMGraphics:OpenGL 2.1 and shader model 3 with 128 MB of memoryDirectX®:9.0cHard Drive:100 MB HD spaceSound:Any sound card capable of stereo outputMacOS:OSX version Snow Leopard 10.6.3, or laterProcessor:2.0+ GHzMemory:512 MB RAMGraphics:Open GL 2.1 and shader model 3 with 128 MB of memoryHard Drive:100 MB HD spaceSound:Any sound card capable of stereo output</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12069">Ikaruga</game><game id="7624">Pac-Man</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/7003/1380317-hero_btv.png</image></root>