<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27399</id><name>Tomena Sanner</name><description>OverviewTomena Sanner is a game by "one button wai wai action" and published by Konami for the iPhone and Nintendo's WiiWare service. In the game the player has to guide a breakdancing salesman past various obstacles by correctly timed button presses.GameplayGeneral GameplayIn Tomena Sanner the goal is to guide a break dancing businessman to the end of 10 levels in various modes. In order to do this the player will have to press the action button just before hitting an obstacle. If the player hits the action button with a small space remaining between the character and the object, the salesman will execute a move to counter the obstacle. However if the player presses the action button just next to the obstacle the businessman will perform another move that passes the obstacle faster and an additional 2 seconds is added to the overall timer. Whenever the player pulls off a "great" move by hitting the action button at the right time the businessman will also speed up to the right side of the screen. If the player bumps into an obstacle the player will lose speed and move gradually to the left of the screen risking losing the game if the salary man is too slow to keep up with the moving screen. If the player happens to press the action button when there is no obstacle the businessman will either jump if there are coins nearby or roll when there are no coins. It is possible to do a quadruple jump in the air to reach higher situated coins and pass obstacles without gaining points for them.Party Time!When the player manages to reach the end of the level before the timer runs out a break dancing minigame plays allowing the player to rake up some extra points by pressing the action button as indicated on screen.Power-upsVarious power-ups that are found throughout the game are kept in colored balloons. The power ups in the game are:Speed UpSpeed DownTime IncreaseSmall SizeBig SizeSecretsThere are various secret moves and locations scattered throughout the game.ControlsThere is only one button needed to play Tomena Sanner, for the sake of choice both the A and B button can be used.ModesNormal modeThe player plays through an enormous campaign mode that takes them to many different locations throughout the universe.Turbo modeJust like in normal mode the player plays through all the levels reaching the end of a level to unlock the next one however the speed of the game is significantly increased compared to normal mode making it quite a bit harder to press the action button at the correct time.Levels1-1The first level in Tomene Sanner lets the player dance around on the streets of a modern day Japanese metropolis.1-2Our hero has warped through time, back into the time of dinosaurs. Break dance with cavemen and ski jump off of T-Rex's backs to pass this level.1-3The champion breakdancer has managed to go to space. Do the moonwalk while breakdancing with aliens to get passed this level.2-1The god of the dance floor has now traveled to medieval Japan. Watch out for ninja's and bow to your sensei to move on to the next stage.2-2The red-tied adventurer is now in "The Streets". Tell some Yo Momma jokes and pull of a slam dunk if you wanna survive the ghetto.2-3Our groovy protagonist has now traveled to the funky future! Launch robots and hop-scotch to get to the next level.3-1The daredevil of disco is now in an urban environment. Play "paper, rock, scissors" with a teddy bear and send the mail to move on with your crazy life.3-2Our graceful wanderer has now moved on to the deserts of Mexico. Dance with Elvis in order to survive.3-3The legendary hero has now entered the pits of hell. Crowd surf on some Egyptians and knock over zombies to win the game.Endless modeEndless mode is a string of all the levels in order in which end as soon as the player dies, the timer resets at the start of every level however.LeaderboardsBoth local and world wide online leaderboards are supported for all the levels including the "endless" level in both normal and turbo mode.MultiplayerIt is possible to play Tomena Sannar with up to 4 players in simultaneous local split-screen. In the multiplayer mode all the players will be running on the same track with their own timers and every obstacle can only be used once forcing the players to stay ahead of the pack. If ever a player drops out of the screen or his/her timer runs out it is game over for that player.Power-upsIn multiplayer mode various multiplayer specific power ups appear in the levels, the different power ups are:...QuotesThe game scrolls by plenty of ridiculous quotes while you are playing, here is a few of them.Make like a tree.. and photosynthesize!A cowardly leap! Yes, fear the manholes!Yes! Great doggy-doo reflexes!Nice technique! Tornado kick to inanimate object!LinksOfficial website: http://www.konami.jp/products/dl_wii_tomenasanner_ww/Trailer: http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GIhrlpZxqjw</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="29550">Bit.Trip RUNNER</game><game id="28976">Canabalt</game><game id="3064">The Rub Rabbits!</game><game id="35673">Bit.Trip Complete</game><game id="39290">Pitfall!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/4/45471/1084014-main.jpg</image></root>