<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27413</id><name>Sim Theme Park</name><description>OverviewSim Theme Park (Theme Park World in Europe and Japan, Theme Park Roller Coaster on the PS2) is a management simulation game following the classic Theme Park.Originally released five years after the first game, it brought the series into full 3d, letting the player walk around their park as a visitor and ride the attractions. Being in 3d it is possible to ride the roller coasters the player creates as opposed to the pre-rendered animations in the first game. A post card feature lets the player capture images of their parks and e-mail them to their friends from the in-game interface.GameplayTheme Park World has a new reward system based around golden tickets and keys. Tickets is awarded by completing specific requirements like having a certain number of people in your park or having a certain park rating.Tickets can be spent to buy new mystery items like new rides. Earning three golden tickets also awards the player a golden key.There are separate park "themes", two of which are available from the start (Lost Kingdom and Halloween World) and others becoming available from earning golden keys during play.In addition, there are numerous "challenges" that become available at random. These have a time limit and awards cash prizes when completed.Theme Park World has an online component which lets players visit their friends' (or random people's) parks through the internet. The online lobby is displayed as an earth globe with city icons, each with all the parks that have been published to that specific town. When visiting parks, players can walk around, ride attractions and chat with their friends through text messaging.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5625">RollerCoaster Tycoon 3</game><game id="11178">RollerCoaster Tycoon 2</game><game id="2236">RollerCoaster Tycoon</game><game id="19042">Dungeon Keeper: The Deeper Dungeons</game><game id="2415">RollerCoaster Tycoon 2: Time Twister</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/11423/1105068-themepark.jpg</image></root>