<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27445</id><name>Retro/Grade</name><description>StoryThe player assumes the the role of Rick Rocket, a spaceship captain who single-handedly defeated an entire alien armada. Rick about to be awarded with a kiss from the Space Princess when all of the sudden a temporal anomaly occurs. It seems that the destruction Rick caused in his your adventures was of such a magnitude that it damaged the space time continuum. Now Rick Rocket must go back in time in order to undo them and restore balance to the cosmos.GameplayThe whole story right here.RIck Rocket is moving back through time, trying to undo the damage he caused along his adventure. This means that the whole game is played like a cassette tape being rewound, so instead of firing bullets at enemies, you need to "un-fire" your shots as they come at you (i.e. receive the shot that you fired) while dodging enemy bullets that are doing the same.Basically the player is reliving events as they happened by going backwards in time. If the player fails to act out events as they truly happened, in all their flawless glory, then the player will be penalized, because you're messing with the fabric of time, and shame on you.It's complicated.Essentially there's a paradox-unaware sci-fi/time-travel context laid upon a pretty straightforward rhythm game. The bullets that the protagonist's ship "receives" will match notes and rhythms, and enemy bullets act as additional obstacles. It's not too dissimilar from the rhythm-game paradigm made famous by Audiosurf.Rick travels in colored lanes associated with the colored frets on the guitar controllers, while strumming as his bullets enter his ship (where "strumming" would be the point in time when Rick Rocket fired said bullet). The player strums as bullets enter the ship, synchronized to an original techno soundtrack. The player must also dodge enemy bullets that are moving from behind Rick Rocket, back into the enemy ships.Whenever you fail to fire a bullet at the right time, or fail to dodge enemy fire, the space time continuum is damaged, since you are doing something that supposedly never happened. You can measure the "health" of the space time continuum through a meter, much like the Rock Meter in Guitar Hero, on the upper left corner of your screen. It is divided in green, yellow and red. If you fail you'll get closer to red, if you hit you'll get closer to the green area. You also have the ability to go back in time, which in this case means to go forward in time, to correct your mistakes. This takes up energy though, which can be measured by a gauge below the space continuum meter.System RequirementsOS: Windows XP SP2, Vista, Windows 7, or Windows 8Processor: 2.0+ GHz or better (dual core recommended)Memory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: NVIDIA 8000 seriesDirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 300 MB HD spaceSound: Windows compatible</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25054">Bit.Trip Beat</game><game id="9436">Audiosurf</game><game id="1826">Boom Boom Rocket</game><game id="20673">Guitar Hero World Tour</game><game id="35673">Bit.Trip Complete</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/6/63119/2298528-retrograde.jpeg</image></root>