<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2760</id><name>Art of Fighting</name><description>Overview Art of Fighting (known in Japan as Ryuuko no Ken) is a fighting game developed and published by                                SNK for the      Neo Geo. Although overshadowed by                               Street Fighter II, released a year earlier, Art of Fighting innovated the fighting game genre through its use of large character sprites (with battle damage), camera zooming, taunting, super and "desperation" moves, and a "spirit gauge" that depletes when certain moves are used.  The game takes place in the late seventies in the fictional city of South Town, where                              Ryo Sakazaki and                             Robert Garcia must find out the whereabouts of Ryo's kidnapped sister,                            Yuri. The game is set decades before the events of                           Fatal Fury.  Gameplay       The game plays like traditional fighting games. The player has two basic attack buttons: punch and kick. The third button is a "utility" button which can allow the player to do stronger punches and kicks (when combined with the punch or kick buttons), throws, and walljumps. The fourth button is a taunting button. Not every character can perform throws and walljumps. This game also features dashing forwards and backwards by pressing the joystick in either direction twice. Fireballs can be canceled out using punches or kicks. The game also features a "spirit gauge", which controls when the player can perform special and super moves. The gauge lowers after the player performs a special/super move. The more powerful the move, the more the gauge depletes. The gauge also depletes when your opponent performs a taunt. The gauge can only be recharged manually by holding down either the punch or kick button. It will be in one of three colors (green, yellow, or  red) depending on the amount left.  Only Ryo and Robert have super (the Haou Shou Ken) and "desperation" (Ryuko Ranbou) moves that can only be learned through a special bonus stage. Both moves take up much of your spirit gauge, but the desperation move can only be performed when the player has 20% life or less (as indicated by a flashing life bar).  In single-player Story mode, the player is usually at a disadvantage with shorter life and spirit gauges. These can be increased in special bonus stages, where the player must perform a certain task (careful button pressing or button mashing). Characters                    Ryo Sakazaki (playable in one-player story mode)                  Robert Garcia (playable in one-player story mode)                 Ryuhaku Todoh Jack Turner                Lee Pai Long           King               Mickey Rogers              John Crawley             Mr. Big (only playable in two-player battle mode by either reaching the final stage and then letting another player join in or via cheat code)            Mr. Karate (only playable in two-player battle mode by either reaching the final stage and then letting another player join in or via cheat code)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="243">Street Fighter II: The World Warrior</game><game id="11156">X-Men vs. Street Fighter</game><game id="2612">Marvel vs. Capcom 2: New Age of Heroes</game><game id="11400">Fatal Fury 2</game><game id="8680">Street Fighter Alpha 3 MAX</game><game id="19025">Deadly Moves</game><game id="3185">ClayFighter 63 1/3</game><game id="16400">Aggressors of Dark Kombat</game><game id="18554">World Heroes</game><game id="5030">The King of Fighters XI</game><game id="5964">The King of Fighters '99</game><game id="15728">The King of Fighters 2000</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="16793">Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors</game><game id="10486">Fighter's History</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="21519">The King of Fighters XII</game><game id="25801">Global Champion</game><game id="16200">The King of Fighters: Neowave</game><game id="6319">Strip Fighter II</game><game id="22629">Rage of the Dragons</game><game id="4896">Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Tournament Fighters</game><game id="23794">CAPOEIRA FIGHTER 3</game><game id="30142">The King of Fighters XIII</game><game id="40698">Makeruna! Makendou 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8072/287432-aof.jpg</image></root>