<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27663</id><name>The Sims 3: World Adventures</name><description>This first expansion pack for the Sims 3 allows the player to take their Sims, using their phones or computers, to exotic locations such as Egypt, the Far East and France through to accept challenges, discover treasure and explore caves. Landmarks can explored, relationships can be built and new skills such as photography can be learnt.   This expansion comes with $10 worth of SimPoints to spend in the online store. New traits for Sims will also be added, of which have a relation to the adventure aspect of the pack. Properties can also be purchased and owned in these news areas in addition to an original home, allowing Sims to live there when going to the exotic locations. Players may also alter the town as they can Sunset Valley, through the edit menu in game.   Adventure in China: Martial Arts  Also being added for the first time to a Sims game is the official ability to build basements. While in the past, players have made makeshift underground portions of their houses, World Adventures will have a full suit of tools for this. Players will be able to build up to four levels down below their homes. Trap doors, hidden passageways, and different triggering mechanisms will be available included the classic torch lever. One will be able to create traditional basements using familiar looks or create dungeons and tomb style settings as well. It has also been mentioned that traps will be available too. This would be a departure from Sims of the past when it was merely the user's manipulation that was used to put their sims in unpleasant situations.    System Requirements PC Computer Requirements PC OS: Windows XP SP2, Windows Vista SP1 or Windows 7CPU: (XP) 2.0 GHz P4 processor or equivalent; (Vista and Windows 7) 2.4 GHz P4 processor or equivalentRAM: (XP) 1 GB RAM; (Vista and Windows 7) 1.5 GB RAMHARD DRIVE: At least 3.5 GB* of free space with at least 1 GB additional space for custom content and saved games.VIDEO: DirectX 9.0c compatible Video Card with 128 MB  of Video RAM and support for Pixel Shader 2.0  Apple Computer RequirementsMAC OS: Mac OS X 10.5.7 Leopard or higherCPU: Intel Core Duo ProcessorRAM: 2 GB RAMHARD DRIVE: At least 3.5 GB* of free space with at least 1 GB additional space for custom content and saved games.VIDEO: ATI x1600 or Nvidia 7300 GT with 128 MB of Video RAM, or Intel Integrated GMA X3100</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="32129">The Sims 3: Late Night</game><game id="33372">The Sims 3: Outdoor Living Stuff</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4938/1119973-boxshot.jpg</image></root>