<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27769</id><name>Lead and Gold: Gangs of the Wild West</name><description>OverviewLead and Gold: Gangs of the Wild West is an online-only, third person shooter delivering a fast paced, team-based multiplayer experience in a western setting. Character classes and game modes emulate the archetypes of the Western era, while the game mechanics focus on players working and fighting together. It was released on the PC April 8, 2010 and on the PSN May 4, 2010.GameplayJeb kills Jennings and levels up!Lead and Gold is different than many current online shooters, in that there is no persistent character progression. At the beginning of each match, all players start out with a rank of 1. As players score experience points throughout the match, they rank up, which positively affects their synergies, health regeneration, and other attributes. But at the end of each match, all ranks are reset back to 1.Each character has their own unique "synergy", which is a range-based booster that enhances the abilities of any nearby teammates. Additionally, sticking close to other teammates will gradually heal any damage you might have taken. With these gameplay elements, it becomes very advantageous for teammates to fight as a pack.If a player is killed, the game utilizes a Down But Not Out concept, where they are immobilized, but are still given a chance to defend themselves with their secondary weapon. Enemies can finish off the player by shooting them, or teammates can come revive them.Character ClassesLead and Gold features four character classes to choose from, each having their own unique weapons, traits, and synergies:The BlasterWields the Coach Gun (a type of double barrel shotgun), effective for close range attacks.Has the "dynamite" trait, which allows him to throw out sticks of dynamite that act as grenades.Radiates the "Armor" synergy effect.The DeputyWields the Repeater Carbine, effective for medium to long range attacks.Has the "tagging" trait, which allows him to tag enemies. He can also untag teammates that have been tagged by the opposing team.Radiates the "Damage" synergy effect.The GunslingerWields the Negotiator (a heavy revolver with high accuracy), effective for medium range attacks.Has the "fanning" trait, which rapidly fires his revolver with reduced accuracy. Good for short range combat.Radiates the "Accuracy" synergy effect.The TrapperWields the Buffalo Rifle (a type of sniper rifle), effective for long range attacks.Has the "traps" trait, which allows her to place bear traps on the ground that immobilize enemies.Radiates the "Criticals" synergy effect.Notes:The Blaster, Deputy, and Trapper all have a secondary revolver called The Admiral.The Gunslinger reloads with speed loaders, everyone else's revolver has to be reloaded one bullet at a time.The Trapper can place traps as often as she wants but she can only have two out at a time.Synergy effects of the same type do not stack.Game ModesLead and Gold features these game modes to choose from:Shootout- Your basic Team Deathmatch mode. The standard rules apply.Conquest- The objective of Conquest is to conquer waypoints in order. One team starts at zone A and moves towards zone E, while the other gang advances in the other direction, from E to A. Clearing a zone of enemies and staying in that zone until your flag is raised will conquer it, and unlock the next zone in the sequence.Powder Keg- Powder Keg is an Assault-type game mode. One team is trying to blow up objectives using powder kegs, while the other team tries to defend these objectives. The Powder kegs are scattered throughout the map, and must be retrieved and carried to the objective. This mode is is played in two rounds with each side taking a turn as attacker and defender.Gold Fever- Gold Fever is a single player or two player co-operative horde-like game mode. The goal is to fend off endless waves of computer-controlled enemies while you and your teammate attempt to obtain as many sacks of gold as possible. The game ends when both players are dead.Robbery- Another Assault-type game mode, Robbery has one team trying to blow up a bank vault and steal three bags of gold. The opposing team attempts to defend the bank and the gold. This mode is played in two rounds with each side alternating as attacker and defender.Greed- The objective in Greed is to deliver as many gold sacks as possible to your team's drop off zone. After a gold sack spawns on the map, both teams fight to bring the sack to their respective drop off zone. Once a team successfully brings the gold sack to their zone, they are rewarded a point, and a new sack spawns on the map.Demolition- Similar to Powder Keg, the goal in this game mode is for both teams to blow up objectives using the available powder kegs. Teams are simultaneously attacking and defending; using the kegs to blow up objectives and preventing their opponents from doing the same.There is also a practice mode which acts as the game's tutorial. You are guided to achieve a series of set goals and to learn the basic mechanics of the game. Partway through the tutorial, the game spawns an endless series of enemies for you to kill.MapsBad Blood Valley - Playable in game modes Greed and Conquest.Deadwater Ranch - Playable in game modes Powder Keg, Robbery, Greed, and Conquest.Devil's Pit - Playable in game modes Robbery and Conquest.Fort Turnbull - Playable in game modes Greed and Conquest.Prospector's Peak - Playable in game modes Powder Keg, Robbery, Greed, and Conquest.Sinner's Gulch - Playable in game modes Greed and Conquest.Jacob's Bridge - Playable in game modes Greed, Conquest, and Demolition.System RequirementsMinimum System RequirementsOS: Windows XP SP2/VistaProcessor: Intel Core 2 DUO E4600 (2.4 GHz)/AMD Athlon64 X2 5200Memory: 1.5 GBHard Drive: 1.5 GB FreeVideo Memory: 512 MB (NVIDIA GeForce 7800/ATI Radeon X1900)Sound Card: DirectX CompatibleDirectX: 9.0cRecommended System RequirementsOS: Windows Vista/Windows 7Processor: Intel Core 2 QUAD Q6600 (2.4 GHz)/AMD Phenom X4 9500 (2.2 GHz)Memory: 2 GBHard Drive: 1.5 GB FreeVideo Memory: 512 MB (NVIDIA GeForce 9800 GTX /ATI Radeon HD 3850)Sound Card: DirectX CompatibleDirectX: 10</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25066">Call of Juarez: Bound in Blood</game><game id="25249">Red Dead Redemption</game><game id="18162">Team Fortress 2</game><game id="8873">GUN</game><game id="30478">Breach</game><game id="25262">Battlefield 1943</game><game id="29806">Monday Night Combat</game><game id="1673">Outlaws</game><game id="35307">Gotham City Impostors</game><game id="36170">War of the Roses</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/30036/1330694-leadandgoldgb.jpg</image></root>