<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27814</id><name>Football Manager 2010</name><description>Football Manager 2010 continues the series' tradition of rolling out new features and refinements every year.Notable Additions  ChangesThe tactics system from the previous games has been all but changed entirely in this installment. Dozens of new possibilities have been added to the system including the capacity to strictly define individual player roles. The ability to shout specific instructions and tactics to the controlled team during a match is also a new addition. Newcomers to FM will be pleased with the brand new match analysis tools. Every action in a match is recorded in a post-game report which can elaborate on where particular tactics/strategies are working or failing.The media aspect of the game has not been overhauled to the extent of the tactics system, but some enhancements exist nonetheless. Managers can subscribe to different channels of news or to specific individuals even. The news center which displays information about the entire game world has also been changed in order to show stories that are more relevant to the game player.While the scouting system has not been changed dramatically, the areas a club's board will allow you to scout have been changed dramatically. This is not always a good change particularly when playing in the lower leagues.Injuries have become somewhat more realistic with amorphous return-to-action dates instead of the exact "this player will be out of action for six weeks" reports from the physios in the previous version.Visually, FM10 sports a brand new new look when compared to the previous games in the series. Much of the interface has been condensed and cleaned up in order to aid newcomers who might feel overwhelmed by the scope of the game world. The 3D match engine has also seen improvements. Over a hundred animations have been added, and match engine AI has been further enhanced for more realism.Playable National league SystemsArgentinaAustraliaAustriaBelarusBelgiumBrazilBulgariaChileChinaColombiaCroatiaCzech RepublicDenmarkEnglandFinlandFranceGermanyGreeceHollandHong KongHungaryIcelandIndiaIndonesiaIrelandIsraelItalyMalaysiaMexicoNorthern IrelandNorwayPeruPolandPortugalRomaniaRussiaScotlandSerbiaSingaporeSlovakiaSloveniaSouth AfricaSouth KoreaSpainSwedenSwitzerlandTurkeyUkraineUnited StatesUruguayWalesRecommended System RequirementsIntel CPU: Pentium 4 3.0GHzAMD CPU: Athlon 64 4000Video Card: Geforce 7600 GT 256MB or Radeon X1800 Series 256MBMemory: 1.5 GBHard Drive: 2.5 GBDirectX: 9.0cMac: Intel Processor, OS X 10.5, Nvidia Geforce 7300 GT / ATI X1600 Radeon</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="40">Soccer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="27051">Championship Manager 2007</game><game id="27881">Championship Manager 2010</game><game id="29234">Pro Cycling Manager: Season 2010</game><game id="29480">Kevin Keegan's Player Manager</game><game id="30630">Baseball Mogul 2011</game><game id="20279">Championship Manager 5</game><game id="10269">Championship Manager 2006</game><game id="27148">Let's Make a Soccer Team!</game><game id="6697">Premier Manager Ninety Nine</game><game id="4805">Soccer Team Manager: English and Italian Leagues</game><game id="32911">FIFA Manager 11</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/28470/1105311-cover.jpg</image></root>