<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27863</id><name>Dust 514</name><description>Command PitDUST 514 is a persistent-world FPS game for the Playstation 3. It has been in development for five years by CCP Shanghai. It takes place in the same universe as Eve Online, and its closely connected to the space MMORPG. Events in Eve Online will affect the events in DUST 514 and vice versa. Players in Eve Online will supposedly be able to, for example, hire DUST 514 players as infantry, send them resources or equipment, and so on.TechnologyDUST 514 will be using Unreal Engine 3.GameplayThe game will feature first person shooter gameplay with vehicles. It will also mix in strategy elements, similar to the commander feature in Battlefield 2. Players develop and customize their characters via a system similar to EVE's. Skills are bought to add and and refine capabilities. Fitting is used to customize your character for battle. The character fitting is similar to EVE's with low, medium, and high slots, and CPU/powergird budgets. Which dropsuit a character is equipped with determines what slots are available and the stat budget.Here is part of an interview with the CEO of CCP Games about the gameplay:Staging areaK:From the press release, DUST will have also RTS elements. How can we imagine that?CCP:If you fight another team in DUST, you can use different tactics. We call this Off-Map-Support. This way “things” can be called to the battle and will last for the whole battle.K:Can you give examples?CCP:Well ok. Stationary weapons would be such an example.K:Okay. How about a Commander-Feature known from Battlefield? A strategic overview from where a commander can lead his troops?CCP:Yes, this will be included.K:Will it be the same in functionality and amount? Or rather low level? It is hard to display such tools on consoles.CCP:Our focus for one is, to create a shooter with strategic elements. We will support the player with the tools he needs to do strategic decisions and accomplish them. I can’t say more atm.Released at Fanfest 2011 (March 26 2011), a trailer for EVE: A Future Vision shows some of the possible integration between EVE: Online and Dust 514. It was also mentioned that most of the video was created using Carbon.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14436">PlanetSide</game><game id="17828">Battlefield 2142</game><game id="21116">MAG</game><game id="16866">Battlefield 2</game><game id="29025">PlanetSide 2</game><game id="29601">Nuclear Dawn</game><game id="35523">Defiance</game><game id="25444">Dead Space 2</game><game id="39035">Battlefield 4</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2478656-box_ed514.png</image></root>