<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27879</id><name>Napoleon: Total War</name><description>CampaignNapoleon: Total War (NTW) focuses on the rise and fall of Napoleon Bonaparte and the Napoleonic wars. Campaigns include Napoleon's Italian campaign, the conquest of Egypt, and the traditional grand campaign seen in previous titles. For the grand campaign the game reverts back to the traditional European map seen in previous titles. durgin the grand campaign the player can either control the nation of France, or one of the four major Coalition nations that opposed France during the Napoleonic wars.Set in the early 1800's, the game vastly differs from previous Total War games for a number of reasons. The primary difference is the passage of time. NTW's turn system now progresses the game two weeks as opposed to six months. This change was made in order to better simulate the bloody actions of the war.Total war takes a literal sense in NTW. In addition to the removal of religious buildings and units, none militarist industry and vast trade systems seen in Empire, NTW focuses all production on military might. Players build Lumber Jacks to reduce the cost of ships, factories to reduce the cost of cannons and tax offices to keep order. Opera houses and secret societies increase public order by happiness, but all intents and purposes every building is built with Total War in mind.Research that was first introduced in Empire has been streamlined in NTW. The player can only build schools on specific towns; the cost of which is the loss of a secret society. There are only 3 branches of research to focus on now (military, industry and administrative) and gentlemen still take the role of speeding up or stealing technology.Taxes and trade are much similar to Empire. You can adjust taxes for both the rich and poor. Increasing taxes too much stems growth and encourages social disorder, while cutting taxes can damage your war effort. Upgrading administrative buildings can increase tax revenue. Trade is handled through diplomacy and the construction of ports, which allows you to trade with more nations.Combat in napoleon is similar to Empire but features improved options and game play. Enemies are still not competent but pose more of a challenge in battle. Generals, being harder to come by, can have a much more drastic effect on war if they are wounded or killed. Battles are still fought in real time with large armies conscripted from cities. A new addition is drop in battles, where you can choose to allow a player to take command of the opposing army, giving more challenge and interactivity to the game.Rewards for conquest have been revamped once again. When the player captures a city, he can either occupy it with minimal unrest penalty, loot the city for money at the risk of riots, or establish a city-state that allies with the player's nation. City-states function in a similar manner to minor nations and will not provide you with tax revenue.AchievementsNapoleon: Total War features 65 Steam achievements, the majority (51) of which can be earned within the single player and co-op campaign. Napoleon: Total War is also Steam activated, much like Empire: Total War, the previous title in the series.DLCNTW features two DLC packs. The first is the Units of the Coalition pack, which offers new elite units for each nation. The second it the Peninsular Campaign, which adds a new campaign with a new map (Spain/Portugal) and four playable factions (France, Spain, Portugal and England). When playing as Spain the game stresses guerrilla warfare and subterfuge.MultiplayerNapoleon: Total War features multiplayer battles in three configurations, land, sea and siege. The game supports battles between up to eight players. For the first time in the series the option to participate in a co-op campaign is included. It is played in a similar manner to the single player campaigns. Each player is given an allotted period of time per turn to carry out their faction's unit movements, build orders, and other tasks before their time period runs out and control switches to another player. If a land or sea battle occurs with an AI controlled faction during the co-op campaign there is an option for one of the human participants to take control of the AI and the fight the battle against the other player. Steam AchievementsComplete each requirement to receive the achievements.UnlockableHow to UnlockA Different SlantPlay a MP naval battle with every factionAbsolute PowerWin a MP Land Battle without losing any unitsBroad Military OutlookPlay a MP land battle with every factionBronze Tower of PisaWin Italian Campaign in easyCelebrated Field-CommanderWin 10 land battlesDaredevilWin a match against someone with double your skill ratingDefensive StrategyWin a battle using only Light Infantry and ArtilleryDesert VeteranWin a MP Egypt Campaign as FranceDiplomat's PinMake all major nations like you (very friendly)Distinguished Service MedalWin a match against a player with double your skill ratingExpecting Calm SeasWin a match having spent half as many funds as your opponentFelix Austria face bellum!Win Europe Campaign as AustriaFirst-rate BullyWin a match with only first ratesGives to the PoorWin campaign having given enemy player 50000 goldGolden Obelisk of the PharaosWin Egypt Campaign in hardGrand General StarWin Silver in 5 Historic BattlesHardened Veteran's BadgeWin 15 SP Campaign land battlesHero of Arcole Commemorative MedalWin Italian Campaign in hardHistorians' College Acknowledgement BadgePlay a historical land battleImperial Fencing Academy Master's NeedleWin 10 sword duelsIndomitable ForceWin 10 MP Land Battles in a rowItalian VeteranWin a MP Italian Campaign as FranceJack Frost's ChosenWin Europe Campaign as RussiaJust DessertsOther player's faction is last to dieMaking HeadwayWin a MP naval battleMarksman BroochWin 10 pistol duelsNautic Star EmblemWin ten SP Campaign naval battlesNo Shore LeavePlay 100 multiplayer naval battesPalace Guard PenchantPlay the game for 30 hours totalPlatinum Star of GloryWin Gold in all Historic BattlesProlong the InevitablePossess 15 regions without taking one by other playersPrussia's GloryWin Europe Campaign as PrussiaQuadriga in Prussian SilverWin Europe Campaign in medium within historic timeRack and RuinSink 1000 ShipsRestauratorWin a MP Italian Campaign as AustriaRevolutionary CocardeStart any campaign, battle or historical battleRule BritanniaWin Europe Campaign as EnglandRussian Doll on Green RibbonWin Europe Campaign in easySeasoned CaptainWin 10 decisive victoriesShield of the ProtectorHave 10 protectorates at one timeSwashbucklerBoard 5 ships in a single battleTake Up OfficePlay a MP CampaignThe BlitzTake other player's capital within 20 turnsThe Bronze Armchair of ComfortWin any Campaign by autresolving onlyThe Bronze DateWin Egypt Campaign in easyThe Emblem of the Enlightened SocietyWin a prestige victoryThe Explorers' Society BadgeCover 50,000 sea or land miles with your armies and fleetsThe Eye of the Ever Watchful GeneralPlay the game for 50 hours totalThe Hand-and-Dagger on Black ChainAssassinate 15 peopleThe Hero's Skull Badge100000 soldiers die in battles with you, friend and foeThe Imperial Crown on Brocade BandWin Europe Campaign in hardThe Imperial LaurelsWin European MP Campaign as FranceThe Imperial School of Strategy CrestHave three generals with full skill level in one campaignThe Imperial WreathConquer all of EuropeThe Lion and Sabers MedalWin any campaign without a single autoresolveThe Lion and the MouseWin a match without any ships of the lineThe Man of the Bosporus is still healthyWin Egypt Campaign as OttomansThe Medallion of the Imperial PsychopathDeclare war on all nations the first turn, never make peace, and win the gameThe Merchant's Navy Medal of GratitudeGain 8000 per turn in trade revenueThe People's CrownHave a 100% approval ratingThe Quick and the DeadlyWin a match without any infantryThe Ribbon of the Promising StrategistCapture 10 regionsThe Seal of the Grand CoalitionHave 6 allies simultaneouslyThe Silver Dromedairy LegionaireWin Egypt Campaign in medium within historic timeThe Silver Olive ChapletWin Italian Campaign in medium within historic timeThe Tireless Watchman BroochPlay the game for 10 hours totalUnqestionable LoyaltyWin 50mp land battlesWind On Your BackWin 6 MP Naval Battles in a rowSystem RequirementsMinimum:OS:Microsoft® Windows Vista®/XP®/Windows® 7Processor: 2.3 GHz CPU with SSE2Memory: 1 GB RAM (XP), 2 GB RAM (Vista®/Windows® 7)Graphics: 256 MB DirectX® 9.0c shader model 2b compatible GPUDirectX®: DirectX® 9.0cHard Drive: 21 GB free spaceRecommended:OS: Microsoft® Windows Vista®/XP®/Windows® 7Processor: 2.6 GHz Dual Core CPUMemory: 2 GB RAM (XP), 4 GB RAM (Vista®/Windows® 7)Graphics: 256 MB DirectX® 9.0c shader model 3 compatible GPUDirectX®: DirectX® 9.0cHard Drive: 21 GB free space</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21493">Europa Universalis III: Napoleon's Ambition</game><game id="9413">Cossacks: European Wars</game><game id="18047">Cossacks II: Napoleonic Wars</game><game id="16130">Imperial Glory</game><game id="4686">Waterloo: Napoleon's Last Battle</game><game id="19887">Rome: Total War</game><game id="32487">Hegemony: Philip of Macedon</game><game id="31531">Total War: Shogun 2</game><game id="37997">Mount &amp; Blade Warband: Napoleonic Wars</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1849087-box_ntw.png</image></root>