<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27992</id><name>Scorpion Disfigured</name><description>Basic InfoThis game is currently only available in Europe, and was released on March 31, 2009 for the PC platform. It was published by Akella, and developed by B-COOL Interactive.  It is a first person shooter set in a post apocalyptic world, where you use a power suit to control time and fight an army of mutants and soldiers. As well the game has some light RPG elements with upgrades that you can apply to your suit based on XP you get from killing your enemies. Story and Gameplay   2048. After the terror came the civil wars. After the civil wars the destruction of the system. Now the Middle East and Southeast Europe are nothing more than a mine field full of tribal wars, religious fanaticism and ruthless Warlords. One of them is Shamil who calls himself "Pharao" and rules over Sarajevo as well as the Zinyth Enterprises, a conglomerate of biochemical and pharmaceutical companies which keeps the former Bosnian capital alive. But by what means?When a young scientist manages to flee from the gigantic industrial complex above Sarajevo, she speaks of human test subjects and the development of a virus that turns humans into will-less suicide bombers as well as a combat suit that grants its wearer unbelievable powers. Luckily she managed to take a prototype with her. Now its the turn of an American special agent known only as "Scorpion" who is send in to investigate - armed with the prototype and the knowledge of the scientist.Scorpion: Disfigured is a straight-forward first person shooter which puts the player in the shoes of said special agent and at the doorsteps of the sewer system of the company. It doesn't take long until he meets the first resistance in form of undead workers, super humans and security guards. To help him deal with the threat, he gets access to several different kinds of weapons ranging from pistols, grenades to machine guns and automatic shotguns as well as to the powers of his suit. Although Scorpion can carry many weapons at once, he can only equip three at a time and has to switch around the layout in the inventory if he wants to use another one.The suit allows the player to slow down time, gives him access to night vision goggles with heat sensors and a shield. But each function drains power from the suit that can only be replenished by finding and using batteries. The same goes for the special abilities including regeneration, psy shock and even mind control which require a different kind of energy. Both the weapons and the abilities can be leveled up. Scorpion gains experience for every enemy he kills and once the bar on top of the screen is full, he gets an upgrade part as a reward allowing him for example to increase the accuracy of his Striker XXI Automatic Shotgun. For the abilities on the other hand he needs to find special containers hidden in the levels containing a vial allowing for example to increase the duration of the time-slowdown. In addition the suit has a build-in Wiki-system that lists information about every weapon, ability and enemy the player encounters as well as a scanner which allows the creating of a rotatable 3D-map of the surrounding area</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2343274-scorpion.png</image></root>