<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27998</id><name>Fatale</name><description>Story Salome is a first century Judean princess mentioned in the Christian Bible by Matthew and by Mark. As a child she dances      for King Herodband asks the head of John the Baptist as a reward. In Wilde's 1891 version, Salome falls in love with the prophet. He rejects her and she has him executed. The play ends with her kissing the lips of his decapitated head. This game takes place after these events in two playable levels.Gameplay Level One: The Cistern The game starts you off in a dungeon, playing as an "unknown prisoner". You can only walk and look around. Eventually a      progress bar will appear at the bottom of the screen and, as it fills up, lines from Oscar Wilde's "Salome" will appear as floating text and fade away after a moment. After the progress bar fills, you are beheaded,  the title appears, and you are in the second level.       Level Two: The TerraceIn the last of the two levels, you play as the disembodied spirit of the prisoner in from the first level. You can float around by clicking either the left or right mouse button to move forward or backwards in the direction you're pointing. You must find various candles, lit matches, and other flames to extinguish. This is done by clicking on it until you enter a close up view. Here your cursor has become a cloud of smoke which can be used to put the flame out.   There are a few noticeable things in this level, including Salome, your executioner, and the decapitated head of John the Baptist. Also, there a few out-of-place things. Such as a guitar amplifier and an iPod  on Salome's waste. After finding all the flames and extinguishing them, the level ends and you are left only with the option of closing the game client.   Epilogue: The Dance"The Terrace" is the last level in the game but if you choose to restart the game client after completion you will be treated to a topless dance by Salome. You take a "throne view" of the terrace. nothing has changed except that it is now daytime. Salome will dance eternally unless you choose to restart the game or exit the client.ControlsFatale features a simplistic control scheme where the player only moves the character forward and backward and looks around. all interactions are done via moving the mouse cursor over objects. The second level of the game holds some very unorthodox controls. instead of using a joystick, or keyboard keys for movement, you instead click the left mouse button to float forward, or the the right mouse button to float backwards. This type if control is said to reduce the risk of motion sickness.  The player can also reduce or increase the amount of grain in the image with the "I" and  "O" keys, and take a screenshot with the "P" key</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/4/49626/1168838-01fatale20091012_051541.png</image></root>