<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>28037</id><name>QuantZ</name><description>GameplayIn the game, the player has to rotate a cube in 3D space to land marbles, called QuantZ, onto it. The goal is to clear the cube of all QuantZ. Colors can be matched when groups of 3 or more are touching each other. Explosions can occur when a Quantz is surrounded by 4 QuantZ of a different color. These reactions can be chained together to clear the cube. The QuantZ can be either free to move around or frozen. When they are frozen they will shimmer and are fixed onto the cube. The game can also be slowed down for precise movement.There are 3 different modes, Strategy, Action, and Puzzle.StrategyIn this mode, there are a limited amount of QuantZ to clear the cube with. Using less QuantZ will grant more score bonuses.ActionIn this mode, the QuantZ are fired off without the player's control. The player has to rotate the cube in accordance with the QuantZ.PuzzleIn Puzzle mode, the player is presented with a configuration of QuantZ on the cube and a limited amount of QuantZ to clear the cube with.Each stage in the game is represented by a different constellation and letter of the Greek alphabet. When each stage is completed, the player achieves the rank of that constellation. Each stage contains 8 levels to be cleared.PC System RequirementsOS: Windows XP/Vista/7Processor: 850MHz processorMemory: 512 MBGraphics: 128 MB of video memory, 16-bit or 32-bit color qualityDirectX®: DirectX 9 or laterHard Drive: 80MB of free hard drive spaceMac System RequirementsOS: OS X version Leopard 10.5.8, Snow Leopard 10.6.3, or laterProcessor: Intel Core 2 Duo 1.66 GhzMemory: 256MB of RAMHard Drive: 80MB free space</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14228">Bust-A-Move</game><game id="19017">Super Bust-A-Move</game><game id="26622">Bust-A-Move Plus!</game><game id="23984">Picross 3D</game><game id="35714">Critical Mass</game><game id="38994">Astroslugs</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1373252-dd_quantz.jpg</image></root>