<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>28082</id><name>Earth Eternal</name><description> Small story intro The time of Man has passed. The great achievements of humankind have been lost to antiquity or reclaimed by Mother Earth, leaving fresh ground for the ancient Beasts from which Man descended to return to Earth and contend with Demons, Faeries, Dragons, Gods, and Titans of old.   Set in a high-fantasy universe that combines real-world history, legend, and myth with original creations, Earth Eternal incorporates a blend of original fiction, mythologies from Norse to Egyptian, and classic fairy tales into an epic, sweeping story.   Game info The game is free to play, although it offers some in-game content which you can purchase with real money.  Races:It has a total of 22 races you can choose from, most being common animals. They look drastically different, but they have absolutely no racial differences among them. They all start with the same stats, and they can all be any of the four classes, none being better than the other in any of them.  The developers have stated that some player versus player combat system will be implemented, although its form has not yet been released.   Classes: The game has a total of four classes: Knight, Rogue, Mage, and Druid. The player can choose one of the four classes as a primary class, followed later in the game by a secondary class and possibly a tertiary class at a later point in the players advancement.  The player will not be restricted to their chosen class however; a Knight could specialize in melee combat, or they could learn some Mage, Rogue, or Druid skills if they want to.  KNIGHT:  The Knight is the primary up-close damage giver for the duration of combat. Others can do more damage up-close in the short term but none can tank and still deal out large amounts of damage.ROGUE: The most damaging class up-close for a short period of time.A little trickier to play as it depends on positioning as compared to the enemy.Rogues depend on being able to sneak up behind an enemy for maximum effectiveness.MAGE: The Mage is a long-range damage dealer, vulnerable up close to physical attacks. Their spells generate lots of aggro.The Mage gets 1 to 4 new mana bars; each bar represents a different element.DRUID: Druid is primary a buff-giver, and healer.Druids gain two mana bars: Life and Death, each of which must be 'focused on their melee weapon (staff, trident, or spear).They fill Life by healing others or being healed.They fill Death by doing damage to enemies.There's an ability to convert death energy into life energy. Groves They are areas, unique to each player or clan in the game. They will be a place separate from any world map; a place where the player can either be alone and in complete safety or a place to invite friends to hang out with while online. Each player will be able to choose from a number of different Groves, and will be able to modify the terrain, making mountains, valleys, lakes, etc. as they wish. Each player will be provided a basic Grove free of any charges. Additions or amenities such as furniture to the Groves will likely cost credits.</description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="24766">Cartoon Network Universe: FusionFall</game><game id="17494">Guild Wars</game><game id="19796">City of Heroes</game><game id="7316">City of Villains</game><game id="18547">EverQuest II</game><game id="21223">Guild Wars 2</game><game id="2268">RuneScape</game><game id="23411">Runescape Classic</game><game id="20666">Warhammer Online: Age of Reckoning</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/33787/1129395-250px_eelogo_bigblackbg.jpg</image></root>