<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>28165</id><name>J-League Soccer: Prime Goal 2</name><description>OverviewJ-League Soccer: Prime Goal 2 is a video game licensed by J-League, published by Namco. It is the second game in the J-League Soccer Prime Goal series, preceded by J-League Soccer: Prime Goal and succeeded by 90 Minutes: European Prime Goal. Prime Goal 2 was released on August 5, 1994 only in Japan for the Super Famicom.GameplayPrime Goal 2 has all of the features of a traditional soccer game.Prime Goal 2 is similar to other top-down soccer simulators of the time. The player controls a single team member at a time. When in possession of the ball, the player will always control that team member, but otherwise the controlled team member can be switched with the press of a button. Control is automatically swapped when the player's character is off-screen, or when the ball begins to approach a different team member.Other than running around, shooting, passing, and slide-tackling, the player has control over several other actions. Naturally, there are throw ins (the player can select which team member to throw the ball to), goal kicks (where the player controls the distance the ball is kicked), fouls (referees even dole out yellow and red cards), and occasionally a one-on-one minigame. In this one-on-one game the player can either manage to relinquish control of the ball from the opponent, or have the opponent jump over the player (depending on the player's button inputs).Of note are the variety of modes that are offered in Prime Goal 2. Naturally, there is a player vs. computer and player vs. player mode, but also included are a campaign mode (complete with a password system), a penalty kick mode, and an "east vs. west" mode where the player is able to consolidate members from several teams into one, customized team.TeamsThe game's twelve teams.Kashima AntlersJEF UnitedShonan BellmareShimizu S-PulseUrawa Red DiamondsVerdy YomiuriJúbilo IwataNagoya Grampus EightYokohama F. MarinosAS FlügelsGamba OsakaSanfrecce Hiroshima</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="40">Soccer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="27453">Sensible Soccer</game><game id="23274">Captain Tsubasa Vol. II: Super Striker</game><game id="7025">International Superstar Soccer Deluxe</game><game id="12888">FIFA Soccer 95</game><game id="14524">FIFA Soccer 96</game><game id="15167">I Play: 3-D Soccer</game><game id="28164">J-League Soccer: Prime Goal</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/14/149200/2238451-prime_goal_2.jpg</image></root>