<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>28229</id><name>Umineko no Naku Koro ni Episode 1: Legend of the Golden Witch</name><description>Series OverviewUmineko no Naku Koro ni: Legend of the Golden Witch is the first episode in the Umineko no Naku Koro ni series and the first entry of The Question Arc.StoryThe story starts in the island of Rokkenjima as the annual family conference of the Ushiromiya family is being held. The children of the head of the family, Kinzo Ushiromiya, all arrive to the island with their families to discuss the inheritance of their father's vast fortune. On the same day a typhoon traps them on the island and seals Rokkenjima off from the outside world. Shortly after the typhoon breaks out members of the family start going missing, leading to the discovery of a gruesome murder scene with six of the people on the island found dead and disfigured.Stranded on an isolated island with a killer among them, it's up to the surviving family members and servants to find the culprit.CharactersUshiromiya FamilyBattler Ushiromiya, Jessica Ushiromiya, George Ushiromiya, Maria Ushiromiya, Ange Ushiromiya, Kinzo Ushiromiya, Rudolf Ushiromiya, Kyrie Ushiromiya, Krauss Ushiromiya, Natsuhi Ushiromiya, Rosa Ushiromiya, Eva Ushiromiya, and Hideyoshi UshiromiyaMansion StaffGenji Ronoue, Kanon, Shannon, Terumasa Nanjo, Chiyo Kumasawa, and Toshiro GohdaGameplayUmineko features no real player interaction from the player. The player's only real interaction is by advancing through the dialogue and story with a click of a button. At any point in the game, the player can go to the games menu and access the TIPS. TIPS are basically supplementary information that is given to the player. They can use this extra information to further enhance the players knowledge about the story or its characters. The TIPS are regularly updated as the story progresses.TranslationWhile the game hasn't been officially translated into English yet a fan translation is available at witch-hunt with episodes 1 through 8 already fully translated. These translation patches work with any fully paid version of the game. The author of the series, Ryukishi07, has given his support to these fan translations and has also added an in-game reference to the fan project in the fourth episode, Alliance of the Golden Witch. In the aforementioned episode a character identifies himself as a witch hunter, a theorist whose aim is to uncover the mysteries surrounding the events that occurred within Rokkenjima. As of December 17, 2011, the Witch Hunt Translation Project has completed their work on all eight episodes of the game.AvailabilityDespite not having an official release outside of Japan, the games can be digitally purchased through the EC Order.com download service. A demo, containing all of Episode 1: Legend of the Golden Witch, is freely available at the Getting Started page of Witch-Hunt.com.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23887">Higurashi no Naku Koro ni: Onikakushi-hen</game><game id="37390">Rose Guns Days</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/39164/1155216-umineko_no_naku_koro_ni_cover.jpg</image></root>