<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>28440</id><name>Madden NFL Arcade</name><description>OverviewA arcade version similar to the 5 on 5 mode in the Wii version of Madden that was released through digital distribution. It was released on November 25 2009.GameplayArcade-Style RulesYou have four downs to score on a shortened 60-yard field. With no penalties or game clock and a streamlined playcall system, you're in for fast-paced, high-scoring games courtesy of the league's biggest stars. The first team to score 30 points is the winner.Co-op and Online Game ModesPlay cooperatively with up to three other players offline, or go head-to-head online in ranked or unranked games. With online leaderboards and custom match options, tailor your Madden NFL Arcade experience to fit your playing style.Take advantage of 13 unique Game Changers to break the game wide open in a single play. Freeze one of your opponent's players, add extra lineman to sack the QB, turn off your opponent's passing icons, grant yourself an extra down on offense, and more. With action-packed Game Changers, every play counts!A complete list of Game Changers is below:Entourage: Bring in the reinforcements as Entourage sends the rest of your lineman into the game to help out for a play.Triple Threat: Disguise which receiver you're throwing the ball by sending out two other decoys with the Power Ball game changer.Bonus Play: Give yourself an additional down to help get in the end zone and earn some much deserved points with Bonus Play.Make It, Take It: If you're good enough to score when you trigger Make It, Take It, the ball is yours to keep on the next possession.Turbo: The Turbo game changer will send players in fast forward by giving them an extra speed burst.Molasses: Game too fast for you? Use Molasses to take down the action on the field to a less frantic pace.Fumbilitis: Turn your opponent's into butter fingers as they'll have a difficult time holding on to the ball with Fumbilitis.It's Alive: Make any pass a scramble for the ball as its Alive will turn any incomplete pass into a live ball.Frostbite: Put the freeze on one opposing player from moving by using the game changer Frostbite.Fast Pass: Fast Pass gives the power to a QB to throw the ultimate bulleted pass.Flying Blind: Sabotage your opponent by using Flying Blind to turn off their passing icons.Flip Flop: Jealous of your opponents score? Flip Flop will nicely borrow the score and never give it back.Dud: Hey, they can't all be winners.</description><genres><genre id="21">Football</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="24738">3 on 3 NHL Arcade</game><game id="33222">NFL Blitz</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1795309-box_maddnfla.png</image></root>