<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>28453</id><name>NEOTOKYO째</name><description>OverviewNEOTOKYO째 is a multiplayer Half-Life 2 modification in the vein of Counter-Strike, set in a near-future Tokyo where a violent coup has led to civil war. As a member of either the National Security Force (NSF) or the ultranationalist splinter cell JINRAI, players will have to engage in tense tactical gameplay in order to achieve the main objective of capturing a valuable cyborg, the Ghost. The modification is a sequel to the first NEOTOKYO째, which originally came out for Unreal Tournament 2004.Aesthetically, the game takes its cues from cyberpunk anime like Ghost in the Shell and Akira, with an exotic, lush soundtrack from composer Ed Harrison.GameplayClassesAfter joining the NSF or JINRAI, there are three playable classes to choose from, each having their own set of different unique abilities. The Recon class can sprint indefinitely unlike the Assault class and can long jump across vast distances, although in doing so it will drain large amounts of auxiliary power which will eventually recharge. The Recon class also has the ability to cloak for far longer time periods compared to the Assault class. Recon is the only class as well to start out with the player activated detonation packs. The Assault class on the other hand, can use any weapon dropped from each class with no penalty, and can withstand more damage though the class is still vulnerable to headshots. They're also the only class to start out with fragmentation grenades. The Support class is the least maneuverable of the three classes due to their heavy combat chassis, preventing them to sprint and jump far distances. In turn though, the Support class can withstand extreme punishing damage, taking multiple body shots which would normally kill a Recon or Assault player. Headshots also have no multiplying damage effect on the Support class. Support players also start out with smoke grenades which will obscure and render the other two classes blind, even with their respective vision modes enabled.Vision ModesEach class also has it's own unique vision mode. Recon players can use night-vision to illuminate dark areas, allowing them to easily navigate and/or prepare ambushes in said areas. Assault players have access to motion vision, which lets them track and detect any object or player which is currently moving with ease, regardless if the player they're tracking has cloaking enabled, though motion vision will not pick up players who are standing still. Support players can use thermal vision to pick up and trace body heat given off by any player, which is extremely useful when Support players throw smoke grenades into the area, allowing them to pick off helpless Recon and Assault players.GhostThe Ghost is a name given to a civilian model android which is storing vital data to both the NSF and JINRAI. It has the ability to hack into any civilian/military network. The team that manages to pick up the Ghost can use it to connect to the opposing team's network to view their current positions in the level, revealing possible flanking maneuvers and ambush points.Capture the GhostCapture the Ghost, also known as CTG, is NEOTOKYO째's main game mode. Players from both teams must engage and use tactics against their respective opposing team while attempting to pick up and retrieve the Ghost. Whoever picks up and retrieves the Ghost or eliminates the entire opposing team will win the round. There is no respawning in this mode, which means dying is a major penalty for those who act carelessly and recklessly.</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11339">Counter-Strike: Source</game><game id="11663">Half-Life: Counter-Strike</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/6/61716/1152333-nt_logo.gif</image></root>