<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>28484</id><name>Joe Danger</name><description>OverviewGame logoJoe Danger is the first game from Hello Games, and was released on the PlayStation Network June 8th, 2010 in the US and June 9th in Europe.The Xbox 360 version was released on the Xbox Live Marketplace more than one year later, on December 14th, 2011 as Joe Danger: Special Edition.The developers have mentioned the possibility of the game eventually being released on the PC as well. A sequel was released in 2012 named Joe Danger 2: The Movie.GameplayDo stunts, earn pointsThe titular Joe Danger is a famous stunt driver and daredevil. Controlled by the player, he can drive both forward and backwards, with the ability to control the speed and direction of the motorcycle, even in midair. Joe can also perform a small hop, to jump over obstacles or jump off ramps and springs for extra height.Using the height gained from ramps, springs, and other obstacles, the player can also perform a variety of stunts before touching the ground. Stunts can be strung together into a combo either by preforming several stunts in the air at once, or preforming a wheelie or endo after touching the ground, or a combination of both. Performing stunts will also fill a boost meter, which can be used when fully charged to provide a temporary speed boost.The levels in Joe Danger consist of three parallel lanes, each with a variety of obstacles, which can either help or hinder progress through the course. Ramps, springs, fans, and boost pads all help by giving either more height or speed, while spikes, shark tanks, mouse traps and the dreaded horizontal bar all serve to make the ride more perilous. Lanes can only be changed at lane change switches, making which lane choice strategic for completing certain objectives.Collect all the coins!Each level has one main objective and at least one secondary objective. The main objective is tied to the rating for the level (gold, silver or bronze). The most common main objective is getting a high score, which is achieved by preforming stunts. More points are awarded for stunts that take longer to complete, for holding the stunt for as long as possible without crashing, and performing as many stunts as possible in a single combo (with each stunt adding to the score multiplier). Other main objectives include landing on targets placed around the course (simply driving over them doesn't count), collecting as many coins within a certain time limit, knocking over bowling pins with Joe 'ragdolling' after crashing, or competing in a race with other drivers.One of the race objectivesThe secondary objectives for each level are tied to stars, which are used to unlock additional levels. Secondary objectives range from landing on targets, collecting coins, knocking over bowling pins, and finishing first in a race, assuming they aren't the main objective, and other goals such as collecting ministars, completing a level or another objective before a set time limit, completing a level or objective while maintaining a combo through the entire level, collecting the letters D-A-N-G-E-R, and lastly, finding stars hidden in the course.Career ModeThe main game mode consists of ten tiers, each with a different set of levels that you unlock progressively.Don't get eaten by a shark!Stunt WeeklyTeam NastyComeback TourHigh VoltageExplosive TourShock HazardCrush ZoneThe Danger ZoneMaster of DisasterGrand FinaleMap EditorJoe Danger also includes a map editor. Every object that was available to the developers is available for the player to build a course. One can also include any objective that is available in the main game in their custom level. Custom levels can be shared via friends on the PlayStation Network, or, as of a recent update, on the Hello Games website.PS3 UpdateIn August 2010, Hello Games released an update for Joe Danger called the "People's Patch". Users can download levels from Hello Games' website, instead of having to share with friends only. Users can also upload their levels for anyone to enjoy. A USB stick is required to move the levels between the console and computer.Levels can be uploaded/downloaded here.Other new features include:Replay saving, and uploading to YouTubeCustom music (play music on your hard drive as you play the game)Added multiplayer levelsEven more level editing propsCostumes, including a monkey suitNew ToursHidden secretsSpecial EditionThe XBLA version released in December 2011 titled Joe Danger: Special Edition features added content, including new environments, characters and gameplay modes, such as new Challenge mode: 'The Laboratory'. At Christmas it also received a free Santa downloadable costume for Joe.System RequirementsOS: Windows® 7 (32/64-bit)/Vista/XPProcessor: 2.0Ghz Dual core processorMemory: 1 GB RAMGraphics: DirectX 10 compatible GPUDirectX®: 10Hard Drive: 700 MB HD spaceAdditional: Microsoft Xbox 360 Controller or Direct Input compatible controller</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26923">Trials HD</game><game id="15025">Excitebike</game><game id="20602">LittleBigPlanet</game><game id="26848">ModNation Racers</game><game id="21436">TrackMania Nations Forever</game><game id="2465">Sonic the Hedgehog</game><game id="859">FlatOut 2</game><game id="31614">Wipeout: The Game</game><game id="335">Kikstart: Off-Road Simulator</game><game id="35566">Trials Evolution</game><game id="19879">Motocross Maniacs</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/6/63119/1444890-joe_danger_psn_and_xbla.png</image></root>