<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>28520</id><name>Portopia Renzoku Satsujin Jiken</name><description>OverviewPortopia Renzoku Satsujin Jiken (The Portopia Serial Murder Case), is an adventure game created by Yuji Horii and published by Enix (now Square Enix). First conceived in 1981, it was released on the NEC PC-6001 in June 1983, and later ported to other personal computers. Chunsoft ported the game to the Nintendo Entertainment System (NES) on November 29, 1985, and to different mobile phone services starting in 2001.The game is an investigation adventure, sophisticated for its time, in which the player must resolve a murder mystery by searching for clues, exploring different areas, interacting with characters, and solving item-based puzzles. The game, especially its NES version, was received positively in Japan, where it was an influential title that defined the visual novel genre, in addition to paving the way for the seminal Dragon Quest series of console role-playing games as well as inspiring new game designers such as Hideo Kojima.It is the first entry in the Yuji Horii Mysteries trilogy. It was followed by Hokkaidou Rensa Satsujin: Ohotsuku ni Kiyu!! in 1984 and Karuizawa Yuukai Annai in 1985.PlotKouzou Yamakawa, the president of the Loan and Savings Company, was found dead inside his mansion. A detective and his assistant arrive at the scene for further investigation. The player must resolve the mystery of a murder by searching for clues, interacting with characters, and solving item-based puzzles.External linkPortopia Renzoku Satsujin Jiken, VNDB </description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="27351">Tantei Jinguuji Saburo: Yokohama-ko Renzoku Satsujin Jiken</game><game id="27348">Tantei Jinguuji Saburo: Shinjuku Chuo Koen Satsujin Jiken</game><game id="27352">Tantei Jinguuji Saburo: Kiken na Futari</game><game id="27357">Tantei Jinguuji Saburo: Toki no Sugiyuku mamani..</game><game id="27358">Tantei Jinguuji Saburo Early Collection</game><game id="28876">Hokkaidou Rensa Satsujin: Ohotsuku ni Kiyu!!</game><game id="28485">Karuizawa Yuukai Annai</game><game id="5758">Famicom Tantei Club Part II: Ushiro ni Tatsu Shoujo</game><game id="26613">Famicom Tantei Club: Kieta Koukeisha</game><game id="38812">Toki no Tabibito</game><game id="39246">Loretta no Shouzou</game><game id="39249">Sanma no Meitantei</game><game id="39499">Cleopatra no Mahou</game><game id="34684">Famicom Mukashi Banashi: Shin Onigashima</game><game id="37119">Yamamura Misa Suspense: Kyouto Ryuu no Tera Satsujin Jiken</game><game id="39835">Satsui no Kaisou</game><game id="17444">Hoshi wo Sagashite...</game><game id="40033">Meitantei Holmes: Kiri no London Satsujin Jiken</game><game id="40131">Jarinko Chie</game><game id="22809">JESUS: Kyoufu no Bio Monster</game><game id="28343">Metal Slader Glory</game><game id="40380">Samurai Sword</game><game id="40394">Jaaman Tanteidan: Matonarikumi</game><game id="40409">Nankin no Adventure</game><game id="40512">Sadakichi Seven: Hideyoshi no Ougon</game><game id="40535">Pro Yakyuu? Satsujin Jiken!</game><game id="37128">Nishimura Kyoutarou Mystery: Blue Train Satsujin Jiken</game><game id="40592">Yamamura Misa Suspense: Kyouto Hana no Misshitsu Satsujin Jiken</game><game id="40780">Meitantei Holmes: M-Kara no Chousenjou</game><game id="41772">Dead Zone</game><game id="4555">Princess Tomato in the Salad Kingdom</game><game id="28487">Wingman</game><game id="28494">Golgo 13: Moretti Ichizoku Zansatsu Jiken</game><game id="28495">Golgo 13: Ōkami no Su</game><game id="28879">Star Arthur Densetsu I: Wakusei Mephius</game><game id="38599">JESUS</game><game id="3709">Déjà Vu: A Nightmare Comes True</game><game id="33786">Tokyo Nampa Street</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/5/59247/1173583-portopia_fm_7.jpg</image></root>