<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2870</id><name>Ian Livingstone's Deathtrap Dungeon</name><description>OverviewDeathtrap Dungeon (AKA as Ian Livingstone's Deathtrap Dungeon) is a third person action adventure game with a medieval fantasy setting of sword  sorcery. The game world is based on the Fighting Fantasy book series, although the actual game and story do not share many aspects or features with the world as depicted in the books. The game is a dungeon crawler with the players controlling one of two possible characters (one being an armored male and the other being a not at all armored female, which rather explains the image gallery) making their way through dungeons ridden with traps and monsters, loaded with treasures and potions, let alone minor puzzle elements such as locked doors etc. Although the combat is essentially melee, players can also launch ranged and magic attacks. The game featured two forms of non-co-op multiplayer modes, Last Man Standing and Deathmatch.WeaponsSword: The regular sword; players begin with this in the inventory.Venom sword: Based on the principle of like-defeats-like, this poisonous sword is most effective against the dungeon's poisoners like spiders etc.Silver sword: Anathema to the undead. Especially useful in destroying skeletons and ghosts.Red sword: Imbued with the essence of fire, this sword is the bane of demons and dragons.Black spiritsword: Found only in Vilefor's lair, this devastating weapon slices cleanly through the toughest hide, but drains health as players slash the enemy.Warhammer: The standard of this weapon type, it will remain in the inventory permanently once found.Magic warhammer: More colorful, and definitely more powerful than it's non- magic counterpart. Made by dwarves, these are the only weapons that can hurt the Rockmen.Grenade launcher: Lobs explosive shells slightly less powerful than bombs in an arc.Infernal device: This hard to find device is essentially a medieval rocket launcher.Firethrower: Known in some circles as the flamethrower, it does just that.SpellsFirefly: Increases illumination in the near vicinity.Starspell: Flies straight and causes minor damage.Fireball: The most common and most reliable spell. Ball of flame flies straight until it hits a target or a wall.Razorspell: Shoots a small burst of razor-sharp blades in a straight line.Jetspell: Shoots a rapidly-spreading burst of rocks than explode on contact.Arc of power: Can instantly electrocute up to 3 enemies.War pigs: This spell launches pigs equipped with explosives that will blow up anyone they run into.</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21473">Blade of Darkness</game><game id="15065">Dark Messiah of Might &amp; Magic</game><game id="9641">Age of Conan: Hyborian Adventures</game><game id="3023">Tomb Raider</game><game id="13474">Rune</game><game id="27265">Fighting Fantasy: The Warlock of Firetop Mountain</game><game id="9407">The Warlock of Firetop Mountain</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/5/58746/1311516-deathtrap_dungeon__video_game_.jpg</image></root>