<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>28876</id><name>Hokkaidou Rensa Satsujin: Ohotsuku ni Kiyu!!</name><description>A visual novel and adventure game, written and designed by Yuji Horii, it is the second game in the Yuji Horii Mysteries trilogy. Soon after the release of Portopia Renzoku Satsujin Jiken (Portopia Serial Murder Case), he began development on Hokkaidou Rensa Satsujin: Ohotsuku ni Kiyu (Hokkaido Chain Murders: Okhotsk Vanishes) in September 1983 and released it in 1984. It was published by ASCII for the PC-6001 and PC-8801 platforms in 1984 and for the FM-7 in 1985.The game was responsible for popularizing the command selection menu system. Its replacement of the traditional verb-noun text parser interface with the command selection menu system would lead to the latter becoming a staple of adventure games and visual novels, as well as role-playing games through Horii's 1986 hit Dragon Quest. The 1987 Famicom port of Hokkaido Chain Murders also featured a point-and-click interface, much like the 1985 Famicom port of Portopia Serial Murder Case.In 1985, Hokkaidou Rensa Satsujin was followed by Karuizawa Yuukai Annai (Karuizawa Kidnapping Guide), the final part of the Yuji Horii Mysteries trilogy.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="28520">Portopia Renzoku Satsujin Jiken</game><game id="28485">Karuizawa Yuukai Annai</game><game id="39499">Cleopatra no Mahou</game><game id="34684">Famicom Mukashi Banashi: Shin Onigashima</game><game id="37119">Yamamura Misa Suspense: Kyouto Ryuu no Tera Satsujin Jiken</game><game id="39835">Satsui no Kaisou</game><game id="40033">Meitantei Holmes: Kiri no London Satsujin Jiken</game><game id="40592">Yamamura Misa Suspense: Kyouto Hana no Misshitsu Satsujin Jiken</game><game id="37128">Nishimura Kyoutarou Mystery: Blue Train Satsujin Jiken</game><game id="33786">Tokyo Nampa Street</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/5/59247/1155950-ohoa.jpg</image></root>