<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2895</id><name>Battle Arena Toshinden 3</name><description>Battle Arena Toshinden 3, released in 1996, is a fighting game for the Playstation. As the third offical game in the Toshinden series, it is the sequel to Battle Arena Toshinden 2 and Battle Arena Toshinden. While it retained the weapon based combat of the first two games, it also changed the series with its gameplay improvements. The most notable change is the enclosed arenas, a first for the series. This allowed players to smash their foes into the walls and ceilings and continue their combos from there, making the game more "juggle" heavy. The combo system also recieved an upgrade, with each character having a preset list of combos. Battle Arena Toshinden 3 also featured 17 new characters with a total of 32 characters; some characters in the previous games were dropped. Battle Arena Toshinden 3 was the last Toshinden game to come out in the United States, with the fourth game being released in Europe only.Initial Playable CharactersEijiShinjoKayinSofiaRungo IronBayhouMondoDuke B. RambertEllisGaiaChaosTracyDavidShizukuNagisaUnlockable CharactersLeonTen CountZolaAdamCuilingToujinBalgaAtahuaTauSchultzRachaelJudgementMiss TilVermilionFinal BossesSho ShinjoAbelVeil</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11822">Soulcalibur II</game><game id="10872">Wu-Tang: Shaolin Style</game><game id="12411">Soulcalibur</game><game id="9855">Soulcalibur III</game><game id="20678">Soulcalibur IV</game><game id="10081">Tekken</game><game id="10387">Tekken 2</game><game id="11189">Tekken 3</game><game id="14684">Tekken 4</game><game id="18753">Tekken 5</game><game id="20689">Tekken 6</game><game id="11606">Tekken: Dark Resurrection</game><game id="10162">Tekken Tag Tournament</game><game id="15584">Virtua Fighter</game><game id="41">Virtua Fighter 2</game><game id="19766">Virtua Fighter 3</game><game id="4313">Virtua Fighter 4</game><game id="4891">Virtua Fighter 4: Evolution</game><game id="707">Virtua Fighter 5</game><game id="2045">Dead or Alive 2</game><game id="7792">Dead or Alive 4</game><game id="6421">Mortal Kombat 4</game><game id="19043">Fighters Megamix</game><game id="3744">Def Jam: Fight for NY</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="721">Ehrgeiz: God Bless the Ring</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/25966/2103897-battle_arena_toshinden_3_coverart.png</image></root>