<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29096</id><name>Everyday Genius: SquareLogic</name><description>Gameplay / ConceptSquarelogic is, at its core, a clone of KenKen-style games. The game takes place on a square grid, where no two numbers may share a row or column. Unlike Sudoku style games, there are no numbers on the grid to begin with. Instead, the numbers are derived through the process of elimination. Segments of the grid have part of a math problem on them, such as "4x." In that case, the numbers within the cage would have to multiply to result in 4, i.e. 4x1 or 2x2. In normal Kenken games, there are also addition, subtraction and division cages.Here are the rules used:Normal KenKen rulesAdditionSubtractionMultiplicationDivisionSpecial Squarelogic rulesOdd: All squares in this cage must have odd values (1, 3, 5, 7, or 9).Even: All squares in this cage must have odd values (2, 4, 6, or 8).Greater Than, Lesser Than: The value of the squares must be greater or lesser than the one next to it according to the bracketsStraight: All squares in this cage must form a "straight" (like poker), IN ANY ORDER (for example: 4,3,5)Hidden: Blank squares that do not show their rule but must be colored in.None: No rule at all.Some puzzles are Double Board puzzles; for these puzzles, both boards have the same answers, and you solve them both simultaneously.RegionsThe game is separated into six regions of which only five are visible from the start. Each new region represents a more difficult size of grid, and this features more difficult puzzles. These regions are separated further into locations. Each location contains a specific type of puzzle. There are 12 practice puzzles, followed by a challenge puzzle. Completing the challenge puzzle unlocks the next location, as well as puzzles of varying difficulty in the current location.The regions and locations within the game are as follows:Ocean - 4x4Canyon - 5x5Forest 6x6BeginningsOcean FloorShipwreckKelpShelfArchShallowsShoreGrottoTunnelCaveCanyonRisePathStreamBridgeTrailGroveGlenHilltopViewMountain - 7x7Sky - 8x8Beyond - 9x9PassWaterfallCrestVistaPrecipiceSpireSummitHorizonCloudVaporRainStormSkyTwilightSecretEnigmaTranquilitySerenitySelf-AwarenessSelf-RelianceBeyond</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="27544">Brain Age Express: Sudoku</game><game id="10477">Buku Sudoku</game><game id="8056">Go! Sudoku</game><game id="27015">KENKEN: Train Your Brain</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/12388/1177698-header.jpg</image></root>