<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29229</id><name>Saints of Virtue</name><description> OverviewSaints of Virtue is a Christian themed first-person shooter where you battle giant floating heads that represent different Christian sins in the kingdom of your heart. The game world consist of four large levels built of strange and erratic mazes. The player's primary objective is to search for scrolls that they then use to unlock the level exit and progress to the next.GameplayThe player starts with a projectile weapon called “the sword of the spirit” which fires small electric sparks. As you progress through the game you collect more powerful weapons, including dual swords and even a machine gun sword!? Navigation can be somewhat frustrating due to limitations in the game engine. You will often encounter deadly drops, high ledges, and enemies on various elevations. Which can be very tricky since the game doesn't support mouse-look or key remapping. Combat offers vary little variety with most enemies usually heading strait for the player while randomly firing. Each enemy's movement pattern can vary, making them harder to hit, but their slow moving projectiles can be easily dodged.TechnologySaints of Virtue was built using ACKNEX 3 (later called 3D GameStudio) by Conitec. Although more user friendly then most engines, the technology was outdated and inferior to most other engines of the time.LevelsThe Amphitheater of ApathyThe first level represents the tendency to be apathetic as a Christian. Locations:Caves of LonelinessPits of DespairMall of DistractionsGallery of NothingnessMedia MazeEnemies:WorldlinessVanityThe Labyrinths of LegalismThe second level is symbolic of belief systems based on worldly works.Locations:Twisty MazeTrap DungeonAbstract MazeRules MazeEnemies:FearSelf-righteousnessThe New Age NirvanaThe third level is representative of the idea that we can become our own gods.Locations:Love  Peace TempleMountains of RelativityShrine of HeavenEarth ShrineTemple of ManEnemies:Self-glorificationArroganceThe Domain of The HeartThe last level contains the temple and throne room of your heart.Locations:Swamplands of SelfishnessRuins of PridePath of PerseveranceTemple of the HeartEnemies:???</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7694">Wolfenstein 3D</game><game id="6716">The War in Heaven</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/5/50264/1189674-saintsofvirtue.png</image></root>