<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29264</id><name>Mega Man III</name><description>Robot Masters Snake ManSnake Man returns from Mega Man 3. His weakness is the Spark Shock (SP). When defeated he grants Mega Man the Search Snake (SN) and Rush Coil (RC). Gemini Man Gemini Man returns from Mega Man 3. His weakness is the Search Snake (SN). When defeated he grants Mega Man the Gemini Laser (GE). Shadow Man Shadow Man returns from Mega Man 3. His weakness is the Gemini Laser (GE). When defeated he grants Mega Man the Shadow Blade (SH). Spark Man Spark Man returns from Mega Man 3. His weakness is the Shadow Blade (SH). When defeated he grants Mega Man the Spark Shock (SP).Giant SuzyGiant Suzy is the mid-game boss players will face inside Dr. Wily's fortress after defeating the first four robot masters. It's weakness is the Spark Shock (SP). Killing Giant Suzy will allow access to the next four robot masters. Dust Man Dust Man returns from Mega Man 4. His weakness is the Drill Bomb (DR). When defeated he grants Mega Man the Dust Crusher (DU) and Rush Jet (RJ). Skull ManSkull Man returns from Mega Man 4. His weakness is the Dust Crusher (DU). When defeated he grants Mega Man the Skull Barrier (SK). Dive ManDive Man returns from Mega Man 4. His weaknesses are either the Dust Crusher (DU) or the Skull Barrier (SK). Both are equally effective. When defeated he grants Mega Man the Dive Missile (DI). Drill ManDrill Man returns from Mega Man 4. His weakness is the Dive Missile (DI). When defeated he grants Mega Man the Drill Bomb (DR).PunkPunk is the mid-game boss players will face inside Dr. Wily's fortress after defeating the second four robot masters. It's weakness is the standard Mega Buster (P). When defeated it grants Mega Man the Screw Crusher (PU) and allows Mega Man to progress deeper into the final level of the game. Dr. WilyAfter facing another Giant Suzy and the other various traps inside Dr. Wily's fortress, players will finally face off with the man himself. During his first phase he is vulnerable to the standard Mega Buster (P). During his second phase he is vulnerable to the Screw Crusher (PU).Critical ReceptionWhen the Game Boy version was released in 1993 Electronic Gaming Monthly awarded Mega Man 3 a Gold Editor's Choice emblem and scores of 8,8,9 and 7. They stated, "...a near perfect copy of the NES version. The game plays the same, looks the same (without color of course) and almost sounds the same. This is easily one of the best GB action titles to come out in a long time. great bosses and not a lot of screen blurring".</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4518">Mega Man 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1806088-box_mmgb3.png</image></root>