<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29265</id><name>Zombie Driver</name><description>SummaryThe player controls a vehicle with guns, or other weapons attached to them. They use said car and weapons to mow down hordes of zombies. The car is viewed from a top down perspective, similar to Grand Theft Auto: Chinatown Wars for DS and PSP. The game also supports nVidia PhysX, which improves the physics in the game. (Not required to play it.)The game was re-released as Zombie Driver HD on October 17, 2012 to XBLA and Steam platforms, with PSN and Android versions forthcoming. The new version now includes 31 missions and new objectives, vehicles and enemies.Game FeaturesThe protagonist running for his car in the opening cut-sceneA story made up of 17 chapters each featuring main objectives and secondary objectives. Completing secondary objectives unlock new cars and upgrades.A large, open city full of zombies.7 different cars: Taxi, limo, sports car, police, ambulance, bus and a super car.9 upgrades for each car for the car's armor, ramming and speed stats.All weapons have 3 tiers which come with unique features.Dynamic combo system with tricks and hordes of zombies to try it on.Many vicious zombie types including zombie dogs and exploding zombies.A new 'Slaughter' game mode added as an update with Patch v1.1.1. It is a survival mode featuring five areas and online leaderboards.A new free mode called Blood Race added during steams midweek madness on November 19th 2010 as part of the latest patch. Includes tournament and single race options. In tournament you compete in multi stage cup races against increasingly more challenging ai. Tracks come in elimination, race and endurance varients. Race is pretty standard, elimination is based on highest kills while endurance involves bombs being strapped to your vehicle and you having to get at many points as possible before exploding while killing zombies and hitting check points.SoundtrackThe original score for Zombie Driver was composed by Pawel Stelmach and is available for free download at the game's official website.Track #Song TitleRunning Time01Red Plague (intro)01.3002City of Destruction (main menu)02.4703Breath of the Underworld03.0504Lonely Struggle02.4405Death Bells03.0906Evil Digit02.3007Dying Here04.0408Rigor Mortis02.2809Dying Here (trailer edit)01.3610City of Destruction (in-game edit)03.3811Breath of the Underworld (alternate edit)03.4712City of Destruction (trailer edit)01.2713Escape from Hell (outro)00.39System RequirementsMinimumRecommendedOS: Windows 7/Vista/XP (Only)Processor: 1.6 GHz Intel Pentium processor or equivalent AMD Athlon processorMemory: 1GBGraphics: 128 MB DirectX 9.0c compatible or better video card with pixelshader 3.0DirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 800MB of free spaceSound: DirectX 9.0c compatible sound cardOS: Windows 7/Vista/XP (Only)Processor: 2.0 GHz dual core processorMemory: 2GBGraphics: 512 MB DirectX 9.0c compatible or better video card with pixelshader 3.0DirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 800MB of free spaceSound: DirectX 9.0c compatible sound card</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13567">Grand Theft Auto</game><game id="10593">Grand Theft Auto 2</game><game id="9112">Crazy Taxi</game><game id="3819">Zombie Shooter</game><game id="29282">Zombie Shooter 2</game><game id="18394">Carmageddon</game><game id="9017">Mad Max</game><game id="25641">D.I.P.R.I.P. Warm Up</game><game id="2954">Zombie Virus</game><game id="32627">Blood Drive</game><game id="18044">Death Rally</game><game id="34619">Renegade Ops</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1370488-dd_zd.jpg</image></root>