<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29321</id><name>Prince of Persia: The Forgotten Sands</name><description>PlotThe Forgotten Sands ignores the 2008 reboot of the franchise and returns to the concluded Sands of Time trilogy of games' story and universe. According to Ubisoft's official press release:Prince of Persia: The Forgotten Sands is the next chapter in the fan-favourite Sands of Time universe. Visiting his brother’s kingdom following his adventure in Azad, the Prince finds the royal palace under siege from a mighty army bent on its destruction.The Prince will be visiting his brothers Royal Palace.The game for the 360, PS3, and PC versions takes place between Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time and Prince of Persia: Warrior Within, giving insight on how the Prince turned from a charming young rogue to an emotionally unstable murderer.The Wii version takes place with the Prince being lead by the Genie Zahra, who is making claims that she can give the Prince a kingdom and princess if he follows her. Once they arrive to the spot where the kingdom was to be, the Prince sees nothing and feels cheated. Zahra tells him to kiss a statue in the middle of the clearing and once he does, he is able to see what Zahra sees, which is the kingdom of Izdihar. The Prince soon realizes that the kingdom is in poor condition, but manages to find a sword stuck in stone. After pulling it out, he accidently frees a women and a beast named Homa. While searching for the beast, Zahra tells the Prince that the genies once lived in Izdihar, but were all killed by the Haoma. In effect, the Wii version is a prequel to the other console versions because as the Prince leaves the ruins of Izdihar, he heads to his brother's kingdom to begin the next part of the Forgotten Sands storyline.Although its release window deliberately coincides with the release of the Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time movie, the storyline of The Forgotten Sands has nothing to do with that of the film.GameplayThe use of the series' trademark time-rewinding mechanics is present, and some new powers have been included, such as allowing the Prince to influence the elements of nature, including earth, water, wind, fire and ice. Several of your elemental powers allow you to control aspects crucial in puzzle solving. For example, the Prince is able to perform an air dash, allowing him to cross long distances. His ability to stop water from flowing allows him to traverse it in unique ways.For the Wii version the game concentrates on small groups of enemies that are more vicious and attack more frequently, creating an atmosphere more akin to the previous Prince of Persia games than the other version of The Forgotten Sands. While in combat, the Prince makes use of his blade with the Wii Remote and hands through the use of the Nunchuk. All of the other moves that the Prince uses for are controlled through the buttons. There are no elemental powers that the Prince can use for this version for the game. Instead the Prince uses an object called the "Sand Ring" which freezes enemies in their place for a limited amount of time.A brand new combat system has been designed, which is said to benefit from the Anvil engine's capability to show countless NPCs at once on the screen, displaying as many as 50 enemies at once on the screen.Various VersionsThe PS3, Xbox 360, and PC versions of the game were developed by Ubisoft Montreal and offer a traditional Prince of Persia experience, using the technology that powered the 2008 game and the Assassin's Creed series of games.The DS, PSP,and Wii versions of the game were Ubisoft Quebec City, and offer a "different experience from the more powerful systems." The Wii version of Prince of Persia: The Forgotten Sands includes the SNES version of Jordan Mechner's original Prince of Persia as a bonus feature.UplayUplay is a service where you earn points and use them to unlock bonus items. Here is a list of Actions (achievements) and Rewards for the PS3, Xbox 360 and PC versions of this game.ActionsPointsMemories of AzadReach the thick of the battle10USolomon's ArmyRelease Solomon's Army20UNot what it looks likeDefeat Ratash30UEye of the stormReach the final fight40URewardsCostPrince of Persia: TFS ThemeUnlock a Prince of Persia: TFS Theme10UExperience Point BoostUnlock enough additional experience for up to two new upgrades.20UEzio CostumePlay in Ezio's costume from Assassin's Creed II. Check the Extras menu to activate this costume.30UChallenge Mode ArenaUnlock a new arena in Challenge Mode.40UMarketingThe first trailer for the game debuted during the 2009 Spike VGAs, which showed The Prince narrowly escaping a building which was crumbling down and then facing a gigantic enemy that only consisted of sand.PC Version DRMUbisoft requires that all of their PC games need an "always-on" internet connection, as part of a new DRM and online services platform. All announced Ubisoft PC games will include the online services, whether sold online, or from brick and mortar stores.If you get disconnected while playing, you're booted out of the game. All your progress since the last checkpoint or save game is lost, and your only options are to quit to Windows or wait until you're reconnected. This happens even if the game loses its connection to Ubisoft's 'Master servers' on their end.SoundtracksWii soundtrack cover The soundtrack of the Xbox 360, PS3, and PC versions was composed by Steve Jablonsky with Penka Kouneva and released on July 5, 2010 by Ubisoft Music. The soundtrack of the Nintendo Wii, DS, and PSP versions was composed by Tom Salta and released on November 8, 2010.Prince of Persia: The Forgotten Sands - Original Game Soundtrack (Steve Jablonsky)No.Track TitleLength (45:33)1."Forgotten Sands" (Main Theme)2:312."The Prince Arrives"2:443."Storm the Fortress"1:104."Family Welcome"1:105."The Release of the Sand Army"3:556."The Army Barracks" (by Penka Kouneva)3:137."Give Me the Medallion"0:518."Treason"1:029."The Baths" (by Penka Kouneva)3:0110."Chase Through the Royal Chambers"2:0511."David and Goliath"0:3012."Climbing the Throne Room"1:0813."Fighting Ratash"1:0614."Malik Ends the Fight"0:5115."The Terrace"0:3016."The Sand Is Rising" (by Penka Kouneva)3:0617."Malik's Transformation"1:2518."A Losing Battle"2:0819."The Tower Breaks"0:4420."The City of Rekem" (by Penka Kouneva)3:0321."Enemies of The Djinn" (by Penka Kouneva)3:0322."The Demon In the Sand"0:5723."Through the Storm"1:3824."The Last Stand"1:3825."Final Words"1:46Prince of Persia: The Forgotten Sands - Original Wii Game Soundtrack (Tom Salta)No.Track TitleLength (70:20)1."Sacrifice" (Prince's Theme)2:242."The Stranded Castle"0:533."The Ancient Halls of Izdihar"2:104."Taking the High Road"1:275."Breaking the Seal" (Sorceress' Theme)2:186."Clear As A Sandstorm"1:377."Tortured Souls"1:468."Ambush in the Caves"1:169."Warriors of the Haoma"1:2010."Interlude I"0:4811."The Menagerie of Legends"1:5112."At the Palace's Gates"2:0713."The Peri" (Zahra's Theme)3:4114."Swarming"1:0415."Challenge of the Beasts"1:1716."Interlude II"0:4117."Water Bearer"1:0018."The Dead City"1:4619."Chase Through the Palace"1:1920."Roaring Fire, Lingering Smoke"2:0021."Augur of Malice"1:2322."Trapped"2:4823."Falling Apart"1:0924."Regret" (Nasreen's Theme)1:0025."Interlude III"0:5826."Harbinger of the Gods"2:3627."Lord of the Sea"1:5928."No End in Sight"1:1629."Dance of the Veil"1:2230."Mah's Void"1:2931."Sacred Ascent"4:0232."The Earth Mother"1:5633."Defying the Haoma"0:5334."Final Confrontation"4:4435."Loss" (Prince's Theme)0:5436."Credits"9:06</description><genres><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22928">Assassin's Creed II</game><game id="20461">God of War III</game><game id="20694">Tomb Raider: Underworld</game><game id="6959">God of War</game><game id="28080">Enslaved: Odyssey to the West</game><game id="29284">Tron: Evolution</game><game id="30636">Garshasp: The Monster Slayer</game><game id="37494">Assassin's Creed III</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/30036/1338516-princeofpersiatheforgottensandsgb.jpg</image></root>