<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2936</id><name>Neutopia</name><description>Overview Neutopia (Neutopia: Frey no Shou in Japan) is an Action-Adventure game released for the TurboGrafx-16\PC Engine, and was developed by Hudson Soft. Known as being a Zelda clone, set in the Fantasy world, the player takes control over Jazeta, the protagonist of the game, who is out to save Princess Aurora from an evil wizard Dirth, by finding the eight medallions.   It was later re-released on the Wii's Virtual Console on May 1, 2007 in Japan, August 20, 2007 in North America, and August 24, 2007 in Europe. During CES 2011 it was announced that the title would have a release on the PlayStation Network in February 2011. Story The evil king demon Dirth shoots down from the sky, and kidnaps Princess Aurora. A young boy is then called upon by an old lady who goes by 'Mother', and tells the young boy named Jazeta all of what has happened. The Mother then tells the young that the evil wizard Dirth was once sealed by the eight Medallions once coming together, and if he was to found the eight medallions, Jazeta could then seal the evil wizard, and save the Princess. Jazeta accepts, he then starts out on a huge adventure, where he must explore the entire world, travel through diverse lands, and battling through tough and treacherous labyrinths full of evil creatures. Jazeta will acquire many skills, as well as items throughout this vast land, and see the world in front of his own eyes, and face all fears to become a true man and a true hero. And once he has saved the princess, peace will then be restored to Earth. using the power of the eight Medallions.  Gameplay Neutopia is played from a flip-screen overhead view (similar to The Legend of Zelda), and is an action-adventure based game. You first off, take control of a young boy by the name of Jazeta, and travel around an overworld, you then walk around and explore shops or different areas of the map. You start the game out with a sword, and you can check your inventory and use items throughout the game, and as well, acquire keys items that will help you advance in your journey. During the game, you move through different areas, and battle enemies in each area, and collect health or magic when you kill them.   Throughout the game there will be labyrinths that you'll have to go through to progress further into the game, while entrances to labyrithns are visible, they later become hidden. Each area in the labyrinths provide you with puzzles to keep moving through. The puzzles will you to use your key items, and each item does something different and unique, such as the bow, bombs, and a boomerang to hit or kill certain enemies and objects throughout the game. Your characters health is represented in a bar, similar to The Legend of Zelda's hearts. Enemies in each area or dungeon are different and unique, requiring you to sometimes use one of your items to somehow defeat an enemy. Bosses are very similar to the Zelda series bosses, using puzzle techniques to have you kill the boss, and also involving the item you found in that dungeon.   Depending on enemies strengths, they will give more damage at a time, like bosses usually doing two bars in the earlier parts of the game, instead of a half of a bar. You can attack enemies with all of your items, and each weapon has its own way to do something harmful to the enemy. You will also have to avoid things like fireballs or spikes, as well as the many traps in different labyrinths that you will have go through during the game.  You will collect items through treasure chests, and they usually involve some sort of puzzle to get to. You can also go to shops and purchase either, weapons, shield, and even some type of magic, like health potions. You can buy things from the shop by using coins found by destroying objects, rocks, and enemies.  In Neutopia you will be traveling through five areas and twelve Labyrinths, and will being collecting medallions. You will talk to towns people throughout your adventure to collect information and clues on where you will have to go next. After every couple medallions, you will then unlock hidden stairs in the main hub, where you will be revisiting a lot to continue in your quest. As you go through labyrinths, each room has its own puzzles, in which can be hidden in anything, such as blocks, holes in the wall, or some type of pattern like moving objects in certain pattern.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11949">The Legend of Zelda</game><game id="10276">The Legend of Zelda: A Link to the Past</game><game id="12945">Lagoon</game><game id="2388">StarTropics</game><game id="8428">Arcus Odyssey</game><game id="27860">3D Dot Game Heroes</game><game id="19383">Legend of Xanadu II</game><game id="35064">The Legend of Zelda: A Link to the Past &amp; Four Swords</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2365555-tg16_neutopia.jpg</image></root>