<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29412</id><name>Stargate Resistance</name><description>OverviewStargate Resistance was an online team-based 3rd-person shooter that took place in the Stargate Universe, ten years after the events of SG-1On November 17 2010 , the developer, Cheyenne Mountain Entertainment notified their customers that:The licensing agreement between MGM and Cheyenne Mountain Entertainment expired on November 16 2010. As a result, Cheyenne Mountain Entertainment will not be able to offer Stargate Resistance for sale to new customers.The game servers were shut down on January 15th 2011, and it is no longer possible to buy, or play the game.FactionsS.G.C.Stargate Command (SGC) is the once top-secret military organization operated by the Air Force within the NORAD facility formed to manage the Stargate Program. Using the stargate, the SGC defends the earth from alien threats, seeks out new resources and technologies, and finds allies sympathetic to the human cause.Their successful campaign against the System Lords and other threats to Earth and humans throughout the galaxy has earned the SGC the respect and admiration of many races throughout the galaxy, as well as made them the primary target for the new emerging System Lords, eager to take back their empire from the upstart humans.Now governed by the International Oversight Advisory (IOA), the SGC has become an international peacekeeping and exploratory force, charged with defense of the Earth and Earth's interests throughout the galaxy. The SGC's primary task remains countering the System Lords' plans for domination, and defending humankind everywhere.SoldierSkilled with all weapons and proficient in adaptive tactics, the SGC soldier is the Swiss army knife of combat throughout the Galaxy. Need it opened, moved, pushed, pulled or dealt with, a soldier is often the first choice. Soldiers aren't as specialized as other classes, but they more than make up for it with the massive firepower of their P90s, smoke grenades, and grenade launchers.CommandoArmed with a deadly high caliber sniper rifle and .50 caliber handgun, the Commando is capable of putting down any foe with a minimum of effort. Claymore mines guard his back while he surveys the battlefield with high-tech vision enhancement that make even the invisible Ash’rak an easy target.ScientistWhile her skills might not initially be seen as expert in a battle, it turns out her mastery of physics, engineering, and biomechanical science gives her one of the broadest combat roles in the war.The scientist can set a massive .50 caliber automatic cannon anywhere she wishes, providing a lethal base of fire as defense or offense. She can also support her team with an automatic healing turret that restores the health of any ally within range. When pressed to fight, the scientist whips out her 9mm, or poisons the enemy with a deadly cloud of nanites specifically engineered to attack their symbiotes!System LordsThousands of years ago an alien parasite, known as the Goa’uld, using the stargate network, created by an even more powerful race of aliens, discovered humanity on a primitive Earth. Humanity offered this snake-like puppet-master a body that perfectly suited its needs, with highly-tuned sensory pleasures that sated their desire for experience and sensation. They enslaved humanity, populating much of the galaxy with this most desired host race, in small, primitive communities, worshipping them as Gods.Always warring amongst themselves, they formed a loose alliance of their most powerful members, known as the System Lords. This cabal ruled the galaxy unchallenged for thousands of years.In recent years, humanity has rediscovered the Stargate and its power. They were also reintroduced to the System Lords, who had long-since forgotten the birthplace of their favorite slaves. Through direct confrontation and clever use of the System Lords' distrust of one another, humanity defeated a number of these ancient beings and created a massive power vacuum within the Goa’uld society.A new generation of Goa’uld, minor players for thousands of years, have now risen to claim their rightful mantle. If they can crush their only resistance, Stargate Command, they will dominate the entire galaxy--beginning with Earth itself!JaffaArmed and armored to strike fear into the hearts of slaves and enemy warriors alike, the Jaffa attack their foes with a massive staff weapon capable of projecting a stream of pure energy that blasts anyone near the impact.With these fearsome weapons the Jaffa lay down massive covering fire for their advancing armies of invisible Ash’rak and shielded Goa’uld. The Jaffa are the primary line of assault and defense, dealing with Commandos, Soldiers, Scientists and their annoying turrets from a safe distance, and clearing the way for their master's assault.AshrakIt might seem strange bringing only a knife to war against guns, lasers, and bombs. But the Ash’rak is no fool. Her blade is instantly lethal to those foes foolish enough to show her their back. She moves silently, almost invisibly through the shadows, creeping up on her enemy before launching with a burst of inhuman speed to drive her blade deep between their shoulders and slay them in one fatal strike.Goa'uldThe Goa'uld are the self-proclaimed rulers of the galaxy.With a variety of devices such as the energy shield, which provides absolute protection from direct-fire weapons, who is to argue? With such an advantage the Goa’uld strides into battle, arrogantly assuming the humans will fall at their feet like so many little toys stepped on by a child.They are often correct. Able to fling enemies away with their Ribbon Device, or lock victims down to drain away their very life-force, the Goa’uld are a fearsome foe. They also can grant life-sustaining energy to their minions should they deign to grant such a blessing.WeaponsGrenade LaunchersSmoke GrenadesDesert EaglesProximity MinesSniper RiflesGun TurretsTok'KalsMa'Tok StaffsGo'Wye RibbonsA'Tak BladesThe Hara'KashAdditional weapons will be announced. More will also be available to unlock in the game through ranking up and gaining in game achievements.Game ModesTeam DeathmatchCapture the TechDominationSystem RequirementsMinimum System RequirementsWindows XP SP2 or Windows Vista2.0 GHZ Single Core Processor512 Mbytes of System RAMNVIDIA 6200 or ATI Radeon 9600 Video Card8 GB of Free Hard Drive SpaceBroadband connectionRecommended System Requirements2.4 GHZ Dual Core Processor1 GBytes of System RAMNVIDIA 7800GTX or ATI x1300 Video Card8 GB of Free Hard Drive Space</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="27757">Stargate SG-1: The Alliance</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/458/1212506-videogame_resistance01_wide.jpg</image></root>