<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29420</id><name>Dance Dance Revolution X2</name><description>OverviewDance Dance Dance Revolution X2 is the sequel to the 2008 arcade game Dance Dance Revolution X. Konami initially revealed the arcade version of the game on November 20, 2009. Konami began the public beta testing on November 25 thereafter. It was first released in Japan on July 7, 2010 and then the North American arcade version was released on December 31, 2010.New FeaturesA new menu interface has been improved. It is a cleaner and more refined version than the one seen in the original Dance Dance Revolution X.A new redesigned song selection interface.New adjustable versions of the Sudden and Hidden modifiers. DANCING!The new ability to adjust different settings and speed of the in-game arrows via control buttons on the arcade cabiet.New arcade cabinets are being introduced for North American arcades. Improvements include the reduction of input lag, and higher quality pads more similar to their Japanese counterparts.91 new songs to be played in X2.A new main menu mode called Replicant D-Action. This mode allows players to choose from a set of 6 difficult songs. When a player gets rank AA or more one of these songs, they receive a medal for that track. When players subsequently earn all 6 medals, they can access the Encore Extra Stage, Valkyrie dimension.SongsThe following songs are the 91 songs currently available in the North American and Japanese versions of DDR X2. They do not include the 7 extra songs featured in the Chinese version. Two songs ("I'm So Happy" and "Theory of Eternity") were unlocked later on via Konami's Append Festival in early 2011.SongArtistEverything We TouchCadcadaFeel Good Inc.GorillazBonafind Lovin'ChromeoIce Ice BabyVanilla IceDaft Punk Is Playing At My HouseLCD SoundsystemTime After TimeNovaspaceTenshiGouryellaSUPER EUROBEAT (Gold Mix)DAVE RODGERS feat. FUTURAETERNITYALEKYMore More MoreCapsuleOnly My RailgunfripSideHide-awayAAAEZ DO DANCETRFBe Your WingsGirl Next DoorSuper DriverAya HiranoResonanceNAOKI-EXCaptain Jack (GRANDALE REMIX)Captain JackDam DamiramJogaHEROPapayaIF YOU WERE HEREJENNIFERIF YOU WERE HERE (L.E.D-G STYLE REMIX)JENNIFERA Brighter DayNAOKI feat. AleishaShiningUnknownSomeday...UnknownHeatstrokeTAG feat. Angie LeeSacred OathTerraShineTOMOSUKE feat. AdreanaYou Are A StarNAOKI feat. Anna KaelinFreezenc feat. NRG FactoryGotta DanceNAOKI feat. Aleisha G.La RecetaCarlos Coco GarciaCrazy ControlD-Crew with VAL TIATIALa LibertadCheryyl HorrocksLove AgainNM feat. Mr. ETaking It To The SkyU1 feat. Tammy S. HansenTHIS NIGHTjun feat. SonnetWhat Will Come of MeBlack Rose GardenALL MY LOVEkors k feat. RIRECG ProjectLatenightersDecadekors k. vs. DJ TAKASky Is The LimitSota F. feat. ANNAWH1TE RO5EYCo.Poseidon (kors k mix)NAOKI UndegroundKISS KISS KISS mixDJ Command(Triangle)MAXDM AshuraOarfishkors kin luv wit youKotaro feat. Ayareal-high-SPEEDMokoto feat. SKaftershock!!DM AshuraDummyRAM888DJ TECHNORCHdirty digitalkors ksakura stormRyuYour AngelDM Ashura feat. kors kPluto the FirstWHITE WALLDazzlin' Darlin'HHHYELLOW CANDYRisk JunkSecond HeavenRyuShe is my wifeSUPER STAR -MITSURU-smoooochkors kBALLAD THE FEATHERSSHIN SOUND DESIGN feat. Naomi KoizumiFIRE FIREStripEDazzlin' Darlin' REMIXDJ CommandDROPdj TAKA feat. Kanako HoshinoGOLD RUSHDJ Yoshitaka feat. Michael a la ModeLeaving...SEIYA MURAI meets "eirmy"UnknownAmuro vs. KillerMAX LOVEDJ YoshitakaMelody LifeNoriaVANESSAUnknowngoing upcolorsZETAZektbachKIMONO PRINCESSjunroppongi EVOLVEDTAG UndergroundI'm So HappyRyuTheory of EternityTAGPierce the SkyJAKAZID feat K.N.Sakura SunriseRyuShiny WorldCAPACITY GATEPOSSESSIONTAG UndegroundNew DecadeSota F.Anti-MatterOrbit1  MiloValkryie dimensionSprigganLOVEdj TAKABREAK DOWN!BeForUCANDYUnkownFreedomBeForUGRADUATIONBeForUUnknownRIYU from BeForULOVE SHINEUnknownTEARSNAOKI underground feat. EKUnder the Sky(BeForU) with platoniX</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="27859">Just Dance</game><game id="31705">Dance Central</game><game id="31724">Michael Jackson: The Experience</game><game id="36371">DJMAX Technika 3: Crew Challenge</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2280577-box_ddrx2.png</image></root>