<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29429</id><name>New Mobile Report Gundam Wing: Endless Duel</name><description>Backstory  Based on the alternate After Colony timeline differing from most Gundam anime, the series follows the exploits of five gundam pilots originally sent to earth as part of the rebel mission Operation Meteor, who eventually play a decisive role in ending the conflict between Earth and its Colonies.  Story Mode  Loosely following the anime, story mode follows the pilot of your choice as he/she battles through progressively more difficult stages against other mobile suits as they chronologically appear in the anime.  Gameplay Borrowing from the Street Fighter Alpha series, dashing, air blocking, air dashing, combos, and juggling are all available. Unique features include double air dashing, or a "vernier", a move which makes your mech float downward temporarily,after an air dash by holding down, or forward, or back. It is also possible to attack an opponent while they are on the ground, a rare feature in 2D fighters. Juggling is more or less limitless and this, combined with extensive air dashing, allows for extensive air combos. Generally among the more aerial combat based fighters ever made, it has a very high playing field, extending about one and a half screens high.Vulcans are another unique means of attack. Used by every mech other than Epyon, they do very little damage but can be done by tapping a punch button at range. The game also has a power meter, which is depleted by supers or level two specials. Level one specials are performed with Y and B. Level two specials are performed with A and X. A level two special with deplete 100 points from your power meter and a super will deplete 200 points from your power meter. Your meter can be replenished my blocking hits, or executing specials or supers, or landing hits against your opponent or having your attacks blocked.   Characters/Mechs                     Heero Yuy                   Wing Gundam  XXXG-01W - Gundam WIng                  Wing Gundam Zero          Trowa Barton                  Gundam HeavyarmsWing Gundam (When playing story mode with Heero Yuy)             Duo Maxwell            Gundam Deathscythe      Quatre Raberba Winner       Gundam Sandrock         Chang Wufei        Gundam Shenlong              Zechs Marquise/                Milliardo Peacecraft                Mobile Suit Tallgeese  Gundam Epyon     Lady Une    Mobile Suit Vayeate   Lucrezia NoinMobile Suit Mercurius    OZ-13MS - Gundam Epyon </description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11585">Mighty Morphin Power Rangers: The Fighting Edition</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/30526/1214398-new_mobile_report_gundam_wing___endless_duel_coverart.png</image></root>