<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29439</id><name>Green Day: Rock Band</name><description>OverviewGreen Day: Rock Band is the follow-up to 2009's band-specific title The Beatles: Rock Band, and chronicles much of Green Day's career. The game was released on June 8, 2010 in North America, Europe, Australia, and New Zealand. It was officially announced on December 12, 2009, when the first trailer premiered at the 2009 Spike TV Video Game Awards. Band members Billie Joe Armstrong, Mike Dirnt, and Tre Cool are all featured alongside 47 songs from the punk-rock group's discography, three unique venues, and plenty of assorted extras, including interviews and live performances from the band members.The core gameplay is markedly similar to the rest of the Rock Band franchise.Pricing and PromotionsStand-alone game (360/PS3): $59.99 USDStand-alone game (Wii): $49.99 USDGreen Day: Rock Band Plus (360/PS3): $69.99Green Day: Rock Band Plus features special packaging and a free export of all songs to Rock Band, Rock Band 2, and Rock Band 3, and is priced at $69.99 USD. For the Xbox 360 and PS3 stand-alone games, all 47 songs can be exported to Rock Band, Rock Band 2, LEGO Rock Band, and Rock Band 3 for $9.99 USD. The songs are not exportable on the Wii.GameStop customers who pre-ordered the regular edition of the game received a free export code. This offer did not apply to the Plus version, as the bonus is already included in the package.FeaturesGreen Day: Rock Band features the following:The game features likenesses of Billie Joe Armstrong, Tre Cool, and Mike Dirnt.The likenesses match each era of the band's career from early 90's era at The Warehouse to American Idiot era at Milton Keynes and finally current day (21st Century Breakdown) at The Fox Theater.Three-part vocal harmonies, first featured in The Beatles: Rock Band, are used.Venues and art can be selected from key moments in the band's history, such as the gig they performed at Milton Keynes, England for their live album and DVD "Bullet in a Bible", The Fox Theater in Oakland, CA, and a fictional venue The Warehouse, which is supposed to represent places where Green Day used to jam at before making it big.Players are able to unlock over 100 images and 40 minutes of videos featuring outtakes, interviews, and live performances.All 47 songs are fully exportable ($9.99 PS3/ 800 MS points) to the PS3 and Xbox 360 versions of Rock Band, Rock Band 2, LEGO Rock Band, and Rock Band 3.TracklistGreen Day: Rock Band features 47 tracks (44 if you note that 3 songs are two-in-one songs) from throughout the band's career. Entertainment Weekly was the first to reveal the entire setlist. It primarily consists of the entire Dookie and American Idiot albums, as well as the remaining songs from 21st Century Breakdown that have not already been released as DLC for the Rock Band platform. There are a few other songs from Insomniac, Nimrod, and Warning as well.Dookie (1994)Venue: The Warehouse"Basket Case""Burnout""Chump""Coming Clean""Emenius Sleepus""F.O.D.""Having A Blast""In The End""Longview""Pulling Teeth""Sassafras Roots""She""Welcome To Paradise""When I Come Around"Insomniac (1995)Venue: Milton Keynes"Brain Stew"**"Jaded"**"Geek Stink Breath"Nimrod (1997)Venue: Milton Keynes"Good Riddance (Time of Your Life)" -"Hitchin' A Ride""Nice Guys Finish Last"Warning (2000)Venue: Milton Keynes"Minority""Warning"American Idiot (2004)Venue: Milton Keynes"Are We the Waiting"*"American Idiot""Boulevard of Broken Dreams""Extraordinary Girl""Give Me Novocaine"**"Holiday""Homecoming""Jesus of Suburbia""Letterbomb""She's a Rebel"**"St. Jimmy"*"Wake Me Up When September Ends""Whatsername"21st Century Breakdown (2009)Venue: The Fox Theater in Oakland"21st Century Breakdown""American Eulogy""Before the Lobotomy""Horseshoes and Handgrenades""Last Night On Earth""Murder City""Peacemaker""Restless Heart Syndrome""See The Light""Song of the Century" -"The Static Age"" ¿ Viva La Gloria? (Little Girl)"Importable DLC TracksSix songs from 21st Century Breakdown are currently available as DLC for Rock Band and Rock Band 2. They will be automatically imported into Green Day: Rock Band and will include vocal harmonies, unique performance videos, and exclusive archival material. These songs are also available by purchasing the Plus edition of Green Day: Rock Band.21st Century Breakdown (2009)"21 Guns""Christian's Inferno""East Jesus Nowhere""Know Your Enemy""Last Of The American Girls""¡Viva La Gloria!"** It should be noted that "Brain Stew"  "Jaded" are one song in Green Day: Rock Band. "Give Me Novocaine"  "She's a Rebel" are also one song and "Are We the Waiting"  "St. Jimmy" are grouped together as well.- It should also be noted that "Good Riddance (Time of Your Life)" has no drum part and "Song of the Century" has no guitar, bass, or drums.</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25536">Guitar Hero: Van Halen</game><game id="22562">Guitar Hero: Metallica</game><game id="30339">Lips: I Love the 80's</game><game id="32905">Singstar Guitar</game><game id="34528">Green Day Revenge</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/39162/1297180-500x_rockband_01.jpeg</image></root>