<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29438</id><name>Star Wars: The Force Unleashed II</name><description>OverviewThe Force Unleashed II maintains the                                                           hack and slash inspired gameplay of The Force Unleashed, while layering on several new                                                         Force abilities and the chance to                                                          dual-wield                                                        lightsabers. Most of the cast from the first game returns as well, with                                                             Starkiller once again taking up the role of                                                       protagonist.    StoryThe game takes place six months after the first                                                      Force Unleashed. Despite having died in the canonical ending to the first game, Starkiller returns as a genetically altered                                                    clone, created by                                                     Darth Vader in an attempt to preserve his Padawan's abilities. The story spans many planets and old characters from the                                                   Star Wars saga appear. The voice cast from the first game reprise their roles and the game's main theme is the same while certain scores from the Star Wars Movies also appear.  The story begins in classic Star Wars fashion: text scroll while the iconic Star Wars theme plays. Once again, the galaxy is on the brink of                                                  civil war. The                                                 rebels have been attacking the                                                Empire for 6 months now. However, they have suffered a severe blow:                                               General Rahm Kota has been captured by the Empire and the rebels have been forced to flee to the                                              Outer Rim of the galaxy. Once the text has ended, the camera pans down to reveal the planet of                                             Kamino. Darth Vader's                                            Tie-Advance is seen entering the orbit of the planet. Vader lands on a                                           platform over the rough seas of the rainy planet and makes his way to a dark room. He looks into a prison pit where one of Starkiller's clone can be seen. Vader is still trying to overthrow                                          the Emperor by way of a super powerful apprentice. Despite Starkiller dying at the end of the first game, Vader has continued looking for the perfect apprentice by creating clones of Starkiller.  The clone has been imprisoned for 13 days. Vader makes it clear that the clone was created for only one purpose: to serve him. All the other clones have gone                                         mad because they were haunted of visions from Starkillers life. The clone, to prove his worth to Vader, must pass the ultimate test. Once he has passed this test, his first mission will be to execute Kota who's being held on the planet Cato-Neimoidia.                                        Proxy                                         The Clone Makes His Escape                                       droids appear and one replicates the look of                                       Juno Eclipse, Starkiller's former                                      love interest. Each time the clone goes to strike her, he is unable and is                                     tortured by violent visions. Vader explains that he must learn to hate what he loved and that this clone, like the others, is of no use to him. Refusing to share the same fate as his brothers, the clone force zaps Vader, makes a giant hole in the building he was in and escapes. After                                    skydiving for a bit and killing all the Imperial troops on the planet, the clone has the idea to steal Vader's                                   Tie Fighter. Vader almost stops him but the clone gets away.  The clone makes his way to the planet Cato-Neimoidia. Kota is being held by the Baron. The blind Jedi is the planet's main attraction as he fights in                                  the stadium defeating the most dangerous creatures. The stadium where he fights is situated in the sky city of Tarko-Se and Kota has been fighting for seven straight days. The clone passes himself as Vader which lets him land with ease on the planet. But when the Baron discovers that Vader, it is not, and that the clone is here for Kota, he flees and sends all kinds of bad guys after him. After slogging through waves after waves of troopers and killing a gigantic                                 helicopter, the clone finally makes it to the stadium. He reunites with Kota who expresses joy, thinking that the clone is in fact Starkiller. The reunion is cut short when the baron unleashes his most powerful creature: the Gorog. This towering beast is so huge, that the only solution for defeating it is to "sink" the city (make it fall through the clouds). Starkiller and Kota separate and begin to make the city fall and they reunite in the Baron's lodge. The Baron is about to get the upper hand on Kota when the city begins to fall and the Gorog latches on to the lodge, eating the Baron and taking Kota in his fall. The clone skydives to save Kota and finishes off the Gorog. As the two Jedi                                freefall, Kota orders his ship, the                               Rogue Shadow and the two are saved.  Kota is rejoiced to meet his old friend. The clone claims that he is not Starkiller but a clone. Kota claims that this is impossible as you can not clone                              Jedi. The clone doesn't know what to think and needs to                             meditate on a far off planet. Kota scolds him, telling him that it is time to strike  Dagobahat the Empire. When the clone asks the old Jedi where Juno is, Kota replies that he does not know. The clone heads for the planet of                            Dagobah. There he finds                           Yoda, who speaks in                          riddles telling him to enter the                         cave of mysteries to seek what he wants. The clone enters and is welcomed by other versions of himself, dying. He finds Juno and has a vision of the future. He sees Juno getting shot and captured. The clone rushes back to the ship to announce this to Kota who decides that they should head to the Outer Rim to meet Juno who is now an officer in the                        rebellion. At the same time, the game shows Vader hiring                       Boba Fett to capture Juno and bring her back to Kamino. Vader knows that this will lead the clone to him.    Kota and the clone arrive at a flock of rebel ships. They head to The Salvation, where Juno is stationed. Upon arriving however, the ship becomes under attack by Imperial forces and terror droids. The clone tries to get to Juno but he fails and she is kidnapped by Fett. Kota decides that the Rebel Alliance must strike against the Empire and the clone gives Kota the plans to the Imperial cloning facility on Kamino. Upon arriving into the planet's orbit, the Empire ambush the rebels and the planet's shields make it impossible to land on the planet. The Rebels are about to be forced to retreat when the clone has the ingenious idea to crash the serenity into the cloning plant. The Serenity is evacuated and the clone crashes it into the facility, allowing the rebels to raid it.  The clone helps Kota and the others attack the cloning facility but he warns Kota that he's here for Juno. Despite Kota not wanting the clone to go on alone, the clone does it anyways. After climbing the facility's spire, the clone begins having increasingly violent visions and is ambushed by Vader (this scene is a major call back to the Empire Strikes Back). Vader fights the clone, telling him he's expendable and that he's going to kill him "a thousand times". After a fairly long fight, Vader flees and the clone gives chase. He finds Vader with Juno. Vader tells him to lay down his lightsabers and become his                      slave if he wants Juno to live. The clone does what he's told; drops his sabers and kneels in front of Vader. Juno grabs one of the lightsabers and attempts to stab Vader who evades and force pushes Juno out the window and onto a platform,  Kaminoapparently killing her. This sends the clone into a furious rage and after yet another battle the clone defeats Vader by cutting off his right hand and zapping him until his voice box starts going haywire. The clone holds Vader at his mercy, Vader who tells him that the clone is but an empty shell and that                     love means nothing. Kota arrives and tells the clone that perhaps killing Vader is not a good idea since the clone will never know the truth about his past. Kota wants to take Vader as a prisoner, judge him, then execute him. At this point, the player is given a choice to either kill Vader (    Dark Side) or let him be taken as prisoner (Light Side).   Light Side Ending The clone decides to let Vader be taken prisoner. He rushes to Juno's body and embraces it. Suddenly, it's revealed that Juno is in fact alive and the two share a                   kiss.                  Princess Leia arrives and Vader is boarded onto the Rogue Shadow. The clone visits Vader who answers none of his questions. When he says that he's finally free, Vader replies that he'll never be free as long as Juno is alive. The Rogue Shadow enters light-speed while a concealed a                 Slave I sneakily follows them (another reference to Empire Strikes Back).   Dark Side Ending The clone is about to execute Vader when suddenly a lightsaber sticks out of his chest. A hooded                Sith appears from behind the clone, who falls to the ground. The Sith frees Vador and force pushes Kota and the rest of the rebels to their               deaths into the stormy water of Kamino. As the clone lives his final moments, Vader explains to him that he wasn't the most perfect clone after all. The Sith removes his hood and is revealed to be a clone. The good clone dies while the Sith goes to hunt the last of the              Rebel Alliance. He passes in front of Juno's lifeless body, barely giving it a glimpse, making him the perfect clone. GameplayFor the first time, Starkiller can dual wield lightsabers, which changes the game's fighting style and combos completely. The game will have more             ranged attacks with the return of the game's trademark over the top force powers. Old powers return, like force grip. The camera work and            targeting around force grip has been reworked. For example, you can now grab a Tie Fighter, crush it into a ball and throw it. One of the new force powers is the iconic Jedi mind trick. When you first get this power, you can turn enemies into allies but once you upgrade it, the enemies will throw themselves off cliffs and even turn into smart bombs, running into a group of enemies and blowing up. There are different types of enemies in the game.           Stormtroopers are at the bottom of the food chain while riot troopers who can block your lightsaber attacks and          jet pack wearing stormtroopers represent a challenge for Starkiller. The clone also fights larger foes like the         Carbonite War Droid who has a carbonite gun and a big        shield that Starkiller must first remove before being able to inflict damage. The game also varies its gameplay with for example a free fall sequences where Starkiller takes out Tie Fighters and avoids       debris. Collector's Edition A collector's edition of the Force Unleashed II was announced on June 8, 2010 by      LucasArts. The collector's edition will be released on October 26, 2010 for the     Xbox 360 and the    Playstation 3 for $79.99 USD with the regular edition of the game.  *below is a list of what items are included in the collector's edition*  Collectible Steelbook Exclusive In-Game Content Three exclusive challenge mode levels Exclusive                                                             Ralph McQuarrie "                                                             Original Starkiller" skin Exclusive Lightsaber crystal Starkiller 2GB Flash Drive designed by Mimobot Digital Art Book  Pre-Order Maul KillerA Pre-Order bonus is also available from GameStop. It was announced on July 21, 2010. It will contain a Sith Lord who is a mixture of   Darth Maul and Starkiller. This character contains a silver lightsaber  crystal to go with the costume. Maulkiller's description is said to be created from the test-tubes of Kamino (the facility that created the Clone Army).     PC System RequirementsMinimum specs   Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo 2.4 GHz or AMD Athlon X2 5200   Memory: 2 GB RAM  Video: 256 MB Video Memory with Shader 3.0 support - ATI Radeon HD 2600 / NVIDIA GeForce 8600 GT  Hard disk space: 10GB 1GB Swapfile  Operating system: Windows XP SP3, Windows Vista SP2, or Windows 7  Sound: 100% DirectX 9.0c compatible Audio Device  DirectX: DirectX 9.0c (March 2009)Recommended specs   Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo 2.8 GHz or AMD Athlon X2 6000   Video: 256 MB Video Memory with Shader 3.0 support - ATI Radeon HD 4800 / NVIDIA GeForce GTX 260</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6959">God of War</game><game id="20461">God of War III</game><game id="11314">God of War II</game><game id="24827">Dante's Inferno</game><game id="823">Legacy of Kain: Defiance</game><game id="32687">Ninja Gaiden 3</game><game id="21876">Ninja Gaiden</game><game id="39749">Ninja Gaiden 3: Razor's Edge</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5150/1424521-fu2.jpg</image></root>