<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29463</id><name>Alliance of Valiant Arms</name><description>Alliance of Valiant Arms is a free to play fps for PC that uses the Unreal 3 engine. It takes place during a fictional now/future war between the European Union (EU) and the Neo Russia Federation (NRF). Originally developed in Korea, it was brought to a North American audience by NHN America, or ijji. It uses a class based system and features many different team-based modes. Player characters gain experience and money (euros in-game) to develop special class skills and acquire more powerful weapons and equipment.GameplayThe game plays similarly to the popular FPS Counter-Strike: Source. Before entering a game, players are allowed to purchase and equip armor, stat boosting items, and weapons which they pay for with the game's currency. Said currency is gained by playing the game, more being given for the better you do.The game's teams are split between the two armies, the EU and the NRF, though neither team has any advantage over the other as they have access to all the same equipment and weapons. The only difference between the two is the look of their soldiers.The game includes a large variety of weapons, with more being added every update. It includes SMGs, Shotguns, Assault Rifles, Machine Guns, Grenades, Pistols, and Sniper Rifles.ClassesThe game has three classes:Point ManThe 'scout' class, this class uses its speed and maneuverability to its advantage. Using SMGs and Shotguns, this class is always on the move and is the fastest class in the game. Its special abilities including leveling up moving speed, knife damage and range, negated fall damage, and increased SMG reload speeds and ammo counts. It is the only class in the game that can add silencers to their main weapon.RiflemanThe rifleman is the most balanced class, being efficient at all ranges and in all combat situations. Using Assault Rifles, this class can be found at the front of any battle and is able to take the most hits out of all the classes. Its special abilities include increased armor and critical-hit defense, grenade throwing range, sighted-accuracy, and increased AR reload speeds and ammo counts.SniperThe long range weapons specialist, this class is at its strongest hidden away at the back lines or in hidden positions picking off enemies from long range. Using both bolt action and semi-automatic rifles, this class has access to the strongest weapons in the game. Its special abilities include increased scoped accuracy, increased on-the-move accuracy, increased movement speed while using sniper rifles, better pistol use, and increased SR reload speeds and ammo counts.Game ModesThe game includes several different competitive and co-operative game modes, with more added every now and then. These modes are:DemolitionA common game mode in military FPS, one team must defend two bomb sites while the other team must plant a bomb at one of the bombsites, and defend said bomb till it goes off. In this mode there is no respawning.ConvoyOne team must take a package to an extraction point on the other side of the map. There is no respawning in this mode.AnnihilationStandard team-deathmatch. Dead players drop dog tags that you can pick up for extra points.EscortOne team must escort a tank to the end of the map within the set time limit. The attacking team must take RPGs from weapon lockers and fire them at the tank to disable it. When disabled, the defending team must repair the tank to get it moving again. Throughout the map the tank will cross checkpoints which pushes the respawn location for the defenders forward and the attackers back. When the defenders reach the end of the map, the teams switch sides and the new defenders must get their tank to the end of the map within the amount of time it took the original defenders to win. If the original defenders did not get their tank to the end of the map, then when teams switch the new defenders only need to get their tank to the location the original defenders did before the time limit.Free for AllStandard FFA deathmatch.RiotThe game's co-op mode. It has two sub-modes. Four players are put into a prison in which they must survive against hordes of AI 'prisoners' (they seem a lot like zombies to me). One of the sub modes is simply to survive as long as you can. As time goes on more and stronger waves of prisoners spawn. The other is escape. This mode is similar to Left4Dead in that the team of four players must go from one side of the map to the exit, but with some large differences. Escape is split into four parts, with each part requiring the players to do different tasks. In each part, the players are given 3 lives. If all 3 lives for all four players are used up, they lose and must start over.PC System RequirementsCPU: Pentium 4 2.4GHzRAM: 1GBVGA: NVidia GeForce 6600 or betterDX: 9.0COS: Windows XP, Vista, Windows 7HDD: 6GBNetwork: Internet Connection required</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="24713">Modern Warfare 2</game><game id="2133">Call of Duty 4: Modern Warfare</game><game id="21646">Battlefield 2: Modern Combat</game><game id="20655">Battlefield: Bad Company</game><game id="12716">Battlefield 1942</game><game id="21591">Combat Arms</game><game id="22609">Soldier Front</game><game id="20989">CrimeCraft</game><game id="11663">Half-Life: Counter-Strike</game><game id="11339">Counter-Strike: Source</game><game id="40582">Mission Against Terror</game><game id="40583">Operation 7</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/29873/1363936-ava.jpg</image></root>