<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29485</id><name>MLB 10: The Show</name><description>Overview MLB 10: The Show is produced by Sony and officially  licensed by the MLB.  The cover athlete for this year's game is Minnesota Twins catcher Joe  Mauer.New FeaturesRoad to the Show 4.0     This  year's installment of MLB: The Show upgrades the popular Road to The  Show mode. The first thing players will notice when starting a RTTS  (Road to The Show) career is the player creation has improved. Now you  can find even more options for players who want to truly customize their  on field superstars. The drill system has also been improved. Now  players can find specific drills for catchers and pitchers in the  practice modes and improve their skills with their respective players  even more. The progression of the mode has also been tweaked. Instead of  players starting out playing spring training against MLB players, they  will start out directly in the Double A season and work up to an invite  to Spring Training. These enhancements will make it easier for new  players to get into the game, and veterans will have time to hone their  skills before starting the season.  Catcher ModeIn Road to the Show mode, an enhanced catcher position is available to play.  The new catcher mode allows players to choose the pitches and their locations behind the mound.  In this mode, the player has a first-person perspective behind the mound, immersing the player into the catcher position.  Playing as the catcher allows players to further manage the game by picking off base runners and fielding the ball.  As the catcher, calling a quality start or picking off base runners will reward the player with experience points.  Being able to play as a catcher and perform all of the duties of a catcher greatly enhances the realism of this game.  Classic Stadiums Given out as a pre-order bonus was a code for a Classic Stadium pack that included Crosley Field, Forbes Field, Griffith Stadium, Polo Grounds, Shibe Park, and Sportsman's Park.  These stadiums could be later purchased as downloadable content from the Playstation Store.Other New Modes and FeaturesOther  new modes for the game help enhance the experience even more. Players can now play the Home Run Derby as a standalone mode or as  part of the All Star BreakNew StadiumsNew gameplay and presentation animationsCustomize the fan chants and game audioFull online league supportNew movie maker feature to allow more diverse editing of replays  and clipsOnline game historyNew camera systemMore details in visuals  Team Rankings All 30 MLB teams are ranked in-game on 4 separate categories: Overall, Batting, Pitching, Defense.    Overall RankingBatting RankingPitching RankingDefense Ranking 1. New York YankeesYankeesYankeesRed Sox 2. Boston Red SoxRed SoxDodgers Mets  3. Philadelphia PhilliesPhilliesRed SoxMariners  4. Los Angeles DodgersRangers Braves Dodgers  5. Tampa Bay RaysRays Diamondbacks Phillies  6. Atlanta BravesRockies White SoxYankees 7. Anaheim AngelsAngelsPhilliesWhite Sox  8. Colorado RockiesCubsAthletics Rays  9.Chicago CubsBraves Cubs Astros  10. Texas RangersDodgersAngels Blue Jays  11. Arizona DiamondbacksTwins Twins Rangers  12. Minnesota TwinsBlue Jays Rays Orioles  13. Chicago White SoxDiamondbacks Giants Cardinals  14. San Fransisco GiantsOrioles Tigers Tigers 15. Toronto Blue JaysMets Cardinals Royals  16. St. Louis CardinalsGiants Rockies Angels  17. New York MetsReds Brewers Athletics  18. Milwaukee Brewers White Sox Padres Nationals   19. Cincinnati RedsBrewers Mariners Reds  20. Baltimore Orioles Cardinals RoyalsPirates  21. Seattle MarinersMarlins Reds Giants  22. Houston AstrosMariners Mets Braves  23. Oakland AthleticsNationals Rangers Twins  24. Detroit TigersAstros Astros Rockies  25. San Diego PadresPirates  Blue JaysIndians  26. Florida MarlinsPadresNationals Cubs  27. Kansas City RoyalsRoyals Pirates Diamondbacks  28. Washington NationalsIndians IndiansBrewers 29. Pittsburgh PiratesTigers OriolesMarlins  30. Cleveland IndiansAthleticsMarlins Padres Soundtrack          Band of Skulls – “I Know What I Am” Baroness – “Swollen and Halo” The Grouch  Eligh – “All In (Feat. Gift of Gab  Pigeon John)” Night Horse – “Come Down Halo” Scarlet Symphony – “Your Blood Is Mine” Silversun Pickups – “It’s Nice to Know You Work Alone” The Budos Band – “The Proposition” The Heavy – “How You Like Me Now (Beats Mix)” The New Regime – “Haunt My Mind” The Soundtrack of Our Lives – “Babel On” We Are Scientists – “Rules” Zodiac Death Valley – “Look Alive!”    </description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="34">Baseball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21255">Major League Baseball 2K7</game><game id="20876">Major League Baseball 2K8</game><game id="24440">Major League Baseball 2K9</game><game id="22546">Major League Baseball 2K6</game><game id="5892">ESPN Major League Baseball</game><game id="21254">Major League Baseball 2K5</game><game id="29990">Major League Baseball 2K10</game><game id="21259">MVP 06 NCAA Baseball</game><game id="23470">Home Run King</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1832925-box_mlb10.png</image></root>