<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29536</id><name>Dark Void Zero</name><description>Dark Void Zero's Faux-retro Legacy     Also has elements of the simulation genre.   In 19XX the "original"  Dark Void was to be one of the first games to be made for the "               Playchoice-10" a dual screen                    arcade machine by                               Capcom.  However, the Playchoice-10 project was discontinued and thus the game never saw the light of day.  In the year 20XX, Capcom stumbled upon the project in their vault and were inspired to make    Dark Void (2010) for the                           PlayStation 3,                          Xbox 360 and                         PC, and re-released the original Playchoice-10 Dark Void under the name "Dark Void Zero" on                        Nintendo's                       DSiWare service,  PC via   Steam and iPhone/iPod Touch.    StorySimilar to the story in Dark Void, an alien race called the Watchers are stuck in a limbo zone between their world and Earth. Called "The Void," many unstable portals have been the only way in or out in the past, however there is one portal, called "Portal X," that the Watchers have stabilized. So far, human survivors trapped in The Void have been unable to destroy it. In Dark Void Zero, the player controls a test pilot named Rusty. Guided by Nikola Tesla, Rusty must travel to three Watcher compounds, collecting the three "portal control codes" that will allow the destruction of Portal X. GameplayInitially, Rusty can only walk, jump, and shoot in eight directions. If he finds a jetpack, he gains the ability to hover by double-tapping the jump button, and to fly straight up by jumping, pressing the jump button again and holding it.   Rusty will encounter many kinds of enemies on his mission to destroy Portal X, including turrets, patrolling soldiers, and mines. Many enemies later in the game may be similar to their early-game counterparts, but may shoot missiles instead of bullets, or have better armor. Additionally, new enemies are continually added into the mix. At the end of each level, Rusty will encounter a Watcher in a armored ship called a Dark Guardian. Each time Rusty faces-off against the Dark Guardian, the guardian gains new abilities, such as shooting homing bombs. Additional "stages" are also added to the guardian fight. For example, the Mark II guardian gains a weapon that is able to shoot Teleforce Lance-like lasers in multiple directions.Weapons, Powerups, and Items Scattered around the world are weapons, power-ups, and items that Rusty can use to fight the Watchers. NameDescriptionLiberator    Blue. The starting weapon. Can shoot rapidly, but has low damage.DisintegratorGreen. Slow rate of fire, short range, but high damage.PulverizorOrange. Rocket Launcher. Slow rate of fire, but high damage. Can destroy weak walls. Teleforce LancePink. Slow rate of fire, but can shoot through walls and enemies.HypercoilPurple. Very high rate of fire and high damage, but can over-heat with continuous use.JetpackAllows Rusty to hover and fly.1upAn extra life.2x ShotsDoubles Rusty's rate of fire.3x ShotsShoots two additional shots at 45 degree angles above and below the regular shot.EM PulseDeals damage within a short radius of Rusty when he fires.Force FieldProtects Rusty from enemy fire and collisions, but not lava or radioactive goo.Electrified FieldLike the Force Field, but in addition to protecting Rusty, it deals damage to enemies that it touches.Blue KeyAllows Rusty to pass through a specific locked door.Portal Control CodeOne of the three items Rusty needs to shut down Portal X. Collectibles In each facility are five collectibles that Rusty can collect (or destroy as the case may be) to fulfill a side-mission for extra points. NameDescription Journals Details a lost patrol, led by Jimmy Fallon. Watcher Scientists Ugly green guys in lab coats. Kill them with fire (or bullets)!! Watcher Incubators Pink-purple vats containing Watcher slugs.    PC Version System RequirementsOS: Windows® XP (SP2 or higher) / Windows  Vista  / Windows 7 Processor: 2.5 GHz Pentium 4 / 1.6GHz  Core2Duo or higher Memory: XP: 512 MB minimum, 1 GB  recommended; Windows Vista / Windows 7: 1 GB minimum, 2 GB recommendedGraphics: DirectX 9.0c compatible video  card with 256 MBDisplay: 800x600 minimum resolution,  1280x720 or higher recommendedDirectX®: Direct X 9.0cHard Drive: 200 MB available disk space  requiredSound: DirectX®9.0c compatibleInput: Windows-compliant keyboard. Gamepads with analogue  sticks may also work, though are not officially supported.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="28508">Matt Hazard: Blood Bath And Beyond</game><game id="20269">Solar Jetman: Hunt for the Golden Warpship</game><game id="20483">Bionic Commando Rearmed</game><game id="20975">Mega Man 9</game><game id="29413">Mega Man 10</game><game id="30945">Bionic Commando Rearmed 2</game><game id="38866">Oniken</game><game id="37207">Mutant Mudds</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/26/1226534-dvz_box.jpg</image></root>