<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29601</id><name>Nuclear Dawn</name><description>OverviewNuclear Dawn is a multiplayer-only game that combines real-time strategy and first-person shooter elements. Players are placed in one of two teams- either Empire or Consortium- and spawn on either ends of a map from where they can capture points that reward resources. One player is voted to be the commander and views the map from the top-down perspective, allowing him to place power grids, resource points turrets and perform other exclusive actions that are afforded to him by how many resources his team has been rewarded. The rest of the team plays from the first-person perspective, and chooses from various classes and kits to capture points and eliminate enemies. The ultimate goal of a match is to destroy your enemy's base.ClassesBoth the Consortium and the Empire use the same classes, though they are differentiated by team colors, aesthetics, and weapon names. Each of the four classes use three kits, with one kit for each class being unlocked only through spending resources. In addition to kits, players can choose 'gizmos' that have various effects. Effects include- but are not limited to- higher bullet damage, higher ammo capacity, etc.AssaultThe Assault class is a versatile medium armored soldier whose special ability is their Thermal Vision which allows them to spot cloaked enemies. The three kits for the soldier are Infantry, Grenadier and Marksman.Infantry KitFN-H F2100 TR Assault rifle (Consortium)/ C1 Avenger Assault rifle (Empire)BAG-90 pistolM-87 Fragmentation GrenadesThermal VisionGrenadier KitM52 Hydra grenade launcherSPETZ-9 ShotgunBAG-90 pistolM-87 Fragmentation GrenadesThermal VisionMarksman KitPaladin PLR-5 Sniper rifle (Consortium)/ PSG-L Sniper rifle (Empire)BAG-90 pistolDaisycutter anti-personnel MineThermal VisionExoThe Exo is a slow moving, heavily armed class whose main special ability is the Suit Lockdown. The Suit Lockdown lets the Exo sacrifice all mobility for improved accuracy. The two kits for the Exo are Suppression and SiegeSuppression KitGAU-20p ChaingunBAG-90 pistolSuit LockdownSiege KItM95 L.A.W.S (Consortium)/ X01 Railgun (Empire)BAG-90 pistolSuit LockdownStealthThe Stealth is the fastest moving, lightest armored class whose special ability is cloaking, allowing themselves invisibility. The three kits for the Stealth are Assassin, Sniper, and Saboteur.Assassin KitMP-500 Sub machine gun (Consortium)/ SP-5 K1 Sub machine gun (Empire)BAG-90 pistolKnives (Consortium)/ Arm blades (Empire)Tactical CloakSniper KitPaladin PLR-5 Sniper rifle (Consortium)/ PSG-L Sniper rifle (Empire)BAG-90 pistolTactical CloakSaboteur KitSupportThe Support class is a lightly armored class whose special abilities are tied directly to what kit their equipped with. When using the Medic kit, they can drop a field medical pack that continuously heals both teammates and opponents in its immediate area. When using the Engineer kit, they are granted with the Field repair tool that will repair friendly structures, and damage enemy ones. The BBQ kit grants the Support excellent crowd control weapons, with the main highlight being the flamethrower.Medic KitMP-7 Machine pistol (Consortium) / PP-22 Machine Pistol (Empire)BAG-90 pistolField Medical PackP-12 Poison grenade (Consortium) / U-23 Poison grenade (Empire)Engineer KitSPETZ-9 ShotgunBAG-90 pistolField Repair toolDaisycutter anti-personnel mineE.M.P. GrenadeBBQ KitNX-300 FlamethrowerBAG-90 pistolP-12 Poison grenade (Consortium) / U-23 Poison grenade (Empire)M-87 Fragmentation grenadePC System RequirementsOS: Windows® 7 32/64-bit / Vista 32/64 / XP or higherProcessor: Intel Core 2 Duo 2.4GHz or equivalentMemory: 2GBHard Disk Space: 6GB of free HDD spaceVideo Card: Video card must be 128 MB or more and should be a DirectX 9-compatible with support for Pixel Shader 2.0b (ATI Radeon HD 2900 - NVidia GeForce 8800)Sound: DX 9.0c compatible sound cardMac System RequirementsOS: MacOS X 10.6.7 or higherProcessor: Core 2 Duo 2.4 GhzMemory: 2GB RAMHard Disk Space: 6GB of free HDD spaceVideo Card: ATI Radeon HD 2400 / NVidia GeForce 8600M / Intel HD Graphics 3000Not Supported: OS X 10.5.x, ATI X1600 or X1900 graphics, NVIDIA GeForce 7 graphics or Intel graphics less than Intel HD 3000.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="31334">Iron Grip: Warlord</game><game id="240">Natural Selection</game><game id="24324">Natural Selection II</game><game id="16088">Battlezone</game><game id="17828">Battlefield 2142</game><game id="4548">Savage: The Battle for Newerth</game><game id="11254">Savage 2: A Tortured Soul</game><game id="27863">Dust 514</game><game id="16742">Wargasm</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4344/1909333-ndboxart_eu.jpg</image></root>