<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29664</id><name>NBA Jam</name><description>OverviewBOOMSHAKALAKA!NBA Jam is a 2-on-2 arcade basketball game developed by EA Canada and published by EA Sports for the Wii on October 5, 2010. Originally a Wii-exclusive, it was later released on November 17, 2010 for the PlayStation 3 and Xbox 360, featuring upgraded HD visuals and online play. (This version was originally planned to be a feature-limited downloadable title included with new copies of the unreleased NBA Elite 11, but was later made a retail release.)Unlike previous Acclaim-developed installments of the franchise, the 2010 installment features gameplay and aesthetics reminiscent of Midway's original NBA Jam. (With help from the original designer, Mark Turmell, who worked with EA Tiburon at the time, and Tim Kitzrow, the iconic announcer of the original game, who shouted famous catchphrases such as "Boomshakalaka!" and "He's on fire!").Building upon the 2010-2011 NBA roster, the game features a "Remix Tour" campaign (featuring new crazy features such as power-ups, new camera angles, and boss battles) and special "legend" characters (legendary former NBA players). The game also brings back special guest characters and easter eggs from the original, such as former president Bill Clinton, hip-hop band Beastie Boys, and Big Head Mode, while adding new, modern secret characters, such as presidents Barack Obama and George W. Bush.An enhanced version, titled NBA Jam: On Fire Edition, was released as a downloadable title for the Xbox 360 (via Xbox Live Arcade) and the PlayStation 3 (via PlayStation Network) on October 4, 2011. On January 11th, 2013, the online servers for the Xbox 360 and PlayStation 3 versions of the original game were shut down.GameplayNBA Jam is a fast-pace arcade style 2-on-2 basketball game that plays very similarly to the 1993 arcade game of the same name. Their are no fouls in NBA Jam other than goal tending (interfering with the ball when it is on the way to the basket) and shot clock violation (24 second shot clock expires before a shot is taken). Since their are only those two fouls, players have the ability to shove their opponents in an attempt to jar the basketball loose. In order to counter this, a new spin move has been added to the series. If the player spins just as they are about to be shoved they will spin out of the shove causing the opposing player to stagger over. Another new offensive move added to the series is a crossover move. A successful counter will cause the opponent to stagger for a moment giving the player a chance to score a bucket. Players also have the ability to perform alley-oops by passing the ball to an airborne teammate or by going up for an alley-oop themselves and having their teammate pass it to them.Trail of fireIf the player manages to score 3 times in a row they will become "on fire" (points scored via goal tending violations do not count). When on fire the player has unlimited turbo, better shot making ability, and the ability to perform gravity defying dunks. The only way to put out an opposing players fire is by scoring a bucket (scoring via a goal tending violation will not put out an opposing players fire). If the players on fire status has not been put out after 5 possessions, it will automatically go out.Game TypesIn addition to the classic 2v2 game, several new modes have been added including 21, Smash, Domination, Elimination and 2v2 Remix. Classic Campaign only features the classic 2v2 game while Remix Tour features the other game types.In 21 the player is stacked up against 1 to 3 AI opponents in a race to 21 points. Only half the court is used and the perspective changes from a sideline view to a view positioned at the players back. The first player to reach 21 points wins the game. It also is make it take it, meaning the last player to score gets the ball back.In Smash the object of the game is to weaken the opposing teams backboard by performing dunks and alley-oops. Regular shots also do damage, but the damage is minimal. Each successful dunk, alley-oop or shot takes life off of the opposing teams backboard. Once the opponents backboard's life meter is completely empty, the backboard's glass shatters and the game ends with the player who shattered the backboard winning the game. The killing blow to the backboard must be a dunk or an alley-oop and not a lay-up or a jump shot.In Domination the object of the game is to gain spots on the court by scoring a basket while standing inside the spot. As in 21, the game is played half court with the camera to the players back and the game can be played in teams of 2 or free-for-all. There are five spots on the court: 4 placed on the three point line and 1 in the "paint". Once a player has control of a spot they continually gain points from it until either the opposing player takes the spot or the spot expires after a certain period of time. The first team or player to reach 100 points wins the game.Elimination is similar to 21 in many aspects, the only difference is that now the objective is to be the last man standing. The game is played in rounds, each round ends after a set period of time and the player with the lowest score is eliminated. This continues until only 1 player is left and that player wins the game. If 2 players tie for the lowest score then they both are eliminated.2v2 Remix is identical to classic 2v2 except that it contains power-ups. Power-ups can provide benefits such as increasing the players speed or strength. However, one power-up shrinks the player having a negative impact on their ability to make shots. Power-ups randomly show up on the court and can be collected by simply walking over them.Magic Johnson boss battleCampaignsNBA Jam features two different campaign modes, Classic Campaign and Remix Tour. Classic Campaign is similar to the older NBA Jam games, it pits the player against all NBA teams (except for the team chosen by the player to avoid the same team playing against itself). In addition to the games against NBA teams, their are also legend battles which pits the player against former NBA legends. Beating the legends unlocks them as playable characters.Remix Tour has the player traveling through divisions defeating NBA teams in the various game types in order to earn trophies. Each NBA team has a bronze, silver, and gold trophy associated with them. Beating the team once earns the bronze trophy, twice the silver, and three times the gold. Remix Mode also features boss battles which puts the player up against a recognizable NBA star that has been given super-human or super-natural abilities. For example, in the boss battle with Magic Johnson, Magic Johnson has the ability to teleport around the court making him very hard to guard. After the player has earned all the trophies from all the NBA teams and after the credits have finished, they will enter one last game against The Beastie Boys in a game of 21. Defeating them unlocks them as playable charactersStandard RosterThe standard roster for NBA Jam includes the 30 standard teams from the 2010-2011 NBA season. Unlike the original NBA Jam, in which teams are divided in the Team Selection Screen into Eastern and Western conferences, this installment lists all teams alphabetically. Each team has 3-4 standard players, and most teams have additional unlockable "legends" (Former NBA players).Atlanta HawksSoutheast Division. Joe JohnsonJosh SmithMike BibbyLegendsDominique Wilkins (unlocked by beating the Southeast Division Legend Team in Classic Campaign mode)Spud Webb (unlocked by beating the Southeast Division Legend Team in Classic Campaign mode)Boston CelticsAtlantic Division. Kevin GarnettPaul PierceRajon RondoRay AllenLegendsLarry Bird (unlocked by beating the Bird/Magic Superteam in Classic Campaign mode)Kevin McHale (unlocked by performing 10 successful jump shots in one game)Charlotte BobcatsSoutheast Division. Gerald WallaceStephen JacksonTyrus ThomasChicago BullsCentral Division. Derrick RoseLuol DengJoakim NoahCarlos BoozerLegendsScottie Pippen (unlocked by performing a 5-win streak in Classic Campaign mode)Dennis Rodman (unlocked by performing 10 successful shoves in one game)Cleveland CavaliersCentral Division. Mo WilliamsAntawn JamisonAnderson VarejaoLegendsMark Price (unlocked by beating the CPU in a 2-on-2 game without shoving)Brad Daugherty (unlocked by beating the CPU in a 2-on-2 game by doubling their score or better)Dallas MavericksSouthwest Division. Dirk NowitzkiJason KiddCaron ButlerDenver NuggetsNorthwest Division. Carmelo AnthonyChauncey BillupsKenyon MartinDetroit PistonsCentral Division. Richard HamiltonRodney StuckeyCharlie VillanuevaBen GordonLegendsIsiah Thomas (unlocked by beating the Central Division Legend Team in Classic Campaign mode)Bill Laimbeer (unlocked by beating the Central Division Legend Team in Classic Campaign mode)Golden State WarriorsPacific Division. Monta EllisDavid LeeStephen CurryAndris BiedrinsLegendsChris Mullin (unlocked by beating the Pacific Division Legend Team in Classic Campaign mode)Tim Hardaway (unlocked by beating the Pacific Division Legend Team in Classic Campaign mode)Houston RocketsSouthwest Division. Kevin MartinYao MingTrevor ArizaLegendsHakeem Olajuwon (unlocked by beating the Southwest Division Legend Team in Classic Campaign mode)Kenny Smith (unlocked by beating the Southwest Division Legend Team in Classic Campaign mode)Indiana PacersCentral Division. Danny GrangerMike Dunleavy, Jr.T.J. FordLegendsDetlef Schrempf (unlocked by winning a game against the CPU with a human teammate)Los Angeles ClippersPacific Division. Baron DavisBlake GriffinChris KamanLegendsDanny Manning (unlocked by scoring 1,000 points overall)Los Angeles LakersPacific Division. Kobe BryantPau GasolRon ArtestLamar OdomLegendsMagic Johnson (unlocked by beating the Bird/Magic Superteam in Classic Campaign mode)James Worthy (unlocked by performing a 10-win streak in Classic Campaign mode)Memphis GrizzliesSouthwest Division. O.J. MayoZach RandolphRudy GayLegendsBryant Reeves (unlocked by winning 100 games overall)Miami HeatSoutheast Division. Dwyane WadeLeBron JamesChris BoshLegendsGlen Rice (unlocked by beating the CPU in a 2-on-2 game by tripling their score or better)Rony Seikaly (unlocked by performing 10 successful dunks in one game)Milwaukee BucksCentral Division. Michael ReddAndrew BogutBrandon JenningsCorey MaggetteMinnesota TimberwolvesNorthwest Division. Kevin LoveJonny FlynnMichael BeasleyLegendsChuck Person (unlocked by being "On Fire" 4 times in one game)New Jersey NetsAtlantic Division. Devin HarrisBrook LopezCourtney LeeLegendsKenny Anderson (unlocked by performing 10 successful steals in one game)Drazen Petrovic (unlocked by completing a game of 21 against a human player)New Orleans HornetsSouthwest Division. Chris PaulDavid WestPeja StojakovicLegendsLarry Johnson (unlocked by winning a game without letting your teammate score)New York KnicksAtlantic Division. Danilo GallinariRaymond FeltonAmar'e StoudemireLegendsPatrick Ewing (unlocked by beating the Atlantic Division Legend Team in Classic Campaign mode)John Starks (unlocked by beating the Atlantic Division Legend Team in Classic Campaign mode)Oklahoma City ThunderNorthwest Division. Kevin DurantJeff GreenRussell WestbrookOrlando MagicSoutheast Division. Dwight HowardVince CarterRashard LewisLegendsNick Anderson (unlocked by completing a Play Now game)Scott Skiles (unlocked by performing 30 successful assists in one game)Shaquille O'Neal (unlocked by beating the CPU in a Backboard Smash game)Philadelphia 76ersAtlantic Division. Andre IguodalaElton BrandLouis WilliamsEvan TurnerLegendsJulius Erving (unlocked by performing 10 successful alley-oops in one gameAllen Iverson (unlocked by performing 10 successful shove counters in one game)Phoenix SunsPacific Division. Steve NashGrant HillJason RichardsonLegendsDan Majerle (unlocked by scoring 100 points in one game)Kevin Johnson (unlocked by beating the CPU in a 2-on-2 game with your drone teammate scoring all of the points)Portland Trail BlazersNorthwest Division. Brandon RoyLaMarcus AldridgeGreg OdenLegendsClyde Drexler (unlocked by completing Classic Campaign mode with a team from each division)Sacramento KingsPacific Division. Tyreke EvansCarl LandryJason ThompsonDeMarcus CousinsLegendsMitch Richmond (unlocked by scoring 10,000 points total)San Antonio SpursSouthwest Division. Tim DuncanTony ParkerManu GinobiliLegendsDavid Robinson (unlocked by performing 10 successful rebounds in one game)George Gervin (unlocked by scoring a Buzzer Beater shot that wins a 2-on-2 game)Toronto RaptorsAtlantic Division. DeMar DeRozanJarrett JackAndrea BargnaniUtah JazzNorthwest Division. Deron WilliamsAndrei KirilenkoMehmet OkurLegendsKarl Malone (unlocked by beating the Northwest Division Legend Team in Classic Campaign mode)John Stockton (unlocked by beating the Northwest Division Legend Team in Classic Campaign mode)Washington WizardsSoutheast Division. Yi JianlianAndray BlatcheGilbert ArenasJohn WallLegendsManute Bol (unlocked by performing 10 successful blocks in one game)Hidden RosterNBA Jam also includes secret teams, which can be chosen by hitting the plus button (right bumper for Xbox 360 version) on the team selection screen. They can either be unlocked by inputting a secret set of initials in the enter Initials screen or by pressing a combination of buttons on the title screen.DemocratsPresident ObamaUnlocked by pressing Left 13 times, then "+" ("A" and "X" on the Xbox 360 and Playstation 3 versions, respectively) on the title screen. Barack ObamaJoe BidenBill ClintonHillary ClintonAl GoreRepublicansGeorge W. BushUnlocked by pressing Right 13 times, then "+" ("A" and "X" on the Xbox 360 and Playstation 3 versions, respectively) on the title screen. George W. BushDick CheneyJohn McCainSarah PalinBeastie BoysUnlocked by pressing up, up, down, down, left, right, left, right, "B", and "+" on the title screen or by beating the Beastie Boys team in Remix Tour mode. Mike DMike DMCAAd-RockESPN SportsNationUnlocked by inputting "ESP" as player one's initials and "NSN" as player two's initials. Colin CowherdColin CowherdMichelle BeadleMascotsG-WizUnlocked by inputting "MAS" as player one's initials and "COT" as player two's initials. G-WizThe RaptorBango the BuckMavs ManRufus LynxRumble the BisonRocky the Mountain LionOriginal Generation JamMark TurmellUnlocked by inputting "MJT" as player one's initials. Mark TurmellTim KitzrowCole  WonderJ.Cole / 9th WonderUnlocked by pressing up, left, down, right, up, left, down, right, 1 and 2 on the title screen. J. Cole9th WonderStickmanUnlocked by beating the Stickman team in Classic Campaign. Stickman YellowStickman GreenStickman BlueStickman RedThe NeighborsMathias MurphyUnlocked by inputting "MMK" as player one's initials and "D35" as player two's initials. (Xbox 360 and PS3 versions only) Kevin DurantMathias MurphyTeam SpriteLebron JamesUnlocked by inputting "SPR" as player one's initials and "ITE" as player two's initials. (Xbox 360 and PS3 versions only) Yellow Lebron JamesGreen Lebron JamesTeam AdidasDwight HowardUnlocked by inputting "ADI" as player one's initials and "DAS" as player two's initials. (Xbox 360 and PS3 versions only) Dwight HowardDerrick RoseJosh SmithTeam JordanDwyane WadeUnlocked by inputting "JOR" as player one's initials and "DAN" as player two's initials. (Xbox 360 and PS3 versions only) Dwyane WadeCarmelo AnthonyChris Paul</description><genres><genre id="22">Basketball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10512">NBA Hangtime</game><game id="4632">NBA Showtime: NBA on NBC</game><game id="946">Rap Jam: Volume One</game><game id="22306">HoopWorld</game><game id="20685">NBA Ballers: Chosen One</game><game id="10302">NBA Street Homecourt</game><game id="61">NBA Street V3</game><game id="9866">NBA Street Vol. 2</game><game id="11686">NBA Ballers: Phenom</game><game id="9938">NBA Ballers</game><game id="8740">Lakers vs. Celtics and the NBA Playoffs</game><game id="698">NBA Street Showdown</game><game id="23316">NBA Ballers: Rebound</game><game id="21747">NBA ShootOut</game><game id="19999">NBA Inside Drive 2004</game><game id="7982">NBA Street</game><game id="31670">NBA Maximum Hangtime</game><game id="26912">NBA Unrivaled</game><game id="33222">NFL Blitz</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1536634-nbajam_box.png</image></root>