<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29686</id><name>Gundam Assault Survive</name><description>OverviewGundam Assault Survive is the successor of the Gundam Battle PSP series which has not seen a new entry since Gundam Battle Universe. Unlike its predecessors, which focused exclusively on Gundam's early Universal Century timeline, it now expands to include alternate universes.    Scenarios-One Year War (UC 0079): Mobile Suit Gundam and related sidestories  Factions: Earth Federation, Principality of Zeon -Operation Stardust (UC 0083): Mobile Suit Gundam 0083: Stardust Memories  Factions: Earth Federation, Principality of Zeon -Gryps Conflict (UC 0087): Mobile Suit Zeta Gundam   Factions:  AEUG, Titans-First Neo-Zeon War (UC 0088): Mobile Suit Gundam ZZ, Mobile Suit Gundam Sentinel  Factions: AEUG, Neo Zeon -Second Neo-Zeon War (UC 0093): Mobile Suit Gundam: Char's Counterattack  Factions: Londo Bell, Neo Zeon -Cosmo Babylonian War (UC 0123): Mobile Suit Gundam F91 (new) Factions: Earth Federation, Crossbone Vanguard -Bloody Valentine War (CE 70): Mobile Suit Gundam SEED (new) Factions: Earth Alliance, ZAFT  -Celestial Being Armed Interventions (AD 2307): Mobile Suit Gundam 00 (first season) (new) Factions: Celestial Being, United Nations Forces  Series included, but not given campaign scenarios include Mobile Suit Victory Gundam and Mobile Suit Gundam: Hathaway's Flash.  OperatorsAnn Friberg (       MS Sensen 0079)Ellen Rochefil (             Climax U.C.)Noel Anderson (      Lost War Chronicles)Hoa Blanchett (              MS Sensen 0079)Miyu Takizawa (               From Place Beyond the Blaze)Yuuki Nakasato      (Lost War Chronicles)Female Soldier (The 08th MS Team)Charlotte Hepner (                Zeonic Front)Maureen Kitamura ( The Blue Destiny) New FeaturesThe player now has two squadmates as opposed to one."True" Create-a-Character is implemented for the first time.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23091">Gundam Battle Universe</game><game id="27065">Macross Ultimate Frontier</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/16207/1240736-assault_survive_boxart.jpg</image></root>