<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29751</id><name>Ace Combat: Joint Assault</name><description>OverviewDeveloped by the renowned Project Aces Development Team at Namco Bandai in Japan, Ace Combat: Joint Assault for the PSP is the follow-up for Ace Combat X in 2006. The close-quarter combat and visuals are completely re-designed for a new fun experience for any flight action game fan. In Japan, the game is titled Ace Combat X2: Joint Assault.PlotAce Combat: Joint Assault takes place years after a global financial crisis. A terrorist group known as Valahia attacks Japan with an army full of tanks, fighter jets, and airborne superfortresses equalized with electromagnetic cannons that can wipe out entire cities. After their initial attack on Tokyo, they begin wreaking havoc on other famous places around the world ( Egypt, London, San Francisco).To counter this dastardly organization, countries from around the world accept the help of Martinez Security, a PMC. You're their latest recruit and take to the skies to fight terror.GameplayAce Combat: Joint Assault is set in the skies over familiar real-world locations such as Tokyo, London, San Francisco and many more. The game features Single and CO-OP, Campaign and Multiplayer VS Battle Wireless online Multiplayer. Up to 4 players Can take on all the missions in the Campaign mode. The New Joint Assault Mission System enables players to work on different maps simultaneously that makes an affect on other tactical situations. The New Enhanced Combat view was created for this game to see Enemies moment clearly.A series first, 3 new 'standard' missiles types are introduced allowing players to choose from 4 millsile types in addition to their special weapon. In addition, players are for the first time granted the option of equipping only special weapons, or forgoe special weapons altogether and equip two sets of missiles.Players must pay to repair their aircraft and any missiles expended in between missions. Because of these maintenance costs as well as significantly higher prices on the aircraft, Joint Assault makes it difficult to obtain all 44 planes. Fortunately, players can sell planes and even weapons to gain back the full amount of credits it took to buy them in the first place, meaning that players are not penalized for selling an aircraft and simply buying it back later.AircraftsAce Combat Joint Assault has 44 aircraft, most of them real-world aircraft. Players can buy them via the Hangar. Unlike previous Ace Combat games where planes are listed in the order you unlock them, aircraft in Joint Assault are organized by real life country of origin and manufacturer. Each aircraft can has six paint schemes to unlock. Joint Assault is the first game in the Ace Combat series to feature WWII fighters as well as the ability to fly a civilian plane -- the Beoing 747 passenger jet. The tuning system from Ace Combat X returns but now every aircraft except the Beoing 747 can be turned.Real-world Aircraft:F-4E Phantom IIF/A-18E Super HornetF-15E Strike EagleF-15S/MTDF-5E Tiger IIA-6E IntruderX-29AF-14D Super TomcatA-10A Thunderbolt IIYF-23A Black Widow IIF-16C Fighting FalconF-16XLF-117A NighthawkF-22 RaptorFB-22 Strike Raptor ConceptF-35 Lightning IITornado IDSEF-2000 TyphoonMirage 2000DRafale MJA 37 ViggenJAS-39C GripenMiG-21-93MiG-29A FulcrumMiG-31 FoxhoundMiG-1.44Su-27 FlankerSu-37 TerminatorSu-47 BerkutS-32F-1 KaizenF-2A Viper ZeroFictional aircraft:Ace Combat Joint Assault features most of the super-powered fictional aircraft from the entire Ace Combat series. It also introduces an all-new fictional aircraft, the GAF-1 Varcolac, which is first encountered in the game's story.XFA-24A ApalisYR-302 FregataYR-99 ForneusXR-35 CariburnXFA-27FenrirADF-1 FALKENX-02 WyvernGAF-1 VarcolacWW2 aircraft:A6M ZeroF6F HellcatCivilian aircraft:747-200B</description><genres><genre id="24">Flight Simulator</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4634">Microsoft Flight Simulator X</game><game id="20968">Heroes Over Europe</game><game id="4075">Wing Arms</game><game id="32364">Top Gun</game><game id="20671">Tom Clancy's H.A.W.X</game><game id="31188">Tom Clancy's H.A.W.X. 2</game><game id="8103">Over G Fighters</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2092581-box_acja.png</image></root>