<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29870</id><name>zeit²</name><description>OverviewZeit² is the first title from independent German developers Brightside Games, and is published by Ubisoft. It began as a project by students at Technische Universität, Berlin, Germany in 2008, and is now available on Xbox Live Arcade and Steam. Before its release, Zeit² was nominated for several awards including Microsoft Dream Build Play 2008, the 2009 Independent Games Festival Student Showcase, and the 2010 Indie Game Challenge. "Zeit" is the German word for "time".GameplayZeit² is a side-scrolling shooter in the vein of classics like R-Type. Visuals are reminiscent of flOw while using time mechanics similar to Braid. You fly around ,shoot enemies, grab power-ups, and the like. The game has 6 different game (arcade, waves, etc.) and leaderboards. Health and the rewind ability are capped. In addition to when the player is shot or touching an enemy, health also goes down when certain enemies past you, when you shoot and ,rewind time. The more health a player has the larger his size.Time PowersThe blue orb is the player while the black is the rewind cloneThe time abilities allow the player to rewind and fast forward time. After the ship rewinds, a black clone is made and does your previous actions to help you fight. Fast forwarding simply makes the game go faster for a chance increased at multipliers. Some enemies can only be destroyed by your time clone.PC System RequirementsOS: Windows XP, Vista, and 7Processor: at least 2.13 Ghz Intel Core 2 Duo or equivalentMemory: 2GBGraphics: at least Geforce 79XX or equivalent with DirectX 9, Shader Model 3.0, 256 MB VRAM, VGA resolutionDirectX®: DirectX 9Hard Drive: 1 GB free disk space</description><genres><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25700">Osmos</game><game id="15849">flOw</game><game id="12069">Ikaruga</game><game id="15784">Galaga</game><game id="16495">Einhänder</game><game id="413">Raiden III</game><game id="21409">Gradius Collection</game><game id="13745">R-Type</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1839044-box_zeit2.png</image></root>