<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2991</id><name>Boulder Dash</name><description>Boulder Dash is a maze game with added gravity. Players control Rockford, a stick man who navigates a series of caverns filled with Earth, boulders, diamonds and a series of creatures who kill on touch. The concept is simple: collect enough diamonds to escape each level within a time limit. But while Rockford isn't affected by gravity, the boulders and diamonds are -- remove a piece of earth underneath a boulder and it will fall, often setting off a chain reaction of falling debris. So the game plays as a puzzler; with each move that the player makes, they have to anticipate the consequences.Boulder Dash is one of a very short list of titles that began on home machines that were later transferred to the arcades. In 2006, Atari2600.com developed an Atari 5200 version of the game in conjunction with First Star Software. One iteration of the game was released in 2007 by ZX Games, and is a largely faithful remake of the original over 20 years after its original release. In 2009, a flash-based Browser version was released, sporting updated graphics.Virtual ConsoleThe Commodore 64 version of Boulder Dash was released on to the Wii Virtual Console on June 1st 2009 for 500 Wii Points.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2587">Dig Dug</game><game id="8482">Emerald Mine</game><game id="9447">O'Riley's Mine</game><game id="19922">Supaplex</game><game id="13583">Wanderer</game><game id="10523">Moai No Hihou</game><game id="25080">Douglas Rockmoor</game><game id="25081">Douglas Rockmoor 2</game><game id="25831">Skulldiggery</game><game id="10641">Mr. Do!</game><game id="31087">Boulder Match 4</game><game id="31380">Boulder Match 2</game><game id="31381">Boulder Match 3</game><game id="31382">Boulder Match</game><game id="14095">Mine Bombers</game><game id="3858">The Pit</game><game id="6407">Rockford: The Arcade Game</game><game id="18094">Exodus: Journey to the Promised Land</game><game id="33558">Werner Flaschbier</game><game id="32738">Delve Deeper</game><game id="12178">Crystal Mines</game><game id="15781">Crystal Mines II</game><game id="35429">Blocks That Matter</game><game id="36601">Bluppo</game><game id="37544">PigMan</game><game id="8514">Flappy</game><game id="8997">Banana</game><game id="42160">Hottaman no Chitei Tanken</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2361183-nes_boulderdash_de.jpg</image></root>