<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29922</id><name>Dragon Quest Monsters: Joker 2</name><description>DQM 2 is the sequel to 2007's DQM Joker, and the fifth game overall in the DQM series. Players will take on the role of a Monster Scout, who, much like a Pokemon trainer in Nintendo's popular franchise, can capture monsters from the wild to use in battles with other Scouts. DQM 2 adds new monsters and returns many old monsters from the very early DQM games that haven't been seen in recent entries, combining them with the monsters from the first DQM for a total of 311.GameplayThe actual gameplay remains largely the same as it was last time, with players wandering the vast overworld in search of new monsters to capture. Once captured, the monster can be manipulated in battle using a turn-based battle system. Monsters have access to a variety of special skills and spells, which players can specifically order the monsters to use. It's also possible for players to hit the "Fight" button and the monster will act of its own accord, choosing whichever attacks it deems appropriate for the situation. After battle, monsters will gain experience and level up, giving them increased stats as well as access to new skills and spells. The only direct interaction that the Scout has with battle comes in the form of distributing items, such as potions, to the monsters when the situation calls for it.In addition to obtaining new monsters by capturing them the old-fashioned way, it's possible to create entirely new species through a process called Synthesis. Much like the Fusion elements in the Persona series, Synthesis allows for several monsters to combine their powers, resulting in an entirely new offspring. For example, synthesizing the Angel Slime with the Cross Eye will produce a Skelegon far more powerful than either of the individual monsters used in synthesis. Synthesis is one of the best ways to get some of the most powerful monsters.StoryEvery year, the world's best Monster Scouts gather for the Monster Scout Challenge, a tournament whose outcome decides the Scout World Champion. Only the best of the best are allowed entrance into this tournament, and this is exactly what your Scout intends to do, although not through entirely legitimate means. As the massive airships transporting the world's top Scouts to the Challenge pull away from harbor, he manages to sneak aboard and stow away in the base of the vessel.Suddenly, a great storm lights up the skies. The harsh weather rips apart the airship, sending it crash landing in the middle of a vast desert. Stranded and surrounded by powerful monsters, it's up to the Scout to capture, train, and level up as many monsters as possible as he proceeds through the desert and towards the Monster Scout Challenge, with the goal of realizing his dreams and attaining the rank of number one.MultiplayerDQM Joker 2 is the second DQM game to feature online multiplayer, after the first Joker pioneered the series into the field. Players can battle against their friends using Nintendo's Friend Code system, or participate in random battles against strangers via Wi-Fi. There are leaderboards which will keep track of the game's best players on the game's official website.ReceptionWhen DQM Joker 2 was released in Japan on April 28, 2010, it was well-received, as most Dragon Quest games are in the region. Famitsu scored the game a 37 out of 40, and the game went on to sell over 1 million copies by July. It ended up being the sixth highest-selling game in Japan for the year of 2010.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26372">Pokémon HeartGold/SoulSilver</game><game id="21676">Pokémon Platinum</game><game id="17424">Custom Robo Arena</game><game id="21079">Dinosaur King</game><game id="25884">Dino Master</game><game id="27048">Fossil Fighters</game><game id="20515">Fossil League: Dino Tournament Championship</game><game id="23143">Monster Racers</game><game id="28033">Medarot DS Kabuto/Kuwagata</game><game id="13974">Pokémon Mystery Dungeon: Blue/Red Rescue Team</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1885621-box_dqmj2.png</image></root>