<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30020</id><name>Galcon Fusion</name><description>Galcon Fusion is the 2010 desktop sequel to 2006's Galcon.GameplayDepending on the game mode, each player will be given one or more starting planets. Players then send units from their planets to other planets in an attempt to capture them. All captured planets automatically generate new units, with larger planets having a faster growth rate than smaller planets. In most game modes, the first player to eliminate all other players from the map wins.Players can change the percentage of a planet's units to be sent by using the scroll wheel. Units that have already been sent can be redirected by clicking the squad and then clicking on a new target. Multiple planets can be selected for an attack by clicking sequentially or dragging a selection box around them. By default, players can also select all planets they control by double clicking any of their planets.Game ModesGalcon Fusion features ten game modes:Classic - traditional Galcon rules. Each playerVacuum (Single Player only) - this mode features no AI. The player must gain control of every planet before the timer expires.Beast (Single Player only) - a player starts with a small number of larger planets, while the AI has multiple smaller planets.3-Way (Single Player only) - a player faces off against two different AI players.Stealth - players will not see units from other players.Billiards - the planets will move, not unlike billiards balls.Crash - a reduced number of planets, with each player starting with many more units than normal. In this mode, a player's ships can crash into their opponent's, destroying both.Assassin - each player is given one other player as their "target". To win, a player must completely eliminate their target before another player does.Teams (Multiplayer only) - players are divided into teams.Retro (Multiplayer only) - the game is played using a retro DOS-like display, which allows players to send ships by typing the letter relating to the planet. (This is available in all single player modes by pressing F10, but is ranked separately online.)For single player, all game modes can be played on one of ten increasing difficulties:Cabin BoyEnsignLieutenantCommanderCaptainAdmiral1-Stripe Admiral2-Stripe Admiral3-Stripe AdmiralGrand AdmiralCompleting a mode on Ensign difficulty or higher yields a rank and an achievement/trophy, but as of release, players can only hold one achievement/trophy per game mode.Online play assigns ranks based on win/loss records using the same scale.PC System RequirementsOS: Windows XP/VistaProcessor: 1 GHz or higherMemory: 128MB RAMGraphics: 128MB, OpenGLHard Drive: 50MB of free spaceMac System RequirementsOS: OS X version Leopard 10.5.8, Snow Leopard 10.6.3, or later</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25339">Eufloria</game><game id="29083">Mushroom Wars</game><game id="37334">Oil Rush</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1373242-galconbox.png</image></root>