<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3003</id><name>Monster World IV</name><description>OverviewMonster World IV was released in Japan on the Mega Drive in 1994 and is the final installment in the Wonder Boy spin-off Monster World series. Monster World IV was never released outside of Japan during the life of the Mega Drive/Genesis, however an English translation patch was released by DeJap Translations and Demiforce on May 29, 2001. Sega eventually created an official English version of Monster World IV which was released on the Wii's Virtual Console on May 10, 2012. The English version of Monster World IV was also included in the Sega Vintage Collection: Monster World on the Xbox 360 and it was released as a stand alone game on PSN.StoryMonster World IV follows the adventures of a young green haired girl named Asha. One day Asha is listening to the wind when she hears a faint call for help from the four elemental spirits, immediately she begins a journey to aid them. Along the way Asha befriends a genie and a small blue monster called Pepe as well as learns of an evil force approaching the kingdom of Rapadagna. Now with the help of her new friends Asha must rescue the four endangered spirits and save the kingdom from evil.TriviaJacket image drawn by Maki OhzoraOn June 22, 2012 the MW Official Fan page on Facebook posted an unreleased song from Monster World IV that was created for an "Ocean Stage" that was never made. The song, like the rest of the MW4 soundtrack, was composed by Jin Watanabe and a special jacket image was created for the song by the game's original artist Maki Ohzora.Monster World IV was originally going to let the player choose between playing as a boy or a girl. However the idea was scrapped due to space limitations on the game's ROM. The boy character was named Eusha, which means "brave man." The girl character eventually evolved into Asha and became the only playable character in the finished game.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4208">Ys III: Wanderers from Ys</game><game id="14787">Popful Mail</game><game id="35891">Fortune Summoners: Secret of the Elemental Stone</game><game id="36225">Magical Taluluto-kun</game><game id="19245">Shantae</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3017/351046-monster_world_iv_01.jpg</image></root>