<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30036</id><name>Suck My Dick or Die!</name><description>OverviewSuck My Dick or Die! is a visual novel where there is very little interaction involved. Most of the time you will be reading text dialogue from the game's various characters and viewing still artwork. The only gameplay in Suck My Dick or Die! will be you making decisions to alter the storyline.Story"In a country full of political unrest, a little girl is raped and murdered by the rebelling guerilla force. Mr. Prosper, commander of the military unit trying to suppress the guerilla threat, advances his army into a small village to hunt down those responsible. However, this was all a ploy by Mr. Prosper. His real plan? To have a raping party all for himself. The girls suspected as members of the guerilla unit are arrested, and so begins Mr. Prosper's raping adventure."CharactersSharumiSharumiThe only child from a wealthy family where the military is stationed, Shirumi is a stubborn, shrewd (but kind) girl with a strong sense of justice. Her voluptuous, mature figure belies her child-like behavior. Riru RiruA maid at the mansion where the military is stationed. Riru is a gentle, reliable, and modest person who values her pure blood. She is one of the servants along with the main character.AlfinaAlfinaThe most intellectual and sexually attractive woman in the village. She teaches the main character reading and writing.FerisFerisA female soldier in the guerilla force. Though rough and simple-minded, Feris is a brave woman whose body is well-toned from working out.LatonaLatonaMr. Prosper's obedient sex slave. She encounters the main character in the beginning of the story, trying to prevent danger.Recommended SpecificationsRequired CPU:Pentium III 600MHzRecommended CPU:Pentium III 800MHzRequired Memory:128MBRecommended Memory:256MBRequired Resolution:640x480Required Colors:65536 colorsRequired HDD Free Space:400MBDirectX:DirectX 8.0</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26948">The Maiden Rape Assault: Violent Semen Inferno</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8960/1447579-smdod.jpg</image></root>