<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30070</id><name>Army Defender</name><description>In Army Defender, you control a giant cannon and must protect your base for a certain amount of time. It was released only on the DSi's download shop as part of DSiWare. Gameplay You play Army Defender by holding your DSi like a book. The game only has one mode (campaign) and lets you choose between playing on easy or hard. Your goal is to protect your base with your giant cannon. On the right screen, you have your health, the time that's remainig and your fury meter. On the left screen, you see the arriving enemies, your score and current combo. Note that this is what you see when playing as a right handed person. The game gives you the option to change that in the options menu.   Your giant cannon can shoot in any direction. The twist is that enemies can come in different colors (red or green). To kill them, you must switch your cannon to the corresponding color by pressing on it with the stylus or pressing any button on the DSi. You aim and fire with the stylus. Enemies come in different forms: regular infantry, jet pack wearing soldiers, helicopters, bombers, etc.  From time to time, an allied plane will fly over you, dropping a special ammo type for your cannon. They can drop three types of ammo: cluster bombs, flamethrower and homing rockets. These ammo types can kill any types of enemies, regardless of color. When you've killed a certain number of enemies, you unlock fury. Fury is basically a nuke that eliminates all enemies on screeen.  To score a high score, you must pay attention to your multiplier. To improve your score multiplier, you must eliminate enemies without missing. By getting a good score, you win health and lives at the end of missions. </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3614/1275071-army_defender_box_art.jpg</image></root>