<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30093</id><name>Monaco: What's Yours Is Mine</name><description>OverviewMonaco is a co-operative game for 1-4 players where the goal is to sneak into a building and steal specific objects, be it money, jewelry, or high profile documents, in the style of heist movies. There are eight different classes, each with their own special abilities and weapons, and all the players have to work as a team to finish the objective. The game is playable by up to 4 people both offline and online, and was released on PC  Mac on April 24th 2013 and XBLA the following May. The game was made using XNA, and has also been ported to a multi-console engine by Empty Clip Games, meaning it works on many consoles and handhelds, but whether the game is released on these platforms is still undecided.AwardsBefore the game was even complete or publicly released, it won two awards at the 2010 Independent Games Festival Awards: the Excellence in Design Award and the Seumas McNally Grand Prize. It should also be noted that at the time, the game had only been in development for roughly five weeks. The prototype submitted for the IGF, then titled Monte-Carlo, was made available as a pre-order bonus for the PC version of the game.StorySet in the titular micro-state of Monaco, and the story involves a group of criminals who escape prison and decide to pull off some heists around the country. Narration will unfold as a series of voice overs at the beginning of each level, told by a member of the crew.ClassesThe eight classes in Monaco each have their own set of passive and active abilities. Before the game's launch only four classes have had their specific information shown, with the rest to be revealed when the game is released.The Locksmith: faster at opening locks and safesThe Lookout: can expand the teams field of vision and track unseen guardsThe Hacker: can spawn security viruses at power outletsThe Pickpocket: has a pet monkey that silently gathers loot; he also can hide in bushes more quicklyThe Mole: can tunnel through wallsThe Gentleman: can disguise himselfThe Redhead: can seduce and distract guardsThe Cleaner: Uses chloroform to knock out unsuspecting guardsMusicThe music in Monaco is done by Grammy-nominated composer Austin Wintory. Best known for his work on the 2012 PSN release, Journey. Pocketwatch Games has released both the OST as well as a special Monaco remix album.System RequirementsPCMinimumOS: Windows XP or laterProcessor: 1.2GHz processorGraphics: Graphics Card that supports Pixel Shader 2.0 and Vertex Shader 2.0(Vertex Shader Support can be supported with software emulation)DirectX®: 9.0Hard Drive: 450 MB HD spaceRecommendedOS: Windows XP or laterProcessor: 1.4GHz processorGraphics: Graphics Card that supports Pixel Shader 3.0 and Vertex Shader 2.0(Vertex Shader Support can be supported with software emulation)DirectX®: 9.0Hard Drive: 450 MB HD spaceMacOS: OS X version Snow Leopard 10.6.3, or later.Processor: 2.0+ GHzMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: OpenGL 2.1 and shader model 3 with 512 MB of memory.DirectX®: 9.0Hard Drive: 500 MB HD spaceLinksOfficial Website</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14087">Bonanza Bros.</game><game id="23768">Subversion</game><game id="7624">Pac-Man</game><game id="6709">Hitman: Codename 47</game><game id="42568">Ping!</game><game id="1739">Lock 'n' Chase</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2412936-box_monaco.png</image></root>