<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30142</id><name>The King of Fighters XIII</name><description>OverviewThe King of Fighters XIII is the latest game in the  KOF series. It was released to arcades on July 14, 2010, coming a little more than a year after its predecessor,  The King of Fighters XII. Addressing widespread complaints regarding the bare-bones nature of KOF XII, KOF XIII adds several new characters and more in-depth subsystems.It is the climax of the Ash Saga, which began in  The King of Fighters 2003.KOF XIII marks the HD debut of  Mai Shiranui,  King,  Yuri Sakazaki,  Takuma Sakazaki,  Vice,  K',  Maxima and  Kula Diamond.  Hwa Jai, who hasn't been a competitor since the original  Fatal Fury, makes his KOF debut in this game.According to the development team, KOF XIII's theme is "KOF-ism," or capturing the "heart" of previous KOF entries. In line with this train of thought, most of the returning characters resemble their earliest forms. For example, Vice wears her business attire from '95 and assumes her stance from '96, and King's stance and moveset comes from Art of Fighting. For the first time in franchise history,  Athena Asamiya does not change outfits between games, merely receiving a paletteswap of her KOF XII costume.Arcade HardwareThe game uses Square Enix's Taito Type X2 arcade system hardware:OS: Microsoft Windows XP EmbeddedCPU: Intel Core 2 Duo E6400Chipset: Intel Q965 + ICH8Monitor: 720p/1080p/1440p HD LCD monitorRAM: DDR2 667/800MHz (1-4 GB)GPU: PCI Express x16-based graphics. Support cards include ATI RADEON X1600Pro to 3800 or nVIDIA GeForce 7900GS to 9800.Sound: Onboard Realtek HD 7.1 channel Sound (supports add-in sound cards)LAN: 10/100/1000 BASE-TI/O ports: 1x JVS, 4x USB 2.0 (up to 8), 1x serial (max 2), 1x parallel port, 2x PS/2, 2x SATAAudio inputs: AKG C535EB Stage Microphone, line-in (Surround 7.1)Audio outputs: 7.1, SPDI/FXExpansion Slots: 1x PCI Express x16 (used by video card), 1x PCI Express x4, 2x PCIStorage: 2x 80 GB 10k RPM SATA hard drivesMedia: 80 GB 10000 rpm hard driveConsole ReleaseOn June 7, SNK Playmore announced that The King of Fighters XIII will be released for the Playstation 3 and Xbox 360. The game was released by Atlus in North America on November 22, 2011. The game was released in Japan on December 1, 2011 by SNK Playmore themselves. Rising Star Games released the title in Europe on November 25, 2011.The console version features ten modes. In addition to the Arcade and Training modes available in the arcade version, the game features a more in-depth Story Mode, Missions, and a Tutorial for new players. There is also console-exclusive characters; with  Billy Kane and  Saiki appearing as unlockables, and three more characters appearing as DLC. In addition, several new stages are included. According to Matsushita's twitter, the concept behind the new stages are "Release previous KOF backgrounds and new backgrounds in beautiful HD quality."One new addition to the game is the ability to change the button configuration from the character select screen. This is done by pressing the Circle Button on the PS3 or the B button on the Xbox 360. The default button layout is similar to Capcom's fighting games. Also, the game can be installed to the HDD to decrease the length of load times.SNK Playmore stated that the online play would be an improvement over The King of Fighters XII's and was their number one priority. There is no English dub for the game, but the text is translated into English, French, German, Spanish, Italian, Chinese and Korean.The game offers downloadable content, including three new characters. These characters, Iori with the Power of Flames, NESTS saga Kyo, and Mr. Karate, are each priced at $5/400msp and include a full set of trials, unique stage based on a previous game, and a custom theme song.iPhone ReleaseThe game was released on the iOS on July 7, 2011 under the name The King of Fighters-i. The game retains most of the same gameplay mechanics as the arcade version. At launch, fourteen playable characters (Team Japan, Team Fatal Fury, Team K', Team Women Fighters, Ash and Billy Kane) were available. On September 9, six more characters (Team Yagami, Team Elizabeth) were added to the roster. There are twelve stages available, with more now available, in the game with some from the arcade version and new designs from older games.There are four playable modes which include Team and Single Battles, Endless, and Training mode. Players can also play against each other in Bluetooth mode.The game uses touch screen controls, similar to Street Fighter IV Volt, but doesn't use the same four button layout as other SNK fighters. There is one button for punches, kicks, special moves, evades, and one for Hyper Drive activation.There are unlockables in the game which include trading cards with original artwork, concept art, and team stories that can be read.PC ReleaseOn August 19th, 2013, a pre-order page for King of Fighters XIII appeared on Steam with a release date of September 13th, priced £22.99. A limited closed beta was also announced, limited to 300 people chosen through a lottery system via the game's official website.StoryThe previous canonical game,  The King of Fighters XI, ended with the death of  Magaki, a member of "Those From the Past." Elsewhere, Ash Crimson defeated  Orochi Iori and claimed his Sacred Treasure, and it was revealed that  Rose Bernstein is under  Botan's control.It's no surprise that another KOF tournament is announced, with Rose as its sponsor. The leader of Those From the Past,  Saiki, plans to use this tournament to start the final phase of his plan. But what is he trying to accomplish? And what role will Ash Crimson play?GameplayKOF XIII does away with many of the changes made by KOF XII and the other Ash Saga games. The overall gameplay speed has been increased, placing it in line with previous entries in the series; the super meter also returns to  KOF 2002's 3-to-5 stock system. Critical Counter and Guard Attacks have been done away with completely, and camera zoom-ins only occur during certain animations.The game's main gimmick is the Hyper Drive Meter. Drive Cancels allow the player to cancel an Special Move into another Special Move which costs 50% of the Hyper Drive Meter. Super Cancels allow players to cancel a Special Move into a Desperation Move which also costs 50% of the Hyper Drive Meter. Additionally, once the Hyper Drive Meter is filled, Hyper Drive Mode allows the player to perform unlimited HD Cancels for a short time.This game also introduces EX Special Moves, EX Desperation Moves, and Neo Max Desperation Moves. EX Specials work similar to EX moves in  Street Fighter III and  IV, giving special moves additional advantageous properties at the cost of one stock of Super Meter. EX Desperation Moves do the same for DMs, while increasing the cost of the attack to two stocks. Neo Max moves, the strongest moves in the game, require three stocks of Super Meter and either a full HD meter or Hyper Drive Mode (as of the console version, the cost is reduced to two stocks if performed from HD Mode). Neo Max moves can be canceled into during combos by using Max Cancel (which is essentially the Dream Cancel from The King of Fighters XI).The game also includes other subsystems that have become KOF standard, including the Jump/Super Jump/Short Hop/Hyper Hop system, rolls, Guard Cancel knockdowns, among others.Other FeaturesSeveral new stages have been created, and some from XII have been improved. Predefined teams return, along with team themes. Each character has ten color choices (fifteen for the console version) that are selected from a mini-menu, like  BlazBlue; some characters also have an additional hidden set of color choices. As a throwback to earler SNK games, King's and Yuri Sakazaki's tops are destroyed when they are finished off by a special or DM.RevisionsThere will be three "versions" of KOF XIII as of the console release. Version 1.0 of the game had several glitches, some of them game-breaking. These were addressed in Version 1.1, which was released after the Super Battle Opera fighting game tournament.The console version will receive a complete rebalance, including the aforementioned cost reduction for Neo Max moves. This rebalance, along with the console-exclusive characters, will be ported back to arcades asThe King of Fighters XIII Climax.Gameplay ModesArcadeThe standard single player mode that is featured in most fighting games. There are six stages; then, depending on certain conditions, the player will either receive the game's "bad ending" or go on to fight the two boss characters. Each round starts with a short conversation between the two participating characters, a feature last seen in  SVC Chaos. During the match, "Target Actions" appear; these are small tasks like "Roll 3 times" or "Perform an EX attack" that grant the player in-match benefits such as stock to the Hyper Drive Meter and Super Meter.StoryDeep story mode explaining the final part of the Ash saga presented in a visual novel format (akin to BlazBlue story mode). There are three perspectives to choose:  Ash,  Adelheid, and  Heidern.VersusSplit up into team battle (three versus three) or single battle (one versus one). Stages can be selected and handicaps can be set. When the match is over, players can immediately go do a rematch, change the order of the team, or go back to the character select screen and choose a different team.There are five levels for the handicap, which are:Level 1 - HP 50%Level 2 - HP 75%Level 3 - NormalLevel 4 - P + 1 - HD 50% (Power meter has 1 stock and 50% stock of Hyper Drive Meter)Level 5 - P - HD MAX (Power meter and Hyper Drive Meter are at full stock)TutorialAn introduction to The King of Fighters. This explains the basic mechanics and the multiple gauges.PracticeA mode which allows players to test their combos and strategies against a dummy opponent. This mode is available in the arcade version by holding down the attack buttons while pressing Start, but is restricted by a time limit. A number of options can be manipulated for the AI dummy such as action, guard, counter hit, attack and passive mode. Also, the gauges in the game (Hyper Drive Meter and Super Meter) can be adjusted as well. By default, the Back/Select button displays the command input for the playable fighter, but this can be changed as well to either reset back to default positions, move the dummy forward or jump.GalleryVisual - This mode allows players to view artwork, endings, and videos from the game.Sound - Grants the ability to listen to BGM, voices for each character and the system voice.InvitationMissionThis is split into three modes:Time attack - "Fight against the CPU under fixed regulations and try to get the fastest clear time."Survival - "Keep fighting against the CPU opponents until you run out of health."Trial - "Challenge a variety of character-specific missions." (This mode is akin to the Challenge mode in BlazBlue)OnlinePlayers will be able to complete globally in either ranked or player matches along with friend match. After the match, replays can be saved and uploaded.Ranked Match - "Prove your strength under specified regulations. Your results will be recorded in the Rankings."Player Match - "Fight under a variety of rules. You can also invite a good friend to play with. Your results will not be recorded in the Rankings."Friends Match - "Check invites from your friends."RankingsReplayOnline matches can be downloaded and saved. When viewing matches, players can choose to frame advance, pause, or skip the round during playback.CustomizeProfile - "Select which items to show in your profile." The online profile allows players to make a default team for online use, add an icon and a short message to display online. Just like colours, icons will be unlocked through playing the game.Character - "Edit characters' custom colours." Each character can have up to five custom colour schemes. When changing colours, the region that will be adjusted will glow when selected. When a colour is selected for that specific region, the game will adjust to that colour and use the proper shade instead of having to adjust each individual shade, as in The King of Fighters XI. Colours will be unlocked as players progress through the game with each respective fighter.Player DataStatistics of wins and losses from online play. Also keeps track total play time along with high score in arcade mode plus percentage completed of trials and unlocks in the gallery.StagesThe stages available in the game (with more to be confirmed) include:JapanIndiaUnited KingdomBrazilEgyptChinaFranceAmericaRose StadiumDestroyed Rose StadiumRose Stage (Misted)Desert (Console version)Clock Tower (Console version)PaoPao Cafe (Console version)Micky's Stage (Console version)Kyokugen-ryu Dojo (Console version)Rose Stadium Rooftop (Console version)Destroyed Manor (Console version)Sky Noah (Console version)Those From The Past Headquarters (Console version)Rival Team Stage '95 (Console version, DLC)Japan Team / Psycho Soldier Team Stage '96 (Console version, DLC)Mr. Karate Stage AOF (Console version, DLC)CharactersElisabeth Team Elisabeth Blanctorche Shen Woo Duo LonJapan Team Kyo Kusanagi Benimaru Nikaido Goro DaimonYagami Team Iori Yagami Mature ViceFatal Fury Team Terry Bogard Andy Bogard Joe HigashiArt of Fighting Team Ryo Sakazaki Robert Garcia Takuma SakazakiKim Team Kim Kaphwan Hwa Jai RaidenWomen Fighters Team Mai Shiranui Yuri Sakazaki KingK' Team K' Kula Diamond MaximaPsycho Soldier Team Athena Asamiya Sie Kensou Chin GentsaiIkari Warriors Team Leona Ralf Jones Clark SteelOther Ash Crimson (with "Evil Ash" as the final boss) Saiki (unplayable sub-boss)Console/Climax-Exclusive Billy Kane"Normal" SaikiIori "with the Power of Flames" (DLC)"NESTS" Kyo (DLC)Mr. Karate (DLC)SoundtracksAtlus and Rising Star Games offered a pre-order bonus for the game which is a compilation of music from all the King of Fighters games entitled "The King of Soundtracks." The bonus spans 4 Cd's. The tracks include:Disc IThe King of Fighters 941. Ne!2. NAPOLITAN BLUES3. JUNGLE BOUNCER4. SLUM No. 55. Kecchaku RD6. Pre Bon (Long Version)The King of Fighters 957. Ryuko to Ken ~Yureru Otoko Gokoro~8. CLUB-M ~Aozora ni Flute~9. Senritsu no Dora10. Chi wo Hau Base11. HAL to Base to Melody to12. THE SUNSET SKY PART6 ~LIEBEThe King of Fighters 9613. Rumbling on the City14. ESAKA?15. Psycho Soldier (REMIX '96)16. Geese ni Katakori17. Dust man18. Requiem in D minor, K. 626 Dies Irae19. SELFThe King of Fighters 9720. Bloody21. COOL JAM ~Arashi no Saxophone 3~22. BLUE MARY'S BLUES23. Still Green24. Rhythmic Hallucination25. The Origin of MindThe King of Fighters XIII26. Soul Road ~KOF 96~27. Esaka ~KOF XI~Disc IIThe King of Fighters 981. Kurikinton (Gomame Guitar Ver.)2. C623. London March4. Fairy5. IN SPITE OF ONE'S AGE6. FANATIC WALTZThe King of Fighters 997. MAD FANTASY8. XXX9. W.W.310. 176th Street11. SHA-LA-LA12. The way to rebirth13. Tears14. Deaf Falling AngelThe King of Fighters 200015. KD-008416. INNER SHADE17. Will18. Ice Place19. DREAM EATER20. CRYSTAL (TypeA)The King of Fightes 200121. BIG PAIN22. Muaki no Homo-o23. THE QUEEN OF FIGHTERS24. NESTS: Yami no Shihaisha25. Warekoso SaikyoDisc IIIThe King of Fighters 20021. Deserted Town2. TACO'S DANCE3. Yuuwaku no Toki4. Last Dance5. Festive moodThe King of Fighters 20036. Splendid Evil7. Joyrider8. KyokuGen9. Villainous10. Blaze11. Kakumei no Etude ~RllThe King of Fighters XI12. kiss or poison13. Secret Circumstances14. Rinrin15. King16. Koubai17. an improvised concertoThe King of Fighters XII18. Cracker19. The Myths of Geb20. Cafe au Lait au Gout de la Victoire21. Matryoshka Dance22. Theme of XII-2The King of Fighters XIII23. PURE ~at good old days~ ~KOFXI~24. Arashi no Saxophone ~KOFXI~Disc IVThe King of Fighters XIIIThe Second JokerEach PromiseEsaka ContinuesWild StreetPurity SoldiersIrregular MissionWho is Queen?Arashi no Saxophone 5Kyokugen Shugyoul ~Yamagomori~Tame a Bad BoyKDD-0063FateDiabolosisLondon March ~Arranged~Toki wo Suberu Morojoker ~KOFXI~Queen ~KOFXI~Street Dance ~KOFXI~Smell of gunpowder ~KOFXI~I'm Hot for You ~KOF2003~After a long absence ~KOFXI~KDD-0075 ~KOFXI~Geese ni Katakori ~Arranged~Fate ~Arranged~Staffroll ~Consumer~System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows XP Processor: Intel Pentium4 2.0 GHz and up Memory: 1 GB RAM Graphics: GeForce 9500 GT ,VRAM: 256MB and up DirectX: Version 9.0c Hard Drive: 5 GB available space Sound Card: DirectSound, DirectX9.0c Compatible AudioRecommendedOS: Windows7 Processor: Intel Core i5 2300 and up Memory: 4 GB RAM Graphics: GeForce GTS 250 ,VRAM: 512MB and up DirectX: Version 9.0c Hard Drive: 5 GB available space Sound Card: DirectSound, DirectX9.0c Compatible Audio</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="28437">Super Street Fighter IV</game><game id="28321">BlazBlue: Continuum Shift</game><game id="617">NeoGeo Battle Coliseum</game><game id="30944">Marvel vs. Capcom 3: Fate of Two Worlds</game><game id="8492">Capcom vs. SNK 2: Mark of the Millennium</game><game id="35938">Ultimate Marvel vs. Capcom 3</game><game id="2760">Art of Fighting</game><game id="35513">Phantom Breaker</game><game id="39531">Xuan Dou Zhi Wang</game><game id="35924">The King of Fighters-i 002</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2074740-box_kofxiii.png</image></root>