<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30198</id><name>Gekirindan</name><description>StoryIn the year 3195 a time machine is created on Earth and is promptly stolen by an unidentified, mechanized being known only as the Huge-Boss. The Huge-Boss quickly uses the time machine to travel back in time and destroy 3000 years of human history. The only resistance HB faces is a group of pilots from different time periods who aim to stop the HB, though some have other reasons than to save mankind. Weapons systemEach fighter has a different shot pattern that can be upgraded or changed. There are also the side-weapon pick-ups including a pair of homing lasers, diagonal firing napalm and missiles.Pilots Player 1 pilots: Hokuto: A strong, though effeminate looking pilot from the 3100 era whose parents were killed by Huge-Boss' attacks. With his mother's hair-tie as his only tangible remnant of them, Hokuto vows to avenge their deaths with the destruction of HB.  Anne: A young woman from the 1900s who pilots a helicopter, she writes all her experiences as she goes through life. Resembles Anne Shirley, a literary character popular in Japan.  Dietza: A wild rockabilly pilot possibly from the 1950s.  Player 2 pilots:  Grother: A confident, no-jokes pilot from an unknown time period. He keeps a picture of a beautiful dark-haired woman with him, but it's unknown who she is.  Shario: A beautiful and ingenious young woman from the 3100 era who attempts to fulfill the last wishes of her recently deceased sister that will be accomplished with HB's destruction. She always travels with her strange looking pet cat.  Orsa  Mayoru: Two young elfen pilots and nature lovers, possibly from the 3100 era. TriviaThe soundtrack (once again composed by Zuntata) mostly consists of the first level theme song remixed differently for every level with no boss themes. This game has many references to previous  Toaplan / Toaplan-developed Taito games.</description><genres><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="33654">Vasara</game><game id="33655">Vasara 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1614/1291224-gekirindan_sat_jp.jpg</image></root>