<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30191</id><name>Lara Croft and the Guardian of Light</name><description>StoryLara Croft is hunting down an artifact in South America called the Mirror of Smoke, which is said to hold the evil god Xolotl prisoner. When she locates the artifact, she is ambushed by some mercenaries, led by a man named Vasco. Vasco, not believing in the curse, takes the Mirror from its pedestal, and releases Xolotl in the process. Xolotl proceeds to summon his demonic minions, and begins his destruction of the world by annihilating Vasco's forces. Fortunately, as Xolotl is released, so is the spirit of Totec, the titular Guardian of Light, a centuries-old Aztec tribesman who had been the one to defeat Xolotl in the first place. He tells Lara that Xolotl must be stopped and the Mirror must be returned to its pedestal before the light of dawn. Without asking why, Lara teams up with Totec (introducing him to modern explosives as she does), and the two chase after Xolotl, taking out progressively bigger and more dangerous foes along the way.GameplayLara and Totec working togetherIn a first for the Tomb Raider series of games, it is played purely from a fixed isometric viewpoint. However in typical Tomb Raider style, players will still traverse through ruins, battle enemies  huge bosses, find hidden treasure, and solve puzzles to progress through the levels. The game can be played either solo or cooperatively, and the story  puzzle-solving will change slightly depending on which mode you're in.In solo mode, the player is forced to play as Lara Croft. When playing co-op (which can be done both locally or online), one player controls Lara while the other takes control of Totec. Each character has their own abilities, and characters will have to utilize their abilities to solve a puzzle or traverse the terrain. For example, Lara can fire her grappling hook across a cavern, and the nimble Totec can tight-rope walk across it. Alternatively, Totec can throw his spear into a wall to create a makeshift platform for the lighter Lara to jump on, to reach an area she couldn't reach on her own. Also, if you die, your teammate can quickly revive you if they are near by, or you can simply respawn next to your teammate after a short countdown (traversal puzzles, in which the player must figure out how to get both characters across an obstacle, will respawn players on the near side, to prevent them from solving the puzzle through suicide).When playing solo, you control Lara and are given Totec's spear, which can be used in pretty much the same ways as in co-op (attacking, creating temporary platforms on walls, etc.). The spear permanently occupies one of four weapon slots. Totec himself shows up only in cutscenes, to tell Lara that he will take a different path from hers. Most of the puzzles that required both characters to do something or stand somewhere are either somewhat simplified, or you are provided with a big heavy ball that takes Totec's place when you need to keep a floor panel pressed down.Another unique aspect of this game is the addition of a scoreboard. Players earn points for defeating enemies, discovering treasures, and completing levels quickly. Each level has its own set of challenges, which, upon being completed, give the player new weapons, relics, or health and ammo upgrades. These scores are then posted to the worldwide leaderboards, where players can see how they stack up against other players.The combat is fairly simple, and controls much like a dual-joystick shooter. You move with the left analog stick, aim with the right, then pull the right trigger to shoot. The weapons range from pistols, to rifles, to flamethrowers, to grenade launchers, and vary in their damage, rate of fire, and ammo consumption. Your ammo is represented by a blue bar underneath your health, and each shot, depending on the weapon, takes away a fraction of that bar. Both the ammo and health bars can be replenished in various ways, such as pick ups you find on the ground or off of dead enemies. Lara's pistols and Totec's spear both have infinite ammo, and characters will automatically switch to them should they expend all their ammo with another weapon. Both characters also carry an infinite amount of explosives, which have a clearly visible blast radius, and can be detonated at any time.As you collect your rewards for completing a level's challenges, or exploring its secret tombs, you will come across the game's "loot" in the form of artifacts and relics. Artifacts serve to increase one of your attributes, which are Weapon (damage), Defense, Bomb (damage  radius), and Speed. The quality of these artifacts ranges from clay, to stone, to gold. The clay and stone ones will increase a specific attribute, but decrease another, whereas the gold ones will not decrease anything. As you progress further, you will find new types of artifacts that increase two attributes at once. The relics, on the other hand, bestow special abilities when they are active, such as health/ammo regeneration, greater bomb blast radius, and powering up the damage of each weapon shot. The catch, however, is that relics are only active when you completely fill your relic power meter by scoring points, and it will drain completely once full when you take damage. Later relics will also bestow more abilities at once.Your character's inventory screen consists of four weapon slots, one of which is permanently occupied by either Lara's pistols or Totec's spear (depending on which character you are controlling), two artifact slots, and one relic slot.ArtifactsYou can use two Artifacts at a time, and they will affect your stats.ArtifactPositive Effects onNegative Effects onObtainableat Level(s)Clay OwlDefenseBomb12Stone OwlDefenseWeapon34Gold OwlDefense---26Clay FeatherSpeedDefense3Stone FeatherSpeedBomb26Gold FeatherSpeed---47Clay ArrowWeaponDefense15Stone ArrowWeaponBomb15Gold ArrowWeapon---68Clay LizardBombWeapon24Stone LizardBombDefense36Gold LizardBomb---59War DrumBombWeapon---710Wind DrumWeaponSpeed---810Serpent DrumBombSpeed---911White DrumDefenseSpeed---811Dark DrumWeaponDefense---1013Clay SerpentSpeedDefenseBomb---1213Stone SerpentWeaponDefenseBomb---1113Jade HeartWeaponDefenseBombSpeed---1213RelicsOnly one relic can be used, so choose carefully.RelicEffect(s)Obtainableat LevelKnife of ItzliPower Shot1Headdress of EhecatlPower Speed1Arrow of TezcatlipocaScatter Shot2Golden Scepter of HuitzilopochtliHealth RegenerationAmmo Regeneration2Scepter of CihuacoatlAmmo Regeneration3Two Arrows of TezcatlipocaHealth RegenerationScatter Shot3Scepter of HuitzilopochtliHealth Regeneration5Golden Scepter of CihuacoatlAmmo RegenerationScatter Shot5Golden Arrow of TezcatlipocaPower ShotScatter Shot6Three Arrows of TezcatlipocaPower BombScatter Shot6Eye of CipactliPower Bomb7Golden Eye of CipactliPower BombPower Speed7Golden Knife of ItzliPower ShotPower Bomb9Mask of ItzliPower ShotHealth RegenerationAmmo Regeneration9Mask of EhecatlPower SpeedHealth RegenerationAmmo Regeneration10Golden Shroud of CihuacoatlPower BombPower SpeedHealth RegenerationAmmo Regeneration10Mask of TezcatlipocaPower ShotPower BombScatter Shot12Fist of TezcatlipocaPower ShotPower BombScatter ShotAmmo Regeneration12Mask of CipactliPower BombPower SpeedHealth Regeneration13Mask of XolotlPower ShotPower BombPower SpeedScatter ShotHealth RegenerationAmmo Regeneration13WeaponsBesides Totec's Spear (which is the player's primary weapon if going solo through the campaign) there's also a wide array of weaponry in the game, each with their own characteristics.WeaponPower(worst - 1 to 10 - best)Rate of Fire(worst - 1 to 8 - best)Ammo Consumption(best - 1 to 10 - worst)Obtainableat LevelHandgun22infinitedefaultMagnums3321Assault Rifle3422Shotgun4232Bolt Action Rifle6242Automatic Shotgun4332Flamethrower5533Fast Action Rifle6343AR-064424Lightweight Machine Pistols4535Double Barrel Shotgun6245Grenade Launcher7266Hand Cannons6256High Power Assault Rifle6437Automatic Pistols6327High Power Flamethrower6548High Power Single Shot Rifle8259Submachine Gun5759Chaingun68410Spear of Fire72610Rocket Launcher91811Heavy Grenade Launcher82711Dual Submachine Gun68412Railgun101712High Power Shotgun83613Golden Shotgun93713Spear of Light1021014Spear of Darkness1021014Unlockable OutfitsThere are a total of 6 Lara Croft outfits present in the game, but 5 of them are only available upon achieving certain objectives within the game.OutfitUnlockable upon...Lara Croft (default)Starting / Default OutfitJungleAccumulating an overall total of 1.410.000 pointsBikerAccumulating an overall total of 1.900.000 pointsDoppelgangerAccumulating an overall total of 2.400.000 pointsLegendDefeating XolotlJungle (heavy variant)Finishing the game for the first timeDLCsAdditionally, publisher Square Enix has announced five DLC packs to be released before the end of the year. The first three being new levels and the last two being character packs. The first of which is the Kane and Lynch character pack, and the second is the Legacy of Kain pack. Not only do they change the appearance of the characters, they change the dialog and story. For example, the Kane and Lynch one involves the dastardly duo finding the mirror two days after Lara leaves, and swear filled adventure ensues (with the swears comically bleeped out).LevelsThere are 13 levels in total, which with their very own different challenges.Temple of Light Temple GroundsSpider TombThe SummoningForgotten GateToxic SwampFlooded PassageThe Jaws of DeathTwisting BridgeFiery DepthsBelly of the BeastStronghold PassageThe Mirror's WakeXolotl's StrongholdConcept  Voice ActorsThe developers, although tactful in their attempt to separate Lara Croft and the Guardian of Light from the Tomb Raider franchise in their naming of the game, have remained true to the latest incarnations of the franchise by having actress Keeley Hawes continue in her voicing of Lara, since her first casting in Tomb Raider: Legend in 2006. Previous voice actresses since inception are Shelley Blond, Judith Gibbins  Jonell Elliot. The voices for Xolotl and Totec are both provided by veteran vocal talent Jim Cummings, who has over three hundred voice accreditations to his name, including Psycrow from Earthworm Jim, Urdnot Wreav from Mass Effect 2 and both Thor and Scorpion in Marvel: Ultimate Alliance 2.Avatar AwardsThis game will feature the following avatar awards.Mercenary Outfit (for male Avatars) - Complete the gameLara's Jungle Outfit (for female Avatars) - Complete the gameReleased originally on August 18th, 2010, for 1200 MS points on XBox Live Arcade, Lara Croft and the Guardian of Light was released later for PS3 and PC on September 28th, 2010.PC System RequirementsOS: Windows 7 / Vista / XPProcessor: 3 GHz Intel or 2.5 GHZ AMDMemory: 1 GB RAM (XP) / 2 GB RAM (Vista)Graphics: NVIDIA GeForce 6 Series (6800GT or better) / ATI 1300XT or betterHard Drive: 7GBSound: DirectX 9.0c compatible sound card and drivers</description><genres><genre id="31">Dual-Joystick Shooter</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="32378">Dimensity</game><game id="32416">DeathSpank: Thongs of Virtue</game><game id="8098">Neo Contra</game><game id="33846">Hamilton's Great Adventure</game><game id="41568">Dungeon Bandit</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3661/1470593-lara_croft_cover_by_spaghettipopcorn.jpg</image></root>