<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30199</id><name>Angry Birds</name><description>OverviewThe game features 318 levels spread across 8 differently themed episodes, each of which sees you attempting to destroy the green pigs by firing various types of "angry birds" using a slingshot with touch controls. In each level, you can gain up to a three star score based rating, which depends upon on how much scenery you destroy and how many birds you have left over at the end.There are over 20 secret golden eggs hidden throughout the game. They can be earned by completing levels or by finding them in hidden locations in the levels and menus.Types of BirdsThere are eight types of bird in the game, and most have a special ability that is activated by tapping the screen.Red - The normal birdBlue - Splits into three and is more effective against ice blocks than other typesYellow - Speeds up and is more effective against wood blocks than other typesBlack - Acts as a time bomb which will explode several seconds after initial impact or upon tapping the screen. The explosion is especially effective against stone blocksWhite - Drops an egg bombGreen - Boomerangs backwardsBig Red - Is heavier and causes more damage than a normal red birdOrange - Inflates to many times its original sizeEpisodesPoached Eggs- 63 Levels- Released December 2009Mighty Hoax- 42 LevelsDanger Above- 45 LevelsThe Big Setup- 45 Levels- Released August 2010- Construction themeHam 'Em High- 48 Levels- Released February - March 2011- Wild West themeMine and Dine- 45 Levels- Released June - August 2011- Mine themeBirthday Party- 15 Levels- Released December 2011- 2 year anniversary celebrationSurf and Turf- 15 levels, with 30 more to be released- Released March 2012- Beach themeMighty Eagle Add-OnAnnounced on the official blog on December 23rd, 2010, the Mighty Eagle is available as an in-app purchase. The one-time cost is $0.99/£0.59/€0.79. The mighty eagle acts as a level skip on uncompleted levels, with a limit of 1 use per hour. On completed levels it adds an additional scoring system. If the player destroys 100% of the objects in the level with the eagle, a feather appears above the star ranking.AvailabilityThe game is downloadable on the iTunes App store, including the full paid version, a free 'Lite' version containing 12 levels and a HD version for the iPad.It can also be downloaded from:Nokia Ovi storePalm App CatalogueAndroid MarketplaceThe game has also been released for the PS3, PSP, PC and Windows Phone 7. A Nintendo DS version is also announced to be in the works.The price for PS3 (PlayStation 3) and PSP (PlayStation Portable) is $3.99. The game can be purchased off of the PSN (Playstation Network) store and Angry Birds is found under "mini".The game is free on Android Marketplace, although it is ad supported. It was also made available on the Google Chrome web store on May 6th 2011.AwardsIn an interview with VentureBeat in August 2010, it was revealed over 6.5 million copies of the full version had been downloaded on the iTunes store and the Lite version had been downloaded over 11 million times. The game has topped the paid App charts in the iTunes store in over 60 countries.The game won Rovio Mobile the 2010 Best New Download IP Award at the Develop Awards in Brighton.</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="32136">Helsing's Fire</game><game id="29901">Crush the Castle</game><game id="32994">Silly Bandz</game><game id="33470">Pandas vs Ninjas</game><game id="33909">Trucks and Skulls</game><game id="36240">Pirates vs. Ninjas vs. Zombies vs. Pandas</game><game id="36711">Where's My Water?</game><game id="37033">Amazing Breaker</game><game id="37365">Fragger</game><game id="37626">Gerbil Physics</game><game id="37672">Artillery</game><game id="37783">Toy Shot</game><game id="25388">Crazy Penguin Catapult</game><game id="38315">Sour Patch Kids: Sour Fling</game><game id="38111">Fibble – Flick ‘n’ Roll</game><game id="20993">Downstream Panic!</game><game id="37659">Wreckateer</game><game id="38256">Shark Dash</game><game id="38498">CastleStorm</game><game id="43464">Catapult King</game><game id="43647">Raving Rabbids Travel in Time</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2163507-box_ab.png</image></root>