<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30301</id><name>µTanks</name><description>GameplayIn uTanks you select one of four various tank colors. This will be your team. If you select another color, your rank will be reset making you become very loyal to your specific team. The gameplay in general consists of traversing a large battlefield in your tank, collecting various upgrades, keeping your fuel level up, placing mines, and destroying the opposing team. The game runs perpetually, with battles constantly occurring on open battlefield. There are no "matches" or "games", simply battles happening on a battlefield. War never changes.The BasicsFactions- There are four factions in uTanks, each represented by a different color: red, blue, orange and purple. Each faction fights against the other three for higher rank and higher positions on the leaderboards.Fuel- This is the equivalent of health in uTanks. It is also used for use of basic functions such as shooting, planting mines, and teleporting. Fuel can be found by radaring the area. If you run out of fuel during a battle your tank will be destroyed and you will respawn somewhere else on the map.Equipment- During the course of the game you'll come across various equipment. By picking up this equipment you receive either a new type of weapon or more uses for your radar mechanism. This can be found in boxes on the field by radaring.General Equipment Capacity- Often abbreviated GEC, maximum carrying capacity for equipment.Promotion Points- Often abbreviated PP, accumulated by attacking and deactivating enemy tanks. PP is required to rank up and to climb the leaderboard. The more PP you accumulate, the higher your ranking on the leaderboards will be.Map- The map allows you to view the position of enemy tanks and fuel barrels of 500 or higher. Clicking on the map teleports you to the coordinates clicked location.Mines- Mines are used to prevent an enemy from moving or teleporting to an area, such as fuel barrel or equipment locations. Enemy tanks may not teleport onto mines, and attempting to drive over mines will halt the enemy tank and cause damage to it. They will not hurt tanks of the same color, however. If the mines are of a different color they will be hidden unless revealed by radar. After being revealed, they can be destroyed by shooting with a standard shot.Radar- The radar is used to discover new fuel barrels, equipment, and enemy mines.EquipmentArmor Shield- Nullifies damage of one enemy shotDual Shot- Fires two shots at once, inflicting double the damageMissile Shot- Capable of firing over mountains and rocks, 1.5x normal damageHoming Missile- Locks on to the enemy and follows them to their next positionExtra Radar- Boosts normal radar to include the entire viewportTarget Beacon- Indicates the position of the targeted enemy on the mapRanksRankPPRequired DeactivationEquipment CapacityTarget BeaconRecruit200-201Private500-251Corporal1000-301Sergeant3000Corporal351Lieutenant7000Sergeant401Captain10000Lieutenant451Major12000Captain502Colonel15000Major553Brig. General20000Brig. General604General--655*PP and Deactivation requirements refer to promotion eligibility (ranking up).AwardsSingle Star- Achieve the rank of CaptainTwo Star- Achieve the rank of MajorThree Star- Achieve the rank of ColonelFour Star- Achieve the rank of Brigadier GeneralFive Star- Achieve the rank of GeneralBronze Bullet- Deactivate 100 enemy tanksSilver Bullet- Deactivate 200 enemy tanksGold Bullet- Deactivate 500 enemy tanksOnyx Bullet- Deactivate 1000 enemy tanksSingle Skull- Experience 20 deactivationsDouble Skull- Experience 50 deactivationsTriple Skull- Experience 100 deactivationsAgauos's Skull- Experience 200 deactivationsShining Sword- Play for 100 hours in one mapBattered Sword- Play for 200 hours in one mapBroken Sword- Play for 500 hours in one mapRusty Sword- Play for 1000 hours in one mapBronze Cup- Place third in a tournamentSilver Cup- Place second in a tournamentGold Cup- Place first in a tournament*Plating- Added to cup of highest ever placing with an additional top three placing in a tournament (bronze, silver, gold, onyx)Exterminator Award- Awarded for testing during uTanks Alpha and BetaCartographer Award- Awarded for designing a map that is selected for play in uTanksWar Correspondent- Awarded for special field correspondence and reporting for uTanks social media platformsPurple Heart- Awarded for winning an official uTanks creative design contestWebsiteThe game client is free to download and free to play. You can download the client and play the game at www.utanks.com.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18008">Combat Tanks</game><game id="5368">Combat</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/13/130547/1792662-logos_raw.png</image></root>