<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30330</id><name>Kingdoms of Amalur: Reckoning</name><description>OverviewKingdoms of Amalur: Reckoning is a large scale, node-based, open-world RPG developed by Big Huge Games  38 Studios. Its structure combines RPG systems of morality, conversation, loot gathering, leveling up, and crafting with third-person action combat involving weapon and and attack combinations all housed in a world of towns and dungeons cordoned-off into manageable sections.StoryKingdoms of Amalur: Reckoning begins with a short scene involving the disposal of the player's corpse, followed by the player's resurrection through The Well of Souls, invented by Fomorous Hugues, a gnome.At this point in the history of the Faelands, the ten year Crystal War is taking place. The Fae, an immortal elven race split into the growth of Summer and the decay of Winter, are in turmoil. One of the Winter Fae, Gadflow, has usurped the Winter Court and now leads his army of Tuatha Deohn in the destruction of the Faelands and Amalur itself.Gadflow's army changes the very makeup of Amalur. The Tuatha have become a third faction, unbalancing the strict harmony between Summer and Winter Fae. They are unmitigated evil, given no sympathy by any character and acting as pure, immortal agressors in a seemingly hopeless war.The player's character enters this world as another agent of change. Whether the player chooses to breed chaos or order, the player is resurrected as The Fateless One. With total agency, the player is the only character unbound by the chains of destiny. Thus, the responsibility of the world falls upon the player's shoulders.FactionsWarswornA band of once-legendary warriors turned mercenaries, though they still consider themselves more. In the midst of the new war, an ancient enemy of the Warsworn returns.House of BalladsHome to the Summer Fae, is in the midst of the Telling - the cycle of ballads each Fae lives out in unending succession. The player finds a place within the House.The TravellersA famous throughout Amalur, known for their skills in trade and thievery. They have three main camps – Star Camp, Moon Camp and Sun Camp.Scholia ArcanaThe Faelands' mages' guild, home to students and scholars of all things strange and magical.House of SorrowsThe home to the Winter Fae.DevelopmentThe game is set in the region around FaelandsThe team that developed Reckoning consisted of several industry veterans as well as several Bethesda alumni. The game's art was developed by Todd McFarlane and its fiction by R.A. Salvatore. Ken Rolston (Lead Designer of Oblivion) is credited as executive producer. As part of the creative process for the Amalur franchise, Salvatore developed nearly 10,000 years of history and asked the developers to pick a point in which to set the game.Earlier known as Project Mercury, development on Reckoning started at Big Huge Games while it was still owned by THQ. In 2009, Curt Schilling's 38 Studios rescued Big Huge games from its closure by THQ. On March 9, 2010, Electronic Arts announced a new publishing deal for the game and credited the close relationship between Curt Schilling and EA Sports' Peter Moore as the catalyst for the deal. The game was expected to receive strong support from EA's own BioWare team.During E3 2011 the developers showed a gameplay feature and chat that can be found here.GameplayDestinyShadowcaster Destiny: A mage/rogue hybridReckoning's base combat skill progression model is the standard warrior, rogue and mage skill trees, each of which improve combat with a given weapon set as well as provide additional active and passive skills for combat use. The weapon skills bound to each tree are the following:Might - Unlocks special abilities with longsword, greatsword, and hammers.Finesse - Unlocks special abilities with dagger, "faeblades", and longbow.Sorcery - Unlocks special abilities with staff, sceptre, and chakrams.Based on the ratio of talent points invested in these trees, the destiny system unlocks special dynamic classes that grants players additional special abilities and passive bonuses corresponding to their playstyle. These bonuses include increased damage for a certain type of attack, better movement during combat, additional health or mana regeneration, etc. Destinies are available for each combination of skill trees, including one for the jack-of-all-trades player.CombatA Fate Shift KillThe combat is based on timing and combos. This can include single-weapon timing combos as well as the inclusion of secondary weapon attacks and activated skills. Timing moves more effectively can juggle enemies, and the use of combos and skills increases a fate meter. Activating the player's fate shift begins bullet-time event and slowly drains the fate meter to zero. During this bullet-time, the player has vastly increased power and, at the conclusion of the meter or by activation, the bullet-time event ends in a button mash quick time events that provides additional experience based on the player's effectiveness.Parrying, blocking, and dodging are also core to the action. With appropriate investment in a skill tree, the player can unlock special attacks with their primary and secondary weapon out of parry, dodge, and block, and each of these avoidance/mitigation moves can leave enemies vulnerable to longer juggle combos. Certain passive bonuses found in the skill trees can cause extra damaging or utility effects during a dodge or mutate the dodge into a short-range teleport.LootPlayers can forge new items with BlacksmithingLoot is an important part of character development and improves magic and weapon fighting abilities. By and large, based on its type, loot will give bonuses to a particular play style, i.e. heavy armor benefits might and block effectiveness, medium armor is primarily intended for finesse and increases crit damage, and light armor benefits mana regeneration for sorcery-invested players.Inserting tradeskill-created gems into weapons and armor is also possible; for example, inserting a magical fire gem into a long sword will create a flaming sword. Players will also find components in the world and/or break down gear and use the resulting ingredients to create better weapons.SkillsThere are nine passive skill trees players can invest in to improve their non-combat characteristics:Alchemy - Grants players the ability to harvest reagents and create potions. More points increases the chance of successfully harvesting reagents.Blacksmithing - Allows players to repair their own weapons and equipment, as well as forge new ones. It also increases the effectiveness of repair kits.Detect Hidden - Gives players an increased chance of finding treasures and detecting traps, ambushes and secret doors. It also increases the amount of gold found while exploring.Dispelling - Allows players to dispel harmful magical spells and wards/locks without taking damage. More points in this tree increase its effectiveness.Lockpicking - Provides mastery over mechanical locks. More points increase its effectiveness.Mercantile - Improves the character's bargaining skill, allowing them to sell at higher price point while buying for less.Persuasion - Increases the character's odds of talking out of any situation.Sagecraft - Improves the character's ability to craft all sorts of gems, useful to enchant weapons and armour.Stealth - Grants players the ability to stay hidden and pickpocket others.Playable RacesAlmainThe AlmainCity and Homeland -- Port Myria, Amere ValleyRacial Bonuses - Blacksmithing (+2), Persuasion (+1) and Alchemy (+1)Noble and honorable, the Almain are humans who reject the chaotic aspects of life, always looking to input structure and ritual into everything they do. The Almain have a long and illustrious military tradition and their patron deity is Mitharu, the god of Order.LjosalfarThe LjosalfarCity and Homeland -- Fieriol, Glen Suthain (the Eternal Vale)Racial Bonuses - Sagecraft (+1), Dispelling (+2) and Alchemy (+1)Steadfast and uncompromising, this proud and insular race strives to preserve Nature and shape it to their will. The light elves resist change and revel in the principle of Justice, fighting time and time again to defend Amalur against the forces of chaos and darkness.DokkalfarThe DokkalfarCity and Homeland -- Rathir, Plains of ErathellRacial Bonuses - Sagecraft (+1), Persuasion (+1) and Stealth (+2)Charismatic, intelligent and seductive, the Dokkalfar are regarded as prominent students of both magic and diplomacy, yet it is their enticing presence that makes them so enthralling. The dark elves are the natural born manipulators, and will often control the actions of others from the backstage.VaraniThe VaraniCity and Homeland -- NoneRacial Bonuses - Detect Hidden(+1), Mercantile(+1) and Lockpicking (+2)The Varani clans are mostly consisted of nomadic traders and mercenaries. These humans may not be as culturally educated as the Almain, but they were nonetheless key to bringing commerce and a certain degree of civilization to the wilds of the Faelands.Non-Playable RacesGnomeThe GnomesCity and Homeland -- Adessa, DetyreDetermined and ingenious, the Gnomes are above all, practical and pragmatic. Highly intellectual, they tend to take a rational approach to all kind of situations. The Gnome society is divided into three sects: the Scholars (inventors of magical devices), the Praetorians (a military force known for their martial skills) and the Templars (the political strategists who set the agenda for their culture).Regarded as a secretive race, the Gnomes are often the topic of conversation, as other races wonder what kind of secrets and motives the gnomes keep for themselves.Seelie (Summer Fae)The Summer FaeCity and Homeland - Gardens of Ysa, DalentarthClaiming to be creatures from beyond the Veil, the Summer Fae represents growth, warmth and the coming of new seasons  life. They hold no mortal desires and simply wish to serve their role in the Great Cycle.Unseelie (Winter Fae)The Winter FaeCity and Homeland - Bhaile, AlabastraThough grim in nature, the Unseelie are not to be mistaken for evil. These elvish folks simply represent the passing of the seasons and death in the endless Great cycle. Their order is in turmoil after a recent coup by the zealot Gadflow, with a few remaining traditionalists refusing his rule and still clinging to their peaceful ways.Tuatha DeohnThe TuathaCity and Homeland - Bhaile, AlabastraA brutal and aggressive subsect of the Winter Fae, led by their new king Gadflow. They're driven by their devotion to a new god and have declared war on the rest of the mortal races in Amalur. They are relentless and once a Tuatha soldier falls in battle, his place is quickly taken by another from the Hollows.MusicThe Album Art for the Games SoundtrackMusic is by Viva Piñata and Banjo Kazooie: Nuts  Bolts composer Grant Kirkhope. In an interview, Kirkhope said he had never really worked on a game like Reckoning in terms of its breath and scope but was happy to undertake the challenge. The soundtrack was released on February 7 and is available on Amazon and iTunes. Players who bought either the Collector's or Signature Edition of the game were treated to a copy of the soundtrack as well.Track ListingReckoning Main ThemeThe Age Of ArcanaDead's EndWell of SoulsTrollDalentarthHouse of BalladsWarswornMines and CavesGardens of YsaNiskaruTitarionThe Plains of ErathellScholia ArcanaRathirFight!DetyreHouse of ValourAdessaThe Erathi RuinsConflictThe ShipsMel SenshirTo WarThe StrongholdsBalorIt Ends HereKlurikonHouse of SorrowsFae HollowsAlabastraBhaileGadflowHeart of AmethynTirnochDemo and Mass Effect 3 cross promotionCrossover Promotional ArtStarting on January 17, 2012 a demo for Kingdoms of Amalur: Reckoning was released on all three platforms (Xbox 360, PlayStation 3 and PC). Playing through the demo unlocked exclusive items for use in the full game. More interestingly it also granted players items for use in Mass Effect 3. And, vice versa, playing the Mass Effect 3 demo granted items to use in the full game of Kingdoms of Amalur: Reckoning:Chakram Launcher - By playing the Reckoning demo and watching the included video in its entirety, the Chakram Launcher unlocked in Mass Effect 3.Reckoner Knight Armor - By playing the Reckoning demo, the Reckoner Knight Armor (Todd McFarlane-designed Warsworn armor) unlocked in Mass Effect 3."Confident" Twist of Fate Card - The "Confident" Twist of Fate Card unlocked by installing the Reckoning demo and linking an Origin account within the demo.Infernal Helm - The Infernal Helm unlocked after completing the Reckoning Mode Tutorial in the Reckoning demo.Twinned Souls Chakram - The Twinned Souls Chakram are unlocked by installing the Reckoning demo and linking an Origin account within the demo.Omniblade Daggers - By playing the Mass Effect 3 demo, the Omniblade Daggers become unlocked in Reckoning.PC System RequirementsMinimumRecommendedOS: Windows XP/Vista/7Processor: Intel Core2 Duo (or equivalent) running at 2.2GHz or greaterAMD Athlon 64 X2 5000+ (or equivalent) running at 2.6GHz or greaterRAM: At least 1 GB for Windows XPAt least 2 GB for Windows Vista and Windows 7Graphics card: NVIDIA GeForce 8800 GT 512MB or betterATI Radeon HD3650 512MB or betterSupporting Pixel Shader 3.0Minimum Resolution Supported is 1280x720Sound Card: DirectX CompatibleDirectX: DirectX 9.0cHard Drive: At least 10.5 GB of free spaceOS: Windows XP/Vista/7Processor: Intel Core 2 Quad (or equivalent) running at 2.4GHz or greaterAMD Phenom X4 (or equivalent) running at 2.6GHz or greaterRAM: At least 3 GB for Windows XPAt least 4 GB for Windows Vista and Windows 7Graphics card: NVIDIA GeForce GTX260 1GB RAM or betterATI Radeon HD4850 1GB RAM or betterSupporting Pixel Shader 3.0Sound Card: DirectX CompatibleDirectX: DirectX 9.0cHard Drive: At least 10.5 GB of free spaceCollector and Signature EditionsKingdom's of Amalur: Reckoning has 2 collector's Editions available exclusively through their own site. The collector's Edition price was set at $200, limited to 700 units and includes the following:Kingdoms of Amalur: Reckoning (Xbox 360, PlayStation 3, or PC).12.5" Limited Edition Prismere Troll Figure by McFarlane Toys.Original lithograph signed by Ken Rolston.Map of Amalur's Faelands.Amalur themed 7-Piece dice set and bag.Full set of 40 Destiny Cards.Kingdom's of Amalur: Reckoning - The Soundtrack.Bonus DLC- Fate-Touched Weapons Pack.For those ultimate Reckoning Fans they also had a Signature Edition for $275 that includes everything above plus:1 of 300 Limited Edition Todd McFarlane sketch screen-prints.Signed Troll Figure (signed either by Todd McFarlane, R. A. Salvatore or Curt Schilling and numbered 1 to 300 (Retail $175)).Pre-Order BonusesDestinies Choice Pack (Play.com, GameStop.com)- unique Twist of Fate card- Compass of Fate- 3 armour sets: Melee, Finesse and SorceryThe Ultimate Treasure Hunter Pack (Amazon.com)- a dowsing rod for making all reagents (potion-making vegetation) visible on the mapThe Fate Touched Weapons Pack (Amazon.com, GameStop.com)- 9 different weapons "touched by Fate's hand"Three Team Fortress 2 hats (Steam), no other items.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3264">Fable</game><game id="6959">God of War</game><game id="20238">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion</game><game id="33394">The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim</game><game id="34776">Dragon's Dogma</game><game id="27878">Fable III</game><game id="41344">Dragon's Dogma: Dark Arisen</game><game id="35668">Of Orcs and Men</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2121648-box_koar.png</image></root>