<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30374</id><name>Sam &amp; Max Episode 305: The City That Dares Not Sleep</name><description>Story If I had tentacles for a beard, I'd be annoyed, too     The game picks up where the previous episode,  Beyond the Alley of the Dolls, left off:  Max is now a giant monster, trashing the city and it's up to  Sam to stop him.  After rounding up his team, including Momma Bosco, pregnant  Sybil,  Superball,  Mr. Featherly,  Papierwaite and  Mr. Norrington, Sam turns  the Desoto into a giant  corndog and gets swallowed by giant Max, ticking off  Beelzebub and  Jurgen in the process. Who knew that Max's insides are a collection of nicely furnished rooms connected via a series of tubes? Sam discovers that a brain tumor is causing the trouble. On a side note,  The Narrator is actually Max's super-ego who is frustrated because the body it's in does not use its full potential to explore the secrets of the universe, or something. All it wants is to let it all end. With a psychic explosion taking out the north-eastern part of the country. Sybil would cut it out of the brain along with the tumor, but alas! Dark matter inside it can only be destroyed using the Toy Robot, currently in Skun-ka'pe's possession. Tricking the general into throwing the Toy of Destiny into his hands, Sam enables Sybil to perform the brain surgery.  Suddenly, Mrs. Lincoln-Pandemic's water breaks and she refuses to have her baby inside a horrible monster. Meanwhile, that horrible monster commits a selfless act and orders everyone to save Sybil!Thus, Max sneezes everyone out, not forgetting the Desoto, and, right before the last  maimtron is able to annihilate the entire City with him,  teleports away. Where to? Let's say that  Stinky and  Skun-ka'pe weren't expecting that call.  Back at the cloning facility, Momma Bosco tries to cook up one hyperkinetic rabbit-thing from some snot, but it turns out that Max's DNA is just too weird to reproduce. Superball runs out crying, and Sam walks out with the credits rolling, devastated, and mourns his buddy at the sight of the beheaded  Statue of Liberty.  Until a past Max pops up in a  time-travelling elevator, and both walk into the sunset. Or time-travel to stop crime. Depends on your dialogue choice, multiple endings and all.PC System RequirementsOperating system: Windows XP / Vista / Windows 7 Processor: 2.0 GHz (3 GHz Pentium 4 or equivalent rec.) Memory: 1GB Sound: DirectX 8.1 sound device Video: 128MB DirectX 8.1-compliant video card (256MB rec.) DirectX(TM): Version 9.0c or better Mac System Requirements:Operating Systems: Mac OS X 10.5 or newerProcessor: Intel Core 2 Duo processor Not Recommended For: Macs with integrated graphics        </description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26776">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 1: Launch of the Screaming Narwhal</game><game id="27084">Strong Bad's Cool Game for Attractive People</game><game id="21670">Wallace &amp; Gromit's Grand Adventures Episode 1: Fright of the Bumblebees</game><game id="10837">Bone: Out from Boneville</game><game id="10505">Bone: The Great Cow Race</game><game id="25467">Wallace &amp; Gromit's Grand Adventures Episode 2: The Last Resort</game><game id="25468">Wallace &amp; Gromit's Grand Adventures Episode 3: Muzzled</game><game id="25469">Wallace &amp; Gromit's Grand Adventures Episode 4: The Bogey Man</game><game id="10528">Monkey Island 2:  LeChuck's Revenge</game><game id="3019">The Secret of Monkey Island</game><game id="26778">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 3: Lair of the Leviathan</game><game id="26779">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 4: The Trial and Execution of Guybrush Threepwood</game><game id="26780">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 5: Rise of the Pirate God</game><game id="23066">Strong Bad's Cool Game for Attractive People Episode 2: Strong Badia The Free</game><game id="24203">Strong Bad's Cool Game for Attractive People Episode 4: Dangeresque 3: The Criminal Projective</game><game id="23778">Strong Bad's Cool Game for Attractive People Episode 3: Baddest of the Bands</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8169/1491401-episode5.jpg</image></root>