<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30372</id><name>Sam &amp; Max Episode 303: They Stole Max's Brain</name><description>PlotThe game starts where the last ended. Sam staring at the body of Max, minus his brain. Sam snaps and becomes and noir style anti- hero. Sam cuts a path through the city, interrogating seedy underworld types, jobless apes and foreign tourists along the way. Sam is directed to the cities museum, and finds General Shun-ka'pe and Aton Paperwaite fighting in the Planetarium.The museum's night guard, Sal, tells Sam that he should move the brainless body of Max before he disposes of it. Sam puts a brain he found in a jar in the Egyptian exhibit of the museum. The brain of the Egyptian pharaoh Sammun-Mak, who featured in the last episode 'The Devil's Playhouse'. Sammun-Mak also has the same psychic powers as Max and is able to use the toys to drive a wedge between General Shun-ka'pe and Aton Paperwaite. The pair erupt into a firefight and Sam is able to reach Max's brain. However, Sammun-Mak notices the Devil's Toybox and opens it. White light spills out of it.Sam and Max stand infront of a huge statue of Sammun-Mak still in Max's body. It appears Sammun-Mak has changed reality to make him ruler of the world. Sam has no memory of his other life although Max remembers everything. Max locates a group of rebels who want to put things back to normal. They instruct Max to use the Brain Screw on Sammun-Mak. But first need to get close to him. Max leads Sam around eventually collecting three special amulets. These amulets allow the duo to have a special audience with Sammun-Mak. After Sam fights General Shun-ka'pe, Max instructs Sam into using the Brain Screw on Sammun-Mak.Reality returns to normal. Sam and Max are back in the Planetarium. Sam puts Max's brain back in his body and just when things seemed like they were better, an army of Sam Clones burst into the Planetarium.The Devils Playhouse continues in Episode 4 " Beyond the Alley of the Dolls"PC RequirementsOperating System: Microsoft® Windows® XP/VistaProcessor: 2.0 Ghz or better (3 GHz Pentium® 4 or equivalent recommended)Memory: 512 MB RAM (1GB recommended)Hard Disk Space: 310 MBVideo Card: 64 MB DirectX® 8.1 compliant video card (128 MB recommended)Sound Card: DirectX® 8.1 sound deviceDirectX® Version: DirectX® Version 9.0c or better (DirectX updater included)Controller Support: YesNo internet connection required to play</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26778">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 3: Lair of the Leviathan</game><game id="21670">Wallace &amp; Gromit's Grand Adventures Episode 1: Fright of the Bumblebees</game><game id="25467">Wallace &amp; Gromit's Grand Adventures Episode 2: The Last Resort</game><game id="25468">Wallace &amp; Gromit's Grand Adventures Episode 3: Muzzled</game><game id="25469">Wallace &amp; Gromit's Grand Adventures Episode 4: The Bogey Man</game><game id="10528">Monkey Island 2:  LeChuck's Revenge</game><game id="3019">The Secret of Monkey Island</game><game id="26776">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 1: Launch of the Screaming Narwhal</game><game id="26777">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 2: The Siege of Spinner Cay</game><game id="26779">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 4: The Trial and Execution of Guybrush Threepwood</game><game id="26780">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 5: Rise of the Pirate God</game><game id="20587">Strong Bad's Cool Game for Attractive People Episode 1: Homestar Ruiner</game><game id="23066">Strong Bad's Cool Game for Attractive People Episode 2: Strong Badia The Free</game><game id="23778">Strong Bad's Cool Game for Attractive People Episode 3: Baddest of the Bands</game><game id="24203">Strong Bad's Cool Game for Attractive People Episode 4: Dangeresque 3: The Criminal Projective</game><game id="10505">Bone: The Great Cow Race</game><game id="10837">Bone: Out from Boneville</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8169/1444947-episode3.jpg</image></root>