<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30370</id><name>Sam &amp; Max Episode 302: The Tomb of Sammun-Mak</name><description>This episode of Sam and Max: Season 3 follows Sam and Max's great-grandparents, Sameth and Maximus, after they discover a supernatural movie projector. The duo are on a quest to recover the Devil's Toybox, the central item to the season's stories.Psychic powers return for Maximus as well as Telltale's signature humorous interactions.PlotIntroIn this chapter of The Devil’s Playhouse, Sam and Max have discovered a pair of skeletons that look just like them, the Astral Projector, and several reels of film in their building’s basement. The film contains the last adventure of Sam and Max’s great-grandfathers, Sameth and Maximus.Sameth and MaximusThe first reel Sam and Max play begins in the Tomb of Sammun-Mak, as Sameth and Maximus make their escape with The Devil’s Toybox from Nicholas St. Kringle. Using Maximus’ psychic abilities, they fool Kringle so that they can make it to the exit. Just before they make it, Kringle catches up to them, and shortly after the film ends in a cliff-hanger.To solve the mystery of the skeletons, as well as how their predecessors escape, Sam and Max must jump between each of the remaining film reels, each containing their own sub-plot.Reel 1In early 1900s , Sameth and Maximus go to a show hosted by Anton Papierwaite featuring The Sphunx Challenge, the prize of which is a trip to the Tomb of Sammun-Mak in Egypt where the mysterious Devil’s Toybox is kept. In the theatre, Sameth and Maximus meet Nicholas St. Kringle, a toy manufacturing tycoon, who also wants to beat the challenge and find the Toybox for himself. They also discover that Maximus has psychic abilities upon discovering a can of nuts, which happens to be a Toy of Power. After retrieving the can, and discovering the secret to the Sphunx Challenge, Sameth and Maximus are on their way to Egypt.Reel 2While aboard the Disorient Express on their way to Egypt, Sameth and Maximus discover they have a stowaway: the blabber-mouth Baby Amelia Earhart. They somehow lose their tickets just as the conductor comes to their cabin. They manage to shut Amelia up and hide just before the conductor opens the door.Aboard the Disorient ExpressWhen they arrive at the Tomb, they must overcome several molemen and their curses in able to retrieve the Toybox. Once there, they meet Jurgen, an explorer from Stuttgart, who was also after the Toybox until he became the victim of a curse. Once freed of the curse by Sameth and Maximus, he flees. They also collect a new Toy: the dummy, which allows Maximus to use psychic ventriloquism.Reel 3After Sameth and Maximus escape the Tomb, they find themselves once again on the Disorient Express, this time headed home. Shortly after, they find The Devil’s Toybox has gone missing; stolen by someone on board. They manage to search through the luggage of Kringle and his elves, the molemen, who have decided to move to America, and Jurgen, but are unable to find it. They figure out that the last person they expected is the culprit: Baby Amelia. After an anticlimactic battle, Sameth and Maximus are able to retrieve the Toybox once again.Reel 4Papierwaite and the Sphunx ChallengeBack at Papierwaite’s theater, Samus and Maximus tell Papierwaite and the audience how they managed to get the Toybox from the Tomb. Papierwaite then turns on them, capturing Sameth and forcing Maximus to use The Devil’s Toybox to summon Yog Soggoth. They manage to trick him into saying the last phrase of the spell, and after a magical explosion, Papierwaite is gone. All seems normal, and they go to visit the molemen, who have moved into the boiler room. They give them the Toybox and promise that their future children will use the office upstairs. When the molemen try to add another layer of protection to the Toybox, Sameth and Maximus are caught in the spell and turned into the skeletons seen at the start of the chapter.FinaleAfter the fourth reel is complete, Sam leaves briefly and Max impatiently watches the final reel. When Sam returns, he discovers, to his horror, that Max’s head has been cut open and his brain removed.PC RequirementsOperating System: Microsoft® Windows® XP/VistaProcessor: 2.0 Ghz or better (3 GHz Pentium® 4 or equivalent recommended)Memory: 512 MB RAM (1GB recommended)Hard Disk Space: 310 MBVideo Card: 64 MB DirectX® 8.1 compliant video card (128 MB recommended)Sound Card: DirectX® 8.1 sound deviceDirectX® Version: DirectX® Version 9.0c or better (DirectX updater included)Controller Support: YesNo internet connection required to play</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26778">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 3: Lair of the Leviathan</game><game id="26776">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 1: Launch of the Screaming Narwhal</game><game id="26779">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 4: The Trial and Execution of Guybrush Threepwood</game><game id="26780">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 5: Rise of the Pirate God</game><game id="26777">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 2: The Siege of Spinner Cay</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8169/1379116-sammun.png</image></root>