<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30475</id><name>Minecraft</name><description>OverviewFully released on November 18th, 2011, Minecraft is a game based around mining various kinds of minerals out of the ground and then building things using those minerals. The game is played from a first-person perspective with the ability to toggle to third-person. The game was originally developed by Markus "Notch" Persson and his development studio, Mojang AB, and is now under the direction of Jens "Jeb" Bergensten. Music and sound design is provided by Daniel "C418" Rosenfeld.Since the Alpha stage of development, Minecraft has received much attention and critical acclaim. Minecraft officially broke the two-million sales mark on April 23, 2011, while still in Beta. As of April 27, 2012, more than twenty-seven million accounts have been registered, and the game has sold nearly eight million copies.DevelopmentMinecraft Classic"Creative"Notch began development of a "cave game" on May 10, 2009. Over the next week he designed a very basic engine, using his own physics, lighting, and fluid dynamics. Worlds were automatically generated on first spawn from May 16 on. On May 17, the game entered distributed from Minecraft.net with free and premium accounts allowing premium users to save levels and spawn points on a server supported by Notch. Multiplayer support was added on June 8, and support for customized skins was added on June 14. The Classic version now available for free on the Minecraft website is version 0.0.23a_01, released on July 12.Survival TestAugust 4th saw the introduction of "Survival Mode" as a new style of play. The player spawned with no items and had an inventory with limited space; blocks could be broken to yield items to build with. Hostile "mobs" (mobiles) such as skeletons, zombies and spiders spawned in the dark and attacked the player. Rain was also added as the first kind of variable weather. The addition of TNT made it possible for the player to put up slightly more of a defense. Minecraft took its last steps of initial development with the addition of a dynamic lighting engine on December 22.Early DevelopmentIndevThe Indev (In Development) stage of Minecraft's life brought it closest to the game it is currently, adding inventory, crafting, specialized tools, torches, smelting, and enhanced A.I. Indev levels could be generated to different themes, such as general weather conditions or even levels resembling heaven and hell. Players were spawned in a rectangular house stocked with the supplies they needed to thrive in the Minecraft world. Indev also saw the addition of farming to Minecraft, which gave players and alternative early in the game to restore health.InfdevNotch's purpose for Infdev (Infinite Development) was to create a viable procedural generation system from Minecraft. The system was first tested on February 27, 2010, and went through numerous changes until the advent of Alpha in late June of 2010. Though Infdev was comprised primarily of improvements to physics and appearance, there were also numerous content additions including signs, doors, ladders, mine carts, and mob drops.Minecraft AlphaThough technically on the same development cycle as Indev and Infdev, Notch gave the game the "Alpha" suffix to indicate that the game was now moving at full speed toward release. The vast majority of Minecraft's content additions took place during Alpha, often through "Seecret Friday" updates where Notch intentionally neglected to provide the players with changelists so they could find the additions themselves. The addition of redstone and device automation marked a significant milestone in players' ability to customize structures and streamline simple actions such as opening doors. The game was also provided with a logic engine allowing players to build computers and other complex devices. Mob A.I. received yet another upgrade in order to prevent pathing into lava or off cliffs. The first visible biomes began to generate into new worlds, with snowfall in cold places and cacti in deserts. The number of placeable blocks now exceeded fifty.Perhaps one of the biggest milestones in Minecraft's development, Survival Multiplayer (SMP), was patched in on August 4, 2010. In preparation for a massive update, Minecraft received mostly insignificant tweaks and bug fixes for about the next month and a half. On October 4th, the Minecraft Halloween update was announced promising new blocks, new mobs, fishing, and a brand-new biome generator. Most importantly, though, the Halloween update added the Nether to the game; a hellish realm flooded with lava and filled with enemy mobs. The update was applied on October 30th and remains one of the most significant updates in the game's history. The Halloween update also caused a massive number of bugs leading Notch to use the next few months as bug fix time. Most actual updates occurring during this time were esoteric or involved minor game mechanics which did not noticeably alter gameplay.Minecraft BetaMinecraft entered Beta on December 20th, 2010. The Beta development period had a wealth of content additions as well as the tweaking of gameplay balance. As Mojang grew, each subsequent major update had a longer and longer changelist. The Beta stage -- especially from 1.5 on -- saw massive improvements to gameplay in mob A.I., inventory management and environment generation. The game's code was overhauled to allow for an improved block I.D. assignment system and a statistics tracker which allowed the insertion of achievements. Update 1.6's changelist contains more than 100 bug fixes in preparation for the next massive update drop.The Adventure UpdateAnnounced on June 10, 2011, and implemented on September 14th with Beta 1.8, the Adventure Update was designed to make Minecraft feel much more like an RPG by adding hunger, experience and a multitude of new mobs, blocks, biomes and random structures. The combat system received a massive face-lift as well, allowing players to sprint and adding a drawback system for bows. Critical hits could be performed by jumping and hitting a mob on the way down, and mobs could be knocked back a long distance by sprinting and hitting them. The adventure update also added Creative Mode to compensate players who wanted only to build and not be bothered by the hunger system.The Sound UpdateThe majority of the work for the so-called "Sound Update" was done by "C418." The patch did not alter gameplay whatsoever, and was silently applied on November 13th. It provided new sounds for chests, doors, fence gates, trapdoors, fishing rods and explosions; as well as a slew of new mob sounds and different injury sounds for the player which were controversial due to the attachment players felt to Steve's signature "ooh" each time he was hurt.Full releaseOn his blog, Notch announced that Minecraft's "Full" release date was nigh. Leaving beta, the plan was for Minecraft to reach "Release" on 11/11/11. Though due to scheduling conflicts with Minecon the date was moved one week to 11/18/11. Notch stated that the chances are that the game will be very close to what it is now and that this date is merely a goal for the studio.The game is currently in the Beta stage, but allows users to pre-order the full version of the game for 75 percent of the price -- currently or This allows early access into many of the games features.The game is also now able to be "gifted." As of December 12, 2010, there are now gift codes available for purchase for the same price as retail. Also, these gift codes can be purchased in packs of 1-10.A demo version of Minecraft was released on April 19th, available to download from http://www.pcgamer.com/2011/04/19/download-the-minecraft-demo that allows you to play Minecraft in its entirety with all options available to you for 90 minutes -- at which point the demo period expires and the player can no longer play for free.A version of the game was announced for the Xbox 360 at E3 2011. The game now has an official release date of May 9th, as part of the Arcade NEXT promotion. Kinect support is being patched in at a later, TBA date.Minecraft was officially released live on stage at Minecon in Las Vegas with Notch pulling the lever to signify its transition into a retail product.A retail Xbox 360 version arrived on June 4th in the United States for $20. The disc-based game includes all the features and content found in the current XBLA version, as well as the addition coming in the ninth title update. With an internet connection the disc version will also receive "all the same content and feature updates as the digital version ongoing." In 2013 in a closely followed announcements Minecraft was said to be targeting releases for the Xbox One, Playstation 3, Playstation Vita, and Playstation 4 in the near future.Xbox Live RefundsXBLA players can use split-screen, but only on HD displaysThe Xbox Live Arcade iteration of the title features split-screen multiplayer, but requires a high-definition television. As this was understated in the title's original synopsis, Microsoft has added the text "To experience split-screen functionality a high-definition television is required.", alongside offering refunds to those who have complained via customer support.Furthermore, Microsoft issued this statement."We updated our pre-sale notification to inform customers that an HD screen is required for the split-screen multiplayer feature on Minecraft: Xbox 360 Edition. If a player does not have an HD screen and purchased this game prior to the notification update, they are eligible for a full refund through customer support."Gameplay BasicsNote: all gameplay info is for Beta mode, not Classic. However, some of the info still applies.Starting OutWhen creating a new game in Minecraft, a world is generated and the player is spawned at a random spot. That spot is the player's spawn point and will remain his fixed spawn point until the player rests in a bed. From that point on the bed becomes his new spawn point. The world continues to generate around the player in all directions for a while, and as the player move around the world more of the world will be generated. The world is stored in 16x16 squares of blocks, called chunks. The world is created of same-sized blocks. The most common of these are dirt, sand and stone. Everything in Minecraft revolves around these blocks and obtaining them and even crafting them into useful items.To collect blocks, just hold left-click on a block and cracks will appear in the block. If you continue to hold left-click until the cracks fill the block, the block will shatter dropping a miniature version of itself (or a particular material depending on the block type). The time it takes to collect a block depends on the block you are collecting and the tool (if any) that you are using. Most mineral-based blocks will require the proper tool to be harvested (stone will not yield cobblestone unless mined with a pick, snow tiles will not yield snowballs unless harvested with a shovel, etc.). Once collected, initial blocks will be placed into the player's hotbar (from left to right), with spillover collecting into the rest of the player's inventory. To place a block, equip it in the hotbar (with either the mouse wheel or corresponding number key) and right-click on another block. [NOTE: Some blocks when collected will yield an item instead of a block (such as diamond or coal) this item cannot be placed and right-click will do nothing.] Take care when using tools as using the incorrect tool on a specific block type will waste two uses of the tool instead of just one (for instance, using a pickaxe on a tree).Collecting blocks is only the first part of playing Minecraft; more importantly is crafting. In the inventory screen (Hotkey: E) there is a 2x2 square grid used for crafting. To craft an item, the player must place the correct ingredients in the correct shape in the square. Some items can be created with very simple diagrams (i.e. a single block of wood will create four wooden planks), while others can be very complicated. One very important early game craft is to create a workbench (which allows players to craft in a 3x3 square allowing them to create more advanced items). A workbench is created with four planks; one placed in each spot of the 2x2 grid.Once players have crafted a workbench, the next step is crafting tools like shovels and axes. These allow for players to gather blocks quicker and collect more advanced blocks. After a player makes tools the rest of the game is up to them. Players can go mining for rare ore, build elaborate structures and much more.Why craft all of these items? The main point of beta mode is survival, and that's a problem because of monsters. Monsters spawn during the night or anywhere that it is dark. Players have to create shelters to prevent monsters from getting in, lighting to keep monsters from spawning, and of course weapons to defend against monsters. The bulk of Minecraft's gameplay is spent finding ways to improve your monster killing/protection effectiveness.WeatherAs of update 1.5, Minecraft has weather in the form of rain, snow and thunderstorms. Rain will occur, if rarely, in all biomes except desert, tundra and taiga, and snow will fall only in the tundra and taiga biomes. Instances of each weather effect will last approximately 15 minutes, and during them both thunderstorms may occur. During thunderstorms the world becomes darker, dark enough that enemy mobs may spawn and lightning strikes setting fire to the block it hits. Snow fall will cover most blocks in snow and cause water to freeze and become blocks of ice.Stats and AchievementsAlso with the 1.5 update, statistics and achievements were added in to the game. The stats aren't retroactive, so they only track what you have done since you updated, but they track things like distance traveled via the various ways of traveling, number of each blocks mined and placed, number of times jumped, and numerous other things. So far there are only a small number of achievements. Again they not retroactive and they seem to be more of a slight tutorial than anything else. For example, the first achievement is to open your inventory then to chop down a tree.BlocksThe following is a complete list of the blocks present in Minecraft as of version 1.2.5. They are listed by their data values as used in the game's code. Items marked with an asterisk cannot be obtained without the use of a memory editor. Certain blocks with identical functions are identified with the same code with an extra digit appended to indicate a different appearance.IDBlock NameBlock DescriptionAppearance0*AirAir is spontaneously generated in any area which is not currently holding a block. It has no effect on the player.1StoneStone is the most abundant block in Minecraft, making up the majority of its cave systems and rock formations. It cannot be obtained without the use of a pickaxe, and drops cobblestone when mined successfully.2GrassGrows on top of dirt when enough light is present. Hoeing grass has a chance to produce grass seeds, which can be planted to grow wheat.3DirtDirt covers most of the surface of the world in Minecraft. It has little use beyond being a makeshift building material, though it can be hoed to produce farmland (see block ID 60).4CobblestoneProduced automatically when stone is mined, or when lava runs over water. Its properties are otherwise identical to that of stone.5-0Oak PlanksAll planks are crafted from logs of their respective wood type. Planks make a good (albeit flammable) building material, and can be used in a multitude of crafting recipes.5-1Spruce PlanksSee above.5-2Birch PlanksSee above.5-3Jungle PlanksSee above.6-0Oak SaplingTree saplings drop from decayed leaves on tree which have been cut down. They can be used to plant new trees.6-1Spruce SaplingSee above.6-2Birch SaplingSee above.6-3Jungle SaplingSee above.7*BedrockBedrock is unbreakable. It inhabits only the bottom of the world and is used to keep players from falling into the Void.8*WaterSlows movement. It can be traversed more quickly in boats. The player can only survive for a finite amount of time underwater before he begins to asphyxiate.9*Water SourceGenerates water.10*LavaSelf-explanatory.11*Lava SourceGenerates lava.12SandSand is found in deserts. It is the only block which permits the planting of cacti. It is also one of only two solid blocks that obey physics.13GravelGravel is the only solid block other than sand that obeys physics. It occasionally yields flint as a drop instead of gravel.14Gold OreGold ore can be mined using a pickaxe and smelted to produce gold ingots. Its characteristics are otherwise identical to those of stone.15Iron OreIron ore can be mined using a pickaxe and smelted to produce iron ingots. Its characteristics are otherwise identical to those of stone.16Coal OreCoal ore can be mined with a pickaxe to produce coal. Its characteristics are otherwise identical to those of stone.17-0Oak LogAll wood logs form the base of trees. When all of a tree's log blocks are harvested, the leaves decay. Logs can be smelted into charcoal.17-1Spruce LogSee above.17-2Birch LogSee above.17-3Jungle LogSee above.18-0Oak LeavesLeaves are generated automatically when a new tree grows. They have a small chance to drop saplings when they decay or are harvested, and can be obtained in their grown form using shears.18-1Spruce LeavesSee above.18-2Birch LeavesSee above.18-3Jungle LeavesSee above.19SpongeOriginally added due to a problem with water generation. This block no longer has any practical use.20GlassIs transparent, allowing the player to make windows and skylights. Windows are now able to use panes (see block ID 102) instead.21Lapis Lazuli OreLapis Lazuli ore can be mined using a pickaxe toproduce lapis lazuli. Its characteristics are otherwise identical to those of stone.22Lapis Lazuli BlockCrafted from nine lapis lazuli. Has no practical use.23DispenserLaunches items a short distance when provided with power. Can also be loaded with arrows and incendiary munition to serve as stationary defense.24Sandstone BlockForms naturally under three blocks of sand or can be crafted from four blocks of sand. Very weak.25Note BlockPlays a player-determined note ranging from F#3 to F#5 when provided power.26*Half-Bed BlockMakes up half a bed. Has no function on its own (see Bed in Items section)27Powered RailMinecart rail that accelerates a cart which passes over it, provided it is receiving power.28Detector RailOutputs a redstone signal when a cart passes over it.29Sticky PistonPushes or pulls a block which remains locked to its surface one meter when provided power.30SpiderwebSlows the player significantly. Inhabits abandoned mineshafts.31Tall GrassOccurs on top of grass. Occasionally yields seeds when harvested.32Dead BushOccurs in desert biomes where tall grass would otherwise have spawned33PistonPushes a block one meter when provided power.34*Piston ExtensionThe end of a piston.35-0White WoolWool blocks are recovered from sheep upon death or shearing. They can be colored using dyes (see Items section).35-1Orange WoolSee above.35-2Magenta WoolSee above.35-3Light Blue WoolSee above.35-4Yellow WoolSee above.35-5Lime Green WoolSee above.35-6Pink WoolSee above.35-7Grey WoolSee above.35-8Light Grey WoolSee above.35-9Cyan WoolSee above.35-10Purple WoolSee above.35-11Blue WoolSee above.35-12Brown WoolSee above.35-13Olive WoolSee above.35-14Red WoolSee above.35-15Black WoolSee above.36*Piston UtilityBlock used by a piston which has not yet extended but is reserving space.37Yellow FlowerCan be picked up and replanted or crushed into dye.38Red FlowerSee above.39Brown MushroomCan be picked up and replanted in low light levels or made into mushroom stew along with red mushrooms.40Red MushroomSee above.41Gold BlockCrafted from nine gold ingots. Has no practical use.42Iron BlockCrafted from nine iron ingots. Slightly stronger than stone.43*Double SlabsBlocks made of two slabs simply revert to their single-block form and the world updates.44-0Stone SlabHalf-block slabs can be climbed by the player without jumping.44-1Sandstone SlabSee above.44-2Plank SlabSee above.44-3Cobblestone SlabSee above.44-4Brick SlabSee above.44-5Stone Brick SlabSee above.45Brick BlockCrafted from four bricks. Slightly stronger than stone.46TNTCan be powered or lit on fire and explodes after a three-second fuse.47BookcaseCrafted from planks and books. Provides knowledge to Enchantment Tables (see Block ID 116).48Mossy CobblestoneCobblestone but with moss. Occurs naturally in dungeons.49ObsidianForms when water runs over a lava source block. Obsidian is explosion proof and can only be mined successfully with a diamond pickaxe. It is used to construct Nether portals.50TorchCrafted from sticks and coal. Portable, reuseable light source.51*FireBurns things and spreads to other flammable things. Cannot be directly placed by the player, but can be started using Flint and Steel (see Items section).52*Mob SpawnerSpawns mobs. Will spawn pigs by default in the lights, and zombies by default in the dark. These settings can be changed with third-party mods.53Wooden StairsStairs allow the player to climb a full block without jumping.54ChestCan be used to store items in 27 slots, or can be placed next to another chest to create a large chest, containing 54 slots.55*Redstone WirePlaced when redstone dust (see Items section) is used on a flat surface. Carries charge from a power source.56Diamond OreDiamond ore can be mined using a pickaxe to produce a diamond. Its characteristics are otherwise identical to those of stone.57Diamond BlockCrafted from nine diamonds. No practical use.58WorkbenchCrafted from four wood planks, the workbench expands a player's crafting space from 2x2 to 3x3, allowing for the creation of more complex items.59*Wheat StalksOccur when seeds are planted on farmland. Can be harvested to produce wheat bundles and seeds (see Items section).60*FarmlandProduced by hoeing a patch of dirt. Allows for planting of melons, pumpkins and wheat. Farmland is fragile and may revert to dirt when walked upon, causing anything planted there to die.61FurnaceUsed to smelt items, usually ores into ingots. Must be fueled using wood, coal or buckets of lava.62*Lit FurnaceA furnace which is currently smelting something. Produces light and flame particles.63*Sign PostOccurs when a sign (see Items section) is placed on a horizontal surface.64*Wooden DoorCan be opened and closed by the player or pressure plates. They keep all mobs out except zombies, who can break down doors after a short period of time.65LadderAllows the player to move one meter up a vertical surface.66Minecart RailGives minecarts (see Items section) direction.67Cobblestone StairsSee wooden stairs (ID 53)68*Wall SignOccurs when a sign is place on a vertical surface.69LeverCan be toggled on/off to provide permanent power or lack thereof.70Stone Pressure PlateProvides power to all adjacent blocks when stepped on. Useful for opening and automatically closing doors from the inside, and for creating mob traps.71Iron DoorCan only be opened by providing power. Mobs cannot destroy this door.72Wooden Pressure PlateCan be stepped on by the player or have an item thrown on top of it in order to provide power.73Redstone OreCan be mined using a pickaxe to produce redstone dust (see Items section).74Lit Redstone OreRedstone ore reacts to the player's touch by producing light for a few seconds.75*Unlit Redstone TorchA redstone torch that is off.76Lit Redstone TorchA redstone torch that is on. Redstone torches provide power to redstone wiring on any adjacent block.77Stone ButtonCan be pressed to provide one second of power to a redstone circuit78*SnowGenerates on the ground spontaneously in snowy, tundra and taiga biomes. Can be shoveled to yield snowballs (see Items section).79IceGenerates spontaneously on top of water in cold biomes.80Snow BlockCrafted from four blocks of snow. Can be stacked and topped with a pumpkin to produce a Snow Golem (see mobs).81CactusGrow spontaneously in deserts. They can only grow on sand, and deal a half-heart of damage to any entity which touches them every second.82Clay BlockGenerate in shallow water. Can be harvested to produce clay (see Items section).83Sugar CaneGenerates spontaneously on grass and sand blocks bordering water. Can be used in crafting to make sugar and paper.84JukeboxPlay records (see Items section) collected from skeleton-creeper infighting.85FenceUsed to keep players and mobs out of an area. Fences cannot be jumped over.86PumpkinGenerate spontaneously in random areas. Can be used to create Jack-O-Lanterns (see Block ID 91), and can be worn on the player's head to avoid being attacked by Endermen (see Mobs section).87NetherrackMakes up the majority of the Nether. Often used to construct fireplaces in the Overworld due to the fact that they to not burn away and can burn indefinitely.88Soul SandAlso found in the Nether. Soul sand slows down players and mobs walking over it.89GlowstoneFound in clusters in the Nether, glowstone emits strong light which does not go out underwater.90*PortalGenerated in a 2x3 rectangle when framed by obsidian which is set on fire. Used to access the Nether.91Jack-O-LanternCrafted by placing a torch inside a pumpkin. Can be used for underwater lighting.92*Placed CakeGenerated when cake (see Items section) is placed on the ground. Can be consumed six times before disappearing.93*Redstone Repeater (Off)Causes a one- to four-tick delay in a redstone signal.94*Redstone Repeater (On)See above.95*Locked ChestAlso know as Steve Co. Supply Crates (a parody of Team Fortress 2's Mann Co. Supply Crates). Added as an April Fool's joke to trick players into thinking that the game would be supporting microtransactions. Can be obtained through hacks but disappear when placed.96TrapdoorSimilar to a door, but opens vertically.97-0Stone Silverfish NestWhen broken, this block releases a Silverfish (see Mobs section). It appears to be its parent block (in this case, stone) until mining.97-1Cobblestone Silverfish NestSee above.97-2Stone Brick Silverfish NestSee above.98-0Stone BrickGenerated naturally in strongholds. Can be crafted using four smooth stone.98-1Cracked Stone BrickSee above.98-2Mossy Stone BrickSee above.98-3Decorative Stone BrickSee above.99Brown Mushroom BlockGenerated spontaneously in Mushroom biomes. Can also be produced by applying bonemeal (see items section) to a mushroom.100Red Mushroom BlockSee above.101Iron BarsSpawn naturally in NPC villages and strongholds.102Glass PaneSpawn naturally in NPC villages. Can be crafted in bulk using six glass blocks.103MelonGrow from melon stems (see ID 105). Drop 3-7 melon slices (see Items section) when broken.104*Pumpkin StemStems grow out of seeds and indefinitely produce their respective crop.105*Melon StemSee above.106VinesSpawn naturally on trees in Jungle and Swamp biomes. Can be climbed if touching a solid block.107Fence GateFunctions like a door but is only a block and a half high.108Brick StairsSee block ID 53.109Stone Brick StairsSee block ID 53.110MyceliumSimilar to dirt but with fungus growing on top. Spawns naturally in Mushroom biomes and releases spores.111Lily PadSpawn naturally on top of water. Can be walked on.112Nether BrickSpawn naturally in Nether fortresses. Properties are identical to those of bricks.113Nether Brick FenceSee block ID 85.114Nether Brick StairsSee block ID 53.115*Nether WartGrows on soul sand. Can be harvested for individual stalks.116*Enchantment TableGenerated when a player uses the enchantment table item on a flat surface. The enchantment table, when placed, generates a floating spell tome which collects knowledge from nearby bookshelves.117*Brewing StandUsed to brew potions using magical ingredients and water bottles.118*CauldronUsed to hold water for filling bottles. Originally intended for use in brewing but were replace with brewing stands.119*End PortalTransport the player to the End. Can only be created inside a full End Portal Frame in which all blocks are occupied by an Eye of Ender.120*End Portal FrameBlocks which run around the outside of an End portal and must have an Eye of Ender inserted in order to function.121End StoneMakes up the majority of the End. Similar to stone.122Dragon EggGenerated when the Ender Dragon is killed. Cannot be picked up.123Redstone Lamp (Off)Redstone lamps are powered by redstone and function identically to glowstone, save the fact that their state can be toggled.124Redstone Lamp (On)See above.ItemsAll items in this section are organized by ID within categories.ToolsTools are used to perform specific tasks. Certain tools can be built out of different materials (wood, stone, iron, diamond, and gold). Swords are no longer included here because their cutting function has been replaced by that of Shears.IDMaterialTool NameDescription269273256277284WoodenStoneIronDiamondGoldShovelShovels are used to harvest "soft" blocks, such as dirt, gravel, clay, and sand. They are also the only tools which can harvest snowballs from snow.270274257278285WoodenStoneIronDiamondGoldPickaxePickaxes are used to harvest stone, ores and other "hard" blocks. No other tool can yield drops from any of these blocks.271275258279286WoodenStoneIronDiamondGoldAxeAxes are used for harvesting wood and blocks made from wood.290291292293294WoodenStoneIronDiamondGoldHoeHoes are used for tilling soil into farmland.259N/AFlint and SteelFlint and Steel is used to set other blocks on fire.325N/ABucketBuckets are used to hold water, lava and milk. Source blocks of lava and water can be placed by right-clicking.345N/ACompassThe Compass in Minecraft points towards the player's spawn point, unless in the Nether, in which case it goes berserk.346N/AFishing RodThe Fishing Rod is used to catch fish from bodies of water, as well as to pull land mobs toward the player.347N/AClockThe Clock gives a general indication of the time of day.358N/AMapThe map gives an overview of a large area, and the player must uncover most of it from fog of war.359N/AShearsShears are used to collect wool from sheep, leaves from trees and cobwebs from abandoned mineshafts.385N/AFire ChargeUsed in a similar fashion to flint and steel. Can also be weaponized by firing out of dispensers.Items built of different materials have varying durabilities. Durability denotes the number of times an item can be used before it breaks and must be replaced. Gold is 33, Wood is 60, Stone is 132, Iron is 251, and Diamond is 1562. Gold, however, harvests standard blocks significantly faster than all other tools.Combat ItemsMinecraft contains a multitude of weapons, armor and ammunition.ArmourArmour reduces damage taken from physical attacks by enemy mobs.IDMaterialNameDescription298314302306310LeatherGoldChainmailIronDiamondHelmetHelmets are worn over the player's head. They provide approximately 15% of a full set of armor's damage reduction.299315303307311LeatherGoldChainmailIronDiamondChestplateChestplates are worn over the player's torso. They provide approximately 40% of a full set of armor's damage reduction.300316304308312LeatherGoldChainmailIronDiamondLeggingsLeggings are worn over the player's legs. They provide approximately 30% of a full set of armor's damage reduction.301317305309313LeatherGoldChainmailIronDiamondBootsBoots are worn over the player's feet. They provide approximately 15% of a full set of armor's damage reduction.Different materials provide different damage reduction. Leather is 17.25%, Gold is 27.5%, Chainmail is 30%, Iron is 37.5%, and Diamond is 50%.WeaponsIDMaterialNameDescription268272267276283WoodenStoneIronDiamondGoldSwordSwords are the primary melee weapon in Minecraft. They can also be used to swiftly cut through leaves and cobwebs. Its durability ratings are the same as those for the tools above.261N/ABowBows can be used to launch arrows. They are the only ranged handheld weapon in Minecraft.262N/AArrowsArrows are the ammunition for bows. They can be found as drops from slain skeletons or crafted from feathers, sticks and flint.FoodThe player must eat to stay alive. Eating enables the player to regain health and to sprint, swim and perform other physically grueling tasks.IDPointsNameDescription2602Red AppleDrops randomly from trees. Can be plated with gold to create a Golden Apple.2824Mushroom StewCrafted from a wooden bowl, one brown mushroom and one red mushroom. Returns an empty wooden bowl after consumption.2972.5BreadCan be made by crafting six wheat bundles together.3191.5Raw PorkchopObtained from killing pigs.3204Cooked PorkchopObtained by cooking a Raw Porkchop in a Furnace.3222Golden AppleCrafted by surrounding an apple with gold blocks. Golden apples cast regeneration on the player for ten seconds, healing one heart every second.3491Raw FishObtained by fishing successfully.3502.5Cooked FishObtained by cooking a Raw Fish in a furnace.3546CakeCan be crafted from Wheat, Eggs, Sugar, and Milk. Cake is often seen as a milestone in a game of survival as an indication that the player has become self-sufficient. Cake is often deployed in combat as a refueling station, as it can be used six times for one food each time.357.5CookieCrafted from two wheat and one cocoa. Often considered to be a waste of resources, as three Cookies use the same ingredients as two Bread but restore 70% less food.3601Melon SliceObtained in bulk by breaking a Melon.3631.5Raw BeefObtained by killing Cows.3644SteakObtained by cooking Raw Beef in a Furnace.3651Raw Chicken3663Cooked ChickenMobsMobs are the organisms that give life to the world of Minecraft. There are four kinds of mob: passive, neutral, hostile, and utility.Passive MobsPassive Mobs will not attack the player under any circumstances.CowCows are useful for two reasons, 1. They can be killed for leather which is used to make the lowest level of armor in the game, and 2. With a bucket players can harvest milk from cows. Since the beta 1.8 Adventure update, cows will draw raw beef which can be cooked to make steakPigsSqueal, Piggy!Pigs can be killed for pork chops which serve as the primary healing item in the game. Eating raw pork chops heals a couple of hearts, but if placed in a furnace they become cooked pork chops which heals six hearts. If a pig is struck by lightning during a thunderstorm then it will become a zombie pigmen; a mob otherwise only found in the hell underworld of the Nether.ChickensChickens can be killed for feathers; feathers are used to make arrows. If left alive, however, chickens can leave eggs on the ground. Since the beta 1.8 Adventure Update, chickens drop raw chicken when killed which can be cooked in a furnace.SheepOriginally sheep could be punched with any non-tool to shear them for 1-3 blocks of wool. After beta patch 1.7, however, punching sheep does not accomplish anything. And while sheep drop wool upon dying, it is only a single block. Sheep must now be sheared with actual shears which harvest 1-3 wool per sheep. As of update 1.1, sheep now eat grass to re-grow their wool.SquidIntroduced with beta 1.2, these mobs spawn only in water with a slight chance of spawning in the shallows. While these animals are peaceful they can be killed to gain ink packets. These packets can be used to dye wool black.VillagersA VillagerVillagers are the NPCs who spawn in procedurally-generated villages. Originally they were meant to have names, though every last one of them had "Testificate" in their name plate -- a nickname that has stuck with them since their inception. Clearly inhuman (having been compared visually to Bert from Sesame Street or Squidward Tentacles from Spongebob Squarepants), the villagers never interact with the player and they are completely passive; not even fighting back if attacked by the player. Although most mobs ignore them completely at night, NPC villages come under attack from massive groups of zombies (as seen below) who will go to such lengths as breaking down wooden doors in order to get at the delicious villagers inside. To protect themselves, villagers construct Iron Golems which are incredibly powerful constructs who will protect their masters to the death.Neutral MobsThese mobs will leave the player alone until provoked. The action causing provocation and the behavior of the mobs after they have been provoked differs between mobs.Zombie PigmenA Zombie PigmanOnly found in the Nether, or if a pig is hit by lightning, Zombie Pigmen are peaceful with the player and will not attack unless provoked. They passively wander around and make sounds crossed between pigs and zombies. They become hostile and make loud angry shrieks when attacked or damaged, at which point any other Zombie Pigmen in the area also become hostile. A single player is generally no match for a group of angry Zombie Pigmen. They wield Golden Swords and drop cooked pork chops upon death. Textures exist within the game for a non-zombie Pigman creature, but there is, as of yet, no way to encounter one.WolvesIntroduced with Beta 1.4 wolves are Minecraft's first tameable pet. They can be tamed by feeding them 5-6 bones. Once tamed, hearts will appear and a red collar is present on their neck. You can tame more than one. The wolves will follow you and teleport to you if you get too far away. If you right-click on them they will sit, and if you feed them pork chops they will regain health. Their health meter is represented by their tail (vertical tail is full health, lowered is low health). They will attack any players or mobs that you attack, and defend you. Mobs will not attack them. In the wild they are neutral but will attack if provoked. They are somewhat rare but commonly found in forest-type areas.Ocelots/CatsIntroduced in 1.2 of the full release, ocelots only spawn in the also-added jungle biomes, and while they will flee the player instead of engaging them if attacked, they will purposely hunt down and kill chickens. Like wolves, ocelots can be tamed, this time with the use of raw fish. However, unlike wolves, ocelots scare easily and will flee at high speeds (the only mob currently capable of sprinting) if the player moves or even looks around too suddenly near them. Once tamed ocelots inexplicably transform into house cats which come in three different varieties: tabby, siamese and tuxedo. Unlike tamed wolves, cats are not combat pets and will not defend their master if attacked by mobs (although they will still hunt chickens).EndermanAn EndermanThe Enderman is the latest mob to be added to Minecraft, starting in Beta 1.8. Technically neutral, groups of endermen will slowly wander around picking up blocks and moving them around (making them the only mob capable of directly interacting with the world's blocks apart from creepers destroying them with their explosions). However, if the player looks directly at an individual enderman by placing their central reticule over one, it will stand motionless and stare back at them until they look away. At this point, the enderman has become hostile. Afterwards, the enderman will remain perfectly still while the player is looking at them, and run towards them extremely fast while their back is turned. In addition, endermen who are not being watched have the ability to teleport about once a second. Because of their similar appearance and names it is commonly thought that the endermen were inspired by "the Slender Man," a fictional cryptid invented on the Something Awful forums. Some have suggested that the Minecraft mob should have a more unique name, with "Far Lander" being suggested after the area towards the extreme edges of a Minecraft world, known as the Far Lands. Notch has made it clear that he will not be changing the endermens name, and that he would be more likely to change the Far Lands to "the End". This was later revealed as a sly reference to the secret home of the endermen; an alternate dimension known as the End.Iron GolemsIntroduced in 1.2 of the full release, Iron Golems are the automatons created by the villagers to protect them from the zombie hordes. Incredibly powerful, with more health than any other Minecraft mob save the Enderdragon, golems are completely harmless to the player unless deliberately provoked. On occasion, iron golems will approach villager children and present them with roses; a reference to a scene from the anime Castle in the Sky. Although they will automatically engage zombies upon detecting them, iron golems will also do battle with any mob that damages a villager nearby. They will also protect the player in this manner, making them handy to have around. The player can also construct their own golems, should they wish. Though they still have the appearance of villagers.Hostile MobsA ZombieEach enemy type has its own special traits. Mobs can be killed with any tool/weapon. However, a sword does the most damage and only counts as one use per hit whereas any tool will do less damage and count as two uses per hit.ZombieThe most basic of enemies, zombies are slow and moan incoherently. They can only attack from a close proximity and will only walk blindly toward the player once they see them. A recently-patched bug had zombies doing damage much more quickly than they were intended to making them incredibly dangerous opponents even for a well-armoured player. Now zombies are only a minor threat to an unwary player. Zombies drop feathers when killed and catch fire in direct sunlight.A SkeletonSkeletonA SpiderSkeletons are ranged opponents; only getting close enough to fire arrows at the player. Their movement patterns often involve circling the player as they get closer. Skeletons make a bone-clattering sound, but are more often identified by the sounds of their arrows being fired. Skeletons drop bones and arrows when killed and catch fire in direct sunlight.SpidersSpiders are dangerous foes being the only ground mob able to jump higher than a single block. In addition to being able to scale sheer walls at will, they move somewhat slowly but leap furiously at the player once they are in range to do so. They are also only a single block tall but two blocks wide, often getting past barriers meant for the humanoid enemies. They make loud hissing noises and have no footsteps. Spiders are docile during the day-time but will still attack if attacked first. A spider that becomes hostile to the player during the night will remain hostile to the player even once the sun rises only giving up once the player dies or it does. They drop string when killed.Cave SpidersA Cave SpiderA smaller, more deadly spider found exclusively underground and primarily in randomly generated mines. They have all of the skills of a regular spider (wall climbing, jumping higher, etc.) plus they poison you if they hit you. While this poison alone isn't deadly (as it will not take you below one heart) it makes it very easy for any mob to finish you off.CreepersA CreeperCreepers are easily the most well-known creatures in Minecraft and arguably the most dangerous having movement patterns almost identical to zombies. The main difference, however, is that creepers make absolutely no noise unless within attack distance at which point they will make a loud hissing noise (similar to an old-fashioned bomb's fuse being lit), promptly before swelling up and exploding. This leaves the player about a second to get out of the blast radius. The explosion is 75% the strength of TNT, and like TNT it destroys blocks around it and does less damage the further you are from the epicenter. Sometimes when a creeper is triggered and the player moves away quickly enough, the creeper will recede to its normal size and will not explode. Creepers drop gunpowder when killed by normal means but will not drop anything if they detonate. They also have a chance of dropping an LP record if they are killed by a skeleton's arrow. If a lightning bolt strikes a creeper or hits very near one, they will become electrified and supercharged. Their explosion is then 50% more powerful than TNT and will usually one hit kill you. Be very cautious when you see a sparking creeper.Some SlimesSlimesSlimes are a very rare enemy that only spawn deep underground in special chunks of the world. Certain programs or mods can be used to find where they can spawn (mainly useful for creating a slime farm). As of now in the current Minecraft 1.8, slimes are limited to spawning between the layers of 0-16, but as of 1.9 pre-release this had been expanded to 0-40. Their attack is similar to a spider's as they simply jump towards the player, albeit not as ferociously. Slimes can spawn in various sizes, merging when they stay close enough to one another for long enough. The smallest slimes cannot do damage to the player. They also can only move around by jumping making plopping sounds as they land. They drop balls of green slime when killed which can be used (along with a piston) to create sticky pistons and both push and pull blocks. Slimes also spawn on peaceful difficulty (no enemies) but do no damage.A GhastGhastsMostly found in the Nether, Ghasts are huge, floating ghostly creatures that are characterized by their constant moaning when idle and blood-curdling screams when attacking. They launch explosive fireballs at the player that will destroy surrounding blocks, much like a creeper's explosion. It is possible to bounce the fireballs back at the ghast either by timing a hit on it with a sword or by shooting it with a bow and arrow. If a ghast manages to hit the player's portal to the real world with its fireball, the portal will close and will need re-igniting in order for the player to be able to leave. When ghasts are killed they drop gunpowder.Notch has added a small chance that ghasts can spawn near active portals in the real world in the 1.5 update. However, this is not as terrible as it sounds given that the real world, unlike the Nether, has no ceiling, Ghasts in the real world will mainly just float off into the sky and harmlessly fly around the cloudline.Spider JockeyThe dreaded Spider JockeySpider jockeys are very rare in Minecraft. They appear as a Spider being ridden by a skeleton. Every time a spider spawns there is a 1% chance it will spawn with a skeleton on its back making it a Spider Jockey. The creature retains the ability of a spider to climb up walls and the skeleton's ability to fire arrows making it a formidable enemy. The game still treats the mob as two separate entities, though, with the spider and the skeleton having separate health and when one is killed the other will remain. The movement of the spider jockey is decided by the spider.BlazesBlazes are mobs found in the Nether. They usually spawn from monster spawners inside Nether Fortresses. Like most spawners, it will start spawning when the player cones with in 16 blocks of the spawner. When they encounter the player, they will start flying and throwing fire charges at the player. When killed by the player they will drop Blaze rods. A bow is a good weapon to use against Blazes seeing as they can fly.Difficulty LevelsThe game has four difficulties as well as a Hardcore Mode.PeacefulPeaceful mode was originally intended for players who preferred to build creatively, but the advent of Creative Mode caused this to become obsolete. However, it is still a viable option for players wishing to become accustomed to the more difficult mechanics of Survival Mode, such as gathering food and avoiding falling off cliffs or into lava. On peaceful mode hostile mobs still spawn but are removed the next time the world updates (1/20 second later). Players can gather food but the food bar does not deplete and thus they cannot eat.EasyMobs spawn but deal insignificant damage. Creepers will "forgive" the player and stop their fuse a short distance away. Players are unable to be poisoned by cave spiders. The food bar will deplete but the player will only suffer starvation damage down to 50% health.NormalMobs deal more damage. The game seems most "realistic" on this level. When the food bar is depleted players will suffer starvation damage down to 5% health.HardSignificantly harder than normal. Mobs deal significant damage and will path towards the player over longer distances. Creeper explosions are difficult to cancel. Poison can cripple the player, and it is possible to die from starvation damage.Hardcore ModeNew in the game's full release, Hardcore mode is nearly identical to Hard difficulty, but with two major caveats: The player cannot change the difficulty mid-game, and upon death the world is deleted.SoundtrackThe game's soundtrack was released on March 4th, 2011, under the name Minecraft: Volume Alpha. The compilation contains a total of twenty-four tracks, ten of which do not appear ingame. Those tracks with file names can be found within the install directory.No.TitleFilenameLength1.Keynuance1.ogg1:052.Door1:513.Subwoofer Lullabyhal1.ogg3:284.Death0:415.Living Micehal2.ogg2:576.Moog City2:407.Haggstromhal3.ogg3:248.Minecraftcalm1.ogg4:149.Oxygènenuance2.ogg1:0510.Équinoxe1:5411.Mice on Venuspiano3.ogg4:4112.Dry Handspiano1.ogg1:0813.Wet Handspiano2.ogg1:3014.Clarkcalm2.ogg3:1115.Chris1:2716.Thirteen13.ogg2:5617.Excuse2:0418.Swedencalm3.ogg3:3519.Catcat.ogg3:0620.Dog2:2521.Dannyhal4.ogg4:1422.Beginning1:4223.Droopy Likes Ricochet1:3624.Droopy Likes Your Face1:57ReceptionWhile still in the alpha phase of development, in December 2010, Minecraft was listed #8 in Gamasutra's Top Ten Games of the Year and Top 10 Indie Games awards. ABC talk show Good Game listed Minecraft as their choice for the Best Downloadable Game of 2010.At the 13th Annual IGF awards, Minecraft won the Audience Award (), and the Seumas McNally Grand Prize ().Notch and his team also won 3 awards at the Game Developers Conference Awards 2011: Best Debut, Best Downloadable Game, and the Innovation Award.Minecraft was #28 on the Giant Bomb User Game of the Year 2010 list. It is unknown whether it will be removed now that it is known that Minecraft is a 2011 release, not a 2010 release.LinksThe Official Minecraft WebsiteOfficial Minecraft ForumsMinecraft on FacebookMinecraft on RedditMinePick</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21594">Slaves to Armok II: Dwarf Fortress</game><game id="23427">Blockland Retail</game><game id="26427">Infiniminer</game><game id="26252">Miner Dig Deep</game><game id="31123">A Tale in the Desert</game><game id="23655">Planeshift</game><game id="33046">Cubelands</game><game id="24239">Love</game><game id="34255">FortressCraft</game><game id="11344">Robinson's Requiem</game><game id="23534">Lego Creator</game><game id="34804">Ace of Spades</game><game id="34940">Terraria</game><game id="25462">Roblox</game><game id="35908">Total Miner</game><game id="36006">CastleMiner</game><game id="35429">Blocks That Matter</game><game id="36227">Salem</game><game id="36874">The Powder Toy</game><game id="20239">Tail of the Sun</game><game id="37154">Castle Story</game><game id="37240">Dig-N-Rig</game><game id="37542">Brick-Force</game><game id="37665">RPG World Online</game><game id="37785">Bit Digger</game><game id="37030">Fortnite</game><game id="37839">Starbound</game><game id="37883">0x10c</game><game id="38649">Starforge</game><game id="38759">Edge of Space</game><game id="39490">Vox</game><game id="39681">Neo Scavenger</game><game id="38059">Yogventures!</game><game id="39798">Guncraft</game><game id="40795">Under the Ocean</game><game id="41143">The Blockheads</game><game id="37608">Proteus</game><game id="41481">Patterns</game><game id="38508">CastleMiner Z</game><game id="39664">Don't Starve</game><game id="42303">Qbots</game><game id="6012">Progress Quest</game><game id="43355">TUG</game><game id="43404">EverQuest Next: Landmark</game><game id="43583">7 Days to Die</game><game id="43777">Block Story</game><game id="44067">Windborne</game><game id="44380">Infinite Pixel</game><game id="44441">Astral Terra</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2127186-box_minecraft.png</image></root>