<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30484</id><name>F.E.A.R. 3</name><description>OverviewWhile F.E.A.R. 3 is being handled by Day 1 Studios the studio stated that it worked closely with Monolith (the original developers of the F.E.A.R. series) in its production. The game features a "divergent co-op" campaign and a evolved cover system. Furthermore, horror director John Carpenter , and horror writer Steve Niles contributed to the games in-game cinematics and script respectively. The game was released in June 2011 on the PC, Xbox 360, and PS3.PlotThe game takes place 9 months after the first F.E.A.R. game and once again follows story of the Point Man and the remaining members of F.E.A.R. squad. Armacham's security forces continue to eliminate all evidence of what has happened within the city of Fairport and to make matters worse, Paxton Fettel, Point Man's psychic brother, is back from the dead and refuses to leave the Point Man's side. Now the Point Man must decide his allegiance.Fettel is back.The game starts in a prison of an unknown south american country. Point Man is being tortured on where his command officer, Jun, is. Jun knows top secret information about Alma and the Fairport incident and Armacham want her out of the equation. Paxton Fettel comes to the rescue, telling Point Man that they must go back to Fairport as something big is about to happen. After busting out of the prison and hijacking a helicopter, the two make it to Fairport.A massive red explosion happens, forcing Point Man to make a crash landing. Shortly thereafter, they realize that the Fairport incident has mutated all survivors into mindless freaks. Jun is eventually saved by Point Man. She has gotten her hands on a tape that shows an Armacham soldier, Beckett, who has apparently some kind of power that connects him to Alma like Paxton and Point Man. Armacham plans to get him out of Fairport but the dastardly duo make it that he doesn't.Beckett is in fact some kind of clone fabricated by Armacham to be like Point Man and Fettel. He experiences the same visions as Alma and it is revealed that Alma is in fact pregnant and that the giant explosions that have been occuring throughout the game are in fact convulsions. It's suggested that Jun is killed by the monsters that are unleashed by Alma which are in fact fragments of her imagination, but before she dies she indicates that Alma must not give birth as whatever she gives birth to will be unstoppable. Fettel on the other hand, suggests that it's time for the family to reunite and become Gods.Before the two can go to Alma, they must first defeat the memory of their "father"Harlan Wade. More of a sadist than a doctor and even less of a father, he tortured Fettel when he was young, tormenting him while making Point Man feel inadequate. During the entire entire game, the two are chased by some kind of monster Called The Creep which is in fact revealed to be the memory of Harlan After defeating the memory, Harlanadmits that he wanted to create Gods but instead created monsters. He then disappears.The game then flashes to Alma giving birth. Her stomach is grossly huge and she's covered in blood. Jun is revealed to be alive and orders Point Man to kill Alma. Fettel once again disagrees, saying that they were always supposed to become Gods and the two can now become Gods. The two begin to fight. At this point, if you have been playing as Pointman, you will get his ending (which is cannon) and if you have been playing as Fettel you will get his. If you have been playing co-op with a friend, the game will compare your scores and the player with the highest score gets his character's ending.Baby or Demon?After being put in a choke hold, Pointman gets free, pulls out his gun and shoots Fettel three times in the forehead. Fettel, telling his brother how foolish he is, disappears. Alma however gives birth. The player does not see what comes out of her stomach, only that it seems to look like a small infant and that Point Man is happy with what he sees. Alma dies during childbirth and Point Man walks away with the baby. The game has an after credits scene where you see Fettel as a child uniting with Alma before killing most of the guards who were guarding his cell.Generative Scare SystemUnlike previous F.E.A.R. games, in which the scary scenes and events were all predetermined scripted sequences, F.E.A.R.3 uses a so-called "Generative Scare System" that delivers similar jump scares dynamically on-the-fly, randomly placing them throughout the game world so that even after completing the game, players can never be quite sure when something terrifying might happen.MultiplayerF.E.A.R. 3 features a wide variety of multiplayer modes that can be played by up to 4 players. The multiplayer consists of a robust class system as well as leaderboards.Soul SurvivorIn Soul Survivor, the objective is to survive wave after waves of enemies that are commanded by a player who has been corrupted by Alma and turned into a specter, a spirit that can control other enemies' bodies. The rest of the F.E.A.R. squad try to survive. If one of the members is downed and not healed fast enough, the reaper will corrupt him and turn him into a reaper. The winner is the last man standing.Soul KingSoul King is a competitive mode where each player starts out as a specter before the map is flooded by enemies. The player must then take control of one of the enemies and kill anything that moves. Each time an enemy is killed, he drops souls that must be collected. The player who's collected the most souls becomes the soul king. The soul king is clearly visible by any player on the map, making him a prime target as whoever kills him gets half of his souls and becomes the new soul king (of course, the player who was the soul king loses half his souls too). The winner is the player who's the soul king when time runs out.Fucking RunPlayers must run from A to B while getting chased by the fog of death created by Alma. The fog begins chasing you once you've reached a certain point on the map. Players must stick together as they plow through waves of enemies, running from the fog. If a player falls, he must be revived immediately before the fog kills him. If the fog kills one player, it's game over for the 3 others. Players are alerted when the fog is about to kill them (the screen starts going black).ContractionsPlayers must work together in a mode similar to Horde in Gears of War 2. Players are surrounded by Alma's fog of death from which enemies come out of are are forced to mount barricades to protect themselves. One player has access to a mech suit. The mode operates in rounds and the game ends when all players are down.Co-op StoryF.E.A.R. 3 is the first in the franchise to have co-op. You can ether play the game single player as the Point Man, or have a Friend join in as Paxton Fettel. Each character has their own unique abilities, allowing the players to use them together for different strategies.Paxton Fettel can not use weapons but instead has psychic powers at his disposal. He can stun enemies, suspend them for the Point Man to shoot, or even possess them and use their weapons to surprise the enemy, Geist-style. He also has a special sense that allows him to see alternate paths and hidden ammo and weapon cashes.F.E.AR 3's co-op mode also has competitive elements built into it as both players compete to become the "favorite son" by scoring points. Points are earned by killing enemies in different ways and completing one of four types of challenges: Aggression (Example: melee kill 3 enemies from behind), Tactics (Example: 8 kills with one grenade), Psychic (Example: harvest 5 psychic links) and Aptitude (Example: 5 suicide kills).System RequirementsOS: Windows XP / Vista / Windows 7Processor: AMD Athlon 64 X2 Dual Core 5600+Memory: 2GB of RAMHard Disk Space: 8GBVideo Card: nVidia GeForce 8800 GTS / ATI Radeon HD 3800 series (or better)Sound Card: DirectX compatibleDirectX: 9 (or higher)Xbox 360 HD InstallInstalling F.E.A.R. 3 on your hard drive takes up 6.1 GB of space.</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1817061-box_fear3.png</image></root>