<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30539</id><name>Naruto Shippuden: Ultimate Ninja Storm 2</name><description>OverviewNaruto Shippuden: Ultimate Ninja Storm 2 is the second 3D installment in the Naruto: Ultimate Ninja franchise. Developed by CyberConnect2, the game was released in the United Kingdom on the 15th of October, in the United States on October 19th, and ending up in Japan on the 21st of October. It is the first of the Ultimate Ninja series to have centralized online battles. This also marks the first time that the Ultimate Ninja series has been released on something other than a Sony platform.Story ModeUltimate Ninja Storm 2 offers a more robust and cinematic single-player experience than than previous entries in the series. It follows the life of Naruto Uzumaki three years after the end of the first game. The members of the original Team-7, Naruto, Sakura, and Sasuke have been getting special training from each of the respective Sannin - Jiraiya, Tsunade, and Orochimaru. The campaign runs on until Naruto's confrontation with Pain, the one believed to be the leader of Akatsuki (this is around the 170 episode mark in the anime). The open world environment has been slightly changed from the previous iteration as you can't jump across buildings and such as the environments have been replaced with painted landscapes.MultiplayerThe multiplayer is comprised of Free Battle (allowing you to duke it out against a local player or CPU) and Online Battle. There are 42 characters available to choose from with each character having unique movesets. Noticeable aspects of online play are the ninja-card and title systems, which you expand on heavily during the story mode through various quests and buying the items in shops. It's your alias on the online database as you can choose your own personal title along with one of hundreds of profile pictures taken straight from the anime.Character ListNaruto - Wind Style: Rasen ShurikenNaruto - Nine-tailed RasenganSakura HarunoSaiNaruto - Sage ModeNaruto - Hokage costumeKarinSuigetsu HōzukiSasuke - KirinSasuke - Chidori True SpearNeji HyūgaRock LeeTentenSasuke - TakaJūgoKabuto YakushiOrochimaruShikamaru NaraIno YamanakaChōji AkimichiTemariKankurōGaaraShino AbarameKiba InuzukaHinata HyūgaChiyoSasoriDeidaraKakashi HakateYamatoMight GuyTobiKakuzuHidanAsuma SarutobiJiraiyaTsunadeKiller BeeKonanKisame HoshigakiItachi UchihaPain (Yahiko's Body/Deva Path)Minato NamikazeLars Alexandersson (Crossover from Tekken)SoundtrackTrack list consists of:1 - Akatsuki2 - Battle in the Sand3 - Sakura's Good Fight4 - Eyes Like Cold Steel5 - Acquantance From Long Ago6 - The Dying7 - Paces Towards Death8 - The Only Brother9 - The Eye of Rinne10 - Lightless Struggle11 - A Will Inherited12 - He who Howls and Rages13 - White-hot Battle at the Summit14 - The Way to Peace</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13129">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai 3</game><game id="15234">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai 2</game><game id="5206">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai</game><game id="690">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai Tenkaichi</game><game id="8789">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai Tenkaichi 2</game><game id="21195">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai Tenkaichi 3</game><game id="20500">Dragon Ball Z: Burst Limit</game><game id="26565">Dragon Ball: Raging Blast</game><game id="22231">Bleach: Blade Battlers 2nd</game><game id="21378">Bleach: Heat the Soul 4</game><game id="32688">Asura's Wrath</game><game id="31233">Dragon Ball: Raging Blast 2</game><game id="20486">Bleach: Shattered Blade</game><game id="24049">Bleach Versus Crusade</game><game id="35032">Kinnikuman Muscle Grand Prix Max 2: Tokumori</game><game id="31999">Yu Yu Hakusho Forever</game><game id="34360">Bleach Soul Resurrección</game><game id="38786">Naruto Shippuden: Ultimate Ninja Storm 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2215081-box_narutouns2.png</image></root>