<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3061</id><name>Will Rock</name><description>OverviewWill Rock is a first-person shooter developed by Saber Interactive and published by Ubisoft for Windows on the PC. Though it was the first game developed by Saber Interactive on the Saber 3D engine, it received little media attention. The graphics were above average for its time back in 2003 and plays Twisted Sister's 'I Wanna Rock' after starting the game. Will Rock received mixed reviews and scores but Saber Interactive continued on to make TimeShift and Inversion. Since the release of the game there has been a patch to implement multiplayer chat and to iron out other bugs.StoryAs the title may insinuate, the protagonist of this Serious Sam-esque game is Willford Rockwell or Will Rock as I like to think his friends call him. Will is your average modern day archaeology student, complete with an experienced mentor - Dr. Richard Headstrong, good body build, average looks and a smoking hot girlfriend who is also the daughter of his mentor - Emma. But when a seemingly uneventful dig takes a turn for the worse, Will is forced into becoming a one-man army against a fanatic cult known as the Olympian Restoration Army (ORA) who have found a way to bring back Zeus and an armada of mythological beings from Ancient Greece.The ORA then murder Richard AND abduct Emma as a mortal bride for Zeus so that he can gain complete power over the mortal world which, unsurprisingly, drives Will over the edge leaving him in a rather distasteful position. Luckily for Will the Titan god Prometheus, who happens to be in the market for recruits to destroy Zeus, was close by. With similar goals in mind, Prometheus imbues Will with power leaving him half-man, half-titan - perfect for Will to exact his revenge and rescue his damsel in distress. Locked, loaded and possessed the player is left to control Will as he storms the lost city of Olympus without fear of the terrors within...GameplayLike Serious Sam, Will Rock is a rather fast paced first-person shooter in which the player has access to a plethora of ridiculous weapons that are used to fend off a just as ridiculous number of enemies. These enemies generally attack in mobs with different types of abilities and the aim of the game is to pretty much obliterate them throughout the levels with the occasional boss fight including a Giant Cyclops (not to be confused with a normal cyclops), Hephaestus, Medusa and Zeus himself. These boss fights may make the player think just a tad more by implementing thunderbolts that should be dodged but in the end it still rounds down to point and shoot.However, the rather non-existent puzzles and platforming in Serious Sam actually show up in Will Rock. The player has to occasionally navigate their way around the environment, usually by jumping around (sometimes with trampolines), destroying yourself a path or finding a switch/lever that does something useful. Swinging axes and spikes are just some of the things that the player must also work around. Scattered throughout the levels are also hidden areas and destructible objects such as pots which contain treasure, encouraging the player to explore and shoot everything. To change things up even more, the player has access to three powers, compliments of Prometheus, which can be purchased and replenished at shrines located around the levels with treasure. They are:Immortality - makes Will invincible for a period of timeTitan Damage - increases Will's damage for a period of timeTitan Motion - slows everything down for a period of time much like bullet-timeApart from this, the gameplay is pretty generic, you have health and armor which are also scattered around the levels and an end-of-level summary is provided for the player's entertainment summarizing the number of enemies you've killed, treasures you've found and all that jazz. There are three difficulty levels for this game, Will win (easy), Will Play (normal), Will die (hard) and there are ten reasonably large levels in both the single player and co-op modes. There is also another multiplayer feature called 'fragmatch', a 16-player deathmatch in which options such as time and kill limits can be set.WeaponsThe starting weapons are the shovel and pistol and the rest of them are unlocked by progressing through the game. They are usually placed in obvious areas with heaps of ammo and are usually paired with many enemies in a situation where the placed weapon would be useful, acting as a kind of tutorial for the weapon.DescriptionImageShovelThis handy archaeological tool serves as Will's melee weapon and is an effective whacking toolPistolThis 14-round handgun has unlimited ammo and mythological creature stopping power. A good weapon for killing small amount of enemies.ShotgunThough able to take care of multiple enemies when close together, requires frequent reloading due to it's 5 round magazine capacity.Machine GunThis rapid fire weapon allows you to spray to your hearts content, with the sacrifice of accuracy of course, this weapon doesn't require to reload.CrossbowThis weapon acts as a sniper in the game that allows you to shoot incendiary arrows while scoped, it needs to reload after shooting 6 arrowsHand grenadeThis weapon is your classic timed hand grenade, not very useful weapon but handy sometimesAcid GunThis splash damage weapon shoots acid that after a few seconds of contact incapacitates enemies, it reloads after 5 shotsFireball ThrowerThis weapon acts as a rocket launcher in the game with nice damage and hit radius. Perfect for crowd control or boss fightsIt's slow and doesn't require to be reloadedMedusa GunAs the name suggests, this slow firing weapon turns enemies to stone with faster incapacitation rate and larger spread then the acid gun; each bottle allows 3 shots before reloadingMini GunLike most mini guns, it's slow to start firing but its damage dealing ability and accuracy are better than the machine gun, however it needs to be reloaded after 100 shots.Atomic GunThis weapon has a slow fire rate but creates rather big explosions that enemies don't like. How straight and far the projectile flies through the air is directly proportional to how long the trigger is held down for. It reloads after 4 shotsEnemiesAlligator/CrocodileAs in real life, these enemies are fast in water and tend to biteApollo Statue/SphinxThis satyr chose the wrong time to reloadThese statues of the god Apollo and sphinxes shoot bolts of energy at youAtlas StatueThese statues of the god Atlas come to life to hurl exploding globes at youCentaurThese horsemen move fast and throw tridents at youCerberusThese multi-headed dogs spit dangerous projectiles at youCupidThese flying babies' weapon of choice is the bow and arrowCyclopsThese one-eyed creatures throw flaming rocks and bash things with their clubsDiscus ThrowerThe name says it all, these statues of discus throwers throw flaming discs at youHarpy/BirdBoth harpies and eagles fly around and spit fire and acid at youHephaestusGolden codpiece proves to be formidable opponentThis Greek god attacks with a hammer and homing rocksLion/TigerThese fast beasts run around and leap or maul to attackMedusaInstead of turning you to stone, she shoots fireballs at you. Go figure.MinotaurThese mythological beasts attack with an axe, sometimes flaming and split into two blood minotaurs when killedRatThese over-sized rodents are suicide bombers and explode after running up to youSatyr/ArcherThese weird looking things shoot arrows at youSkeletonThese dead foot soldiers come in different varieties including your average foot soldier, a flaming spear wielder, a centurion, and even a centaurSoldierThese fat men either throw exploding flaming maces or blue ricocheting knives at youZeusThis guy just sits and attacks you with lightning or fire while summoning minions</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5036">Serious Sam II</game><game id="13600">Painkiller: Overdose</game><game id="20425">Painkiller: Battle Out of Hell</game><game id="6730">Painkiller</game><game id="16194">Smash TV</game><game id="9553">Powerslave</game><game id="20532">Legendary</game><game id="17646">Unreal</game><game id="621">Doom II: Hell on Earth</game><game id="8015">Quake</game><game id="15660">Hexen II</game><game id="27205">Dreamkiller</game><game id="2288">Blood II: The Chosen</game><game id="25814">Painkiller: Resurrection</game><game id="27152">Serious Sam: The First Encounter</game><game id="24434">Powerslave</game><game id="16355">Nitro Family</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1987/709711-will_rock_front.jpg</image></root>