<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30636</id><name>Garshasp: The Monster Slayer</name><description>OverviewHack and slash for vengeanceGarshasp is a third person action-adventure game set in mythological ancient Persia, a world occupied by monsters. While camping in the wilderness, Garshasp is attacked by a horde of creatures. Fearing these creatures are the harbinger of a larger attack, Garshasp runs to warn his home city of Ariasp but is too late. The city has been ransacked and Garshasp's own brother has been murdered by the horde's leader, Hitasp. Garshasp then goes on an epic quest to avenge his brother's death and end Hitasp's reign of terror.The game was developed by Fanafzar Game Studios and is the studio's first game. Fanafzar Studios mainly used free software tools for most of the game's development, including: the OGRE Engine, OpenAL library, Boost C Libraries, and WxWidgets. The game is currently exclusive to the PC; trade sanctions prevent the developers from licensing console development kits.GameplayThe game is highly derivative of God of War. Combat is melee only and focuses heavily on combo moves. There are however some quick-time events used to finish larger enemies, especially bosses. There's also platforming elements and a few simple puzzles for the player to solve.System RequirementsMinimumRecommendedOperating System: Windows XP, Vista, 7Processor: P4 2.0 GHzRAM Memory: 1 GBGraphics: 256 MB RAM, Nvidia 6600 and upDirectX速: DirectX速 9.0cHard Drive: 3 GB freeSound: DirectX compatibleOperating System: Windows XP, Vista, 7 64-bitProcessor: 2.5GHz dual core CPURAM Memory: 2.5 GBGraphics: 512 MB RAM, GeForce 8800 or Radeon 4600 GPUDirectX速: DirectX速 9.0cHard Drive: 3 GB freeSound: DirectX compatible</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6959">God of War</game><game id="11314">God of War II</game><game id="20461">God of War III</game><game id="24827">Dante's Inferno</game><game id="21876">Ninja Gaiden</game><game id="20928">Golden Axe: Beast Rider</game><game id="35629">Bloodforge</game><game id="5235">Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time</game><game id="17357">Prince of Persia: Warrior Within</game><game id="21380">Prince of Persia: The Two Thrones</game><game id="29321">Prince of Persia: The Forgotten Sands</game><game id="39754">Wild Blood</game><game id="40862">Tales of Another Galaxy</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1786567-box_garshasp.png</image></root>