<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3063</id><name>Godzilla</name><description>Plot To all the uninformed,  Godzilla had a son by the name of Minilla (or Minya.) He appeared in Son of Godzilla (1967) and Godzilla's Revenge (1969). He appeared again here, in video game form. Horrible monsters had kidnapped Minilla and hidden him somewhere among the sixty-four rooms of a giant maze-like labyrinth. Granted, this could have been an easy task for Godzilla: traverse through the rooms (destroying the boulders along the way) until finding the room in which Minilla is confined. Easy for Godzilla, right? Well...it would be...if it weren't for the fact that numerous amounts of his various opponents from the past were at his neck with every move he made. The likes of Baragon, Mechagodzilla, Hedorah, Anguillas, Rodan, and Ghidrah were all just waiting for a chance to get a shot in. Thus, with that gloomy setup, the game began. Gameplay By pausing the game, players were given four options: Continue, Try Again, Entire Plan, and Password. If the player selected continue, the pause screen would close and gameplay would continue. Try again would restart the level from the beginning with all objects in their original places. Entire Plan would show a map of all sixty-four rooms: unvisited rooms were marked with a question mark while visited rooms were marked with arrows representing the rooms one could enter from that room. The room in which one currently stood would blink. Password would show one the password for that level.  Two passwords were displayed: a four-digit password (such as this one: MRN7) which started the player in the room they left off in but without any other rooms cleared and an eighteen digit password (such as this one: MLSMB/=RD 55C=2NJM7) which started players in the room they left off in while also keeping all previously cleared rooms still in a state of completion. This menu helps to explain what the core premise behind the game is.  Somewhere, in one of these rooms, Minilla is trapped. To complete the game, Godzilla (the player) must find that room. In each room, there are multiple doors which lead to different rooms. Marked by an arrow, these doors only appear when a certain condition is met: all boulders in the room must be smashed. As easy as this may sound, it can actually prove quite difficult. By pressing the B button, Godzilla throws a punch. Unless the boulder is pressed up against either a wall or another boulder, the rock will only move in the direction it was hit. When combined with numerous places in which the rock can get stuck, the developers were able to present plenty of interesting and difficult puzzles (some so much so that the try again button was desperately needed). When combined with the constant onslaught of enemy monsters, the pressure certainly began to go up. Most monsters could be defeated with a simple punch (a press of the B button), though they would re-spawn not long after. Some enemies presented a particular challenge because of their special abilities: Rodan could fly and Hedorah could only be defeated with rocks (either by a boulder being dropped on top of him or by being smashed between a wall and a boulder) though he could be pushed back with a fist. Time was also a pressure because if the puzzle wasn't solved fast enough, Ghidorah would appear. He would come on screen to kill Godzilla and would, of course, succeed (considering his invincibility).  There were three on-screen indicators noticeable while playing: the stage number, the player's score and the player's health bar. The stage number is self explanatory: each of the sixty-four stages is numbered and this displays the number of the stage upon which the player is currently located. The player's score is made up of increases from every time a boulder or enemy is destroyed and from the amount of health Godzilla has left when the stage is completed (the more, the better). Last, but not least, Godzilla's health bar is a measure how close he is to dying. When it is empty, Godzilla is dead. Whenever an enemy monster is touching Godzilla, his health bar is draining. Upon death, Godzilla disappears in a puff of smoke. Enemy MonstersBaragon Movie Appearance: Frankenstein vs. Baragon (1965) Method of Defeat: Godzilla's Fist Punch (B button)   MechagodzillaMovie Appearance: Godzilla vs. Mechagodzilla (1974) Method of Defeat: Godzilla's Fist Punch (B button)  HedorahMovie Appearance: Godzilla vs. Hedorah (1971) Method of Defeat: Boulder Smash (a boulder falling on top of him or being hit by a boulder when standing next to a wall)  AnguillasMovie Appearance: Godzilla Raids Again (1955) Method of Defeat: Godzilla's Fist Punch (B button)     RodanMovie Appearance: Rodan (1956) Method of Defeat: Godzilla's Fist Punch (B button), specially good at evasion due to its ability to fly however   GhidrahMovie Appearance: Ghidorah, The Three Headed Monster (1964) Method of Defeat: Invincible, appears after set amount of time and kills Godzilla immediately  </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/6529/216332-godzilla_game_boy.jpg</image></root>