<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30717</id><name>Pu-Li-Ru-La</name><description>OverviewPu-Li-Ru-La is a game that almost defies explanation. Its basic gameplay is similar to Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles, The Simpsons, or any other arcade brawler, but Pu-Li-Ru-La's engrish translation, wild abstract moments, and simplified brawler mechanics make it a very interesting game to play.The game was eventually converted and released for the rare Japanese only video game console, the Fujitsu FM Towns Marty. Later on versions were released for the Seaga Saturn, Playstation and Playstation 2.StoryThe game's attract mode informs you that Pu-Li-Ru-La takes place in a world called Radishland, where every town has a Time Keeper who keeps time's flow with a magic key. However, a "Bad Man" steals a Time Key and begins freezing towns in time. So two children from another town are given magic wands and sent out to stop the unnamed adversary.GameplayGameplay wise, Pu-Li-Ru-La is a typical arcade brawler with a twist: Most enemies are defeated in just one hit. This one hit mechanic helps keep the game moving quickly. Once defeated with your magic wand, enemies will be shot over to the side of the screen, at which point they will turn into ducks, puppies, pigs, or other small animals for some reason. Once transformed, they will run across the screen towards you and can be collected for points. The further they run across the screen before being collected, the more points they are worth. Going for a high score presents an interesting challenge as you need to try to keep up with the flow of enemies while collecting the animalized forms of defeated enemies, preferably letting them run as far as possible for maximum points.</description><genres><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6722">Final Fight</game><game id="14351">Golden Axe</game><game id="20436">Streets of Rage</game><game id="29491">Scott Pilgrim vs. The World: The Game</game><game id="36259">Gourmet Sentai Bara Yarou</game><game id="10811">Bubble Symphony</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/31700/1328297-pulirula_17.png</image></root>