<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30864</id><name>Tank! Tank! Tank!</name><description>OverviewTank! Tank! Tank! Is an arcade game that supports up to 4 players published and developed by Namco Bandai. The game was later ported to the Wii U as a launch game.GameplayMultiplayer Gameplay.Each player controls a tank and can compete in 3 different game modes. Players control their tanks using a steering wheel and forward and reverse pedals. Both the seat and the steering wheel shake when firing a shot or being struck by one. The game includes multiple power ups for your tank, including the Plasma Bolt, Machine Gun, Missile Rack, Colossus Missile, and Mega-Beam. Before the start of each match, each player can have their picture taken by a camera included with the cabinet or the Wii U gamepad and choose one of many different costume overlays to include with it.Game ModesCo-op: All players work together to take down a series of giant monsters, culminating in a battle against King Ghidora-esque 3 headed robot dragon.Free-for-All: Players fight against each other in one of two different settings. The player who destroys the most tanks during the time limit wins.Team Battle: Players split up into two different teams and fight for supremacy.My Kong ( Wii U Only ): One player takes control of a large gorilla monster via use of the Gamepad while up to 3 other players using the standard tank attempt to destroy them.Wii U VersionAt Nintendo's E3 2012 press conference, a Wii U port of Tank! Tank! Tank! was announced.The Wii U port features local co-op and competitive multiplayer with support for up to 4 players, one of which can play on the gamepad with the other 3 sharing a split screen. It also includes the My Kong mode for asymmetric competitive multiplayerGameplayThe Wii U version of the game is played with the Wii U gamepad and Wii remotes. Tanks are controlled with the Wii remote. Players hold the remote horizontally in their hands, using the directional pad to move their tank around while hitting A to fire. Players lock on to their targets and can destroy the environment to dig up upgrades that increase their fire power or armor.In multiplayer, one player uses the Wii U gamepad to control the level's boss. The player uses the controller's screen to control their character and can tap the screen to unleash powerful attacks such as devastating stomps and barrages of missiles. The front facing camera of the controller lets players put their face into the game as the boss's face.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="30477">Tokyo Wars</game><game id="7338">Earth Defense Force 2017</game><game id="17922">BattleTanx: Global Assault</game><game id="34610">Face Raiders</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2348799-box_ttt.png</image></root>