<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30886</id><name>Flora's Fruit Farm</name><description>OverviewFlora's Fruit Farm is a casual PC game developed by Honeyslug, and published by SQUARE ENIX, Eidos Interactive. It is currently available exclusively on Steam for $11.99. The goal, as described in the Steam summary, is to "create a blossoming fruit farm empire," by managing various fruit / farming related resources. Figuring players might not be content with "farming for the sake of farming," there are additional stakes at hand for the titular player character:Clementine Valley used to be the place to be! It was world renowned for its fantastic fruit trees lovingly tended to by Old Jim. Unfortunately Jim has lost the energy to grow enough fruit to keep the locals happy, let alone attract the tourists Clementine Valley used to have. Luckily for Jim, Flora’s kind gesture showed him that she has the spirit to continue his legacy and he gives her his Magic Gardening gloves...It’s up to Flora to restore life to Clementine Valley by growing fruit with her magic gardening gloves!The game features 50 different fruit-bearing trees, which can be explored from the roots up in order to collect seeds and flower bulbs. There are "7 different types of special characters" which your fruits can be sold to, each with their own favorite fruits to be taken into consideration. As if this weren't enough for poor Flora to juggle, she must also contend with vicious birds and gophers seeking to overturn your fruit farm empire! If this becomes too much for a player to handle, they can summon a squirrel helper to do their work for them.System RequirementsOS: Windows 2000/XP/Vista/Windows 7Processor: Pentium III 1 Ghz processor or higherMemory: 512 Mb RAMGraphics: Intel i945 graphics chipset or any 64Mb video graphics card able to display a minimum of 640x480 resolutionHard Drive: 50 Mb hard disc spaceSound: Any 16-bit Sound card</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8125/1338413-floras_title_screen.png</image></root>