<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31001</id><name>Assassin's Creed: Brotherhood</name><description>StoryThe story is a continuation of the Assassin’s Creed II storyline following Ezio Auditore Da Firenze, the Master Assassin, as he travels to the city of Rome in order to recruit and train the Brotherhood of assassins. This time around, Ezio will encounter a powerful condottieri, Cesare Borgia. After a surprise attack on Monteriggioni, the Templar grandmaster, Cesare kills Mario as he invites Ezio to Rome, with the Apple of Eden lost to them, and the villa in ruins. Ezio travels to Rome to establish the Assassin Order, and to bring the Templar order to their knees once and for all.One of Ezio's many combat techniques.The game opens with Ezio running on a battlefield and gripping Cesare Borgia. As he attempts to stab the condottieri in the neck, Cesare pushes him off and the memory, known as sequence 9, goes out of synch. The game flashes back to where Assassin's Creed II ended. Ezio is in a vault beneath the Vatican speaking to Minerva. Despite having many questions, she disappears and Ezio is left bewildered. He returns to where he had left the Pope who has since escaped. Ezio attempts to take the Papal staff that retracts into the ground, and he is left with only the Apple of Eden. Mario arrives and together they escape the Vatican. Right before escaping though, Ezio hesitates to get rid of the apple so no one will ever be able to harness its power but decides not to.The game flashes to 2012 where Desmond, Lucy and the gang are on the run from Abstergo. They arrive at Ezio's villa in the hopes of locating the other pieces of Eden before Abstergo finds them. Desmond re-enters the Animus to find clues to where the Apple of Eden may be.Ezio returns to his family mansion. He meets with his mother, sister, Mario, Niccolo Machiavelli and Caterina Sforza on what to do with the apple. Machiavelli scolds at Ezio for not having killed Rodrigo Borgia and that the Borgia family will strike back, which causes Machiavelli to leave for Rome. Despite all this, Ezio seems content that his adventure is over, hands the apple off to Mario and sleeps with Caterina.Ezio and his uncle Mario at the Villa.The next morning, things go terribly wrong. As Caterina and Ezio lie in bed, a giant cannon ball comes crashing through the room, nearly killing them. Ezio barely has time to realize that his beautiful manor is being attacked by Cesare Borgia. Despite his grandest efforts, the Borgia pierce the walls and capture Mario and Caterina. As Ezio races to save them, he is shot in the shoulder, Mario is executed, and the apple is taken. Ezio drags himself back to the manor, where he manages to escape through an underground crypt with his mother and sister thanks to a man with an eyepatch who fends off the troops. As the rest of the surviving Auditore family go to a safe house, Ezio decides to ride a horse for Rome to get the apple back. As Ezio rides, he collapses from loss of blood and passes out.Ezio wakes up in a house in Rome, healed and with his assassin gear. It's made unclear on who brought him to the house but he decides to go meet Machiavelli. Rome is under Borgia rule. Many shops are closed and martial law is in effect, with soldiers patrolling everywhere. The Borgia have everyone in their pocket, from the military to the church. Ezio wishes to make a difference, inciting a rebellion against the Borgia and give Rome back to the Romans. Ezio decides that the only way to do this is with allies. He gains the trust of La Volpe (thieves guild), the courtesans and Bartolomeo (mercenaries guild) and things begin to take shape.The allies decide that Ezio must assassinate Cesare Borgia to eliminate the oppression. Ezio doesn't think that eliminating the Borgia will solve anything but decides to take the mission anyways to save Caterina who's being held at the Vatican in Castle Gandolfo. There, he misses Cesare but meets Lucrezia Borgia, Cesare's sister and lover. He manages to save Caterina who returns to Forli and spares Lucrezia. Ezio decides to orchestrate a plan to remove corruption from Rome. By helping out the citizens of Roma, he brings Assassins to his cause. He decides that the only way to destroy Cesare Borgia is to cut off different elements starting with funding.Ezio manages to kill Cesare's banker by killing him in the middle of an orgy. Cesare is using the French to enact military pressure on Rome and the final non-corrupt institutions. Ezio kills the French general (Baron de Valois) guaranteeing that Rome stays Roman. Ezio chooses to take down the Pope as he is a centerpiece to the Borgia empire. By manipulating information, the Borgia begin to turn on each other. Ezio orchestrates one final attack on Castel Gondolfo.The new combat mechanics in action.Cesare meets with the Pope inside the castle. Fearful that Cesare was going to turn on him, the Pope, Rodrigo Borgia, attempts to poison Cesare with an apple. Disgusted, Cesare takes the poisoned apple, sticks it into the pope's face and chokes him to death. In the meantime, Lucrezia shows up and in his rage, Cesare tells her that he never loved her. This only makes Ezio's job easier as Lucrezia tells him where the Apple is hidden. Ezio finds the apple and brings it back to the assassin hideout on Tiber Island. There, he is made Master of Assassins and uses the power of the apple to squash the remains of Cesare Borgia's empire. Cesare is eventually arrested but flees to Spain.The game skips ahead to the previously inaccessible Sequence 9. There, Ezio finally kills Cesare by throwing him off the top of a castle. Ezio then goes back to Rome and hides the Apple of Eden in a vault beneath the Coliseum. Having discovered its location, the crew drive out to Rome to get it.After solving several puzzles, Desmond and Lucy make it to the Apple. Desmond meets Juno a hologram of "those who came before" that explains the history of the two race of creatures. The holograms of Juno around the vault seem to be hostile against Lucy, claiming that she is not who she seems to be. When Desmond touches the Apple, everything freezes and he loses control of his body. As the spirits yell that she must be eliminated, Desmond unwillingly takes out his hidden blade and stabs Lucy. The screen fades to black and the credits roll.Subject 16Subject 16There are 10 clusters hidden around the game world that have been placed there by Subject 16. Each cluster has 4 puzzles each and includes information about the Templars and Abstergo. By solving them all, Desmond is able to meet some version of Subject 16 who explains to him that there is no more time and that they must act and that he must find his Eve. It is unclear if Subject 16 is still alive in the real world or if he just programmed himself into the Animus. Before he can answer any important questions, he disappears.Campaign GameplayThe game's story starts immediately after the events of Assassin's Creed II. After some complications, you travel to Rome to build a guild of assassins. Each assassin has to be recruited individually, equipped and trained through sending them on missions throughout Europe. The trainees are recruited through missions where you save them, but are easily lost if you are not careful. Otherwise all (or almost all) gameplay elements from Assassin's Creed II return for the sequel. Additions this time around are the ability to ride inside a city and fight from a horse. NPC characters are also able to ride this time around and can be assassinated even when they are on their horses.Ezio fighting a soldier on horseback!The crossbow - which has been teased since the intro FMV to the original Assassin's Creed - is finally introduced to the series, and functions similarly to the hidden gun; while the crossbow has more ammo available, it is ineffective against armored enemies, where the gun can easily take down an armored guard. However, the crossbow can be used to silently eliminate guards.Another notable refinement is the inclusion of the hidden gun into combat. Players are now able to hold down the attack button for a moment to aim and fire the gun, rather than breaking out to a menu to select and equip it as in the previous game. The gun is also used in several of Ezio's execution attacks.Leonardo Da Vinci returns to the game, and is once again in the business of helping Ezio expand his arsenal. Leonardo has been drafted by the Borgia and forced to invent weaponry for them. Take on a range of missions to destroy, disable, and otherwise sabotage these new weapons, and he will help Ezio by providing new gadgets like a dart gun in his hidden blade and a parachute that can be used to both break falls and improve mobility.Unlike AC2, you can replay memories. Each memory has a particular goal to meet, such as not being detected, not being hit, or not touching the ground over the course of the mission. Meeting these goals will improve Desmond's synchronization to Ezio; however, the player will not fail the memory if they aren't met.LocationsThe game is set entirely in Rome, which is massive in scope and includes both city and countryside. Ezio cannot leave the city or the country, but he can send his assassin recruits all over Europe to complete missions.The Assassin tombs have returned from AC II, although they are now associated with the Followers of Romulus, rather than the Assassins.MultiplayerThe multiplayer of Assassins Creed Brotherhood focuses on trying to kill other players through disguise and tricks. Players select from a number of different player models, and then every NPC will have one of those player models. The players themselves attempt to kill a target while escaping from another, with certain game modes changing the balance of escaping and killing. Players are encouraged to use stealth by standing near similar player models or disguising, or smart attacks like attacking from a rooftop onto an unsuspecting target below.Game ModesWanted - Features up to 8 players. Each player in the match has a target, meaning that everyone has someone to kill and someone that is trying to kill them.Manhunt - Features up to 8 players. Everyone is divided into two teams of four. The Hunters (all consisting of the same character model) must kill the Hunted team (all consisting of the same character model as well). After the first round, the team's switch.Alliance - Features up to 6 players. 3 teams of 2 are assigned another team as their target, functioning similarly to Wanted.Advanced Wanted - A more difficult version of Wanted. The compass is less precise (goes farther away from your target) and no longer shows your target's height.Advanced Alliance - A more difficult version of Alliance. The compass is less precise (goes farther away from your target) and no longer shows your target's height.Chest Capture- Features up to 8 players. 2 teams of four are assigned two tasks. One team defends 3 chests that are spawned at random locations, while the other team simultaneously tries to rob the chests. Similar to Manhunt, it is based around a 2 round increment. After each round, teams swap.Escort: Added in the Animus 1.2 update. Unique NPCs with a specific model roam the map; the attackers can only kill the NPC or stun the defenders. The defenders can only kill the attackers.Assassinate: Added in the Animus 1.2 update. This is the equivalent to complete FFA deathmatch. You are not given a target, but instead lock onto personas in order to gain a contract on them. You are not told if you are locking onto a player or an NPC, and can only rely on your detection skills to pick out another player instead of an NPC. If you know that an enemy is stalking you, then you can also declare them your target to create a "stalemate" situation, where you both lose your contract against each other, and cannot reacquire the same person as a contract for some time.AbilitiesAll abilities have cooldown times and are activated with the press of a button. In addition, the player will unlock advanced forms of different abilities as they level up.Ability NameLevel RequiredDescriptionDisguiseLevel 2Changes the player into a random character model. This can be used to throw off pursuers or to surprise targetsSprint BoostLevel 3Gives the player a burst of speed. This can be used to escape pursuers or catch up to fleeing targetsSmoke BombLevel 6Creates a smoke cloud that temporarily incapacitates opponents as they choke on the cloud.Hidden GunLevel 8A ranged attack that allows the player to instantly kill distant targets, albeit after the shot lines up.FirecrackersLevel 11Functions like a flashbang in that it turns the screen of the affected player's white, temporarily blinding them. NPCs caught in the area will fall to the ground, but other players will not. This can be used to single out targets in a crowd.MorphLevel 14Transforms NPCs in the area into the character model of the player. This can be used to blend in more efficiently and confuse pursuers.Throwing KnivesLevel 16Slows down fleeing targets when it hits them. This can also be used to negate the Sprint Boost ability.Templar VisionLevel 19Similar to Eagle Vision in the Story mode, Templar Vision paints targets in blue, pursuers in red, and hiding spots in white. (The player glows while using Templar Vision, which can alert nearby targets)ChargeLevel 21Allows the player to barge forward, automatically knocking over any NPCs in the way. This can be used to gain ground on targets or stun opponents.DecoyLevel 24Transforms a nearby NPC into the player's character model and sends them off running in a random direction. This can be used to trick pursuers.MuteLevel 26Works as a "Silence" ability, preventing the target from killing, stunning, or using abilities for 1 second.PoisonLevel 29Allows the player to gently brush up against a target, which poisons the target and kills them a few seconds laterPerksPerks are passive abilities.Perk NameLevel RequiredDescriptionEnhanced AutobashLevel 20Allows the player to run into 2 NPCs in high profile without stumbling instead of 1.Wall RunnerLevel 22Allows the player to climb higher when they start a climb.ResistanceLevel 27Reduces the amount of time a player is unconscious on the ground following a stun.BlenderLevel 30Changes one character in a group to the player's character model when they blend in with said group.Fast GetawayLevel 33Reduces the amount of time a player needs to be hidden during a chase to get a successful escape.Chase ExpertLevel 38Allows the player to run 15% faster while in a chase.Overall CooldownsLevel 40Reduces the cooldown time for every ability by 10 seconds.Silent HuntLevel 42Increases the amount of time a player can be in high profile near their target before a chase is initiated.List of Multiplayer CharactersBarberBlacksmith (Unlocked via multiplayer experience/levels)CaptainCourtesanDoctorFootpad (Unlocked via multiplayer experience/levels)EngineerExecutionerMercenaryNoblePriestProwlerSmugglerThief (Unlocked via multiplayer experience/levels)Harlequin (Limited Edition or Preorder Exclusive)Officer (Limited Edition or Preorder Exclusive)Hellequin (UPlay Exclusive)Knight (Animus Update 1.2)Dama Rosa (Animus Update 1.2)Marquis (Animus Update 1.2)Pariah (Animus Update 1.2)PS3 ContentIt was announced at Sony's E3 2010 Keynote that special mission content and access to the multiplayer beta for Assassin's Creed Brotherhood would be exclusive to the PS3.The beta opened on October 4th, ended October 18th, and was available to select PlayStation Plus members as well as those who preordered the game at GameStop.On Nov. 3, 2010, it was announced that the exclusive content for the PS3 is called the "Copernicus Conspiracy" and will feature Nicholas Copernicus. The content will be available free to download on launch day on the PSN.Collector's EditionThe AC: Brotherhood Collector's Edition setThe collector's edition was announced on August 9, 2010 for the Xbox 360 and PlayStation 3. Two versions will be released: one for GameStop and one for the other participating retailers. The main difference between the two versions will be the Jack-in-the-Box is included. Gamestop will be getting the Harlequin and the rest will have Doctor J. The full list of content in the collector's edition includes:A copy of Assassin's Creed: BrotherhoodAn Exclusive art bookA hard copy map of RomeA bonus disc that includes trailers, a making-of video, the soundtrack, a digital sneak-peek of the Assassin's Creed comic, and a developer diaryTwo exclusive in-game single-player mapsAn Assassin's Creed themed Jack-in-the-BoxIn the Assassin's Creed: Brotherhood Multiplayer Trailer, the song used for the trailer is called "We Want War" by These New Puritans.Limited Codex EditionLimited Codex EditionThe Codex edition was the top-tier Special Edition sold exclusively through select retailers in each region.The Limited Codex Edition includes:Renaissance Collector ChestAssassin's Creed: Brotherhood Standard EditionMap of Rome from the gameExclusive Codex Art BookBonus Making of DVD and SoundtrackMultiplayer Character Collector Cards: A set of trading cards representing all the characters of Assassin's Creed Brotherhood Multiplayer featuring character bios and kill moves.Aquaducts and Trajan Market Single Player MapsHarlequin and Officer Multiplayer CharactersHelmshmied Drachen Armor Single Player CostumeExclusive Retailer:Australia: EB GamesAuditore EditionAuditore EditionThe Auditore Edition is a middle-tier Special Edition priced between the Standard and Collector's Editions.The Auditore Edition includes:Exclusive Display Box with 3D thermoformed portrait of Ezio and 'Animus' effect.Assassin's Creed: Brotherhood Standard EditionAssassin's Creed Lineage DVD: Discover the story of Ezio Auditore by following his father, Giovanni, in this three episode short film.Multiplayer Character Collector Cards: A set of trading cards representing all the characters of Assassin's Creed Brotherhood Multiplayer featuring character bios and kill moves.Aquaducts Single Player MapExclusive Single Player CostumePre-order BonusesThe following items were available as an exclusive pre-order bonus with the Standard Edition of the game from select retailers in each region.Aquaducts Single Player Map - 'In the mines of Tivoli, Templars are working hard to steal a long lost treasure.'Harlequin Multiplayer Character - 'A corrupt nobleman underneath the mask, the Harlequin performs acts of terror among the people to further the Templar Cause. The grin never leaving his face, he always keeps his Daggers in case anyone demands an encore performance.'Exclusive Retailer:Australia: EB GamesSoundtrackCD Album CoverThe original score for Assassin's Creed: Brotherhood was once again written by award-winning composer Jesper Kyd.Track #Song TitleRunning Time01Master Assassin3:1802City of Rome5:3103Cesare Borgia2:5904Flags of Rome2:3305The Brotherhood Escapes2:0106Brotherhood of the Assassins3:0107The Pantheon3:0308Villa Under Attack2:1109Echoes of the Roman Ruins2:5010Borgia Tower2:1111Borgia Occupation3:0112Roman Underworld3:4313Countdown3:3214Borgia: the Rulers of Rome3:5815Ezio Confronts Lucrezia2:5616Battle In Spain1:3417Fight of the Assassins2:3518Desmond Miles4:4519VR Room2:4720End Fight (AC II bonus track)1:3721Legacy of the Borgia Family2:2922Rome Countryside2:59PC System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows® XP (32-64 bits) /Windows Vista®(32-64 bits)/Windows 7® (32-64 bits)Processor: Intel Core® 2 Duo 1.8 GHZ or AMD Athlon X2 64 2.4GHZMemory: 1.5 GB Windows® XP / 2 GB Windows Vista® - Windows 7®Graphics: 256 MB DirectX® 9.0–compliant card with Shader Model 3.0 or higher (see supported list*)DirectX®: 9.0Hard Drive: 8 GBSound: DirectX 9.0 –compliant sound cardPeripherals: Keyboard, mouse, optional controllerSupported Video Cards: ATI® RADEON® HD 2000/3000/4000/5000/6000 series, NVIDIA GeForce® 8/9/100/200/300/400/500 seriesNote* * This product does not support Windows® 98/ME/2000/NTRecommendedOS: Windows® XP (32-64 bits) /Windows Vista®(32-64 bits)/Windows 7® (32-64 bits)Processor: Intel Core® 2 Duo E6700 2.6 GHz or AMD Athlon 64 X2 6000 or betterMemory: 1.5 GB Windows® XP / 2 GB Windows Vista® - Windows 7®Graphics: GeForce 8800 GT or ATI Radeon HD 4700 or betterDirectX®: 9.0Hard Drive: 8 GBSound: 5.1 sound cardPeripherals: Keyboard, mouse, joystick optional (Xbox 360® Controller for Windows recommended)Supported Video Cards: ATI® RADEON® HD 2000/3000/4000/5000/6000 series, NVIDIA GeForce® 8/9/100/200/300/400/500 seriesNote* * This product does not support Windows® 98/ME/2000/NT</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19960">The Ship</game><game id="5235">Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time</game><game id="20464">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Conviction</game><game id="17357">Prince of Persia: Warrior Within</game><game id="21380">Prince of Persia: The Two Thrones</game><game id="21213">Mirror's Edge</game><game id="29284">Tron: Evolution</game><game id="33074">The Cursed Crusade</game><game id="21243">The Crossing</game><game id="30455">SpyParty</game><game id="31391">Bloody Good Time</game><game id="6601">Hitman: Contracts</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2261082-box_acb.png</image></root>