<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31007</id><name>Booster Trooper</name><description>Overview In Booster Trooper all players have a                   health bar, a limited amount  of                  jetpack boost which they can refill when they land and a limited  amount of                 ammunition. Avatars in the game will fire wherever on the  screen the cursor is placed while the fire button is held down. Booster  Trooper supports up to 12 players or                bots per match and has an online                leaderboard system. Game modes include              deathmatch,             team deathmatch,             capture the flag and destroy the beacon. At the start of each match  players are given the choice of which primary weapon, secondary weapon  and    explosive they spawn with and can also choose whether they use a  male or female avatar at the start of each game. Players can pick up  additional weaponry, ammunition and health on the maps. The game was  released on  Steam on April the 16th, 2010, but it was available as early  as April 1st through competitions held on Moddb and the   DnS Development  forums.    Maps FactoryErona MinesSorayaTycho CityLatoga MarshlandNameless ShrineLake YoshiPeak  Weapons           Assault Rifle         Pistol        Shotgun       Sniper Rifle      Rocket Launcher     MinigunMagma ThrowerPlasma ThrowerArm Cutter    GrenadeShredderC4  System RequirementsMinimum RequirementsOS: Windows XP Sp3, Windows  Vista Sp2, Windows 7Processor: 2 Ghz multicore  or higherMemory: 2 GB or moreGraphics:  512 MB, Shader model 3.0 or higher,  NVIDIA 7800, ATI X1800 or betterDirectX®:  DirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 800 MB availableSound:  DirectX 9.0c compatible soundcard</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13773">Soldat</game><game id="10757">Liero</game><game id="20483">Bionic Commando Rearmed</game><game id="22951">Crash Commando</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4344/1348727-website_splash_top.jpg</image></root>