<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31023</id><name>Breath of Death VII</name><description>StoryDuring a vicious world war in 20XX an atomic weapon was detonated in a desperate attempt to end the war, causing all life to be wiped out across the world. Fortunately an undead civilization began anew, prospering until an evil force invaded the land prompting the four heroes of the story, Dem, Sara, Erik and Lita to embark on an epic quest to stop this evil from conquering the land.GameplayBreath of Death VII uses a turn based combat system very similar to traditional Japanese Role-Playing Games but with a twist: it has a combo system which allows you to build up your attacks; the higher your combo, the more powerful certain abilities will be; rewarding the player for saving their more powerful attacks until later on in battles. There are also "unite abilities" which allow two different heroes in your party to team up to perform a unique move. They can provide bonuses or deal damage depending on the characters with which you execute them. After each fight you gain experience which allows you to level your characters up with a branching leveling system, giving you choices of different attacks, spell upgrades or stat upgrades on each level allowing you make your character's stats cater to their strengths.There are also several towns to explore which feature shops, inns, houses and ghostly citizens to speak to. When outside of these towns you enter an overview of the world map in which you move your characters. The outside world is dangerous and you can be ambushed by monsters whilst you are on your way to other destinations, but going off the beaten path can provide rewards for risky adventurers.Game ReferencesThe game has several references to RPGs and other video games. Some of these are as follows:Breath Of Fire: The title, Breath of Death VII, is an obvious play off of this game.Paladin's Quest: The game's first town, Palad-Lennus, is a reference to this game.Lennus: Just like above but the second part of the title of the townEarthbound: The town Motherbound is a reference to this series.Lufia: The town Lufestopolis is a reference to this game.Langrisser: The town Langsong is a reference to this gameWarsong: Same as above except its the second part of the title of the town.Zelda II: When you beat the Junk Robot boss he says "I Am Error." This is a famous line from Zelda II.Fallout: The opening sequence states "War never changes." This line is used in the Fallout series.Resident Evil 4: The shop owners are a reference to The Merchant.Mega Man: The game's opening sequence states "In the year 20XX." This is a reference to the Mega Man games which take place in the year 20XX. Also a character named Dr. Dark is a reference to Dr. Light.Adventure: The game's hidden optional boss, Dragonduck, is a parody of the Dragons ( Grundle, Rhindle and Yorgle) from Adventure which look like ducks.Phantasy Star IV: The scene where Dem and Sara first leave Palad-Lennus together is directly ripped out of Phantasy Star IV.Final Fantasy VII: There is a move in the game called Cross Slash. One of Cloud Strife's Limit Breaks is called Cross Slash. Also the VII in Breath of Death VII could possibly be referencing the game.Super Mario Bros: When you are looking for Prince Eric one of the characters from the castle states "Perhaps the prince is in another castle."Atelier Iris: Sara goes up to one of the soldiers in the castle, she says "SOLDIER." The soldier replies back "BARREL."Castlevania Symphony of the Night: When Dem speaks to the troll chief at the beginning of the game the chief says, "What is an undead man? A miserable little pile of secrets!" The narrator replies, "Enough talk! Have At You!" This references the famous opening conversation between Dracula and Richter Belmont.Diablo: When speaking to one of the guards in Motherbound Castle he says "Stay a while and listen." A line often spoken by Deckard CainPC System RequirementsOS: Windows XP, Vista, 7Processor: 1.6Ghz or higherMemory: 1GBHard Disk Space: 200 MBVideo Card: DirectX 9.0c compatibleDirectX®: 9.0c compatibleSound: DirectX 9.0c compatibleAdditional: Current version of Windows Media Player</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16305">Dragon Warrior</game><game id="15629">Breath of Fire</game><game id="8403">Final Fantasy</game><game id="8307">EarthBound</game><game id="2254">Dragon Warrior VII</game><game id="33626">Cthulhu Saves the World</game><game id="34061">Bonded Realities</game><game id="36252">Penny Arcade's On the Rain-Slick Precipice of Darkness 3</game><game id="32108">Faery: Legends of Avalon</game><game id="41682">Penny Arcade's On the Rain-Slick Precipice of Darkness 4</game><game id="43309">Cosmic Star Heroine</game><game id="39473">Dragon Fantasy: Book II</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3948/1351281-xboxboxart.jpg</image></root>