<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31042</id><name>Planet Minigolf</name><description>Overview Planet Minigolf is a minigolf game that features 16 courses in 4 exotic locales, customizable characters  courses, online  local multiplayer, and                   PlayStation Move support. Additionally, players have the ability to save replays and     upload  them to youtube.  Many of the holes contain power-ups, which are located on the fairways, and are obtained by simply rolling into them with your ball. These power ups can help you navigate some of the trickier parts of the course, by doing things like making your ball lighter so it floats, making your ball a magnet so it gets sucked uphill, or even giving you control of your own ball, allowing you to steer it using the          sixaxis tilt function of your controller. The game allows you to pick one of three control schemes. The first setting, called "easy", is a one-click method that allows you to pick the power of your shot by simply holding down the  button.  The second setting is the popular "three-click method", where you press the  button 3 times to decide the power and accuracy of your shot. The third setting has you pull back and push forward on the left analog stick for power and accuracy.   A fourth control scheme is available using the PlayStation Move motion controller, which was patched into the game for free September 19th, 2010.Courses Planet Minigolf features 4 different locations:  SoHo (London neighborhood city theme)Ancient Valley (jungle  Mayan ruins theme)Buccaneer's  Hideout (tropical island  pirate theme) Polar Station (snowy research station  UFO crash site theme)   Each location has 4 minigolf courses, and each course has 9 holes, totaling 144 holes to play in the game.   Downloadable Content Stronghold Island - Features 36 new holes in a medieval castle ruins-themed area in the Mediterranean Sea. Also comes with new tiles and objects that are usable when creating your own courses. Multiplayer  Planet Minigolf features local and online multiplayer, as well as  worldwide leaderboards and tournaments. There is also a course  editor, which will allow you to create and share user-made courses with  the community. </description><genres><genre id="28">Golf</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="31462">Mini Golf Pur</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/6/63119/1352404-planet_minigolf.jpg</image></root>