<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3113</id><name>GripShift</name><description>OverviewGripshift, although lacking a story, throws you into a wacky world filled with doodads, weapons, racing and plenty of frustration.  Pressing start and hitting 'Restart Level' will become an instinct.  The game has a slew of unlockables and levels to experience but with only a few cars and characters to accompany them. The goal, if there really is one, is to collect all of the credits in the game to achieve the 100% completion mark (SEE: Credits / Unlockables section).  Use the doodads (rocks, trees, etc) to your advantage to make better angled jumps with a mix of boost to cut your times and complete your objectives!  Visit the 'PLATFORM SPECIFIC CONTENT' section of this page to view content that each version of Gripshift has for you to experience.   Track ThemesAll of the tracks and theirs surroundings (doodads) in the game are based off of four themes.  The theme names are self explanatory.- Jungle- Desert- Ice- Horror Credits Brief description of the credits system in Gripshift:         In total, there are 2000 credits in Gripshift.  There are milestones for achieved credits that upon reaching said milestone, unlockables will become available (SEE: below).  Credits can be earned by doing various objectives.  During race missions, one can earn credits by collecting bronze, silver or gold amounts stars (but still winning) or by getting a bronze, silver or gold time on the track.  During challenge tracks, credits can be earned by grabbing the Gripshift icon (and completing the level after getting the icon), collecting the bronze, silver or gold amount of stars (and finishing the track) or by getting a bronze, silver or gold time on the track. UnlockablesUnlockables range from new characters, cars, car decals, wheels for your cars and music.  Each unlockable is obtained by reaching a certain credit milestone.  (To find out what cars, car decals, wheels, characters and music are available in the game, continue reading below in their respected sections.) Characters / Drivers Character/Driver models do not effect the performance of the cars.- Sasse- Bud- Dante- Stacey- Tommy Battle- Fly Car Skins The cars color is able to be changed between 25 colors across the rainbow while a decal is equipped or not.  If a decal is on, part of its color will change as well.  BUT, with some decals equipped, the user will be unable to change the body color due to the button being greyed out.  Car skins do not effect the performance of the cars.- Basic (Plain paint job with no skin.)- USA- Union Jack (British Flag)- Syn (Hood flames)- Racer (White race stripe)- Flames (Flames covering car)- Tribal (Tribal pattern)- Bling (Dollar signs litter the car)- Sidhe (Race stripes and the sidhe logo/mascot on the car._- N2 Fern (Stylish design, similar to leafs on the rear end.)- Camouflage- Neon (Vibrant line pattern, TRON-esque.)- Hazard (Dukes of...)- Moo (Cow spots)- Spider (spiderweb design)- Taxi (Chekered design)- Italian- Spanish- German- French- Japan Wheels Wheels do not in any way effect the performance of the cars.- 2Endos- Astrals- Hammers- Arachnids- Args- Fangs- Hydras- Spinners- Hovers (Tires flipped horizontally with a blue aura glowing below them.  Gives you the sense that your car is floating.) Hood Decals Hood Decals do not effect the performance of the cars.- No decal- Sharky- Star- Cat- Insane (Pumpkin)- Bombs- Paw- Hoof- Bulls Eye- Sid (Sidhe logo/mascot)- Yin Yang- Tagger (Spray Paint Can)- Peace- Loop- Wrenches (Skull and Crossed Wrenches)- Penguin- Sad- Cow- Duke ( the number 01)- Zoom (the word: Zoom!)- Rocket- Gripshift (GS token) CARSTraxion - The beginner car in Gripshift.  The Traxion has average speed and good handling.  (Perfect for levels where tight maneuvering is a necessity.)                   TOP SPEED  =  3/5 Stars                   ACCELERATION = 3/5 Stars                  HANDLING = 5/5 StarsChoppa - What it lacks in overall speed, it makes up for in acceleration. (Okay for challenge maps but don't expect to set many records or win every race.)                  TOP SPEED = 2/5 Stars                  ACCELERATION = 4/5 Stars                  HANDLING = 4/5 StarsGravla - Well-Rounded car with a better sense of speed than the traxion.  (Good for all around use in every mode.)                 TOP SPEED = 4/5 Stars                 ACCELERATION = 3/5 Stars                 HANDLING = 3/5 StarsStrike -  Slightly re-focused Gravla, but still a well-rounded beast.  (Also good for every mode, but slightly preferable over the Gravla for cluttered tracks with hard turns.)                 TOP SPEED = 3/5 Stars                 ACCELERATION = 4/5 Stars                 HANDLING = 4/5 StarsColt -  American muscle at its finest, flexing its speed prowess on the track.  (Great for gaining a lot of speed for jumps!  Although being slightly better at turning then the Bruiser, it is also slightly slower.)                 TOP SPEED = 4/5 Stars                 ACCELERATION = 5/5 Stars                 HANDLING = 2/5 StarsBruiser -  The fastest herse in town.  But make sure you don't get in its way, it might not be able to miss you.  (Great for non-twisty race tracks and challenge tracks.)                  TOP SPEED = 5/5 Stars                  ACCELERATION = 5/5 Stars                  HANDLING =  1/5 Stars Track Pick-upsNitrous - Blue canisters with an "N" found on most levels in which when driven into (collected), one's boost meter will fill and at any capacity, one can press the boost button to drain your boost meter but give the car a nice boost useful for catching up during race tracks, making jumps and making turns (with short bursts)....On almost all tracks, the basic objectives (stars and GS token [Only Challenge tracks for GS token] ) and nitrous can be found.  But on some levels, green rimmed clocks can also be picked up.Clocks -  These green-rimmed clocks help the user by putting a few seconds back onto the game clock before time runs out and you fail the challenge track....During Race tracks, players can be equipped with a few gadgets to aid them in beating their oponent to the finish line.The Question Mark - The question mark pickup randomizes the aid that the player recieves between weapons and defensive items.  The choices are slim however, only 3 gadgets.         1.  TNT -  The player can drop TNT behind his car for trailing oponents to run into and be stunned, however, these TNT crates only stay on the track for a limited amount of time.         2.  Rocket -  The player can shoot a homing rocket at his oponent to stun them, but these rockets aren't always 100% hits.         3.  Shield - The shield is obviously not a weapon but protects the driver.  When hit by a rocket or after running over a TNT crate while having a shield equipped, the player's shield will just disappear, not effecting the player's driving.  The shield, like the TNT crate, does disappear after a certain amount of time in use By stunned, I am referring to the oponents car stalling and being reset on the track nearby where he/she was struck with a weapon.  Player's can only have 1 weapon lined up to be used.  If the player rides over another question mark, no new items will be added for later use, nor will the previously held item be changed.  So a smart strategy could be for the leader of the pack to keep rocket in stock in case he loses the lead at any point. MultiplayerOnline multiplayer is provided in every version of Gripshift, with the ps3 version limited to just race track versus while the xbox 360 can do races and deathmatch arena battles and the psp version can do race versus and share user created levels.There is however, no split screen offline or online multiplayer on either console version of the game, nor is there any Online race versus standings. Challenge Mode Levels List In Challenge Mode, when you start the track, no matter what objective you are aiming for, a countdown timer appears and if you don't get to the finish line in time, you will be forced to retry.  Also, Rankings/Leaderboards for each of your quickest level times are supplied and can also be checked on your computer at www.SidheInteractive.com Beginner Levels                 Samples (Youtube Videos)     1.  Accelerate                                     2.  Round the Bend     3.  Stars     4.  Nitrous     5.  Go Off Road     6.  Race Challenge 1     7.  Checkpoint     8.  Loop the Loop     9.  Back and Forth   10.  Drawbridge   11.  Fork in the Road   12.  Race Challenge 2   13.  Down   14.  Speed Ups   15.  Fans and Ramps                  (Sample)   16.  Rock It   17.  Power Jumps   18.  Race Challenge 3   Easy Levels   19.  Easy One   20.  Any Door Will Do   21.  Tight on Time   22.  Move Along   23.  Draw A Blank   24.  Race Challenge 4   25.  Loop Mania   26.  Puck   27.  Moving Platforms   28.  Dropoff   29.  Narrow Band   30.  Race Challenge 5   31.  Jump Pad   32.  Loop Too   33.  Stepping Stones   34.  Bank On It   35.  Right Or Left   36.  Race Challenge 6   37.  Petra   38.  Gold Rush   39.  Bouncy Bouncy   40.  Push Me Crush You   41.  Bomb   42.  Race Challenge 7 Intermediate Levels   43.  Handbrake Turn   44.  Off Road   45.  Camberquick Green   46.  George   47.  Elephant of Surprise   48.  Race Challenge 8   49.  Rampland   50.  Rampalot   51.  Hurry Up   52.  Stairway   53.  Rite of passage   54.  Race Challenge 9   55.  Junglicious   56.  Speed Pup   57.  Snail Trail   58.  Ramp Up   59.  Speed Ports   60.  Race Challenge 10   61.  Desert Run   62.  Rocks of Ages   63.  Guest Stay   64.  Mags    65.  Hang Ten   66.  Race Challenge 11   67.  Bobapalooza   68.  Dinofall   69.  Thin   70.  Which Way Now   71.  Teleports   72.  Race Challenge 12 Hard Levels   73.  Magnetize   74.  Minefield   75.  bomb Run   76.  Dodge 'em   77.  Handbrake   78.  Race Challenge 13   79.  Commercial Brake   80.  Rock Hard   81.  Power Tour   82.  Moving Maze   83.  Warp Party   84.  Race Challenge 14   85.  Spaghetti Arrabbiata   86.  Downhill Fast   87.  Speedy McSpeed   88.  Dreadloops   89.  Jump Skillz   90.  Race Challenge 15   91.  Beary Quick   92.  Plummet   93.  Elemental   94.  Beans   95.  Grasshopper   96.  Race Challenge 16   97.  Right To Drive   98.  Gone Loopy   99.  Rampant 100.  Sliders Revenge 101.  Slidey Slalom 102.  Race Challenge 17 103.  Falling In Love 104.  Compact 105.  Quad Spin Crazy 106.  Day At the Links 107.  Shove Off 108.  Race Challenge 18 Insane Levels 109.  Straight  Narrow 110.  Perfect Move 111.  Defanestration 112.  Dust Hill 113.  Shove  Smash 114.  Race Challenge 19 115.  Magnet Madness 116.  Incredijump 117.  Twisty 118.  Starry Starry Night 119.  Jimsanity 120.  Race Challenge 20 121.  Trapped 122.  Death By Warp 123.  Drawback 124.  #1 Fan 125.  Jump Maze 126.  Race Challenge 21 127.  Brain Wrong 128.  In Pieces 129.  Snake run 130.  Traptastic 131.  Temples of Doom 132.  Race Challenge 22 133.  Fanbase 134.  Monster Speed 135.  Intertwined 136.  Traveleater 137.  Krushko 138.  Race Challenge 23 139.  Fanatic 140.  Mind the Gap 141.  Rings 142.  Slippery Slope 143.  Decent Descent 144.  Race Challenge 24 145.  Magnetrode 146.  Haunted 147.  Bridge Out 148.  Precision 149.  Magnaloop 150.  Race Challenge 25 Race Mode Levels There are four sub-modes under Race Mode; these include 'Single Race', 'Time Trial', 'Practise' and Championship.  Under each sub-mode, the same race maps are played but under different circumstances.  Championship includes 1 extra difficulty, Ultimate, which pits the player up against all 25 race tracks with 7 laps on each track.  All Race Mode tracks are the same as the 25 Race Challenge tracks during Challenge mode, but given names. Beginner Tracks- Round and Round- The Loop- Easy Oval Easy Tracks- Ski Jump- In Finite- Crossroads- Sweeping Intermediate Tracks-Downhill Sass- Fridge Racer- Lupi- Stack Race- Run Forest Run Hard Tracks- Speedster- Mt Jim- Long Run- Racing Beans- Rocket Science- Pew Pew Laser Insane Tracks- Hard  Fast- Jump Track- Figure of Hate- Tight Turns- Evil Oval- Highway 112- Final Circuit Music Soundtrack All music in the game (when unlocked) can be played at any time by pressing the 'Start Button', selecting 'Options' and then selecting 'Change Music'.  You start off with a few songs, but you must unlock more by earning credits during the game.  The music is not organized by artist in the game.  I merely chose to list them this way for ease. ||---------Artist-------||||||--------Song-------------------------||North Shore Pony Club  -  Vice                  The Upbeats  -  Late Nite Fright                             B-Line  -  Getchagroove                             B-Line  -  Freeway               Greg Churchill  -  Shock Rocket 2006               Greg Churchill  -  Loony Bin 2005            Salmonella Dub  -  Gospel According To Mant                       Filterbrats  -  Street Lights                       Filterbrats  -  Pikelits                       Filterbrats  -  Tinkera                       Filterbrats  -  Ice Cream                       Filterbrats  -  Frights                       Filterbrats  -  Whakatane                           Undertow  -  Nose Bleed                     Flash harry  -  Chain Saw                               Minuit  -  This Music Is Good For The Species                               Minuit  -  A Room Full of Cute                               Minuit  -  Fuji                      Perception  -  I Want It                      Perception  -  Thumpa                      Perception  -  Caviar                      Perception  -  Miracle             Rhian Sheehan  -  Bounderies (Module Remix)             Rhian Sheehan  -  Cosmology  (Agent Alvin Remix)                                Oose  -  K-Phun                                        Oose  -  Pulsar                             Module  -  Star and Sky                             Module  -  Nitro Is Good                             Module  -  Night Riding                             Module  -  Pedal 2 the Metal            Misfits of Science  -  Shift (Module Remix)           Misfits of Science  -  Fools Love (Ragga Remix)           Misfits of Science  -  3 Days of the Blender           Misfits of Science  -  Attack of the 'Riders           Misfits of Science  -  Mmmhmm           Misfits of Science  -  Catch Up           Misfits of Science  -  Fools Love           Misfits of Science  -  Shift  (Gripshift Theme Song) Platform Exclusive Content CONTENT                                                                PSP                   XBOX 360                    PS3Track Editor                                                                                      YES                                   NO                                    NO           Turbo Expansion Pack                                                                   NO                                    YES                                   NOSome Content In Expansion Pack Others                               YES                                   NO                                    NODeathmatch Arenas                                                                         NO                                   YES                                   NOOnline Multiplayer                                                                            YES                                  YES                                  YESRankings/Leaderboards                                                                NO                                    YES                                  YESFor Details on any of the content listed above, please visit www.SidheInteractive.com </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8972">TrackMania</game><game id="13008">TrackMania Sunrise</game><game id="10362">TrackMania United Forever</game><game id="6240">TrackMania Nations ESWC</game><game id="21436">TrackMania Nations Forever</game><game id="22406">Trackmania DS</game><game id="14777">TrackMania: Power Up!</game><game id="23186">Supersonic Acrobatic Rocket-Powered Battle-Cars</game><game id="29822">TrackMania Wii</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1388551-gshift_box.png</image></root>