<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31147</id><name>Final Fantasy III</name><description>OverviewDeveloped by Matrix Software, the DS remake of Final Fantasy III is based on the original 1990 game for the NES that was never released outside of Japan. Though the basic flow of events remains the same as that of the original version, the storyline has been rewritten to account for four all-new protagonists; Luneth, Ingus, Arc, and Refia. In the original version of Final Fantasy III, the player characters were four children with no unique backgrounds or personalities. This version of Final Fantasy III was later ported to Android and iOS devices, as well as the PSP.New FeaturesThe remake of Final Fantasy III features a number of changes and additions that weren't present in the original version. These changes include:New Starting ClassIn the original version of Final Fantasy III, the default starting class for the four party members was "Onion Knight." In the remake, Onion Knight has been remade as a special unlockable class. As a result, the starting class is a new class called "Freelancer."Secret DungeonAn optional dungeon can be found in an underwater region after meeting the prerequisites. Inside this dungeon is an optional boss, the Iron Giant, which is more powerful and difficult to face than the game's final boss, Cloud of Darkness.Wi-Fi SupportPlayers may send messages to one another over the Nintendo Wi-Fi Connection by using the in-game Mognet service. Characters within the game will also periodically send messages to the player. Sending and receiving messages to and from other players is part of the process that unlocks the Onion Knight class, as well as the secret bonus dungeon.ClassesThe full list of classes available in the DS version of Final Fantasy III Is as follows:FreelancerWarriorMonkBlack MageWhite MageRed MageThiefRangerKnightScholarGeomancerVikingDragoonDark KnightEvokerBardBlack BeltMagusDevoutSummonerSageNinjaOnion Knight</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="36942">Genso Suikoden: Tsumugareshi Hyakunen no Toki</game><game id="40312">Dragon Quest VII</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1814628-box_ff3ds.png</image></root>