<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31214</id><name>LittleBigPlanet 2</name><description>OverviewLittleBigPlanet 2 was developed by Media Molecule and is a PS3 exclusive. Originally scheduled for a November 16th 2010 release, the game was delayed to January 18th, 2011.The story mode featured a brand new adventure and wacky characters, while showcasing the new set of features in the form of objectives. Players still control Sackboy or Sackgirl, collect stickers, decorations and tools which they can use in create mode. Whereas creators where restricted to making platforming games in the original Little Big Planet, LBP2 broadened the gameplay possiblities immensely, allowing the creation of dual stick shooters, racers, fighting games, RPG's, real-time strategy games and so on. Creators have since been able to exploit the engine to give their creations a three-dimensional appearance, though the games that employ this are usually unstable and are graphically inferior.HistoryLittleBigPlanet 2 was first revealed in the June 2010 issue of Game Informer, with an official announcement from Media Molecule announced alongside a trailer shortly after.During the lead-up to E3 2010, Media Molecule invited a handful of the original LittleBigPlanet top creators over to their studios for a "Community Game Jam" event for LBP2. The creators were given a challenge to create a level within 24 hours. The winner was given a prize and all of the contestants had their levels briefly shown at E3.Later, at Gamescom 2010, PlayStation Move content was showcased. Briefly shown in motion before LBP2's reveal, it was confirmed that 10 additional (separate from the main story) levels would ship on the disc, with tools for level creation for the Move coming later. This was later announced as Sackboy's Prehistoric Moves, a PSN for up to two players locally.August had the announcement of a Beta trial for both LBP2 and the new web-portal LBP.me that allowed players to promote their levels, search for levels and even add them to a que for instant acces on the console. The Beta was originally restricted to specific European users, and after a lift of the Beta's Non-Disclosure Agreement (NDA), was available to North American users as well.While development was approaching the original release date of November 16, Media Molecule announced that the game would be pushed back to January 18th, 2010 in order to better polish the game, most likely due to responses during the Beta tests. This also lead to an extension of the Beta trial itself.September held the official announcement of Sackboy's Prehistoric Moves for release on December 15th (still free on the LBP2 disc), and a story only demo of LittleBigPlanet 2 for December 22nd.Less then a week before the game's release, Sony with the help of IGN announced an event for the Guinness Book of World Records 2011 Gamer's Edition. On January 17th through to the 19th, a selected group of players sat down and played LittleBigPlanet 2 for a total of 50 hours and 1 minute (with mandatory breaks in-between) to get the following records:Longest marathon playing LittleBigPlanet 2Longest marathon playing a platform video gameMost video game genres played in one video game in 24 hoursMost user-generated video game levels played in 24 hoursMost user-generated video game levels played in a marathonAnd also recognition for the following records:Most gaming genres in one video gameMost player-created levels in one video gameGameplayLittleBigPlanet 2's main focus is no longer platforming, although that is still an integral part. The game's new level creation tools allow for much more than simple platforming gameplay.The game's new motto a "Platform for Games", tells of the new focus of the creation aspect: Allowing the user to create the experience they want to share.Examples mentioned are racing games, fighting games, RPGs, and more.This new initiative presents itself in the developer levels, where a lot of the tools that the players use are in turn used by the devs to create these new skewed genre level varieties.Sackboy's interaction is no longer limited to jumping on buttons or grabbing switches or blocks. New tools (that are detailed below) allow each button on the controller to be literally wired to a multitude of commands, opening up control schemes to the creator.StoryThe game starts with Sackboy frolicking about in a developer/pre-credits level, when he is then attacked by an "inter-dimensional, hyper-spatial, 1800 watt Vacuum Cleaner" known as the "Negativitron". Before Sackboy can be sucked up, Larry Da Vinci intervenes and rescues Sackboy.Some of The Alliance. From left to right: Avalon, Victoria, Eve, and Larry. Not Pictured: Clive and Dr. HigginbothamLarry is the leader of "The Alliance", a group dedicated to fighting the evil vacuum cleaner before it destroys the Cosmos. Sackboy gets recruited to The Alliance so they can fight off the vacuum cleaner.The story totals 50 levels and the themes span several mixed time-period styled abstract design as opposed to country based history which was how the original themes were structured.Da Vinci's HideoutTechno Renaissance: a mix of microchips and electricity with wood, chalkboards, and hand-made structures. This is where you meet Larry Da Vinci, the short-tempered leader, who trains you on the basics of gameplay to see if you're worthy of his group: The Alliance. You are also introduced to the grappling hook power-up, and where you first see the Negativitron. The final Boss Level is Larry in a wooden monkey-mech that uses electric yo-yos to attack.Victoria's LabSteam  C ake: steampunk mixed with 'a little girl's tea party'. Here you meet Victoria Bathysphere, an insecure bipolar baker, whose kitchen has been invaded by evil cupcakes manipulated by the Negativitron. Here you are introduced to the Creatinator, being used in these levels as a "Cakeinator." The Boss Level is a creature that sprouts legs, and climbs a building after Sackboy, using electric floors and beams to attack.The Factory of a Better TomorrowNeon Propaganda: Cold War style propaganda mixed with a grim feeling neon factory. Here you find Clive Handforth, a depressed calendar, who lost his factory's control to the Negativitron. Sackboy n eeds to free the Sackbots from being enslaved by the factory. The Boss Level is actually a chase sequence where you must run away from the factory's guard chicken Copernicus.AvaloniaFluffy High-Tech: take high-tech future, and throw in fluffy bunnies and sheep. Here is where you meet Avalon Centrifuge, a vain character with a very high ego. This is where you are introduced to the Controlinator, which is attached to multiple fluffy animals and creatures. In this Boss Level, you must protect "Huge Spaceship" from a Negativitron created attack robot.Eve's AsylumDesigner Organic: nature and design, where plants become architecture. Here, Sackboy meets up with Eve Silva Paragorica, the self-absorbed curator of the asylum. You need to defeat the Negativitron manipulated Sackbots in order to get to Dr. Higginbotham to can repair Huge Spaceship. One of the levels features a top-down caterpillar driving sequence as well as using a Creatinator to douse flames in water. The Boss Level is actually you shrinking down inside Dr. Higginbotham to defeat the meanies inside him.The CosmosHand-Made Arcade: Arcade influenced levels combined with space, this is also the final showdown, and a combination of all the things you've learned. Having saved Dr. Herbert Higginbotham, a far-thinking far-out professor, he repairs Huge Spaceship and everyone sets course for the Negativitron. You're briefly introduced to changing gravity before you finally take on the Negativitron. The Final Boss is of course the Negativitron. Use a Creatinator hamster, your grappling hook and bounce pads, and finish him off with old fashioned throwing things at him.New Create Mode Features and Tool-setsMore tips and descriptions on tools and logic can be found in the ever growing LittleBigPlanet Wiki. The following only details additions and changes from LBP1.New "Create" DevicesControlling "Direct Control"The Controlinator is a tool that allows the creator to assign commands to the controller when Sackboy is in the seat. Almost every button and option is mappable including the Sixaxis tilt commands. The trigger radius for entering the seat can be tweaked, setting automatic entering, enabling exiting, and even setting remote controls that allow your sackperson to be as far away from the device as they want. All this combined allows creators much more vehicle manipulation then Sackboy's simple jumping grabbing switches and buttons.Sackbots of many sizes, and some of their cool features.Sackbots by default look like a squarish Sackboy without a face, like a puppet or marionette. But by adding a costume to the Sackbot, you can make them look like any type of Sack-person, including ones who play the level they're in.Sackbots can be tweaked to single layer restriction, have a fear of hazards or heights, be faster then a regular Sack-person, use old and new pick-up power-ups, use multiple animation styles based on the story characters, and even record player movements for animation.Sackbots can follow or flee from Sackboy very well, even over pits, they can use direct control seats to follow Sackboy if the device isn't too complicated, they can even be controlled by Controlinators.Movers are tools that do just as their titled. They can be controlled using logic switches and improved with Anti-Gravity Devices (detailed below) to make the effects of flying machines and such. They allow more freedom then complicated piston contraptions.Linear Movers are controlled by the x and y speed with properties for speed, acceleration, and deceleration. They move along the x and y axis relative to the level or the object. A follow/flee device can be used to set the Mover to follow/flee a Sack-person or Magnetic Key, with maximum/minimum distance settings, and x/y axis movement locking. There is also a non-physical magic rocket tool that simulates the existing jet tool, but can be compacted into microchips.Rotational movers have the same logic control as the linear Movers and a look at player/magnetic key option. A gyroscope tool will attempt to stand the object upright vertically, which can be tweaked for speed and activate via switch.The final special Mover moves things between layers. The movement according to the physics is instant, but the animation takes time. The movement cannot be stopped mid animation, so no keeping things off the set layers.The SequencerThe Sequencer was originally intended for strictly music, but as the developers used it, they found it could be used to trigger more then just the music. When placed, a timeline appears similar to a circuit board when using Microchips. When the creator selects an Instrument, an editing window appears displaying a keyboard and another mini timeline with different mix, key, and visual tools.Not only can music notes be added, but logic triggers can be placed to allow music based gameplay triggers, and more cinematic quality. For sequences without music, a regular music-less sequencer exists.MIDI InstrumentsThe Instruments featured in LBP2 are MIDI based. The original ones focused more on retro video game sounds, while the 17 additional instruments included in the Move Pack focused more on classical sounds. Media Molecule synthesized these sounds and developed some of them closely with Baiyon.Keys: Honkytonk PianoKeys: PianoPercussion: 8 bit KitPercussion: Acoustic Kit 1Percussion: Baiyon Kit 1Percussion: Beatbox Kit 1Percussion: Beatbox Kit 2Percussion: Synth Kit 1Percussion: Synth Perc. Kit 1Plucked: Bass GuitarPlucked: Electric Guitar (muted)Plucked: Electric Guitar (distorted)Plucked: Electric Guitar Power ChordsPlucked: HarpSFX: Baiyon GuildfordSFX: Baiyon KyotoSFX: Record StaticSynth: Baiyon Bass 1Synth: Baiyon Bass 2Synth: Baiyon ShinySynth: Baiyon TinkleSynth: BellSynth: E-PianoSynth: GhostSynth: HarpsichordSynth: Mime ArtistSynth: MosquitoSynth: NoiseSynth: Pulse WaveSynth: Ray GunSynth: RobotSynth: Saw WaveSynth: Sine WaveSynth: Space PianoSynth: Square WaveSynth: StringsSynth: TennisSynth: Triangle WaveSynth: WoodpeckerSynth: WormTuned Percussion: GlockenspielWind: ConcertinaAdditional Instruments included in the Move PackPlucked: Col LegnoPlucked: Double Bass PizzicatoPlucked: EktaraTuned Percussion: Glass HarmonicaPlucked: KotoPlucked: Nylon String GuitarPlucked: Strings LegatoPlucked: Strings PizzicatoTuned Percussion: KalimbaTuned Percussion: MarimbaTuned Percussion: Music BoxTuned Percussion: Tubular BellsTuned Percussion: VibraphoneVoice: Choir AahsWind: BassoonWind: BrassWind: ClarinetNew "Play" DevicesThe Grappling Hook controls are simple. Press R1 to shoot out the hook that only latches onto surfaces that can be grabbed. You can reel in/out by pressing the right stick up/down, and swing with left/right.The Creatinator is a helmet that works as an emitter on your head. The creator chooses the object(s) that are emitted, and you point the helmet, press R1, and it emits in that direction.Grabinators let the player lift items over their head with R1 and carry them between layers to throw them. You can pick up and throw other players or Sackbots.Bounce Pads are like trampolines that can be tweaked for specific heights. Also, multiple Sack-people wont mess up each others jumps.New "Create Mode" Devices and ImprovementsObjects can now be hidden to edit areas behind them by tapping R1.You can now group select individual objects by holding R2 when selecting them using the popit cursor. This is similar to PC Ctrl-Clicking.There's an option where objects can be rotation snapped by any 5 degree increment up to 90, for those precise rotations.Popit navigation improvements like a full screen option, sort by color option, collapsible categories, the ability to create custom categories you can use for sorting, and a new section showing all the pop-it items used the level for easy access to already used stickers or objects.Joystick Rotator - Attach the analog stick of a Controlinator to this, to create 1:1 analog rotation.Anti-Gravity Tweaker - Allows an object to be partially or not affected by gravity. Dampening options allow the object to slow down as it moves.Collision Switch - Activates upon a collision of anything, like a sack-person, an object/wall, an specifically tagged object, or any combination.Material Tweaker - Can change the bounciness, friction, grab-ability, or destructibility of an object so it can't be crushed.Lethalizer - Can make any object lethal or non lethal with either Fire, Electricity, Gas, or the new Plasma element.Smoke Machine - Can tweak the color or intensity of smoke. Better effect then the jet from LBP1, and no noise.Score Switch - Increase or decrease scores for the person who activates them, even through logic.Score Detector - Activates when a set score is reached.Level End Switch - Set to Win or Lose the level when activated.Notes - Little notes that allow comments for players or creators.A preview mode changes the display of objects that are normally invisible in Play Mode to invisible in Create Mode, so you don't have to constantly play-test levels to see how they would look when published.UV Tool allows creators to shift around the texture on a material instead of having to adjust the whole material.Advanced Glue lets users glue two specific objects rather then all the objects next to the material.Magnetic switches and proximity switches can be set to activate on specific layers.Magnetic Key Switches can use labels as well as colors to allow multiples of magnetic keys in the same space (think: microchips). The color and the label must match for the key's logic to activate. Also, when in the tweaking options for the switch, all the angles and ranges of the switches that match will be shown. Finally, the key's themselves can be activated/deactivated by logic."Signal type is determined at destination, not source. This allows for multiple signal types from a single device. So a magnetic switch could output speed to a wheel and on/off to an LED."Emitters have effects for emitting and destruction of the emitted object: Explosion effect (no damage), appear/disappear (no sound), dissolve (like in LBP1; with sound), and shrink/grow.Along with any item in your pop-it, Emitters can use an item in the world without having to save it in the pop-it. Any changes to the object in the level then get reflected in all Emitters, including Emitters in Emitters, etc. When done editing the object, you can delete it to lock its memory to each Emitter.New Bullet objects. Simple pre-made Fire, Water, Electric, or Plasma bullets to use for your levels.You can set your level to a variety of specific types. Cooperative, the standard/default type. Competitive, that allow separate scores, score limits, and a timer that deathlessly (read: can still "ace" the level) transports the players to the scoreboard where line-graph tallies are shown. And Movie, where you show off cinematics that set-up and lead into other levels. Competitive and Movie both add banners around your level badge to further indicate the level type to players.Level Linking Badges allow users with multiple levels (like in a series) to stream levels together, unlike level keys which still only show the levels the keys linked to. Use level link's with the Sub-Level option to create a series of small levels link into one grand saga, as Sub-Level rate/comment options lead back to the starting level.Much more flexible create thermometer; levels don't fill up as quickly.When using Magic Mouths, users can record and use their own voice over the game's stock gibberish sounds. Then can also use subtitles only when placing the mouths on a sequencer.New "Logic" Tools for "Create Mode"Logic is the term used for activating, deactivating, or influencing the level using sensors or switches.Microchips projecting circuit boardsMicrochips are a new tool that allow logic on circuit boards to be condensed into a small scape, thus saving physical space in the level, and saving thermometer room.Any logic or even tool that you would normally stick to the side of a contraption in LBP1 can be added onto the circuit board. Magnetic Key sensors and Emitters use the Microchips to act as the position of the sensor.Even Microchips can be in Microchips!New Logic Chips:NOT - Output is made the inverse of the input.AND - All inputs must be active to activate an output.OR - Output is made if at least one input is active.XOR - Output is made if an odd number of inputs are active.Battery - Always outputs.Toggle - Inverts output each time an input is given.Timer - Outputs speed/strength proportional to its current value. It can also be reset.Selector - Cycles through each of its outputs every time it is activated. Can also take overrides to jump to specific outputs.Counter Switch - Increases a counter each time is is activated up to a maximum value. Can also be reset.Randomizer - Many options can be used to vary up the randomization pattern.Directional Splitters/Combiners - Allows a bi-directional signal (like from a three way switch or analogue stick) to be split or combined into its signals.New "Create Mode" Visual Tools/ImprovementsCameras can now be zoomed back further and can be rotated on the plane it is placed on. Thus the camera can go sideways and even upside down.Cameras now have a number of effects: pan, angle / zoom, camera shake effects, fades and other transition effects.The cutscene mode can allow player movement, so the camera effects can add new visual experiences and effects.Activation times can be added to cutscene cameras and Magic Mouths so that they can be closed on cue. They also have output switches that can be used to activate another mouth/camera/trigger once the scene ends.There is a camera mode for flatness that makes the game look like "front view" from create mode in LBP1.It is also possible to allow each player their own camera in a level. This will help with multiplayer levels or races that will let each player see their Sack-person better.There are many more Sound Effects in the game. Volume control is optional on each sound effect as well as a setting to allow the sound to be heard anywhere in the level despite the distance. Reverb and other audio effects can be added to each sound.Comparing the new lighting and textures to the oldThe Global Sound Tool can change the music and sound volume via switch or trigger as well as globally apply sound filters on everything in the level.Lighting has been greatly improved, with a better engine, a wider variety of colors, and fog can be changed by percent rather then on/off from LBP1.New "Create Mode" MaterialsLight Matter, exactly the same gravity-free material as LBP1's Dark Matter, but it is beige and without the rounded edges.Fluffy Materials use LBP2's new rendering power.Animated Materials can have the animation speed altered and come in many styles like water, chocolate, and space.Filter Glass Materials effect objects behind them visually like retro green lines, x-ray effects, pixelated, and more.Holographic Material is a translucent, internally lit, semi-transparent looking material. Color can be tweaked and has a brightness option. It can be altered with switches with the "off" and "on" states being tweakable. Transparency can be altered via stickers too. The material can't be affected by gravity, and can go through objects, with the option to set off collision switches.New Creator FeaturesA creator is allowed to create 20 levels maximum in order to prevent an abundance of spam or low quality levels. In addition, a creator is still allowed 20 maximum levels to import from the original title.Along with the standard trophies that the game will have, Media Molecule also told of a 'pin system'. Sort of like internal achievements, the pins will detail hundreds of micro-events that you've completed or achieved in the main story/game or online (including a pin for each trophy task). You are then able to choose three pins to place on your in-game creator picture that shows up with your levels or creator profile. This helps players understand the type of player/creator you are when they brows your levels.An example of a few of LBP2's planet themes.Another neat thing is customizing the LittleBigPlanet itself. In single-player, each level set (usually consisting of a few levels and survival challenges) changes the appearance of the planet to better fit the themes of the levels.Well, when in the main menu, you can now add stickers and decorations to the planet itself. Then when another player views your levels or profile on the system, the planet changes into the one you created.In LBP2, you can even customize the entire planet.Patches and Patch NotesPatch 1.01 - "Cupcake" - 7.5MB - Released Feb. 14th, 2011Full Official patch notes found HERE.Some important fixes:Captured DLC costumes like the Crown that were pirated through glitch levels will be stripped from all players.Broken PODS will be reset along with an easier reset option.Changing your PSN avatar will no longer make a giant Craftworld block your view.Patch 1.02 - "Apple Cake" - 13MB - Released Mar. 8th, 2011Full Official patch notes found HERE.Some important fixes:Players that glitch imported beta profiles and were wearing DLC they didn’t own could still wear them.1.01 stripped rare DLC items that the players didn't own, however the DLC is still visible in pop-it although with an exclamation mark over its icon. Players could highlight these items and very quickly press O and X, which would allow the user to still wear it.Patch 1.03 - "Battenburg" - 13MB - Released April 15th, 2011Full patch notes found HERE.Some important fixes:The music sequencer no longer skips the first few notes when activated by Logic.Fixed a stability issue to do with the player being disconnected from the host when on a loading screen.Patch 1.04 - 13MB - Released July 4th, 2011Update containing DLC data.Patch 1.05 - 93MB - Released July 12th, 2011Full patch notes found HERE.Some important fixes:The "Spawn Pop" / "Growing Sackboy" glitches, as well as the "Overlord" glitches and any issues surrounding them have been fixed.Fixed Sackboy re-sizing/deforming their Sackboy.New interface for in-game PlayStation DLC store.Patch 1.06 - 567MB - Released Sept. 6th, 2011Full patch notes found HERE.Some important fixes:Fixed the "Local Space" camera option.PlayStation Move Support for all future and existing levels.Added free tools: Speed, Rotation, and Angle Sensors and the Slice 'N' Dice Tool.Recommended minimum and maximum players option.Additional tweaks options for Bounce Pads, the Water Bullet, Magic Mouths, the Score Giver, the Game Camera.Added the "More Stories" section for faster DLC story pack access.Added content for the PlayStation Move DLC Pack including the data, additional pins, and trophies.Community  Online Network: LBP.meThe LBP.me Front PageTags from LBP1 were being redone to make them more meaningful. A creator can now assign tags with more vote weight then other player tags.Writing good level reviews (as voted on by others) makes your vote weigh more. They can be written on LBP2 or on LBP.meEvery LittleBigPlanet user will be granted a profile on LBP.me, a better way of tracking, sharing, and promoting creators and their levels, as well as a way to check out the LittleBigPlanet while away from your PS3.Features of LBP.me include an activity feed, level previews, a level queue, leaderboards for your levels, and integration of QR Codes that can be printed for sharing.Levels picked by Media Molecule (Mm Picks) get a special "seal of approval" to help distinguish them from the herd. As well as seals for versus levels and cinematic/movie levels.MusicAlong with the Sequencer, the tool used in LBP2 to program music tracks (among other things), a number of licensed track titles have been seen."A Go Go" by Trüby Trio"A Fifth of Beethoven" by Walter Murphy"Also Sprach Zarathustra" by Daniel Pemberton TV Orchestra"Automaton" by Lorn"Batteroo" by The Planet Rockers"Disco Divertimento" by Daniel Pemberton"Disco Shmisco" by Kenneth Young"Elevate This" by Kenneth Young"Finale" from "The Gadfly Suite, OP. 97a" Composed by Dmitri Shostakovich and preformed by the Ukraine National Symphony Orchestra"Ghosts" by Ladytron"I Have Changed" by HP Riot"Infontain Me" by Ochre"Limehouse Blues" by Django Reinhardt"Mahalageasca" (Felix B Jaxxhouse Dub) by Mahala Rai Banda"New Family" by Plaid"Planetarium" by Squarepusher"Rock Your Body Rock" (Original Little Big Edit) by Ferry Corsten"Silver Surfer, Ghost Rider Go!!!" by Trentemoller"Sleepyhead" (Instrumental) by Passion Pit"Vision One" (Instrumental) by Röyksopp"What Are You Waiting For?" (Instrumental) by My Cheap Little Dictaphone"Whoever Brings the Night" (Instrumental) by NightwishThere are also tracks that were used in trailers, but not in the finished game:"You Look So Pretty" composed by Peter O'Shea, Patrick Hanna, Mark Chester, and Bronwyn Murphy-White."Jump On It" by Sugarhill Game Apache.Content Transfer, Built-In Content  User LevelsWhen starting the game, if a LBP1 player has created a Profile Back-Up, that player will be prompted to transfer his profile over to this sequel.Everything unlocked from the 'vanilla' version of LBP, as in costumes, stickers, and materials will be transferred. The single player levels will not transfer.All downloadable content costumes, stickers, material, and tools will transfer. DLC made for LittleBigPlanet 1 disc can be purchased and played in LBP2.Also, Game of the Year Edition bonus DLC levels are not accessible. Only the DLC that is unlocked in this GOTY version will be transferred.Any DLC released for LittleBigPlanet 2 will not be compatible with the original game, or the Game of the Year Edition.LBP1's water creation tools from the Pirates of the Caribbean DLC (only the tools, not the levels or costumes) are usable for create mode in LBP2 without the purchase of the pack from LBP1. Also all of the content from "Creator Pack 1", such as the Global Lighting and Infinite Checkpoint, is accessible.The Metal Gear Solid Paintinator is NOT built-in and must be purchased and transferred.All 3 Million user levels made for LBP1 can be accessed, played, and even filtered in LBP2, but levels made in LBP2 can only be played in LBP2.All levels you have on your Moon will also transfer to LBP2, but you will still be limited to a 20 level publishing cap. However, your 20 level publishing cap for LBP1 will remain untouched, essentially allowing you to publish 20 LBP1 levels and 20 LBP2 levels.Re-publishing a LBP1 level in LBP2 will also render the level unplayable in LBP1. So if you wish to make touch-ups, make sure to edit and re-publish while in LBP1.</description><genres><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26848">ModNation Racers</game><game id="35117">BEEP</game><game id="21989">My Pokémon Ranch</game><game id="39928">Oddworld: Abe's Oddysee New 'n' Tasty</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1794116-box_lbp2.png</image></root>