<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31233</id><name>Dragon Ball: Raging Blast 2</name><description>Overview The game was announced in the May 3rd issue of                                                                                                                                                                                                                             Shonen Jump Magazine. It was developed by                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                     Spike for the                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            PlayStation 3 and                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                           Xbox 360 and released November 2nd, 2010. Spike are the same developers of the                                                                                                                                   Dragon Ball Z: Budokai Tenkaichi franchise, where this game pulls many elements from. Making this franchise more-so a successor to the last. Gameplay   The usual start of a fight.     Raging Blast 2's gameplay stems from the same tree all of Spike's Dragon Ball fighting games grow from. Battles take place in a 3D space as opposed to the popular 2D style, with the fighters flying into mid-air combat or being slammed unto underwater struggles. At  times, a character's "lock-on" can break, leaving the character unable  to preform precision attacks or special moves until he re-spots his  opponent. The game also has the fast paced combat you would expect in a                                                                                                                                                                                                                     Dragon Ball game, although now the game will slow down at points of counteracting to allow the human player(s) to react.   Graphics Dragon Ball hero Goku in his new coat of HD paint.       Instead of the original game's anime inspired graphics that resemble the show, this new style more resembles a more real look that is hand-painted with shading and gradients. This makes the characters look less like classic                                                                                                                                                                                                                        cell-shading and more like the backgrounds they fight on. The game has also been stated to run at                                                                                                          60 frames-per-second, just like the                                                                                                           previous game. Single Player Although there is no deep telling of the story, the    Dragon Ball Z story is played out again in this sequel. Contents from the                                                                                                                          Saiyan arc,                                                                                                                        Namek arc,                                                                                                                       Android arc, and                                                                                                                      Majin Buu arc appear as well as content from Dragon Ball Z                                                                                                                   movies and                                                                                                                  specials. Also showing are some developer made "What-If" match ups.  Galaxy ModeGalaxy Mode is a very loose telling of each characters progression through their DBZ story (as mentioned above). You follow a chain of fights that eventually lead to their story climax, with branching and challenging paths along the way. Through this mode players unlock modifiers they can use on their character to increase their Health, Ki, and attacks as well as other buffs and modifications. All of which can be carried over to other single player modes and multiplayer (local and online). Progressing through this mode unlocks almost every other playable character and level, but not all the modifiers.Battle ZoneBattle Zone is similar to other fighting games challenge type modes. Here you select a character and then fight a set of characters called a zone. Each zone has a theme to the characters and each fight has a set amount of challenges in them which when complete unlock more modifiers. These challenges request things like 'don't use super attacks' and 'don't use any modifiers', even requesting that you use a de-buff item. Finishing the final fight, and thus the zone, unlocks more goodies too.Tutorial  Training Also included is the standard tutorial and training modes. Tutorial helps show you how Galaxy Mode works, and Training is fighting practice. Shenron  PorungaAlso standard in DBZ games is the summoning of an eternal dragon.   Shenron is the standard summon and can grant you a modifier, a level, or some background music that can be selected before matches out of "Single Play". Porunga randomly shows up when summoning the Dragon Balls, and he allows you to select three things from the list as opposed to the single selection Shenron lets you have.MuseumCharacter EncyclopediaThis is the place where you find character bios. and voice samples for the characters you have unlocked. Pretty simple and strangle becoming a standard with Spike games...BGM CollectionA way for you to listen to background music tracks while out of a fight. Each track is numbered, allowing you to tell if you haven't unlocked all of them yet.Battle ReplayThis is where you go to view any replays you've saved from a fight. You can also delete them.View PictureAs you play through Galaxy Mode, you'll unlock pictures from the anime that usually correspond with the fight you are in, or the character you are playing as. This is the place where you can view them.View MovieTwo "movies" are available by default: The opening movie and the "Dragon Ball: Plan to Eradicate the Super Saiyans", which is talked about next. The remaining "movies" are the credits, and both Shenron and Porunga's Dragon Ball summoning sequences from the game, which are unlocked after you've unlocked everything on their list.  "Plan to Eradicate the Super Saiyans"           An August 2010 issue of Shonen Jump Magazine revealed one of the game's more interesting features... It was originally a plot to for a                                                                                                                               NES card battle game from 1993, also being made into 2 VHS "Official                          Visual Guides", and a year later made into a                                                                                                                              Playdia FMV game.  Comparing the original animation to the new Known as "The Lost Movie" among fans, the OVA "The Plan to Eradicate the  Saiyans" has been "completely reconstructed, re-scripted and re-edited" into a 30 minute short. This new version, being renamed "Plan to Eradicate the Super Saiyans" will be available on the retail game disc and watchable immediately. Sadly, only English subtitles are available for North America, due to licensing and time issues. Players who watch this the whole way through are treated to a bonus in-game character, the movie's antagonist                                                                                                            Hatchyack. This will be the first time this character has been playable in anything. Other Modes   Battle   This is the standard local multiplayer or "vs. CPU" mode. You can select  from Single Battle (1 on 1), Team Battle (1-5 vs. 1-5), or Power Battle  which gives all the selectable characters a "power level", and you can  choose a max of 5 but you have a power level cap (meaning stronger  characters have a higher level).  World Tournament   Select between the regular World Tournament of the Cell Games (with  custom rules in-between), choose your fighter, and compete. The new  thing here is optional commentary that follows along your fight with  many oohs and awes.Options Here you can adjust your screen size, the screen shaking, your controller configuration, brightness, sound effects/volume, captions, and whether the game's characters speak English or Japanese.Online PlayStandard  FreestyleStandard is a fight between characters without any modifiers where only their moves are customizable. Freestyle is the opposite, allowing you to select a custom character that has its modifiers and moves already set. You can even select a character that you've used in Galaxy Mode.World TournamentSimilar to the Single Player version, but online. Battle Points and online ranking aren't affected.LeaderboardsThroughout the game, your single player scores are being uploaded to the Leaderboards, that combined with your ranked matches are displayed here.Battle RecordHere you can view said battle records, as well as change your online title that people can see before fights.Fighting StagesBattle arenas are said to be bigger then before. Spanning the ground,  sea, and air at similar fighting locals from the previous game, and of the anime.    Confirmed Arenas  Arenas new to this sequel are in bold.Abandoned City Cave                                                                       Cell Games ArenaDark Planet † Glacier † Islands                          Janemba's Hell †                           Kami's Lookout †                                                                        Planet Namek Ruined NamekRocky Land                                                                    Supreme Kai's WorldWasteland World Tournament Stage† Stages new to this sequel. 4 total.Playable Characters  Character Select ScreenThis game features over 100 characters to the first game's 73  (including transformations for both numbers).  Of these 27  new characters, 6 have never before been playable in any Dragon Ball game.  Playable CharactersCharacters and forms are listed Alphabetically. Base stands for a character's normal state. SSJ is the common abbreviated form of Super Saiyan (Saiya-jin).                                                                                                                                           Android 13 [Base †, Super ]                                    Android 14 ‡                                    Android 15 ‡                 Android 16                    Android 17       Android 18                                                                                                                                                                       Android 19                                                                                                                                                    Bardock                                                                                                                                       Bojack [Base †, Full Power †]                                                                                                                                                    Broly [Base, SSJ, Legendary  SSJ] Broly - Super Saiyan 3                                                  Burter                                                                              Majin                                Buu Super Buu [Base, Gotenks, Gohan]Kid Buu                                                                                                                                                                                  Captain Ginyu                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        Cell [1st, 2nd, Perfect Form, Perfect]                                                 Cell Jr. †                                               Chiaotzu                                                          Cooler [Base †, Final Form †] Meta-Cooler †                                              Cui †                                                                                           Dabura †                                                                                                                                                   Dodoria           Doore ‡                                                                                                                                                                           Dr. Gero                                                                                                                                                  Frieza [1st, 2nd, 3rd, Final, 100%] Mecha Frieza †                                                                                                                                                    Gogeta [Super Gogeta]  Kid                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        GohanTeen Gohan [Base, SSJ, SSJ2] Gohan [Base, SSJ, SSJ2]Ultimate Gohan  †                              Future Gohan [Base †, SSJ †]                                                                                                                                                   Goku [Base, SSJ, SSJ2, SSJ3]             Goten [Base, SSJ]                          Gotenks [Base, SSJ, SSJ3]                                               Guldo                                                                                           Hatchyack ‡                                                                                            Janemba [Super †]                                                                                                                                                                    Jeice                                                                                                                                                     Krillin                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    Nail †                                             Nappa          Neiz ‡                                                                                                                                                    Piccolo                                                                                 Pikkon †                                                                                                                                                    Raditz                                             Recoome                                          Saibamen †            Salza †        Tarble ‡                                                             Tien                                                                                                                                                                        Trunks (Sword) [Base, SSJ]Trunks (Fighting) [Base, SSJ, Super] Kid                         Trunks [Base, SSJ]                                                          Turles †                                                                                                                                                    Vegeta [Scouter] Vegeta [Base, SSJ, Super, SSJ2] Majin VegetaVegeta - Super Saiyan 3                                                                                                                                                   Vegito [Base, Super Vegito]          Videl                                                                                                                                                                             Yamcha                                                                      Zangya †                                         Zarbon [Base, Monster]† Characters added to this sequel; Not new to a game. 21 total.‡ Characters new to this sequel and first playable debut in a game. 6 total.</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="30539">Naruto Shippuden: Ultimate Ninja Storm 2</game><game id="20689">Tekken 6</game><game id="20678">Soulcalibur IV</game><game id="20449">Mortal Kombat vs. DC Universe</game><game id="38786">Naruto Shippuden: Ultimate Ninja Storm 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2352249-box_dbrb2.png</image></root>