<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31277</id><name>Monster Hunt</name><description>Generally: This is the classic arcade game created by Maik  Heinzig,  and  published by mhs-Studio.  Players attempt to eliminate monsters,  ghosts, bats and other baddies.  This game is the first of a series. The  next is "Monster Hunt 2" and the last is "Monster Hunt revenge", but  this titel is unpublished.    The full name of the game:Monster  Hunt is short for: Monster Hunt or the little Wonderland.  Story:Our  hero Maxi Mini needs to rescue his girlfriend from the claws of the  evil Popmuckel. His journey takes him through different landscapes and  many dangerous situations. To acchieve his goal he should collect as  many bonus items as he can to get more than the initial three digital  lives he has. There is one extra life for each 99 bonus items collected.  He should also pay close attention to specially marked stones, because  touching one of those turns them into an "Atari" mark, which should be  collected quickly. The more of these he collects the better his  equipment will become.   Maxi will turn green after  collecting one Atari mark; this allows him to destroy stones more easily  and will also get him more points. Atari mark two will allow our hero  to shoot at the smaller enemies and the thrid Atari mark will give him  more time to explore levels. Mark four gets him an extra life and of  course bonus points; should he be able to collect five or more Atari  marks, he will get different extras and naturally more bonus points. If  Maxi looses one of his lives, all previously collected Atari marks are  gone as well.   The hidden entrances to the Bonus  Levels is a special recommendation for our hero, as he can collect bonus  hearts here with ease. Unfortunately, these entrances are hard to  find.Sometimes an arrow will lead the way though. Since Mini must be  rescued as fast as possible, time is very limited. If Maxi is too slow,    one of his lives is gone. The same happens if he touches a monster,  ghost or one of the elements water, fire, earth (dust) or falls into the  abyss. But there are also many useful items to find such as a secret  door which skips the whole level. Too bad that these doors are invisible  and therefore hard to find.   Popmuckel has placed  some magic stones all over the levels. Should Maxi touch one of these,  he is glued to the stone and it will cost him one of his lives. In the  higher stages there are no neutral enemies anymore and life will get  harder and harder for Maxi. Available: Monster  Hunt 1 obtainable of Floppy Disc (1991) and Cartridge(1999). The   Cartridge version is very rare ( prototype ).     Re-released:    In 2007 the game was re-released for PC as "Jump Jack".          In  gamecharacters:    Maxi - The hero   Mini - in the credits   Popmuckel - in the  story   Eumel - a restless enemy of a different game   Joki - The Jokerman  Octi - one eyed Qctopus  Batzi - the brown Dog   Lots of monsters, ghosts, bats and  other baddies.    Characteristics  of the original version:   - No more than 10 lives  are possible. If more lives have been collected, the message "Too many  lives" will pop up and the game will end. This was implemented on  purpose to make life a bit harder for users with a freezer module.   - But a bug in level design made it possible to reach more than 10  lives anyway. To do that a heart must be collected at the very left of  the screen and the character must be moved to the left of the screen  continously. If the heart item was placed very close to the edge of the  screen the bonus collection did not stop and the player only had to take  care, that he did not collect more than 10 lives.     Different to cartridge:    - The level bugs are fixed - more Level - other  End with a little animation</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19726">Mario Bros.</game><game id="15544">Super Mario Bros.</game><game id="13277">The Great Giana Sisters</game><game id="31282">Jump Jack</game><game id="31278">Monster Hunt 2</game><game id="31631">Jump Jack 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/94457/1374131-mh1_main.png</image></root>