<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31334</id><name>Iron Grip: Warlord</name><description>StoryThe game takes place in Theia, a dieselpunk world which blends Napoleon era politics with World War II technology. The player assumes the role of an Atelian Warlord. The player must protect their cities from the Confederation army, which plans on taking hold of Alteria and see you as an obstacle in their path.GameplayThe game pits a small group of players against wave after wave of enemy soldiers. Players must hold back the invaders and protect their stronghold. Defeating large quantities of enemies, vehicles and defeating their Officers reduces their morale. Victory is achieved once the enemy morale reaches zero. Player morale is decreased should the enemy manage to take down their Stronghold.The game mixes both FPS and RTS elements. Both these revolve around Power. Power is the game’s currency, slowly generating over time and increasing when enemies are killed. Large Power bonuses are granted should an Officer be killed, should a player find one of the few treasures scattered around the map or should the enemy harm a civilian.Players can use Power to help strengthen their own character. This includes the purchase of a small variety of weapons, or benefits that affect their character such as health regeneration, damage increase, movement speed increase and so on. On the other hand, Power can also be used to build fortifications and buildings. These range from basic infantry and anti-vehicle turrets to supply stations to traps to rebuilding their stronghold. Turrets can further be upgraded to increase damage and durability.PC System RequirementsOS: Microsoft Windows 2000/XP/Vista/7Processor: Pentium 4 2.0 GHz or Athlon XP 2000+Memory: 512 MB of available system memoryHard Drive: 550 MB of available hard drive spaceGraphics: 128 MB OpenGL compatible Video Card (FX 5200 or Radeon 8500 or better)Sound: DirectX Compatible Soundcard</description><genres><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="29601">Nuclear Dawn</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/4/47392/1382228-256px_warlordslogo.jpg</image></root>