<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31347</id><name>Just Dance 2</name><description>Overview  Just Dance 2 is the sequel to the original      Just Dance  for the   Nintendo Wii. This game continues what the original introduced in terms of a rhythmic dancing game while also adding various new game modes such as the two player cooperative Dancing Duet where your dance moves make you interact with your partner, the calorie-tracking Just Sweat Mode, and the team-based Dance Crew Face-Offs, and can be played with up to eight players. There is also a Track List mode that lets you make a playlist of songs and dance through them without having to worry about score or doing the correct movements at all.  Game Modes  Just Dance - Select any song and go for the high score.  For 1-4 players.   Dance Battle - Competitive mode for 2-8 players.  Within Dance Battle, the following options are available.  Dance Battle does not allow the user to freely select songs, instead it provides a random song and the option to reshuffle the selection once.  Dance Battle: Players complete the regular choreography and scoring.  Medley: A medley of songs.  Simon Says: A song's regular choreography is displayed, but each player will independently be tasked with either stopping or clapping in time for short periods.  Race: Each player completes the choreography, attempting to be the first to reach 4,000 points, at which time the song ends.  Duet: Players complete 2 player duets, but the highest score wins.  Workout Mode: Select songs and the game tracks calories burned.  TracklistUbisoft has confirmed that over 45 songs will appear in Just Dance 2, up from the 32 in the original. The entire setlist is:  Avril Lavigne - Girlfriend **Benny Bennasi - SatisfactionBeyonce Knowles - Crazy In Love *Blondie - Call MeBollywood - Katti Kalandal **Boney M. - RasputinBritney Spears - Toxic *Charleston - Mugsy Baloney **Cher - The Shoop Shoop Song (It's In His Kiss) **Digitalism - IdealisticDonna Summer - Hot Stuff **Elvis Presley - Viva Las VegasFatboy Slim - Rockafeller SkankFranz Ferdinand - Take Me OutHarry Belafonte - Jump In The Line **Ike  Tina Turner - Proud MaryJames Brown - I Got You (I Feel Good)Jamiroquai - Cosmic GirlJunior Senior - Move Your FeetJustice - D.A.N.C.E.Ke$ha - TiK ToKKool  the Gang - Jungle Boogie *Kris Kross - Jump * **Madonna - Holiday *Mardi Gras - Iko IkoMarine Band - Sway (Quien Sera) **MIKA - Big Girl (You Are Beautiful)Outkast - Hey Ya!Quincy Jones  His Orchestra - Soul Bossa Nova **Reggaeton - Baby GirlRihanna - S.O.S.Snap! - The PowerSorcerer - DagombaSupergrass - Alright **The Bangles - Walk Like An EgyptianThe Beastie Boys - Body Movin' (Fatboy Slim Remix)The Frighteners - Monster MashThe Jackson 5 - I Want You BackPussycat Dolls - When I Grow UpThe Rolling Stones - Sympathy for the Devil (Fatboy Slim Remix)The Ting Tings - That's Not My NameThe Weather Girls - It's Raining MenVampire Weekend - A-Punk **Wham! - Wake Me Up Before You Go-Go*This song is a cover; not performed by the original artist.**This song is a duet, allowing a pair to dance together, each with their own unique dance moves.Downloadable ContentUbisoft has released DLC for the game purchasable in the in-game store. Each song is priced at 300 Wii Points (US$3.00) and includes a completely original dance routine. The current songs available for download are: Katy Perry - Firework ***Aqua - Barbie Girl * **Rihanna - Pon De ReplayM.A.R.R.S. - Pump Up The VolumeMichael Sembello - Maniac *Steppenwolf - Born To Be WolfNick Phoenix  Thomas Bergersen - Professor Pumplestickle ***This song is a cover; not performed by the original artist.**This song is a duet, allowing a pair to dance together, each with their own unique dance moves.***This song was released for free.Open casting On May 7th 2010, Ubisoft announced an      open casting via Facebook for the background dancers that will be featured in the game. The final casting was held in Paris on May 31st.</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="31705">Dance Central</game><game id="31787">SingStar Dance</game><game id="32238">Gold's Gym: Dance Workout</game><game id="31724">Michael Jackson: The Experience</game><game id="32856">Kidz Bop Dance Party! The Video Game</game><game id="31801">DanceMasters</game><game id="34611">Country Dance</game><game id="35532">Dance Central 2</game><game id="35638">Everybody Dance</game><game id="34784">DanceDanceRevolution</game><game id="36861">Nickelodeon Dance</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2331124-box_jd2.png</image></root>