<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31391</id><name>Bloody Good Time</name><description>Overview Bloody Good Time is set in a Hollywood studio, where Director X is making his next batch of horror movies, with the small exception that all the violence, action and killing is not acting; it's real. There are three different movie sets (maps), and four game play modes that are further tweaked with variant rule sets. Game Modes The game modes in Bloody Good Time feature unique rule sets, but one thing is consistent between all of them:  you cannot just murder with complete free will.  This is due to NPC security guards who will attack any character openly brandishing a weapon on sight, meaning that players have to be careful to take out their target without being detected by security.  There are also security cameras that may spot you killing someone or carrying a weapon, which can lead to being "wanted" by the security.  You can outrun and hide from guards to lose your wanted level.  If you are caught by a security guard, your character will be tazed and lose whatever equipment you are currently using.  All of the game modes are called "scenes" in the game, and many matches will consist of up to 12 different scenes.  Some matches will rotate the different types of scenes between rounds, while others will concentrate solely on a main scene type.  Over the course of the game modes, you'll gain Fame, which is indicated by the number of stars you have collected.  You gain Fame by killing with style (boasting and/or humiliating a player before and after a kill), killing with higher-starred weaponry, using traps instead of weapons, and creative kills (like killing someone by kicking them in the crotch while they use the toilet).  Anti-griefing measures are in place to prevent extended player abuse.  Since the objective of the game is to either kill your main target (or not kill people like in The Infected), everyone else is considered an innocent.  Killing six innocents will cause you to be stuck in a Spectate only mode for the entirety of a round.Hunt Each player selects a character, and at the beginning of the match, they are given another player (or quarry) as a target for them to hunt down and murder, while at the same time one of the other players (or perhaps even their own quarry) is attempting to find and kill them.  Revenge Each murder you commit gains you a new quarry, but the people you have murdered may in turn murder you for revenge.  These revenge seekers stack up, so you could become the ire of many more than just one person. Elimination Most comparable to a Last Man Standing style of match, Elimination forces you to murder one quarry at a time until you are the last man standing.  Deathmatch Much like tradition would have it, Deathmatch is a free-for-all match where any player can be killed without anti-griefing measures mattering.    Hunt The Leader:  One player in the round is dubbed "the leader", while everyone else is given the job of trying to murder the leader.  Many of the same rules from Hunt, such as security guards and cameras detecting murders, still apply in this game mode as well.   The Infected:  Half of the players in the match are carrying an infection, while the other half are not.  The point is not to kill anyone, but instead to pass the infection through touching the uninfected.  The longer a character has no infection, the better their score is at the end of the round.Scene Stealer:  The goal is to try and hold on to the golden award for Fame, while everyone else is trying to murder the award carrier in order to take the trophy for themselves.  Movie SetsThere are three different movie sets (or maps) that matches can take place on. Spring Break:  Modeled after what seems like old surfer movies, Spring Break features a multi-story skyscraper and a beach house.Vegas:  Lined with slot machines, fancy dinner tables, and bright neon lights, Vegas features the aesthetics of a casino.Horror House:  Graffiti lines many of the walls, but murder lines most of the halls in this ode to classic houses in horror film history.  The Characters The various characters you can play as are just that:  character skins.  There is no difference between any of them in terms of skills, stats, or anything other than pure appearance.  Upon starting a match and choosing a character, a random name generator creates a custom name other than your gamertag for the course of the match.  The Gambler  The Bunny The Beach Babe  The Clown    The Goth  The Showgirl The Stoner  The Surfer Character Maintenance As you play Bloody Good Time, your character will require some maintenance in order to stay in full working shape.  Three "Need" meters will determine your level of sleep, hunger, and waste.  Each of these Needs handles a different aspect of your character.  While you maintain your character, you leave yourself completely vulnerable for attack by other players.Sleep:  As you grow more tired, you will lose speed-related skills, such as slowing down to a walking pace rather than running pace.  To cure this, you will need to sleep on a bed, chair, couch, or other object that allows you to do so.Hunger:  The more strenuous your activities, the more hungry you get.  Hunger affects skills like your overall damage and attack power.  In order to prevent this from happening, you'll need to find something to eat or drink.Waste:  Sometimes, especially after eating or drinking, you might need to poo or pee.  Waste affects skills like your defensive capabilities.  If you want to make sure someone doesn't kill you easily, make sure you stop by the toilet and pop a squat.    System Requirements MinimumOS: Microsoft Windows XP SP2 / Vista SP1 (32bit) / Windows 7 (32bit)Processor: Pentium 4 3.0GHz Dual CoreMemory: 1 GBGraphics: 128 MB, Shader model 2.0, ATI 9600, NVidia 6600 or betterDirectX®: DirectX 9.0cHard Drive: 2 GB freeSound: DirectX 9.0c compatible sound cardPeripherals: PS2/USBFor 6-8 player multiplayer matches, the Recommended System Requirements are strongly suggested.Internet (TCP/IP) and LAN (TCP/IP) play supported. Internet play requires broadband connection and latest drivers. LAN play requires network interface card and latest drivers. RecommendedOS: Microsoft Windows XP SP2 / Vista SP1 (32bit) / Windows 7 (32bit)Processor: Pentium 4 3.0GHz Dual CoreMemory: 2 GBGraphics: 256 MB, Shader model 3.0, ATI X1600, NVidia 7600 or betterDirectX®: DirectX 9.0cHard Drive: 2 GB freeSound: DirectX 9.0c compatible sound cardPeripherals: PS2/USB    </description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19960">The Ship</game><game id="6108">Manhunt</game><game id="18162">Team Fortress 2</game><game id="31001">Assassin's Creed: Brotherhood</game><game id="29539">Naughty Bear</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1514443-bgt_box.png</image></root>