<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31525</id><name>The First Templar</name><description>OverviewMarie, Celian and RolandDeveloped by Bulgarian studio Haemimont Games, The First Templar is a co-operative action-adventure game set during the late 13th century. The game centres around a quest for the Holy Grail led by a templar named Celian d'Arestide and Marie d'Ibelin, the "heretic" daughter of a prominent noble family. The game features third-person hack  slash combat, stealth, puzzles and RPG elements. The game can be played solo (with an AI partner) or in multiplayer (local or online).The Arena DLCIn May of 2011 The Arena DLC was available to purchase on Xbox Live Marketplace. This DLC was actually released on the marketplace before the games US release (but after it's release in Europe). The Arena was made available for 400 Microsoft Points (or $5) and was also included in a special edition release of the game.The Arena DLC has a simple story. The main character has been kidnapped by a man named Byzantine. The player must then escape from an arena by defeating the gauntlet of enemies before facing Byzantine himself.PC System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Windows XP / Vista / Windows 7Processor: 2.4 GHz Single CoreMemory: 1GB of RAM (XP) 2GB (Vista / Windows 7)Graphics Card: 256MB GeForce 6 Series / ATI X 1300Hard Disk Space: 5GBSound Card: DirectX 9 compatibleRecommended:OS: Windows XP / Vista / Windows 7Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo 2.0 GHz / Athlon 64 X2 Dual Core 4600+ (or better)Memory: 2GB of RAMGraphics Card: 512MB GeForce 8 Series / ATI HD 4800 (or better)Hard Disk Space: 5GBSound Card: DirectX 9 compatible</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="34776">Dragon's Dogma</game><game id="33074">The Cursed Crusade</game><game id="30393">Hunted: The Demon's Forge</game><game id="37494">Assassin's Creed III</game><game id="41344">Dragon's Dogma: Dark Arisen</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1783092-box_firsttemp.png</image></root>