<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31555</id><name>Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows: Part 1</name><description>OverviewEA Games and Warner Bros. Interactive Entertainment Inc. announced on June 1st, 2010 that they would be co-publishing the latest installments in the Harry Potter game franchise, based on the film and novel Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows. To maximize the profits available from the final Harry Potter entry, both the movie and video game will be separated into two parts. This page deals with the video game based on the first half of the novel.GameplayPlayers control Harry Potter, the titular character, as he searches for the remaining Horcruxes to bring an end to Voldemort's reign of terror. Except that he won't succeed, since this is only part one of two. Enemy types will vary from creatures featured in previous films as well as a swarm of Death Eaters and Snatchers in the situations surrounding the Deathly Hallows.A trailer was released shortly after that showed some game play footage, which used an over-the-shoulder camera angle and resembled a shooting game. Players will have a range of spells to choose from, and each spell will hold unique properties; some will rapid fire like a machine gun, others will provide a big burst like a shotgun. For the purposes of game play, some of the spells used in the game will have uses or effects that differ from the way the are depicted in the novels. Notably, the spell Crucio is available as a rapid-fire attack despite it being a spell that Harry uses sparingly in the novels, and Expelliarmus disables enemy wands instead of ejecting them from the wielders' hands. However, none of Harry's spells are actually lethal, and any enemies he defeats will vanish by dissipating.</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20497">Dark Sector</game><game id="31749">Sorcery</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2285652-box_hpatdhp1.png</image></root>