<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31580</id><name>Men of War: Assault Squad</name><description>OverviewMen of War: Assault Squad is a stand-alone expansion for the original Men of War title. Remaining in the World War II era environment, the game allows you to take on the role of a soldier from five groups in the conflict. These groups are as follows:FactionGroupNazi GermanyWehrmachtUnited States of AmericaUS ArmySoviet RussiaRed ArmyCommonwealthCommonwealthImperial JapanImperial Japanese NavyAssault Squads allow players to take direct control over troops. This allows a player to control individual soldiers and vehicles in order to combat their enemies.Gameplay ModesAll gameplay modes feature two factions.SkirmishAn attacking force must penetrate increasingly fortified lines of defense and capture all the control points on the map to win. This is the only gameplay mode that can be played solo, but can be played with up with 8 players cooperatively. The defense is always controlled by AI.Assault ZonesEach side fights to control the majority of an odd number of capture points. On a 1v1 map there are three points, 2v2 features five points, etc. If one side controls more points than the other, their point counter will increase. The first side to reach the target number of points wins.CombatEarn points by destroying enemy units. Each unit gives a number of points relative to its cost. First side to the target number of points wins.FrontlinesSimilar to Skirmish except both sides are controlled by users and there is a time limit. Offense gets more resources to spend on timed intervals while the defense has a limited amount of resources. In this mode, each side gets a turn at offense and defense.Day of VictoryIntroduced in the MP Supply Pack Bravo DLC this mode is similar to Assault Zones except there is only one flag to fight over.ChangesAssault Squad makes several changes to the original title, with altered and improved multiplayer balancing. The artillery system present in the game has also been reworked, allowing players to use it in both offensive and defensive strikes at their enemies. Unsurprisingly, new multiplayer maps are also included in the game. Infantry has been reworked in its usage, and rather than buying groups a player can purchase individual troops. Tank ammunition has also been changed, and weapons have been altered to better reflect their real-world counterparts.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18930">Company of Heroes</game><game id="40891">Call to Arms</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5761/1700783-download.jpeg</image></root>