<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31592</id><name>Barkanoid</name><description>Barkanoid   Principle of the game:You are in control of a bat that can be moved to the left and to the right in the lower corner of the screen.  Later, there is an extra that allows vertical control, too. The bat has to be controlled in order to keep the ball on the playfield.  If the ball hits a brick, the brick gets destroyed. Some bricks lose extras on their destruction. If you cleared all the bricks from the playfield, you will get to the next level.  There is an extra called "level - jump". If you manage to collect that extra, you will jump to the next level right away, no matter, how many bricks are left.Basics:This is the first version of Barkanoid ever developed for PC-Windows.  Being the successor of                         Atari Barkanoid, the programmers waived an additional „1“. Barkanoids (1) basics were long known through games like                     Arkanoid and                  Breakout, so the developers decided to put several innovations into the game.  Among, them the 30 extras, to be exactly, 16 extras plus updates.  Those extras were further improved in every successor of Barkanoid 1.  Furthermore Barkanoid had enemies, that were not locked behind walls of bricks in contrast to other break out clones.  Enemies were floating all over the place right from the beginning of the levels. Barkanoid also had boss monsters that had to be defeated every 10 levels in order to advance in the game.   Those boss mob fights remind of a side-scrolling shooter and could not be disabled in the game options.  Another feature of Barkanoid are the colorful, detailed graphics and animations, although Barkanoid (1) does not have a lot of variety through its options.  You could not change bricks or backdrops, like in later Barkanoid games. Regarding the age of the game, the level design was fabulous! It had 100 levels, some of them enormous, colorful and they got harder the further you got in the game.  Sadly, Bakanoid (1) did not ship with a level editor. So the player could not create his or her own levels, like in later games of Barkanoid.Extras:-    6 different kinds of bats in 5 different sizes-    ordinary bat-    glue bat-    bound bat-    automatic bat-    flying bat-    shooting bat Bonuses positiv -    Extra life-    Score doubler-    Lava ball-    Weapon upgrade (5 levels)-    Smart bomb-    Slowdown-    Ball doubler-    Automatic bat-    Wider bat (5 steps)-    Flying bat-    Shooting bat-    Glue bat-    Level jump Negative Bonuses-    Gasified bat-    Beer-    Cage-    Speedup -    Random-    Skull</description><genres><genre id="45">Block-Breaking</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16818">Barkanoid 2</game><game id="12116">Barkanoid 3 Gold</game><game id="31263">Aquanoid GOLD</game><game id="31510">Aquanoid 3 - 3D</game><game id="31591">Break It 3</game><game id="31590">Break it 1</game><game id="15107">Arkanoid</game><game id="14886">Arkanoid: Revenge of DOH</game><game id="31593">Barkanoid 3</game><game id="31397">Barkanoid</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/94457/1394469-barkanoid_cover.jpg</image></root>