<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31634</id><name>Driver: San Francisco</name><description>OverviewDriver: San Francisco is the fifth console title in the Driver series. The game returns to something of a past styling, as it brings the action to San Francisco, which was featured in the first game, as well as restoring the character Tanner, who was the protagonist in the first three games. Also making a comeback are Tanner's partner from Driver 2 and 3: Tobias Jones, and arch-nemesis Jericho (also from Driver 2 and Driv3r) who returns as the villain.StoryStarting six months after the events of Driv3r, Tanner has managed to successfully apprehend Jericho, whereupon he has been extradited back to the United States to face trial. Jericho is secured in a maximum security penitentiary, but has a plan for breaking out as he is taken to court. Using some of his underworld contacts, he has a guard plant an acid pill in his mouth, so that he can break free of his handcuffs. A news helicopter is also sabotaged, and an RPG-7 is used from the moving helicopter to take out part of the police escort. Tanner and Jones pursue the prison van, now controlled by Jericho, though are eventually ambushed in an alleyway by Jericho. Using the superior bulk of the prison van, he slams into Tanner's Dodge Challenger, and forces it into a road, where it suffers severe damage and Tanner is put into a coma.Initially, Tanner himself is not aware that he is in a coma, believing he has simply gained some incredible abilities. He does not realise that he is in a coma for a large amount of the story, though in this dream world he is able to manipulate cars in a manner that other people could not. The game takes place in Tanner's mind, and he pursues Jericho's syndicate as they perform various criminal actions. This ranges from the theft of a large amount of platinum to a small number of classic automobiles.It is shown at the end of the game that Tanner has regained consciousness, and that the world he saw in his mind was based on the news reports he heard from the television in his hospital ward.GameplayAs was mentioned in the story, Tanner ends up in a coma. This has given him an ability called "Shift," which slows time and allow the player to select a nearby car, which they then take over. The developers wanted to bring the game back to its roots, and this meant removing the on-foot gameplay in order to focus on the driving. As Tanner shifts into different cars he will be able to take on different missions. NPCs who might be passengers in the car all have thousands of recorded lines of dialogue. Missions vary from ones related to the story, to humorous side missions such as helping a troubled teenager with their angry driving school teacher.The Shift ability upgrades during the game, from initially allowing a street view, to a block view and eventually allowing them to teleport to the other side of town. Shift is limited to certain missions, and will need to be charged. As to how it will be charged is unknown.In addition, this is the first title in the series to feature officially licensed cars, roughly 140 of them. Unlike most games featuring real cars, they are fully destructible.The San Francisco game area is approximately over 200 square kilometers of driving space. The city of 'Frisco was made famous in the film Bullitt, and like the early games in the series, Driver San Francisco is based on the same premise as '70s car chase movies. The proprietary engine for San Francisco has been developed to allow realistic physics, heavy vehicle handling and cinematic driving, like that of the original Driver.Car listA full list of both licensed and unlicensed vehicles.Licensed:Abarth:500 (2008)Fiat 695 ss Assetto Corse (1970)Alfa Romeo:159 Ti (2009)8C Competizione (2007)Giulia TZ2 (1965)Giulietta (2010)Mito (2009)Spider Duetto (1966)AMC:Pacer (1980)Aston Martin:Cygnet (2011)DB5 (1964)DB9 Volante (2010)Rapide (2010)V12 Vantage (2010)Audi:A4 2.0 TFSI (2010)Q7 4.2 FSI quattro (2010)R8 5.2 FSI quattro (2010)RS 6 Avant (2008)S5 Coupe (2010)Sport quattro S1 - Rally (1985)TT RS Coupe (2010)Bentley:Arnage T (2005)Continental Supersports (2010)Cadillac:CTS-V (2010)DTS (2010)Eldorado (1959)Escalade (2007)Escalade - Cop (2007)XLR-V (2009)Chevrolet:Bel Air (1957)Blazer (2001)C10 (1965)C10 - Tow-Truck (1965)Camaro SS (1968)Camaro SS - Jones’ car (2010)Camaro Z28 (1986)Chevelle SS (1970)Corvette (1960)Corvette Z06 - Drift (2009)Corvette ZR1 (2010)Corvette ZR1 - Cop (2010)El Camino (1973)Impala (2006)Impala - Taxi (2006)Volt (2011)DMC:DeLorean DMC-12 (1983) [ Wiki Page]Dodge:Challenger R/T - Tanner’s car (1970)Challenger SRT8 (2009)Charger R/T (1969)Charger SRT8 (2009)Charger SRT8 - Cop (2009)Grand Caravan (2009)Grand Caravan - Taxi (2009)Monaco (1974)Monaco - Cop (1974)Neon (2002)Ram 3500 Laramie (2010)Ram SRT10 - Jericho’s car (2006)Viper SRT10 ACR (2009)Ford:Crown Victoria (1999)Crown Victoria - Cop (1999)Crown Victoria - Taxi (1999)F-150 XLT SuperCrew (2010)F-350 Super Duty (2008)Gran Torino (1974) [ Wiki Page]GT (2006)Mustang Convertible (2008)Mustang GT Fastback (1968)Mustang Mach 1 (1973)RS200 - Rally (1985)Shelby GT500 (2010)Taurus SHO (2010)GMC:C5500 (2008)C5500 - Ambulance (2008)Savana - News Van (2005)Sierra (1998)Sierra - Monster Truck (1998)Vandura (1983)Hudson:Hornet (1951)Hummer:H3X (2009)Jaguar:E-Type (1966)XFR (2010)XKR (2010)Jeep:Wrangler (1988)Lamborghini:Countach LP400S (1978)Diablo VT (1994)Gallardo LP560-4 (2009)Jalpa (1986)Miura (1972)Murcielago LP640 (2007)Murcielago LP670-4 SV (2009)Lancia:Stratos - Rally (1974)Lincoln:Town Car (2010)Maserati:GranTurismo S (2008)McLaren:F1 (1997)MP4-12C (2011)Mercedes-Benz:McLaren SLR (2008)Nissan:370Z (2009)370Z - Drift (2009)GT-R (2010)Skyline GT-R (R33) - Drift (1998)Oldsmobile:Cutlass 442 (1970)Vista Cruiser (1972)Pagani:Zonda Cinque (2009)Pontiac:GTO The Judge (1970)Lemans (1971)Solstice GXP (2009)Solstice GXP - Drift (2009)Trans Am (1975)Trans Am (1977)Trans Am (1980)Range Rover:Sport Supercharged (2010)Ruf:CTR 3 (2010)CTR Yellow Bird (1987) [ Wiki Page]RK Coupe (2010)RK Spyder (2009)Rt 12 (2010)Shelby:Cobra 427 (1966)GT500 (1967)Volkswagen:Camper (1965)Scirocco R (2009)Scirocco R - Rally (2009)Baja Buggy (1963)Beetle (1963)Beetle Convertible (2009)UnlicensedASYM:Desanne 3.0T (Civilan)Desanne LX (Taxi)Desanne X/T pursuit (Cop)Caisson:Elementary C (School Bus)Fairview (City Bus)Whippet (Tour Bus)Camion:HydraMax 505 (Fire Truck)HydraMax AERV (Fire Truck – Airport Style)Dykemann:Bison 453 (Garbage Truck)Boldius 278 (Old Big Rig – Cab)Dolva C-575 (Fixed-Back Rig Truck – Cement)Dolva R-575 (Fixed-Back Ramp Truck)Dolva S-575 (Fixed-Back Rig Truck – stake/prop)Dolva T-575 (Fixed-Back Rig Truck – Tanker)Haulier SF (Modern Big Rig - Cab)Vandoorn:Atlus 3.8L (Courie)Carson 3.8 (Prison Van)Carson 3.8 (Security Van)Y.A.R.E:Buggy (Boxy Buggy)SoundtrackThe game includes 76 songs. They include:22-20s - Devil In MeAgnostic Mountain Gospel Choir - 10,000 YearsAlan Hawkshaw - Beat Me Till I'm BlueAll Thieves - Only Of YouArchie Bronson Outfit - Cherry LipsAretha Franklin - Rock Steady (alt mix)Basement Freaks - Gypsy Breaks Tal M Klein RemixBeastie Boys - Suco De TangerinaBeck - Black TambourineBig Joe Louis - Go Go TrainBilly Boy on Poison - On My WayBlack Rebel Motorcycle - Club Weapon Of ChoiceClarence Wheeler  The Enforcers - Right OnColdCut - Everything Is Under ControlDeath in Vegas - Sons of RotherDesert Sessions - Subcutaneous PhatDJ Shadow - 100 Metre DashDJ Shadow - Dark DaysDr John - Everybody Wanna Get Rich Rite AwayDr Rubberfunk - Northern Comfort feat. John TurrellEdenheight - PeaceboyEditors - In This Light And On This EveningElbow - Grounds For DivorceFatal - Tuned upFort Knox Five - Kool It ManFunkadelic - As Good As I Can Feel (1969 Version)Hound - Dog Taylor Sitting At Home AloneJamiroquai - Whatever it is, I just can’t stopKram - Ridin HighLCD Soundsystem - No Love Lost (Joy Division cover)Leaving the fold - On YouLiars - Plaster Casts Of EverythingMaps - Let go of the fearMarlena Shaw - California Soul (Diplo Remix)Narco - Worth ItNorthern Light - CocaineOC Tolbert - Along came a womanOverseer - Pump ActionPedro - Fear  Resilience (Cherrystones)Presets - SteamworksPrimal Scream - KowalskiPrimal Scream - If They Move, Kill 'EmQueens of the Stone Age - Lost Art Of Keeping A SecretRecoil - BacksliderRobert Palmer - Sneakin' Sally Thru The AlleySeasick Steve - Big Green and YellerSouthside Movement - I've Been Watching YouSpan - Baby's Come Back (Radio Edit)Stephen Yerkey - Link Wray's GirlfriendSugarman Three - Funky So-And-SoThe Black Keys - Black DoorThe Black Keys - Strange TimesThe Black Keys - LiesThe Black Keys - Your TouchThe ChiLites - Are You My Woman Tell Me SoThe Cure - LabyrinthThe Dirtbombs - Chains of LoveThe Eels - PrizefighterThe Flaming Lips - The Sparrow Looks Up At The MachineThe Heavy - Big Bad WolfThe Heavy - How You Like Me NowThe Heavy - The Sleeping Ignoramus instrThe Heavy Trash - Good ManThe Herbaliser - On Your KneesThe Hustlers - InertiaThe Noisettes - Dont Give UpThe Prodigy - World's On FireThe Stooges - 1969 (Alternate Vocal)These New Puritans - We Want WarTV on the Radio - Wolf Like MeTwo Fingers - Two Fingers (Instrumental)Two Lone Swordsman - Born Bad/Born BeautifulUNKLE - Eye For An EyeUNKLE - UnrealViva Voce Devotion - Viva VodezZz - SoulTriviaAccording to information in the E3 2010 presentation, Tanner's first name, which has never been revealed before, is John, while Jericho's first name is Charles.In the E3 2010 trailer, it says that Jericho is a crime lord. This is not impossible, but would be unusual due to the fact that in Driver 2 he was Solomon Caine's hitman, until he betrayed him. During Driv3r, he was a contract killer, and was responsible for shooting Tanner after he relented and left him alive in Istanbul, Turkey.The game marks not only the return of Tanner after a seven year absence, but also series creator Martin Edmondson, who left Reflections in 2004 due to a dispute with the studio's previous publisher. Tanner did not appear in Driver: Parallel Lines and Edmondson was not involved in its development.The yellow and black-striped Dodge Challenger heavily featured in the game and in promotional trailers is a nod to a "mythical" car in the Driver series: a Buick GSX which was featured in an early build demo of the first game, and was a hidden car in Driver 2.PC System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows XP (32/64 bit), Windows Vista (32/64 bit), Windows 7 (32/64 bit)Processor: Intel Pentium D 3.0 Ghz or AMD Athlon64 X2 4400+ 2.2GhzMemory: 1GB Windows XP / 2GB Windows Vista - Windows 7Graphics: 256 MB DirectX–compliant, Shader 4.0–enabled video cardDirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 10GBSound: DirectX 9.0c – compliant sound cardInternet: An Internet connection is required to activate the game during initial installation</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5648">Burnout Paradise</game><game id="31698">Need for Speed: Hot Pursuit</game><game id="20741">Need for Speed: Undercover</game><game id="20698">Wheelman</game><game id="25485">Test Drive Unlimited 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1885931-box_driversf.png</image></root>