<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31644</id><name>Kingdom Hearts Re:coded</name><description>OverviewKingdom Hearts Re: coded is a Nintendo DS remake of Kingdom Hearts: coded, a Japan-exclusive cell phone title. More than a simple port, the game will be significantly overhauled in its move to the new platform. Re: coded was released in North America on January 11, 2011.StoryFollowing the events of Kingdom Hearts II, Jiminy Cricket and King Mickey review the contents of Jiminy's journal maintained over the course of Jiminy's journey with Sora, only to find a passage that he did not write: "We must return to free them from their torment." Mickey decides to digitize the journal in hopes of discovering the meaning of the passage and where it came from. The player controls a digital version of Sora that explores the journal's contents in an effort to uncover the secret.GameplayBattle SceneThe game is being designed in order to take the story and setting of the original release of coded and infuse it with elements of both Birth by Sleep and 358/2 Days. The battle system will play like the Birth By Sleep battle system, with that game's co-director working on implementing it, as well as designing the maps for the game. The leveling up system in the game will be an expansion of the Panel System that was used in 358/2 Days. The game will also feature an adjustable difficulty selection similar to the system used in another Tetsuya Nomura title, The World Ends With You. In addition to the traditional action RPG gameplay of Kingdom Hearts, Re:coded features some gameplay types not present in previous Kingdom Hearts games such as 2D platforming and traditional turn-based RPG segments.SoundtrackMusic created specifically for Re: Coded was part of the 3rd disc of the Birth by Sleep soundtrack along with original music from 358/2 Days and the Final Mix of Birth by Sleep. The music appears in full orchestrated versions as opposed to the digitized versions in the original DS cart. The following is only original music from Re: Coded:No.TitleLength1.Dearly Beloved2:572.On the Debug!!0:463.Wonder of Electron2:214.No More Bugs!!3:185.Wonder of Electron -Bug Ver.-2:206.No More Bugs!! -Bug Ver.-3:177.Pretty Pretty Abilities3:03Total Length:18:02Use in HD 2.5 RemixRe: Coded is included in Kingdom Hearts HD 2.5 Remix for Playstation 3 (with Kingdom Hearts II Final Mix and Kingdom Hearts Birth by Sleep Final Mix). Like how 358/Days was represented in 1.5 Remix, this version of Re: Coded is not playable and instead is a collection of cutscenes telling the game's story.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23282">Henry Hatsworth in the Puzzling Adventure</game><game id="23977">Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles: Echoes of Time</game><game id="22015">Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles: Ring of Fates</game><game id="21371">Avalon Code</game><game id="25152">Blue Dragon: Awakened Shadow</game><game id="32403">Rabbit x Labyrinth</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1897537-box_khrc.png</image></root>