<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31657</id><name>Jolly Rover</name><description>OverviewIn this classic point-and-click adventure you play as Gaius James Rover, a dog pirate that wants to start a circus. On his journey realizing his dream he has to overcome pirates, love, pirates, empty chest devoid of loot, pirates and the usual puzzles.Extra's to unlock are the Pieces of Eight and Crackers concept art of the character's early development, and music tracks featured throughout the game. Also keep an eye out for flag pieces to unlock bios of the nefarious captains you meet along your adventure.CharactersGaius James RoverNamed after Gaius Julius Caesar, Gaius James "Jolly" Rover is a young dachshund who wishes to be a great circus dog like his father. Instead, he gets stuck running shipments of Jolly Rover Rum from his uncle's plantation. He prefers to go by his middle name, James, and occasionally will call himself Jolly Rover.Governor DeSilverGovernor of Groggy Island, famous pirate hunter, and brother of Captian SIlvereye.Juan LeonTalkative parrot met on Captain Howell's ship. Juan will give James hints on how to proceed in exchange for crackers.Captain HowellNotorious pirate and neither friend nor enemy of DeSilver, Captain Howell shanghais James' boat and shipment of Jolly Rover Rum. Captain Howell's favorite dish is Salamagundi.VoodooMany puzzles in Jolly Rover are solved with the help of Ron Copper's Voodoo book and cheat sheet.PC System RequirementsOS: Windows 7, Vista, XP SP1  2Processor: Pentium IV 1.2 Ghz processor or fasterMemory: 256 MB RAMGraphics: StandardDirectX®: DirectX® 9.0cHard Drive: 160 MBSound: StandardMac System RequirementsOS: Mac OS X 10.6, 10.5.8,Processor: G4 800 MHz or faster processorMemory: 256 MB RAMGraphics: StandardHard Drive: 160 MBSound: Standard</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3019">The Secret of Monkey Island</game><game id="5729">The Curse of Monkey Island</game><game id="10528">Monkey Island 2:  LeChuck's Revenge</game><game id="9058">Escape from Monkey Island</game><game id="25680">Ghost Pirates of Vooju Island</game><game id="10927">Loom</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/11165/1653481-boxshot_full_large.jpg</image></root>