<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31653</id><name>MicroVolts</name><description>OverviewMicroVolts (or ToyWars in Japan) is a Third Person Shooter developed and published by SK iMedia for the PC platform and Steam. You take on the role of 4 toy dolls fighting each other in different arenas in a war. each character is customizable, along with weapons and other accessories, all of which improve the character's stats.GameplayEach character has 7 weapons to choose from: a melee weapon, an SMG, shotgun, sniper rifle, minigun, rocket launcher and grenade launcher, which can be used at all times. there are different variations of each weapon, each with their own stats and attributes. The character's accessories will also aid in battle, providing boosts in different areas such as health, speed, weapon switch, for example. The base health of each character is 1000hp, but can be increased by different accessories.These accessories can be bought in the in-game store using either in-game currency (Micro Points) or Rock Points, which need to be purchased with real money. Certain items are only available with Rock Points. when an Item is bought, an attribute bonus can be selected, and the length of time it is obtained can vary from 7 days, 30 days, 90 days, or it can be bought permanently, usually for a much higher price.CustomizationA look at the wardrobe.There are four initial character archetypes to choose from (See: The Characters). Each of which is billed to have "unlimited" amounts of customization. Each character has seven slots open for equipment. You have a choice of which weapons and items you would prefer to bring into the each match. New weapons can be either earned or payed for in the form of tokens that are purchased from the publisher (much like most Korean free-to-play games as well as EA's own Battlefield: Heroes).CharactersKnox, Pandora, C.H.I.P. and NaomiThere are 4 main characters in Microvolts, Knox, Naomi, C.H.I.P. and Pandora, with the latter two unlockable characters. each character has their own loadouts and accessories. weapons can be used by all characters, but are not shared when equipped.Knox - a male action figure designed on a Hip hop star, and is said to intimidate his opponents with his demeanour.Naomi - a female doll designed after a high school girl in Japanese style. She has a sweet demeanour which can be used to mislead her enemiesC.H.I.P. - is a robot built from spare parts. he is very impatient, and is willing to rush the enemy irregardless of his safety.Pandora - a female doll who uses deception to defeat her enemies. she also has a rivalry with Naomi.Initial BacklashThe proposed similaritiesWhen the initial trailer to H.A.V.E Online was released, quite a few websites and forumites criticized the trailer for having a stylistically and thematically striking resemblance to Team Fortress 2. SK iMedia (H.A.V.E. Online's publisher) offered a rebuttal to these allegations. "Debating (as to if it's a rip off or not) is like having blind men touching an elephant and describing what it looks like." Offering also, "We will reveal the gameplay soon. Other than that, we have no comment at this time." Although actual gameplay has subsequently been posted on YouTube by several players, most forumites choose to believe that the gameplay is still similar (although it as futile as trying to compare InstantAction to Onlive).</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/6/63119/2198350-microvolts_logo.jpg</image></root>