<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3165</id><name>SEGA SuperStars</name><description>Sega superstars is a game developed by Sonic Team for the PS2 and is only playable with Sony's EyeToy peripheral. It features 12 games each built around a popular Sega franchise. The game is one of the highest rated games for eyetoy and showed Sega’s ability to build enjoying games using non traditional interfaces. List of Games  Billy Hatcher and the Giant Egg Players move the egg through the world by rubbing on two targets on the screen and must try to get the egg to the goal while avoiding or crushing the enemies in the level. ChuChu Rocket! Based on the Dreamcast game of the same name players must guide the ChuChu through the level and avoid the KapuKapu’s trying to eat them. Crazy Taxi Players must try to stop the taxi by making as much noise and movement as possible to complete the level.House of the Dead Zombies attack from all directions and players must use their arms, head, legs and other parts of the body to try to hit as many as possible while avoiding the civilians who occasionally get in the way. NiGHTS Into Dreams Based on the Sega Saturn game of the same name players fly as NiGHTS through the rings in the level to reach the goal.Puyo Pop Fever Influenced by the games of the same name the player must position their body to direct as many of the puyos into the corresponding coloured pots whilst avoiding bombs that occasionally drop from falling into these same pots. Samba de Amigo Based around the game of Samba de Amigo on the Dreamcast players choose a song from a list of Sega classics and then must hit 6 different targets on the screen in time with the music.Sonic the Hedgehog Based around the bonus levels from Sonic the Hedgehog 2, Sonic runs down a round tunnel and the player uses his hands to control the position of Sonic and try to collect as many rings as possible earning Chaos emeralds.Space Channel 5 The Morolians show a combination of moves and the player must hit the buttons in time with the music to repeat these steps.Super Monkey Ball Players hold out their arms and use the onscreen display to move their monkey ball around the obstacles of the levels trying to collect bananas along the way.  Virtua Striker Players stand at one side of the screen a ball drops from the top and the player has to head the ball into the coloured balloons on the other side of the screen earning more points for hitting the more difficult balloons. Virtua Fighter Players stand on one side of the screen and must beat a selection of fighters from Virtua fighter by kicking and punching them into submission.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="3">Sports</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6930">EyeToy: Play</game><game id="7172">EyeToy: Play 2</game><game id="4583">EyeToy: Play 3</game><game id="6739">EyeToy: Kinetic</game><game id="9806">EyeToy: AntiGrav</game><game id="16620">EyeToy: Groove</game><game id="3792">Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban</game><game id="20575">Samba de Amigo</game><game id="21168">You're In the Movies</game><game id="26657">Sonic &amp; Sega All-Stars Racing</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/19490/688376-sega_superstars_coverart.png</image></root>