<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31705</id><name>Dance Central</name><description>OverviewDance Central is a dance rhythm game for the Xbox 360, developed by  Harmonix, published by  MTV Games and distributed by  Microsoft Game Studios. Using the  Kinect peripheral, the game is able to scan your body and register the dance moves you are performing. The game was revealed at  E3 2010 during the Microsoft press conference. It was released on November 4th and 10th, 2010 in the US and EU respectively, alongside the launch of the Kinect.GameplayThat girl is poison!The on-screen action is divided into three parts: Your score, the dancer, and the dance slides.A  boombox to the left hand side displays your score and multiplier as well as your star rating. You are scored on how accurately you perform each move and aim to achieve a 5 star rating, not too different from star ranking system found in the  Rock Band and  Guitar Hero series'. As you perform a string of successful moves, you build up a score multiplier gaining you more points for each step. Due to the lack of a  life bar as in previous Harmonix games you are unable to fail songs, basing it all on how well your score and star rating are. The main screen shows dancers demonstrating the moves you must mirror in order to score points. If you fail to match the movement of the dancer, the part of your body which is at fault lights up on the center dancer model. Success is also measured by a ring at the feet of the center dancer which fills as you perform the correct steps. To allow the player to know which steps are coming up, the right hand side of the screen displays dance slides. These small diagrams, complete with a name for each one, allow the player to see which move he should currently be performing and which move will follow. As with previous Harmonix titles, varying difficulty determines the complexity of the moves, allowing players of all skill levels to enjoy the game.The game features three modes:Break It Down! mode runs the user through each dance move used in the selected song. Every move is separately practiced, at slower speed if desired. Then of 3-4 moves are then put together in a small recaps similar to the actual song performance. Every song song is broken down in 2-3 practice and recap segments.Perform It! mode runs through the song from start to finish giving the player a rating on their performance. Additionally the "Workout Mode" option will display time played and estimated calories burned.Dance Battle mode is the multiplayer mode in which two players face off in a hotseat style dance battle.There is some minor player progression available in the form of being able to unlock new outfits for the dancer avatars, by earning stars with them. Similarly new venues are unlocked by increasing total stars on all songs, or by completing challenges. There is also an additional unlockable dancer avatar.Included SongsDance Central comes with 32 songs of varying genres, ranging from the 1970s to today. Each song's routine is categorized under one of seven difficulty levels. Each difficulty level is finished up by a challenge. This is a combination of all songs of this difficulty, which unlocks once the player has scored at least 4 stars on each song.ArtistSong TitleAudio PushTeach Me How to JerkBasement JaxxRendez-VuBeastie BoysBody Movin' (Fatboy Slim Remix)Beenie ManKing of the DancehallBell Biv DevoePoisonBenny BenassiSatisfactionCascadaEvacuate the DancefloorChristina MilianDip It LowThe CommodoresBrick HouseCraig MackFlava in Ya Ear (Remix)Dirty VegasDays Go ByEric B.  RakimDon't Sweat the TechniqueFannypackHey MamiJay Sean ft. Lil WayneDownKool  The GangJungle BoogieKylie MinogueCan't Get You Out of My HeadLady GagaJust DanceLady GagaPoker FaceLipps, Inc.Funky TownM.I.A.Galang '05Nelly FurtadoManeaterNina SkyMove Ya BodyNo DoubtHella GoodPitbullI Know You Want Me (Calle Ocho)Quad City DJ'sC'mon N' Ride It (The Train)RihannaPon de ReplaySalt-N-PepaPush ItSnoop Dogg/PharellDrop It Like It's HotSoulja Boy Tell 'EmCrank That (Soulja Boy)TechnotronicPump Up the JamWreckx-n-EffectRump ShakerYoung MCBust a MoveXbox 360 Game InstallationWhen installed on the Xbox 360 Hard Drive, the game takes up 1.6GB of space. There are no performance gains to be had when installed.Downloadable SongsHarmonix offers downloadable content for Dance Central. Each song will cost 240 Microsoft Points, which is more expensive than anything on the official Rock Band Music Store, due to the choreography, motion-capture, and voiceovers required for each new routine. Harmonix have also included a forum within the games official website which allows users to vote for which songs they would like to see released as future DLC.ArtistSong TitleRelease DateCameoWord Up!November 4, 2010Ne-YoBecause of YouNovember 4, 2010Lady SovereignI Got You DancingNovember 4, 2010Sean PaulTemperatureNovember 23, 2010Tag TeamWhoomp! (There It Is)November 23, 2010The Black Eyed PeasI Gotta FeelingNovember 23, 2010BlurGirls and BoysDecember 21, 2010Janet JacksonControlDecember 21, 2010RhiannaDisturbiaDecember 21, 2010ChicLe FreakFebruary 15, 2011Missy ElliottWe Run ThisFebruary 15, 2011Rick JamesSuper FreakFebruary 15, 2011AmerieHeard 'em AllFebruary 15, 2011Fatboy SlimWeapon of ChoiceMarch 15, 2011 Gwen StefaniHollaback GirlMarch 15, 2011Keri HilsonTurnin' Me OnMarch 15, 2011Paula AbdulStraight Up!March 15, 2011JusticeD.A.N.C.E.April 19, 2011Dem Franchize BoysLean Wit It, Rock Wit ItApril 19, 2011Tone LocWild ThingApril 19, 2011SnowInformerMay 17, 2011 Fergie feat. will.i.amFergaliciousMay 17, 2011N.E.R.D (feat. Lee Harvey and Vita)LapdanceMay 17, 2011Taio CruzBreak Your HeartJuly 19, 2011Trey SongzSay AahJuly 19, 2011Afrika BambaataaPlanet RockJuly 19, 2011 James BrownGet UpAugust 16, 2011Sean PaulGet BusyAugust 16, 2011LloydGet It ShawtyAugust 16, 2011The Pussycat Dolls ft  Busta RhymesDon't ChaSeptember 20, 2011RupeeTempted To TouchSeptember 20, 2011Timbaland ft. Keri Hilson and D.O.EThe Way I AreSeptember 20, 2011Exporting songsHarmonix announced at E3 2011 that all songs (including DLC) from Dance Central can be exported to  Dance Central 2. The export function costs 400 Microsoft points and is achieved by entering a 16 digit code found in the Dance Central manual into Dance Central 2.</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="31347">Just Dance 2</game><game id="27859">Just Dance</game><game id="31787">SingStar Dance</game><game id="31724">Michael Jackson: The Experience</game><game id="32865">Dance Paradise</game><game id="31801">DanceMasters</game><game id="34611">Country Dance</game><game id="35638">Everybody Dance</game><game id="34784">DanceDanceRevolution</game><game id="29420">Dance Dance Revolution X2</game><game id="35553">Just Dance 3</game><game id="36861">Nickelodeon Dance</game><game id="36664">Let's Cheer!</game><game id="36619">Grease Dance</game><game id="31714">Kinect Star Wars</game><game id="37609">Country Dance All Stars</game><game id="42433">K-Pop Dance Festival</game><game id="42899">D4</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1886598-box_dcentral.png</image></root>