<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31719</id><name>Sonic Free Riders</name><description>OverviewThe latest release in the Sonic Riders series is a hoverboard racing game using Microsoft's Kinect technology on the Xbox 360, announced by Sega during the 2010 E3 conference. The game released on November 4, 2010 as one of Kinect's launch titles.GameplayThe gameplay for Sonic Free Riders involves the player standing in front of Kinect in-order to control a character from the Sonic franchise on a hover board and pushing with ether foot for boost/acceleration and learning left or right to turn. Each of the tracks feature unique shortcuts to get through the races quicker. Free Riders also includes powerups and weapons that can be picked up during the race that can be used to knock your competitors off-course and give you the edge in the race.PlotThe plot is similar to the other games in the Sonic Riders franchise with Dr. Eggman attempting to gain control of the Chaos Emeralds by setting up another hoverboard competition. The story also focuses on the rivalry of Sonic the Hedgehog and his green counterpart Jet the Hawk. The cutscenes, however, are all just conversations between talking heads rather than fully acted out scenes.CharactersThe characters in Sonic Free Riders are divided into different teams based on the character's personality.Team SonicSonic the HedgehogMiles "Tails" ProwerKnuckles the EchidnaTeam BabylonJet the HawkWave the SwallowStorm the AlbatrossTeam DarkShadow the HedgehogRouge the BatE-10000BTeam RoseAmy RoseCream the RabbitVector the CrocodileAdditional CharactersDr. EggmanSilver the HedgehogBlaze the CatMetal SonicE-10000GAvatarSonic Free Riders is a cool and groovy game.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9806">EyeToy: AntiGrav</game><game id="20448">F-Zero GX</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1881084-box_sonicfr.png</image></root>