<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31721</id><name>Rayman Origins</name><description>OverviewCreated by the forest nymphs, Rayman springs to life and is unexpectedly out of control. He quickly uses his detached head and hair as a fan to blow air up a nymph's skirt (to her aggravation and awkward satisfaction) and continues running amok until he is literally slapped in the face by his Double -- his blood brother, his id -- a Globox who somehow has a magical connection to him. The two are an inseparable pair and look to cause general mayhem around this new Rayman universe.GameplayRayman: Origins's gameplay is focused on jumping, gliding, slapping and climbing. Enemies and obstacles are either deftly avoided or quickly dealt with and include some familiar elements from Rayman and Rayman 2. At the end of each level, Rayman (or whomever the player chooses to be) will free some Electoons from a cage, though in most of the normal levels there is also two other hidden cages throughout the level. Additional Electoons may also be earned when the player collects enough Lums, or by completing the level in a given amount of time. The collection of Electoons unlocks playable characters and Treasure Hunt levels. These levels feature Rayman chasing a treasure chest through tightly scripted sequences, that are both chaotic and exhilarating, and includes elements such as falling boulders that block the players path, and a pirate ship that shoots the platforms from under the player's feet. Aside from normal levels and Treasure Hunt levels, the game also contains "Shoot'em up" sequences and boss battles, all with multiple side missions for getting extra Electoons.The co-op gameplay does not have players killing each other, though the players can slap each other (which can lead to death if they are knocked into harmful obstacles, enemies, or a bottomless pit). Up to four players can play together in a "hop-in/hop-out" fashion.LevelsJibberish JungleIt's a Jungle Out There...Geyser BlowoutCan't Catch Me!Punching PlateausGo With The FlowSwinging CavesOver the RainbowHi-Ho Moskito!Desert of DijiridoosCrazy BouncingBest Original ScoreCacophonic ChaseWind or LoseSkyward SonataNo Turning BackShooting Me SoftlyGourmand LandPolar PursuitDashing Thru the SnowSink or SwimPiping Hot!Mending the RiftAim for the Eel!Sea of SerendipityPort 'O PanicSwimming with StarsPirate's Treasure!Freaking FlipperBad Bubbles and BeyondFire When WettyMystical PiqueMoseying the MountainMystical MunkeysTricky Treasure TempleWay of the ElectoonsGolly G. GolemMoody CloudsRiding the StormOn Top of Old SmokeyMecha No Mistake!Tricky Temple TooThe RevealGet Away!Shoot for the StarsThe Land of the Livid DeadUBIart FrameworkThe UBIart Framework logoAt Ubisoft's E3 2010 press conference, Michel Ancel revealed that the game is being developed by a small team (5-6 employees) using a new backend called UBIart Framework. It is described by the UBIart blog as a toolset designed to "limit the repetitive tasks to keep the team as small as possible and to keep it happy." Somewhat like the tools given to players in LittleBigPlanet, it is as yet unclear as to how much freedom Rayman Origins users will have to create their own levels but user generated content is definitely a big part of the game's feature set.PC System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows® XP / Windows Vista® / Windows® 7 (only)Processor: 3.0 GHz Intel® Pentium® 4 or 1.8 GHz AMD Athlon™ 64 3000+Memory: 1 GB Windows XP / 1.5 GB Windows Vista, 7Video Card: 128 MB DirectX® 9.0c-compliant video card or higher* (see supported list)Sound: DirectX 9.0c-compliantPeripherals Supported: Windows-compatible keyboard, mouse, optional controller (Xbox 360® Controller for Windows recommended)RecommendedOS: Windows® XP / Windows Vista® / Windows® 7 (only)Processor: 2.0 GHz Intel® Core™2 Duo E4400 or 2.0 GHz AMD Athlon™ X2 3800+ or betterMemory: 2 GB recommendedVideo Card: 128 MB DirectX® 9.0c-compliant video card or higher* (see supported list)Sound: DirectX 9.0c-compliantPeripherals Supported: Windows-compatible keyboard, mouse, optional controller (Xbox 360® Controller for Windows recommended)</description><genres><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20963">Wario Land: Shake It!</game><game id="31732">Donkey Kong Country Returns</game><game id="21407">Eternity's Child</game><game id="26841">New Super Mario Bros. Wii</game><game id="27175">The Adventures of Tintin</game><game id="37124">Sonic the Hedgehog 4: Episode II</game><game id="36686">South Park: Tenorman's Revenge</game><game id="5269">Oddworld: Abe's Oddysee</game><game id="40464">Fly'N</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2062201-box_raymano.png</image></root>