<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31737</id><name>Resident Evil: Revelations</name><description>OverviewResident Evil: Revelations is the first story-based Resident Evil game to be released for the Nintendo 3DS. It is part of the main Resident Evil storyline and features some of the series' most recognizable faces, such as Chris Redfield and Jill Valentine. The game was initially released in North America on February 7, 2012 and was the first 3DS game to support the Circle Pad Pro accessory outside of Japan. Development of Revelations was headed by Koushi Nakanishi of Tenchu and Shinobido fame.Announced on January 22, 2013 was an HD port of the game, sub-subtitled "Unveiled Edition" in Japan, to be released on Xbox 360, PlayStation 3, Wii U and PC in at the end of May 2013.StoryChris and Jill hang out on a boat. Taking place four years before the events of Resident Evil 5 (and one year before the events of the Lost in Nightmares DLC story), Resident Evil: Revelations puts Chris Redfield and his long-time friend and colleague Jill Valentine, founders of the Bio-terrorism Security Assessment Alliance (BSAA), on a mission to the Cruiser Ship, Queen Zenobia, and then to Europe.GameplayResident Evil: Revelations is a third-person action game. Like in other games in the franchise, players must shoot their way through hordes of hideously mutated creatures while solving puzzles. Much like Resident Evil: The Mercenaries 3D before it (and first introduced within the series via Resident Evil: Outbreak - File #2), players can shoot and move at the same time, and can even switch between both first and third-person views (the 3DS gyroscope can also be used for aiming). The trusty knife can also now be instantaneously brought out for an attack with the press of a button, rather than requiring the player to aim first.Night-vision goggles have been added to the players repertoire, and not only do they let the players see in the dark, they also let them scan the environment for items such as herbs, reminiscent of the popular Detective Mode from Batman: Arkham Asylum and Batman: Arkham City.The game uses the touchscreen for solving puzzles. As shown at E3 2011, the touchscreen has players unscrewing bolts on control panels, which then leads to a puzzle involving covering electric nodes. The touchscreen will also be used for herbs.RAID ModeSimilar in scope to the Mercenaries minigame from prior Resident Evil games, RAID mode allows one or two players to fend off against a multitude of creatures, earning points which allows the player to upgrade their weapons and characters. The difference over Mercenaries is that there is no fixed timer constantly ticking down (though for better rankings, it's still advised that players attempt to get through the stages as hastily as possible), and players progress through the stages in a much more linear pattern, with a specific beginning and end point.There are a varied selection of playable characters with alternate costumes and gear to unlock, which can be upgraded via randomized loot rewarded at the end of each stage; the end-mission rank determines the quality of loot players are gifted. Characters can also level up, allowing players to equip better and more efficient gear and weaponry.Characters:Chris RedfieldJill ValentineJessica SherawatParker LucianiClive R. O'BrianRaymond VesterMorgan LansdaleQuint KetchumKeith LumleyHunk (Unveiled Edition Exclusive)Rachel (Unveiled Edition Exclusive)HD Console/PC Versions (Unveiled Edition)The HD port of Revelations, dubbed Unveiled Edition in Japan, comes with support for online co-op in RAID Mode, a new higher difficulty (Inferno Mode with different item and enemy placements and amounts), new custom parts, new RAID weapons, a new enemy type, and two new playable characters in RAID Mode (HUNK and Rachel) along with the expected upgrade in visuals as well as Xbox Live Achievements and PSN Trophies. Like Resident Evil 6, the Unveiled Edition of Revelations also supports RE.Net for online events and goodies such as unlockable dioramas of characters and monsters and custom parts and weapons for use in the solo campaign and RAID Mode. Wii U Exclusive FeaturesThe "Creature Voice" feature in action.The Wii U version also supports Off-TV Play and the Wii U Pro Controller. along with Miiverse integration that, upon death, lets players post messages directly to RE: Revelations' Miiverse community from within the game. Finally, the Wii U version also contains a "Creature Voice" feature that lets players add speech bubbles to certain monsters personalized monster sounds to other players in RAID Mode. Premium SetPriced at 42,000 Yen ($467), the Premium set is a Collector's Edition to be released exclusively for the PC, PS3, 360, and Wii U ports. It includes:Resident Evil: Revelations game.An arranged soundtrack on CD.BSAA card case.A replica of Jill Valentine's BSAA wrist watch made by the USAgency Watch Company.The noticeably high price is the result of the wrist watch, and as such there exists two alternative, lower tiered sets; one includes only the game and the watch, priced at 39,900 yen ($443), and the other removes the watch from the feature list, bringing the average pricing down to 7,490 yen ($83).Steam Preorder Bonuses:Free copy of Lost Planet: Extreme Condition.Digital copy of the soundtrack.Digital Art book.Season Pass Content.System RequirementsMinimumOS: XP or laterCPU: Intel® Core™ 2 Duo 2.4Ghz or better | AMD Athlon™ X2 2.8 Ghz or betterMemory: 2 GB RAMHard Disk Space: 8 GB or moreDisplay: 800x600 or higherDVD drive: DVD9-compatibleVideo Card: VRAM（256MB or more | NVIDIA® GeForce® 8800GTS or better | ATI Radeon™ HD3850 or betterSound Card: DirectSound supported with DirectX9.0c or betterDirect X: DirectX® 9.0c or laterRecommendedOS: Vista or laterCPU: Intel® Core™ 2 Quad 2.7 Ghz or better | AMD Phenom™ II X4 3 Ghz or betterMemory: 4 GB RAMDisplay: 1280×720 or higherVideo Card: VRAM（512MB or more) | NVIDIA® GeForce® GTX 560 or better | ATI Radeon™ HD6950 or betterOthersRequired: Mouse  keyboardSupported: Gamepad (Xbox 360® Controller for Windows® recommended)Required: Steam used for network connectionsSoundtrackResident Evil Revelations official soundtrack coverThere are 66 songs separated into 2 disk and it was released on February 22, 2012.Disk 1Track No.TitleArtistDuration1.Revelations -Previous Story-Kohta Suzuki0:542.Deep SeaKohta Suzuki3:493.LostIchiro Kohmoto  Kohta Suzuki1:554.Ghost Ship IIchiro Kohmoto  Kohta Suzuki2:245.Terror from the Water IIchiro Kohmoto  Kohta Suzuki2:086.BroadcastIchiro Kohmoto0:497.O'BrianTakeshi Miura1:168.LiquefactionIchiro Kohmoto2:169.Eyecatch IIchiro Kohmoto0:1310.HuntingIchiro Kohmoto1:5311.Ghost Ship IIIchiro Kohmoto2:2112.True BeginningIchiro Kohmoto0:4213.Episode EndTakeshi Miura1:1514.Terragrigia Panic IIchiro Kohmoto2:3515.Lost CityTakeshi Miura1:4116.RaymondTakeshi Miura0:4217.HallTakeshi Miura2:5118.ScreamIchiro Kohmoto2:0519.Game OverKohta Suzuki0:1220.VeltroIchiro Kohmoto2:4321.Terror from the Water IIKohta Suzuki1:5122.Quint  KeithIchiro Kohmoto1:3323.BehindIchiro Kohmoto2:2824.InvisibleIchiro Kohmoto2:3025.Ship BattleTakeshi Miura2:4526.Eyecatch IIKohta Suzuki0:1227.Panic!Takeshi Miura2:0728.Seismatic ActivityTakeshi Miura4:0029.StartingTakeshi Miura1:1330.TightropeIchiro Kohmoto3:2331.EnvelopmentIchiro Kohmoto3:1532.DisturbanceIchiro Kohmoto1:1333.AbyssIchiro Kohmoto2:2434.Eyecatch IIIKohta Suzuki0:1235.Ride on SeaTakeshi Miura3:0936.Rest  IntensifyKohta Suzuki1:35Disk 2 Track No.TitleArtistDuration1.Cruel MarksIchiro Kohmoto2:452.Red PlaceTakeuchi Miura3:153.InsanityTakeuchi Miura  Kota Suzuki2:144.DiscardKohta Suzuki3:105.JessicaTakeuchi Miura2:056.Unknown SignIchiro Kohmoto2:107.Dear My...Kohta Suzuki0:538.CountdownIchiro Kohmoto2:389.ParasitesKohta Suzuki3:0010.FlashbackKohta Suzuki0:4211.Eyecatch IVKohta Suzuki0:1312.Terragrigia Panic IIIchiro Kohmoto3:0813.RelianceIchiro Kohmoto0:5314.MorganTakeuchi Miura  Kota Suzuki1:5215.Revelations -the Truth-Kohta Suzuki0:5016.To TruthIchiro Kohmoto1:1217.Falling Chorus ITakeuchi Miura3:5118.Veltro -Qualtetto-Kota Suzuki  Ichiro Kohmoto1:2819.Falling ChorusTakeuchi Miura3:1020.Eyecatch VKohta Suzuki0:1321.O vendetta di DioKohta Suzuki3:3722.LastKohta Suzuki2:2823.BSAAKohta Suzuki2:3324.Revelations -Full Ver.-Kohta Suzuki3:5425.Beyond the SeasKohta Suzuki1:1726.A Drop of RainKohta Suzuki3:1727.Trace of RiddlesKohta Suzuki4:0928.ChaosIchiro Kohmoto3:2929.BleaknessKohta Suzuki2:5230.CasinoIchiro Kohmoto2:15</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="38270">Dead Space 3</game><game id="25444">Dead Space 2</game><game id="20800">Dead Space</game><game id="32684">Shadows of the Damned</game><game id="37937">Lost Planet 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/82063/2484600-revelaitons.jpg</image></root>