<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31750</id><name>PlayStation Move Heroes</name><description>OverviewPlayStation Move Heroes is a game developed by Nihilistic Software, known for making the 2007 Conan game and PSN, XBLA game Zombie Apocalypse. The game requires the use of the PlayStation Move controller, and takes place in worlds based on the universes of the characters (Sly Cooper, Bentley, Jak, Daxter, Ratchet, and Clank). The missions are mini-games ranging from "bowling" and "disc" games to games based on close range combat with whip and shooting missions.  Gameplay   PlayStation Move Heroes is a PlayStation Move only game that features two-player co-op functionality, as well as the traditional single-player mode. Levels in the game consist of several mini-games.  The game features six characters, Jak, Daxter, Ratchet, Clank, Sly Cooper, and Bentley.   There are a total of 50 levels to play through, with those levels being spread out in 5 different worlds. Before each level the player has the choice of which character they want to use. Each character, as most know, will have their own unique movees and play style. Co-op functionality has the first player choosing a hero, and depending on the hero they've chosen the second player will be that respective hero's sidekick.  PlayStation Move Heroes has five weapon classes, Melee, Projectile, Disc, among others. Using the PS Move controller you would throw the disc like you would a frisbee in real life. You control the frisbee by moving the PS Move controller left and right. Melee will use each characters famous weapons, if they one, such as Ratchet's wrench.  Environments and territories from each hero's world are also in the game, for example Haven City from Jak and Daxter, Metropolis City from Ratchet  Clank , and an all-new original world Planet X, which was created just for PlayStation Move Heroes.</description><genres><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="31304">Ape Escape Move</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1974400-box_psmh.png</image></root>