<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31776</id><name>The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time 3D</name><description>OverviewThe Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time 3D is a remake of the N64 classic for the Nintendo 3DS. The game was first displayed in a tech demo format at E3 2010. It was released on June 19, 2011 in North America.Previewed behind closed doors at Nintendo's E3 developer roundtable, Shigeru Miyamoto claimed that one of the reasons Nintendo made the 3DS was so that players could get the "Hyrule Feel". He wanted players to experience what it would feel like to actually be running around in Hyrule.Eiji Aonuma said that portions of the game (such as the Water Temple) would be easier because of the ability to quickly change equipment with the touchscreen. A new addition to Ocarina of Time 3D is that the Water Temple features fluorescent patterns on the walls which enable the player to find the switches to alter the water levels more easily.Extra ContentIn addition to the enhanced version of the original game, Ocarina of Time 3D also includes some extra content:Water TempleThe Water Temple adds multiple colored lines which extend the length of the entire dungeon per floor. Each line can be found in every room in the temple. These lines each lead to one of the three doors which lead to the three points where you change the water levels. This greatly decreases the pure frustration of fans of the original release by making the temple much less maze like.Master QuestAfter completing the original version of Ocarina of Time 3D players will unlock Master Quest, which is a remixed version of the game originally released on the Nintendo GameCube. Though it is the same game at its core, the Master Quest version of Ocarina of Time 3D is fully mirrored and consist of rearranged dungeons and enemies that do twice the damage in order to be more challenging.Boss ChallengeAn all-new side mode which is accessible by talking to Link's bed in Kokiri Forest. Boss Challenge is simply a mode that lets the players fight the game's bosses in one-off battles or as a Boss Rush.VisionsOcarina of Time 3D includes videos that players can consult if they get stuck. These videos are called visions and can be found through Sheikah Stones, which look like bigger versions of the Gossip Stones. These videos give the player hints on how to beat certain puzzles. Visions are not accessible in the Master Quest playthrough of the game.Download VersionBlock Size: 4,096 blocks (512 MB)</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15835">Beyond Good &amp; Evil</game><game id="12614">Sphinx and the Cursed Mummy</game><game id="19026">Star Fox Adventures</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1817089-box_zeldaoot3d.png</image></root>