<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31771</id><name>Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon: Shadow Wars</name><description>OverviewTom Clancy's Ghost Recon: Shadow Wars is a turn-based strategy game, the first of its kind in the Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon series. The title draws comparisons to Fire Emblem and the X-COM series of which the latter had been created by Shadow Wars producer Julian Gollop. As in previous series entries, the player assumes the role of the "Ghosts", an elite squadron of American soldiers. The Ghosts operate in secrecy, used to intervene in situations that the United States does not wish to be publicly involved with. In Shadow Wars, the Ghosts go from Kazakhstan to Siberia attempting to stop a new Russian empire. It is up to the Ghosts to bring peace to control the tensions in the Middle East that have risen due to Russian influence.Gameplay ModesCampaignThis is the mode that follows story of the Ghosts through their mission to covertly unravel a Russian conspiracy. Missions have three difficulty levels, which affect health and ability of enemies, as well as the amount of upgrades that the player can use on his Ghosts. PEC points are also awarded, which increase the player's overall rank.Skirmish MissionsSkirmish missions test the skill of the player in three different difficulty levels in specific scenarios. The various classes are used in unique situations that highlight each class' abilities. PEC points are awarded in this mode as well.MultiplayerThe Multiplayer Mission mode allows players to go up against friends using the same 3DS console in specially designed multiplayer skirmishes. PEC points cannot be earned in this mode.Characters  ClassesDukeClass: Commando (Either Anti-Vehicles or Anti-Personnel)Special Ability(s): Three explosive projectilesBio: Special Forces Officer. Comes from a long line of West Point graduates. Solid, dependable, caring, and reasonable.Weapons:Main: Assault RiflesSecondary: Shoulder Mounted Missile-LauncherUpgrades:Commando Speciality - blast against infantry and vehiclesHealth 3Health 3SCAR-H Assault RifleSMLVA1 Missile LauncherHealth 3HPA1 Body Armor (HP 16; Movement -2)Health 4Urban Warrior (No speed reduction in buildings)G36 Assault RifleHazeClass: SniperSpecial Ability(s): NoneBio: One of the longest established Ghost squad members. Acts as second-in-command to Duke. Calm and soft spoken, he is the voice of reason within the squad, even bringing Duke back into line when the heat really turns up.Weapons:Main: Heavy Sniper Rifles, Light Sniper RiflesSecondary: AP (Armor Penetration) Grenades, EMP GrenadesUpgrades:Sniper Speciality - long range damageHealth 2Health 2M14 ER Sniper RifleCG1 Blast GrenadeHealth 3MPA1Sn - Body Armor (HP 10; Movement -1)Health 3Long Shot (10 Power Points per long range attack)HSR Heavy Sniper RifleSaffronClass: MedicSpecial Ability(s): HealBio: Former Navy medic. Looks after the Ghosts like a a mom at times (occasionally referred to as "Mom" in the field), but can also be a strict disciplinarian.Upgrades:Medic Speciality - healing and supportHealth 3Health 3UTSP - pistolMPGE2 medkitHealth 3MPA1 Body Armor (HP 10; Movement -1)Determination (1 Power Point for each HP lost)Health 3SG1 Pistol and Riot ShieldRichterClass: GunnerSpecial Ability(s): Support FireBio: Transferred from the Green Berets. Bold and brash, he likes to have fun with the younger squad members.Weapons:Main: HMGSecondary: GrenadesUpgrades:Gunner Speciality - defence and support fireHealth 4Health 4G101 Heavy Machine GunCG1 Blast GrenadeRage (15 Power Points attacking with  50% HP)Health 4HPA1 Body Armor (HP 16; Movement -2)Strong Arm (Increases range of grenades by 2)M249 Heavy Machine GunMintClass: EngineerSpecial Ability(s): Repair Vehicles and DronesBio: Newest member of the squad. Passed out of training with the highest marks in the group. Optimistic, talkative, earnest, and trusting.Weapons:Main: Assault RiflesSecondary: Deployable Gun Turret, Assault DronesUpgrades:Engineer Speciality turrets, drones and repairHealth 3Health 4SCAR-H Assault RifleHealth 3Steadfast (15 Power Points if not moved in a turn)HPA1 Body Armor (HP 16; Movement -2)Health 3Health 3EMAW1 (Electo-magnetic anti-vehicle weapon)BansheeClass: ReconSpecial Ability(s): CloakBio: Became a Recon because she prefers to work alone. Fiery temper, which she controls and unleashes at just the right time. Takes no aggravation from anyone - friend or foe.Weapons:Main: Silenced CarbinesSecondary: EMP Grenades, KnifeUpgrades:Recon Speciality - close combat and stealthHealth 2Health 2SCARQ - Silenced SMGMK111 combat knifeMPA1St Body Armor (HP 10; Movement -1)Cold Blooded Killer (15 Power Points for a close range kill)Health 3Jungle Warrior (No Speed reduction in trees and bushes)P90 Silenced SMG</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12719">Advance Wars</game><game id="11939">Advance Wars: Dual Strike</game><game id="1520">Fire Emblem</game><game id="196">X-COM: UFO Defense</game><game id="17276">Rebelstar: Tactical Command</game><game id="34522">Shin Megami Tensei: Devil Survivor 2</game><game id="31810">Shin Megami Tensei: Devil Survivor Overclocked</game><game id="26505">Frozen Synapse</game><game id="37152">XCOM: Enemy Unknown</game><game id="32398">Jagged Alliance: Back in Action</game><game id="10537">Jagged Alliance</game><game id="24466">Jagged Alliance</game><game id="884">Jagged Alliance 2</game><game id="1379">UFO:Extraterrestrials</game><game id="14581">UFO: Aftershock</game><game id="15734">UFO: Aftermath</game><game id="18650">UFO: Afterlight</game><game id="40275">Frontline Tactics</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1783144-box_grsw.png</image></root>