<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31798</id><name>Swarm</name><description>Overview Swarm, the new game by            Hothead Games, introduces the           Swarmites, blissfully ignorant little blue creatures that have zero awareness of their surroundings, thus making way for some sadistic yet very funny moments. Swarm was released on March 22, 2011 for PlayStation Network and the following day for the Xbox Live Marketplace. Gameplay  A clueless Swarmite     Swarm is all about getting to the end of the level with the highest possible score. The player must use and abuse the Swarmites in order to do so, sometimes sacrificing some for the greater good (read score), or sometimes sparing them from some terrible death in order to unlock more and more goodies to collect and to increase their final score.   You have a multiplier that you must keep going in order to achieve a good score. As written above, sacrificing swarmites is a way to keep your multiplier going. But that's not the only way to score points. There are multiple explosive boxes that you can blow up to get little swarmite food that keeps your score going. There are different types of objects to collect including collectible DNA.  To keep your multiplier going, you must: Kill your own swarmites.Blow up objects that unleash little swarmite food that are drawn towards your swarm.Collect any kind of swarmite food (they come in different sizes) or DNA.Hit a checkpoint.Unlock a Death Medal.Use a pressure pad that requires a certain number of swarmites to unlock more swarmite food. Your swarmites can be ordered and take different positions. You can spread them out or huddle them together. These two basic commands lead to other kinds of possibilities. By advancing  with a huddled swarm you can de-huddle them which results in a sprint. By huddling them together and not moving, you can pile them onto each other to reach higher areas. You can also air dash. In order to finish a level, the player only has to reach the end with a single Swarmite, but will be rewarded if more are able to conclude the level. Death MedalsSwarm actively rewards the death of the Swarmites by actually featuring an        achievement system that discriminates how many Swarmites die and in which way they die-- there's a specific achievement for each general "way to die" (fire, electrocution, etc), among others.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20594">Lemmings</game><game id="1446">Lemmings</game><game id="12965">Lemmings &amp; Oh No! More Lemmings</game><game id="16466">Let's Go Crazy with Lemmings</game><game id="18769">Lemmings X-Mas</game><game id="7122">The Lemmings Chronicles</game><game id="18818">Lemmings 2: The Tribes</game><game id="6920">Oh No! More Lemmings</game><game id="7673">Lemmings 3D</game><game id="24824">Christmas Lemmings 1994</game><game id="6547">3D Lemmings Winterland</game><game id="19179">Lemmings Revolution</game><game id="26923">Trials HD</game><game id="29106">Prinny 2: Dawn of Operation Panties, Dood!</game><game id="23692">Prinny: Can I Really Be the Hero?</game><game id="2405">Pikmin</game><game id="2480">Pikmin 2</game><game id="35581">Kirby Mass Attack</game><game id="36458">Mercury Hg</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1744559-box_swarm.png</image></root>