<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3181</id><name>Burn: Cycle</name><description>OverviewBurn: Cycle is a point and click adventure from the early 1990s which has many of the characteristics of the early games made available on the relatively new format of compact disc. The graphics were a mix of polygonal backgrounds with live actors imposed over them. The game is played largely in a first person perspective in which the player clicks on objects to collect them/shoot them/interact with them. Story           This adventure title put you in the shoes of a courier named Sol Cutter (along the lines of Johnny Mnemonic) who carries sensitive information in a hard drive grafted into his head.  At the outset, you are in the middle of a job and suddenly a piece of the data glitches and knocks you on your butt. From here, you have to escape the enemy compound and get back in touch with your manager/pilot/friend Kris. This goes incredibly wrong and you are forced to run and go undercover.  You eventually run into a few interesting characters who help you along your journey like Zip, a man who's addiction to direct sensation input gives him connections to the underworld, and Doc, who knows a thing or two about the televerse (the game's interpretation of the internet/matrix).Gameplay  The crux to the gameplay was the time limit. You were given 2 real-time hours to disarm the virus-bomb in your head. If you ran out of time, you died. Once you find the cure, you win the game.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1353">The Beast Within: A Gabriel Knight Mystery</game><game id="4327">Roberta Williams' Phantasmagoria</game><game id="3626">The Last Express</game><game id="18074">Cyberia</game><game id="33584">Kowloon's Gate</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9408/720918-eurofront.jpg</image></root>