<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31828</id><name>Cosmic Break</name><description>OverviewCosmic Break is a free to play third-person shooter MMO that was developed by Japanese video game company, CyberStep. The game was originally released for Japanese market, then the game got its first English Open Beta that began in June 10, 2010, and ended on July 10, 2010. By December 23, 2010, Cosmic Break's Official Server released to anyone around the world.RobotsRobots are humaniod-mecha that are categorized in any forms from sizes to different type of robots.Robot TypesLand TypeHound Dog - Land TypeLand Type robots are boast superior maneuverability on the ground as well as the ability to equip various powerful sub and main weapons.Air TypeGwyain - Air TypeThe Air Type robot has the ability to remain airborne for extended long time than other robots.Artillery TypeSturbanger - Artillery TypeArtillery Type robots are specialize in heavy firepower, with the ability to use different long range weapons, and including various bombs and missile.Support TypeMedi Aide - Support TypeThe Support types have the ability to uses the special Wonder Bit that other robot type that's unavailable to them, allowing the Support type to repair and support their allies during battle.Robots SizeThe robots comes in many sizes from S-Size (Small) to L-Size (Large).S-SizeThe smallest sized robots that had increased maneuverable, allowing them to move faster to avoid enemy fires. However, they have least defense than other Robots Size and they unable to equip various large parts.M-SizeThe medium sized robots are fairly balanced, making them easy to customize. They can equipped with wide variety of weapons, in which they can be equipped in any different situations.L-SizeThe large sized robots have higher HP than rest of the robots and they may equipped with many powerful weapons. Their large size makes them easy target to any one, so utilize their HP by added more to make up for their weakness.PC System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows 2000 / XPPossessor: Pentium 3 1.2 GHz or higherMemory: 256MBGraphics: VRAM 32 MBDirectX: DirectX 9.0c or moreHard Drive: 800 MB or moreRecommendedOS: Windows Vista / 7Possessor: Pentium 4 2.0 GHz or moreMemory: 1GB or higherGraphics: VRAM 128MB or more</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20512">Exteel</game><game id="4819">Cyber Troopers Virtual-On: Oratorio Tangram</game><game id="30084">Aika Online</game><game id="42371">Kritika Online</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/80630/1908528-cosmic_break_logo.png</image></root>