<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31847</id><name>Dr.Tool Lern Coach für Kinder</name><description> Dr. Tool Coach for KidsDr. Tool Coach for kids is a brain-trainer for younger people.   It is about stimulating your brain by solving smaller logical puzzles. If you are regularly exercising in a gym, you should not forget about your mental fitness either.   Compared with other video games, Dr. Tool Coach for Kids surely is of pedagogical value.  Here is a clear statement from the manufacturer:What do you normally do, when you have completed an ordinary computer game? Do you wait for a possible sequel?  At best, you have had lots of fun, and depending on the genre, you might even had to use your head, to complete the game.  But did you ever play a game you directly benefit from? Parents usually try to protect their children from unwanted negative influence from often brutal video games, of course this will never happen with Coach for kids. Obviously, nobody will become Einstein from playing our game - but if you play regularly, the game can help you improve your learning performance.  People who never play such games are not going to be stupid either, but does it really hurt to keep your brain in training? So much for the basic concept.  If you are new to those games or just interested, here is another explanation of the game principle:  Think of many scientifically grounded tasks from  varying assignments. They should increase the performance of your brain on repetition. As an extra and to be able to control your own progress, the program saves all events and can visually enhance the charts when the user retrieves them. For motivational purposes, the program offers special tasks that need to be unlocked but completing other challenges. The exercises are divided into certain branches on assignment:  - Read the clock:   Read the time of the day that the left clock shows and adjust the clock on the right side accordingly.    At the same time you have to convert an analog clock to a digital one or vice versa.  Take special care about AM/PM that is shown on analog clocks. You can set digital clocks with the keyboard. For analog clocks you must use your mouse to set them.- Shape recognition:  Memorize the large shape that is shown in the lower half of your screen.    Then locate the same shape in the upper corner of your screen. Please note that it is all about the shape of the object - colors and shades are faded out.- Clicking digits:  This time you have to determine and click on the lowest digit.    At higher difficulty levels the digits also move on the screen.    Your reaction time as well as your mistakes are taken into account for your score.    - Rebuilding pictures:   Your task is to rebuild the shaded pictures with the help of the white objects.    Select an object with the left mouse button.    Keep the button pressed to drag the object over the screen and drop it anywhere you like.    You can also use A/D keys to rotate selected objects in steps of 15 degrees. Use the cursor keys to move the object on screen. W/S can be used to resize the selected object.- Remember me:  Find all the hidden pairs and reveal them.    Select card with the left mouse button. If you uncover two mismatching cards they will turn and become covered again.    Be quick and try to avoid to uncover mismatching pairs.- Caclulate with the clock:  This time you have to calculate with different times of the day.    Depending on the task, you have to add or subtract different times of the day.    Please note that certain times could clash over into the next day, e.g. 0:59   0:10 = 0:09    - Adding squares:  This time you have to add two or three colored squares.    Pick the square in the lower corner of your screen that shows the correct solution.    - Find words:  This time you have to find a complete word in the rotating pool of letters.    Enter the word with your keyboard. On using,  letters are removed from the pool.- Change money:  Calculate the change and try to use the minimal amount of coins possible.  In the top / left corner of the screen there are the number of notes and coins you have to pay.    Right next to them there is the money you have just paid.    You can drag and drop coins and notes from the stack to the screen.    It is also possible to undo payments by just dragging and dropping the money back to the stack it came from.     - Calculate rebate:  This time you have to determine the price after you applied the rebate. Hit ‘enter’ to verify your input.    The biggest difference from the correct amount is being shown afterwards.- Scales:   Try to balance the scales by dragging and dropping the sets of weights from the bottom corner of the screen to either side of the scales.    You cannot move weights that are marked in red!      Also, there is a given time limit for every scale. If you do not manage to obey the time limit your attempt is regarded as a failure.      Visually Dr. Tool Coach for kids makes a pretty good impression. At once you realize that the product wasn't "rushed" out due to the global economy crisis.    The exercises are all very well done and they challenge you on a fair base at every difficulty level - there are three of them per task (easy, normal, hard).    Wherever there are animations shows, they are very well done and also the structure of the menus feels sophisticated. In the end, design is always a matter of taste. Motivational limitations:There is a training mode available, to not have the user struggle right from the beginning of the game.  In that mode you can select every single task and try it without a time limit. Beware that not every task if available from the beginning.  Some of them have to be unlocked before they become available. You unlock tasks by successfully completing prior tasks.  At the beginning of the game, there are only 5 areas freely available.  Own profiles for every player:Using the menu profiles, every player can create an own user profile.  In total, you can create up to four user-profiles, that should be enough room to play with your family and / or friends.  The menu can be used to either select, create or delete a user profile. Integrated Manual:Now this option is not so common anymore, nowadays: While playing, you can press "H-Key" to open a special help for the current event. Evaluation:After having finished playing, an evaluation window will pop up.  It contains all necessary information about your style of play. There is also a smaller evaluation window after each completed challenge.  If you reach a grade of 2.5 or better, you automatically unlock a new game.</description><genres><genre id="8">Educational</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/94457/1413194-dr.tool_lern_coach_f_r_kinder_2008_cover.jpg</image></root>