<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31852</id><name>Marvel Super Hero Squad Online</name><description>Marvel Super Hero Squad Online is MMORPG based upon the popular kids TV show The Super Hero Squad show. It's aimed at a younger audience and will be free to play with in game micro transactions. It was developed by the Gazillion Entertainment company, in association with Marvel Entertainment.Little is known about the game play except for the fact that combat will be card based and each server will regroup a group of heroes so everyone can play as their favorite super hero without having to come across another player playing as the same hero.The game keeps the same look as the show and the toys with the heroes having big arms and legs.Playable CharactersMarvel Super Hero Squad Online has an ever growing list of super heroes for players to take control of and explore.AvengersCaptain AmericaCaptain America is the leader of the Super Heroes Squad. He's a natural leader and veteran of numerous wars. So patriotic that he's probably wearing stars and stripes undies.Powers:Delaware SlideShield TossHistory LessonIron ManIron Man is a member of the Super Heroes Squad and the team inventor. He uses a super powered suit of armor he created with his own hands. Sure that's impressive, but can he make a sandwich?Powers:Repulsor BeamsArmored FlightExploding UnderwearSpider-ManSpider-man is the friendly neighborhood wall crawler. he's the wisecrackin' jokester of the Marvel Super Hero Squad. He can climb on walls and wrap the baddies up in this webs.Powers:Web-slingingInsult-slingingWall ClimbingAlternate Costumes:Scarlet SpiderBlack SuitHulkHulk sure is incredible in both strength and size. He loves a good fight and emptying the fridge. Just don't make him angry. You wouldn't like him when he's angry.Powers:Super StrengthPurple PantsLarge HugsAlternate Costumes:Red HulkWolverineWolverine is a powered mutant with three claws to each hand. He can claw through anything and chop a mean salad. Down side is that he ruins his shirts. Up side is that locked doors don't mean touch to him.Powers:ClawsRegenerationBuying New FurnitureAlternate Costumes:Civilian GearThorPowers:Mighty Thunder BoltHammer TossYea And Verily AttackBlack WidowPowers:Widow’s BiteSpy FeverLooks that KillWar MachinePowers:Repulsor BeamsHeavy WeaponsNot Iron ManWaspPowers:The StingEnergy BlastsItty BittinessMs. MarvelPowers:Energy BeamsFlightNaggingShe-HulkPowers:Super strengthFriendlyNo anger managementX-MenCyclopsPowers:Optic Blast Eye-BeamsTeam LeaderStraight-A StudentJean GreyPowers:Mind BendPsi CryGuess What?StormPowers:LightningWeather ManipulationRaining On Your ParadeEmma FrostPowers:Diamond formDiamond blastsNot a villainRoguePowers:Power absorptionCan "borrow" powersUltimate coolnessFantastic FourMr. FantasticPowers:Power StretchBig WordsBlinding ScienceInvisible WomanPowers:InvisibilityCreation of Invisible ObjectsSuper SneakinessHuman TorchPowers:Flame OnHot ShotsMarshmallow RoastingThingPowers:Super-StrengthRocky ExteriorHeart of GoldMisc.DaredevilPowers:RadarSuperhuman SensesDrum SolosElektraPowers:Sais TwirlRise AgainWhere’d She Go?Dr. StrangePowers:Spell CastingMystic Mind ControlSpiffy DressingSilver SurferPowers:Energy TossMatter ConversionUltimate Cosmic CoolnessBlack PantherPowers:Herbal EssencePanther ClawKing of Scratching PostsVillainsDoctor DoomGreen GoblinSuper SkrullDoctor OctopusM.O.D.O.K.JuggernautMagnetoAlternate CostumesSpidey's alternate costume options.Just in time for the Halloween season of 2010, Gazillion revealed that they would be offering alternate costumes for customization of the Marvel Super Heroes. It appears that each character would be getting the option of two alternate looks.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26649">Marvel Super Hero Squad</game><game id="23609">Magic: The Gathering - Duels of the Planeswalkers</game><game id="6132">Pokémon Stadium 2</game><game id="36105">Club Penguin</game><game id="34489">Spiral Knights</game><game id="37656">MilMo</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1872/1413209-gallery07.jpg</image></root>