<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31895</id><name>Digital Combat Simulator: A-10C Warthog</name><description>Single PlayerCampaignThe campaign in DCS: A-10 takes place during the same conflict as DCS: Black Shark, The Georgian Oil War. Unlike Black Shark, the player will be fighting with the native Georgian inhabitants to help push the invading Russian forces back out of the country.The campaign itself is semi-dynamic in that the missions are linked together based on your performance. For instance, if you do poorly on a mission, the next may be fighting to regain lost ground instead of finishing the enemy off. This method keeps the campaign fluid so the player can continue to progress in the campaign without having to re-fly failed missions repeatedly.Instant ActionThe Instant Action mode of DCS: A10 features five scenarios of varying difficulty. The player will start each scenario in the air, fully loaded with weaponry, and is talked through a series of targets each posing a more significant threat than the last.Mission GeneratorAccessed from the 'Create Fast Mission' option, the mission generator creates random scenarios for the player to fly based on various locations and unit templates. The player my specify difficulty, season, weather, time, and unit sizes involved in the scenario.MultiplayerDCS: A-10 is multiplayer compatible with DCS: Blackshark 2.JTACThe Joint Terminal Attack Controller featured in DCS: A10 is a specialized ground unit that is available to assist the player in finding their targets. Depending on the situation, JTAC can assign targets through UTM coordinates, IR pointer, smoke marker, and laser designator. They are also able to send data directly to the aircraft that is visible on the TAD. In addition to finding the targets, JTAC will also make weapon and attack heading recommendations to help avoid friendly fire.System RequirementsOperating system: 64-bit Windows XP, Vista, and 7Processor: CPU: Core 2 Duo E6600 or AMD Phenom X3 8750 or betterMemory: 4GBHard disk space: 7 GBVideo: Shader 3.0 or better; 512MB NVIDIA GeForce 8600GT DirectX 9.0c or betterSound: DirectX 9.0c-compatibleDirectX®: 9.0C</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="24">Flight Simulator</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11755">Falcon 4.0: Allied Force</game><game id="14628">Falcon 4.0</game><game id="12271">A-10 Cuba!</game><game id="41640">Lock on: Flaming Cliffs 3</game><game id="10331">iF-22</game><game id="42072">Digital Combat Simulator: UH-1H Huey</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/23546/1848560-8.jpg</image></root>