<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3201</id><name>Dual Orb II</name><description>PlotTwo scientists have successfully lead the world into advanced science and technology. Their hunger for knowledge lead them to discover an orb containing infinite power. One scientist became consumed by greed and wanted to take over the world with the orb's power. The other scientist defeated him and the world was left in ruin, but humanity survived and continued to thrive. Years later, an empire manages to revive the evil scientist. Now that he has returned, the fate of humanity is left in the hands of a child born from the heavens.Playable charactersAleth, unofficially a Paladin, who was found by the height priest of Garade during a journey to the castle. He was given the honor of being the next high priest when Lagnus is king of Garade. He and Lagnus grew up together and became best friends. He is raised by the current high priest of Garade and has the ability to use holy magic. Lagnus, prince of Garade. An excellent spearsman that desires for more power to defend his kingdom.  Cassius, a bard who's true secrets are revealed later in the game. Serra, a Goddess that only processes typical human magic powers and a rifle.  Saladin, a thief. A typical swordsmen who eventually learns magic. Najiri, a beast boy who only has one attack, a nail slash. Karina, princess who has power over men, Saladin in particular. She has no magic abilities, but uses a Stab attack. Bargan, captain of a pirate ship who helps players invade an enemy pirate hideout.  Music for Dual Orb II was composed by Nobuyuki Hara and Yu Yoshida. References http://www.fantasyanime.com/legacy2/dualorb2_about.htm </description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6336">Final Fantasy VI</game><game id="20829">Final Fantasy IV</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/12482/750151-dualorb2_box.jpg</image></root>