<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32045</id><name>Deep Black</name><description>OverviewDeep Black is a third-person shooter developed by Biart Studio. The game takes place almost entirely in underwater environments, featuring realistic physics and cover-based shooter gameplay. The game is DirectX 10 compatible and uses an in house engine.StoryThe plot of the game is set in a not so distant future, where bio terrorists plan to deploy a deadly bio virus through the world's water supply. You play as Pierce, a Special Ops soldier equipped with a high tech government suit that gives you the ability to freely roam underwater environments. He's the only hope to stop the terrorists deadly plans.GameplayDeep Black takes place mainly underwater. You control Pierce the same way that you would control Isaac during the zero gravity portions of Dead Space. Pierce can rotate 360 degrees in all directions and never runs out of breath thanks to his suit. To make underwater navigation easier, Pierce is equipped with a jet pack that propels him to where he needs to go.The player has access to high tech equipment such as the harpoon. The harpoon is important for taking out enemies and solving puzzles (most of which consist in raising water levels or opening doors). The harpoon can be used to hack panels that are out of reach. It can also be used to hack some of the smaller mech enemies, turning them against their allies. If you are faced with a human enemy or a bigger mech, the harpoon will drag them over to you, at which point you must complete a quick time event to melee kill your opponent (usually with the blade that sticks out of Pierce's arm).Weapons are an integral part of Deep Black. You have an assault rifle, a pistol and a shotgun. All these weapons can be used underwater, the game providing an over the shoulder zoom when aiming. There are also sequences in the game where you will be fighting on land. For these sequences, the game lets you take cover behind objects as well as perform stealth takedowns.DevelopmentDeep Black was originally called Underwater Wars until a renaming of the game was announced. The game was supposedly going to be released in the first quarter of 2011, however it had been pushed back. It was released in Germany in May 2011, but only in the German language. A worldwide release is due February 2012.System RequirementsOS: Windows XP, Vista or Windows 7Processor: Core 2 Duo 2.4 GHz or Althon X2 2.7 GHzMemory: 1GBHard Disk Space: 6 GB free hard drive spaceVideo Card: DirectX 9, 10 or 11 compatible NVidia or AMD ATI card. NVidia GeForce 8800 or higher. ATI equivalent. Intel Sandy Bridge and higherSound: DirectX compatible sound cardAdditional Notes: Utilizes Sixense technology and supports Hydra RazorExternal LinksOfficial info page of Deep Black.</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="29903">Vanquish</game><game id="30615">Gears of War 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2206970-deep.png</image></root>