<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32089</id><name>Apache: Air Assault</name><description>FeaturesRealistic cockpit with animated gauges, dials and buttonsFull array of the real Apache's arsenal16 multi-stage missions set in South America, Africa and the Middle EastArcade and Realistic difficulty settingsRealistic sound effects and original live orchestra soundtrackDynamic lighting, volumetric clouds and explosionsLocal Co-op with two players choosing between taking the pilot and gunner seatsOnline Co-op for up to four playersAircraftAH-64D LongbowThe upgraded version of the AH-64A features improved sensor capabilities, a fully integrated cockpit, and more advanced weapons. The Fire Control Radar (FCR), is the primary improvement over previous variants. Located in the dome above the main rotors, the FCR provides the capability to detect and launch of missiles at targets while the Apache is still masked from view. It also shares targeting data with other Longbow Apache units who can engage based off the detection from a single Apache.Armaments30 mm M230 chain gun: electronically operated using external power instead of recoil to reload rounds. Capable of firing 300 rounds per minute with a maximum capacity of 1,200 rounds.AGM-114L Hellfire missile: air-to-surface missile designed primarily for anti-armor use. Each Hellfire has a 20 lb (9kg) warhead and has a maximum operating range of 8,000 meters. The Apache can carry up to 16 Hellfire missiles on its hard point wing stub pylons.AIM-92 Stinger: air-to-air missile developed from the shoulder launched FIM-92 Stinger system for use with Apache helicopters. The Apache can carry a total payload of four of these missiles in two by two-round pods on each side of the wing stubs.Hydra 70: Folding-fin Aerial Rockets (FFAR) are unguided 70 mm (2.76 in) rockets, and used for general purpose. They are mounted on hard point pylons on the Apache’s wing stubs. The Hydra can be fitted with a number of different warheads including flechette anti-personnel, general purpose blast fragmentation, and armor piercing.WAH-64 Westland Apache AH-1British Army variant of the AH-64D built by Augusta Westland in Yeovil, England. Changes include new more powerful Rolls Royle engines, new electronic defensive aids suite, and folding-blade mechanism allowing for ship deployment. Rounds are designed to fragment upon impact with a lethal radius of 10 feet.Armaments30MM M230 chain gunAGM-114 HellfireAIM-92 StingerCRV7: Unguided rockets with a larger blast radius and further range than the Hydra. The Westland Apache can carry up to 75 CRV7s.Aircraft available in Free Flight modeMi-35 HINDMQ-8B Fire ScoutLocationsTaziristanMountain-yDefinitely not Afghanistan. It's Taziristan. Totally different letters. You are part of a private military corporation (PMC), imaginatively titled Lastline Defense Corporation, linked with a Joint Task Force operating out of Forward Operating Bases (FOB) in a mountainous region of Afgha... Taziristan. Pesky insurgents are constantly attacking FOBs in the area and your Apache unit are the lastline (zing!) of defense.SalcedoJungle-yCentral American country. War on Drugs. Apache gunships. Nicholas Cage. Tommy Lee Jones. A relatively sane Sean Young. Yes, Fire Birds was a piss-poorTop Gun knock-off. Salcedo, on the other hand, is a jungle based area of operations where some very naughty drug cartels are in desperate need of somegood old 30 Mike Mike.Lualia People's RepublicDesert-yWe can't name it Somalia, that would be uncouth! OK, how about... Lualia? Perfect! Just make it a People's Republic and the disguise is complete! Yes, thecoast of Africa (Laughfrica, surely?) is plagued by nefarious blaggards and pernicious pirates. What better way to deal with these poor third world wretchesthan by sending in heavily armed gunships to give them a good thrashing. In the empty immensity of earth, sky and water, there you'll be, incomprehensible, firing into a continent, in an Apache.PC System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows 98/ME/2000/XPProcessor: Pentium 3 @ 450 MHzMemory: 96 MBHard Drive: 300 MB FreeVideo Memory: 16 MBSound Card: DirectX CompatibleRecommendedOS: Windows 98/ME/2000/XPProcessor: Pentium 4 @ 1 GHzMemory: 256 MBHard Drive: 300 MB FreeVideo Memory: 32 MBSound Card: DirectX Compatible</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="24">Flight Simulator</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20722">Il-2 Sturmovik: Birds of Prey</game><game id="1003">Gunship 2000</game><game id="20968">Heroes Over Europe</game><game id="13712">Blazing Angels: Squadrons of WWII</game><game id="19216">Blazing Angels 2: Secret Missions of WWII</game><game id="35580">Top Gun: Hard Lock</game><game id="1807">Apache Air Assault</game><game id="20011">Enemy Engaged: Apache/Havoc</game><game id="39118">Apache</game><game id="32297">Ace Combat Assault Horizon</game><game id="10926">Jane's Combat Simulations: AH-64D Longbow: Flash Point Korea</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/6/63119/1554375-91ezxgzweol._aa1500_.jpg</image></root>