<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32248</id><name>The Sims Medieval</name><description>Overview A medieval kingdomThe Sims Medieval combines elements from The Sims 3, Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles: My Life as a King and an RPG.  Unlike other games in the Sims franchise, players start The Sims Medieval by themselves as a hero in a kingdom of one. Through quests that you'll be given in-game you will earn points. You can use points to add new buildings and bring people to your kingdom.  EA has stated that combat and questing in The Sims Medieval will be relatively simplistic.  Another change from the other games in the series is the ability to control all of the people in your kingdom at will, not just a single household.As you gain followers they'll have two main jobs within your kingdom.  First they'll have everyday tasks based on their profession.  So a physician will be responsible for curing patients.  Second, your followers can be used to complete quests. Quests are given to the player by the game and will have multiple choices for completion.  Once a quest has been successfully completed, points are awarded.  The ultimate goal in The Sims Medieval is  to achieve your kingdom's ambition.EA also states that the game will have the following features, but no additional information is available on them:  Magic is available and can be used by Wizards. A Crafting system will be in place for creating weapons and medicine. Diplomacy will allow you to trade with or declare war on surrounding kingdoms. Buildings can be customized but must retain their given shape.  This means players will not be able to create their own buildings from scratch like you can in other Sims games.System RequirementsWindows: Processor: 2.0 GHz P4 / 2.6 GHz P4 (Vista)Memory: 1 GB of RAM / 1.5 GB (Vista)Graphics Card: 128 MB Video Card with support for Pixel Shader 2.0 (or better)DirectX: 9.0cHard Disk Space: 5.3 GB / 1 GB of additional space for custom content and saved gamesMAC OS X: OS: Mac OS X 10.5.8 Leopard or higherProcessor: Intel Core DuoMemory: 2 GB of RAMGraphics Card: ATI X1600 or Nvidia 7300 GT with 256 MB of Video RAM, or Intel Integrated GMA X3100.Hard Disk Space: 5.3 GB / 1 GB of additional space for custom content and saved games</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17463">The Sims</game><game id="2473">The Sims 2</game><game id="20581">The Sims 3</game><game id="20648">Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles: My Life as a King</game><game id="8897">Stronghold 2</game><game id="35872">The Sims Medieval: Pirates and Nobles</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/30036/1777126-box_165433_hd.jpg</image></root>