<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32274</id><name>Knight Online</name><description>FeaturesFight in a permanent PVP environmentChoose a side in the conflict between El Morad and Karus4 character classesMage wielding magic from beyondA stoic PriestWarrior with bone crushing strengthA Rogue hidden within the shadowsBi-weekly wars and castle SiegesEarn the chance to be KingCompletely Free2PlayPurchase exclusive items in the Power Up StoreClassesRoqueThe roque is able to use ranged weapons as well as daggers. Humans can specialize as Rangers (Job 2) and Kasar Hood (Job 3), while the Orcs specialize as Hunter (Job 2) and Shadow Bane (Job 3).MageMages are able to use magic in order to attack their enemies. They later on are able to master their abilities in one school of magic. Humans can specialize as Mage (Job 2) and Arc Mage (Job 3), while the Orcs specialize as Sorcerer (Job 2) and Elemental Lord (Job 3).WarriorWarriors are in the front row of the battlefield. They take the most damage while dealing high damage to their enemies and serve as the classic tank class. Humans are able to specialize as Blade (Job 2) or Blade Master (Job 3), while Orcs specialize as Berserker (Job 2) and Berserker Hero (Job 3).PriestPriests are the classic support class. They are able to cast buff and healing spells. Humans are able to specialize as Cleric (Job 2) and Paladin (Job 3), while Orcs specialize as Shaman (Job 2) and Shadow Knight (Job 3).  System Requirements Minimun: CPU: Celeron 300 MhzMemory: 128 MBHard Disk Space: 400 MBVideo Card: 16 MB Direct X 8.1 Recommended: Pentium II 400 MhzMemory: 256 MBHard Disk Space: 600 MBVideo Card: 32 MB Direct X 8.1</description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22087">Silkroad Online</game><game id="22187">Flyff - Fly For Fun</game><game id="27896">World of Warcraft: Cataclysm</game><game id="22239">Runes of Magic</game><game id="20666">Warhammer Online: Age of Reckoning</game><game id="9641">Age of Conan: Hyborian Adventures</game><game id="35439">Kal Online</game><game id="27070">Mu Online</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/39947/1792503-1s_large.jpg</image></root>