<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32417</id><name>Neverwinter</name><description>OverviewNeverwinter is a free, action MMORPG set in the Forgotten Realms city of Neverwinter, developed by Cryptic Studios. Neverwinter is planned to be a crossmedia event accompanying a tabletop game from Wizards of the Coast and four books by fantasy author R.A. Salvatore.StoryIt's been 100 years since the spellplague left the world of Faerûn in ruins. Neverwinter built near the Sea of Swords is still being rebuilt from the destruction when dark forces gather to take of control the land for themselves. This is a world where death is found for the weak, glory and gold for the brave and bold, and danger for this is the world of Neverwinter.GameplayNeverwinter is an action-MMORPG set in a ever evolving persistent world with thousands of other players. Neverwinter is being built with the same engine as Cryptic's two other MMOs, Champions Online and Star Trek Online.Adventure Creation Tools (Foundry)Neverwinter will feature The Foundry, the same user-generated content tool as Star Trek Online. Cryptic claim that players will be able to create their own dungeons, castles, quests, NPCs, and other MMO content, and then share it with the entire player base.ClassesGreat Weapon FighterThe Great Weapon Fighter is a warrior class which wields two handed weapons.Guardian FighterThe Guardian Fighter is a sword and board tanking class which specializes in defence.Trickster RogueThe Trickster Rogue class is a dual-wielding blade class who have teleportation abilities.Divine ClericDivine Clerics are the healers in Neverwinter, although they also have access to AoE damage spells.Control WizardA crowd control-focused mage class. The Control Wizard has the ability to stun multiple enemies at once.Playable RacesHumanRacial Traits:+2 to any Ability ScoreVersatile Defense - Increased defense by 3%Heroic Effort - Gain additional Feat Point at levels 10, 15, and 20Half-ElfRacial Traits:+2 Constitution+2 Charisma or WisdomDilettante - +1 to a non-class Ability ScoreKnack for Success - +1% Deflect, +1% Critical Severity, and +1% Gold FindElf (Wood)Racial Traits:+2 Dexterity+2 Wisdom or IntelligenceElven Accuracy - Increases Critical Strikes by 1%Wild Step - 10% resistance to Slow effectsDwarfRacial Traits:+2 Constitution+2 Strength or WisdomStand Your Ground - Increased resistance to Knock and Repel effectsCast-Iron Stomach - Increased damage resistance to DoT effectsTieflingRacial Traits:+2 Charisma+2 Constitution or IntelligenceBloodhunt - Deals additional 5% damage to foes below half healthInfernal Wrath - 10% chance when hit to lower the Power of the attacker by 5% for 5 secondsHalflingRacial Traits:+2 Dexterity+2 Charisma or ConstitutionNimble Reaction - Grants 3% chance to Deflect attacksBold - Increases resistance to Crowd Control effects by 10%Half-OrcRacial Traits:+2 Dexterity+2 Constitution or StrengthFurious Assault - Additional 5% damage on Critical HitsSwift Charge - 10% increase to Run Speed for 3 seconds when entering combatDrow (Announced. Not yet available) DevelopmentChanging FocusNeverwinter was announced as a coop game in August of 2010. Atari owned Cryptic Studios at the time and was planning on releasing Neverwinter in 2011 as part of a greater media campaign for Neverwinter-based products. This idea was shelved when Atari sold Cryptic Studios to Perfect World Entertainment in May, 2011. The game was shown at E3 2011, but shortly thereafter began its transformation from coop RPG to free-to-play MMO. It was delayed multiple times by Perfect World, ultimately pushing it into mid-2013.BetaNeverwinter held several closed beta weekends beginning in February 2013. Players were phased in based on their level of purchase (into founders packs), other Perfect World games they own, and PAX attendance keys. The open beta began Apr. 30, 2013. As of the open beta, player accounts will not be wiped and the game is essentially released.System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Windows XP SP3, Vista, 7 or 8CPU: Dual-core 2.0GHz CPURAM: 1GBGPU: 128MB, GeForce 6800 or ATI Radeon X850 or higher, Shader Model 2.0Sound: DirectX 9.0c compatible sound chip or onboard audioInternet: Broadband Internet Connection RequiredRecommended:OS: Windows XP SP3, Vista, 7 or 8CPU: Intel Core 2 Duo 2.8GHzRAM: 2GBGPU: 512MB, GeForce 8800 or ATI Radeon HD 2900GT, Shader Model 2.0Sound: DirectX 9.0c compatible sound chip or onboard audioInternet: Broadband Internet Connection Required</description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/97089/2502904-untitled.png</image></root>