<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32412</id><name>Star Ruler</name><description>OverviewStar Ruler is a Real-Time 4X Strategy Game with an emphasis on scale and user customization.GameplayLike many other 4X strategy games, Star Ruler encourages players to eXplore, eXpand, eXploit, and eXterminate. In Star Ruler, this is accomplished by building up and designing combat ships and establishing colonies in various solar systems within the scope of a single galaxy. Star Ruler distinguishes itself within the genre through several key gameplay mechanics.Procedurally-Generated GalaxiesEvery time you start a new game of Star Ruler, the engine randomly generates a galaxy from the initial variables set up by the player. Each of these systems will contain unique planets with different characteristics and varying statistics. The number of star systems within the galaxy is literally only limited by the power of your CPU.ResearchIn a Real-Time Strategy (RTS) games, players are clearly told what each research objective will yield. In keeping with the procedurally-generated nature of Star Ruler's galaxy-generation system, the research tree is similarily randomized. Some research decisions may turn into dead ends. They may also facilitate a breakthrough in a different field, thus opening further research options. As players unlock upgraded technologies, they are then able to add new subsystems to be added to ship blueprints. This works in tandem with the random galaxies to ensure that no two games roll out in precisely the same way.CombatStar Ruler fully simulates Newtonian physics as battles play out. This means that ships will not come to a dead stop when you tell them to stop moving. They will drift and orbit one another. Furthermore, individual components and subsystems of ships can be compromised and/or damaged in a variety of ways. This means that you can hypothetically create a massive fleet of expendable fighters as shock troops to overwhelm the targeting systems of a massive battelcruiser before sending in a few boarding party ships to take over the behemoth and add it to your fleet.Ship ScaleStar Ruler is perhaps most well-known for the insane scale that can be reached with ship designs. There are numerous YouTube videos displaying ships that have been designed to be larger than the entire galaxy in which the game takes place. Of course, the usefulness of these monstrosities is a little questionable, but it is in keeping with Blind Mind's apparent dedication to absolute freedom when it comes to playing Star Ruler.System RequirementsMinimumOperating System: Windows XP, Vista, 7CPU: 1 Core, 2.0 GHz, SSE2 Support (Pentium 4 and higher)System Memory: 512 MBGraphics Memory: 256 MBGraphics Driver: OpenGL 2.1 or betterScreen Resolution: 1024x768 or HigherFree Hard Drive Space: 500 MB KeyboardRecommendedCPU: 2 Cores, 2.5 GHzSystem Memory: 1024 MBGraphics Memory: 256 MB</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9115">Sins of a Solar Empire</game><game id="13152">Sword of the Stars</game><game id="30750">Sword of the Stars II: The Lords of Winter</game><game id="5647">Imperium Galactica II: Alliances</game><game id="6605">Lost Empire: Immortals</game><game id="30683">Distant Worlds</game><game id="30452">Armada 2526</game><game id="3072">Ascendancy</game><game id="8154">Stars!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14230/1474321-3049178975_1.png</image></root>