<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3242</id><name>Sid Meier's Civilization III: Conquests</name><description>ConquestsMesopotamiaRise of RomeFall of RomeMiddle AgesMesoamericaAge of DiscoverySengokuNapoleonic EuropeWorld War II in the PacificNew CivilizationsByzantines- Scientific/Seafaring, Leader: Empress Theodora, Unique Unit: Dromon (replaces Galley)Hittites- Commercial/Expansionist, Leader: King Mursilis I, Unique Unit: 3-Man Chariot (replaces Chariot)Incans- Agricultural/Expansionist, Leader: Sapa-Inca Pachacuti, Unique Unit: Chasqui Scout (replaces Scout)Mayans- Agricultural/Industrious, Leader: Great Instigator Smoke-Jaguar, Unique Unit: Javelin Thrower (replaces Archer)Netherlands- Agricultural/Seafaring, Leader: King William of Orange, Unique Unit: Swiss Mercenary (replaces Pikeman)Portugal- Expansionist/Seafaring, Leader: Prince Henry the Navigator, Unique Unit: Carrack (replaces Caravel)Sumeria- Agricultural/Scientific, Leader: King Gilgamesh, Unique Unit: Enkidu Warrior (replaces Warrior)Austria (hidden)- Industrious/Militaristic, Leader: Emperor Charles V, Unique Unit: Hussar (replaces Cavalry)New Civilization TraitsAgriculturalStarting Techs: Pottery (Masonry if paired with Expansionist trait)Bonuses: Base city squares produce 1 additional food. Irrigated desert squares produce extra food. Cheaper aqueducts, recycling plants, and solar plants.SeafaringStarting Techs: Alphabet (Pottery if paired with Commercial trait)Bonuses: Higher chance of starting near ocean. Coastal cities receive bonus commerce. Ships have increased movement and less chance of sinking at sea. Cheaper water based city improvements (Coastal Fortress, Harbor, Offshore Platform, Commercial Docks).Civilization Trait AdjustmentsCarthaginians to Industrial/SeafaringSpain to Religious/SeafaringEngland to Commercial/SeafaringScandinavia to Militaristic/SeafaringCelts to Agricultural/ReligiousIroquois to Agricultural/CommercialAztecs to Agricultural/MilitaristicNew GovernmentsFascismIncreased worker speed, war weariness eliminated.FeudalismLessened corruption, heightened war weariness, unit maintenance cost increased, city improvement maintenance costs eliminated.New Great Wonders of the WorldThe Internet- Research Lab added to every continental friendly city. Triggers Golden Age.The Statue of Zeus- Produces Ancient Cavalry unit every 5 turns for free. Rendered obsolete by Metallurgy.The Temple of Artemis- Adds a temple to every city on the continent. Rendered obsolete by Education.The Mausoleum of Mausollos- Makes 3 unhappy citizens content in city which built.Knights Templar- Produces free Crusader unit every 5 turns. Rendered obsolete by Steam Power.New Small Wonders of the WorldSecret Police HQ- Acts as second Forbidden Palace. Only available to build and under effect with Communism as government.New UnitsScientific Great Leaders- Used to boost science in a city for 20 turns or to hurry production.GuerillaMedieval Infantry- Upgrades from SwordsmanTOW InfantryAncient Cavalry- Created by Statue of Zeus wonderCrusader- Created by Knights Templar wonderModern ParatroopersCurraghTrebuchet- Upgrades from Catapult, Upgrades to CannonCruiserFlak CannonMobile SAMNew City ImprovementsCivil Defense- Provides a defense bonus against attack and bombardment.Commercial Dock- Increase trade in every water square in city's radius. Only available for coastal cities.Stock Exchange- Boosts tax output of city. Prerequisite for Wall Street small wonder changed from 5 banks to 5 stock exchanges.New Victory ConditionsEliminationRegicideMass RegicideVictory Point ScoringCapture the PrincessReverse Capture the Flag Online PlayThis expansion pack featured online play featuring all the new victory conditions as well as Hotseat play and PBEM (Play by Email)</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="8">Educational</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16457">Sid Meier's Civilization IV</game><game id="14391">Heroes of Might and Magic: A Strategic Quest</game><game id="17753">Europa Universalis II: Asia Chapters</game><game id="12343">Call to Power II</game><game id="1915">Heroes of Might and Magic V</game><game id="21681">Europa Universalis III: In Nomine</game><game id="21493">Europa Universalis III: Napoleon's Ambition</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/15/155745/2168069-box_pc.jpg</image></root>