<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3244</id><name>Toki Tori</name><description>OverviewThe game's logo.Toki Tori is a puzzle-platformer, originally released on September 12, 2001 and was originally published by Capcom. The title was met with poor sales, although it received generally positive reviews.A remake with new levels was released on WiiWare as a downloadable game. The game was priced at 1000 Wii Points ($10) in North America and 900 Wii Points ($9) in Europe. The remake included new levels, enhanced graphics, cooperative play, and more. An iPhone version of the remake was released in May 2009 with bonus levels not included in the Wii version.On January 29th, 2010 the game was released on Steam. This PC-version includes several new levels and content, and 37 Steam-achievements.The original Game Boy Color version was made available on the 3DS eShop (in the US) on August 30, 2012.GameplayA screenshot from the PC version.The goal of Toki Tori is simple: Collect all of the eggs scattered around the levels using whatever abilities you have been given.Toki Tori is able to run around, climb ladders, jump half block distances and survive any drop by flapping his wings, however only by utilising powers such as a freeze gun to disable enemies, the bridge tool to build across gaps, a teleport power to move past some walls, can he avoid the many dangers and collect all of the eggs in each level.However Toki is limited in how many of each power he can use, this is where the game becomes challenging and requires the player to think carefully about what powers they use at what time, as many times a player may run out of the necessary ability as they come within 3 blocks of the final egg, forcing the player to restart the level again.The puzzles take Toki Tori through a variety of worlds, ranging from lush, colorful jungles to underground sewage systems, crawling with slugs, to the ocean, where frozen enemies float to the top of the levels.Skills / AbilitiesIn order to solve the many puzzle the game has to offer, Toki Tori has 8 different abilities at his disposal, all of which having a limited number of uses per level, depending on the level itself.BridgeThis item will allow Toki Tori to build a section of bridge right in front of him, thus allowing him to move over gaps-- you cannot build bridges too near to lava.TelewarpA basic teleport; Toki Tori can be moved into a nearby space, given there is room for him there and that the covered distance meets the ability's limited reach. The Teleport can move Toki Tori up or down, left or right.Freeze-O-MaticThe Freese-O-Matic is a weapon to be used against enemies-- as the name hints, firing this gun will freeze foes into an ice cube. The player must however be aware that these ice cubes are not movable and they will never unmelt, so they can really block your passage.Brick SwitchCertain sets of bricks that are blocking your way can be move, as long as Toki Tori uses this ability-- Toki Tori will grab a stack of bricks directly in front of him and will drop them right behind him.Ghost TrapToki Tori will place a magical trap on the ground beneath him-- if a Ghost walks over the trap it immediately falls right through the floor, taking any blocks with it, leaving a hole and possible passage to what used to be an unreachable area. The Ghost Trap only works on brick floors, though, never on wood.Slug SuckerAny Slugs in your way can either be removed or redirected with the Slug Sucker-- you can change a Slug's direction by standing behind it and quickly pressing the ability key/button; this will make the Slug turn towards you. If you press the ability key/button for a longer period of time, you will instead suck the Slug into your Slug Sucker and remove it from the level.Note: you will only use up this item when the Slug is sucked all the way into the sucker; changing a Slug's direction will not consume the ability.Instant RockToki Tori will throw a small pebble in the space directly in front of him; as soon as it touches the ground it will instantly grow into a large square stone. This can be used to fill gaps in the ground or simply to gain access to higher platforms.Bubble SuitUse this suit to float underwater. This ability is only hindered by its limited number of moves, but these can be refilled by using bubble sources. You can move up or down and left or right. Once you have used your last move the bubble will burst. This ability can be used to move across gaps or reach higher platforms.System Requirements for PCOS: Windows XP, Vista, or Windows 7Processor: Intel Pentium 4 / AMD Athlon XP 1.5 Ghz or higherMemory: 1 GB RAM (Vista), 512mb (XP)Graphics: DirectX 9 compatible, 128MB VRAMDirectX: DirectX 9.0cHard Drive: 200 MB of free space</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1446">Lemmings</game><game id="5429">The Lost Vikings</game><game id="11650">Troddlers</game><game id="19090">Mario vs. Donkey Kong 2: March of the Minis</game><game id="18285">Mario vs. Donkey Kong</game><game id="15800">Humans 1 and 2</game><game id="25524">Lode Runner</game><game id="33376">RUSH</game><game id="20716">Braid</game><game id="22664">Catrap</game><game id="38475">A Day in the Woods</game><game id="38473">Super Yum Yum Adventure</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3661/1331974-header__7_.jpg</image></root>