<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32451</id><name>Game Chest: Solitaire Edition</name><description>Overview   Game Chest: Solitaire Edition is a Solitaire game developed by                  Bonfire Studios and published by                 Microsoft Studios for the                Windows Phone 7. Gameplay   One of the In-Game Pins Game Chest: Solitaire Edition is comprised of three different Solitaire variations. Each of the three games uses the same touch controls. The player can choose a card by tapping it and then tapping the desired spot for the card to go or the card can be tapped, held, and then drug to the desired location.  Game Chest Solitaire features the ability to resume any game that was left playing. Game Chest: Solitaire utilizes the Windows Phone 7               Xbox Live capabilities and features              achievements. On top of the Xbox Live achievements there are several in-game only achievements known as pins. There are also individual leader boards for each of the Solitaire games that track the amount of wins the player has had. All three of the games in Game Chest Solitaire feature lifetime stat tracking. These stats include:  Total Games PlayedLifetime WinsLifetime LossesCurrent Winning StreakBest Winning StreakWorst Losing StreakLifetime MovesLifetime Completed SuitsLifetime Cards FlippedFastest Win TimeTotal Game TimeAverage Game TimeSolitaire GamesGame Chest Solitaire contains three different variations on Solitaire:  Klondike Solitaire   A Game of Klondike Solitaire     Klondike Solitaire is the classic Solitaire game. There is an option to play either draw 1 or draw 3. There are four empty foundation spaces at the top of the playing table, the object of Klondike Solitaire is to build the foundation piles starting at the Ace of a suit to the King.   Scoring: Moving a card from the waste pile to the table: 5 PointsFlipping up a face down card on the table: 5 PointsMoving a card on to a foundation: 10 PointsRemoving a card from a foundation: -15 Points Spider Solitaire    A 4 Suit Game of Spider Solitaire    In Spider Solitaire the goal is to build  groups of cards of a single suit from King down to Ace. The stacks are all built on the play field and will be removed once a complete stack from King to Ace has been completed. This game features the option to include 1 suit, 2 suits, 3 suits, or all 4 suits.   Scoring: Moving a card or stack: -1 PointBuilding a full stack of a single suit: 100 Points   Tri-Peaks Solitaire   A Game of Tri-Peaks Solitaire    In Tri-Peaks Solitaire the object of the game is to get rid of all the cards on the table. The cards on the table are laid out like 3 pyramids side by side. In order to get rid of a card from the table it must be 1 number lower or higher than the card on the top of the waste pile.  Scoring: Dealing a card: -5 PointsPlaying a card on to the waste pile: 1 Point, plus one more point for every card played without drawing a new one from the deckPlaying the last card from a peak: 15 PointsPlaying the last card from the last peak: 30 Points</description><genres><genre id="13">Card Game</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="624">Soltrio Solitaire</game><game id="31055">Solitaire: Ultimate Collection</game><game id="32450">Game Chest: Logic Games</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8272/1789982-game_chest__solitaire_edition2073.png</image></root>