<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3247</id><name>Untold Legends: Brotherhood of the Blade</name><description>In Untold Legends, you take control of a warrior, berserker, druid, or alchemist in order to save the city you live in. Strange monsters  have been threatening the city with destruction, both from the forests surrounding the city and the sewers underneath. The gameplay is straight hack'n'slash, with an attack button and two spell hotkeys. Each character gets unique skills and weapon abilities, and can wear unique armor specific to their class.StoryIn the beginning of the game your character wakes up after having some disturbing dreams. After waking up you find that the city of Avon is under attack by the spider race known as the Praetox. Your character fights his way through the streets of Avon to find Overseer Lyetta who tells you to go into the catacombs to stop the Praetox. After your character has explored a few of the sewers, he will be tasked with recovering the Venom off the Prateox Queen.You go into the sewers one final time and fight the Praetox Queen, when defeated, you give the Venom back to the Overseer so you can help Kaylee (A woman who has been bittenby the prateox so will soon turn into a lifeless zombie). Afterwards, your character talks to the Eldar of Avon and he tasks you with going out of the gates of the city and fighting a race known as the Gorgein. Your first task involves defeating the three Gorgein shamen and afterwards recovering the Distilling Crystal that is needed to help Kaylee. Once you have recovered the crystal your goal is to prevent the Gorgein attackingAvon, so you try and create a war between the Gorgein and another race so Avon can prepare a defence.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13217">Champions of Norrath</game><game id="13822">Monster Hunter Freedom</game><game id="20223">Monster Hunter Freedom 2</game><game id="11620">Dungeon Siege: Throne of Agony</game><game id="25133">.hack//Link</game><game id="25694">Ys I &amp; II Chronicles</game><game id="25690">Ys SEVEN</game><game id="19621">Ys: The Ark of Napishtim</game><game id="839">Ys: The Oath in Felghana</game><game id="13091">Baldur's Gate: Dark Alliance</game><game id="12107">Baldur's Gate: Dark Alliance II</game><game id="21633">Soma Bringer</game><game id="25935">Monster Hunter Freedom Unite</game><game id="21636">Dungeon Explorer: Warriors of Ancient Art</game><game id="11806">Silverfall</game><game id="32416">DeathSpank: Thongs of Virtue</game><game id="30580">Monster Hunter Portable 3rd</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1837519-box_ulbotb.png</image></root>