<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32489</id><name>Puzzle Bots</name><description> Overview Puzzle Bots is a       point-and-click adventure game, developed by     Erin Robinson with some assistance from          Wadjet Eye Games.PlotPuzzle Bots takes place in Dr. Hugo’s Factory for Making Robots, which is a factory specializing in, you guessed it: making robots. One of the inventors employed there, named Zander, stumbles across a mysterious box outside the factory. He brings it up stairs to show it to his co-workers, but they have no clue how to open it. After a set of events involving the mysterious box, the factory's robots set on a grand adventure.Gameplay Puzzle Bots is a puzzle-centric adventure game. The player has to use the robots to overcome obstacles and solve puzzles with their specific abilities. The player can take control of one robot at a time and can switch between them at anytime. Each robot has their own unique ability:   Hero  Hero is Zander's creation and has the ability to climb and pick up objects Ultrabot is Theo's robot, and has the ability to push heavy objects.  Ibi is Yukiro's invention, and has the ability to swim. Kelvin is Viktor's bot, and has the ability to burn objects with his flamethrower.  Bomchelle is Astrid's robot, and has the ability to throw bombs Characters Dr.Hugo Dr. Hugo - Dr Hugo is the proud owner of Dr Hugo’s Factory for making Robots.  His Factory is rolling out a new line of kinder, gentle robots and he is hoping to get all the robots ready by Christmas time.                       Zander   Zander -  Creator of Hero. Zander is nice and friendly but  absent minded.          Theo       Theo-  He is the creator of Ultrabot and a College-student intern and certified nerd. He is a snob when it comes to robots.         Yuriko       Yuriko - Creator of Ibi, Yuriko is a shy Japanese girl. She learnt everything she knows from the Japanese school system. Yuriko has a secret crush on her co-worker Zander.           Viktor       Viktor - Creator of Kelvin, Viktor has a blunt personality. He is trying to get fired, and as a result he has created a robot with a flamethrower. He knows about Yuriko's secret crush on Zander.           Astrid. Astrid- Creator of Bomchelle, Asrid is the newest employee of Dr Hugo’s Factory for Making Robots. She is the smartest employee of Dr Hugo’s  factory- and knows it.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="24816">Emerald City Confidential</game><game id="37223">Resonance</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/97089/2240236-pb_posterb.png</image></root>