<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32490</id><name>Shibuya</name><description>OverviewShibuya is a falling block puzzle game created by            Nevercenter for the            iPhone and            iPad.  The game is named after a            district of Tokyo  known for its bright, colorful lighting and is designed around touch  screen controls that are simple and easy to grasp.  Shibuya was created  by Tom Plewe, John Plewe, Stephanie Schenck, and David Randall. John  Plewe is credited as the concept creator, but all four of the credited  team members played major roles in the game's development.  It was  selected as one of the            PAX 10 independent titles and put on display at            PAX 2010 in Seattle.  Gameplay    The play field is composed of falling blocks that must be stacked by color.      Shibuya  offers two basic modes of play.  A Quick Play mode in which the game  will last for a maximum of two minutes, and Endless, in which the game  will end when the stack of blocks reaches the top of the screen.  In the  main play field, a continuous flow of empty, gray blocks falls.  If  tapped by the player before it lands on the top of the stack, the block  will fill with the current color at the top of the queue.  The player is  not obligated to immediately fill each block as they come along, and  may skip blocks in order to fill others first. Following these  basic rules, the objective of the game is to create stacks of blocks of  matching colors in groups of two or more.  Like-colored blocks that are  stacked together can then be cleared from the board with a single  touch.  Combos can be formed by tapping multiple groups of matched  blocks in a row, which will increase your multiplier.   Music  The game features licensed music from            Millionyoung.  All of           Millionyoung's songs featured in Shibuya can be found on the "Be So True EP."           "Be So True EP" Track List:    1. "Cynthia"  2. "Soft Denial"  3. "Mien"  4. "Pilfer"  5. "Day We Met"    Achievements  Currently, Shibuya offers 47 achievements divided into eleven different  levels. The first ten levels have four achievements and the eleventh  level has seven achievements. The player cannot unlock level two  achievements until they have unlocked all of the level one achievements.  Some of the achievements are as easy as playing a game in Quickplay  mode, but they quickly ramp up in difficulty.    Level 1 - Getting Started  Play Quickplay ModeMake a Combo in QuickplayReach Level 2 in Endless Survive Quickplay on SlowLevel 2 - Neophyte 1   4x Combos in Quickplay1   All Clears in Quickplay  1   Massive in QuickplaySurvive Quickplay on Normal Level 3 - Novice  Reach Level 14 in Endless1000  Points in QuickplaySurvive Endless for 3 Minutes5 Survive Quickplay on Adept Level 4 -  Intermediate  1   5x Combos in Quickplay 3   Massives in Quickplay5   All Clears in Quickplay5   4x Combos in QuickplayLevel 5 - Competent   Get 100  Skill in Quickplay2000  Points in Quickplay1   Supermassives in QuickplaySurvive Endless for 5 Minutes Level 6 - Veteran  10   All Clears in QuickplayReach Level 26 in Endless 1   of Each Stat in Quickplay10   4x Combos in Quickplay  Level 7 - Advanced 3000  Points in Quickplay5  Massives in Quickplay15  All Clears in QuickplaySurcice Quickplay on Fury  Level 8 - Skilled  15  4x Combos in QuickplaySurvive Endless for 10 Minutes4000  Points in Quickplay2  Supermassives in Quickplay</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1992/1481730-shibuya.jpg</image></root>