<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32594</id><name>Top Spin 4</name><description>OverviewTop Spin 4 is the follow-up to PAM Development's tennis simulator Top Spin 3. Top Spin 4 boasts a robust career mode and an extensive list of playable Tennis professionals.GameplayMy Player ModeMy Player Mode allows players to play as a custom Tennis star that they've created and altered to their liking. Players can determine their star's facial features, nationality and even play style. Play style dictates the star's swings and reactions.Once a custom star has been created, players will then use the career calender to attend events and choose training partners. If an event is selected, players will face one of the game's licensed professionals.My Player Mode awards players with experience points they will use to improve and tweak their star. Using the game's evolution screen, players can distribute points into skills such as forehand, backhand, serve, volley and many others. Gaining experience points and fame will increase the player's rank and notoriety. Leveling up allows the player to hire new coaches to further improve their skills and abilities.As players gain notoriety, they will be contacted by agents and journalists to increase their publicity, gain endorsements and unlock even more events.ControlsPrevious Top Spin titles have been chastised for boasting complicated unintuitive control-schemes. In Top Spin 4, a large focus was put on simplifying the control-scheme, while maintaining the rewarding aspect of previous systems.Basic shot types--these include lob,flat,slice and top spin--are mapped to the face buttons with modifiers mapped to the shoulder buttons.The game's Top Spin Academy is a system whose goal is to get the player acclimated to the new control-scheme while also explaining the basic and complex aspects of the gameplay. The tool attempts to pin-point the player's problems and offer suggestions.Playstation Move and 3D SupportTop Spin 4 is compatible with Sony's Playstation Move. While the title takes advantage of Sony's motion-control technology, the game is not compatible with Microsoft's Kinect.Along with Move support, Top Spin 4 allows players to experience the game in 3D. This feature is available on both the Xbox 360 and Playstation 3.RosterAndre AgassiTop Spin 4 marks the first time tennis legend Andre Agassi has appeared in an interactive entertainment experience in almost a decade. Agassi, along with Rafael Nadal and Serena Williams, appears on the cover of Top Spin 4.Licensed PlayersATPRoger Federer - SwitzerlandRafael Nadal - SpainAndy Murray - Great BritainNovak Djoković - SerbiaAndy Roddick - United StatesJames Blake - United StatesNikolay Davydenko - RussiaGilles Simon - FranceStanislav Wawrinka - SwitzerlandBernard Tomic - AustraliaWTACaroline Wozniacki - DenmarkSerena Williams - United StatesAna Ivanović - SerbiaJelena Janković - SerbiaDinara Safina - RussiaVera Zvonareva - RussiaEugenie Bouchard - CanadaLegendsAndre Agassi - United StatesPete Sampras - United StatesBjorn Borg - SwedenJim Courier - United StatesMichael Chang - United StatesPatrick Rafter - AustraliaIvan Lendl - Czech RepublicBoris Becker - GermanyLicensed TournamentsGrand SlamsAustralian Open (Rod Laver Arena) - Melbourne, Australia (Hard)French Open (Court Philippe Chatrier) - Paris, France (Clay)US Open (Arthur Ashe Stadium) - New York, New York, United States (Hard)Masters 1000BNP Paribas Open (Indian Wells Tennis Garden) - Indian Wells, California, USA (Hard)BNP Paribas Masters - Paris, France (Carpet/Indoor)Sony Ericsson Open - Miami, Florida, United States (Hard)World Tour FinalsATP World Tour Finals (O2 Arena) - London, England (Hard/Indoor)Other VenuesClayMadrid Sports Arena - Madrid, Spain (Masters)Stadio San Alessandro - Rome, Italy (Masters)Court Principal - Monte Carlo, Monaco (Masters)Casablanca Stadium - Casablanca, Morocco (Major)Barcelona Stadium - Barcelona, Spain (Major)Buenos Aires Tennis Center - Buenos Aires, Argentina (Major)Westside Drive - Houston, Texas, USA (Minor)Teranga Tennis Court - Dakar, Senegal (Playground)GrassDublin Stadium - Dublin, Ireland (Grand Slam)London Tennis Club - London, England (Major)Boston Bay Tennis Center - Boston, Massachusetts, USA (Major)Auckland Stadium - Auckland, New Zealand (Minor)American Tennis Garden - San Francisco, California, USA (Minor)Thorsten Brom - Munich, Germany (Minor)HardShanghai Palace - Shanghai, China (Masters)Canada Tennis Center - Toronto, Canada (Masters)Cincinnati Tennis Center - Cincinnati, Ohio, USA (Masters)Hamburg Stadthalle - Hamburg, Germany (Major)Moscow Tennis Arena - Moscow, Russia (Major)Texas Arena - Dallas, Texas, USA (Major)Seoul Colosseum - Seoul, South Korea (Major)Amsterdam Tennis Park - Amsterdam, Netherlands (Major)Vienna Tennis Center - Vienna, Austria (Minor)Stavgaard Tennis Hall - Stavgaard, Sweden (Minor)Abhijava Stadium - New Delhi, India (Minor)Estadio Do Sol - Estoril, Portugal (Minor)Silvjie Krleza - Omis, Croatia (Playground)Bermuda Stadium - Hamilton, Bermuda (Playground)Atlanta's Doves - Atlanta, Georgia, USA (Playground)Dubai Sports Complex - Dubai, UAE (Playground)CarpetGrande Estadio De Chile - Santiago, Chile (Minor)The Bauhinia - Hong Kong, China (Minor)Kiev Indoor Arena - Kiev, Ukraine (Minor)SoundtrackThe game features 15 licensed tracks.Chromeo - "Fancy Footwork"LCD Soundsystem - "North American Scum"Daft Punk - "Da Funk"OK Go - "This Too Shall Pass"Schpilkas - "Fuzzy Fro"Light Alive - "Trust Revenge"RAMZI - "Mr. Pamplinas"PURPL PoP - "It's Your Town"Tigers That Talked - "Black Heart, Blue Eyes"Ben Taimi - "Ticking Of Your Bicycle"Gamble and Burke - "Isolated (With You)"Darko Saric - "Circles"Christian Larsen Music - "Breakwall"Richard Boal/Robin Barter - "TPL Music" (ATP 20 and ATP Deep House)Richard Parks/Joel Doran - "Free Air"Pre-Order Bonus2K Sports teamed up with GameStop to offer a pre-order bonus for Top Spin 4.Players who pre-ordered Top Spin 4 for the Xbox 360 or Playstation 3 from GameStop received a vintage Andre Agassi character model featuring his signature mullet.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="25">Tennis</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25294">Virtua Tennis 2009</game><game id="24396">Grand Slam Tennis</game><game id="32369">Virtua Tennis 4</game><game id="19443">Virtua Tennis 3</game><game id="9908">Virtua Tennis: World Tour</game><game id="14977">Tennis 2K2</game><game id="21145">Smash Court Tennis 3</game><game id="21822">Smash Court Tennis: Pro Tournament 2</game><game id="1789">Smash Court Tennis Pro Tournament</game><game id="20578">Sega Superstars Tennis</game><game id="15769">Anna Kournikova's Smash Court Tennis</game><game id="31474">Namco Tennis Smash Court</game><game id="23423">Agassi Tennis Generation</game><game id="19171">Andre Agassi Tennis</game><game id="5332">ATP Tour Championship Tennis</game><game id="16770">Rockstar Games presents Table Tennis</game><game id="36106">Grand Slam Tennis 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2266556-box_ts4.png</image></root>