<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32604</id><name>Hoard</name><description>OverviewCombining elements of a real-time strategy game with those of a dual-stick shooter, Hoard gives the player control a dragon out to hoard the largest pile of gold. Each dragon has the ability to breathe fire, fly and perform several special abilities by collecting power-ups. Map   Gold is earned in several ways, mostly by killing merchant wagons or destroying buildings but also by picking up treasure chests that appear. Dragons have a limited carrying capacity and must return to their hoard to deposit the gold they have. Destroying crops and other resources will have an effect on the kingdom, causing its inhabitants to prosper or decline, which in turn effects the player's access to gold and their final score. Dragons can also acquire gold by kidnapping princesses, scarring tribute from villages or stealing from the hoard piles of other dragons.There is a rudimentary levelling system in the game tied to the collection of gold. Once certain amounts of gold have been deposited in hoard the player will level up. This will unlock upgrade points that can be used in one of four abilities: fire breath, speed, carrying capacity and armour. Putting points into one of these categories will improve your dragon's performance and adds another layer of strategy to the game.Hoard includes both competitive and co-operative mulitplayer with up to four players.Game ModesTreasureThe goal of this mode is to collect as much treasure as possible in 10 minutes.Princess RushThe goal of this mode is to be the first dragon to ransom fifteen princesses.HoardThe goal of this mode is to simply stay alive as long as possible. You have no hoard, and gold that you pick up is instantly counted toward an automatic upgrade that gives your dragon better armor, speed, and fire breath.Co-opThis mode works just like Treasure, except that multiple dragons share one hoard and work together to build it up.UpgradingAs you drop gold at your hoard, certain gold intervals allow you to invest upgrade points in your dragon's stats. You can upgrade your dragon in 4 ways:SpeedUpgrades how quickly your dragon can fly.Fire BreathUpgrades how long you can breath fire and how much damage the breath does.CarryUpgrades how much gold your dragon can carry and how fast your dragon drops off gold.ArmourUpgrades how much damage your dragon can take before having to return to your hoard.Note: your dragon's appearance will change depending on how you upgrade it.Objects/EnemiesImmediately after a game is started in any mode, the human kingdom will begin to develop. The civilization's structures and units are as follows:NameNotesImageMill / farmMills produce farms and carts at a regular rate. Each farm is worth 100 gold when destroyed, but adds value to carts that leave the mill. PC System RequirementsOperating System: Windows XP or BetterProcessor: Dual Core 2GhzRAM Memory: 2GBHard Disk Space: 625 MBVideo Card: ATI Radeon X800 XL or betterSound Card: Supports OpenAL 1.1 or betterAdditional: Requires OpenGL 2.0 support or better. XBox 360 controller recommendedMultiplayer: Online multiplayer requires Internet ConnectionMac System RequirementsOperating System: OSX 10.5.8 or betterProcessor: Dual Core 2GhzRAM Memory: 2GBHard Disk Space: 625 MBVideo Card: ATI Radeon X800 XL or betterSound Card: Supports OpenAL 1.1 or betterAdditional: Requires OpenGL 2.0 support or better. XBox 360 controller recommendedMultiplayer: Online multiplayer requires Internet Connection</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="31">Dual-Joystick Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20603">Calling All Cars!</game><game id="40873">Be a King: Golden Empire</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3503/1512007-hoardbanner1.jpg</image></root>