<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32606</id><name>Gyakuten Kenji 2</name><description>OverviewGyakuten Kenji 2 is the sixth game in the Ace Attorney franchise and a direct sequel to Ace Attorney Investigations: Miles Edgeworth. The game was released in Japan for the Nintendo DS on February 3rd, 2011 by Capcom but unlike the previous entries in the series the title was not localized for English territories.English ReleaseCapcom USA's Senior Vice President Christian Svensson has stated that Capcom would not be localizing Ace Attorney Investigations 2 on the Nintendo DS citing "the costs of localization are higher than the forecasted return". In subsequent interviews, however Svensson stated that niche titles like AAI2 are good candidates for digital distribution and has reportedly been in talks to convince Capcom to release AAI2 on other platforms. Producer Motohide Eshiro has also stated that main reason AAI2 was not localized was because of scheduling. He stated that the game's development team was disbanded after its release and that the members were assigned to different teams so,"they weren't in a position to localize."However in 2011 a dedicated team of translators and hackers from the Ace Attorney fansite, Court Records, started work on an unofficial English patch for AAI2. The ambitious project is still incomplete but in September of 2013 the team released a beta patch that translated the game's first two cases.StoryMiles Edgeworth, Dick Gumshoe, and Kay Faraday return as main characters. The story further explores Edgeworth's past including a case in which you play as Miles' father, Gregory Edgeworth. New characters introduced include Tateyuki Shigaraki, Gregory Edgeworth's assistant, Yumihiko Ichiyanagi, a rival prosecutor, and Hakari Mikagami, a new judge who seeks to end Miles Edgeworth's career.GameplayAs if chess wasn't logical enoughGyakuten Kenji 2 plays similarly to its predecessor. Some previous mechanics such as the "Little Thief" device have been expanded while some mechanics from previous games such as the luminol fingerprint testing return.A new game mechanic called "Logic Chess" is introduced. </description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1159">Hotel Dusk: Room 215</game><game id="29533">Last Window: The Secret of Cape West</game><game id="17990">Trace Memory</game><game id="23953">Another Code: R - A Journey into Lost Memories</game><game id="24237">Again</game><game id="25156">Lux-Pain</game><game id="21578">Ace Attorney Investigations: Miles Edgeworth</game><game id="40045">Devil's Attorney</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/27239/1620136-15.jpg</image></root>