<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32629</id><name>Trenches</name><description>OverviewTrenches is a game that was developed and published by Thunder Game Works in 2009. It is a mix between castle attack and tower defense games and is set during the Great World War (WW1). Players are put in control of the British Forces as they fight against the Germans on 2D battlefields in a sort of tug of war configuration. Thunder Game Works has included Open Feint support   Gameplay      The game is fairly simple and is very much like any other tug of war or castle attack game as players spawn units which they can then direct forwards or backwards with swipes. All of the units on the field can be manipulated at the same time using two-finger swipes to signal an advance. Each of the various unit types serve very different purposes such as rifleman which are bread  butter units while the mortars work well against packs of units. Artillery and poison gas attacks can also be used against the enemy in combination with trenches placed along the battlefield (defensive structures) and barbed wire which slows movement.    Unit TypesUnitPurpose Riflemen Bread  Butter, good all around EngineersUseful for their ability to upgrade trenches into bunkers Snipers Long-range, high damage units with a slow rate of fire  Machine Gunners Rapid-fire units that can mow down standard infantry Mortar Teams Useful for displacing trenches filled with enemies  Game ModesNameType BattleA standard battle in which victory is achieved by destroying the opponent's bunker The Great Escape A single squad of riflemen is stuck behind enemy lines and needs to be escorted across the battlefield with support from artillery and poison gas OverrunHold off against waves of German forces  Box Barrage The Germans are retreating, cut them off with support elements King of the Trench Capture and defend a central trench from the Germans SappersCapture and upgrade three lines of trenches into bunkers to set up a defensive line against the coast Pygmy HordeHold off against waves of Pygmys from the Pocket God iPhone game  Zombie HordeHold off against endless waves of zombies</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10687">Risk</game><game id="23102">South Park Let's Go Tower Defense Play!</game><game id="32009">SteamWorld Tower Defense</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/10/103101/1514461-trenches_screenshot_1.jpg</image></root>