<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32620</id><name>Section 8: Prejudice</name><description>OverviewJetpacks and Control Points    In response to poor sales numbers of the original Section 8, TimeGate Studios decided to create a sequel solely for digital distribution. A digital distribution pricing model followed suit, dropping the new Section 8's price to $15. TimeGate then shipped a game with complete single player campaign, multiplayer cooperative and adversarial modes, stat tracking, and bot support, hoping players would respond positively to the amount of content for the budget price. As a sequel, Prejudice adds new features and general balancing improvements. The area of effect pulse cannon and speedy hover bike have been added to the armory. The HUD has been overhauled in response to complaints that the original, while informative, was too crowded and distracting. The "burn in" mechanic -- players are spawned kilometers above the playing field and hurtle towards the planet's surface -- is now in third person, making the experience more appreciable for its ludicrous speed.Just don't get shot down...     Unlike the original, new equipment and cosmetic costumes can be unlocked by gaining experience in multiplayer modes or earning stars in single player modes. This new equipment is often a specialized variety of standard equipment. For instance, grenades may deal additional shield or armor damage, and rockets may produce a burning damage over time effect. On 3 May 2011, TimeGate announced that a new "assault" mode would be unlocked for all Prejudice players once 10 million kills had been recorded. Assault mode focuses more on the attack / defend aspect of multiplayer. When the match starts, one team possesses all control points on the map, and it is up to the other team to capture these control points before time runs out. Upon conclusion of the round, the teams swap objectives and begin again.  The goal of 10 million recorded kills was achieved on 11 May 2011. Campaign Lengthier and more story driven than the original Section 8, the campaign revisits Alex Corde, a rookie from the first game, now a battle-hardened veteran. Corde and the other members of the 8th Armored Infantry seek to eradicate the Arm of Orion, a rogue military unit, and the mysterious benefactors who provide the Arm with ships and munitions.  The commander is voiced by     Michael McConnohie, also known as the voice of       The Agency Director in the       Crackdown series.  Dynamic Combat Missions Making a return to conquest mode, DCMs are side missions that occur alongside the battle for control points. Successful completion of a DCM results in bonus victory points for the appropriate team as well as other benefits depending on the mission type: Intelligence: One team must capture another team's intelligence data and carry it back to their base. Successful completion results in all enemy positions being temporarily revealedConvoy: A powerful vehicle must be piloted by a player back to their base. Doing so means the team gets to keep the vehicleOutpost: The team must protect a structure from destruction. If successful, the team now has an additional mini-base with supply depot and anti-aircraft turretVIP: A powerful AI character drops onto the battlefield and must be escorted to safety. Successful completion means the NPC stays to protect a baseAir strike: The team must carry a beacon to an enemy base, resulting in the destruction of all enemy structures at the baseInfiltrator: One player gets to wear an augmented suit that also looks like a member of the other team. This infiltrator must capture an enemy control point to complete the missionJammer: Both teams fight for control over a sensor jammer. Whoever controls the jammer has their positions hidden from the other team's radar within a certain radiusRecover: Pieces of wreckage are scattered across the map. One team must gather the wreckage while the other defends the wreckage until time runs outElimination: All enemy positions are revealed on the map and must be eliminated. Eliminated enemies may respawn and are no longer revealedMinimum System Requirements  Processor: Intel 3.0GHz (single), 2.0GHz (dual), or AMD Athlon XP 3200+ OS: Windows XP / Windows Vista / Windows 7 (latest service packs) Video: NVIDIA GeForce 7800 or ATI Radeon X1900 (NVIDIA GeForce GTX 460 or better recommended) RAM: 2 GB HD: 5.5 GB of available space</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20576">Section 8</game><game id="9993">Halo 3</game><game id="18162">Team Fortress 2</game><game id="17828">Battlefield 2142</game><game id="16866">Battlefield 2</game><game id="18883">Enemy Territory: Quake Wars</game><game id="6026">Medal of Honor: Airborne</game><game id="23436">Shattered Horizon</game><game id="14292">Unreal Championship 2: The Liandri Conflict</game><game id="26786">Halo: Reach</game><game id="36230">Blacklight Retribution</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3661/1765950-prejudice.jpg</image></root>