<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32640</id><name>King's Bounty: Crossworlds</name><description>Orcs on the March expands the content of "King's Bounty Armoured Princess" by providing the following:Various new creatures to command or fight against.Seventy new items and eight new items sets.Seven new quests.Fifty new abilities and skills.Thirteen new spells.A game editor to enable players to create their own new content.Champion of the Arena - You assume the role of Arthur, a mercenary assigned the task of winning fights in a gladiatorial arena. The merchant who employed him in this task wants the grand prize of the Champion' s Belt brought back to him.This campaign contains the following:Five hero skills.Eleven armour bearers.Nine guilds that provide assignments for you to complete.Eight arena bosses.Seven enemy heroes.Defender of the Crown - Princess Amelie is the main character you control in this arena campaign. 3 new heroine skills are available for her while she battles through six arenas with random enemies and allies.PC System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Windows XP/VistaProcessor: 2.6 GHzMemory: 1 GBGraphics: nVidia GeForce 6600 with 128 MB or equivalent ATIHard Drive: 5.5 GB free hard disk spaceSound: DirectX-compatible soundcardRecommended:OS: Windows XP/VistaProcessor: 3 GHzMemory: 2 GBGraphics: nVidia GeForce 7950GT with 512 MB or equivalent ATIHard Drive: 5.5 GB free hard disk spaceSound: DirectX-compatible soundcard</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1915">Heroes of Might and Magic V</game><game id="10692">Heroes of Might and Magic IV</game><game id="13989">Heroes of Might and Magic III: The Restoration of Erathia</game><game id="12466">Heroes of Might and Magic II: The Succession Wars</game><game id="21130">Disciples III: Renaissance</game><game id="33448">Vantage Master</game><game id="33450">VM Japan: Vantage Master - Mystic Far East</game><game id="32374">Might &amp; Magic Heroes VI</game><game id="41470">Folk Tale</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/378/1528015-crossworlds.jpg</image></root>