<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32675</id><name>UFC Personal Trainer</name><description>OverviewUFC Personal Trainer is a game that helps you get fit through training routines designed for and by    MMA fighters. The game is developed by   Heavy Iron Studios and published by  THQ and features different exercises for each console.The game lets you organize your workouts. Each workout is guided by a UFC personal trainer who helps you choose 12 exercises (there are over 70 in the game) for your daily workout routine that works both your arms and legs as well as your upper body and abs. These work outs range from sit ups to hitting punching bags. Your progress is kept in a journal.Kinect FeaturesThat's you bottom right.On the    Xbox 360, the game is compatible with    Kinect. The game shows you arrows indicating how you're supposed to punch or kick (uppercut, low kick, high punch...). On the bottom left of the screen, a green silhouette represents your body and parts of your body glow red when you aren't doing the exercise correctly. You can control your routine with your voice thanks to the built in Kinect microphone.The 360 version also offers multiplayer where you challenge your friends in score attack mode by seeing who can punch the punching bag the most times or flip the tire over the fastest. The 360 version also comes with 4 exclusive UFC trainers and 9 extra exercises.Wii FeaturesThe    Wii version of the game supports both the    Wii Motion Plus and the    Wii Balance Board. Here, the balance board works in the same way as in Wii Fit: you do push ups with both hands on the board so the game can detect how many full push ups you have done. The game also comes with a knee pad that lets the game track your legs.There is no online multiplayer in the Wii version.PS3 VersionThe    PS3 version of UFC Personal Trainer is a mix of both the Wii and Xbox versions. You use the    Playstation Move wand to workout as well as the Knee pad. Like in the 360 version, you can challenge you friends online in score attack modes. RosterCoachesGreg JacksonMark DellaGrotteJavier MendezRachelle Leah Xbox 360 exclusive fighters   Dan Hardy   Frank Mir   Diego Sanchez   Kenny Florian</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre><genre id="44">Fitness</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="32388">Get Fit With Mel B</game><game id="34214">Fit in Six</game><game id="31743">Zumba Fitness</game><game id="30346">EA Sports Active 2.0</game><game id="36440">Billy's Bootcamp</game><game id="43834">Fighter Within</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2133358-box_ufct.png</image></root>