<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32696</id><name>The Ico &amp; Shadow of the Colossus Collection</name><description>OverviewOfficially announced at the  Tokyo Game Show 2010, The ICO and Shadow of the Colossus Collection is a  PlayStation 3-exclusive re-release of the classic  PlayStation 2 games  Ico and  Shadow of the Colossus. Both games are on one Blu-ray Disc, and feature full 1080p  HD remastering (including a smoother frame rate),  3DTV support, and  Trophies. Also, the box contains a  PlayStation Network voucher for a dynamic XMB-theme and video content from Ico, Shadow of the Colossus, and the upcoming  The Last Guardian (the video features are on the disc in the US version). The HD versions are based on the European release which means that, along with different artwork for Ico, Shadow of the Colossus has a different ending, and additional features not present in the original North American version on PS2.ReleaseThe collection was initially due to be out in Spring of 2011, but in April, Team Ico announced that the HD collection along with their current game, The Last Guardian, would be delayed. A Japanese trailer was released in the run up to  E3 2011 stating a Japanese release date of September 22nd 2011. In Japan, the games are released separately on disc, while also being made available in a "Limited Box" which also includes an art booklet and a code for downloadable content. Sony's US and European PlayStation blogs confirmed the game's final release date as September 27th and 30th, respectively.</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="32804">Prince of Persia Trilogy</game><game id="31788">The Sly Collection</game><game id="28001">God of War Collection</game><game id="33396">Splinter Cell Trilogy</game><game id="35534">Halo: Combat Evolved Anniversary</game><game id="37715">Ratchet &amp; Clank Collection</game><game id="36890">Jak &amp; Daxter Collection</game><game id="39248">God of War Saga</game><game id="28006">Okamiden</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3699/2336521-ico___shadow_of_the_colossus_collection___cropped.jpg</image></root>