<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32716</id><name>Tekken Tag Tournament 2</name><description>OverviewTekken Tag Tournament 2 is a 3D 2-on-2 tag-team fighting game developed and released by Namco Bandai for Japanese arcades in 2011. The eighth main installment of the Tekken franchise, Tekken Tag Tournament 2, is the successor to 1999's Tekken Tag Tournament, which pits most characters from the series' history (at that point in the series) in non-canonical 2-on-2 tag team battles.The original arcade game received a revision (titled Tekken Tag Tournament 2 Unlimited) on March 27, 2012, featuring the option to choose one character instead of two (in which the character is granted both higher vitality and the "Rage" system from Tekken 6) and a new Pair Play mode (in which four players fight simultaenously in 2-on-2 battle royales, similar to Scramble Mode in Street Fighter X Tekken). This version would later be used in the worldwide console release for Xbox 360 and PlayStation 3 on September 11, 2012. This release features new characters (both inclusive and DLC), character customization, an enhanced Practice Mode (in which players unlock new moves for a customizable training robot), and the option to use custom soundtracks. The Wii U received its own console version on November 18, 2012 with additional Nintendo-themed content, including costumes based on popular Nintendo franchises.GameplayTekken Tag Tournament 2 is a combination of Tekken 6's mechanics and the previous Tekken TAG's 2-on-2 system. This section will exclusively cover the game's tag mechanics.In TTT2, matches still consist of best-of-3 or best-of-5 sets. (Local matches default to best-of-3, while ranked online matches are best-of-5.) A round ends when one character is knocked out, regardless of the health of their partner.Tagging is accomplished with a fifth "tag" button. Inactive partners slowly recover any "red" health that they may have received from taking damage while active. Unlike most tag-based fighting games, red health is not lost whenever a character is tagged in normally.Rage is a comeback mechanic state that is enabled for the inactive character once the point character has received a certain amount of damage. When enough damage is taken, the partner's life-bar will flash, and tagging them in will allow them to deal more damage for a short while. The damage required to activate Rage is partially dependent on in-story character relationships: for example, Heihachi will receive Rage faster than normal if Kuma is the active character, but will receive it much later than normal if his partner is Jin or Kazuya. Solo characters receive Rage at 50% health, at near-death, and whenever hit with a Tag Assault.By pressing the Tag button while performing a launcher, the player will perform a Tag Combo. The player's inactive character runs in, and the resulting combo will eliminate part of the opponent's red health. Pressing Right Punch and Tag together performs a Tag Throw, which switches characters while eating the opponent's red health. Some pairings have special Tag Throws; their method of activation varies per team.By pressing Tag during a Bound move (or both Punch buttons and Tag to create a generic bound), the player will perform a Tag Assault. The partner will jump in, losing all of their red health in the process, and the player can perform one attack string before control is passed back to the original point character. However, Tag Assault doesn't eliminate red health, and will always give the opponent's partner Rage.The Tag Crash system gives players a way to tag in safely while under pressure. It requires the active character to be grounded and the inactive character to have Rage available. By pressing both Punch buttons and Tag simultaneously, the partner character will dive in from the air. Performing Tag Crash surrenders both Rage and the exiting partner's red health.Ranking SystemHow the Ranking System Works:All Players start at "Dan 1" RankTo get promoted you need 6 points to get demoted you need -6If you fight someone at your rank, you can win or lose 2 points to your current rank.If you fight someone +1 or -1 of your rank then you get or lose 1 point.If you fight someone 2 ranks above or below you, you only get or lose .5 points.If you fight anyone more than 2 ranks above or below, you only gain or lose .25 points.Full List of RanksBrownBeginner9th Kyu8th Kyu7th Kyu6th Kyu5th Kyu4th Kyu3rd Kyu2nd Kyu1st KyuSilver1st Dan2nd Dan3rd DanLight BlueDiscipleMentorMasterGrand MasterGreenBrawlerMarauderFighterBerserkerYellowWarriorAvengerDuelistPugilist - ( Current Online Ranking Cap)OrangeVanquisherDestroyerConquerorSaviorRedGenbuByakkoSeiryuSuzakuBlueFujinRaijinYaksaMajinToshinPurpleEmperorTekken LordTekken EmperorGoldTekken GodTrue Tekken GodCharactersLike the previous Tag Tournament, Tekken Tag Tournament 2 will feature an extensive roster of characters from the Tekken series fighting in a tournament that exists outside of the series canon storyline.Returning Tekken 6 charactersJin KazamaKazuya Mishima (Can transform into Devil Kazuya)Asuka KazamaLeo KliesenLili RochefortKingArmor KingMarshall LawPaul PhoenixFeng WeiMiguel Caballero RojoHwoarangBaek Doo SanSteve FoxLing XiaoyuCraig MardukJack-6ZafinaBruce IrvinBobGanryuDevil JinKumaPandaMokujinLei WulongWang JinreiRoger Jr.Bryan FuryEddie GordoNina WilliamsAnna WilliamsChristie MonteiroLing XiaoyuYoshimitsuSergei DragunovLars AlexanderssonAlisa BoskonovitchAltered Tekken 6 charactersHeihachi Mishima (younger appearance)Jaycee (Julia Chang disguised as a luchador)Pre-Tekken 6 charactersJun KazamaTrue OgreJinpachi Mishima (human form)The following are exclusive to the console version:Tiger JacksonAlexPrototype JackForrest LawPreorder DLC CharactersThose who preordered TTT2 were given early access to these characters. They were unlocked for all players on November 13, 2012.Michelle ChangAncient OgreKunimitsuAngelPost-Release DLC CharactersUnlocked on October 8/9, 2012:Sebastian (Lili's butler)Miharu Haruno (Xiaoyu's friend from Tekken 4)Slim Bob (Bob's skinny form from his Tekken 6 ending)Unlocked on November 13, 2012:Unknown (also final boss for all versions)Violet (Lee Chaolan's alter-ego from Tekken 4)Dr. BosconovitchAll DLC characters are provided free of charge, and were unlocked for PS3 and Xbox 360 players via title updates. The Wii U version automatically features every character except Unknown, who is unlocked upon clearing Arcade mode.Console Version InformationReturning Gameplay ModesTekken Tag Tournament 2 features many of the same gameplay modes as its predecessors: Arcade Battle, Time Attack, Ghost Battle, Team Battle, and Survival. Pair Play mode allows up to four players to participate, giving each player control over a single character.Fight LabFight Lab is a tutorial mode. The player trains a Combot by participating in various minigames; each of these minigames emphasize certain aspects of the main game. Combot's movelist consists of other characters' techniques and can be customized by the player.Tekken TunesTekken Tunes allows players to replace the normal in-game BGM with his or her personal music. Songs can be assigned to each individual stage.Preorder BonusesNamco Bandai offered a large number of incentives to those who preordered Tekken Tag Tournament 2, including early access to four characters.Those who preordered at GameStop received:Day-one access to four characters: Kunimitsu, Ancient Ogre, Michelle Chang and AngelDay-one access to the Snoop Dogg stage and Knocc ‘Em Down songSnoop Dogg Knocc ‘Em Down Mash TracksCollectable Girl Power posterExclusive Xbox 360 avatars or PlayStation 3 system themesBig Bikini Bundle – over 100 summer styles for the entire cast of charactersTekken Takes Tokyo DocumentaryArt gallery with 20 pieces of original artThose who preordered from other retailers received (items may vary by retailer):Day-one access to two characters: Michelle Chang and AngelDay-one access to the Snoop Dogg stage and Knocc ‘Em Down songSnoop Dogg Knocc ‘Em Down Mash TracksBig Bikini Bundle – over 100 summer styles for the entire cast of charactersWorld Tekken Federation (WTF)Launching alongside the game will be a brand new community site called WTF. It will be similar to the Halo Waypoint or Call of Duty Elite services in that it will have complex stat-tracking and allows players to form clans (called Teams in this game) to earn points together.PatchesAccording to Harada, on October 9 a patch was released to lower the waiting time in ranked matches along with changing the difficulty of the offline modes. DemoA demo version, Tekken Tag Tournament 2 Prologue, was included in Tekken Hybrid, a hybrid Blu-Ray that also includes the Tekken: Blood Vengeance CGI film and the previously unreleased Tekken Tag Tournament HD.</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="31236">Dragon Ball Z: Tenkaichi Tag Team</game><game id="28437">Super Street Fighter IV</game><game id="7792">Dead or Alive 4</game><game id="30944">Marvel vs. Capcom 3: Fate of Two Worlds</game><game id="36412">Dead or Alive 5</game><game id="30064">Virtua Fighter 5 Final Showdown</game><game id="35161">Soulcalibur V</game><game id="42599">Dead or Alive 5 Ultimate</game><game id="25042">Mortal Kombat</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2303999-box_ttt2.png</image></root>