<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32719</id><name>Dynasty Warriors 7</name><description>OverviewDynasty Warriors 7 is a PS3/ Xbox 360 entry in Koei's long-running Dynasty Warriors series. The game was released in North America on March 29, 2011 for both platforms. The game features over sixty playable characters from the Shu, Wei, and Wu kingdoms, as well as the new faction Jin. Although characters from other factions are included, they are not playable in the primary story mode. Both the PS3 and Xbox 360 versions of the game support stereoscopic 3D.StoryDynasty Warriors 7 features a completely revamped story mode. Similar to Dynasty Warriors 4, each kingdom has its own story. However, for this entry, the officer played in each mission is fixed in a manner similar to Warriors: Legends of Troy. The game also does away with the pre-battle planning screen and instead transitions seamlessly from cutscenes to control of the chapter's playable character, either in camp (where the player may make preparations such as equipping weapons or spending skill points) or directly into battle.For the first time in the series, the storyline does not end at the Battle of Wu Zhang Plains. The game instead tells the story of the Jin kingdom, which arose late in the Three Kingdoms era and eventually won out, uniting China and establishing the Jin Dynasty in 280 A.D. The vast majority of the Jin-aligned characters are all-new, with only Sima Yi (formerly a Wei character) returning from previous entries. The Jin storyline begins with stopping Gongsun Yuan's rebellion, and ends with the final stage being the subjugation of Shu and the surrender of Liu Shan.Conquest ModeConquest Mode is the second primary gameplay mode. In it, the player selects a character and advances across a map of China by completing missions. Scattered about the map are cities that the player may visit once freed, where weapons can be forged and purchased, visiting characters may be spoken with, and other special events may take place. Each character also has access to their own Historic Battle challenges ("Legend" stages), with some based on events of Romance of the Three Kingdoms, while others are original scenarios.GameplayThe combat gameplay is similar to the classic "Charge" attack system seen in titles predating Dynasty Warriors 6. This game also borrows the dual weapon system used in Dynasty Warriors: Strikeforce. Each character is capable of using two weapons. The player can freely equip different weapon types to each character, though characters equipped with a weapon they have poor affinity with are not as effective as they are with other weapons. Characters can also actively switch between their equipped weapons during battle and will perform a special attack during the transition.The musou gauge is split in up to two bars. This is similar to Samurai Warriors 3, allowing the player to do multiple musou attacks in a row. In addition to the standard and horse-mounted musou attack variants, some characters can unlock a second standard musou, and some can perform musou attacks in midair.A new addition to the gameplay is the use of siege weapons. In previous games, such weapons appeared strictly as either obstacles to destroy or targets to protect. However, in Dynasty Warriors 7, the player can take active control of siege weapons in select stages, including catapults, ballistas, and others. Use of such weapons is required to complete certain objectives, such as destroying gates or sinking ships.Playable CharactersKingdom of WeiCao CaoCao CaoFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty WarriorsEX Weapon: SwordVoice Actor: Douglas RyeLeader of Wei, known as the "Hero of Chaos."Cao PiCao PiFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 5EX Weapon: Dual SwordsVoice Actor: Doug ErholtzCao Cao's son and Zhen Ji's Husband, succeeds his father as the leader of Wei.Xiahou DunXiahou DunFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty WarriorsEX Weapon: SwordVoice Actor: Kirk ThorntonCao Cao's right hand general. Also his cousin.Xiahou YuanXiahou YuanFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 2EX Weapon: BowVoice Actor: Tony OliverExpert archer and prominent general of Wei. Cousin of Xiahou Dun.Cao RenCao RenFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 4EX Weapon: FlailVoice Actor: Beau BillingsleaSpecializes in defense and fights to end the turmoil. Cousin of Cao Cao.Zhen JiZhen JiFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 3EX Weapon: FluteVoice Actress: Wendee LeeOriginally the wife of one of Yuan Shao's sons, now married to Cao Pi.Xu HuangXu HuangFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 3EX Weapon: PikeVoice Actor:Devoted to the Warrior's Path, trains for strength.Cai WenjiCai WenjiFirst Playable Appearance: Multi Raid 2EX Weapon: HarpVoice Actress:Talented musician, saved by Cao Cao from a tribe.Zhang LiaoZhang LiaoFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 2EX Weapon: Dual HalberdsVoice Actor: Travis WillinghamGeneral under Lu Bu until his defeat at Xia Pi, hero of He Fei.Dian WeiDian WeiFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty WarriorsEX Weapon: AxeVoice Actor: Beau BillingsleaCao Cao's loyal bodyguard.Jia Xu (New Character)Jia XuFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 7EX Weapon: Chain and SickleVoice Actor: Vic MignongaStrategist that travels the land, defeats Cao Cao before joining Wei.Zhang HeZhang HeFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 3EX Weapon: ClawsVoice Actor: Yuri LowenthalDefected from Yuan Shao during the battle of Guan Du.Xu ZhuXu ZhuFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty WarriorsEX Weapon: ClubVoice Actor: Doug StoneStrong warrior who is a bodyguard of Cao Cao.Kingdom of ShuLiu BeiLiu BeiFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 2EX Weapon: Twin SwordsVoice Actor:Founder of Shu and sworn brother of Guan Yu and Zhang Fei. Fights for virtue and the people.Guan YuGuan YuFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty WarriorsEX Weapon: PikeVoice Actor: Dave B. MitchellKnown as the "God of War", and famous for his long beard. Sworn brother of Liu Bei and Zhang Fei.Zhang FeiZhang FeiFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty WarriorsEX Weapon: Double-ended bladeVoice Actor: Steve KramerStrong warrior who has bad drinking habits. Sworn brother of Liu Bei and Guan Yu.Zhuge LiangZhuge LiangFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty WarriorsEX Weapon: Feather FanVoice Actor: Lex LangLiu Bei's strategist. Known as arguably the greatest strategist of the era.Liu Shan (New Character)Liu ShanFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 7EX Weapon: RapierVoice Actor:Son of Liu Bei, known as an incompetent leader.Xing CaiXing CaiFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 5EX Weapon: Sword and ShieldVoice Actress: Wendee LeeDaughter of Zhang Fei, fights along side Guan Ping.Guan PingGuan PingFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 5EX Weapon: GreatswordVoice Actor: Bryce PappenbrookGuan Yu's adopted son. Strives to be like his father.Guan Suo (New Character)Guan SuoFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 7EX Weapon: NunchakuVoice Actor: Spike SpencerGuan Yu's fictional third son. His sincerity makes him popular with the people.Bao Sanniang (New Character)Bao SanniangFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 7EX Weapon: SpinnerVoice Actress:Character created for the game, no historical origin.Jiang WeiJiang WeiFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 2EX Weapon: SpearVoice Actor:Zhuge Liang's successor. Originally a member of Wei.Yue YingYue YingFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 4EX Weapon: Bo StaffVoice Actress:Zhuge Liang's wife. Invented Shu's Juggernaut.Zhao YunZhao YunFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty WarriorsEX Weapon: SpearVoice Actor: Terrence StoneOne of Shu's greatest warriors. Poster boy of the series.Ma Dai (New Character)Ma DaiFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 7EX Weapon: Magic BrushVoice Actor: Justin GiddingsMa Chao's cousin, best known for slaying Wei Yan.Wei YanWei YanFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 3EX Weapon: Double-ended BladeVoice Actor:Strong warrior but his loyalty was often questioned by Zhuge Liang.Pang TongPang TongFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 3EX Weapon: StaffVoice Actor:A talented strategist overshadowed by Zhuge Liang, known for his odd appearance.Ma ChaoMa ChaoFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 2EX Weapon: SpearVoice Actor: David BerónBelieves in fighting for justice. Vows to get revenge on Cao Cao for killing his father.Huang ZhongHuang ZhongFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 2EX Weapon: BowVoice Actor: Alan ShearmanLegendary archer, known for being a fearsome warrior despite his old age.Kingdom of WuSun JianSun JianFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 2EX Weapon: SwordVoice Actor:Known as the "Tiger of Jiang Dong" Triggers the events to form the Kingdom of Wu, but dies before it is realized.Sun CeSun CeFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 3EX Weapon: TonfasVoice Actor: Yuri LowenthalFounds the Kingdom of Wu, but like his father, dies early.Sun QuanSun QuanFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 2EX Weapon: SwordVoice Actor: Gideon EmerySecond son of Sun Jian, and most prominent leader of Wu.Sun Shang XiangSun Shang XiangFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty WarriorsEX Weapon: Wind-and-fire WheelsVoice Actor: GK BowesDaughter of Sun Jian and wife of Liu Bei.Zhou YuZhou YuFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty WarriorsEX Weapon: Bo StaffVoice Actor:Wu's early strategist. He is Sun Ce's childhood friend, and rivals with Zhuge Liang.Lu XunLu XunFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty WarriorsEX Weapon: Twin SwordsVoice Actor: Skip StellrechtLater era Wu strategist. Responsible for the defeat of Shu at Yi Ling.Lu MengLu MengFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 2EX Weapon: PikeVoice Actor: Tony OliverCommon soldier who studied and trained to become a great general and strategist.Taishi CiTaishi CiFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty WarriorsEX Weapon: Dual RodsVoice Actor: Darrel GuilbeauWas rivals with Sun Ce but joined Wu after being defeated.Da QiaoDa QiaoFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 3EX Weapon: Metal FanVoice Actor: Wendee LeeSun Ce's wife. The more thoughtful of the Two Qiaos.Xiao QiaoXiao QiaoFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 3EX Weapon: Metal FanVoice Actor: Carrie SavageZhou Yu's wife. The more impulsive of the Two Qiaos.Zhou TaiZhou TaiFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 4EX Weapon: Curved SwordVoice Actor: Travis WillinghamLoyal bodyguard to Sun Quan. He is usually calm and composed.Lian Shi (New Character)Lian ShiFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 7EX Weapon: CrossbowVoice Actor:Sun Quan's wife and the bodyguard of Sun Shang Xiang.Ding Feng (New Character)Ding FengFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 7EX Weapon: GauntletsVoice Actor: Kyle HebertKnown for his fearsome appearance. Served Wu for a long period of time.Ling TongLing TongFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 5EX Weapon: NunchakuVoice Actor: David LodgeFought with his father and driven after his death. Has a rivalry with Gan Ning.Huang GaiHuang GaiFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 3EX Weapon: ClubVoice Actor: Lee EverestEarly era Wu general, known for carrying out the fire attack at Chi Bi.Gan NingGan NingFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 2EX Weapon: Chain and SickleVoice Actor:One of Wu's strongest warriors, former pirate that joined Wu to be appreciated.Kingdom of JinSima YiSima YiFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 2EX Weapon: Feather FanVoice Actor: Kyle HebertBrilliant Wei strategist who eventually stages a takeover, setting the foundation for the Jin Kingdom.Sima Shi (New Character)Sima ShiFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 7EX Weapon: RapierVoice Actor:First son of Sima Yi. Has a perfectionist attitude, and comes off as cold to others.Sima Zhao (New Character)Sima ZhaoFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 7EX Weapon: SwordVoice Actor:Second son of Sima Yi. Seems to be aloof and uncaring, but is a talented general.Wang Yuanji (New Character)Wang YuanjiFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 7EX Weapon: Throwing DaggersVoice Actor: Tara PlattWife of Sima Zhao, also spends a lot of time keeping him focused.Zhuge Dan (New Character)Zhuge DanFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 7EX Weapon: Feather FanVoice Actor: Keith SilversteinCousin of Zhuge Liang who eventually rebelled against Jin.Guo Huai (New Character)Guo HuaiFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 7EX Weapon: Arm CannonVoice Actor:Wei general who is loyal to Sima Yi. Reformed the ranks after Xiahou Yuan's death in battle.Zhong Hui (New Character)Zhong HuiFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 7EX Weapon: Flying SwordsVoice Actor: Quinton FlynnTalented yet arrogant general for Wei who eventually rebels against Jin with Jiang Wei.Deng Ai (New Character)Deng AiFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 7EX Weapon: Drill SpearVoice Actor:General who uses the terrain to his advantage. Very prominent in the final battles against Shu.Xiahou Ba (New Character)Xiahou BaFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 7EX Weapon: GreatswordVoice Actor: Vic MignognaSon of Xiahou Yuan, he is loyal to Wei, but pressured when the Jin uprising occurs.Other Forces (Not affiliated with any of the main kingdoms)Lu BuLu BuFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty WarriorsEX Weapon: HalberdVoice Actor: Jamieson PriceKnown and often feared as the strongest warrior in the land. Also famous for his legendary horse Red Hare.Diao ChanDiao ChanFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty WarriorsEX Weapon: Chain WhipVoice Actor:Affiliated with Dong Zhuo before she convinces Lu Bu to rebel against him. The only person Lu Bu cares for.Yuan ShaoYuan ShaoFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 2EX Weapon: RapierVoice Actor: Dave WittenbergThe Grand Commander of the coalition against Dong Zhuo. Arrogant because of his noble upbringing.Dong ZhuoDong ZhuoFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 2EX Weapon: Ball and ChainVoice Actor: Richard EpcarUsurps the power from the Emperor. A tyrant who causes misery for the people.Meng HuoMeng HuoFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 3EX Weapon: GauntletsVoice Actor: Kirk ThorntonKing of the Nanmans, famous for his many battles with Zhuge Liang and Shu.Zhu RongZhu RongFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 3EX Weapon: Throwing DaggersVoice Actor: Jessica GeeMarried to Meng Huo, known for being related to the goddess of fire.Zhang JiaoZhang JiaoFirst Playable Appearance: Dynasty Warriors 2EX Weapon: StaffVoice Actor: Doug StoneLeader of the Yellow Turban cult and instigator of the rebellion against the Han.MerchandiseAs a pre-order bonus in Japan, people received one random pen from a set of four featuring character art. This was also a pre-order bonus in the UK through shops such as GAME.Pre-order bonus pensIn Japan there was a Treasure Box version of the game available, which contains special postcards (featuring each kingdom, plus Zhao Yun and Lu Bu have one each), an art book, and more.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26645">Trinity: Souls of Zill O'll</game><game id="36291">One Piece: Pirate Warriors</game><game id="37103">Sengoku Basara 3 Utage</game><game id="6513">Bladestorm: The Hundred Years' War</game><game id="38478">Sengoku Basara HD Collection</game><game id="37019">Dynasty Warriors Next</game><game id="37022">Warriors Orochi 3</game><game id="35700">Saint Seiya: Sanctuary Battle</game><game id="39884">Senran Kagura Shinovi Versus: Shōjo-tachi no Shōmei</game><game id="35965">Naruto Shippuden: Ultimate Ninja Impact</game><game id="40315">Hakuoki: Warriors of the Shinsengumi</game><game id="34360">Bleach Soul Resurrección</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1820018-box_dw7.png</image></root>