<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32728</id><name>Super Mega Worm</name><description>Earth is on the brink of destruction and Mother Nature has released the Super Mega Worm to destroy all of the humans and keep the Earth from dying. And you control the worm! The game takes on a retro 16-bit style in both its art direction and some of its music (the title track sounds somewhat like the Metroid title track.)  GameplayThe gameplay of Super Mega Worm is fairly simple at first but requires skill to be good at. The main idea is that you steer the worm around to gain momentum to blast out of the ground and eat/destroy object by coming in contact with them. To progress through each level you have to eat or destroy a certain number of objects that are indicated right below the health bar.  Combos  Combos are gained by eating or destroying multiple objects in one above ground jump. You can stay above ground by bouncing off of objects such as cars, tanks and helicopters. For every object you destroy you gain one multiplier.   Power Ups As you progress through levels you gain power-ups that will help you in your quest to kill everything.  Gas: By holding down this button you will go faster. This will greatly help you in blasting above ground to have a snack.Spit: When above ground the "Gas" button turns into a "Spit" button. Spitting shoots a ball of red energy fire stuff that destroys those you lie in its wake.EMP: This ability causes everything within its blast radius to blast away in addition to time slowing down. This allows you to aim with the spit ability much better and can help to add a little more precision to your movement. SpecsPrice - € 0,79 - $ 0,99 Last Update - Sep 14th iTunes Link -  http://itunes.apple.com/app/super-mega-worm/id388541990?mt=8</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14564">Death Worm</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1169/1528643-iphone_screenshot_1.jpeg</image></root>