<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32839</id><name>Dynasty Warriors: Gundam 3</name><description>OverviewDynasty Warriors: Gundam 3 is the third Gundam-themed offshoot of Koei's Musou franchise. The game features characters and mobile suits from throughout the numerous Gundam universes in a crossover storyline.Story ModePrevious modes such as Free mode and Official mode have been replaced by Story mode. Story mode allows the player to choose different missions based on a gundam character's story line. There are several different types of missions the player can choose in story mode.Story ChapterMissions relating to the story of the pilot chosen.RelationshipA series of missions that allows the player to build relationships/friendships with other Gundam pilots.FriendshipMissions where a variety of pilots will appear as your ally.HistoryMissions that reenact events from the Original Gundam series.CollectionMissions where a variety of pilots will appear as your enemy. New Gundam plans can be obtained by playing these missions.ChallengeDifficult missions that tests the player's skill.TutorialSeries of tutorial missions for new players to get familiar with the game.MemorialMissions that commemorate the player's accomplishments. Different rewards can be obtained by playing these missions.SpecialMissions where upon completion awards the player with vast sums of money.Playable Mobile suitsMobile Suit GundamRX-78-2 Gundam ( Amuro Ray)MS-06S Zaku II Commander Type ( Char Aznable)SD-06F Zaku II (Crown)MS-14S Gelgoog Commander Type ( Char Aznable)MS-15 GelgoogMSN-02 Zeong ( Char Aznable)YMS-15 Gyan (M'Quve)RX-77-2 Guncannon ( Kai Shiden, Hayato Kobayashi)MS-07B Gouf ( Ramba Ral)MS-09 Dom/MS-09R Rick-Dom (Black Tri Stars)RB-79 BallMSM-07 Z'GokMSM-07S Z'Gok Commander Type ( Char Aznable)RGM-79 GMMSM-04 Acguy *Mobile Suit VariationsMS-06V Zaku TankMS-07H Gouf Flight TypeMobile Suit Gundam 0080: War in the PocketRGM-79G GM CommandMobile Suit Gundam 0083: Stardust MemoryRX-78GP01-Fb Gundam Full Vernian "Zephyranthes" (Kou Uraki) *RX-78GP02A Gundam "Physalis" (Anavel Gato) *Mobile Suit Zeta GundamMSZ-006 Zeta Gundam (Kamille Bidan, Judau Ashta, Roux Louka)MSN-00100 Hyaku Shiki (Quattro Bajeena, Beecha Oleg)RX-178 Gundam Mark II (AEUG Colors) (Kamille Bidan, Emma Sheen, Elle Viano)RX-178 Gundam Mark II (Titans Colors) (Jerid Messa, Kacrikan Cacooler, Kamille Bidan, Emma Sheen)RX-160 Byalant (Jerid Messa)PMX-003 The O (Paptimus Scirocco)AMX-004 Qubeley (Haman Karn)RX-139 Hambrabi (Yazan Gable, Ramsus Hasr, Dunkel Cooper)PMX-001 Palace Athene (Reccoa Londe)NRX-055 Baund Doc (Rosamia Badam, Jerid Messa)RMS-099 Rick Dias (Apolly Bay, Emma Sheen, Amuro Ray, Quattro Bajeena, Roberto)RMS-179/RGM-79R GM IIMSA-03 NemoRMS-106 Hi-Zack (Jerid Messa, Kacrikan Cacooler)RMS-108 Marasai (Jerid Messa, Kakrikan Cacooler)RMS-154 BarzamAMX-103 Gaza C (Haman Karn)Mobile Suit Gundam ZZMSZ-010 ZZ Gundam (Judau Ashta)AMX-004-2 Qubeley Mark II (Black) (Elpeo Puru)AMX-004-3 Qubeley Mark II (Red) (Puru Two)AMX-107 Bawoo (Glemy Toto)AMX-004G Mass Production QubeleyAMX-106 Gaza D (Glemy Toto)Mobile Suit Gundam: Char's CounterattackRX-93 Nu Gundam (Amuro Ray)MSN-04 Sazabi (Char Aznable)RGM-89 JeganAMS-119 Geara DogaMobile Suit Gundam UnicornRX-0 Gundam Unicorn (Unicorn Mode) (Banagher Links) *RX-0 Gundam Unicorn (Destroy Mode) (Banagher Links) *MSN-06S Sinanju (Full Frontal)*NZ-666 Kshatriya (Marida Cruz) (DLC) *Mobile Suit Gundam F91F91 Gundam Formula 91 (Seabook Arno, Cecily Fairchild)Mobile Suit Victory GundamLM314V21 Victory 2 Gundam (Üso Ewin)ZMT-S33S Gottrlatan (Katejina Loos)ZM-S24G Gedlav *Mobile Fighter G GundamGF13-017NJII God Gundam (Domon Kasshu, Schwartz Bruder)GF13-001NHII Master Gundam (Master Asia)Death Army *Mobile Suit Gundam WingXXXG-00W0 Wing Gundam Zero (Heero Yuy, Milliardo Peacecraft,Duo Maxwell,Trowa Barton)OZ-13MS Gundam Epyon (Milliardo Peacecraft, Heero Yuy)XXXG-01D2 Gundam Deathscythe Hell (Duo Maxwell) *XXXG-01H2 Gundam Heavyarms Kai (Trowa Barton) *OZ-00MS2 Tallgeese II (Treize Khushrenada) *After War Gundam XGX-9901-DX Gundam Double X (Garrod Ran) *Turn A GundamSYSTEM ∀-99 ∀ Gundam (Loran Cehack)CONCEPT-X 6-1-2 Turn X (Gym Ghingham)AMX-109 Kapool (Sochie Heim) *Mobile Suit Gundam SEEDZGMF-1017 GINN *Mobile Suit Gundam SEED DestinyZGMF-X42S Destiny Gundam (Shinn Asuka, Lunamaria Hawke)ZGMF-X20A Strike Freedom Gundam (Kira Yamato)ZGMF-X19A Infinite Justice Gundam (Athrun Zala, Lacus Clyne)Mobile Suit Gundam 00GN-0000+GNR-010 00 Raiser (Setsuna F. Seiei) *CB-0000G/C Reborns Gundam (Ribbons Almark) *GNX-Y901TW Susanowo (Graham Aker) (DLC) *GN-006 Cherudim Gundam (Lockon Stratos) (DLC) *GN-007 Arios Gundam (Allelujah Haptism) (DLC) *GN-008 Seravee Gundam (Tieria Erde) (DLC) *SD SengokudenMusha GundamMusha Gundam MK. IISD Gundam Gaiden Sieg Zion HenKnight Gundam *(" * " denotes Mobile Suits that have not been playable previously in the series.)</description><genres><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="36291">One Piece: Pirate Warriors</game><game id="37103">Sengoku Basara 3 Utage</game><game id="6513">Bladestorm: The Hundred Years' War</game><game id="38478">Sengoku Basara HD Collection</game><game id="37019">Dynasty Warriors Next</game><game id="37022">Warriors Orochi 3</game><game id="35700">Saint Seiya: Sanctuary Battle</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2126443-box_dwg3.png</image></root>