<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32889</id><name>Cut the Rope</name><description>OverviewCut the Rope is an iPhone game developed by ZeptoLab and published by Chillingo. The goal of Cut the Rope is to get a piece of candy into your pet monster's mouth by cutting ropes. The game introduces more gameplay elements as the levels progress including bubbles, blowers and obstacles such as spikes and spiders. There are also three stars to collect in each puzzle which add to the difficulty. These stars are needed to unlock each of the other stages in the game.StagesThere are 25 different puzzles in each stage (or box). Each puzzle has 3 stars to collect, meaning that there are a possible 75 total stars in each box. The developers have promised more puzzles in the future, but the boxes that are currently found in Cut the Rope are as follows:Cardboard BoxFabric BoxFoil BoxGift BoxCosmic Box (250 stars needed to unlock)Valentines BoxMagic BoxToy BoxReceptionCut the Rope was met with critical acclaim and universal praise for it's simplicity and value. Gameblog noted that, "Cut the Rope is the perfect iPhone game. Smart, easy to pick up and play in short sessions, and blessed with sublime level design and brilliant physics based gameplay mechanics". Similarly, AppSpy raved over the game, "Cut the Rope is quite simply a bombshell of cute, clever, addictive physics puzzle gameplay that's hard to pass up on". Cut the Rope currently averages 5 stars on the iTunes App store and a 93% on Metacritic.AchievementsBronze Scissors - Collected 50 starsSilver Scissors - Collect 150 starsGolden Scissors - Collect 300 starsRope Cutter - Cut 100 ropesRope Cutter Maniac - Cut 800 ropesUltimate Rope Cutter - Cut 2000 ropesQuick Finger - Cut 3 ropes at onceMaster Finger - Cut 5 ropes at onceBubble Popper - Pop 50 bubblesBubble Master - Pop 300 bubblesSpider Buster - Outsmart 40 spidersSpider Tamer - Outsmart 200 spidersWeight Loser - Lose candy 50 timesCalorie Minimizer - Lose candy 200 timesTummy Teaser - Om Nom has opened his mouth 10 times in a rowRomantic Soul - Reunite 100 candiesMagician - Dropped candy into magic hats 200 timesCardboard Box Completed - Complete the Carboard BoxCardboard Box Perfect - Three stars in all levels of the Cardboard BoxFabric Box Completed - Complete the Fabric BoxFabric Box Perfect - Three stars in all levels of the Fabric BoxFoil Box Completed - Complete the Foil BoxFoil Box Perfect - Three stars in all levels of the Foil BoxGift Box Completed - Complete the Gift BoxGift Box Perfect - Three stars in all levels of the Gift BoxCosmic Box Completed - Complete the Cosmic BoxCosmic Box Perfect - Three stars in all levels of the Cosmic BoxValentine Box Completed - Complete the Valentine BoxValentine Box Perfect - Three stars in all levels of the Valentine BoxMagic Box Completed - Complete the Magic BoxMagic Box Perfect - Three stars in all levels of the Magic BoxToy Box Completed - Complete the Toy BoxToy Box Perfect - Three stars in all levels of the Toy Box</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="35769">Feed Me Oil</game><game id="35657">Rotastic</game><game id="36711">Where's My Water?</game><game id="38470">ichi</game><game id="26938">Obulis</game><game id="41493">Feed Garfield</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2163510-box_ctr.png</image></root>