<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32945</id><name>Super Crate Box</name><description>OverviewSuper Crate Box is an arcade style, single player shoot 'em 'up indie game, in which the objective is to collect crates for a high score while fighting off hordes of enemies. With further progression through the game and higher scores the player can unlock new player skins, more modes of play, and more experimental weapons.GameplayA game of Super Crate Box starts with the player in the middle of the level with a basic pistol and a single crate spawning at a random location. Almost immediately enemies will begin to fall from a hole at the top of the level, ranging from small green skulls, large green skulls, and flying white skulls, in varying patterns of waves.The objective is to collect the crates, which contain random and more powerful weapons, without colliding with an enemy, which instantly kills the player. To further complicate this task, a pit is placed at the bottom of the level which kills the player if they fall in, but upgrades enemies to a much quicker,dangerous state if they progress to the pit. They will then respawn at the top of the screen to repeat the path to the bottom, while new enemies continue to spawn. In order to maintain a high score the player must balance out the tasks of collecting crates with using the weapons found in the crates to keep enemy numbers to a minimum.Gameplay ModesNormal - The enemies spawn at the top of the stage at an average spawn rate.SFMT - The enemies spawn at the top of the stage at a quicker spawn rate.Ambush - The enemies spawn in random locations at an average spawn rate.WeaponsAfter subsequent playthroughs, the player will unlock certain milestones based off of high scores as well as total crates accumulated of the course of play time. These milestones will make available new weapons, characters, and unlock new levels and difficulties. Being as such, while the player's options are somewhat limited during their first few playthroughs, they can use unlocked weapons from prior games to improve their scores in further play.Weapons include:Weapon NameUnlock ConditionsDescriptionPistolNoneYou always start out with one, fires a single bulletDual PistolsNoneShoots bullets both waysShotgunNoneWide area damage, close range, takes a while to reloadBazookaNoneFires missile with exploding AOE damageMachine GunNoneFires bullets continuously, has small recoil that can push player off platform eventuallyRevolver10 CratesFires quick large bullets with a large amount of damageFlamethrower30 CratesCreates fire that will harm enemies while they walk in it, makes player jump if walked inDisc Gun60 CratesShoots out circular discs that can rebound once and possibly kill the player (The only weapon that can directly kill the player).Mines100 CratesPlant for exploding AOE damage upon contact with an enemyMinigun150 CratesFires bullets very quickly with a large spread but has massive recoilKatana210 CratesShort range melee weaponGrenade Launcher280 CratesFires grenades at an angle that have exploding AOE damageLaser Rifle360 CratesCharges a beam that can fire across the whole stage, the charge can also act as a melee weaponStatsOverall statistics the game keeps track of include:Crates GottenOverall killsOverall DeathsMinutes PlayedMore specific statistics include:Highest score for each stage on each modeNumber of times you've killed each enemyNumber of times you've died to each enemyNumber of times you've fallen into the fire pitNumber of times you've been killed by a disc from the disc gunAn iPhone and iPad version has also been announced, and was scheduled to be released in September, 2011. But was eventually released on January 5, 2012.Super Crate Box can be downloaded for free for PC and Mac on the game's websitealongside an online leaderboard and a download link for the game's quirky chiptune soundtrack. Download it hereThe game was also nominated for an IGF award in the Excellence in Design category, but lost to Desktop Dungeons.System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows XPProcessor: 1.2 GhzMemory: 512 MB RAMDirectX®: 8.0Hard Drive: 100 MB HD spaceRecommendedOS: Windows XP, Vista or 7Processor: 2.2 GhzMemory: 512 MB RAMDirectX®: 8.0Hard Drive: 100 MB HD space</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19726">Mario Bros.</game><game id="4995">Bubble Bobble</game><game id="35899">The Binding of Isaac</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2340740-custom.png</image></root>