<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32943</id><name>Angry Birds Seasons</name><description>OverviewAngry Birds Seasons features various holiday themed level packs for players to reap their revenge on the green pigs by firing their Angry Birds at the green pigs' castles.In each pack, a bonus level is unlocked if the player attains a 3 star rating in every level. Each level pack contains at least one secret golden egg that unlocks another bonus level.Level Packs2011 SeasonsTrick or Treat- 45 levels- Released November 2010 for HalloweenSeason's Greetings- 25 levels- Like a Christmas advent calendar, a level was unlocked each day from December 1st to December 25th 2010.Hogs and Kisses- 18 levels- Released February 2011 for Valentines DayGo Green, Get Lucky- 18 levels- Released March 10th 2011 for St. Patricks DayEaster Eggs- 18 levels- Released April 2011 for EasterSummer Picnic- 30 levels- Released June 2011 for summerMoon Festival- 33 levels- Released September 2011 for the Mid-Autumn Festival2012 SeasonsHam'o'ween- 30 levels- Released October 2011 for Halloween- Features explosive pumpkin lanternsWreck the Halls- 25 levels- One level unlocked every day from December 1st to December 25th 2011 for ChristmasYear of the Dragon- 15 levels- Released January 2012 for Chinese New Year- A free version of the Mighty Eagle, the Mighty Dragon is usable in this level setCherry Blossom- 15 levels- Released March 2012 for SpringPiglantis- 30 levels- Released June 2012- Includes levels with water physicsAvailabilityThe game can be downloaded via the iTunes for the iPhone. An 'HD' version for the iPad is also available. Both of these versions support Game Center.A free ad supported Android version has also been released.It is available for WebOS phones in the Palm App Catalog.on 2/20/13 the game was released for Windows Phones.</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="29901">Crush the Castle</game><game id="32994">Silly Bandz</game><game id="33470">Pandas vs Ninjas</game><game id="33909">Trucks and Skulls</game><game id="37033">Amazing Breaker</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2444487-1504002389-mzl.d.png</image></root>