<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33002</id><name>Sniper: Ghost Warrior 2</name><description>OverviewSniper: Ghost Warrior 2 is a first-person shooter that is built on CryEngine 3. The player assumes the role of Captain Cole Anderson who is tasked with resolving a bio-weapon threat. The game is split into 3 acts, each of which takes place at a different time and location.Act 1 takes place 6 days before 'present day' and has the player tracking down a bio-weapon in the jungles of Burma. Anderson is partnered up with Diaz who acts as his 'spotter'. He will call out targets in a specific order for the player to shoot.Act 2 takes place in 1993 in Sarajevo, Bosnia. The player is partnered up with Carl Maddox to meet up with a contact and take photographic evidence of genocide taking place for NATO.Act 3 is in 'present day' and the player is reunited with Diaz in Tibet. The pair have to stop Merinov and the bio-weapon threat.Game play is primarily stealth based as getting into open combat with enemies usually leads to the player's demise very quickly.Bullets in the game are affected by distance, gravity and wind speed and direction. As a result on easy and normal difficulties the game has a red circle appear in the scope that indicates where the bullet will hit.In addition to sniping the player can also sneak up on unsuspecting enemies and do a quick instant melee kill with a knife. The player also carries a silenced pistol for close quarters dispatching of enemies. It is not effective when you need to deal with more than one enemy at a time. MissionsAct ICommunication BreakdownOut from NowhereLeave No Man BehindAct IIOperation ArchangelAnd Justice for AllGhosts of SarajevoAct IIIKnife in the DarkBurning BridgesBad KarmaNo Loose EndsWeaponsHandgunsSIG-Sauer P220M1911 VariantIMI / Magnum Desert Eagle Mark VIIAssault RiflesHeckler  Koch XM8INSAS Assault RifleIMI Tavor TAR-21Sniper RiflesRemington MSRRemington M24 Sniper Weapon SystemCheyenne Tactical M-200 InterventionBarrett XM500Knights Armament Company SR-25SVD DragunovMk 14 Mod 0 Enhanced Battle RifleAccuracy International Arctic Warfare 50DSR-Precision DSR-1VSS VintorezMachine GunsRheinmetall MG3System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows XP, Vista or Windows 7, with the latest Service PackProcessor: Intel Core 2 Duo at 2Ghz, or AMD Athlon 64 x2 2Ghz, or betterMemory: 2GBHard Disk Space: 9GbVideo Card:NVidia 8800GT with 512Mb RAM or betterDirectX®: 9.0cSound: DirectX Compatible Sound CardSoundtrackThe game has soundtrack which all composed by Michal Cielecki with 15 tracks and released on March 12, 2013 as a digital downloadTrack No.TitleDuration1.Main Theme3:292.Bad Karma2:063.No Way Around3:484.Right Behind You3:175.Pursue and Neutralize1:266.Only Four Bullets In This Piece3:547.This Ain't Sarajevo4:368.Move Up0:449.Return Fire2:4710.I've Had It With Caves a While3:0611.Razor Three Two3:1312.Clock Is Ticking1:0613.Be Ready To Act3:4014.The Bullet2:1015.Deadly Precision3:02</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="30566">Sniper: Ghost Warrior</game><game id="17853">Sniper Elite</game><game id="34715">Sniper Elite V2</game><game id="41928">Sniper Elite 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2391159-box_snipergw2.png</image></root>