<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33013</id><name>Sexy Adventures on Porn Island</name><description>OverviewSexy Adventures on Porn Island is a video game by Grimmstone. The player takes the role of a castaway washed ashore onto Porn Island, where they quickly become a director in the local adult film industry. The player can film various adult films located in sets around the island. Each film is played through as a falling-block puzzle game, where the actors fall from the top of the screen in Tetris-like poses. Completing films unlocks more complex and interesting actor shapes as well as clothing, backdrops, hair, and skin options for the Photo Shoot, a sandbox mode where the player can dress and pose up to five actors. GameplayA scene from "Pirates of the Spanish Main".     The goal of the game is to score points by positioning the actors in such a way that they connect with one another. Building up larger groups of actors will score more points than many smaller ones. As the player earns points, the scene progresses. At certain points in each scene, conversations will begin between the actors, or the actors present in the scene will change. In this way the 'story' of each film will unfold. Once the entire scene has been filmed the next scene begins.  The game is lost when an actor is placed above the top of the board. To avoid this, connected pieces must be placed above all of the cameras at the bottom of the screen; the actors on the board then scroll down until one or more of the cameras is unobstructed again, giving the player more space to arrange pieces.  Some actors will have a star present on some part of their body. If the player manages to connect that body part to another actor, they will earn more points for the connection and also increase their score multiplier. The score multiplier is halved whenever an unconnected star drops off the bottom of the board.  Several scenes introduce other elements, such as cannons firing at the board, waves of random pieces filling up the board, or cameras filming horizontally as well as vertically. Content The bulk of the content for the game is provided through paid content packs. Each content pack has a specific theme, and contains three movies and many items of clothing, custom skins, props and backdrops.  There are currently three content packs available:   Uptown AnticsSuburban and apartment-living theme, featuring the movies: A challenging scene in "Dear Maddy," Sins in the Suburbs. A parody of  Desperate Housewives. The film follows the saucy acts of the residents of Mysteria Lane.Dear Maddy,. A parody of  Sex and the City. Madeline Moore, a sex-advice columnist for the New Apple Star, is exchanging sex stories with her friends.I Wish... At the bridal shower before Sophie's wedding, she and her friends swap their fantasies.  Space Sirens from Planet X Space and science-fiction theme, featuring the movies:  The "boss battle" in Sauce Wars. Sexy Trek: A Tale of Two Queens. A parody of the original series of  Star Trek. Captain Dirk and the crew of the USS Enterthise beams down to the planet of Zebulon, getting into trouble when the Zebulonian princess seduces the officers.Sauce Wars IV : The First Poke. A parody of  Star Wars: A New Hope. Poke Starrider is taught the way of the Sauce by Big-Waan Lussto and thwarts the plans of villianous Girth Evil.Space Rangers vs. The V.E.N.U.S. Engine. A 60s retro-future space adventure, in which the Space Rangers (Allix, Tish and Eve) race to the ends of the galaxy to defeat sex-obsessed androids - before they can steal all of humanity's men for themselves.   The Treasure of Booty Isle Pirate theme, featuring the movies: Pirates of the Spanish Main. A parody of  Pirates of the Caribbean. When his love is abducted by a crew of cursed pirates, William Cavendish, the son of the Port Royal governor, enlists the aid of the notorious 'Black' Jack James to track her down.Pleasure Island. A parody of the classic  Treasure Island. Jim Porkins battles with Long-Johnson Silver for the hidden treasure of Pleasure Island.The Secret of Spunky Island. A parody of the videogame,  The Secret of Monkey Island. Shortplank Hardwood journeys to Scrumm Island to complete the Three Trials and become a pirate, and ends up facing the dread ghost pirate LeBonq. Photo Shoot In addition to the game, players can enter the photo shoot where they can pose up to five large-scale actors against any of the backdrops. Each actor can be customised and dressed with outfits and hair that they have unlocked by playing through movies. The actors can be posed by dragging their wrists, hands, ankles, feet, etc.   Soundtrack Sexy Adventures on Porn Island features three tracks licensed from  Pornosonic: Dirk Dagger's ThemeSpiderpussyLaying Pipe</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/11/115909/1565910-logo.png</image></root>