<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33019</id><name>Bejeweled 3</name><description>OverviewThe new Bejeweled returns with 8 game modes such as Classic, Puzzle, Lightning, Poker and the endlessly relaxing Zen mode. The new Quest mode boasts 40 new levels which feature unique mechanics. Zen mode allows users to alter their own experiences, changing the background sounds, images and "binaural beats" to create a unique retreat. Lightning mode brings an element of Bejeweled Blitz to the new release with the time based trials that made the Facebook game so popular. The game also contains 65 in game achievements and a progressive leveling system, including high score boards.Game ModesClassicThe original match-three gameplay that Bejeweled is famous for.ZenAn endless session that focuses on the player's relaxation, with subliminal encouraging messages and binaural beats to soothe the player (a safety warning appears when this option is turned on).LightningSimilar to the popular Bejeweled Blitz, Lightning mode gives the player one minute to achieve a high score. Time can be added by matching time gems, which are added after the original minute expires.QuestQuest mode contains 40 different mini-games, each with a unique premise. You unlock the mini-games in sets by completing the previous set's mini-games.PokerA mode that focuses less on speed and more on making the perfect match. Players are given 5 cards, and each match puts the gem matched onto one of the cards. The goal is to make a Flush, 4 of a Kind, Full House, 3 of a Kind, 2 Pair, Spectrum (one of each gem color/type) or pair match from the five cards. Skulls show up periodically, where the player has to make a hand above the skull hand to continue playing. If the player doesn't succeed, a coin is flipped determining whether the game is over (similar to Peggle's no-pegs hit coin flip).ButterfliesButterflies appear on the board as different colors. The goal of this mode is to match the butterflies with gems to make them fly away, without letting any butterflies be eaten by the spiders waiting for them at the top of the board. Each time you make a match, every butterfly on the board moves up one spot. If a butterfly reaches the top, they are eaten by a spider, and the game is over.Ice StormColumns of ice rise from the bottom of the board. To make these ice columns disappear, you must match gems in the same grid as the ice column you want to get rid of. When the ice columns hit the top of the board, you only have a few seconds to get rid of them before they crack and the game ends.Diamond MineThe bottom of the board is filled with gold and treasure. The goal of this mode is to dig as deep as you can by matching gems at the bottom of the board.System RequirementsPCMinimum RequirementsOS: Windows XP SP2 / Vista / 7Processor: 1.2 GHzRAM Memory: 1 GBGraphics Card: 128 MB of video memoryDirectX®: 9.0c or higherHard Drive: 320 MB of free hard drive spaceSound Card: DirectX 9.0c or higher soundDirectX: 9.0cRecommended RequirementsOS: Windows XP SP2 / Vista / 7Processor: Pentium 3.2 GHz or Athlon 64 3200RAM Memory: 1 GBGraphics Card: 256 MB; Nvidia GeForce GT120 or ATI Radeon X700 series or betterHard Drive: 1 GB of free hard drive spaceSound Card: DirectX 9.0c or higher soundDirectX: 9.0cMacMinimum RequirementsOS: Mac OS X 10.5 - 10.6.xProcessor: Intel Core Duo 1.66 GHz or betterRAM Memory: 1 GBGraphics Card: 128 MB of video memoryHard Drive: 320 MB of free hard drive spaceRecommended RequirementsOS: Mac OS X 10.5 - 10.6xProcessor: Intel Core Duo 1.66 GHz or betterRAM Memory: 1 GBGraphics Card: 256 MB of video memoryHard Drive: 1 GB of free hard drive space</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="29289">Puzzle Quest 2</game><game id="20567">Puzzle Quest: Galactrix</game><game id="27207">Chains</game><game id="13308">Luxor</game><game id="12020">Luxor 2</game><game id="21177">Neopets Puzzle Adventure</game><game id="17012">Zuma</game><game id="27504">RockinRoll</game><game id="24746">Bang Attack</game><game id="7395">Pokémon Trozei!</game><game id="19154">Pokémon Pinball</game><game id="37962">Treasures of Montezuma Blitz</game><game id="38477">Jewel Keepers: Easter Island</game><game id="39741">Diamond Twister</game><game id="44444">Knack's Quest</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2011572-box_bj3.png</image></root>