<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33086</id><name>Reflec Beat</name><description> Songlist Default songs *Cover* -  Juunen SakuraSakanaction - Aruku AroundVenus - Choo Choo Train (Venus Mix)M-Flo - Come Again*Cover* - Go OnGirl Next Door - Guuzen No KakuritsuMeg - HeartAAA - Heart And SoulHalf Life - J-Pop*Cover* - JoyfulCapsule - JumperGTS feat. Baby M - Last ChanceFripSide - Level 5 (Judgelight)9mm Parabellum Bullet - Living Dying MessageYuki Kimura - Love  JoyAi Otsuka - Lucky StarFuyumi Sakamoto - Mata Kimi Ni Koi ShiteruMai Ooshima - Mendo Kusai Aijou Dede Mouse - My Favorite SwingDaft Punk - One More TimeGirl Next Door - Ready To Be A LadyKotoko - Shichiten Hakki Shijou Shugi!Aprils - Shine x Shine x ShineMay J. - Shiny Sky*Cover* - SolaninAcid Black Cherry - Spell MagicMinmi - Summertime!!Moumon - Sunshine GirlAya Hirano - Super DriverCali*Gari - TouThe Black Horn - WanaMeajyu - Your Supporter  Unlockable songs Qrispy Joybox - Colorful MinutesTag - Diamond DustTag rejected by DJ Yoshitaka - Diamond Dust (Try To Sing Ver.)Kors K - Gymnopedie (Kors K Mix)Girl Next Door - InfinityKors K Lovers DJ Yoshitaka - JuicyTatsuki Boyz - Kushikosu Post Seishun Ska Punk Mix!Zektbach - L'erisia (Primal Logic)DJ Taka feat. Flare - MessageAsaki - Niji No Saki Ni Nani Ga Aru KaRyu* - Sakura ReflectionCultvoice by S.S.D. Products - Shoujou Shoukei Saimiyouroku ~Kage~Yukky feat. Rio Kuniyoshi - SpangleDJ Yoshitaka - Stay My SideTatsh feat. Runa - Toumei Na EmotionKors K - Wuv UKanako Hoshino - Yume No Furu MachiPon - Yuusei OverdoseEeL - 777Creative Life - Non-Fiction Story!Koushoku Litmus - Rin Toshite Saku Hana No GotokuTerra - Secret OathNekomata Master - Sayonara HeavenKors K - SigSigNekomata Master - SilenceKors K - SmoooochPink Turbo - Starmine (Swallowtail Mix)Sota Fujimori feat. Kemy - We Can Change</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="38348">Reflec Beat Limelight</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2424/1623840-img_h2r0vz.png</image></root>