<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33149</id><name>Risen 2: Dark Waters</name><description>OverviewRisen 2: Dark Waters is a pirate-themed sequel to the 2009 CRPG Risen. Just like Risen and the Gothic series, it focuses on exploration and freedom of choice. It uses an enhanced Risen engine with licensed components (SpeedTree, PhysX, etc.) Risen 2 is Piranha Byte's most expensive project to date.StoryThe nameless protagonist has become a drunkard, plagued by the memories of the events that occured in Risen. He lives in the last refuge of Inquisition, Caldera. But a new threat rises; monsters, risen from the depths of the sea, attack and sink many ships, endangering the island's supply situation. The man is ordered to investigate one of the wrecked ships. During the investigation he meets Patty, a character from the preceding game. They discover that captain Steelbeard, Patty's father, has found a way to sail the seas without getting harmed by monster attacks. They team up to find the captain and his secret.GameplayRisen 2's gameplay core is similar to Risen and the Gothic series, however, there are some changes and additions. The most notable is the replacement of bows and crossbows with guns and rifles. Risen 2's world consists of several islands, and it has been said that they have the size of Faranga, the Island where the events of Risen took place.You can sail between the islands by ship, and you can also hire companions for it.Some facts regarding Risen 2's gameplay:Inventory screenYou can craft weapons, but not armor.The armor is made of individual sets of boots, gloves, hats, upper and lower clothing etc.There will be 5 categories of skills: melee, archery, cunning, hardness and magic.When you loot your enemies, an inventory screen won't appear unlike in the first game.Dirty tricks are the new addition to the game (part of the Cunning skill). For example, you can kick your enemy, throw sand to his eyes, or distract him with a parrot.Staves, shields and swimming will NOT be available in the game.System RequirementsMinimumRecommendedOS: Windows XP (with Servicepack 2)Processor: Dual core with 2.1 GHzRAM: 2GB system RAMGraphics card: AMD Radeon 3870 or NVidia GeForce 8800 GTX (512MB VRAM)Sound Card: DirectX-compatible sound chipDirectX: Version 9.1cHard Drive: 5.5GBInternet connection for online activation required.OS: Windows Windows XP (with Servicepack 2), Vista (with Servicepack 1) or Windows 7Processor: Dual core with 3GHzRAM: 4GB system RAMGraphics card: AMD Radeon 4890 or NVidia GeForce GTX 260 (1GB VRAM)Sound Card: DirectX-compatible sound chipDirectX: Version 9.1cHard Drive: 5.5GBInternet connection for online activation required.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="28178">The Witcher 2: Assassins of Kings</game><game id="14759">Two Worlds</game><game id="27218">Two Worlds II</game><game id="33394">The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim</game><game id="17367">The Elder Scrolls III: Morrowind</game><game id="20238">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion</game><game id="10473">The Witcher</game><game id="1982">Gothic</game><game id="1804">Gothic II</game><game id="7753">Gothic 3</game><game id="35702">Raven's Cry</game><game id="41179">Caribbean!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2179497-box_risen2.png</image></root>