<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33157</id><name>The Adventures of Shuggy</name><description>OverviewA puzzle-platformer for XBLA and PC; the protagonist, Shuggy, must use an array of tools to solve puzzles throughout his newly inherited castle.GameplayAiming to take all the clever bits of numerous platform/puzzlers and combine them into a single game, Shuggy is a 2D patformer at its most basic. Many levels introduce new mechanics like rotating the screen around Shuggy, playing with multiple time-delayed copies of yourself, winding a physics-based rope through the level, guiding a zombie version of Shuggy, racing against obstacles and more. Over 100 levels are promised and subsequent runs through completed rooms unlocks a time attack timer. A two-player co-op mode has also been promised with online and competitive variations. Progress through the game's huge Scottish-inspired castle takes place on a map-style screen where doorways slowly allow access to more and more rooms.ReleaseDating back to at least mid-2007, The Adventures of Shuggy was created using XNA tools and has been planned as an Xbox Live Arcade release for years. The official site has been updated a few times through 2009 and an extensive demo was shown off at GDC 2010; it can be seen here.On June 14 2012, the game was released for PC and is available at Steam and Desura.PC System RequirementsOS: Windows XPProcessor: Dual Core 2.0 GHzMemory: 512 MB RAMGraphics: 128 MB Video RAM and at least Shader Model 2.0DirectX®: 9.0Hard Drive: 82 MB HD space</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="37311">Escape Goat</game><game id="928">Solomon's Key</game><game id="37900">Offspring Fling!</game><game id="38873">Gateways</game><game id="40503">Sugar Cube: Bittersweet Factory</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2204860-box_taos.png</image></root>