<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33212</id><name>Football Manager 2012</name><description>Football Manager 2012 is an entry in the football management franchise, Football Manager. Developed by Sports Interactive and published by Sega, Football Manager 2012 covers the 2011/2012 football season throughout the world of football. The game was announced on August 13th, 2011, on the Football Manager website. It was released on PC and Mac on October 21st 2011.OverviewThe Football Manager series casts you as the manager of any football team in the game's expansive coverage of real-world players and teams. As manager, you organize contracts and transfers, set a formation and tactical plans both before and during the game, give pep talks and press conferences, and set up a staff to make your team as successful as possible within the constraints of your club's reputation and finances. Matches can be seen either in their entirety or as a package of highlights in a 3D match engine that becomes more detailed every year, allowing for highlight-reel goals on a small scale to dynamically develop, depending all on your managerial ability.New Features"Manage Anywhere, Anytime"One new addition to this year's game is the "Manage Anywhere, Anytime" feature. This gives the player the ability to add or take away playable nations in their saved games as often as they please, as opposed to being stuck with the nations one picked at the start as in previous games in the series. If a player adds a new nation mid-game, the game will simulate the results and performances of the players in that particular nation to catch up with the world of the already playable nations. New nations will enter into the game at the end of a season. Players can also reduce the number of divisions playable in a nation mid-game. If, for example, a player manages a team from the Blue Square Premier all the way up to the English Premier League, they can remove lower leagues to speed up their game.Transfers  ContractsTransfers and Contracts have been fleshed out, adding in new features such as loyalty bonuses, improved implementation of amateur and youth player contracts and an improved transfer center as well as the ability to lock areas of contract. If you have a salary cap, you can "lock in" parts of the contract, such as the player's wage, to say that is your final price and you will not budge. This will help the player persuade agents to sign on a contract when on a budget.Intelligent InterfaceAn improved adaptive layout system for menus means that the higher a player's screen resolution, the more information will be displayed. The new interface also contains new filters, customisable columns, a new tactics screen, and lots of new overview screens. For example, on the manager's overview screen, a player can have up to nine boxes of information on screen depending on a payer's screen resolution.ToneThe player can now specify the way they wish to say things when giving pep talks. There are five different tones in the game, including tones from calm to angry, and player reactions to pep talk comments are immediately displayed.Scouting ImprovementsVia Sport Interactive's real life scouts, new in-game scout reports have been created which includes squad analysis, tactics information and information about goals scored along with various other scouting improvements.3D Match ImprovementsThe 3D Match Engine is now much more detailed than in previous installments. A new crowd system has been implemented (including new animations for members of the crowd including things like scarf waving), along with an improved weather system, more stadium models and two new match camera angles - "Director's Cam" (which has a number of cameras cuts like those seen on TV) and "Behind Goal" as well as all other camera angles in the game now being reversible.New TutorialThere are two different tutorials found in this years' game, a tutorial mode separate from the main game as well as a "how-to" tutorial system. The new out-of-game tutorial promises to "help new players find their way around the game easily, whilst also offering tips to experienced managers and how to get the most out of the game". The "how-to" system has also seen an overhaul from previous entries in the series.PC System RequirementsOS: Windows XP/Vista/W7Processor: XP - 1.4GHz or Faster, Vista/W7 - 2.0GHz or Faster. Intel Pentium 4, Intel Core, AMD Athlon.Memory: XP - 512MB RAM, Vista/W7 - 1.0GB RAMGraphics: 128MBSupported Chipsets - Nvidia FX 5900 Ultra or greater; ATI Radeon 9800 or greater; Intel 82915G/82910GL or greater.Earlier cards may only display 2D Match Viewer Mode and are not supported.Earlier cards may require the DirectX 9.0 SDK is installed to run the game.Mac System RequirementsOS: OS X 10.5.8/10.6.8/10.7.x or higherProcessor: Intel ProcessorMemory: 1GBGraphics: Nvidia Geforce 7300 GT or greater; ATI Radeon X1600 or greater.Hard Drive: 2GB</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="40">Soccer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="32911">FIFA Manager 11</game><game id="27881">Championship Manager 2010</game><game id="4805">Soccer Team Manager: English and Italian Leagues</game><game id="10527">Premier Manager 2005-2006</game><game id="29209">FIFA Manager 10</game><game id="29210">FIFA Manager 08</game><game id="454">FIFA Soccer Manager</game><game id="3753">FIFA Manager 07</game><game id="5605">FIFA Manager 06</game><game id="24888">FIFA Manager 09</game><game id="19272">FIFA Manager 07: Extra Time</game><game id="2004">LMA Manager 2006</game><game id="2237">LMA Manager 2004</game><game id="4715">LMA Manager 2003</game><game id="4728">LMA Manager 2001</game><game id="8249">LMA Professional Manager 2005</game><game id="11938">LMA Manager 2005</game><game id="13450">LMA Manager 2002</game><game id="17090">LMA Manager</game><game id="22092">LMA Manager 2007</game><game id="40875">Disaster Response Unit</game><game id="40889">Woodcutter Simulator 2013</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14452/1867414-football_manager_2012_video_game_1.jpg</image></root>