<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33317</id><name>SD Gundam G Generation World</name><description>Overview SD Gundam G Generation World is the sequel to                                    G Generation Wars, both of which are part of the                                     SD Gundam G Generation series of turn-based strategy games. It is both the Wii's and the PSP's second G Gen game. This game adds more series, more characters, and more Mobile Suits. Gameplay G Gen World's gameplay does not appear to deviate far from its predecessors. The player builds a force of Mobile Suits and pilots and uses them to fight in missions based on the various Gundam series. As an MS attacks, dodges, or gets hit by an attack, its pilot's "MP" rating increases or decreases accordingly. If the pilot's MP is maxed out, he or she goes into Critical mode and deals much more damage; if the pilot's MP is emptied, he or she become highly vulnerable to enemy attacks.  Most of the systems from G Generation Wars returns, including Exchange and Wars Break (now "Generation Break"). This game introduces "Challenge Missions," special missions which involve secret units.  For the first time, the player is allowed to create their own faceless pilot. The pilot's name, gender, faction, voice, and battle music can be customized. Master CharactersThe Master Character system from G Generation Wars returns, and is expanded to include a handful of rival characters. Like Wars, the Master Character receives a "Basic," downgraded version of his/her signature MS that must be upgraded to become the regular version.  Unlike Wars, the Master Character is not neccessary to unlock side characters; with the exception of Collection-based unlocks, all pilots are available from the start. CharacterSeries                                Amuro Ray (UC 0079)Mobile Suit Gundam                                Char Aznable (UC 0079)Mobile Suit Gundam                               Kou UrakiGundam 0083  Anavel Gato Gundam 0083                              Kamille Bidan Zeta Gundam            Quattro Bajeena Zeta Gundam                             Jerid Messa Zeta Gundam                            Judau Ashta Gundam ZZ                           Haman Karn (UC 0088)Gundam ZZ           Amuro Ray (UC 0093)Char's Counterattack         Char Aznable (UC 0093)Char's Counterattack                          Banagher Links Gundam Unicorn                         Seabook Arno Gundam F91                        Tobia Arronax Crossbone Gundam                       Uso Ewin Victory Gundam                      Domon Kasshu G Gundam                     Heero Yuy Gundam Wing      Zechs Merquise Gundam Wing                   Garrod Ran Gundam X                  Loran Cehack Turn A Gundam                 Kira Yamato (CE 71)Gundam SEED                Athrun Zala (CE 71)Gundam SEED               Shinn Asuka SEED Destiny              Setsuna F. Seiei  (2307 AD) Gundam 00             Mr. Bushido Gundam 00  Featured SeriesMobile Suit GundamMSVMSXMobile Suit Gundam MS IglooMobile Suit Gundam: The 08th MS TeamMobile Suit Gundam Side Story: The Blue Destiny                                                 Mobile Suit Gundam: Zeonic Front                                               Mobile Suit Gundam Side Story: From Place Beyond the BlazeMobile Suit Gundam 0080: War in the Pocket                                            Mobile Suit Gundam Battlefield Record U.C. 0081Mobile Suit Gundam 0083: Stardust MemoriesAdvance of ZMobile Suit Zeta Gundam (TV and A New Translation)Z-MSVGundam SentinelMobile Suit Gundam ZZMobile Suit Gundam: Char's CounterattackCCA-MSVM-MSVMobile Suit Gundam UnicornMobile Suit Gundam: Hathaway's FlashMobile Suit Gundam F90Mobile Suit Gundam Silhouette F91Mobile Suit Gundam F91F91-MSVMobile Suit Crossbone GundamMobile Suit Crossbone Gundam Skull HeartMobile Suit Crossbone Gundam Steel SevenMobile Suit Victory GundamMobile Fighter G GundamNew Mobile Report Gundam WingNew Mobile Report Gundam Wing: Endless WaltzAfter War Gundam XTurn A GundamMobile Suit Gundam SEEDMobile Suit Gundam SEED AstrayMobile Suit Gundam SEED X AstrayMobile Suit Gundam SEED DestinyMobile Suit Gundam SEED C.E. 73 StargazerMobile Suit Gundam 00Mobile Suit Gundam 00 - A wakening of the TrailblazerSD Gundam Sangokuden: Brave Battle Warriors                                        SD Gundam Gachapon/Gashapon Senshi series                                           SD Gundam GXMobile Suit Gundam: Gihren's Greed                                          Mobile Suit Gundam: Cross Dimension 0079                                         Mobile Suit Gundam: Bonds of the BattlefieldG Generation Originals</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/16207/1662995-ggenworld.jpg</image></root>