<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33320</id><name>Ghostbusters: Sanctum of Slime</name><description>Overview Meet the RookiesGhostbusters: Sanctum of Slime is a downloadable game from                               Wanako Games, that introduces four new rookies that help out the Ghostbusters with their recent influx of work.  The new guys fight paranormal threats in this top down/                            isometric adventure.  None of the stars of the original Ghostbusters movies  the 2009  video game are expected to lend their voices. While the original characters are in the game, it is not their likeness and they aren't the main characters.  Instead, a new group of rookies are tasked with helping the team get the ghost population under control while the main Ghostbusters tackle other issues in the city.             Gameplay Ghostbusters: Sanctum of Slime is a dual stick shooter (if you play with a controller) that has the player traversing through areas while taking out ghosts along the way. You can team up with up to three other human players or simply use the computer AI to fill in the rest of your team if you go solo. While eliminating ghosts throughout the levels, unlockables and money can be found hidden in the breakable environments, for which you gain extra points. Leaderboards are available as well and are displayed after each level in the campaign. You can also link together kills which increases your point bonus in a chain. This is achieved by merging the streams, which not only makes them more powerful, but also causes splash damages to any of the neighboring ghosts. As the player progresses through the story, Egon will invent new technology and weapons for the team of Rookies to use. This is most important to defeating the several types of ghosts the player encounters throughtout the entirety of the game, seen that Egon has discovered that certain entities have auras with specifc colors around them, which makes them more susceptible to certain types of energy. Players can then switch between the different colors and the respective proton-weapon associated with it will be stronger against that particular type of enemy. Finally, mixing colors by merging streams can produce a third color, which can prove more successful against unique ghost types. Sanctum of Slime also introduces a few driving sections, wherein the four Rookies are all on the back of the brandly new Ecto-4WD, chasing and being chased by several different types of ghosts.  Story The Ghostbusters we all know and love are busier than ever these days. They are taking on more cases than they can possibly handle and they need assistance with the recent paranormal activity at the Sedgewick Hotel. The Ghostbusters make the call and send in their 4 newest recruits to check things out. Before they know it, they are entwined in a four thousand year old mystery centered around a cult and a strange green artifact. But it all begins 4000 years ago, involving a strange cult mourning the death of one Dumazu, an ancient demon of death and destruction. Then, with a quick jump to 1989, we see that the museum curator Janosz Poha is sent to a mental institution following the sucession of events seen in Ghostbusters II, the movie. In this mental institution, he comes face to face with Ismael, who si apparently the last member of the Dumazu cult. Ismael is in desperate need of a  Shard of the Relic of Nilhe, a mystical artifact that carries the power to bring Dumazu back to life with it. Ismael convinces Janosz Poha to seek the Shard, promising the insane curator Dana Barrett as a reward.Janosz is released a few years later and coincidently (or not), that's when a huge wave of paranormal activity starts manifesting all across the city of New York. And seen that the original Ghostbusters are deep in their neck with work, this is where the players come... well, into play.   CharactersPlayable Characters NameDescription Alan Crendall "Practical and hardworking, he has no real background in the paranormal  but is the workhorse leader of the team -- the others know he's always  there to pick them up after a Knock Down or help with wrangling a  frenzied ghoul. He's also the steady hand of the team - when things go  wrong he's the one with the plan." Bridget Gibbons "The tough chick with a fierce determination and a penchant for  wisecracks at other's expense. Like Alan, she has no paranormal  training, but she is a natural Ghostbuster, always at the forefront of  the battles. At times sparks can fly between her and the rest of the  team, but the jokes end when there's work to be done." Gabriel Sitter "The technical genius of the group, he's also not scared of getting his  hands dirty when the ghosts try and get up close and personal. Following  in Dr. Spengler's footsteps, he's keen to learn more about being a  Ghostbuster, and make his own mark unearthing more information on the  spectral realm and developing his own new technologies." Samuel Hazer "An optimistic scientist with a positive outlook that keeps the team's  spirits up. There's no ghost too big or bad that can't be figured out  and then busted. He has a slight advantage with his studies in the  paranormal and makes good use of this extra knowledge to help bust the  stranger entities that the team comes across." Character descriptions are displayed as seen in the game's               official website.Guest Appearances           Dr. Peter Venkman          Dr. Ray Stantz         Dr. Egon Spengler        Dr. Winston Zeddemore  Slimer  Weapons  EquipmentWeapons Proton Stream --  RedPlasma Inductor --  YellowFermion Shock --  Blue EquipmentEctoplasmic ShieldPower EnhancerNano-Massage Health Recovery SystemPC System Requirements  Operating System: Windows XP SP2, Vista SP2, 7 Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo E4300 or AMD Athlon X2 4400   RAM Memory: 1GB Graphics Card: ATI Radeon HD 2600 or NVIDIA GeForce 8600 or faster DirectX®: 9.0c Hard Drive Space: 500MB free  Sound Card: DirectX 9.0c compatible Peripherals: Keyboard plus  3 button Mouse or Microsoft Xbox 360 Controller  for PC</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="27866">Dead Nation</game><game id="12245">Gauntlet Legends</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14741/1743212-1986gbsos_generic_box_copy.jpg</image></root>