<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33337</id><name>The Spire</name><description>OverviewThe Spire looks like something very similar to the popular Portal franchise; an action-adventure puzzle-solver played out in first-person view with big focus on manipulating physics and objects around you. The game is developed by Undrawn Reality, and this is their first title to be released. As of April 2012 there's no release date for the title, which will be launched for the PC. The Spire uses the Unreal Development Kit.As of May 2013 Undrawn Reality's website is no longer available and neither is their Twitter, Facebook or YouTube page. Therefore, it seems the studio has closed and that The Spire has been cancelled.StoryIn the year 2029 a global catastrophe is around the corner as the world's population have reached its climax and fossil fuels are nowhere to be found anymore. Meanwhile a conspiracy is brewing as the world's leaders are uniting under one banner, a one world government to rule all nations.David Samuel Maher wakes up in an unknown research facility buried deep beneath the Antarctic with no memory on how or why he's there. He must unearth his past and seek answers to why he's there, and at the same time discover how he's connected to the major conspiracy that's building up in the world above him.FeaturesIn David's forearm he's armed with what is known as "The Tool", which is not yet known if it's a weapon, a simple tool or something else entirely. The Tool is used to manipulate physical objects he encounter with various strategies, such as push, pull, grab, pin and crush objects and enemies. It can also be used to construct objects, repair devices and generally interact with the world.PC System RequirementsMinimum System RequirementsOperating System: Windows XP (with SP2) / Vista / Windows 7Processor: 3.0Ghz Single Core ProcessorMemory: 1024MB RAMVideo Card: nVidia 6200, ATI Radeon 9600 or equivalent graphics cardSound Card: DirectX compatibleHDD Space: 6GBRecommended System RequirementsOperating System: Windows XP (with SP2) / Vista / Windows 7Processor: Dual Core CPUMemory: 2048MB RAMVideo Card: nVidia 7800GTX, ATI x1300 or equivalent graphics cardSound Card: DirectX compatibleHDD Space: 6GB</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21170">Portal</game><game id="21169">Portal: Still Alive</game><game id="33380">Prominence</game><game id="27951">Twin Sector</game><game id="35936">Recall</game><game id="36234">Quantum Conundrum</game><game id="36268">Q.U.B.E.</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/6/62890/1871568-indie_spotlight_the_spire_banner.jpg</image></root>