<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33415</id><name>Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 3: Citizen Brown</name><description>Marty McFly returns to 1986 but something has gone awry. After fixing the timeline in 1931 to save Doc's life, he finds Hill Valley is now a veritable police state, with it's citizens governed by the omnipresent Citizen Brown (Doc) and Edna Strickland (Edna Brown in this timeline). Marty has to find a way of talking to Citizen Brown if he has any hope of figuring out how to fix this timeline and hopefully avoid the sinister "Citizen Plus" program.This is the first episode to introduce Marty's girlfriend, Jennifer Parker and his mother, Lorraine. Also introduced is soup stand worker, Leech and Jennifer's father, Officer Parker (it was his father that arrested Kid Tannen in 1931).PC System RequirementsMinimum:OS: XP Service Pack 3 / Vista / Windows 7Processor: 1.8 GHz Pentium 4 or equivalentMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: ATI or NVidia card w/ 256 MB RAMDirectX®: Direct X 9.0cHard Drive: 2 GB Space FreeSound: Direct X 8.1 sound deviceRecommended:OS: XP Service Pack 3 / Vista / Windows 7Processor: 2.7 GHz Pentium 4 or equivalentMemory: 3 GB RAMGraphics: ATI or NVidia card w/ 512 MB RAMDirectX®: Direct X 9.0cHard Drive: 3 GB Space FreeSound: Direct X 8.1 sound deviceMac System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Snow Leopard (10.5.8)Processor: 2.0 GHz Pentium or equivalentMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: ATI or NVidia card w/ 256 MB RAMHard Drive: 2 GB Space FreeNot recommended for MAC Minis or early-generation MacBooksRecommended:OS: Snow Leopard (10.5.8)Processor: 2.3 GHz Pentium or equivalentMemory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: ATI or NVidia card w/ 512 MB RAMHard Drive: 2 GB Space FreeNot recommended for MAC Minis or early-generation MacBooks</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="32796">Tales of Monkey Island</game><game id="26776">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 1: Launch of the Screaming Narwhal</game><game id="26777">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 2: The Siege of Spinner Cay</game><game id="26778">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 3: Lair of the Leviathan</game><game id="26779">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 4: The Trial and Execution of Guybrush Threepwood</game><game id="26780">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 5: Rise of the Pirate God</game><game id="21670">Wallace &amp; Gromit's Grand Adventures Episode 1: Fright of the Bumblebees</game><game id="25467">Wallace &amp; Gromit's Grand Adventures Episode 2: The Last Resort</game><game id="25468">Wallace &amp; Gromit's Grand Adventures Episode 3: Muzzled</game><game id="25469">Wallace &amp; Gromit's Grand Adventures Episode 4: The Bogey Man</game><game id="6049">Sam &amp; Max Save the World</game><game id="38889">Back to the Future: The Game</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/86881/2145322-game_back_to_the_future_episode_3_citizen_brown.png</image></root>