<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33414</id><name>Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 2: Get Tannen!</name><description>After saving Doc Brown from Kid Tannen, Marty starts fading from history; the subpoena he issued to his grandfather Arthur McFly resulting in fatal retribution from the bootlegging gang. Rescuing his grandfather and saving his own timeline, Marty returns to 1986, only to find that Kid Tannen never ended up going to jail and has now sired a crime family that runs Hill Valley. Returning to 1931, he has to work with the young Emmett Brown again to get Kid arrested and sent to jail for good. Thanks to Kids's jilted girlfriend, Trixie Trotter, and Hill Valley Police Officer Danny Parker, grandfather of Jennifer, Kid Tannen is arrested after a shootout and is sent to jail.PC ImprovementsStarting in Episode 2 Telltale made some minor interface improvements for PC players using an Xbox 360 controller. They started displaying the relevant Xbox controller buttons on the in-game interface.Episode 1 InterfaceEpisode 2 InterfaceAlso Telltale started offering text localization for French and German. Voice acting and in-game text (store signs for example) remained in English.Episode 1Episode 2Main MenuMain MenuPC System RequirementsMinimum:OS: XP Service Pack 3 / Vista / Windows 7Processor: 1.8 GHz Pentium 4 or equivalentMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: ATI or NVidia card w/ 256 MB RAMDirectX®: Direct X 9.0cHard Drive: 2 GB Space FreeSound: Direct X 8.1 sound deviceRecommended:OS: XP Service Pack 3 / Vista / Windows 7Processor: 2.7 GHz Pentium 4 or equivalentMemory: 3 GB RAMGraphics: ATI or NVidia card w/ 512 MB RAMDirectX®: Direct X 9.0cHard Drive: 3 GB Space FreeSound: Direct X 8.1 sound deviceMac System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Snow Leopard (10.5.8)Processor: 2.0 GHz Pentium or equivalentMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: ATI or NVidia card w/ 256 MB RAMHard Drive: 2 GB Space FreeNot recommended for MAC Minis or early-generation MacBooksRecommended:OS: Snow Leopard (10.5.8)Processor: 2.3 GHz Pentium or equivalentMemory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: ATI or NVidia card w/ 512 MB RAMHard Drive: 2 GB Space FreeNot recommended for MAC Minis or early-generation MacBooks</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="29474">Sam &amp; Max: The Devil's Playhouse</game><game id="34205">The Walking Dead</game><game id="6049">Sam &amp; Max Save the World</game><game id="32796">Tales of Monkey Island</game><game id="34211">Hector: Badge of Carnage</game><game id="26776">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 1: Launch of the Screaming Narwhal</game><game id="26777">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 2: The Siege of Spinner Cay</game><game id="26778">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 3: Lair of the Leviathan</game><game id="26779">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 4: The Trial and Execution of Guybrush Threepwood</game><game id="26780">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 5: Rise of the Pirate God</game><game id="21670">Wallace &amp; Gromit's Grand Adventures Episode 1: Fright of the Bumblebees</game><game id="25467">Wallace &amp; Gromit's Grand Adventures Episode 2: The Last Resort</game><game id="25468">Wallace &amp; Gromit's Grand Adventures Episode 3: Muzzled</game><game id="25469">Wallace &amp; Gromit's Grand Adventures Episode 4: The Bogey Man</game><game id="38889">Back to the Future: The Game</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/86881/2145323-game_back_to_the_future_episode_2_get_tannen.png</image></root>