<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33464</id><name>Fate of the World</name><description>OverviewStart of a new missionIt's the year 2020, and during the last decade the earth has endured the consequences of global warming more than ever before. The nations of the world join together and create the international GEO, Global Environmental Organization, and you become it's president. It's up to you to save the world from total destruction (or maybe hasten it, if you are so inclined).To change the world, you recruit agents to work for you in different regions of the world. You then assign each agent a special "card", that will tell him what to do. Some cards will be done after one turn, while some will continue to be in use until you remove them.GameplayThe game originally shipped with four playable missions, more missions have been added along with patches. This is a list of the current missions:The Rise of Africa: Raise Africa's HDI to 0.70 by 2045. With only two regions available for control, this mission serves as a tutorial for basic game mechanics.Oil Fix It: Survive until 2080 with sustained fuel production and a high standard of living. While a more basic version of 'Fuel Crisis', it is arguably a much harder mission.Fuel Crisis: Reach 2120 with global warming in check and a basic standard of living.Cornucopia: Survive to 2200 with global warming in check and a basic standard of living. Fossil fuels never run out during this mission.Denial: Survive to 2200 with a thriving global economy and a basic standard of living. Global warming is disabled during this mission. Available as a Pre-Order bonus  Steam Summer Camp 2011 Prize booth.Earth Day: Survive to 2200 with global warming in check and a basic standard of living. All regions begin the mission with their outlook set to "Green".Three Degrees: Survive to 2200 with global warming in check and a basic standard of living. Without any additional modifiers, this is the hardest mission in the game.The Flood: Survive to 2200 without minimal deaths due to climate migration and climate change, while ensuring a basic standard of living. You begin this mission at 2100.Dr. Apocalypse: Survive to 2200 or raise global temperatures to 6 degrees above pre-industrial times. Aim to sabotage the world's recovery.System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Windows XP, Vista, 7Processor: 2.33Ghz processor or betterMemory: 2GBHard Disk Space: 1GBVideo Card: 512MB graphics cardSound: Integrated soundDirect®: 9Recommended:OS: Windows Vista, 7Processor: 2.33Ghz processor or betterMemory:3GBHard Disk Space: 1GBVideo Card: 512MB graphics cardSound: Integrated soundDirect®: 9</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4777">X-COM: Apocalypse</game><game id="30057">Sid Meier's Civilization V</game><game id="20674">StarCraft II: Wings of Liberty</game><game id="20660">Command &amp; Conquer: Red Alert 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/30604/1662208-pc_cover_fotw_website_small.jpg</image></root>