<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33494</id><name>Dungeons &amp; Dragons Daggerdale</name><description>OverviewDungeons  Dragons: Daggerdale is a video game developed by Bedlam Games and published by Atari for release on the Xbox Live Marketplace and PC platforms. It is an officially licensed Dungeons  Dragons product, and features gameplay derived from that found in Blizzard Entertainment's Diablo series.GameplayDaggerdale features the 4th edition ADD Rules. It has typical modern console hack-and-slash gameplay. There are four actions mapped to the face buttons on the controller that are able to be swapped using a modifier button similar to Dragon Age. Daggerdale also features a heavy loot component with inventory management.The player can pick one of four pre-made characters:Halfling WizardElven RogueHuman FighterDwarven ClericMultiplayerTwo players can play in local co-op, with both characters sharing a single screen, and up to four player co-op over Xbox Live.System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows XP SP3, Vista SP2, 7Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo E4300 or AMD Athlon X2 4400+Memory: 1GBGraphics: ATI Radeon HD 2900 or NVIDIA GeForce 8800 or fasterDirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 4GB freeSound: DirectX 9.0c-compatibleOther: 64Kbps+ Internet Connection requiredRecommendedOS: Windows XP SP3, Vista SP2, 7Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo E8400 or AMD Phenom II X2 555Memory: 2GBGraphics: ATI Radeon HD 3870 or NVIDIA GeForce 9800 or fasterDirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 4GB freeSound: DirectX 9.0c-compatibleOther: 256 Kbps+ recommended for multiplayer. 3-4 player co-op require internet connection</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5985">Diablo</game><game id="25983">Torchlight</game><game id="1119">Diablo II</game><game id="15589">Diablo II: Lord of Destruction</game><game id="4673">Fate</game><game id="21229">Mythos</game><game id="32130">Darkspore</game><game id="13091">Baldur's Gate: Dark Alliance</game><game id="12107">Baldur's Gate: Dark Alliance II</game><game id="13217">Champions of Norrath</game><game id="3156">Champions: Return to Arms</game><game id="5153">Sacred</game><game id="20901">Sacred 2: Fallen Angel</game><game id="28483">Sacred 2: Ice and Blood</game><game id="7791">Kong: The 8th Wonder of the World</game><game id="31832">Konung III: Ties of the Dynasty</game><game id="20803">Diablo III</game><game id="35668">Of Orcs and Men</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1793289-box_dndd.png</image></root>