<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33585</id><name>Queen's Gate: Spiral Chaos</name><description>OverviewFrom the same people who brought you Queen's Blade: Spiral Chaos comes Queen's Gate, a sequel with plenty of girls from other franchises joining the fight.CharactersQueen's GateInformationAppearanceAlice the Gate OpenerName: Alice FayeWarrior Title: Gate OpenerOccupation: Treasure HunterFrom: NitroplusAlice is a treasure hunter in Queen's Gate. Character design by Niθ.AliceInk Nijihara the Witch GirlName: Ink NijiharaWarrior Title: Witch GirlOccupation: StudentFrom: MoetanInk Nijihara is a character from the video game, Moetan.Ink NijiharaMai Shiranui the Crimson NinjaName: Mai ShiranuiWarrior Title: Crimson NinjaOccupation: NinjaFrom: Fatal Fury/King of FighterMai Shiranui is a character from the Fatal Fury and King of Fighter series. Character design by Mahiuru Izumi.Mai ShiranuiIroha the Repayer of KindnessName: IrohaWarrior Title: Repayer of KindnessOccupation: Maid to her "master"From: Samurai ShodownIroha is a maid from the Samurai Shodown series. Character design by Iizuki Tasuku.IrohaMina Majikina the Holy ArcherName: Mina MajikinaWarrior Title: Holy ArcherOccupation: ExorcistFrom: Samurai ShodownMina Majikina is a character from the Samurai Shodown series. Character design by There steward Tsuto Shino.Mina MajikinaDizzy the Child of FateName: DizzyWarrior Title: Child of FateOccupation: Half-GearFrom: Guilty GearDizzy is a character from the Guilty Gear series. Character design by Takumi Inoue.DizzyCham Cham the Protector of the JungleName: Cham ChamWarrior Title: Protector of the JungleOccupation: NoneFrom: Samurai ShodownCham Cham is a character from the Samurai Shodown series.Cham ChamLili the Daddy's Little GirlName: Lili RochefortWarrior Title: Daddy's Little GirlOccupation: NoneFrom: TekkenLili is a character from the Tekken series. Character design by Morita Kazuaki.LiliJunko Hattori the Class 1-A ChairmanName: Junko HattoriWarrior Title: Class 1-A ChairmanOccupation: UnknownFrom: Ichiban Ushiro no Daimaou (Anime/Manga)Junko Hattori is a character from the Ichiban Ushiro no Daimaou light novel and anime series. Character design by Pop Zundare.Junko HattoriKatja the Puppeteer of CopperName: KatjaWarrior Title: PuppeteerOccupation: UnknownFrom: Seikon no Qwaser (Anime/Manga)Katja is a character from the Seikon no Qwaser anime/manga series. Character design by Fuzzuentateinmento.KatjaJubei Yagyu the Awakened PrincessName: Jubei YagyuWarrior Title: Awakened PrincessOccupation: StudentFrom: Hyakka Ryouran Samurai Girls (Anime/Manga)Jubei Yagyu is a character from the Hyakka Ryouran Samurai Girls anime series. Character design by Mahiuru Izumi.Jubei YagyuPainkiller KotoneName: Painkiller KotoneWarrior Title: UnknownOccupation: UnknownFrom: Hyper NursePainkiller Kotone is a character from the Hyper Nurse series.Painkiller Kotone-ChanIvy the Twisting Blade of SolitudeName: Isbella ValentineWarrior Title: Twisting Blade of SolitudeOccupation: UnknownFrom: Soul CaliburIvy is a character from the Soul Calibur series.IvyNoel VermillionName: Noel VermillionWarrior Title: UnknownOccupation: UnknownFrom: BlazBlueNoel Vermillion is a character from the BlazBlue seires.Noel VermillionQueen's Blade OriginalsAll the characters from the Queen's Blade anime series will be feature in the game.InformationAppearanceReinaName: Reina VanceWarrior Title: Exiled WarriorOccupation: AdventurerReinaTomoeName: TomoeWarrior Title: Musha-MikoOccupation: Musha-MikoTomoeNanaelName: NanaelWarrior Title: Angel of LightOccupation: Messenger of HeavenNanaelYmirName: YmirWarrior Title: Steel PrincessOccupation: Master BlacksmithYmirNowaName: NowaWarrior Title: Guardian of the ForestOccupation: Forest GuardianNowaCattleyaName: CatteyaWarrior Title: Weapon MerchantOccupation: Shop OwnerCattleyaIrmaName: IrmaWarrior Title: Assassin FangOccupation: Neighborhood CustodianIrmaClaudetteName: Claudette VanceWarrior Title: Lord of ThundercloudOccupation: GeneralClaudetteElinaName: Elina VanceWarrior Title: Captain of the Royal GuardOccupation: Captain of the Royal GuardElinaNyxName: NyxWarrior Title: Master of FlameOccupation: SorceressNyxAiriName: AiriWarrior Title: Infernal TempterOccupation: Maid/Swamp Witch ServentAiriMelonaName: MelonaWarrior Title: Protean AssassinOccupation: Aide to the Swamp WitchMelonaMenaceName: MenaceWarrior Title: Ancient PrincessOccupation: PrincessMenaceAlleyneName: AlleyneWarrior Title: Fighting MasterOccupation: Fighting Master of the Forest ElvesAlleyneRistyName: RistyWarrior Title: Bandit of the WildernessOccupation: BanditRistyEchidnaName: EchidnaWarrior Title: Veteran MercenaryOccupation: MercenaryEchidnaAldraName: AldraWarrior Title: QueenOccupation: GondoolierAldraQueen's Blade: Spiral ChaosThe original characters from Queen's Blade: Sprial Chaos will be feature in the game.AranaeCuteJeanLamicaPuiaCerateDoraQueen's Gate: Spiral Chaos OriginalAinaHyumina</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="29245">Queen's Blade: Spiral Chaos</game><game id="42855">Super Heroine Chronicle</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/80630/1718820-002.jpg</image></root>