<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33701</id><name>Dai-2-Ji Super Robot Taisen Z Hakai-hen</name><description>Overview Super Robot Wars Z2 is the sequel to 2008's                   Super Robot Wars Z. This is the first in a two-game series, and some anime will only have their stories partially completed in this game. Despite this, the developer claims that Z2 will feature more missions than any other handheld SRW.  Z2 introduces many popular series from the latter half of the previous decade, including Tengen Toppa Gurren Lagann, Gundam 00, and Code Geass. However, this game also marks the debut of Armored Trooper Votoms, one of the earliest pioneers of the "Real Robot" genre of mecha anime.Story Super Robot Wars Z2 takes place in a different universe than its predecessor. In this universe, twenty years have passed since the world was thrown into chaos by the dimension-shattering "Break the World" incident. On top of the aftereffects of the Space-Time Oscillation Bomb, such as the occasional appearance of vicious "dimensional monsters," the world is essentially split between the Advanced European Union, Human Reform League, and the Britannia Empire.   The game follows    Crowe Broust, an unlucky ex-soldier who suddenly gains a 1,000,000G debt. He becomes a test pilot to pay off the debt, and soon after joins ZEXIS, a team dedicated to defeating the dimensional monsters, malicious aliens and other threats to international security. Featured Series This is a list of anime that will be featured in the game. Anime that make their first Super Robot Wars appearance in this game are marked with "(new)".  Mobile Suit Zeta GundamMobile Suit Gundam: Char's Counterattack New Mobile Report Gundam Wing After War Gundam X   Turn A Gundam  Its name is...its name is...its name is...ITS NAME IS...ROCKET PUUUUUNCH!        Mobile Suit Gundam SEED Destiny        Mobile Suit Gundam 00 (First Season, new)        Shin Mazinger Impact! Z Chapter (new)Getter Robo ArmageddonInvincible Super Man Zambot 3Invincible Steel Man Daitarn 3Invincible Robo Trider G7Space Emperor God SigmaSpace Warrior BaldiosSix God Combination GodmarsCombat Mecha XabungleArmored Trooper Votoms (new)Armored Trooper Votoms: The Last Red Shoulder (new)Armored Trooper Votoms: Red Shoulder Document: The Roots of Ambition (new)Armored Trooper Votoms: Pailsen Files (new)Super Dimensional Century OrgussSuper Beast Machine God DancougarDancougar Nova    Dai-Guard (new)The Big O    Overman King Gainer Licensing issues were just another impossibility for Gurren Lagann to overcome. Super Heavy God Gravion Zwei Genesis of AquarionCode Geass: Lelouch of the Rebellion (new)Tengen Toppa Gurren Lagann (new)Gurren Lagann The Movie: Childhood's End (new)Macross FrontierMacross Frontier The Movie: The False Songstress (new)Psalm of Planets Eureka Seven: Good Night, Sleep Tight, Young Lovers (new) GameplayZ2's core gameplay is identical to that of its predecessors; it is a strategy RPG in which players field his or her favorite robots and pilots, and then use their variety of attacks to destroy the enemy army. Each pilot has a number of  seishin, special commands which grant temporary bonuses to their robot or, in some cases, hinder the enemy force.  Z2 forgoes its predecessor's Tri-Battle System in favor of the more traditional single-robot units. However, to prevent unused pilots from falling too far behind, Z2 introduces the Sub Order System. After each mission, unused pilots can take part in one of four different tasks; each task grants the pilot with a certain bonus. A total of 20 pilots can participate in a single session.  Z2 also features the return of Ace Bonuses, last seen in           Super Robot Wars A Portable. This grants a special ability to a character whose kill count his high enough to be considered an "Ace."  Although much of the game's interface seems to identical to the first SRWZ, the map is a huge departure. The map is isometric in Z1, as it is in virtually every console game since          Super Robot Wars Alpha, but the map in Z2 is 2D and top-down, again like A Portable. In terms of battle animation, Z2 seems to be on par with the first Z. For the first time since         Neo Super Robot Wars, Gundams use non-SD art during certain events and/or attacks.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="37264">Dai-2-Ji Super Robot Taisen Z Saisei-hen</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/16207/1723551-z2.jpg</image></root>