<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33885</id><name>Muchi Muchi Pork!</name><description>Muchi Muchi Pork! (むちむちポーク!) is a vertical bullet hell shoot 'em up developed by Cave and released in 2007. The main programmer was Shinobu Yagawa.The game allows players to choose between three pig-girls: the small-chested, fast Rafute (aka Muchi Muchi Yellow), the large-chested, medium-speed Momo (aka Muchi Muchi Pink) and the massive-chested, slow Ikuo (aka Muchi Muchi Blue). Killing enemies with the regular shot produces a number of parachuting pigs in the air, and/or a number of pigs on the ground that slowly run away. Collecting pigs fills the lard meter, allowing the player to use the lard attack. Enemies killed with the lard attack produce golden pig medals which, when collected, increase the player's score.The game has five stages, and a rank system that increases difficulty when the player collects extra lives or increases his score.  Muchi Muchi Pork!  Pink SweetsAn Xbox 360 port compilation that includes, in addition to Muchi Muchi Pork!, Pink Sweets ~Ibara Sore Kara~ as well as a bunch of extra content (arrange modes, new music and, for buyers of the first print, Muchi Muchi Pork! Matsuri Version, a special version of Muchi Muchi Pork! that includes the boss fights from Pink Sweets) was announced at the Cave summer festival of August 2010. The port is free of region protection, and was released February 24 2011.</description><genres><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="32381">Pink Sweets ~Ibara Sorekara~</game><game id="22919">Battle Garegga</game><game id="32547">Battle Bakraid</game><game id="33917">DoDonPachi Daifukkatsu Black Label</game><game id="22956">Ibara</game><game id="29280">Mushihime-sama Futari</game><game id="22393">Mushihime-Sama</game><game id="30001">Espgaluda II Black Label</game><game id="26366">Espgaluda II</game><game id="17644">Espgaluda</game><game id="22550">DonPachi</game><game id="216">Dodonpachi Dai-Ou-Jou</game><game id="26433">DoDonPachi Dai Ou Jou Black Label EXTRA</game><game id="21705">DoDonPachi</game><game id="32344">DoDonPachi Resurrection</game><game id="34124">Ibara Kuro: Black Label</game><game id="34237">Ketsui: Kizuna Jigoku Tachi</game><game id="34001">Crimzon Clover</game><game id="34268">Mushihime-sama Futari Black Label</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/12/122378/1818723-muchi_muchi_pork_festival_poster_small.png</image></root>