<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34012</id><name>Anarchy Reigns</name><description>OverviewAnarchy Reigns (known in Japan as "Max Anarchy") is a 3D beat 'em up developed by PlatinumGames and published by Sega for the Xbox 360 and PlayStation 3 on January 8, 2013. Originally released in Japan on July 5, 2012, Anarchy Reigns features arena-based multiplayer for up to sixteen players in a variety of game modes (from standard deathmatch to a crazy sports-inspired mode influenced by the DeathBall mod for Unreal Tournament 2003 and Unreal Tournament 2004).Set in a distant, chaotic future (where, due to terrorism and biological warfare, mankind would be extinct if not for the development of nan-machines and cybernetic organisms), the story is split into two overarching stories: the White Side (where players control Leonhardt "Leo" Victorion, a cybernetic agent of the Bureau of Public Safety and leader of the Strike One team) and the Black Side (where players control Jack Cayman, a cybernetic mercenary, or "Chaser"). Either way, they must hunt down Maximillian Caxton, the former leader of Strike One and a fugitive (who is believed to have murdered his wife).Although the game's story is not related to PlatinumGames's 2009 action game MadWorld, Anarchy Reigns features playable characters from that game (including Jack Cayman as one of the main playable protagonists). The game also includes Bayonetta (from the 2010 action game Bayonetta) as a playable guest character.ModesSingle PlayerPlayers play through both a White Side and Black Side campaign starring their respective characters. After both White and Black sides have been completed, a Red Side will unlock with the story's true ending where Leo and Jack team up to defeat a mutual superpowered enemy. While only Jack and Leo will be playable at the start, certain story missions let the player take control of other characters if they wish. A variety of optional and obligatory missions will be available alongside missions that progress the story. During battles The battlefield will change in real time during some fights -- bridges will collapse, natural disasters will occur, military bombardments will hit the area, and so on.MultiplayerThe multiplayer mode consists of a selection of competitive online modes supporting a large number of players. Special "action trigger events" will regularly occur in matches, introducing environmental hazards like tsunamis and black holes.The modes include:Death Match: A free-for-all battle mode where a maximum of 4 players fight each other.Tag Battle: A mode in which 8 players battle each other in 4 separate pairs (or 2v2v2v2 Death Match).Team Battle: 4v4 team deathmatch mode.Cage Match: A 1-on-1 deathmatch mode that takes place in a small cage. Every so often items will be dropped in that can shift the tide of battle.Battle Royal: A free-for-all battle mode where up to 16 players (8 people and 8 AI-controlled players max) fight each other for dominance.Survival Mode: A horde mode in which a team of up to 3 players works together to fend off progressively tougher waves of computer-controlled enemies.Mad Survival (DLC): Similar to Survival mode but the enemy waves include various player characters.Dogfight (DLC): Two players fight each other using hijacked gunship turrets.Capture the Flag: Just like it sounds, 2 teams of 4 players each have to capture the enemy's flag and return it to their base while keeping their own flag from being taken. The flag-carrier can smack people while holding the flag, but cannot use their full movelist.Death Ball: A mode where both teams try to shoot or run a ball into the enemy team's goal to score points before time runs out, using their character's powers to either stop the competition or add power to their own shot.CharactersSashaSashaGoing by the moniker Ice Queen, Sasha utilizes advanced technology to coat a set of levitating spikes with ice. She is a member of Strike-One with Leo and Nikolai, and a prodigy who was accepted into the unit after just two years in the military.Age: 24Height: 1.71 m / 5'6''Weight: 53 kg / 117 lbsCategory: HumanWeapons: Snow Spikes, six ice-producing spikes deployed from a main unit mounted on the user's back.ZeroZeroA ninja assassin in a stealth-tailored nano-machina suit, Zero fights with two swords: Onimaru and Juzumaru.Age: 26Height: 1.97 m / 6'5"Weight: 152 kg / 335 lbsCategory: HumanWeapons: Onimaru and Juzumaru, authentic Japanese katana rumoured to be two of the five mythological Tenka Goken blades.Big BullBig BullA cyborg with a massive, jet-powered hammer that doubles as a jetpack. Became a cyborg four years ago, when his human body was seriously injured. Currently runs a gang out of an abandoned foundry in Altambra and occasionally uses Baijiquan moves in battle.Age: 35 (became a cyborg at age 31)Height: 2.88 m / 9'4"Weight: 1300 kg / 2866 lbsCategory: Cyborg (the brain is the only human part in his body)Weapon: Jet Hammer, a jet-powered hammer that doubles as a jetpack.Nikolai Dmitri BulyginNikolaiAn intelligent warrior/philosopher cyborg who fights with electric shocks, the current leader of Strike-One with his own moral code and sense of justice that clashes with Leo's.Age: 32Height: 2.10 m / 6'8"Weight: 310 kg / 683 lbsCategory: CyborgWeapon: Tesla Blitz, a back-mounted generator that sends a powerful electric current through the arms.Leonhardt VictorionLeoAn ex-Marine and Muay Thai specialist who is a member of Strike One with Sasha and Nikolai. He refuses to believe that Max actually killed his wife, and decides to bring him back alive for questioning.Age: 28Height: 2.04 m / 6'6"Weight: 164 kg / 361 lbsCategory: CyborgWeapon: Positron Blade, electric-powered blades attached to each arm that can slice through almost anything.DurgaDurgaA bounty-hunting cyborg with a large revolver in his right leg. Durga has a weird tiger-like demeanor and prefers the thrill of fighting to any material reward from his bounties.Age: 31Height: 1.99 m / 6'5"Weight: 147 kg / 324 lbsCategory: CyborgWeapon: Revolver Cannon, a literal cannon built into his right knee that fires ammo cartridges from a revolving cylinder.GarudaGarudaA mercenary who died and had his mind transferred to a cybernetic body. Armed with drills and capable of transforming into a jet plane. Currently working with Durga.Age: Body - 2, Mind - 30Height: 2.6 m / 8'5"Weight: 1210 kg / 2668 lbsCategory: AndroidWeapon: Tornado Drills attached to his hands.Edgar OinkieOinkieA scientist who has developed a drug, "The Juice", that allows him to temporarily turn into a powerful mutant. Has a love of all things technology and runs a gang out of Port Valenda that helps him scavenge any new tech he can, regardless of whether the owner is still alive.Age: 28Height: 2.18 m / / 7'1" (human form), 3 m / 9'8" (mutant form)Weight: 150 kg / 331 lbs (human form), 350 kg / 772 lbs (mutant form)Category: Human / MutantWeapon: The Juice, allows him to briefly transform into a mutant.Jack CaymanJackAn ex-marine with a chainsaw attached to his right arm who currently works as a "Chaser," hunting down people and objects for the right price. Asked to track down Max by Max's daughter Jeannie, but also blames Max for his own daughter's death. Originally appeared in MadWorld.Age: 42Height: 2.18 m / 7'1"Weight: 230 kg / 507 lbsCategory: Cyborg (25% human)Weapon: Gator Tooth, a double-bladed chainsaw attached to his right arm.Blacker BaronBlacker BaronA pimpin' black man who wields a pair of flaming gauntlets he stole from a "pyromaniac sex-freak" he took down with Jack at some point in the past. Later teams up with Jack at Amala's urging and the promise of a large bounty on Max's head. Originally appeared in MadWorld.Age: 37Height: 2.05 m / 6'7"Weight: 256 kg / 564 lbsCategory: CyborgWeapon: Super Sexy Fists of Fire, a pair of flaming gloves stolen from a "pyromaniac sex-freak" he took down with Jack sometime in the past.MathildaMathildaOne of the Black Baron's consorts, wielding a spiked mace. Rarely talks. Originally appeared in MadWorld.Age: 27Height: 1.88 m / 6'1"Weight: 188 kg / 414 lbsCategory: CyborgWeapon: Iron Maiden, a spike-endowed mace that doubles as a heavy sash around her waist.BayonettaAn Umbra witch who quadruple-wields guns and uses her hair for attacks. Originally appeared in Bayonetta. A guest star in this game due to both titles being Platinum Games property.Age: Over 500Height: 11.951 uwh (magical unit of measurement)Weight: 4.67 uww (magical unit of measurement)Category: WitchWeapon: Wicked Weave. Bayonetta uses her hair to channel the power of Madama Butterfly, a demon, into giant fists and other weapons.Maximillian CaxtonMaximillian CaxtonThe former leader of Strike-One and a fugitive. Accidentally killed Jack's daughter during a hostage rescue situation and now has PTSD from the incident, currently being hunted by the Bureau of Public Security he once served with pride.Age: 45Height: 2.7 m / 8'8"Weight: 620 kg / 1366 lbsCategory: CyborgWeapon: Positron Blades  Tesla Blitz, a lethal combination of the same powers that Leo and Nikolai have.Douglas WilliamsburgAn old fighter who is trying to find mutants that killed his wife and child.Age: 180 (estimation)Height: 2.4 m / 7'8"Weight: 1850 kg / 4078 lbsCategory: CyborgWeapon: The Twins AKA Romeo and JulioRin RinOne of three sisters and part of a Chinatown triad gang. She uses fans that project flames. Originally appeared in MadWorld.Age: 19Height: 1.7 m / 5'5"Weight: 45 kg / 99 lbsCategory: HumanWeapon: Yanlong, a pair of flaming oriental fans.Fei RinOne of three sisters and part of a Chinatown triad gang. She fights with a staff that shoots ice.Age: 20Height: 1.7 m / 5'5"Weight: 45 kg / 99 lbsCategory: HumanWeapon: Zilong, a large bo staff with icicle spikes at each end.Ai RinOne of three sisters and part of a Chinatown triad gang. She wields a set of nunchuks that discharge electricity.Age: 18Height: 1.7 m / 5'5"Weight: 45 kg / 99 lbsCategory: HumanWeapon: Huanglong, nunchaku with electric blades at each end.SoundtrackAnarchy Reigns OST cover.The soundtrack to Anarchy Reigns was released on Amazon and iTunes on July 4th, 2012.Track No.TitleArtist1RuthlessTre-Dot2Over In a FlashSick YG3My PrideSkitz The Samurida4Sound the AlarmC.Wilkes (Ox)5MortifiedWonder Brown6Laughin At UTre-Dot7Soon EnoughSick YG8I Know U Want MeBandy Leggz9My Town, My CitySkitz The Samurida10Gotta Get the CashDoujah Raze11Kill Em AllC.Wilkes (Ox)12MDK'sVstylez13They Came From UndergroundRushden  Diamonds14Play My Ass OffJosh Clemons15VenommuzeONE16Unlimited ResourcesSkitz The Samurida17JawmuzeONE18Play For KeepsSick YG19We PlayDoujah Raze20The Hand of ScienceSkitz The Samurida21Here We GoTheory Hazit22DemiseWonder Brown23Days of OldVstylez24It`s All About MeBandy Leggz25Fast LameRushden  Diamonds26Testin`MeDoujah Raz27Rock OnDoujah Raze28We All SoldiersSkitz The Samurida29Lights OutC.Wilkes (Ox)30MercilessTheory Hazit31Find YouDoujah Raze32This Is MadnessDilated PeoplesXbox 360 and PS3 Game InstallationAnarchy Reigns requires 7.7GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD and 3.3 GB on PS3.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5888">God Hand</game><game id="21173">MadWorld</game><game id="29036">Fist of the North Star:  Ken's Rage</game><game id="20831">Castlevania Judgment</game><game id="21520">Viewtiful Joe: Red Hot Rumble</game><game id="38563">Fist of the North Star: Ken's Rage 2</game><game id="9555">Spawn: In the Demon's Hand</game><game id="10734">Heavy Metal Geomatrix</game><game id="20100">Power Stone</game><game id="20710">Bayonetta</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2367490-box_areigns.png</image></root>