<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34182</id><name>The Testament of Sherlock Holmes</name><description>OverviewFamous Detective Sherlock Holmes returns to London to solve yet another case. According to a game representative at E3 2011, over the course of the story Holmes becomes increasingly violent and angry, eventually murdering someone himself. As a result, Watson is forced to take up arms against and kill Holmes, leaving the direction of future installments in the series uncertain. The game is said to be approximately 15 hours long, with Holmes being playable for about 10 of them.It was further revealed at E3 2012, that Sherlock Holmes' dog would be an additional playable character, giving the player the ability to sniff footprints in an effort to help solve cases. Further details regarding Holmes' dog's abilities have yet to be unveiled.The game was initially made for the PC by Frogwares and was ported to the PS3 and 360 by Spiders.StoryThe game starts in London in the year 1898 with the world famous detective Sherlock Holmes retrieving a priceless set of jewels. The case seems to be coming to a close until the owner of the jewels reveals that the jewels Holmes returned to him are nothing but a poor imitation of the real ones. All the clues lead to one man and that is none other than Sherlock Holmes. Holmes, not attempting to clear his name, tells Watson that he has an important meeting with the Bishop of Knightbridge and that they must leave immediately to meet him. When they arrive they find the bishop's burnt and mutilated corpse. Things only get worse for Sherlock Holmes as all of London starts to suspect him of perpetrating these horrible crimes and the fact that Holmes seems incapable of actually proving his innocence makes things even worse. Even Doctor Watson starts to doubt Holmes when he starts to avoid the police, destroy evidence and disappear mysteriously in the middle of the night.PC System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Win Xp 32CPU: Celeron E1400 Dual-Core 2GHz or Athlon 64 X2 Dual Core 4400+RAM: 2 GBHDD: 14 GB free disk spaceGraphics: GeForce 8600 GT Inno3D 256MB GDDR2 or Radeon HD 2600 XTSound Card: DirectX 9 CompatibleDirectX: Version 9Recommended:OS: Win 7 32 or Win 7 64CPU: Core 2 Duo E6850 3.0GHz or Phenom II X2 555 Black EditionRAM: 3 GBHDD: 14 GB free disk spaceGraphics: GeForce GT 240 or Radeon HD 2900 XT 512MBSound Card: DirectX 9 CompatibleDirectX: Version 9</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12749">Agatha Christie: Murder on the Orient Express</game><game id="29378">Nancy Drew Dossier: Lights, Camera, Curses!</game><game id="40033">Meitantei Holmes: Kiri no London Satsujin Jiken</game><game id="42346">The Raven</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2280535-box_ttosh.png</image></root>