<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34205</id><name>The Walking Dead</name><description>OverviewThe "walkers".The Walking Dead (also known as "The Walking Dead: A Telltale Games Series") is a five-part horror adventure game developed and published by Telltale for the Xbox 360 (via Xbox Live Arcade), PlayStation 3 (via PlayStation Network), PC, Mac, and all iOS devices, between April 24, 2012 and November 21, 2012. It was later released in retail for the Xbox 360, PlayStation 3, and PC on December 11, 2012. The game received DLC in July 2013 which followed the lives of five new survivors.The game is set in the same universe as Robert Kirkman's comic book series of the same name, players follow the story of Lee Everett, a 37-year-old convicted murderer who gains a second chance in life (as the guardian of a 8-year-old girl named Clementine) throughout Georgia, U.S.A. at the beginning of the zombie apocalypse.Making moral decisions is a pillar of the series, complete with branching consequences that tailor the player's story to the pressured choices they are forced to make. Characters met throughout the story learn from and react according to dialogue choices Lee makes, which also affect key parts of the story. Like the comic book and television series of the same name, the game focuses on creating interactions between the human characters, rather than killing large numbers of the undead (as most zombie-related games tend to rely on).Gary Whitta is a story consultant for the game, and was the writer for Episode 4: Around Every Corner.GameplayLee comes face to face with a walker.Players take control of the main character Lee Everett and guide him through his survival of the zombie apocalypse. Players have full control over the character's movement, and using the on-screen reticule, can interact with and use objects. Players will have to search through shelves, cars, and other objects to help other people you've found along the way survive.The game focuses on interactions with other human characters through dialogue trees, often with limited time to make a choice. Characters will remember things you have said before and will often realize if your story doesn't add up. These interactions can also affect where the story progresses as well.Combat isn't a priority in the game, and is handled similarly to the rest of the gameplay, only more urgent and time-based. You'll find yourself needing to use items you've gathered throughout the game to chop down zombies or load guns with bullet shells you've found laying around. Choices you've made previously can also affect how you fight against zombies, such as possessing different equipment or having other characters with you.Downloadable ContentA downloadable expansion to the game titled 400 Days was released on July 2nd 2013 on PSN and July 3rd on PC and XBLM. This episode is set during the first 400 days of the apocalypse; it will focus on five new characters, and is not directly tied into the storyline of the main game. In order to play the DLC, players will require at least the first episode of Season One. Choices from Season 1 will be carried over from 400 Days and then into Season Two. At least one of the familiar faces from Season One can be found in this 5-part episode. Each part can be played in any order preferred - the timelines will ultimately intertwine.CharactersDue to the game being separated into episodes, this section will cover the main characters, who have appeared in more than one episode. For the "secondary" characters, check the episode section in which they appear.Introduced in Episode One ("A New Day")Lee Everett is the main protagonist of the game (and the character the player indirectly controls). Born and raised in Macon, Georgia (where his family owned a pharmacy before the zombie apocalypse hit), Lee was a 37-year-old history professor at the University of Georgia before being convicted for the murder of a senator (whom Lee's wife had an affair with).As he was being escorted by police to prison (during the initial outbreak), the police car crashes off the side of the road. Lee, being the only survivor, makes his way through the undead to a nearby neighborhood. He finds Clementine, an eight-year-old girl whose parents were on vacation, and decides to be her guardian as they find other survivors.Lee's personality and allegiances are determined through player choice throughout the game. Regardless, he is trusted by the rest of the roaming group, both by his actions and his guardianship of Clementine.Clementine is a young, quiet 8-year-old girl who survived the first days of the zombie apocalypse alone in a small Georgia neighborhood (while her parents were on vacation in Savannah, Georgia). After saving the life of Lee, she accompanies him as they try to find safety.Throughout the game, she helps the group in various situations (mainly by using her small physique to get through obstacles too small for the adults). She also forms a strong friendship with Lee, looking out for him (as much as he's looking out for her).Shawn GreeneHershel GreeneKenny is a hard-working family man and a former fishing boat captain from Ft. Lauderdale, Florida. He cares the most about his wife, Katjaa, and his son, "Duck," and can perform feats of great bravery to protect them when they are in danger. However, he can be a flawed and selfish individual, putting himself and his family above others (especially in dangerous situations).Because he's quick to take charge, he often contests with certain members of the group, particularly Lilly, about how the group should be run.Katjaa is the calm-headed Belgian wife of Kenny and the mother of "Duck." She is also a former veterinarian whose medical skills are put to the test at certain points in the game.Duck, whose real name is Kenny Jr., is the child son of Kenny and Katjaa. He's oblivious to the serious situation of living in the zombie apocalypse.Lilly is a stern leader and a former mechanical engineer from Macon, Georgia. Although strong-willed and quick to take charge, she usually caves in at the demands of her father, Larry, whom is the only thing she has left in the world.Her paranoid leadership and distrust of strangers have often put her at odds with most of the group, particularly Kenny.Larry is a aggressive, judgmental man and a retired military commander from Macon, Georgia. Although he is well-intentioned and cares about his daughter, Lilly, he has a history of heart-related problems, and sometimes suffer from heart attacks.He knows early on that Lee is a convicted murderer, which makes him very distrustful and even hateful towards him.Carley is a former regional news reporter from Atlanta, Georgia. A logical, independent quick-thinker, she is a surprisingly good shot with firearms.She has a romantic interest in Doug, after he saved her life. Her actions sometimes put her at odds with Lilly. She also knows early on that Lee is a convicted murderer, but wants to trust him.Doug is a former IT technician from Atlanta, Georgia. Although he's a non-aggressive, non-confrontational individual, his technical knowledge and industrious skill has helped the group from time to time.He has a romantic interest for Carley, after saving her life.Glenn is a former pizza delivery boy from Macon, Georgia.Unlike the other characters in the game, Glenn appears as a major character in both the original comic book series and the TV series. Both media series serve as different sequels to Glenn's story in the game.Introduced in Episode Two ("Starved For Help")MarkBen PaulAndrew St. JohnDanny St. JohnBrenda St. JohnJoleneIntroduced in Episode Three ("Long Road Ahead")ChuckOmidChristaIntroduced in Episode Four ("Around Every Corner")MollyVernonBrieIntroduced in Episode Five ("No Time Left")"Station Wagon Man"Story (Spolier Alert!)Due to the branching nature of the storyline in The Walking Dead, not all the specific choices have been listed. Instead, just a basic outline of the main story elements are described below.Episode 1 – A New DayLee does whatever it takes to survive.Set shortly after the initial outbreak, the story starts out following Lee Everett, who has been arrested in Atlanta and is being transported out of the city in a police car. After a car crash, he escapes into a small nearby neighborhood already hit by invading zombies. He soon meets 8-year-old Clementine, a girl who has been hiding out in her tree house for a few days waiting for her parents to come home. They set off to find a safe place nearby in case her parents return from their vacation. they soon meet up with other survivors, as well as several characters from the graphic novel's original storyline such as the Greene family and Glenn. After spending some time at Herschel Greene's farm they leave and encounter another set of survivors holed up in a pharmacy, and it is revealed that the (assumed dead) owners of the pharmacy are Lee's parents. After going to a local motel to siphon gasoline, they return to the pharmacy, which is soon overrun with zombies and they flee back to the motel.Episode 2 – Starved For HelpSt. John Dairy Farm.Episode 2 starts three months after the end of Episode 1. The group is still holed up at the motel, but food and water are in short supply, and the group is going hungry. They soon encounter a couple of people that are living at the nearby St. John Dairy Farm, and the group is invited to come have some food  shelter. Some members of the group are suspicious of these newcomers, but the group decides to accept their offer. Lee agrees to help out around the farm, but encounters bandits in the nearby woods and a member of the group is injured by an arrow. The farmers agree to treat the injured group member, but soon after it becomes apparent that there are ulterior motives at play. Just as they are about to sit down for the meal Lee discovers that the dairy farmers are cannibals, about to serve them the flesh of their injured friend. The farmers become violent and Lee is knocked out, the group is kidnapped then locked in a storage shed. They soon escape the room, rescue other characters from the farmers, and flee into the woods. The episode ends with the discovery of an abandoned station wagon filled with food and supplies, the owner of which is a mystery.Episode 3 – Long Road AheadLee teaching Clem how to shoot.After the shocking events at the St. John Dairy Farm, the remaining group members return to their haven at the motel. Lee and Kenny are delegated to scavenging supplies from a nearby drug store, however upon their return, there is friction as Lilly has suspicions that someone is stealing provisions. Meanwhile, Kenny insists the group needs to move on and head for the Atlantic coast. He gets his way, although through circumstances no one is happy with. Over the course of the episode, tensions start to reach a breaking point as the group starts to crumble. A few characters perish, while another leaves. A few new faces are introduced as well: Chuck, Christa and Omid. Lee starts to teach Clementine how to protect herself, by teaching her how to shoot a gun, and keeping herself safe by cutting her hair to a much more suitable length. Eventually the group is able to successfully start up and operate a train engine. As the group arrives in Savannah, the episode then ends with Lee hearing a strange voice on Clementine's walkie talkie.Episode 4 – Around Every CornerA temporary home.The group arrives in Savannah, finding the city vacant. A church bell rings, drawing a zombie horde towards their location. The group escapes the herd by taking up residence in an abandoned home. While Christa attends to Omid's wounds, Lee and Kenny head to the waterfront to look for a boat. Although they don't find any working boats, they do encounter some new survivors. These survivors, Molly and Vernon, warn Lee of a ruthless survivor community within Savannah known as Crawford. Upon returning to the group's temporary home, Clementine shows Lee a working boat kept in the house's garage. In order to get fuel for the boat and medicine for Omid, the group makes a stealth raid of Crawford. Disaster ensues and the group narrowly escapes Crawford with the supplies. Once safe at home, Vernon offers to take Clementine back to his group. While considering Vernon's offer, Lee falls asleep watching Clementine. Lee wakes up to find Clementine and the new survivors missing, and suffers an unfortunate injury while frantically looking for her. The chapter ends with another message from the walkie talkie.Episode 5 – No Time LeftA tense conversation with Clementine's captor.After a conversation over the walkie-talkie with the anonymous captor of Clementine, Lee is now determined to rescue her. Not long after, his aforementioned injury means for some distressing decisions. Lee then climbs to the roof of the hospital and makes his back to where the boat was located, only to find a note from Vernon explaining he has taken it. After a while, Clementine contacts Lee, revealing she is being kept in a hotel on River Street. Upon arrival, Lee is greeted by the captor who describes his situation. His insanity is slowly revealed, causing a fight to ensue resulting in his death. Finally reunited with Clementine, Lee makes for a plan to escape Savannah with her. Sadly, Lee's injuries overcome him and can no longer carry on. Reaching a secure location with a trapped police officer-turned-walker, Lee advises Clementine to take the gun and handcuff himself to the wall. Realizing Clem has the capability to take care of herself, they have a tearful farewell as Lee passes away.Clementine, now alone, finds her way to the countryside and spots two figures in the distance. Suddenly, they stop and direct their gaze upon her.AccoladesDICE AwardsAdventure Game of the YearDownloadable Game of the YearOutstanding Character Performance (Lee Everett)Outstanding Achievement in StorySpike VGAsGame of the YearBest Adapted Video GameBest Downloadable GameSystem RequirementsPCMinimumOS: XP Service Pack 3.CPU: 2.0 GHz Pentium 4 or equivalent.RAM: 3 GB RAM.Hard Disk Space: 2 GB Space Free.GPU: ATI or NVidia card w/ 512 MB RAM (Not recommended for Intel integrated graphics).DirectX: Direct X 9.0c.Sound: Direct X 9.0c sound device.RecommendedOS: Windows 7.CPU: Core 2 Duo 2GHz or equivalent.RAM: 3 GB RAM.Hard Disk Space: 2 GB Space Free.GPU: ATI or NVidia card w/ 1024 MB RAM (Not recommended for Intel integrated graphics).DirectX: Direct X 9.0c.Sound: Direct X 9.0c sound device.Mac System RequirementsMinimumOS: Snow Leopard (10.6.X).CPU: 2.3 Ghz Intel.RAM: 4 GB RAM.Hard Disk Space: 2 GB Space Free.GPU: 512 MB NVidia or ATI graphics card.Additional: Not recommended for Intel integrated graphics or Mac Minis or early-generation MacBooks.RecommendedOS: Snow Leopard (10.6.X).CPU: Core 2 Duo 2GHz.RAM: 4 GB RAM.Hard Disk Space: 2 GB Space Free.GPU: 1024 MB NVidia or ATI graphics card.Additional: Not recommended for Intel integrated graphics or Mac Minis or early-generation MacBooks.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="33414">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 2: Get Tannen!</game><game id="33851">Jurassic Park</game><game id="21304">Heavy Rain</game><game id="37416">Yesterday</game><game id="2494">Indigo Prophecy</game><game id="20984">Alpha Protocol</game><game id="25933">Fallout: New Vegas</game><game id="36237">Zero Escape: Virtue's Last Reward</game><game id="27266">999: 9 Hours, 9 Persons, 9 Doors</game><game id="2426">Dreamfall: The Longest Journey</game><game id="42346">The Raven</game><game id="43488">Postmortem</game><game id="38541">Beyond: Two Souls</game><game id="34213">The Wolf Among Us</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2348800-box_twdead.png</image></root>