<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34211</id><name>Hector: Badge of Carnage</name><description>OverviewHector is fearless.Hector: Badge of Carnage consists of three games:Episode 1: We Negotiate with TerroristsEpisode 2: Senseless Acts of JusticeEpisode 3: Beyond Reasonable DoomHector: Badge of Carnage is a short, point-and-click adventure game that is published by Telltale Games. It is planned as a three episode series. The first episode is titled "We Negotiate with Terrorists". The player controls Detective Inspector Hector, who is the only person the city's got after a crisis with a terrorist erupts. Hector does whatever it takes to achieve his goals; such as commandeering a youth's pants and grabbing a paper clip out of a very unsanitary toilet. The game features mature and vulgar humor, which is uncommon from the Telltale Games publishing house. Interactive dialog, simple puzzles, and many interactive objects compose gameplay.PlotEpisode 1: We Negotiate with TerroristsClapper's Wreake, England is in crisis. A terrorist has taken hostages and is picking off officers one by one. Detective Inspector Hector is the only one who can stop him; however, the sniper has a list of demands (which, surprisingly, seem to help the city). To save the hostages, Hector must complete the terrorist's demands, which consists of shutting down a porn shop, fixing a clock tower, and supporting a man trying to increase tourism. After completing the sniper's demands, Hector returns in hope of negotiating the safety of the hostages. He is able to sneak into the occupied building by pretending to deliver pizza to the hostages, but once inside, he discovers that there is no sniper, just a rifle connected to a laptop. This episode ends on a cliffhanger with the shot of a gunshot and Hector's fate unknown.Episode 2: Senseless Acts of JusticeThe second episode begins right where the first episode ended, revealing that Hector was able to avoid being shot by the laptop-controlled sniper rifle. Using various items, Hector is able to trick the sniper rifle to shoot the laptop, disabling itself. However, upon trying to leave, a number of explosives go off, crumbling the building to the ground.Episode 3: Beyond Reasonable DoomDevelopment and ReleaseHector: Badge of Carnage, developed by Straandlooper and designers Dean Burke and Kevin Beimers, was released for the iPhone on June 2, 2010. The game was planned to be a three-part episodic series. Before the release of the latter episodes, however, Straandlooper formed a partnership with Telltale Games to release their games on PC and Mac, with optimized iPad versions. The first episode was re-released for Mac and PC on April 27, 2011. An optimized iPad version is forthcoming, along with the other episodes.PC System RequirementsMinimumOperating System : Windows 7 / Vista / XPProcessor : 1.8 GHz Pentium 4 or equivalentRAM Memory: 2 GBHDD Space: 500 MB availableVideo Card : DirectX 9.0c ATI or NVidia card w / 256 MB RAM</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6049">Sam &amp; Max Save the World</game><game id="20587">Strong Bad's Cool Game for Attractive People Episode 1: Homestar Ruiner</game><game id="30622">Doctor Who: City of the Daleks</game><game id="31537">Blood of the Cybermen</game><game id="32400">Doctor Who: TARDIS</game><game id="34796">Doctor Who: Shadows of the Vashta Nerada</game><game id="32592">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 1: It's About Time</game><game id="33414">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 2: Get Tannen!</game><game id="20696">Penny Arcade Adventures: On the Rain-Slick Precipice of Darkness - Episode One</game><game id="23689">Penny Arcade Adventures: On the Rain-Slick Precipice of Darkness - Episode Two</game><game id="32796">Tales of Monkey Island</game><game id="5729">The Curse of Monkey Island</game><game id="9058">Escape from Monkey Island</game><game id="10528">Monkey Island 2:  LeChuck's Revenge</game><game id="3019">The Secret of Monkey Island</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2347656-hectorposterlg.jpg</image></root>