<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34213</id><name>The Wolf Among Us</name><description>OverviewThe Wolf Among Us is an episodic adventure game developed by Telltale Games based on the comic book series Fables by Bill Willingham. The game takes place in New York City prior to the events of the comics and follows Fables protagonist Bigby Wolf.DevelopmentOriginally announced in 2011 with a planned release date of the first quarter of 2012. It was delayed twice, in part because of the success of Telltale's The Walking Dead game. Telltale have stated that they incorporated more elements of player choice into The Wolf Among Us due to its success in The Walking Dead.StoryEpisode 1: FaithThe first episode revolves around the murder of a lesser known Fable calling herself Faith. Bigby Wolf takes up the investigation, with some help from Snow White, chasing several suspects, among them his old arch nemesis The Woodsman.Episode 2: Smoke and MirrorsEpisode 3: A Crooked MileEpisode 4: In Sheep's ClothingEpisode 5: Cry WolfSystem RequirementsPCMinimumOS: XP Service Pack 3Processor: 2.0 GHz Pentium 4 or equivalentMemory: 3 GB RAMGraphics: ATI or NVidia card w/ 512 MB RAM (Not recommended for Intel integrated graphics)DirectX: Version 9.0cHard Drive: 2 GB available spaceSound Card: Direct X 9.0c sound deviceRecommendedOS: Windows 7Processor: Core 2 Duo 2GHz or equivalentMemory: 3 GB RAMGraphics: ATI or NVidia card w/ 1024 MB RAM (Not recommended for Intel integrated graphics)DirectX: Version 9.0cHard Drive: 2 GB available spaceSound Card: Direct X 9.0c sound deviceMacMinimumOS: Snow Leopard (10.6.X)Processor: 2.3 Ghz IntelMemory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: 512 MB NVidia or ATI graphics cardHard Drive: 2 GB available spaceAdditional Notes: Not recommended for Intel integrated graphics or Mac Minis or early-generation MacBookRecommendedOS: Snow Leopard (10.6.X)Processor: Core 2 Duo 2GHzMemory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: 1024 MB NVidia or ATI graphics cardHard Drive: 2 GB available spaceAdditional Notes: Not recommended for Intel integrated graphics or Mac Minis or early-generation MacBooks</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="34205">The Walking Dead</game><game id="2494">Indigo Prophecy</game><game id="38541">Beyond: Two Souls</game><game id="21304">Heavy Rain</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2560206-box_twau.png</image></root>