<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34292</id><name>B.U.T.T.O.N. (Brutally Unfair Tactics Totally OK Now)</name><description>OverviewDeveloped by Copenhagen Game Collective and released on February 28th 2011 Brutally Unfair Tactics Totally OK Now was released as an   Xbox Live Indie Game on   Xbox Live Marketplace and   PC. It supports 2-8 players.  Brutally Unfair Tactics Totally OK Now was nominated as a finalist for a Nuovo Award   at the 13th Annual    Independent Games Festival  in 2011 . GameplayIn Brutally Unfair Tactics Totally OK Now the objective is to reach your button first. The button is located on the Xbox 360 Controller or the   keyboard for the PC version. It is possible for 4 players to play using one controller or 8 people if they use 2 controllers. The game will display various rules for each round but not actually keep track of whether the players obey these rule or not. This is not looked at as a shortcoming, but as a feature as it is up to the players to decide whether to play by the rules or not. The game has many different rules eg: slow-motion, pose like a ninja,  jump up and down like a monkey and many more. Different VersionsBrutally Unfair Tactics Totally OK Now currently comes in 3 different version.   The Xbox 360 VersionThe   Xbox 360 version is considered an older version of the game, though the developers have said it might get updated in the future. It features an optional Adult/Naughty Mode. Steam VersionThe   Steam version of Brutally Unfair Tactics Totally OK Now features   Steam Achievements. This version, however, does not include the Adult/Naughty mode. Non-Steam PC VersionThe non-Steam PC version of  Brutally Unfair Tactics Totally OK Now has no achievements, however it does include the Adult/Naughty mode.  Soundtrack The soundtrack for  Brutally Unfair Tactics Totally OK Now was composed by Nicklas "Nifflas" Nygren and features 11 tracks.  Track listing 01. Brutally Unfair Tactics02. This Might Hurt a Little03. Kissing Another Player04. Now Make a Run For It05. Intermission06. Dancy Round07. Pre-Apocalyptic08. Gameplay Gone Wrong09. The Legend of the Friendly Round10. Amorphous Bewilderment11. Evil Game Developer Villains</description><genres /><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3661/1722113-capture.png</image></root>