<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34304</id><name>Iron Brigade</name><description>OverviewA Mobile Trench.Iron Brigade (formerly Trenched) is a co-operative mech combat/tower defense game developed by Double Fine Productions that pits players in powerful, hulking bipedal tanks called "Mobile Trenches" up against machines made out of television parts called " Monovisions" (because there's only one channel). The four-player game proceeds in waves and is a split between Trench combat and some tower-defense-like turret placement. Turrets and other objects can be placed around the map and upgraded. Players spend scrap -- broken TVs that pop out of enemies when they're defeated -- to build additional turrets. The game was developed using a version of the same technology behind Brütal Legend and was published by Microsoft in the United States on June 22, 2011.GameplayGameplay in Iron Brigade consists of two primary activities. The first is building and maintaining defence structures to protect the base, as in a tower defence game. The second is actively combating enemy waves by taking direct control of a Trench and fending them off. Effective gameplay requires both elements be used in tandem, with defensive turrets placed in positions to assist the players as they fight off the encroaching enemies. A matchmaking system which supports public, friend, and party play allows for up to four players to cooperatively play the game's missions with each other online.There are fifteen levels which are evenly distributed between Europe, Africa, and the Pacific, each composed of four missions followed by a boss fight.As players progress, they gain levels and earn items on the battlefield. Money earned from missions and by completing challenges can be spent in the store. Items can be used to customize the player's Trenches. Players are also able to customize their player characters.StoryTwo war time codebreakers, Frank Woodruff and Vladamir Farnsworth, receive an alien transmission-- referred to only as "the Broadcast." The other codebreakers who heard it had their brains fried, but Frank and Vlad gained superintelligence from it. Frank goes on to make robot legs for war time heroes so they can be mobile after the war, while Vlad invents the television years ahead of its proper time, and becomes obsessed with networking the world. He releases robots made of said television tubes to lay cables across the world to network the entire planet.In Europe, Frank discovers that the robots, dubbed Monovisions, have begun destroying everything that lies in the path of the cables they wish to lie, regardless of the cost in Human lives. When all traditional military forces are defeated, Frank expands the scope of his robot legs project to create enormous bipedal war platforms, designed so that each soldier is protected by his own "mobile trench". Using these Trenches, Frank leads the battle against the Monovisions, and manages to gain a foothold against the "tube" invasion. Gaining back ground, along with new intel, the newly-christened Mobile Trench Brigade pushes onward until they have enough leverage to commence an attack on what seems to be the source of the Broadcast by destroying a Pylon in the northern region. Successfully neutralizing it, a greater truth is revealed upon the discovery of a much larger cable which leads underseas towards Africa, which has now been entirely taken over by the Tubes, while the Brigade was focused on the battle elsewhere.Suspecting that the Pylon in Europe was a product of some greater entity, Frank's outfit follows the cable south to Africa and begins to take back land starting in the desert, beginning with a small-yet-inhabitable oasis. After reclaiming more ground, another attempt at penetrating enemy forces is made by acquiring much more powerful firepower with a ship's cannon, and deploying a giant bomb underground in order to disrupt the Tube infrastructure. Successfully crippling most of the opposition, Vlad's newest behemoth creation lies in wait: a massive worm-like Monovision referred to as the Guardian. Upon taking Farnsworth's desert fortress and defeating the Guardian, a final push is initiated in order to track down Vlad once and for all.The Brigade returns to the Pacific region, where Frank first met Vlad twenty years prior to the current engagement. Frank discovers that Vlad has been searching for the origin of the Broadcast as well, in his obsession of understanding and controlling the Tubes. The Brigade subsequently gathers necessary equipment in the region (some which has been left behind by Vlad), in order to assemble and operate the technology which will help discern Vlad's location. After using the top of a volcano to generate a signal which pinpoints Farnsworth, the Brigade confronts him for a final showdown.Vlad's obsession with the Monovisions and the Broadcast have helped him to assimilate a monstrous alien machine, which he hopes to use to destroy the Brigade, and all others who resist, but it is no match for the quick-witted Trench pilots of the Brigade. After the destruction of this robot, Vlad's corpse is retrieved from inside it; his body has withered away and atrophied from all the time spent exposing himself to the tubes. Frank wonders what fate awaits him, as he reflects on the consequences Vlad had incurred, and notes that while the battle was won, he is not sure the war is over.CustomizationThe player has the ability to fully customize their Mobile Trench unit, from weapons to body types, all the way down to legs. Each Part has different stats that can effect how the player can effect the battle field. A player may want to go full engineer and place lots of turrets or go full force with a Trench capable of 3 weapon slots on each side. Players have many choices when it comes to taking on the Monovisions.The weapon categories the player can choose from include machine guns, shotguns, grenade launchers, sniper cannons, artillery cannons, and broadcasters. Machine guns are ideal for close to medium range combat with many smaller enemies and ones with the flak ability are used against aerial enemies. Shotguns are primarily used in short range situations with fewer, stronger enemies. Grenade launchers are an explosive class used to disperse clustered groups and targets with additional armor. Sniper cannons deal with threats that are farther away or ones that require additional accuracy and high amounts of damage. Artillery cannons are mainly used to take the armor off of breakers but can be used on all enemies somewhat effectively. Finally, broadcasters are used to absolutely destroy enemies up close (excellent against the knobs).The player can buy items in the shop. Or get lucky and get them as drops in the missions.Marine Items (Hat)RankItem NameCost1PSI GogglesChallenge Reward2Chemical Mask$1002Private Helmet$1002Trench Pot$1003Trench Helmet$3003Sailor Hat$2004HeadsetChallenge Reward4Sergeant CapChallenge Reward4Blast CapChallenge Reward4Bowler Hat$3004Standard Helmet$4005Pith Helmet$5005Desert Hat$5006Red BandanaChallenge Reward6Flight HelmetChallenge Reward7SunglassesChallenge Reward8Gas Mask$9008Tiki MaskChallenge Reward9Special Forces Mask$1,20010Dress HatChallenge Reward10Top Hat$10,000Marine Items (Outfit)RankItem NameCost1Standard UniformDefault1Raz SweaterChallenge Reward2Battle Shirt$2002Anchor Shirt$3003Overalls$2003Military Coat$2004Field Officer JacketChallenge Reward4Flak Jacket$5005Trench ArmorChallenge Reward5Special Forces JacketChallenge Reward5Bomber JacketChallenge Reward5Ghillie SuitChallenge Reward5Hunter JacketChallenge Reward6Radio JacketChallenge Reward7Regiment Coat$70010Dress UniformChallenge Reward10Tuxedo$20,000TBDAviator JacketChallenge RewardTBDRipped ShirtChallenge RewardCore Items (Chassis)RankItem NameChassis TypeSlots (L x R)ArmorSpeedCost1Woodruff Mk IStandard2 x 23030$4001McGarry Mk IAssault3 x 24818$5001Selker Mk IEngineering1 x 12522$4002Selker Mk IIEngineering1 x 13022$7002Woodruff Mk IIStandard2 x 23620$6003Karlsson Mk IAssault3 x 36918$1,2005Selker Mk IIIEngineering1 x 13622$1,,4005Karlsson Mk IIAssault3 x 38318$1,,8005Hamer Mk IStandard3 x 05220$1,4005Honeychurch Mk IEngineering2 x 03622$1,0005Woodruff Mk IIIStandard2 x 25220$1,0006McGarry Mk IIAssault3 x 26918$1,0006Hamer Mk IIStandard3 x 06220$2,1006Honeychurch Mk IIEngineering2 x 04422$1,6007McGarry Mk IIIAssault3 x 210018TBD7Hamer Mk IIIStandard3 x 07520TBD7Honeychurch Mk IIIEngineering2 x 06322TBD7Karlsson Mk IIIAssault3 x 310018$2,4008Woodruff Mk IVStandard2 x 27520TBD910Selker Mk IVKarlsson Mk IVEngineeringAssault1 x 13 x 3521142218TBDTBDCore Items (Paintjob)RankItem NameCost1Olive Paintjob$1003Blue Paintjob$3003Urban Paintjob$4004Red Paintjob$4004Gray Paintjob$4005Splinter Paintjob$5005Desert Camo Paintjob$5006Yellow Paintjob$6006Black PaintjobChallenge Reward7Lozenge Reward$7008Jungle Camo Paintjob$8009Dazzle PaintjobChallenge Reward10Bling PaintjobChallenge RewardCore Items (Legs)RankItem NameAbilityCost1Biped LegsNone$3002Sprinting Biped LegsSprint$5002Quickload Tripod LegsQuickload$6004Quadruped LegsSmash$9004Standard Tripod LegsFortify/Quickload$9005Stunning LegsStun Smash$1,4005Speedy Biped LegsSprint+$1,0006Defensive Tripod LegsFortify++$1,3007Advanced Tripod LegsFortify+/QuickloadTBD7Hot PantsExplosive SprintTBD7Long Stunning LegsStun Smash+$1,6008SmashersSmash++TBDLegal Troubles and Re-brandingUpon its initial North American release, Iron Brigade was originally entitled Trenched. However, the subsequent release of the game in Europe met with a legal battle regarding trademark conflict. The trademark to the name "Trench" is currently held by the creator of a World War I-inspired board game registered in Portugal. Due to the way European law works, the trademark also covers basic variants on the title, giving the board game creator the rights to the name "Trenched" as well. Various trademark agreements in place between the European Union countries mean that the trademark ownership is extended throughout most of the European region.Microsoft chose to avoid a legal battle by releasing Trenched under the name "Iron Brigade" in Europe. However, due to embarrassing coding issues within Xbox Live, this change to the game made it incompatible for multiplayer games with the North American version, Trenched. On September 9th, 2011, Brad Muir regretfully announced that the game would be renamed Iron Brigade across all regions. An updated version of the game was later released in North America with the Iron Brigade name.DLCThe first and last DLC pack for Iron Brigade, "Rise of the Martian Bear," includes a horde mode, as well as new weapons and costumes, some of which are from Double Fine's other downloadable games, Costume Quest and Stacking. Most importantly, it continues the story of Iron Brigade, in which it is discovered that Vlad's death triggered a program in which an electronic copy of his mind was downloaded into the brain of his pet bear, who now attempts to rebuild Vlad's Tube empire on the foreign soil of the planet Mars, where it will not be disturbed by pesky Humans until it is too late for them to stop him. The Mobile Trench Brigade responds by reverse-engineering Monovision technology to make their mobile command base space-worthy, and blasts off to Mars to take the fight to the Martian Bear.PC VersionAfter less-than-subtle teases during visits to the Giant Bomb offices earlier in the year, Brad Muir officially announced on August 6th, 2012, via the Double Fine website, that Iron Brigade would at last leave its XBLA trenches and make an assault on PCs via Steam. This version includes the "Rise of the Martian Bear" DLC for free.PC System RequirementsSystem: Windows XP / Windows Vista / Windows 7Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo at 2 GHz, or AMD Athlon 64 at 2 GHzMemory: 1GBVideo Card: 256 MB NVidia 8800+, ATI 3850+Sound Card: DirectX Compatible Sound CardHard disk: 1.8 GB</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17438">MechAssault</game><game id="17861">MechAssault 2: LoneWolf</game><game id="16018">MechWarrior 2: Ghost Bear's Legacy</game><game id="19719">Chromehounds</game><game id="13931">MechWarrior</game><game id="16656">Armored Core</game><game id="4609">Armored Core 2: Another Age</game><game id="26008">Front Mission Evolved</game><game id="34811">Sanctum</game><game id="28325">Toy Soldiers</game><game id="35786">Tower Defense: Lost Earth</game><game id="32695">Steel Battalion: Heavy Armor</game><game id="33593">Dungeon Defenders: First Wave</game><game id="34265">Orcs Must Die!</game><game id="2962">Earthsiege 2</game><game id="6232">Metaltech: Earthsiege</game><game id="13820">Starsiege</game><game id="35613">Defenders of Ardania</game><game id="37860">Orcs Must Die! 2</game><game id="32474">Dungeon Defenders</game><game id="37420">Sanctum 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2092592-box_ib.png</image></root>