<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34507</id><name>Red Dead Redemption: Undead Nightmare</name><description>On November 23rd, 2010, Rockstar released Red Dead Redemption: Undead Nightmare to retail stores in North America. The European version came out on November 26th, 2010. The Undead Nightmare retail disc contained all non-free DLC along with the original Free Roam Multiplayer mode as a standalone disc. Also included is a foldout poster with Undead Nightmare artwork with a map of the game world on the other side that reflects the Zombie invasion.In-Game Content:Liars and CheatsLegends and KillersUndead NightmareOriginal Red Dead Redemption Free-Roam Multiplayer (Standalone)CompatibilityYou don't have to own or have played the original Red Dead Redemption to be able to play this standalone Undead Nightmare-disc content. If, however, you already have played the game and its multiplayer, your online-progress carries over into Undead Nightmare. Challenge stats, character level, playtime data, and all other stats are imported from your save file. The free DLC - "Outlaws to the End Co-Op" and "Hunters and Traders" pack are also compatible with Undead Nightmare, as well.To ensure compatibility, make sure that you do not mix regions (i.e.: North American Red Dead Redemption and European Undead Nightmare). The different European releases (BBFC, PEGI, USK) appear to be compatible with each other. For example, the PS3 version of Undead Nightmare from the UK (BBFC 18 rating, BLES Code 01179) works with a previously installed Red Dead Redemption from France (PEGI 18 rating, BLES Code 00680). And since both discs also carry the German USK 18 rating logo, compatibility to the German version can be considered a given.Whether or not releases from different regions are compatible with each other is unknown but highly unlikely.InstallThe PS3 version of Undead Nightmare requires a minumum 2427MB install and stacks on top of previous Red Dead Redemption trophy data.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="32431">Dead State</game><game id="34088">State of Decay</game><game id="36304">inFamous: Festival of Blood</game><game id="31992">Yakuza: Dead Souls</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3699/1790555-red_dead_redemption___undead_nightmare_cover.jpg</image></root>