<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34553</id><name>Resident Evil: Operation Raccoon City</name><description>OverviewResident Evil: Operation Raccoon City is a multiplayer team-based third-person shooter developed by Slant Six and published by Capcom for the PC, Xbox 360, and PlayStation 3 on March 20, 2012. Set during and between the events of Resident Evil 2 and Resident Evil 3: Nemesis, players take on the role as commandos belonging to one of two opposing factions: the Umbrella Security Service (U.S.S.) or the U.S. Special Forces (Spec Ops), as they battle through the zombie-infested Raccoon City.StoryLeon's back!The game is set in the original 1998 Raccoon City zombie outbreak, where three factions, the USS from Umbrella, Spec Ops operating on behalf of the U.S. government, and Umbrella's now-unleashed bio-organic weapons (B.O.W.s) are fighting each other. Umbrella are out to destroy any and all evidence of their illegal activities and are to kill any outbreak survivors (including such high-profile characters like Leon Kennedy) who could potentially leak any harmful intel against Umbrella, while the government is there to find out who is behind the catastrophic outbreak. The B.O.W.s, meanwhile, are out to destroy and/or devour everything in sight. The story of REORC cannot be considered canon, at least in its entirety, as it is possible for players to choose whether to kill or save key characters of the series. However, REORC does feature many of the canon events of Resident Evil 2 and Resident Evil 3.Players experience the game's story through the eyes of the USS agents Vector, Beltway, Bertha, Spectre, Four-Eyes and Lupo, while in the competitive multiplayer modes, players are randomly assigned to either the U.S.S team or the opposing Spec Ops team.Other familiar RE2/RE3 characters, including Nemesis, William Birkin and Nicholai Ginovaef play roles in the story as well.GameplayAnother familiar faceResident Evil: Operation Raccoon City is a third person shooter with an emphasis on 4-player cooperative teamwork and online play, as popularized by Left 4 Dead. Though multiplayer is the recommended way to play, the main campaign can still be played offline with three other AI characters. In addition to Campaign mode, which is the only cooperative mode of play, there are four competitive modes for online play: Team Attack, Biohazard, Survivor, and Heroes (see below for mode descriptions).Following up from Resident Evil games such Outbreak File #2, Mercenaries 3D and Revelations, players can shoot/aim and move around at the same time, as well as run while reloading. The game also has a cover mechanic and overall plays very similarly to titles from the SOCOM franchise; Slant Six Games developed SOCOM: Confrontation.Like in other recent games in the RE series, the camera follows your character with an over-the-shoulder view. Entering aiming mode with a gun makes the camera zoom in while keeping the character's head still in view on the side of the screen, unless the weapon has a scope in which case a screen-filling scoped view appears. Each playable character has a unique and devastating melee finishing move and five unique abilities that can be unlocked and upgraded. Health in Operation Raccoon City does not regenerate--instead you must find and use Green Herbs or First Aid Sprays scattered around the maps.Each time a zombie bites a character, there is a chance of that character contracting the zombie infection. When a character becomes infected, their health begins rapidly draining away. If an infected player dies, they player loses all control of their character as it rapidly mutates into a feral zombie and attacks their surviving teammates, forcing former comrades to gun it down to survive. The only way to cure infection before death is using an Antiviral Spray, which can be found just like First Aid Sprays scattered about maps.There are two playable opposing factions in the game, the USS and Spec-Ops, as well as hordes of zombies who attack everyone. Many maps feature all three of these side fighting warring at once. Each of the two factions has a squad of six different playable characters. You start off each match by choosing a character, one of that character's active abilities, a primary weapon, and a sidearm. Each character has two passive abilities (such as faster movement speed) that are always in effect while playing as that character and three active abilities (such as planting a trip mine), but only one active ability can be equipped at a time. Any character can equip any primary weapon and sidearm, as long as you have unlocked them.Completing games in both campaign mode (singleplayer and co-op) and versus mode (online competitive) earns you experience points which form a simple persistent leveling system for unlocking new weapons and character abilities. The XP works as a universal currency in the game and is not character- or gamemode-specific. You initially only have four primary weapons (out of 20 total) and one sidearm (out of five total) unlocked to use. Each character can equip any weapon that you have yet unlocked without restriction. All characters begin with all of their five unique abilities locked. After being unlocked, each ability can be further upgraded two more times to incrementally increase its effects.CharactersU.S.S.Operation Raccoon city has 2 different factions you can play as: The Umbrella Security Service or USS and the U.S. Spec Ops. Bio-Organic Weapons also patrol the levels as a hostile third faction towards both the U.S.S and the U.S Spec Ops teams.Umbrella Security ServicesPortraitCharacter ProfileName: VectorClass: ReconOfficial Bio: Vector's file remains largely confidential, his true identity hidden. Training at Rockfort island he developed his lethal martial art ability and elite skill for reconnaissance. As a covert operative, his achievements in-the-field are only matched by his former master, HUNK.Passive AbilitiesActive AbilitiesStealth Run - Increases movement speed and lessens the sound emitted from footsteps.Detection Avoidance - Allows the player to avoid being detected on the minimap when moving at less than 50% speed.Motion Detector - Gives the player a motion detector that can stick to any surface and display enemies on the minimap.Mimicry - Allows the player to mimic enemy Spec Ops NPCs and players for a limited time.Active Camouflage - Allows the player to turn temporarily invisible to players and most B.O.Ws.PortraitCharacter ProfileName: BeltwayClass: DemolitionsOfficial Bio: Hector 'Beltway' Hivers is an elite demolition expert that was discharged from the Army Corps of Engineers. Not much is known about the incident other than the addition of Beltway's prosthetic leg. His dedication to his craft is beyond question, while his joy for blowing things up is always visible.Passive AbilitiesActive AbilitiesBlast Armor - Prevents the player from being knocked down by explosives and increases overall resistance to explosives.Blast Master - Reduces ability cool-down time.Fragmentation Mine - Plants a manually detonated mine.Timed Sticky Explosive - Allows the player to throw an explosive sticky mine that'll automatically detonate after an allotted amount of time.Laser Trip Mine - Plants a laser trip mine that'll explode should an enemy player trigger the laser.PortraitCharacter ProfileName: BerthaClass: MedicOfficial Bio: Michaela 'BERTHA' Schneider finds a pleasure in pain. After an unsuccessful return to civilian life, this discipled former soldier with a devotion to medicine eagerly joined Wolfpack as their medic when she was assured anesthetic would be considered a luxury and not a priority.Passive AbilitiesActive AbilitiesFirst-Aid Proficiency - Allows the player to spawn with a first-aid spray and increases overall first-aid spray carrying capacity.Field Medic - Increases the efficiency of both herbs and first-aid sprays.Stimpack - Gives the player a hypo gun which can be used to temporarily increase other players, or their own, overall accuracy and movement speed.Neutralize Infection - Gives the player a hypo gun which can be used to remedy other players, or their own, T-Virus infection.Painkiller - Gives the player a hypo gun which can be used to temporarily increase other players, or their own, damage resistance.PortraitCharacter ProfileName: SpectreClass: SurveillanceOfficial Bio: A veteran of the Cold War, former spy, Vladimir 'Spectre' Bodrovski was moved from Umbrella's European win for unknwon reasons. The premier surveillance expert of the U.S.S., he was transferred to Wolfpack when the upper echelon of Umbrella management realized his skills could greatly benefit them.Passive AbilitiesActive AbilitiesProximity Detection - Increases the size of player's minimap and automatically reveals players within a set proximity on their minimap.Item Detection - Allows the player to see items within a set proximity on their minimap.Threat Scanner - Allows the player to scan for enemy players within a set proximity; any players that are picked up, both enemy and friendly, are permanently placed on the player's minimap until they die.Biothermal Vision - Allows the player to temporarily see enemies, both Spec Ops and B.O.Ws, at a greater distance within a set proximity.Sonar Vision - Allows the player to temporarily see both allies and enemies through walls.PortraitCharacter ProfileName: Four-EyesClass: Field ScientistOfficial Bio: Developing an unhealthy obsession with science at a young age, Christine 'Four-Eyes' Yamata specializing in virology. She is so deeply focused on her work, that she has little interest in anything else, including the feelings, or lives, of other human beings. Studious and detailed, she always wants to know more about a given situation.Passive AbilitiesActive AbilitiesAntiviral Proficiency - Allows the player to spawn with an antiviral spray and increases overall antiviral spray carrying capacity.Biometric Vision - Allows the player to see B.O.Ws and infected players at an increased distance.Induce Infection - Gives the player a hypo gun which can be used to potentially infect an enemy player or turn a regular zombie into a Crimson Head.Attraction Pheromone - Gives the player a grenade which can be used to lure B.O.Ws to a specific location.Program Infected - Gives the player a hypo gun that can be used to make an ally out of a B.O.W of their choice (including Tyrants).PortraitCharacter ProfileName: L upoClass: AssaultOfficial Bio: A former French Special Forces Op. Karena 'Lupo' Lesproux specializes in weapons. Lured by money, Lupo joined the Umbrella and leads Wolfpack. Her knowledge in the field makes her highly trusted by her team. She looks out for them, like a wolf looks out for her cubs, which has made the team affectionately call her ''Wolf Mother''.Passive AbilitiesActive AbilitiesBody Armor - Reduces overall damage taken.Quick Reload - Reduces time to reload weapons.Incendiary Rounds - Temporarily allows the player to shoot incendiary rounds with any weapon.Guns A' Blazin' - Temporarily gives the player infinite ammo for all weapons.Super Soldier - Nullifies so much damage before it wears off and increases overall weapon accuracy for a set time.U.S. Spec-OpsPortraitCharacter ProfileName: DeeAyClass: AssaultOfficial Bio: Crispin 'Dee-Ay' Jettingham has been a soldier for as long as he can remember. He was the government's top choice to be the leader of Echo Six Team. Always calm and collected, he is a true soldier and is highly skilled and efficient with his weaponry and orders.Passive AbilitiesActive AbilitiesBody Armor - Reduces overall damage taken.Quick Reload - Reduces time to reload weaponsIncendiary Rounds - Temporarily allows the player to shoot incendiary rounds with any weapon.Guns A' Blazin' - Temporarily gives the player infinite ammo for all weapons.Super Soldier - Nullifies so much damage before it wears off and increases overall weapon accuracy for a set time.PortraitCharacter ProfileName: Party GirlClass: SurveillanceOfficial Bio: Sienna 'Party Girl' Fowler got her reputation throwing wild parties in her youth for businessmen and officials. Little did they know that every party she threw was also recorded with hidden equipment, which would be sold to the highest bidder. The Government hired her after she managed to dupe their top surveillance expert at one of her parties.Passive AbilitiesActive AbilitiesProximity Detection - Increases the size of player's minimap and automatically reveals players within a set proximity on their minimap.Item Detection - Allows the player to see items within a set proximity on their minimap.Threat Scanner - Allows the player to scan for enemy players within a set proximity; any players that are picked up, both friendly and enemy, are permanently placed on the player's minimap until they die.Biothermal Vision - Allows the player to temporarily see enemies, both Spec Ops and B.O.Ws, at a greater distance within a set proximity.Sonar Vision - Allows the player to temporarily see both allies and enemies through walls.PortraitCharacter ProfileName: ShonaClass: Field ScientistOfficial Bio: Exposed to death at a young age, Lawrence 'Shona' Kimbala began treating diseases in his home country of Zimbabwe. After his father's death, he attended Harvard medical school where he realized he had a skill for controlling viruses instead of curing them. He joined the army's special weapons program as their foremost expert in virology.Passive AbilitiesActive AbilitiesAntiviral Proficiency - Allows the player to spawn with an antiviral spray and increases overall antiviral spray carrying capacity.Biometric Vision - Allows the player to see B.O.Ws and infected players at an increased distance.Induce Infection - Gives the player a hypo gun which can be used to potentially infect an enemy player or turn a regular zombie into a Crimson Head zombie.Attraction Pheromone - Gives the player a grenade which can be used to lure B.O.Ws to a specific location.Program Infected - Gives the player a hypo gun that can be used to control a B.O.W of their choice (including Tyrant).PortraitCharacter ProfileName: WillowClass: ReconOfficial Bio: Caroline 'Willow' Floyd developed her skill for speed and elusion growing up alone on a reservation in Montana. She joined the Army straight out of school, excelling as part of the Special Forces. Never satisfied with herself, Willow continues to hone her skills each and every day.Passive AbilitiesActive AbilitiesStealth Run - Increases movement speed and lessens the sound emitted from footsteps.Detection Avoidance - Allows the player to avoid being detected on the minimap when moving at less than 50% speed.Motion Detector - Gives the player a motion detector that can stick to any surface and display enemies on the minimap.Mimicry - Allows the player to mimic enemy USS NPCs and players.Active Camouflage - Allows the player to turn temporarily invisible to enemy players and most B.O.Ws.PortraitCharacter ProfileName: HarleyClass: MedicOfficial Bio: A foul-mouthed ex-biker, Erez 'Harley' Morris joined the service to avoid going to jail. Excelling in medicine during operation Desert Storm, Harley unexpectedly became one of the best medics in the field. Always putting other peoples lives before his, he will always do his best to make sure no man is left behind.Passive AbilitiesActive AbilitiesFirst-Aid Proficiency - Allows the player to spawn with a first-aid spray and increases overall first-aid spray carrying capacity.Field Medic - Increases the efficiency of both herbs and first-aid sprays.Stimpack - Gives the player a hypo gun which can be used to temporarily increase other players, or their own, overall accuracy and movement speed.Neutralize Infection - Gives the player a hypo gun which can be used to remedy other players, or their own, T-Virus infection.Painkiller - Gives the player a hypo gun which can be used to temporarily increase other players, or their own, damage resistance.PortraitCharacter ProfileName: TweedClass: DemolitionsOfficial Bio: Marissa 'Tweed' Ronson has a quick tongue and a ready fuse. Originally working for the British Secret Service, she disappeared after a bomb removal operation left her scarred. Hand-picked by the Government, Tweed became a part of Echo Six because of her unparalleled expertise in demolitions.Passive AbilitiesActive AbilitiesBlast Armor - Prevents the player from being knocked down by explosions and increases overall damage resistance to explosives.Blast Master - Reduces ability cool-down time.Fragmentation Mine - Plants a manually detonated mine.Timed Sticky Explosive - Allows the player to throw an explosive sticky mine that'll automatically detonate within an allotted time.Laser Trip Mine - Plants a trip mine that'll explode should an enemy player trigger the laser.DLCEcho Six Expansion Pack - A free additional cooperative campaign mission where players take up the roles of the Spec Ops team instead.Nemesis Mode - Day one DLC, exclusive to the 360 version, Nemesis Mode plays similarly to a regular Team Deathmatch, only it is now possible for each team to find the Nemesis control unit and awaken him. This then allows Nemesis to follow as a friendly and attack the opposing team.Competitive ModesTeam AttackThe two teams of four (U.S.S. vs Spec Ops) fight through regions of Raccoon City, competing for points earned by killing powerful B.O.W.s and members of the enemy team. It's basically score-driven team deathmatch with zombies everywhere.BiohazardThe two teams of four attempt to seek out, capture, and then escort samples of the G-Virus back to their allocated base. In other words, it's one-flag capture the flag.SurvivorsIn this mode, eight players across both teams of four must fight to survive against an endless stream of zombies and other B.O.W.s for 10 minutes, at which point the extraction chopper will finally arrive. Only problem is, it's only got room for four, so it's going to be a less than friendly contest for seats. For some reason, the four seats can be taken by a mixture of players from the two teams, who instantly become friendly with each other once seated.Heroes Multiplayer ModeThe heroesIn Heroes mode, each team starts the match with all four players playing as hero characters, as listed below, instead of the normal USS or Spec Ops characters described above. Each hero has its own unique combination of existing class abilities and much more health than any of the usual characters. When a player dies as their hero, they can only respawn as a normal USS/Spec Ops character from then until the end of the match. The first team to lose all four of its heroes loses the match.The Spec Ops team heroes:Leon S KennedyClaire RedfieldCarlos OliveiraJill ValentineThe USS team heroes:H.U.N.KLone Wolf (a new character introduced in Operation: Raccoon City)Ada WongNicholai GinovaefSpecial EditionOperation Raccoon City also features a special edition, which includes the usual assortment of additions for an increased price. Minus the full game, which also comes in a steel case, the special edition is packaged with:An alternate costume for each of the six USS members.Eight additional weapons unlocked from the outset.USS and US Spec Ops embroidered patches.</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26532">Aliens vs. Predator</game><game id="16068">Aliens Versus Predator 2: Primal Hunt</game><game id="1503">Aliens Versus Predator 2</game><game id="7140">Aliens Versus Predator</game><game id="30196">SOCOM 4: U.S. Navy SEALs</game><game id="20676">SOCOM: U.S. Navy SEALs - Confrontation</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2193301-box_reocr.png</image></root>