<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34614</id><name>Guerrilla Bob</name><description>Overview   Guerrilla Bob fights his way through 7 levels of bad guys to get revenge on John Gore, a school friend that took on a life of crime when he parted ways with Bob. Modes  Single PlayerArcade Story mode - Bob fights for fame, collecting medals as he goesMercenary Story mode - Bob fights for money, collecting it from his dead enemies bodies Classic Survival mode - Bob fights off endless enemies coming at him from all directions Wave Attack mode - Bob fights wave after wave of bad guys, stopping to shop for guns and upgrades between waves  Multiplayer Guerrilla Bob supports  cross-platform multiplayer on a local Wi-fi connection as well as  split-screen multiplayer on the iPad HD version.Weapons     The game is available on Android marketplace, the Apple App store and the Mac App store. A free version is available on the iPhone as well as an HD version for iPad (supporting 2 player split-screen). Angry mob Games is rumoured to be releasing a PC version in the near future  Weapons and their corresponding upgrades can either be found along the way during the arcade story or purchased in the store between levels in the mercenary story. Bob can utilize any of the following weapons:  Machine Gun Timed Bombs Molotov Cocktails Shotgun Double Uzis Flamethrower Rocket Launcher Grenade Launcher Sticky Bow Chaingun       Updates iOS  1.40 - "Play a multiplayer game using a Personal Hotspot!"- Fixed server discovery issues.- Added an option to manual connect to the server.       1.31 - Play CO-OP on local Wi-Fi networks: connect together your iPhone, iPod, iPad or Mac - Retina Display support - Fast App Switching - Game Center support - Improved controls - Various game balance tweaks- New playable characters: Rob McBang and Santa Bob      Android1.1.1      - More improvements   -  The back button now navigates through menus as in other apps - The menu button now brings up the pause menu </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25841">Zombie Apocalypse</game><game id="6823">Apocalypse</game><game id="16194">Smash TV</game><game id="20715">Rocket Riot</game><game id="29061">Minigore</game><game id="29991">Age of Zombies</game><game id="25415">Dracula - Undead Awakening</game><game id="38099">Tiny Troopers</game><game id="42727">Muffin Knight</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/12/125537/1748361-giant_bomb_sub_2.jpg</image></root>