<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34622</id><name>Spider-Man: Edge of Time</name><description>OverviewSpider-Man faces one of his greatest challenges ever: saving Spider-Man. Developed by Activision-owned studio Beenox, Spider-Man: Edge of Time challenges the player to take on the roles of both classic Amazing Spider-Man and Spider-Man 2099 to correct the timestream gone awry and prevent a catastrophic future brought on by the early death of Peter Parker. One of the game's main selling points is that actions taken by the Amazing Spider-man in the past will change things in the future of 2099 Spider-man, for better or for worse.StoryMarvel veteran Peter David (co-creator of Spider-Man 2099) is currently writing the story. From what is known, the story so far goes something like this: In the year 2099 an evil scientist, Walker Sloan, travels back in time in order to change the timeline as he sees fit. One of the changes he makes, however, is implanting a series of control chips in Anti-Venom's brain. These control chips cause the now conflicted Eddie Brock (Anti-Venom) to seek out and kill Peter Parker, also known as the Amazing Spider-Man. While trying to stop Sloan, Spider-Man 2099 is trapped in a time bubble that shields him from the changes to the timeline happening around him. As a result he can still remember the future as it should be, and after making contact with past Spidey before his death, they both try to restore order to the timeline. The player will bounce back and forth between the roles of the Amazing Spider-Man and Spider-Man 2099.GameplaySpider-Man: Edge of Time lets the player control both Spider-Man (Peter Parker) and Spider-Man from the year 2099 (Miguel O'Hara). Player's actions as Peter Parker will affect the actions of Miguel O'Hara. These consequences are shown via split-screen events where a little pop up shows what's happened in the future following what happened in the past. Choices players make in the past will affect what sort of enemies they will face and how the story will unravel in the future.Edge of Time plays much like Spider-Man Shattered Dimensions with one button for heavy attacks and one for light, quick attacks which can be chained together to create a combo. Both Spider Men can web swing and fling web at their opponents. They also both have the ability to create a time paradox which freezes in time all nearby enemies. However, both characters have unique abilities such as the ability to move at super fast speed (Spider-Man) or the ability to distract enemies by generating a clone (Spider-Man 2099).</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="32845">Captain America: Super Soldier</game><game id="24747">X-Men Origins: Wolverine</game><game id="29196">Thor: God of Thunder</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2484712-box_smeot.png</image></root>