<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34623</id><name>Death Rally</name><description>OverviewDeath Rally is a modern remake first released for iOS devices; the iPhone, iPod Touch and iPad, on March 28th 2011. It was developed by Cornfox  Brothers Ltd. and Mountain Sheep, and published by Remedy Entertainment. The original game was released in 1996 on the PC by Remedy Entertainment and Apogee Software.It's a top-down vehicular combat game where the player has to race against competitors who all have weaponized racing vehicles. Career mode features different events events and players earn achievements, cars and weapons by winning those events. The game has tracks in cities, deserts, jungles, ice ranges and mountains. Online progress is noted in leaderboards.The game was released on PC on August 3rd 2012. It supports the multiplayer game mode and players can play it with a controller.PC System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Windows XP SP2Processor: AMD K8 series, for example Athlon 64, or Intel Pentium 4Memory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: DirectX 10 compatible with 256 MB memoryDirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 600 MB HD spaceSound: DX9.0c compatibleAdditional: Even slower systems may run the game, but may have problems with multiplayer compatibilityRecommended:OS: Windows 7Processor: AMD K10 series, for example Athlon X2, or Intel Pentium Dual Core, or fasterMemory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: DirectX 10 compatible with 512 MB memory, or fasterDirectX®: 10Hard Drive: 600 MB HD spaceSound: DX9.0c compatibleOther Requirements: Broadband Internet connectionAdditional: Even slower systems may run the game, but may have problems with multiplayer compatibility</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13567">Grand Theft Auto</game><game id="12318">Twisted Metal</game><game id="18044">Death Rally</game><game id="40787">Fuel Overdose</game><game id="28960">Metal Drift</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/38405/1748101-img_0615.png</image></root>