<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34631</id><name>Take On Helicopters</name><description>OverviewThe player assumes the role of a civilian chopper pilot who is trying to maintain Harry Larkin's aviation company, despite hitting turbulent economic times. After decades in operation well-known Seattle pilot and businessman Harry Larkin has passed on, and the business he left to his sons is weeks away from being shuttered. The Larkin brothers struggle to save their father's legacy by taking on contracts and competing against other aviation companies.The game features large detailed environments based on real-world North American and South Asian terrain and highly detailed helicopter models in this open-world sandbox flight game. In addition, the game also features a level and mission editor. Downloadable ContentBohemia Interactive has released three pieces of DLC. Hinds is the first piece of DLC, for $8.99 on the Steam PC service. It introduces a variety of helicopter gunplay and gameplay. Players assume the role of pilot of the famous Hind helicopter and its several notable variants (Mil Mi-24P, Mil Mi-24V, andMil Mi-24 SueprHind MK.III). These new vehicles have interactive cockpits, retractable landing gear systems, and multiple weapon loadouts. Hinds comes with new singleplayer challenges on the battlefield, five new Time Trials, and a multiplayer death match pitting players one-on-one as either or both pilots and gunners. The second piece of DLC, named Noisecontrollers is free and contains DJ mixes from a collaboration between Noisecontrollers (Bas Oskam and Arjan Terpstra) and Bohemia Interactive, new light helicopter liveries, and 14 new tough Time Trials. New paint schemes for the Light helicopter are included in this DLC and Bas and Arjan appear as virtual characters within the game. The third piece of DLC, named Rearmed, is also free. It merges Arma 2 and Arma 2: Operation Arrowhead content into Take on Helicopters, allowing you to fly over familiar landscapes from within those games such as Chernarus, Takistan, and Utes, as well as handling incoming anti-air fire and fighting alongside armed operations. Tanks, cars, motorcycles, fixed-wing planes, helicopters, boats and other vehicles are included as well as rifles, machine guns, shotguns, sidearms, launchers, artillery, and explosives. You'll also encounter soldiers, marines, guerrillas, and civilians.  System SpecificationsMinimumOS: Windows XPProcessor: Intel Dual-Core 2.4 GHz or AMD Dual-Core Athlon 2.5 GHz or fasterMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: NVIDIA GeForce 8800GT or ATI Radeon 4850 with Shader Model 3 and 512 MB VRAM or fasterHard Drive: 20 GB HD spaceSound: DirectX 9.0c compatible audio-cardRecommendedOS: Windows Vista, Windows 7Processor: Intel Dual-Core 3GHz or AMD Dual-Core Athlon 3GHz or fasterMemory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: NVIDIA GeForce 9800GT or ATI Radeon 5850 with Shader Model 3 and 1024 MB VRAM or fasterHard Drive: 20 GB HD spaceSound: DirectX 9.0c compatible audio-card</description><genres><genre id="24">Flight Simulator</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4634">Microsoft Flight Simulator X</game><game id="2653">LHX: Attack Chopper</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5761/2005589-625930_203923_front.jpeg</image></root>