<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34710</id><name>NBA Jam: On Fire Edition</name><description>OverviewRazzle Dazzle your opponents by shooting like a child!NBA Jam: On Fire Edition is a downloadable 2-on-2 arcade basketball game developed by EA Canada and published by EA Sports for the Xbox 360 (via Xbox Live Arcade) and PlayStation 3 (via PlayStation Network) on October 4, 2011.An enhanced version of the 2010 NBA Jam, the game updates the player roster (to the 2011-2012 NBA season) while adding a new career campaign, updated player AI, new unlockable teams/players (such as the Seattle Supersonics and an EA-based team featuring Isaac from Dead Space and Faith from Mirror's Edge), and new gameplay mechanics (such as "Team Fire" from NBA Hangtime and new "Razzle Dazzle" taunting moves).On January 25 2013, the game's roster was updated to match the 2012-2013 NBA season.Game ModesRoad Trip:On Fire Edition's career mode is called Road Trip which allows players to face off against teams from all the NBA divisions. Each team has three challenge levels, bronze, silver, and gold, and players pick the order of teams they play against. Bronze challenges are simple 2v2, 4 quarter matches. Silver and gold often pit the player against "Legends" from that team, and sometimes the parameters of scoring are changed.Jam Now:This lets up to 4 players simply play a game of NBA Jam.Online Arena:This is where players can duke it out online against other Jam players.Jam Store  UnlockablesOn Fire Edition rewards players with Jam Bucks for playing in any game mode. These are spent at the Jam Store on new players, teams, player icons and titles, and new gameplay mutators (such as bighead mode).RosterStandard TeamsTeamRoster (Original)Roster (Updated)Atlanta HawksJosh SmithJoe JohnsonAl HorfordJeff TeagueSpud WebbDominique WilkinsHarry the Hawk (mascot)Josh SmithJoe JohnsonAl HorfordTracy McGradyJeff TeagueSpud WebbDominique WilkinsHarry the Hawk (mascot)Boston CelticsKevin GarnettPaul PierceRay AllenRajon RondoJeff GreenJermaine O'NealLarry BirdKevin McHaleLucky (mascot)Kevin GarnettPaul PierceRay AllenRajon RondoJermaine O'NealLarry BirdKevin McHaleLucky (mascot)Charlotte BobcatsTyrus ThomasCorey MaggetteD.J. AugustinRufus Lynx (mascot)No changesChicago BullsDerrick RoseCarlos BoozerJoakim NoahLuol DengDennis RodmanScottie PippenBenny the Bull (mascot)Derrick RoseCarlos BoozerJoakim NoahRichard HamiltonLuol DengDennis RodmanScottie PippenBenny the Bull (mascot)Cleveland CavaliersBaron DavisAntawn JamisonAnderson VarejaoMark PriceBrad DaughertyMoondog (mascot)Antawn JamisonAnderson VarejaoMark PriceBrad DaughertyMoondog (mascot)Dallas MavericksJason KiddDirk NowitzkiCaron ButlerJason TerryPeja StojakovicJ.J. BareaJamal MashburnChamp (mascot)Jason KiddDirk NowitzkiJason TerryJamal MashburnVince CarterYi JianlianLamar OdomChamp (mascot)Denver NuggetsJ.R. SmithKenyon MartinDanilo GallinariAl HarringtonDikembe MutomboRocky (mascot)Danilo GallinariAl HarringtonDikembe MutomboRocky (mascot)Detroit PistonsBen GordonTayshaun PrinceCharlie VillanuevaRodney StuckeyTracy McGradyRichard HamiltonBill LaimbeerIsiah ThomasDennis RodmanHooper (mascot)Ben GordonTayshaun PrinceCharlie VillanuevaRodney StuckeyBill LaimbeerIsiah ThomasDennis RodmanHooper (mascot)Golden State WarriorsStephen CurryMonta EllisDavid LeeAndris BiedrinsTim HardawayChris MullinStephen CurryMonta EllisDavid LeeNate RobinsonAndris BiedrinsTim HardawayChris MullinHouston RocketsKevin MartinCourtney LeeLuis ScolaYao MingHakeem OlajuwonKenny SmithClutch the Rockets Bear (mascot)No changesIndiana PacersMike Dunleavy, Jr.Danny GrangerT.J. FordRik SmitsDetlef SchrempfBoomer (mascot)David WestDanny GrangerDetlef SchrempfRik SmitsBoomer (mascot)Los Angeles ClippersBlake GriffinEric GordonRandy FoyeChris KamanMo WilliamsDanny ManningBlake GriffinChris PaulMo WilliamsRandy FoyeCaron ButlerDanny ManningChauncey BillupsLos Angeles LakersKobe BryantPau GasolDerek FisherRon ArtestLamar OdomMagic JohnsonJames WorthyKobe BryantPau GasolDerek FisherRon ArtestMagic JohnsonJames WorthyMemphis GrizzliesRudy GayO.J. MayoZach RandolphMarc GasolBryant ReevesGrizz (mascot)No changesMiami HeatLebron JamesDwyane WadeChris BoshMike BibbyGlen RiceRony SeikalyBurnie (mascot)Lebron JamesDwyane WadeChris BoshGlen RiceRony SeikalyBurnie (mascot)Milwaukee BucksBrandon JenningsAndrew BogutStephen JacksonMichael ReddBango the Buck (mascot)Brandon JenningsAndrew BogutStephen JacksonMike Dunleavy, Jr.Bango the Buck (mascot)Minnesota TimberwolvesRicky RubioKevin LoveMichael BeasleyChuck PersonCrunch the Wolf (mascot)Ricky RubioKevin LoveMichael BeasleyChuck PersonJ.J. BareaCrunch the Wolf (mascot)New Jersey JetsDeron WilliamsBrook LopezAnthony MorrowKenny AndersonDrazen PetrovicSly Fox (mascot)Deron WilliamsBrook LopezAnthony MorrowMehmet OkurKenny AndersonDrazen PetrovicSly Fox (mascot)New Orleans HornetsChris PaulCarl LandryJarrett JackTrevor ArizaDavid WestLarry JohnsonAlonzo MourningMuggsy BoguesHugo (mascot)Carl LandryEric GordonLarry JohnsonAlonzo MourningJarrett JackChris KamanTrevor ArizaMuggsy BoguesHugo (mascot)New York KnicksAmar'e StoudemireCarmelo AnthonyChauncey BillupsPatrick EwingJohn StarksAmar'e StoudemireCarmelo AnthonyMike BibbyPatrick EwingJohn StarksBaron DavisOklahoma City ThunderKevin DurantRussell WestbrookSerge IbakaNate RobinsonKendrick PerkinsRumble the Bison (mascot)Kevin DurantRussell WestbrookSerge IbakaKendrick PerkinsRumble the Bison (mascot)Orlando MagicDwight HowardJameer NelsonHedo TürkoğluGilbert ArenasJason RichardsonShaquille O'NealNick AndersonScott SkilesStuff (mascot)Dwight HowardJameer NelsonHedo TürkoğluJason RichardsonShaquille O'NealNick AndersonScott SkilesStuff (mascot)Philadelphia 76ersAndre IguodalaElton BrandEvan TurnerLou WilliamsAndrés NocioniJulius ErvingDarryl DawkinsHip Hop (mascot)No changesPhoenix SunsSteve NashGrant HillChanning FryeVince CarterDan MajerleKevin JohnsonGorilla (mascot)Steve NashGrant HillChanning FryeMichael ReddDan MajerleKevin JohnsonGorilla (mascot)Portland Trail BlazersBrandon RoyLaMarcus AldridgeGerald WallaceGreg OdenRaymond FeltonClyde DrexlerBill WaltonBlaze (mascot)Gerald WallaceLaMarcus AldridgeClyde DrexlerGreg OdenRaymond FeltonBill WaltonBlaze (mascot)Sacramento KingsTyreke EvansDeMarcus CousinsJ.J. HicksonJason ThompsonMitch RichmondSlamson (mascot)No changesSan Antonio SpursTony ParkerTim DuncanManu GinobiliDavid RobinsonGeorge GervinThe Coyote (mascot)Tony ParkerTim DuncanManu GinobiliT.J. FordDavid RobinsonGeorge GervinThe Coyote (mascot)Toronto RaptorsDeMar DerozanAndrea BargnaniVince CarterThe Raptor (mascot)DeMar DerozanAndrea BargnaniJosé CalderónVince CarterThe Raptor (mascot)Utah JazzDevin HarrisAl JeffersonMehmet OkurAndrei KirilenkoKarl MaloneJohn StocktonJazz Bear (mascot)Devin HarrisAl JeffersonJosh HowardKarl MaloneJohn StocktonJazz Bear (mascot)Washington WizardsJohn WallJaVale McGeeYi JianlianJosh HowardAndray BlatcheRashard LewisG-Wiz (mascot)John WallJaVale McGeeRashard LewisAndray BlatcheG-Wiz (mascot)Special TeamsTeamRosterSeattle SupersonicsShawn KempGary PaytonDetlef SchrempfTeam EAIsaac SecurityIsaac EliteIsaac AntiqueFaithEA Cover KingsKevin DurantDwight HowardCarmelo AnthonyDwyane WadeGilbert ArenasAthens PanathinaikosMike BatisteDimitris DiamantioisRomain SatoAntonis FotsisMaccabi ElectraDoron PerkinsLior EliyahuSofoklis SchortsanitisChuck EidsonReal MadridJosh FischerSergio LlullCarlos SuarezPablo PrigioniRain MakersSteve NashRay AllenChuck PersonDan MajerleLarry BirdFull Court PressKevin GarnettBill LaimbeerRon ArtestDennis RodmanScottie PippenDunk ChampsDwight HowardSpud WebbBlake GriffinNate RobinsonVince CarterFast BreaksChris PaulDeron WilliamsDerrick RoseKevin JohnsonMuggsy BoguesBlock PartyDikembe MutomboYao MingAlonzo MourningDavid RobinsonHakeem OlajuwonDime DroppersBrandon JenningsJohn StocktonRajon RondoMagic JohnsonMark PriceBeastie BoysMike DAd-RockMCADemocratsBarack ObamaHillary ClintonBill ClintonAl GoreJoe BidenRepublicansJohn McCainGeorge BushSarah PalinDick CheneyAngry MascotsChompyTizzlewolfLolmeowRarSSXEliseKaoriMacHoney BadgersSleepyFeistyNastyNBA StreetStretchAnklebreakerMonsterPhatProdigySupersizedSad PandasKarlEmmaEmoVancouver StickmenS. RedS. BlueS. YellowS. GreenNimble NinjasBergitsuPojitsuCoditsuSkeleton CrewSkinnyBonesHankThe GobblersWalterPluckyTurkSanta SlammersBoomShakaSanta</description><genres><genre id="22">Basketball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="33222">NFL Blitz</game><game id="24738">3 on 3 NHL Arcade</game><game id="7982">NBA Street</game><game id="35847">MLB Bobblehead Pros</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1885918-box_nbajamofe.png</image></root>