<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34783</id><name>Senran Kagura</name><description>OverviewSenran Kagura is a side scrolling action game for the  3DS. The player will assume the control of 5 different female ninja characters. The more they are damaged by enemies, the more their clothes are torn off. The game will also feature erotic elements that use the features of the Nintendo 3DS system such as stereostopic, 3D cleavage along with 3D images of other body parts. Senran Kagura will feature character designs from Nan Yaegashi and scenario work from  Yukinori Kitajima.GameplayAsuka attackingThe genre of the game has been defined as: "Flying Out Enormous Breast Drama Hyper Battle." "Flying out" refers to the game's usage of 3D to display some of the ninja girls' body parts popping out at the player during cutscenes that the player can trigger during the "hyper battle" segments. Players will dash, perform double jumps and aerial combos during these action segments to defeat enemies. Each ninja girl will have her own unique abilities.CustomizeAsuka customizedPlayers will be able to customize the girls with clothing items and accessories that can be collected during the course of the game.StoryThe game revolves around female ninjas who attend Hanzo Academy, a school created by the government in order to train ninjas who are considered "good" to fight against the "evil" ninjas that are those who are employed by corrupt politicians and big corporations.CharactersPlayableInformationAppearanceAsukaJapanes seiyuu: Hitomi HaradaHeight: 155cmBust size: 90cmA second year student who has a black ponytail and wears knee socks, Asuka's ninja skills are currently subpar.AsukaIkarugaJapanese seiyuu: Asami ImaiHeight: 168cmBust size: 93 cmA third year student who is the best in her class. She is normally nice, but gets relentless when angered.IkarugaKatsuragiJapanese seiyuu: Yuu KobayashiHeight: 165cmBust size: 95cmThird year student who enjoys sexually harassing younger girls, Katsuragi has long blonde hair and wears her shirt with the front buttons down.KatsuragiYagyuuJapanese seiyuu:  Kaori MizuhashiHeight: 158cmBust size: 85 cmFirst year student, Yagyuu wears her hair in pigtails and also has an eye patch. She is very skilled for her academic level.YagyuuHibariJapanese seiyuu: Yuka IguchiHeight: 160cmBust size: 80cmFirst year student, Hibari tends to cause a lot of problems even though she works hard.HibariRivalsInformationAppearanceHomuraHeight: 163cmBust size: 87cmHomuraYomiHeight: 95cmBust size: 95cmYomiHikageHeight: 160cmBust size: 85cmHikageMiraiHeight: 150cmBust size: 62cmMiraiHarukaHeight: 169cmBust size: 99cmHarukaDevelopmentSenran Kagura's producer  Kenichiro Takaki came up with the idea for the game around April 2010 when he decided to make a 3DS game. Apparently, within 30 seconds of thinking about a possible game he realized that one of the things people want to see the most in 3D are breasts. The producer then began Senran Kagura's design document as well as working on a budget, creating characters, a plot and deciding upon gameplay elements. Takaki also met with character designer Nan Yaegashi and scenario writer  Yukinori Kitajima.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/33880/2093270-senran_kagura.png</image></root>