<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34827</id><name>Hyperdimension Neptunia mk2</name><description>OverviewHyperdimension Neptunia mk2 is the sequel to Hyperdimension Neptunia. Like the original, it was developed by Idea Factory and Compile Heart and was released exclusively on the PS3. It features a more fluid combat system with direct control over character movement, skills, and item use, an improved world map, a relationship system called Lily Rank, and cut scenes animated in 3D, as opposed to the visual novel-like 2D interludes of the original. Players may also load custom textures for Nepgear from the PS3 hard drive.StorySet in a different timeline than Hyperdimension Neptunia, in mk2 the four CPUs, Neptune, Noire, Vert, and Blanc, along with Neptune's sister Nepgear, are defeated by the followers of the evil goddess Arfoire and imprisoned inside a graveyard. While they are remain trapped, Arfoire's followers, known as ASIC, begin a plan to destroy the world of Gamindustri by giving away illegally copied discs and cartridges. This causes the faith of the people in their goddesses to fade, further weakening the CPUs.Three years later, IF and Compa manage to find Neptune and the other goddesses. After IF distracts a powerful monster, Compa frees Nepgear, and the three barely manage to escape. When Histoire informs Nepgear of the existence of the other CPU Candidates, Uni, Ram, and Rom, Nepgear resolves to find them and rescue their older sisters.CharactersCPU Candidates and CPUsDescriptionHuman FormHDD FormNepgearMain Page: NepgearUniMain page: UniRamMain page: RamRomMain page: RomNeptuneMain page: NeptuneNoireMain page: NoireVertMain page: VertBlancMain page: BlancGamindustri Savior SetNIS America released a exclusive Gamindustri Savior Set as a preorder exclusively through their online store for $64.99. The bundle includes a collector's box, playing cards, art book, and official soundtrack, on top of the standard edition of the game.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="36">Text Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26556">Trinity Universe</game><game id="23693">Cross Edge</game><game id="21094">Star Ocean: The Last Hope</game><game id="25769">Tales of Graces</game><game id="36336">Tales of Graces F</game><game id="10518">Eternal Sonata</game><game id="37766">Mugen Souls</game><game id="31900">Record of Agarest War 2</game><game id="41474">Mugen Souls Z</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2126445-box_hdn2.png</image></root>