<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3483</id><name>Yu-Gi-Oh! Power of Chaos: Joey the Passion</name><description>Overview Yu-Gi-Oh! Power of Chaos: Joey the Passion is a PC only Yu-Gi-Oh game, and is the third and final in the Power of Chaos series. Joey the Passion features 771 different cards which can be used to make a custom deck. Joey the Passion contains the most content of any of the Power of Chaos games, and is the only one of the series to feature LAN multiplayer. The interface remains relatively unchanged from the other two games in the series, it merely has a new skin on it. Gameplay The only computer opponent in this game is Joey Wheeler. When you choose to duel Joey, you will have the option to play a single duel or a match duel. A single duel is just that, the winner is determined by whoever wins one match. A match duel is a best of three series, the winner being whoever wins two matches. In between duels you can swap out any cards that are located in your side deck into your main deck. If you have the other games in the series also installed, those cards will be transferred over into Joey the Passion.  DifficultyJoey the Passions features a new increasing difficulty. As you defeat the computer player you will earn stars, the more stars you earn the higher the difficulty will be. As the difficulty increases, the computer will switch their deck to a more powerful one. If you lose multiple duels in a row, you will start to lose stars which will decrease the difficulty.  Getting new cards Every time you win a single duel in Joey the Passion you will be awarded with one random card to go into your pool of usable cards. Each time you win a match duel you will win three new cards to go into your pool of usable cards. A new feature that Joey the Passion has over the other games in the Power of Chaos series is that you have a chance to "re-roll" one time what card you receive.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="13">Card Game</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2532">Magic: The Gathering - Duels of the Planeswalkers</game><game id="3000">Magic: The Gathering</game><game id="9265">Magic: The Gathering - Spells of the Ancients</game><game id="9558">Magic: The Gathering Online</game><game id="10489">Pokémon Trading Card Game</game><game id="19085">Dragon Ball Z: Collectible Card Game</game><game id="3210">Marvel Trading Card Game</game><game id="2789">Duel Masters: Limited Edition</game><game id="9324">Duel Masters Sempai Legends</game><game id="10219">Duel Masters Shadow of the Code</game><game id="13159">Duel Masters Kaijudo Showdown</game><game id="12071">Digimon Digital Card Battle</game><game id="33448">Vantage Master</game><game id="33450">VM Japan: Vantage Master - Mystic Far East</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8272/1345064-920746_56267_front.jpg</image></root>