<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35003</id><name>Marvel Heroes</name><description>OverviewMarvel Heroes was announced by Gazillion Entertainment at a press event on April 28, 2011. It is a free-to-play MMORPG in which you can play as a character from the Marvel Universe, rather than make your own character as in DC Universe Online. It will feature a hack-and-slash style of gameplay, similar to that of the Diablo games. Brian Michael Bendis, most notable for writing Ultimate Spider-Man and the New Avengers, has been confirmed as a writer for the game. The game launched to the public June 4, 2013.PlotPlayers will have to explore and fight across the Marvel Universe to stop Dr. Doom's evil plans of using the Cosmic Cube for his own selfish purposes. Players will battle solo, or with online friends, against many infamous organisations such as A.I.M, Hydra and the Purifiers, and face off against soon-to-be-revealed villains.Throughout this MMO, players can visit famous Marvel landspots such as the Savage Land and Avengers Tower.Chronicles of DoomOn Marvel Heroes launch date Gazillion Entertainment released a 4-part motion comic video containing a prequel to the games storyline.GameplayCharactersPlayable HeroesThere are 21 heroes available at launch and five more set for release sometime after the launch. At the start of the game the player can choose one of five free starter heroes, the player obtains more heroes through in-game drops or buying them with "G," Marvel Heroes' real money currency.The Five Free Starter Heroes At Launch DaredevilHawkeyeScarlet WitchThe ThingStorm Other Heroes Available At Launch WolverineThorSpider-ManRocket RaccoonThe PunisherMs. MarvelJean GreyIron ManHulkDeadpoolCyclopsColossusCaptain AmericaCableBlack WidowBlack PantherHeroes Due For Release Post Launch Emma FrostHuman Torch (Now available)Luke CageNovaSquirrel Girl  NPCsVillainsBullseyeDoctor DoomElectroGreen GoblinGrim ReaperKingpinMagnetoMister SinisterRhinoShockerTaskmasterThe HoodVenomElectraGorgonBlobToadDevelopmentCryptic StudiosMarvel Universe Online, which eventually became Champions Online, was an MMORPG under development by Cryptic Studios and was to be published by Microsoft Game Studios under a license from Marvel. On February 11, 2008 the project was changed due to "an inability to compete" with the current MMO marketplace. Cryptic continued development using a new IP license related to Champions.Gazillion EntertainmentOn March 17, 2009, Gazillion Entertainment revealed that they had signed an exclusive ten year deal with Marvel games. Marvel Universe was renamed Marvel Heroes and changed to an MMO ARPG. Marvel Heroes uses Epic Games' Unreal Engine 3 for the visuals and audio, while the back-end MMO components were written using entirely new code. Founders ProgramPrior to the game's official release, Gazillion Entertainment had a Founders Program which let players purchase their favorite heroes and receive other bonuses, such as in-game currency and boosters, at a discounted price. There were three tiers to the Founders Program, Starter Packs which were $19.99, Premium Packs which were $59.99 and The Ultimate Pack which included every hero and costume for $199.99. Before May 6th each pack also included bonus in-game currency at $5, $25 or $45 depending on the pack.Starter PackAll starter packs contain the following:One HeroOne Extra Costume$10 of In-Game CurrencyEarly Access starting July 2ndTwo Experience and Item Find BoostsExclusive Forum Title and AvatarPremium PackMulti-Hero premium packs contain the following:Four HeroesFour Extra Costumes$30 of In-Game CurrencyEarly Access starting May 31stSix Experience and Item Find BoostsExclusive Forum Title and AvatarSingle Hero premium packs contain the following:One Hero5 Extra Costumes$55 of In-Game CurrencyEarly Access starting May 31stSix Experience and Item Find BoostsExclusive Forum Title and AvatarThe Ultimate PackThe ultimate pack contained the following:All 21 Launch Heroes, with other heroes to be added post-launchOver 100 Alternate CostumesThree Ultimate Pack Exclusive CostumesOne Ultimate Pack Exclusive Enhanced Costume (Spider-Man Symbiote)$50 of In-Game CurrencyEarly Access starting May 28th, 20135% Permanent Experience and Item Find BoostListed in the game CreditsExclusive Forum Title and Access to All AvatarsSystem RequirementsOS: Windows XP 32 bit or higherProcessor: Core 2 DUO 2.1 GHz / AMD Athlon X2 2.1 GHZ or betterMemory: 2Gb or higherHard Disk Space: 10Gb or higherVideo Card: DirectX9.0c Compatible ATI Radeon 3870 / NVIDIA 8800 GT / Intel HD 3000 Integrated Graphics with 512 MB VRAM or higher</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21110">DC Universe Online</game><game id="20803">Diablo III</game><game id="38966">Ultima Forever: Quest for the Avatar</game><game id="21559">Marvel Ultimate Alliance 2</game><game id="1119">Diablo II</game><game id="43649">Diablo III: Reaper of Souls</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/31936/2490076-2490075-0487588280-Marko.jpg</image></root>