<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35317</id><name>inMomentum</name><description>GameplaySave some time - follow the green balls!inMomentum is in its essence a time-attack game in which the player has to finish the level as quickly as possible to achieve the greatest score. By using regular jumps, bouncing, wall jumps, a laser gun and clever level design the player races through the level trying to finish it as fast as they can. Being quick on your feet is not the only way to get the best score; throughout the levels there are several green balls to collect, each of them knocking off some time from the clock. Jumping off the edge and falling down in the infinite sky results in the player being returned to the last activated checkpoint gate that they passed through.By performing one jump after the other players can build up speed and velocity in order to achieve greater heights and to give them more momentum to use when performing regular jumps and advanced wall jumps. When performing wall jumps there are other factors as well that determines the result of your wall jump, such as at which degree you hit the wall. In order to get through the harder puzzle sections, the player can get a helping hand by slowing down time using the mechanism Time Slow, which is handy when a puzzle requires a lot of accuracy and timing. The Time Slow can only be used for a few seconds before it runs out, after which is has to recharge in order to be used again.The laser can fired at red switches found across the levels. Doing this will activate level altering mechanisms such as opening locked doors, making platforms move or removing them completely, thus allowing the player to proceed forward. There are also plans for introducing Power Ups which will directly increase the speed of your character and how high you can jump, among other things.MultiplayerThe multiplayer mode of Momentum will have the participating players race each other on the same level at the same time to see who can be the first to reach the finish line.In the multiplayer mode, the laser cannot only be used to trigger switches but also to harm other players as well by pushing them of the map.PC System RequirementsOS: Windows XP, Vista, 7Processor: Intel or AMD Single-Core Processor (2,5 GHz)Memory: 2 GBHard Disk Space: 1 GBVideo Card: ATI X1900 or nVidia 8800 GTX with 512 MB RAMDirectX®: 9.0cSound: Direct X compatible</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21213">Mirror's Edge</game><game id="35950">Fotonica</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/97089/2530518-untitled.png</image></root>