<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35383</id><name>ArmA III</name><description>OverviewThe island of Stratis.Arma 3 is a sandbox oriented first person shooter in a realistic simulated environment. It takes place on two new islands called Altis and Stratis. The islands are highly detailed massive environments featuring a variety of terrain and cities 270km² and 20km² respectively. Arma 3 supports singleplayer, coop, and multiplayer. It is highly moddable and supports custom maps and modes.FeaturesSingleplayer in which you can evolve from a lone soldier to a commander in a story driven and open ended campaign.Vehicles and weapons which provide accurate simulation.Customisable soldier loadout in which you can change your look and weapon kit.Physical simulation and improved animations. Arma 3 uses PhysX.The game world will be modelled from real geographic data.Multiplayer support with dedicated servers for both Windows and Linux.Completely moddable with easy to use mission editor.StoryArma 3 is set in the 2030s when a war between NATO and Iran has come to the Aegean islands of Greece. The singleplayer campaign revolves around a British special forces operative named Scott Miller. NATO's initial attempts on the island fail and the player is forced to find a way to survive and and go on a variety of missions both on his own and with squad mates.SteamworksBohemia announced on Feb. 21, 2013 that Arma 3 would use Steamworks, allowing developers to focus on developing the game itself rather than ancillary tools. The developer stated Arma 3 wouldn't release in 2013 without Steamworks. The server browser still uses some form of Gamespy technology. Players are able to export their missions from the mission editor directly onto Steamworks.ReleaseAlphaIt's an alpha.Arma 3 entered an alpha state on Mar. 5, 2013. This is when it became available for sale on Steam. Steam buyers have immediate access to the alpha (and eventually the beta and retail versions as part of the included cost). With each successive tier of development, Bohemia is planning to increase the price from $33 for the alpha, to $45 for the beta, to $60 for the full retail release. This means fans purchasing during the alpha phase will ultimately pay almost 50% less for a full copy of the game.Alpha LiteThe Arma 3 Alpha Lite started on Mar. 14, 2013. It is almost the same as the Alpha, although it does not include multiplayer, saving in the mission editor, or the ability to add mods.Three keys were given as Steam gifts to people who purchased the Alpha. This version also does not upgrade to the beta or full versions when they are released.BetaThe beta was released on the 25th of June, adding more single player showcases, multiplayer scenarios, a new 'Green Faction', and multiple new weapons and vehicles.Digital Deluxe and Supporter TierThe digital deluxe version includes a digital soundtrack, maps, and tactical guide as well as a copy of Arma: Cold War Assault. The supporter tier includes all of the digital deluxe edition in addition to a copy of Arma X (a collection of all Arma and Arma 2 games and expansions), all future Arma 3 DLC (excluding standalone expansions or sequels), and a "forums badge".Single PlayerAlthough the full game has been released, Bohemia Interactive has said that they have delayed the single player portion of the game and will release it in October.System RequirementsMinimumOSWindows Vista SP2 or Windows 7 SP1CPUIntel Dual-Core 2.4 GHz or AMD Dual-Core Athlon 2.5 GHzGPUNVIDIA GeForce 8800GT, ATI Radeon HD 3830, or Intel HD Graphics 4000GPU Memory512 MBDirectX®10RAM2 GBHard Drive15 GB free spaceHard Drive (Alpha)10 GB free spaceAudioDirectX® compatible on-boardOtherInternet connection and Steam accountRecommendedOSWindows Vista SP2 or Windows 7 SP1CPUIntel Core i5-2300 or AMD Phenom II X4 940GPUNvidia GeForce GTX 560 or AMD Radeon HD 7750GPU Memory1 GBDirectX®11RAM4 GBHard Drive25 GB free spaceHard Drive (Alpha)20 GB free spaceAudioDirectX® compatible soundcardOtherInternet connection and Steam account</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2590">Operation Flashpoint: Resistance</game><game id="5333">Operation Flashpoint: Cold War Crisis</game><game id="39256">DayZ</game><game id="13066">America's Army: Operations</game><game id="21665">Operation Flashpoint: Dragon Rising</game><game id="32243">Operation Flashpoint: Red River</game><game id="39035">Battlefield 4</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/18149/2569992-4939205824-Arma3.jpg</image></root>