<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35388</id><name>LEGO Harry Potter: Years 5-7</name><description>OverviewBased on the last three Harry Potter books and final four films, LEGO Harry Potter: Years 5-7 takes players through Harry Potter’s heroic adventures in the Muggle and wizarding worlds. From Privet Drive in Little Whinging to Diagon Alley, Hogsmeade, and Hogwarts – plus new locations including Grimmauld Place, the Ministry of Magic, and Godric’s Hollow – players will encounter new faces, new challenges, and new magic, preparing them for the ultimate face-off against Lord Voldemort.LEGO Harry Potter: Years 5-7 builds upon the magical gameplay, lessons, and potion-making skills learned in LEGO Harry Potter: Years 1-4 to equip gamers with the tools necessary to challenge a host of new foes and some familiar ones (including He Who Must Not Be Named). The upcoming title is action-packed from start to finish, including loads of new lessons, spells, and bonus content for hours of family friendly gaming.CollectiblesAs with other LEGO-based videogames, there are collectibles, and these are the same ones found in LEGO Harry Potter: Years 1-4.LEGO Studs: Currency in the LEGO videogames and scattered just about everywhere. Collect enough in each level and you will earn the True Wizard status.Hogwarts House Crests: Finding all four parts of a House crest in a level will unlock a Gold Brick.Character Tokens: These are hidden in many levels, and once found allow the player to purchase new playable characters from Madam Malkin's Robes for All Occasions. There are over 200 characters to unlock.Red Bricks: Finding a red brick in a level will unlock it for purchase in Diagon Alley. They give players perks like invincibility or LEGO studs X4. Once purchased, red bricks can be activated within the Extras section of pause menu.Gold Bricks: Earning these will grant the player special rewards and bonus content.Students in Peril: These are Hogwarts students trapped in some kind of difficulty. Help them out!</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="33207">LEGO Pirates of the Caribbean: The Video Game</game><game id="20822">LEGO Batman: The Videogame</game><game id="36898">LEGO Batman 2: DC Super Heroes</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2284684-box_legohpy57.png</image></root>