<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35423</id><name>Dungeons of Dredmor</name><description>OverviewThis is a "diggle". You'll find many of these cute looking things in the dungeons.Dungeons of Dredmor is a 2D indie roguelike role-playing game developed and published by Gaslamp for the PC and Mac (both via Steam) on July 13, 2011. As the unfortunate hero (with large eyebrows), players must descend through a dungeon with the ultimate goal of defeating Lord Dredmor.The game shares many characteristics of other roguelike RPGs (such as procedural map generation, turn-based gameplay, and permanent death), but features a clean, streamlined user interface, hand-drawn graphics, a simplistic control scheme, the optional to disable perma-death, a unique "Skill" system, and comical, absurd humor (including various references to other video games).Along with numerous updates (including the option to play as a female hero), the game features two paid expansion DLC ("Realm of the Diggle Gods" and "Conquest of the Wizardlands", both $2.99) and one free DLC ("You Have To Name The Expansion Pack"). The game also features an expansive mod support (using Steam Workshop for distribution).GameplayDungeons of Dredmor uses a cleaner, less cumbersome interface which may be more intuitive to players not experienced with roguelike games; traditionally, these games are incredibly complex, punishingly difficult, or visually simple (the majority of roguelikes consist entirely of ASCII graphics).The game features many staples of traditional roguelikes, including procedural map generation, turn-based gameplay, and permanent death. However, it also employs a streamlined user interface with hand-drawn sprites and backgrounds, a mouse-and-keyboard control scheme, and the option to turn off permanent death.In order to complete the game, the player must find and defeat Lord Dredmor, the game's main antagonist. To do so, the player must traverse many levels, progressing only by finding staircases leading further down into the dungeon.Upon starting a new game, the player is able to choose seven skills from a possible 34. These skills define the player's character; they determine which weapons and magic types can be used, which items the player starts the game with, bonuses the player receives and other abilities that can be taken advantage of throughout the playthrough. The player can also choose to have the seven skills randomly chosen or to retain the skill set from the previous playthrough.SkillsFor those who put their trust in the Random Number God, there is the option to have the game choose your skills.A feature that distinguished Dungeons of Dredmore from other roguelikes is its skill system - each player character gets a choice of seven different skills, offering a number of spells as well as active and passive abilities. Each time the player levels, another level of the skill of the player's choice gets unlocked, making available a new ability, as well as a stat increase. Since there is no way to change what skills you have after character creation (with the small and very rare exception of an item's enchantment offering extra levels in a crafting skill), this choice determines how the character will play throughout the game, and the order in which skill points are assigned is the only significant way the player has to develop the character, except for giving him equipment.If you would like to have another go at a character like your last one, there is the Last Choice option.The skills are divided between three types: Warrior, Rogue and Mage. The Warrior skills are dominated by the various weapon trees. Except for ranged weapons, a character suffers severe penalties (and receives no benefit from dual-wielding) if they are using a weapon they do not have the corresponding skill for. The Rogue skills are one that help the character survive in the dungeon environment: deal with traps, create items, and so on. The Mage skills are the various schools of magic available, as well as wizardly support skills. The mix of skills a character has affects his starting condition a bit, but this influence pales in comparison to the effect the skill choices themselves have.Warrior SkillsSkillDescriptionSwords SkillSwords are the most common weapon in the dungeons, and investing in this skill gives the highest counter chance of any of the weapon trees.Axes SkillThe axes tree provides very powerful abilities, especially the area-of-effect attack at level 4, but its stat increases are small compared to the other weapon trees.Maces SkillDeveloping your skill at maces gives you early access access to a knockback ability, as well as perhaps the highest pure damage output of any option.Staves SkillThe staves skill tree offers respectable damage, but its biggest drawcard is the bonus to magic power it offers to wizards at the highest levels.Unarmed Combat SkillThis skill tree allows the character to fight effectively without any weapons being equipped. This is especially useful if you want to use the weapon slots to hold two shields, or magic orbs, which use a shield slot.Dual Wielding SkillAllows the character to use two weapons at once, greatly increasing the damage dealt. Developing this tree gives a useful proc and increases counter chance (though this is bugged in version 1.03).Shield Bearer SkillInvesting in the Shield Bearer skill tree greatly increases block chance while have a shield equipped, and gives active to active and passive abilities.Berserker Rage SkillThe Berserker Rage skill tree is a progression of three ever more powerful procs which fire when you are hit, greatly increasing your mêlée stats.Master of Arms SkillDeveloping your skill as a Master of Arms improves the character's ability to withstand attacks from enemies by increasing the block chance and ability to absorb damage, as well as with some buffs.Deadshot Skill*The Deadshot skill tree makes it harder for enemies to avoid your attacks (both ranged and mêlée), and gives easy access to some debuffs on hit that are normally only available deep into a mêlée weapon skill tree.*At some point between launch to the expansion you name yourself, this skill might not appear anymore as it was probably removed.Rogue SkillsSkillDescriptionArtful Dodger SkillThis skill greatly improves the character's dodge chance and all-round nimbleness, as well as providing a very handy short-range teleportation skill.Archery SkillThe Archery skill improves the character's ability with crossbows, as well as slightly increasing the likelihood of retrieving ammunition. Archery tends to do more damage than thrown weapons.Thrown Weapons SkillThis increases the effectiveness of thrown weapons, increases dodging chance as well as the likelihood of recovering ammunition. Thrown weapons very often deal area-of-effect damage.Perception SkillPerception increases sight range, accuracy when attacking, and the likelihood of spotting and being able to deal with traps.Burglary SkillThe Burglary skill tree is a grab-bag of useful skills you'd associate with a thief in a dungeon: easy access to lockpicks, dealing with traps, ways to ease your movement and hinder those of your enemies, and a skill for stealing from the shopkeepers you find in the dungeons.Assassination SkillInvesting in this skill tree unlocks a progression of three damaging and debilitating procs you occasionally activate against your target.Fungal Arts SkillA surprisingly versatile skill, the Fungal Arts allows you to easily farm the various mushrooms, and the bonuses they provide, allows you to create fungal pets to serve you and unleash some mycological chaos in combat.Archaeology SkillAs well as providing useful bonuses to your character's nimbleness, a career as a rogue Archaeologist makes you far more handy with artifacts (enchanted items), including the ability to re-roll the randomly-assigned enchantments.Alchemy SkillMastering Alchemy allows the character to brew a large array of useful potions, as well as craft a few items that are useful to a mage.Tinkering SkillTinkering allows the character to craft a traps, bolts and crossbows, as well as various odds and ends from items picked up in the dungeon, and is a very useful support skill for players who prefer to keep away from danger while allowing their enemies to fall into it.Smithing SkillThe Smithing skill tree gives the character access to an enormous amount of mêlée equipment, from weapons through to armour, as well as providing a hefty bonus to burlinessMage SkillsSkillDescriptionGolemancy SkillThe spells within the Golemancy tree allow the character to get aid from inanimate objects, either summoning a variety of pets or by altering convincing walls to rise or fall.Fleshsmithing SkillInvesting in Fleshsmithing allows the character the buff up their physique and healing rates through a number of spells that are especially useful to the mage who isn't afraid of getting into the thick of the action.Mathemagic SkillThe Mathemagic skill tree allows the character to manipulate the environment and the enemies with the universal language of numbers, or, more directly, debuffs and very poweful damage-over-time spells, with teleportation thrown in for good measure.Psionics SkillDeveloping a character's skill at Psionics opens a range of spells that make enemies pliable to your will, through a sleep spell through stunning effects and culminating in a mind-control ability. Because of the practical nature and low mana cost of the spells, this skill tree is very attractive to more combat-minded characters who want a use for their mana points.Necronomiconomics SkillThrough a series of bargains with dark powers and a firm grasp of Necronomiconomics, a character can unleash devastating magical abilities but must suffer from a series of side-effects every time he does so.Viking Wizardry SkillThe abilities of Viking Wizardry are ways for the mage to control the battlefield with buffs to himself, debuffs to his enemies and dramatic area-of-effect spells.Astrology SkillThe Astrology skill tree contains a number of spells which draw on the protective power of light, which proves a very effective way to keep the character out of danger in the dark underworld of the dungeons.Promethean Magic SkillPromethean Magic is the most direct way to bring lots of hurt to lots of enemies very quickly through the power of fire. Indicative of this approach is the fact that every spell has an area of effect, except for the long-lasting wall of fire, and handily progress also brings conflagratory damage resistance.Magic Training SkillThe character gains no abilities at all across the three tiers of Magic Training, but does receive very large boosts to stats most relevant to magic users, which leads to magical abilities they do have being much more powerful.Blood Mage SkillDabbling in the skills of the Blood Mage allows the character to gain mana, and at later levels, buffs to magic power, from killing enemies, allowing him to keep fueling his destructive magics from the effects of carnage past.Ley Walker SkillGreater skill as a Ley Walker greatly increases the character's mana pool and the rate at which that pool refills.Vampirism SkillTaking the Vampirism skill means that the character no longer naturally regenerates health, nor does so through eating food as other characters, but instead by hitting enemies in mêlée combat, at a rate tied to his magic power.Wand Lore SkillThe Wand Lore skill allows the character to get more use out of the wands that he is sure to find lying around the various levels of the dungeons.Attributes and StatsAttributesBurliness - The primary attribute of the Warrior (and pertains to hitting ones head on other people and getting hit by large objects). Affects the player's Life Points, Melee Power, and Block Chance stats.Sagacity - The primary attribute of the Wizard (and is mostly about being a know-it-all). Affects the player's Mana Points and Magic Power stats.Nimbleness - The primary attribute of the Rogue (and is the quality of swiftness and not getting hit by things). Affects the player's Dodge Chance, Enemy Dodge Reduction, Counter Chance, and Sneakiness stats.Caddishness - The primary attribute of the Pirate (and revolves around not caring about others). Affects the player's Critical Chance, Counter Chance, and Life Points stats.Savvy - The primary attribute of the Bard (and involves avoiding trouble). Affects the player's Haywire Chance and Sneakiness stats.Stubborness - The primary attribute of the Monk (and involves the ability to ignore mean things other people say about them). Affects the player's Magic Resistance and Block Chance stats.Stats (Life and Mana)Life Points - The current and maximum pool of health the player has. (Base value: Burliness points + Caddishness points + 5)Health Regeneration Bonus - Determines the number of turns required to regenerate one point of health. The value is subtracted by the base health regeneration rate (5 steps for easy, 7 steps for normal, 13 steps for hard). Does not apply to those with the Vampirism skill.Mana Points - The current and maximum pool of mana the player has. (Base value: doubled Sagacity points + 5)Mana Regeneration Bonus - Determines the number of turns required to regenerate one point of mana. The value is subtracted by the base mana regeneration rate (5 steps for easy, 7 steps for normal, 8 steps for hard).StatsMelee Power - Affects the bonus damage dealt with melee attacks.Critical Chance - Affects the percentage that the player's melee attack scores a "critical hit", doubling the Melee Power bonus damage and negating both dodges and counter-attacks.Counter Chance - Affects the percentage that the player, as a defender, can "counter", which negates an enemy's melee attack while automatically making a free melee strike. Does not apply to critical hits.Magic Power - Affects the potency of the player's spells and spell-like effects.Haywire Chance - Affects the percentage that the player's spells scores a "haywire", significantly affecting the magical ability.Magic Resistance - Affects the percentage that the player, as a defender, can "resist", which reduces damage taken by the spell or trap.Armour Absorption - Affects the amount of damage reduced by melee attacks.Block Chance - Affects the percentage that the player, as a defender, can "block", which further reduces damage taken by melee attacks.Dodge Chance - Affects the percentage that the player, as a defender, can "dodge", which negates an enemy's melee attack. Does not apply to critical hits.Enemy Dodge Reduction - Affects the penalty against the enemy's Dodge Chance.Sneakiness - Affects whether nearby monsters (who are not in confrontation with the player) notice the player walking by and affects whether traps activate by the player stepping on it.Visual Sight Radius - Affects how many tiles away players can see. Does not apply to Monster Zoo rooms.Trap Sight Radius - Affects how many tiles away players can identify the presence of traps of invisible monsters.Trap Affinity - Affects the chance that players can disarm traps. Can also affect whether players can easily identify and pick up certain traps.Wandcrafting Level - Determines which recipes can be used when crafting with an N-Dimension Lathe.Smithing Level - Determines which recipes can be used when crafting with a Smithing Kit or an Ingot Press.Alchemy Level - Determines which recipes can be used when crafting with an Alchemy Box or Porta-Still.Tinkerer Level - Determines which recipes can be used when crafting with a Tinkerer Parts or an Ingot Press.Downloadable ContentRealm of The Diggle GodsThe first DLC for Dungeons of Dredmor, "Realm of the Diggle Gods", was released on Steam on December 14, 2011 for $2.99. The game adds an optional "Realm of the Diggle Gods" setting when configuring a new game, adding five new unique levels (Deeper Dungeon, Stygian Dojo, The Mechanarium, Underground Forest, and The Ossuary, each with their own unique environments and special rooms) beneath the final level (moving Lord Dredmor down to The Ossuary).Occasionally, these levels may contain shrines to the various Diggle Gods (that diggles apparently worship), each of which may grant a permanent blessing to the hero if he/she prays to it. Only one blessing is applied at a time, and praying to another shrine removes the previous blessing.Diggle God of War - Grants +7 to both Burliness and Caddishness, as well as +10 to Melee Power and +8 to Armour Absorption. In addition, melee attacks have a 1/3 chance of applying Fleshbore onto that target and being hit by enemies has a 1/3 chance of the player gaining Monstrous Rage.Diggle God of Fertility - Grants +10 to Stubborness, as well as +22 to Life Points and +12 to Health Regeneration Bonus. In addition, being hit by enemies has a 1/3 chance of the player gaining Minor Regen.Diggle God of Death - Grants +10 to Sagacity, but adds -25 to both Health Regeneration Bonus and Mana Regeneration Bonus and -2 to Visual Sight Radius. The hero also gains +5 Necromantic Damage and +5 Putrefying Damage to attacks, as well as various Damage Resistance buffs (+15 to Necromantic, Putrefying, Toxic, and Asphyxiative, and +5 to Hyperborean). In addition, melee contact with enemies (either attacking or attacked) has a 1/3 chance of causing Deadly Putrefaction (causing the target to get engulfed in a temporary 3x3 cloud of +7 Necromantic, Putrefying, Toxic, and Asphyxiative Damages, which the hero is resistant to).Diggle God of Digging - Grants +1 to both Burliness and Caddishness, as well as +2 to Melee Power and +8 to Armor Absorption. The hero also gains +6 Blasting Damage and +10 Piercing Damage to attacks. In addition, melee attacks have a 1/2 chance of applying Fleshbore onto the target.Diggle God of Secrets - Grants +50 to Sneakiness, +3 to both Trap Sight Radius and Trap Affinity, and +2 to Wandcrafting, Smithing, Tinkering, and Alchemy Levels, but adds -5 to Visual Sight Radius.Alongside the new levels, the expansion adds (regardless of toggling the "Realm of the Diggle Gods" setting):New special room types (featuring new traps and puzzles) for the original game levels (including the three-runed "Room of Demands", the horde-creating "Mass Pitting Mechanism", the evil crate-spawning "Dwarven Mail System", the two-levered "Room of Levers", and the enemy-infested "Corrupted Shrine of Krong")Twelve new monster types (Fish Warrior, Evil Magic Potato, Entropic Elemental, Slick, Mummy, Ectoplasmic Excession, Muscle Diggle, Living Statue, Wight, Gnome, and Undead Aethernaut) that can be found in most of the game's levels.101 new weapons and armor, almost half of which have new crafting recipes.Eight new Steam achievements, including the mastery of the new skill trees and death by either drowning or by the new Muscle Diggle.Six new skill trees:SkillDescriptionBig Game HunterAn animal hunter-themed warrior skill tree (with five levels), adding a variety of anti-animal abilities while increasing the Enemy Dodge Reduction, Visual Sight Radius, and Sneakiness stats. In addition, killing animals give bonus experience points.Further leveling up Big Game Hunter grants the following abilities:Butchering meat from animals, giving a 30% chance that some form of meat will drop from killing an animal enemy. Passive ability.Luring a particular enemy towards you (enraging them in the process), temporarily debuffing some of its stats.Increasing the success chance of butchering meat from animals while increasing the experience point bonus from killing animals. Passive ability.Summoning a pack of Diggles to fight other enemies.DemonologistA demon-themed rogue skill tree (with seven levels). Players who start upgrading the tree start becoming a force for righteousness (increasing resistance for Righteous Damage).However, after the third level, the hero quickly becomes corrupted with evil (significantly decreasing resistance for Righteous Damage while increasing Conflagratory Damage resistance).Eventually, the hero has the ability to summon demons and to temporarily permutate into demon form.EmomancyAn emo-themed wizard skill tree (with seven levels) that adds a variety of emo-themed support spells:Teleporting an enemy away from the hero.Healing the hero and removing curses, but debuffing the hero for 99 turns.Throwing a ball of acid that causes an explosion into a large cloud of acid, dealing Acidic, Asphyxiative, and Putrefying Damage while inflcting Weak Acid Burn. This cloud lasts for 12 turns.Temporarily casting an Antimagic Field onto a tile.Summoning a sigil onto a target tile, damaging enemies that step onto it (with Existential Damage) while pacifying them (if they're angry), inflicting Ennui on them, and (in a random chance) paralyzing them.Buffing various resistances (which require a mana upkeep to maintain).Fires a beam that both deals Existential Damage to enemies and pacifies angry enemies.Killer VeganA vegan-themed warrior skill tree (with five levels). Along with increasing the player's Burliness, Nimbleness, and health-related stats, this skill makes all animal enemies peaceful towards the hero. However, the player receives a major debuff for attacking animal enemies (in melee combat) and eating non-vegan food (such as meat or cheese). In addition, killing a vegetable enemy gives the player a 50% chance of harvesting vegan food (such as fruits and tofu). Players also start with five pieces of tofu.Further leveling up Killer Vegan adds these abilities:Charming animals to fight other enemies (including other animals) for you temporarily.Further committing to Veganism (granting bonus experience for killing vegetables but increasing the debuff for attacking animal enemies in melee combat). Passive ability.Gaining an aura of self-righteousness (giving the hero additional Righteous damage to attacks, Righteous damage resistance, and a small chance to blind enemies around the hero when in melee combat). Passive ability.Removing all current debuffs (unlocking the deep, hidden secret of vegans).PiracyA pirate-themed rogue skill tree (with five levels), each increasing the player's Caddishness attribute (by +1) and giving the hero additional pirate-themed abilities. In addition, killing an enemy has a 10% chance to drop a random gem. Players also start with four lockpicks.Further leveling up Piracy adds these active abilities:Utilizing the art of swashbuckling (buffing the hero's Counter Chance).Summoning a cloud of mist (buffing the hero's Dodge Chance and Sneakiness while pacifying and confusing enemies that come into contact with the mist).Marking an enemy with the "Black Spot" (heavily debuffing its ability to avoid attacks and make it more vulnerable to basic damage).Firing a cannonball (from an unexplained cannon) onto a targeted enemy, dealing Crushing and Blasting Damages while knocking the enemy back two tiles.Werediggle CurseAllows the hero to temporarily polymorph into a Werediggle (indistinguishable from other cute lil' diggles). While in this form, most of the player's stats are temporarily buffed. However, he/she cannot use any other skill in Werediggle form.This rogue skill tree has eight levels, two of which further increase the stat buffs. Other abilities (in Werediggle form only) from leveling up include:Infecting enemies with the Diggle Plague (through random chance and melee combat), debuffing them. Passive ability.Laying Diggle Eggs.Temporarily becoming invisible.Drilling through walls.Smashing enemies like an Arch-Diggle (dealing basic damage while inflicting Bleed).You Have To Name The Expansion PackThe second DLC for Dungeons of Dredmor, "You Have To Name The Expansion Pack", was released on Steam on June 5, 2012 for free. The expansion was created to celebrate the release of Steam Workshop support, and is a collaboration with some of the game's modders. In addition, players can "name" the expansion pack in the expansion's title screen (by highlighting it with the mouse cursor). The expansion includes:Over 100 new special room types (featuring new traps and puzzles), including various Monster Zoo rooms and shop rooms.Two new trap types: caltrops (deals mostly Piercing Damage when stepped on) and caltrop eruptors (deploys caltrops in surrounding tiles).19 new monsters (including various Diggles, Ravens, and a new monster type: Cloned Heroes).New gear (mostly steampunk gear relating to some of the included skill trees): 11 new armor pieces, 5 new melee weapons, 3 new wands, 3 new crossbow bolts, a new throwable weapon, a new crossbow, and a new tome.New crafting recipes for most of the above gear. Players can also find scrap metals (iron, steel, copper, and aluminum, each of which can be crafted into their specific Ingots) and alchemical ooze (which can be used to craft Salt, Saltpere, Plastic Ingots, and Brimstone)Seven new achievements, including mastery of the new skill trees, "naming" the expansion pack, and death by either the new Hungry Diggle or the new Thirsty Diggle.Four new skill trees:SkillDescriptionClockwork KnightWarrior tree. The Clockwork Knight uses his/her tinkering ability for special attacks  abilities as well as scavenging to tear down Dredmor's forces. Players also start with a Leather Cap (with a Cog on it).Rogue ScientistRogue tree. The Rogue Scientist mixes skills of Alchemy, Tinkering, and Wandcrafting to make abilities for damaging foes with chemical attacks, avoid dangerous environments, and the Ateheric Death Ray. Players also start with a Sonic Wand, two Acid Flasks, and two Poison Flasks.Battle GeologyA geology-themed warrior skill tree (with six levels). Using the power of rocks, each level adds a variety of new abilities:Transforming a target's (hero or monster) hand (or some other appendage) into stone, giving it greater melee power (at the cost of both critical attack and counter-attack chance).Unlocking the defensive properties of rocks, often temporarily giving the hero a variety of defensive buffs when blocking an attack. Passive ability.Having a seismic wave erupt through the ground at an enemy, stunning it and dealing Crushing damage. All monsters between the target and the hero get dazed and receive Blasting damage.Turning the hero's skin to stone, adding a variety of defensive buffs while damaging monsters (with Crushing damage) who hit him/her with melee attacks.Petrifying a target (hero or monster), paralyzing it while giving an extreme variety of defensive buffs. If the target is a monster, it also deals increasing Asphyxiative damage over time (due to suffocation).Creating an earthquake, stunning all monsters in a large area around the hero (dazing all monsters in an even larger area around the player). Also deals Crushing damage to those monsters.WarlockeryA wizard skill tree (with eight levels) for wizards who prefer direct combat. Players start with an Aluminium Wizarding Hat.Each level in the skill tree adds a variety of new spells:Injecting burning-raw magical energy directly to an enemy, dealing Athereal damage.Protecting the hero in a shield of mana, adding various resistances while draining the player's mana pool every time the hero is hit.Channeling the "essence of battle" into an Empowered form, buffing up various attributes while increasing the efficiency of all other Warlockery spells. Requires mana upkeep and drains all mana when cancelled.Twisting the fabric of time, allowing the hero to move for a few turns while all other monsters are still.Surrounding the hero with burning-raw magical energy, dealing Athereal damage to monsters who successfully hit him/her. Passive ability.Charging the hero's weapon with arcane energy, granting an extra effect with the weapon's next attack. Attacking too early reduces the effect. Attacking too late causes the energy to overload and explode, dealing great damage to the hero.Unleashing the Manacalypse, draining all of the character's mana while dealing Athereal, Conflagratory, and Voltaic damages to everything in the hero's vicinity. May leave behind crystallized mana (which can heal the hero).Conquest of the WizardlandsThe third and final DLC for Dungeons of Dredmor, "Conquest of the Wizardlands", was released on Steam on August 1, 2012 for $2.99. The game adds the Wizardlands, mysterious levels used by former Wizardkings to store magical wizarding booze (and other treasures). The hero can access these special levels by finding special codes (known as "Arcane Addresses") scattered around the dungeon as rainbow graffiti (spray-painted on walls by the Wizardkings during wild parties) and inputting them in a special teleportation device found in the new Pocket Dimension.Added in the main game at the same time as the expansion, the Pocket Dimension is a special small level that the player can access at any time (provided he/she has found the Wizard Keys and has been out of the Pocket Dimension for 40 consecutive turns). While players can not use items or regenerate health/mana (but can still craft items), it can be used to store additional items on the ground for easier maintenance. When the expansion is applied, two devices are added into the Pocket Dimension:A device that changes the environment of the Pocket Dimension to the theme of any level the hero has ventured into. This is purely for cosmetics.A teleportation device (resembling a "slipgate" from Quake) with an accompanying console. Players can input Arcane Addresses in the console, which activates the device. Stepping into the portal warps the player.Using valid Arcane Addresses in the teleportation device can warp players to a random Wizardland, which includes random enemies. Using an invalid code causes the device to glow red, and stepping into that warps the player to Diggle Hell (a dangerous place with diggles of various shapes and sizes). Either way, players must find the level's exit, and cannot access the Pocket Dimension.In Diggle Hell, players have a chance to encounter Vlad Digula, a unique boss monster that is ridiculously tougher than Lord Dredmor. Players also have a chance of encountering the shrine of the Diggle God of Hell, which grants a blessing in similar vein to the Diggle God shrines in the Realms of the Diggle Gods expansion (giving a permanent buff that cancels out any existing blessing and is cancelled out by any future blessing). Praying to the Diggle God of Hell (also known as the Diggle Devil) grants the hero +6 Blasting Damage and +6 Conflagratory Damage to attacks and a +6 resistance to Conflagratory Damage (at the cost of -10 resistance to Righteous Damage). In addition, players with the blessing have a small chance of applying a fire effect against the target (10% chance of Ignition Bolt and On Fire, 5% chance of applying Gog's Tactical Pyre).In addition to all of the above, the expansion includes:An exclusive Encrusting system, allowing heroes to use their crafting abilities to add special buffs to weapons and armor. Be warned, however, each encrust adds to the item's instability percentage. Encrusting an item and activating its instability causes the item to have a dangerous negative effect.Seven new monster types (Murderous Rutabaga, Crustaceanoid Warrior, Cloud Gremlin, Samedi, Fruit Treant, Samurai-Bot Mk. III, and Amazonian Bumblebeeperson).Various new items, ten of which have their own crafting recipes.Two new audio tracks (the themes played during the Pocket Dimension and Diggle Hell).Twelve new achievements, including mastery of the new skill trees, completing a Wizardland, entering Diggle Hell, praying to the Diggle God of Hell, defeating Vlad Digula, throwing The Bomb, and death by a Diggle in Diggle Hell.Six new skill trees.System RequirementsPCOperating System: Windows XP, Vista, 7Processor: Core 2 Duo/Athlon 64 or above recommendedMemory: 1 GB of RAM minimum; 2 GB recommendedHard Disk Space: 400+ megabytesVideo Card: Any DirectX-compatible video device with a minimum resolution of 1024 x 600 or 1024 x 768DirectX®: 9Sound: Any DirectX-compatible audio deviceMacOperating System: OS X version Snow Leopard 10.6.3, or later.Processor: Core 2 Duo/Athlon 64 or above recommendedMemory: 1 GB of RAM minimum; 2 GB recommendedHard Disk Space: 400+ megabytes</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26831">Shiren the Wanderer</game><game id="24453">Elona - Eternal League of Nefia</game><game id="30676">Dungeon Crawl Stone Soup</game><game id="8535">Linley Henzell's Dungeon Crawl</game><game id="21594">Slaves to Armok II: Dwarf Fortress</game><game id="22309">Rogue</game><game id="140">NetHack</game><game id="20262">Angband</game><game id="3014">Reaping the Dungeon</game><game id="31011">Desktop Dungeons</game><game id="35930">Tales of Maj'Eyal</game><game id="13105">Baroque</game><game id="35899">The Binding of Isaac</game><game id="37153">Dark Delve</game><game id="37313">Hack, Slash, Loot</game><game id="36612">Cardinal Quest</game><game id="42003">Chasm</game><game id="33217">100 Rogues</game><game id="41913">Sword of the Stars: The Pit</game><game id="42985">Pixel Dungeon</game><game id="42828">Rogue Legacy</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1841709-box_dod.png</image></root>