<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35429</id><name>Blocks That Matter</name><description>OverviewBlocks That Matter is a puzzle/platformer where the player controls Tetrabot, a small robot that can drill certain blocks and then put them back on the map. Because of the way he was programmed, the blocks can only be placed in groups of four, restricting the player to placing blocks in formations that resemble tetrominoes from Tetris. In the beginning of the game, Tetrabot can only drill more soft blocks, like sand, stone and wood, but later upgrades allow metal blocks, like iron, gold and silver, and eventually precious stones, like diamond, to me drilled. Just like in Minecraft, the sand and gravel blocks will fall due to gravity (the latter will only fall after stepped on) and wooden blocks will burn if the come into contact with fire slimes or lava.The game focuses on solving puzzles, although there some levels where the player must run from "Big Mama", a giant version of the slimes, while she destroys everything in her path. If touched by her or by fire slimes, Tetrabot will "nanoreset" instantly, but he can take one hit from common slimes before dying. Tetrabot can't be damaged by falling blocks, but it is possible to kill enemies this way.StoryBlocks That Matter tells the story of two successful indie game developers from Sweden, Alexey and Markus, who are kidnapped due to the highly anticipated game that they were creating. After being kidnapped, it is revealed that what they are working is not actually a game, but instead a robot, Tetrabot, with the ability to destroy several kinds of blocks and then place them back on the world. Tetrabot is activated by the developers, and has to work his way to the place where they are being kept by a nefarious man.The Blocks that MatterThrough out the game the player will find locked boxes, one for each level, some of them are easy to get and some are harder, such that sometimes the player will have to upgrade Tetrabot before he can acquire it. Each box contains a Block That Matters, each of which represents a game (or a game concept) that is, in some way, related to Blocks That Matter. The name of the levels are also tied to the secret game to be found. For instance, the level called "Collateral Damage" contains the "med pack" hidden in it, while the level "Underground People" contains the game Minecraft. There is also one Steam achievement that requires the player to find the three games that inspired the creation of Blocks That Matter.System RequirementsMacMinimumRecommendedOS:LeopardProcessor:Core2Memory:1 GB RAMGraphics:Intel HD GraphicsHard Drive:250 MB HD spaceSound:Integrated chipset OpenAL compatibleOS:SnowLeopardProcessor:Core2Memory:2 GB RAMGraphics:AMD Radeon HDHard Drive:400 MB HD spaceSound:Integrated chipset OpenAL compatiblePCMinimumRecommendedOS:WindowsXPProcessor:Pentium4Memory:1 GB RAMGraphics:OpenGL compatible 128Mo VRAMDirectX®:dx90cHard Drive:250 MB HD spaceSound:Integrated chipset OpenAL compatibleOS:Windows7Processor:Core2Memory:2 GB RAMGraphics:OpenGL compatible 256Mo VRAMDirectX®:dx90cHard Drive:400 MB HD spaceSound:Integrated chipset OpenAL compatible</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17602">Gish</game><game id="1896">Tetris</game><game id="30475">Minecraft</game><game id="15544">Super Mario Bros.</game><game id="2991">Boulder Dash</game><game id="26914">Snapshot</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3699/1868754-blocks_that_matter.jpg</image></root>