<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35432</id><name>Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon Online</name><description>OverviewGhost Recon Online (GRO) is a free to play multiplayer third person shooter for the PC developed by Ubisoft Singapore, currently in Open Beta.The Nintendo Wii U version however is currently ‘on hold’ as the developers are focused on ‘doing the PC version right.’GameplayMuch like Ghost Recon Future Soldier, GRO is a third person cover based shooter. You have the choice of three different classes each with their own strengths, weaknesses, specific weapons and specialized abilities.To complete your objectives you have an array of weapons and accessories available, including weapon attachments and consumables such as grenades.Due to the free to play nature of the game everything is microtransaction based, each weapon, accessory and consumable can either be bought with ‘RP’ earned as rewards for doing well in games, or you can purchase ‘GC’ that let you buy items at a reduced cost.Game ModesThere are three game modes available in GRO, all game modes are based on capturing and holding objectives until the timer runs out. Rounds can be won by either capturing all the objectives or defending the objectives until the round timer expires.ConquestConquest is a take and hold game mode, around the map are five capture points labelled A through E, both teams start opposite the central objective (point C) and when the round starts both teams advance on the objective, once the objective is captured by either team the attacking team spawn moves forward one point and the defending team moves backwards one point, so if the attacking team takes point C then the attacking team spawns at point C and the defending team at spawn E.The round ends when a team has either captured all of the objectives, or the round ends and the team that has the most objectives held. OnslaughtOnslaught is a two round attack and defend game mode, each team has the chance to attack and defend once the round changes. The defending team has to hold two objectives, once the attacking team has captured both objectives a third objective opens up and the attacking team has to capture the final objective to win the round. HoldoutHoldout is a two round defend game mode, each team must take and hold a central objective until the timer runs out, if the attacking team capture the central objective then time is added to the timer and the defending team must now attack to recapture the point.Teams switch sides after the round ends and the winning team is the one that captured and held the point the most or longest. ClassesLike most games the player has a choice of classes which each of their own strengths, weaknesses, weapon types and abilities.To ensure victory each team must have the right mix of the classes and abilities, each class can choose from two primary weapons of which you can only use one a time, a pistol, armour, grenades and abilities.The player must choose the class before entering a match but once in a match then the player cannot change the class only his weapons and abilities.AssaultThe front-line class, with a choice of assault rifles and shotgun the Assault class has the most armour but is also the slowest of the three classes.The Assault class has a choice of two abilities, HEAT and Blitz. Heat causes a directed microwave affect wherever the device is pointed causing disorientation and small amounts of damage to the enemy behind cover making them move position. Blitz is a ballistic shield ability, once activated allows the player to rush forward with the shield and knock enemies over, it also has the added bonus of storing the shield on the players back giving them added protection from the rear. ReconThe sniper, with a choice of sniper rifles and sub machine guns is the lightest and fastest of the classes but also the lightest armour, the role of the Recon is to provide long range support and intelligence for the team.The Recon class also has a choice of two abilities, Oracle and Cloak. Cloak is an invisible camouflage ability and allows the player to move about for a short period of time undetected. Oracle is a radar like system that detects enemies and shows them on your team-mates HUD. SpecialistThe Specialist class can choose from Light Machine guns and Shotguns. With medium armour gives them a balance between speed and protection, the role of the specialist is to support the Assault classes with their unique abilities.The specialist can choose from two abilities, Aegis and Blackout. Aegis is a force shield bubble that extends around the player which team mates can take cover under, Aegis provides protection from both bullets and grenades. Blackout is a chargeable EMP effect which stuns enemies and stops them using abilities, the longer you charge Blackout the further its area of effect range, if you get shot while charging the effects are directed back at the player. WeaponsEach primary weapon has three configurations to fit the play style of the player, close, medium and long range. Weapons can also be customised with attachments such as scopes, laser targeting, high capacity magazines, muzzle breaks and suppressors. Through repeated use each weapon can level up giving you added chance of giving a critical hit to the enemy.Assault RiflesM27 CM27 D10RSM27 D20As ValAs Val CVSSMk 16 CQCMk 16 SVMk 16Sar-21Sar-21 CSar-21 SDACRACR CACR SVAR-21AR-21 CAR-21 SVF2000F2000 SPF2000 SDSniper RiflesM24A2M24 SVM24 CSRSSRS CSRS SDSentinel SR-1Sentinel SR-1 SVSentinel SR-1 SDSR-25SR-25 SDSR-25 SPMSRMSR CMSR SDM-200M-200 SDM-200 SVSVDSVD SVSVDSSubmachine GunsMP5A2MP5SD-N2OC-14 4A01OC-14 4A02OC-14 4A03PP2000PP2000 CPP2000 SDMP7MP7 CMP7 SDPP-19PP-19 SDPP-19 SPMP9MP9 CMP9 SDP90P90 CP90 SDLight Machine GunsMk 3 SPMk 4 CMk 5M96M96 CM249MK 46 Mod 0M249 ParaL86 SVL86A1 IWL86A1 LSWMG4MG4 CMG4 SPMG36 KMG36 KVMG366P416P41 SP6P41 SVShotgunsM500M500 CM500 SVPentagunPentagun SPPentagun SDPM5PM5 SPPM5-350M1014M1014 CM1014 SDNS2000NS2000 CNS2000 SPModel 10aModel 10a CModel 10a SPKPS-12KPS-12 CKPS-12 SDHandgunsP250USP 45TR-1FiveSevenP-45RedhawkPX4Attachments     ScopesReflexReflex have no magnification but offer the widest field of view for quick target acquisitionAssaultAssault scopes have close to medium range magnification at the cost of some field of viewSniperSniper Scopes have medium to long range magnification but have the most restrictive field of view. StocksStocks affect recoil and weapon ready times switching to and from the weapon. MagazineUpgraded magazines offer higher capacities and larger pools of ammo Bottom AttachmentsBipodBipods stabilize weapons when in cover or prone, giving improved accuracy and reduce recoil at the cost of reduced mobility.Vertical GripGrips are best used in close quarters giving improved accuracy recovery and reduced recoil at the cost of long range accuracy Side AttachmentsIR Laser DesignatorAllows the player to set waypoints and designate enemies that show up on team mates HUDMuzzle AttachmentsSilencerSilences eliminate muzzle flash, improve accuracy and greatly reduce noise at the cost of reduced damage.Muzzle BreakMuzzle breaks greatly reduce weapon recoil and slightly reduce muzzle flashFlash SuppressorFlash suppressors significantly reduce muzzle flash and slightly reduce recoil ConsumablesConsumables are limited use items gained by purchasing, rewards for accomplishing objectives or picking up via the loot system.Armour InsertsArmour comes with slots so the player can insert armour plates that have special attributes, the player can purchase better armour that have more slots. Each insert has a unique ability that boosts the players attributes.There are four types of inserts each with four levels of increasing effects.  Health – Increases your maximum health.Regeneration – Increases the rate at which you regenerate health.Toughness – Decreases the damage taken by enemy bullets.Crit Evasion – Decreases the chance that the enemy will give you a critical hit.GrenadesGrenades have two types, impact and fuse and two variants which increase the blast range and damage.AmmoMagnum ammo can be equipped onto a weapon to provide extra damage. MapsThere are currently six maps in the Open Beta, these are not final maps and have much changed from the closed beta.Shearwater 51 – Oil Rig based Onslaught Mode Map    Markhov Station – Moscow Metro based Conquest Mode Map    Korolyov Towers – Construction site based Onslaught Mode Map    Chertanovo LZ – Moscow City based Conquest Mode Map    Tomsk-9 – Russian Nuclear Processing Planet based Onslaught Mode Map    Balaklava Sub-Pen – Submarine Pen based Holdout Mode Map  </description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26423">Call of Duty: Black Ops</game><game id="24713">Modern Warfare 2</game><game id="2133">Call of Duty 4: Modern Warfare</game><game id="20464">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Conviction</game><game id="24699">America's Army 3</game><game id="32243">Operation Flashpoint: Red River</game><game id="21528">ArmA II</game><game id="29336">Medal of Honor</game><game id="25246">Battlefield: Bad Company 2</game><game id="20655">Battlefield: Bad Company</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/39/1791782-ghost_recon_online_logo.jpg</image></root>