<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35450</id><name>Sexy Beach Zero</name><description>OverviewCompared to previous Illusion games, the graphics and lighting have improved. The game now features an anaglyph 3D feature as well as HDR lighting. The camera remains the same as it did in the previous game Sexy Beach 3. The left click allows you to rotate around the character and right clicking allows for panning on a 2D plane in front of the character. The camera also features multiple saved positions which can attained by pressing Q,W,E,R, and T.The player will follow a distinct progression path with each girl. Going on dates and talking to the girls as well as giving gifts eventually builds trust. As the player builds trust the girl opens up to the player eventually letting the player engage in the eroge (i.e sex) mini-games. Each girl has a specific swimsuit type that is distinctively hers. By playing with each individual girl the player can access new swimsuits to buy and dress up the girls.The game is also features very prominent gravure picture taking opportunities. Using the camera controls the player can instantly take a picture of any scene with the Print Scrn button. The pictures are then saved in the screen capture folder for later viewing.After complete progression with each girl the "Free Mode" is unlocked which allows complete customization of Clothes and body options which include arm, bust, hips, calves, butt. The player can then select from any scene in the game at free will to view with the customized options.CharactersAll characters are from previous Illusion games.Bael Altarus: Bael is the woman that manages the Illusion Hotel Resort. She has short blue hair and purple eyes and is found in the games Des Blood 4, and Digital Girl ~Bael~, as well as having previously appeared in Sexy Beach 3 (Although not unlocked for play until the release of the SB3 Plus expansion disc).AI: AI is a modern looking Japanese woman with short black hair. She originally appeared in Real Kanojo.Rin: Rin is a brown haired school girl who has appeared previously in Biko 3 and Digital Girl RinHotaru: Hotaru is a blonde haired woman who was a biological experiment gone wrong. She previously appeared in Des Blood VRSetsuna Yagami: A purple haired woman who has appeared in Battle Raper 2.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="24964">3D Custom Girl</game><game id="29609">3D SexVilla 2: Ever-Lust</game><game id="20099">7 Sins</game><game id="22041">Artificial Girl 3</game><game id="15683">Artificial Girl 2</game><game id="24274">Artificial Girl</game><game id="32581">Biko</game><game id="11902">Biko 2</game><game id="12174">Biko 3</game><game id="18638">Des Blood</game><game id="18495">Des Blood 4: Lost Alone</game><game id="9156">Des Blood 3</game><game id="14130">Des Blood 2</game><game id="32582">Des Blood VR</game><game id="33367">@Home Mate</game><game id="5706">Lula 3D</game><game id="26948">The Maiden Rape Assault: Violent Semen Inferno</game><game id="8911">Battle Raper II: The Game</game><game id="16696">RapeLay</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/92448/1793269-604961_177580_front.jpg</image></root>