<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35475</id><name>Firefighter Command: Raging Inferno</name><description>OverviewSet in the US West Coast, the game puts you in control of a firehouse. The game isset up into missions, each with its own different location and objectives. The player will have to use a predefined number of firefighters and vehicles in order to complete the missions. Missions take place in very varied locations such as suburbs, industrial sectors, malls, and forests. The player will also have to confront different types of fires such a metal fires and chemical fires.In order to create the most realistic firefighting simulator, the developers worked closely with real firefighters to learn how fire would react in different situations. Unit Types Firefighter:  The firefighter or "smoke eater", forms the basic unit in Firefighter Command. He can use all the equipment necessary to combat the flames and free a passage.Paramedic:The paramedic is a specialist who works alongside the firefighters. His mission is to administer first aid to civilians so that they can reach the ambulance unaided.Extrication Specialist:The extrication specialist is used every time large obstructions or metal debris have to be removed.Technical Officer:The technical officer is a specialist who is required to hanbdle the more complex mechanisms. He can repair vehicles.Approach Suit Specialist:The approach suit specialist is useful when action is urgently needed on equipment exposed to the fire. He wears a bio suit to protect himself from chemical fires.Dog-Handling Specialist:This specialist works closely with his dog. The dog's acute sense of smell means he can detect civilian victims in collapsed structures or avalanches so they can be rescued before they suffocate.VehiclesPumper:The pumper is a firefighting vehicle. It carries a small independant water supply, a pump, and a hose mounted like a cannon on its roof.Foam Truck:The foam truck is similar to the pumper, only it pumps out foam, not water. This vehicle is typically deployed on hydrocarbon fires, which generally start on industrial sites.Ambulance:Ambulances are used to administer first aid to civilians or firefighters.System RequirementsSupported OS: Windows 2000/XPProcessor: 1GHz Pentium III or AMD Athlon (1.4 GHz recommended)RAM: 256 MB (512 MB recommended)Video Card: 64 MB DirectX 9.0cSound Card: DirectX 9.0c compliantCD-ROM: 4x or betterHard Drive Space: 1.5 GBMultiplay: 56 Kbps (broadband recommended)</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/13692/1797073-g22009txw2y.jpg</image></root>