<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3549</id><name>Konung 2: Blood of Titans</name><description>Konung 2 is a sequel to Konung: The Legend of North It is a very open ended RTS/RPG-hybrid, where you decide what approach you want to take. You can play the game with almost no combat, or with alot of it. With a few partymembers, or alot of them, micromanaging towns, or ignoring towns almost completely. It comes with six playable characters, all with some different approach to the game.  StoryA powerful warrior has taken over Woodland with the power of an ancient  bracelet of lordship, and you, as one of Titan's descendants, are the  only ones who can take Woodland back. Party MembersRatibor Starts with extra money, two unique hirelings, owns Pinesville, and is a competent fighter. While playing Ratibor you'll be under more attacks from huntingparties, and they will be a bit stronger than usual as well. Velmira Velmira starts in Blackwood, and has it available immediately.  Helga She is proficient in healing, and has access to a good mercenary others do not. Her combatskills are a bit low at beginning of the game. Aanastasia Won't hire male mercenaries, and takes longer to take over settlements.Einar Starts in prison, with no healing abilities and a low abilityscore.  Alexander Begins the game in a cave, and with the highest combat-ability of all the playable characters.  InformationMinimum System Requirements   Operating System: Windows 95/98/Me/XP   Processor: Pentium II 400 MHz   Memory: 64 MB RAM   Video card: 1024*768, High Color (16 bit)   Sound card: DirectX-compatible   Hard disc:    CD ROM: CD-ROM: 16-x     Recommended System Requirements  Operating System: Windows 95/98/Me/XP   Processor: Pentium II 400 MHz   Memory: 128 MB RAM   Video card: 1024*768, High Color (16 bit)   Sound card: DirectX-compatible   Hard disc:    CD ROM: CD-ROM: 16-x</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="52">Baldur's Gate</game><game id="10637">Baldur's Gate II: Shadows of Amn</game><game id="13091">Baldur's Gate: Dark Alliance</game><game id="6795">Baldur's Gate II: Throne of Bhaal</game><game id="12107">Baldur's Gate: Dark Alliance II</game><game id="9789">Beyond Divinity</game><game id="12">Blade &amp; Sword</game><game id="5985">Diablo</game><game id="15589">Diablo II: Lord of Destruction</game><game id="1119">Diablo II</game><game id="7386">Divine Divinity</game><game id="5153">Sacred</game><game id="1714">Throne of Darkness</game><game id="31832">Konung III: Ties of the Dynasty</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1403/531748-496_konung_2.jpg</image></root>