<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35495</id><name>UFC Undisputed 3</name><description>OverviewUFC Undisputed 3 is third and final instalment in the UFC Undisputed franchise developed by Yuke's Co Ltd and published by THQ. The game differs significantly from UFC Undisputed 2010, the biggest change is the addition of the PRIDE mode where you are allowed to knee, stomp and kick to the head of a downed opponent. The game also boasts many improvements that you would expect such as enhanced visuals, more moves to perform, a new submission system, better online play and new camera angles. The game features the newest divisions in the UFC, Bantamweight and Featherweight, and a huge roster of over 150 UFC fighters. The PRIDE FC experience has been recreated along with the Saitama Super Arena, legendary ring announcer Lenne Hardt and commentary provided by Stephen Quadros and the legendary Bas Rutten.New FeaturesHighlight ReelA video editing mode new to the UFC Undisputed series. UFC Undisputed 3 will save your 50 most recent rounds of fighting and give the user the ability to edit them together to create their own unique Highlight Reel. Videos can be uploaded the UFC Undisputed Community Hub or to YouTube for mass sharing. Also added is the "Smart Highlight Reel", which uses an algorithm to automatically make a highlight reel.Fighter EntrancesFor the first time in the Undisputed series, players will be able to see their favorite fighters walk out to the Octagon. The entrances are not only a show of presentation, but are treated as a way to inform users about fighter's strengths through commentators Joe Rogan and Mike Goldberg.PRIDE ModePaying homage to the home of some of the best MMA fighters, UFC Undisputed 3 features PRIDE FC with its own mode and roster. PRIDE FC uses a different rule set and a different pace compared to UFC. First round is 10 minutes and the following two rounds are 5 minutes. Knee to a downed opponent, soccer kicks and stomps are completely legal. The mode is rounded out by the authentic presentation using ring announcer Lenne Hardt and holding the bouts at the Saitama Super Arena.Finish The FightA feature that was in the first UFC Undisputed game, but was taken out in UFC Undisputed 2010, was the ability for players to attack an opponent after a KO. For UFC Undisputed 3, THQ/Yukes brought the feature back as the Finish The Fight feature. As soon as your opponent hits the floor from a KO, players are able to jolt to the downed opponent and start swinging away to assure their win adding the much needed physical exclamation point to all KOs.Amateur Control SchemeMaking sure UFC Undisputed 3 was accessible to all interested players, UFC Undisputed 3 includes an Amateur Control scheme. Instead of performing quarter-circles for Minor Transitions and half-circles for Major Transitions on the Right Analog stick to advance positions, players using Amateur Controls can now just flick up or down on the Right Analog stick to advance in position. However, using this control scheme will take out some techniques like the ability to fake your transitions.FIGHTERSHeavyweightAlistair Overeem (DLC)Antonio Rodrigo "Minotauro" NogueiraBen RothwellBob SappBrandon Vera (LHW)Brendan SchaubBrock LesnarCain VelasquezCheick KongoDan SevernDon FryeFrank MirGabriel GonzagaGary GoodridgeGilbert YvelHeath HerringJunior dos SantosKevin Randleman (LHW)Mark ColemanMark HuntMirko Cro CopPat BarryRoy NelsonSean McCorkleShane CarwinStefan StruveTravis BrowneLight HeavyweightAnderson Silva (MW)Antonio Rogerio NogueiraBrandon Vera (HW)Chuck LiddellCyrille DiabatéDan Henderson (MW)Forrest GriffinJason BrilzJon JonesKazuhiro NakamuraLyoto MachidaMatt HamillMauricio "Shogun" RuaMichael Bisping (MW)Murilo RuaPhil Davis (DLC)Quinton "Rampage" JacksonRameau SokoudjouRashad EvansRich Franklin (MW)Ryan BaderThiago SilvaTito OrtizVitor Belfort (MW)Vladimir MatyushenkoWanderlei Silva (MW)MiddleweightAlan BelcherAlessio Sakara (DLC)Anderson Silva (LHW)Brian Stann (DLC)Chael SonnenChris LebenCourt McGeeDan Henderson (LHW)Demian MaiaDenis KangGeorges St-Pierre (WW)Jake Shields (WW)Jason "Mayhem" Miller (DLC)Jorge RiveraKendall GroveKyle Noke (DLC)Mark MunozMartin Kampmann (WW)Michael BispingMike Swick (WW)Murilo BustamanteNate MarquardtPaulo Filho (WW)Phil BaroniRich Franklin (LHW)Rousimar PalharesVitor Belfort (LHW)Wanderlei Silva (LHW)Yoshihiro AkiyamaYushin OkamiWelterweightAkihiro GonoAnthony Johnson (DLC)B.J Penn (LW)Carlos ConditChris LytleDan HardyDiego Sanchez (LW)Dong hyun KimGeorges St-Pierre (MW)Jake Shields (MW)Jon FitchJohn Hathaway (DLC)Josh KoscheckMartin Kampmann (MW)Matt HughesMatt Serra (LW)Mike Swick (MW)Nate Diaz (LW)Nick Diaz (DLC)Rory MacDonald (DLC)Paulo Filho (MW)Paulo ThiagoPascal Krauss (DLC)Royce GracieRyo ChonanSean Sherk (LW)Thiago AlvesLightweightAnthony PettisBen HendersonB.J Penn (WW)Charles Oliveira (DLC)Clay GuidaDennis SiverDiego Sanchez (WW)Donald CerroneEvan DunhamFrankie EdgarGeorge SotiropoulosGray MaynardJens Pulver (FW)Jim MillerJoe Lauzon (DLC)Joe StevensonKenny Florian (FW)Marcus AurelioMatt Serra (WW)Melvin GuillardNate Diaz (WW)Ross PearsonSam Stout (DLC)Sean Sherk (WW)Takanori GomiTyson GriffinFeatherweightChad MendesCub SwansonDiego NunesErik KochFredson PaixaoGeorge RoopJavier VazquezJens Pulver (LW)José AldoJosh GrispiChan-Sung Jung (DLC)Kenny Florian (LW)Leonard GarciaManvel GamburyanMark HominickMike BrownRaphael AssuncaoTiequan ZhangUrijah Faber (BW)BantamweightAntonio BanuelosBrad PickettBrian BowlesCharlie ValenciaChris CariasoDamacio PageDemetrious JohnsonDominick CruzEddie WinelandJoseph BenavidezMiguel TorresNorifumi YamamotoRenan BaraoScott JorgensenTakeya MizugakiUrijah Faber (FW)DLCA week before release, THQ released their DLC schedule for UFC Undisputed 3 which includes a couple Fighter Packs, a handful of Ultimate Fights Packs, and a Season Pass.FIGHTER PACKS (400 MSP/$4.99 PSN):Fight Of The Night Pack (March 2012)A pack dedicated to fighters who have earned the prestigious Fight Of The Night honors.Joe Lauzon (LW)Rory MacDonald (WW)Charles Oliveira (LW)Sam Stout (LW)Anthony "Rumble" Johnson (WW)International Pack (April 2012)A pack of some of the most notable non-North/South American fighters including the other half of 2010's Fight of the Year and an Ultimate Fighter participant."The Korean Zombie" Jung-Chan Sung (FW)John Hathaway (WW)Pascal Kraus (WW)Kyle Noke (MW)Alessio Sakara (MW)Contenders Pack (Gamestop Pre-Order Bonus/240 MSP/$2.99 PSN)A pack of four fighters that once were considered to be in top title contention.Phil Davis (LHW)Jason "Mayhem" Miller (MW)Nick Diaz (WW)Brian Stann (MW)Ultimate Fights Packs (400 MSP/$4.99 PSN)Ultimate Submissions (FREE AT LAUNCH)Fights which include a highlight reel submission ending.UFC 109: Paulo Thiago vs. Mike SwickUFC 115: Mirko Cro Cop vs. Pat BarryUFC 116: Brock Lesnar vs. Shane CarwinUFC Fight Night 19: Nate Diaz vs. Melvin GuillardUFC Fight Night 21: Kenny Florian vs. Takanori GomiUltimate Rivals (FREE AT LAUNCH)Match-ups that famously had a lot of verbal heat leading up to the fight itself.UFC 92: Quinton "Rampage" Jackson vs. Wanderlei SilvaUFC 111: Dan Hardy vs. Georges St. PierreUFC 114: Quinton "Rampage Jackson vs Rashad EvansUFC 117: Chael Sonnen vs. Anderson SilvaUltimate Finale 9: Diego Sanchez vs. Clay GuidaUltimate Upsets (March 2012)Fights with the least predictable outcomes.UFC 92: Frank Mir vs. Antonio Rodrigo NogueiraUFC 109: Chael Sonnen vs. Nate MarquardtUFC 112: Frankie Edgar vs. BJ PennUFC 116: Chris Leben vs. Yoshihiro AkiyamaUFC 121: Cain Velasquez vs. Brock LesnarMixed Bag (April 2012)A mixed pack of fights for each Ultimate Fights category including Best of PRIDE and Ultimate Knockouts.Best of PRIDE - Final Conflict 2003: Antonio Rodrigo Nogueira vs. Mirko Cro CopSubmissions - UFC 125: Takanori Gomi vs. Clay GuidaUpsets - UFC 110: Joe Stevenson vs. George SotiropoulosRivals - UFC 124: Stefan Struve vs. Sean McCorkleKnockouts - UFC 120: Dan Hardy vs. Carlos ConditUltimate Knockouts (Walmart Pre-Order Bonus)A pack of fights showcasing devastating knockouts.UFC 96: Matt Hamill vs. Mark MunozUFC 101: Anderson Silva vs. Forrest GriffinUFC 110: Antonio Rodrigo Nogueira vs. Cain VelasquezUFC 113: Lyoto Machida vs. Shogun RuaUFC 115: Chuck Liddell vs. Rich FranklinAlistair Overeem (Free on Facebook/80 MSP/$.99 PSN)To build the UFC Undisputed 3 Facebook page, THQ offered former Strikeforce Heavyweight Champion and current UFC Heavyweight contender Alistair Overeem as a free download for an exchange of a "Like" on Facebook. The offer has since ended, but the fighter is currently available for purchase Xbox Live and Playstation Network for 80 MSP or $.99 respectably.All Unlockables (160 MSP/$1.99 PSN)A pay-for-convenience pass to immediately unlock all in-game content.Create-A-Fighter Boost (240 MSP/$2.99 PSN)Another pay-for-convenience fee to add skill points to your fighter without spending the time to do so.Season PassFollowing the trend of other THQ games, Saints Row: The Third and WWE 12, UFC Undisputed 3 will offer a "buy all at a discount" Season Pass. The Season Pass will allow players to download these assorted DLC packs when available:Fighters Pack - Fight Of The Night Pack (March 2012)Fighters Pack - International Pack (April 2012)Ultimate Fights Pack - Ultimate Upsets (March 2012)Ultimate Fights Pack - Mixed Bag (April 2012)Alistair OvereemAll UnlockablesThe Season Pass does not include The Contenders Pack, Create-A-Fighter boost, or the Online Pass. The Contenders Pack and the Create-A-Fighter Boost will be available for purchase on launch day. The Online Pass will be included in all new copies of UFC Undisputed 3. The Season Pass will cost 1360 Microsoft Points on Xbox Live or $16.99 on the Playstation Network.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26815">EA Sports MMA</game><game id="29912">K-1 Premium 2004 Dynamite!!</game><game id="29913">K-1 Premium 2005 Dynamite!!</game><game id="29376">UFC Undisputed 2010</game><game id="37682">Bellator: MMA Onslaught</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3699/1982798-ufc_undisputed_3_cover.jpg</image></root>