<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3550</id><name>Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six: Vegas</name><description>OverviewTom Clancy’s Rainbow Six Vegas (RSV) is the 6 installment in the acclaimed Rainbow Six series. Rainbow Six Vegas was developed by Ubisoft Montreal and published by Ubisoft on November 21, 2006. The game focuses on the counterterrorist unit Rainbow Six who have been send to Las Vegas, Nevada to stop terrorist from blowing up casinos and eventually detonating a bomb on the Nevada Dam. RSV was the first Rainbow Six and Xbox 360 game to be featured in the Major League Gaming tournament.The game itself was well received earning many awards which praised it for its tactical gameplay, innovative AI and sharp graphics. Ubisoft has also stated that as of March 31, 2007, it sold over 1.7 million copies.PlotVegas...baby?The story follows Rainbow team leader Logan Keller on a mission accompanied by two squad mates, Gabriel Nowak and Kan Akahashi. The mission is in a Mexican border town called San Joshua del Mosquiera in the year 2010. Rainbow's intelligence officer, Joanna Torres, briefs Logan on his mission; the objective is to arrest Irena Morales, a terrorist ringleader. As Logan and his squad reaches the landing zone, Logan fast-ropes down first, but the helicopter and the rest of the team is forced to retreat as a rocket-propelled grenade narrowly misses them. After fighting trough groups of armed terrorists he re-joins his squad and finally confront Irena in an abandoned mine, however she has planned an ambush leaving Logan for dead and taking Kan and Gabriel hostage. After escaping the mine and fighting trough an abandoned factory with only his pistol Logan contacts Joanna and escapes by helicopter.[Please edit this article with further plot summary]LevelsMexico Las VegasFremont StreetThe SpireDante's CasinoHoover DamGameplayCover system allows Logan to take cover behind wallsRainbow Six Vegas is a first person shooter that incorporates a third-person cover mechanic. At any open corner or chest-high wall, the player can choose to enter a cover state. The camera will then move to a third person perspective, allowing the player to peek out while remaining partially hidden, and blind-fire at targets.Weapon ListPistolsMk. 23USP4092FSGlock 18Desert EagleRaging BullSMGMP5MP7A1UMP45P90MP9MAC11AssaultSCARC-H CQCM8AUGA3G3KA4552CG36CMTAR21FAMASAK47LMGMK4621EM249SPWMG36ShotgunsM3SPAS12870MCSXM26-LSSSniperPSG1M40A1SV-98Scout TacticalMultiplayerThe multiplayer is a big feature in Rainbow Six Vegas, including a robust character customization feature, and a persistence to the leveling system in the multiplayer. As you attained a higher level/rank, the more stuff would gradually be granted for you to use. This stuff could include color/camouflage schemes, weapons, armor, masks, clothes, among other things. This was an innovative feature in the game's multiplayer that was a major contributing factor in the games lifespan. To go with the persistence, there are several game modes that can be played. These include your team deathmatch, deathmatch, attack and defend, terrorist hunt, and other modes in a decent variety of maps to be played on. The highest player count to be achieved on the console versions of the game is 16.Rainbow Six Vegas features the following game modes:Attack  DefendSurvivalSharpshooterTeam SurvivalTeam SharpshooterRetrievalAssassination (DLC, found in the Red Edition)Conquest (DLC, found in the Red Edition)Expansion packsPlayer's Pack Red EditionThe pack includes two new game modes. The first is "Assassination" whereby one team has to protect a VIP armed only with a pistol, whilst the other team needs to assassinate him. The second is Conquest . Three new maps were also included: "Doscala Restaurant," "Marshalling Yard," and "Roof." The maps "Killhouse" and "Border Town" have been redesigned and packaged as two new "redux" maps.The Player's Pack Black EditionFeatures five new maps. "Red Lotus", "Wartown" and "Neon Graveyard" are the three newly featured maps. "Streets: Redux" has been redesigned in a similar fashion to the Redux maps found in the Player's Pack Red Edition, and "Presidio" is a map overhauled and upgraded from Rainbow Six 3.Both the Red and the Black expansion packs were included in the PS3 version and were released for PC. Upon the release of the PS3 version, Ubisoft then made both the Red and Black Editions free for all XBOX 360 users.Xbox 360 Collector's EditionA Limited Collector's Edition of the Xbox 360 version has been released. It contains a making-of documentary and a series retrospective. It also features another box art.PC System RequirementsAs displayed on the back cover of the boxOperating System: Windows XP.CPU (Processor): Pentium 4 3GHz or AMD equivalent.System RAM: 1024MB (1GB).GPU (Video Card): (3D Card) 128MB, Shader model 3 and Direct X 9.0c compatible (see supported list*).DirectX Version: DirectX 9.0c.DVD-ROM Drive: 4x.Sound Card: DirectX 9.0c compatible.HDD (Hard Disc) space: 7GB free space.*Supported Video Cards at Time of Release (laptop models of these cards are not supported) :ATI X1600 / X1800 / X1900Nvidia 6600GT / 6800 / 7300 / 7600 / 7800 / 7900</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11663">Half-Life: Counter-Strike</game><game id="14048">SOCOM 3: U.S. Navy SEALs</game><game id="11339">Counter-Strike: Source</game><game id="11151">X Squad</game><game id="2444">Full Spectrum Warrior: Ten Hammers</game><game id="19874">Kane &amp; Lynch: Dead Men</game><game id="7023">SOCOM: U.S. Navy SEALs - Tactical Strike</game><game id="7288">SWAT 4</game><game id="20476">America's Army: True Soldiers</game><game id="22948">Specnaz: Project Wolf</game><game id="24584">SAS: Secure Tomorrow</game><game id="21665">Operation Flashpoint: Dragon Rising</game><game id="7334">Crossfire</game><game id="20834">Brothers in Arms: Hell's Highway</game><game id="9137">Brothers in Arms: Road to Hill 30</game><game id="3617">Brothers in Arms: Earned in Blood</game><game id="30196">SOCOM 4: U.S. Navy SEALs</game><game id="1339">Star Wars: Republic Commando</game><game id="8632">Soldier of Fortune: Payback</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/13158/1048160-gb.png</image></root>