<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35511</id><name>Zone of the Enders HD Collection</name><description>A High Voltage Software-developed compilation of PS2 games Zone of the Enders and Zone of the Enders: The 2nd Runner, originally featuring 720p HD visuals but updated to 1080p in a later patch for the PS3 version and Achievement/Trophy support, released on Xbox 360 and PlayStation 3. Both games feature improved audio, widescreen support and a brand new HD opening animation created for the collection by renowned anime studio Sunrise, featuring highlights from both games. 60fps gameplay was also announced but the final release didn't live up to that.  Later, a patch was released for the PS3 version of the game which provided consistent 60fps gameplay to Zone of the Enders: The 2nd Runner. PS3 PatchOn episode 311 of the HIDERADIO podcast (as translated here), Hideo Kojima stated that fan reaction to the PlayStation 3 version's frame rate issues had led to the Kojima Productions team developing a patch in-house (rather than at High Voltage Software) to improve performance and visual effects. No date was given for the patch, but it will be included on future printings of the retail disc. No Xbox 360 version is planned.As a result of the poor reception to the HD Collection, Kojima also revealed that development on the next game (Enders Project) had been suspended, and the development team disbanded.Transfarring and PS Vita PortZOE HD Collection was originally announced with support for Transfarring, allowing PS3 saves to be synced with an eventual PS Vita port of the game, much like Metal Gear Solid HD Collection. The Vita port was officially announced alongside a Vita port of MGS HD Collection at TGS 2011. However, several months before release, all references to the PS Vita or Transfarring were scrubbed from the official website and final boxart in all regions. No public announcements have been made about the fate of either but given the lackluster response to the 360/PS3 version, the abandonment of sequel plans, and poor Vita hardware sales in general, it seems safe to assume that they have been quietly cancelled.Metal Gear Rising DemoHarking back to the infamous Metal Gear Solid 2: Sons of Liberty demo that was included with the original Zone of the Enders, ZOE HD Collection includes early access to the demo for Metal Gear Rising: Revengeance on Xbox 360 and PlayStation 3. In the West, the demo is included on a second disc on 360 and is installable from the Blu-ray on PS3, while in Japan a download code is included with the PS3 version - the Xbox 360 version does not include the demo in Japan, as MGR is a PS3 exclusive there. The demo was announced in a Mega64 sketch during Konami's Pre-E3 2012 live event (a follow-up to the Mega64 video that originally announced the ZOE and MGS HD Collections one year prior).</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20039">Armored Core 2</game><game id="15116">Armored Core 3</game><game id="17675">Armored Core 4</game><game id="22133">Armored Core: for Answer</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2341983-box_zotehdc.png</image></root>