<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35532</id><name>Dance Central 2</name><description>OverviewDance Central 2 is the second installment in the series by Harmonix. The game was announced at the Microsoft E3 2011 Press Conference and was released worldwide in late October, 2011. It is the sequel to the first Dance Central game released in November 2010, which uses the Kinect infrared and camera sensors to track body movement.FeaturesSimultaneous two-player Dance Battles, which can be either head-to-head or cooperative.Drop-In / Drop-Out support, allowing anyone to join a solo dance mid-song by raising their hand.Career Mode, in which players meet Dance Crews and challenge them to Dance Battles. The game now follows a light narrative arc, similar to Rock Band 3.Improved Break It Down mode, featuring selectable individual moves and in-song navigation controls.Players are now able to navigate ingame menus entirely with voice controls."Freestyle mode", where the game takes a break from choreographed moves, is now completely optional in all Dance Central 2 songs.A proper ingame music store, in which songs (and dance moves) can be previewed before purchase.Dance Battle mode now features segments in which players are shown an array of four moves and compete to do them first.The ability to create and play setlists up to 20 songs long. Several setlists are included on the disc.An enhanced Workout Mode, that can be toggled on and off from the main menu.Included songsDance Central 2 featured 44 on-disc songs at launch. It is also compatible with all 32 songs exported from the first Dance Central, as well as all DLC released to date -- making for a total of over 100 songs available at launch. (Pre-Dance Central 2 songs are compatible with every feature introduced in Dance Central 2, aside from removing freestyle mode.)The complete song list was released on October 18 2011.Atlantic Connection And Armanni Reign - ReachAs made famous by Britney Spears - ToxicB.o.B. feat. Bruno Mars - Nothin on YouBananarama - VenusBobby Brown - My PrerogativeBruno Mars - GrenadeChingy - Right ThurrCiara - GoodiesDaddy Yankee feat. Fergie - Impacto (Remix)Daft Punk - TechnologicDarude - SandstormDavid Guetta feat. Akon - Sexy ChickDigital Underground - The Humpty DanceDonna Summer - Hot StuffElectric Valentine - Body To BodyEnrique Iglesias feat. Pitbull - I Like ItExile - I Wish for YouFar East Movement feat. The Cataracs and Dev - Like a G6Flo-Rida feat. David Guetta - Club Can’t Handle MeGnarls Barkley - Run (I'm A Natural Disaster)Haddaway - What Is Love?Justin Bieber - Somebody To LoveKevin Lyttle - Turn Me OnKurtis Blow - The BreaksLa Roux - BulletproofLady Gaga - Bad RomanceLady Gaga - Born This WayLena - SatelliteLittle Boots - MeddleMary J. Blige - Real LoveMissy Elliott - Get Ur Freak OnMontell Jordan - This Is How We Do ItNew Boyz - You’re A JerkNikki Minaj feat. Sean Garrett - Massive AttackO-Zone - Mai Ai Hee (Dragostea Din Tei)P. Diddy feat. Keyshia Cole - Last NightRemy Ma - Conceited (There’s Something About Remy)Rihanna - Rude BoySean Kingston - Fire BurningSir Mix-A-Lot - Baby Got BackTweet feat. Missy Elliot - Oops (Oh My)Usher feat. Pitbull - DJ Got Us Fallin' In LoveUsher feat. Ludacris  Lil' Jon - Yeah!Willow Smith - Whip My HairDownloadable songsAll DLC from Dance Central is compatible with Dance Central 2. Removing the freestyle sections will not work on any pre-Dance Central 2 songs, though.ArtistSong TitleCrew  CharacterRelease DateLady GagaMarry the NightThe Glitterati (Jaryn)November 22, 2011Lady GagaThe Edge of GloryLu$h Crew (Ms Aubrey)November 22, 2011RihannaWhat's My NameFlash4wrd (Taye)December 20, 2011RihannaSMThe Glitterati (Jaryn)December 20, 2011RihannaOnly Girl (In the World)Flash4wrd (Li'l T)December 20, 2011Ne-YoCloserHi-Def (Mo)January 10, 2012Busta RhymesDon't Touch Me (Throwda Water on 'Em)Riptide (Bodie)January 17, 2012C+C Music FactoryGonna Make You Sweat(Everybody Dance Now)Riptide (Emilia)January 24, 2012Cee-Lo GreenForget YouHi-Def (Glitch)January 31, 2012Michael Franti  Spearhead feat.Cherine AndersonSay Hey (I Love You)Riptide (Bodie)February 14, 2012KelisMilkshakeLu$h Crew (Ms. Aubrey)February 21, 2012LMFAOParty Rock AnthemHi-Def (Mo)February 28, 2012Chris BrownYeah 3XRiptide (Bodie)March 13, 2012Janet JacksonEscapadeRiptide (Emilia)March 27, 2012Janet JacksonNastyLu$h Crew (Ms. Aubrey)March 27, 2012Yolanda Be Cool  DCUPWe No Speak AmericanoHi-Def (Glitch)April 10, 2012Kelly Rowland Ft. David GuettaCommanderThe Glitterati (Kerith)April 17, 2012Pitbull Ft. Ne-Yo, Afrojack  NayerGive Me EverythingLu$h Crew (Angel)April 24, 2012Spice GirlsSpice Up Your LifeFlash4wrd (Li'l T)May 8, 2012Diddy-Dirty Money Ft. T.I.Hello Good MorningRiptide (Bodie)May 15, 2012A Tribe Called QuestScenarioHi-Def (Glitch)May 22, 2012Flo Rida ft. T-PainLowFlash4wrd (Taye)May 29, 2012IyazReplayLu$h Crew (Angel)June 12, 2012NellyHot In HerreHi-Def (Mo)June 19, 2012Kat DeLuna Ft. Elephant ManWhine UpFlash4wrd (Taye)June 26, 2012Selena Gomez  The SceneRound  RoundLu$h Crew (Ms. Aubrey)July 10, 2012Demi LovatoLa La LandFlash4wrd (Li'l T)July 17, 2012Justin Beiber Ft. Jaden SmithNever Say NeverHi-Def (Mo)July 24, 2012Jeremih ft. 50 CentDown on MeLu$h Crew (Angel)August 7, 2012Naughty By NatureO.P.P.Hi-Def (Glitch)August 14, 2012Kevin Rudolf ft. Lil' WayneLet It RockRiptide (Bodie)August 21, 2012Nelly Furtado Ft. TimbalandPromiscuousLu$h CrewAugust 28, 2012Dance CrewsDance Central 2's Crew Challenge Mode features five dance crews. The crews battle against one another, in a style reminiscent of fighting games and games like Bust-A-Groove. Each crew has a venue of their own.Lu$h Crewis composed of Angel and Miss Aubrey, both returning from Dance Central 1. Their venue is a yacht with a helicopter on it, and the skyline of a city in the distance.Flash4wrdis composed of Taye and Li'l T. Taye returns from DC1; Li'l T is her little sister, and one of the game's two teenage characters. Their venue is a minigolf course with a prehistoric theme.Riptideis composed of Emilia and Bodie. Emilia returns from DC1; Bodie is a new character. Their venue is a beach at sunset, with surfers and a bonfire in the background.Team Hi-Defis composed of Mo and Glitch. Mo returns from DC1; Glitch is the game's other teen character, described as a dance prodigy by Harmonix. Their venue is a subway station/train, where they "keep it underground".The GlitteratiThe game's first completely original dance crew, composed of twin brother-and-sister Kerith and Jaryn. Their venue is a rooftop set in front of a darkened city skyline. Their attitude runs counter to the other crews, who are generally encouraging and sportsmanlike.Though all five playable crews have been revealed, Harmonix has stated that boss battles in the game's career mode may provide a venue for some other DC1 characters to return.Hidden and Bonus CrewsThere are several hidden crews in Dance Central 2 that are unlockable by completing various challenges and gaining stars in the crew challenge mode.D-CYHPERD-Cypher includes CYPH-56 (Pink) and CYPH-78 (Blue). This crew is unlocked by completing the crew challenge mode on easy or medum which means getting at least 4 stars on each crews unlockable song in a dance battle played one after another with no breaks in between.Tan IndustriesThis crew features Dr. Tan and CYPHELITE (Bernice). This crew is unlocked after completing crew challenge mode on hard.Ninja CrewThe ninja crew was unlocked by users installing the Dance Central 2 Challenge Facebook App. Shinju and Kichi make up this crew. Shinju appeared in Dance Central after entering the code LUXURY at the title screen.Icon CrewThis crew was unlocked after the worldwide online player community earned a combined total of 100 million stars. Marcos (Blue) and Frenchy (Pink) form this crew. They are named after 2 of the choreographers that worked on the game. This crew 2 of the silhouettes that make up the dance previews on the song select and downloadable content purchase screens</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="27859">Just Dance</game><game id="31347">Just Dance 2</game><game id="35553">Just Dance 3</game><game id="31724">Michael Jackson: The Experience</game><game id="31801">DanceMasters</game><game id="32865">Dance Paradise</game><game id="35638">Everybody Dance</game><game id="34784">DanceDanceRevolution</game><game id="36861">Nickelodeon Dance</game><game id="36619">Grease Dance</game><game id="31714">Kinect Star Wars</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2525166-box_dc2.png</image></root>