<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35541</id><name>Kinect Disneyland Adventures</name><description>OverviewKinect Disneyland Adventures allows players, alone or with a friend, to explore a complete recreation of the Disneyland theme park in Anaheim, California. The entire park has been fully modeled, with details such as location-correct audio (ride announcers, visitor chatter, etc). Kinect allows players to interact with Disney characters in various ways, such as dancing, hugging, and asking for autographs.FeaturesFull Kinect utilization (voice command, motion controls, player recognition)Entire Disneyland park modeled in an open-world fashionDozens of Disney characters to interact withTwo-player simultaneous play and park explorationScannable tags that give in-game costumesGameplayPlayers explore the park with the help of an anthropomorphized golden ticket. Movement is controlled by holding one's arm out in the intended direction. Fast travel to any attraction or area of the park can be done by using Kinect's voice recognition to pull up a map, and saying the location's name. Disney characters are found throughout the park, and can be engaged in conversation by waving when nearby. Once they're talking, players can hug, dance, high-five, or ask the character for an autograph. Quests are given to the player by the characters or the golden ticket, and consist of finding appropriate items (horseshoes for Jessie from Toy Story, for example) or speaking to other characters. Coins can be earned or found strewn about the park, with which costumes for the player's avatar can be purchased.MinigamesWhile the park itself is faithfully modeled, and rides are visible, entering a ride leads to a minigame that is themed to the ride, but not a recreation of the ride itself. Space Mountain, for example, consists of a space-shooting sequence through asteroid fields and the like. Players are given a bronze, silver, or gold medal depending on the number of points scored during these games.Scan TagsPreorders (from GameStop) or plush dolls (from Toys "R" Us) come with scannable tags. Storefronts in the park have an option to scan these tags, which give the player gender-specific costumes and other items, as well as quests.</description><genres><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="36720">Kinect Rush: A Disney/Pixar Adventure</game><game id="31704">Kinect Adventures!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2106398-box_kda.png</image></root>