<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35586</id><name>Blades of Time</name><description>OverviewA spiritual successor to  X-Blades. The primary game mechanic that sets it apart is time manipulation; being able to record the main character performing an action and then rewind to before that action began and record another, ultimately creating and fighting alongside multiple versions. The general gameplay is a hybrid of third person shooting and hack n' slash melee combat.StoryThe plot follows treasure hunter Ayumi, who is trapped on a mysterious island and separated from her treasure hunting partner Zero. Ayumi must deal with multiple factions, including the Skyguard, the Hordes of Chaos and fellow humans, on a mysterious path of discovery.GameplayStandard two button attack based action and extreme player character mobility are the core gameplay mechanics. Time manipulation, in the form of a rewind ability, is mainly utilised for multiple switch based puzzles and boss encounters. This ability is limited to 10-15 seconds and slowly refills over time. As the game progresses there is a light RPG layer with a limited selection of gear and a degree of character customisation, although by the endgame the main character should be equipped with every ability available. The game also features third person shooting action, though the applicability of this is limited to certain encounters.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6681">Devil May Cry 4</game><game id="20710">Bayonetta</game><game id="31803">NeverDead</game><game id="22999">Onechanbara: Bikini Samurai Squad</game><game id="18385">Blinx the Time Sweeper</game><game id="3399">Blinx 2: Masters of Time and Space</game><game id="21868">The Misadventures of P.B. Winterbottom</game><game id="30393">Hunted: The Demon's Forge</game><game id="29806">Monday Night Combat</game><game id="36739">Heroes of the Storm</game><game id="39749">Ninja Gaiden 3: Razor's Edge</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2139771-box_bot.png</image></root>