<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35598</id><name>Jerry Rice and Nitus' Dog Football</name><description>GameplayIn Jerry Rice  Nitus' Dog Football, up to four players can play either co-op or head to head with 20 different playable breeds of dogs and 14 different human quarterbacks to choose from (including Jerry Rice) on a total of 12 differently themed, interactive fields.Compared to other football games, control is simplified to allow children easier access to play. For instance, at the beginning of a pass play better known in this game as a "Pass it!" play, players simulate a typical passing motion with the Wiimote in order to get the ball to the receiver. Once the ball is acquired, the dog is guided with a rotating dog bone on the screen through the motion of the Wiimote. In addition to Pass It!, there are also Run it! and Just for Kicks! plays that do as their titles indicate, all 185 of which are viewable in multicoloured lines at the beginning of each play.Dog SpecificsThe game splits up the 20 breeds of dogs into three classifications: small, medium and big. Each breed of dog has its own statistics which players can take into account when choosing a breed. For example larger dogs may be slower, but they will also be harder to tackle. On the other hand smaller dogs will be able to run a lot quicker, but can also become easily scared when animals such as raccoons run on the field. Other such variations within dogs also lie within their touch down stances, varying from chasing their tails to simply peeing on a log.Players also have the ability to customize their dog with the option to change its jersey, collar, hat and shoes.The games changes several football terms to fit the theme of the game. For instance, First Downs are called Fur-st downs, Out of Bounds is coined Out of Bow-wow-nds, and P.A.T.s are referred to as A.R.F.s.This is the first game in the series of pet sports game crossovers that JUDOBABY plans to develop. No, seriously.Playable BreedsRottweiler (Jerry's Dog Nitus)Golden RetrieverAmerican BulldogBoston TerrierBoxerChihuahuaEnglish BulldogPoodle StandardJack Russell TerrierLabradorSaint BernardGiant SchnauzerScottish TerrierSiberian HuskyYorkshire TerrierEnglish MastiffGreat DaneCollieAltair-Beast (Alien Breed)Robo-Dobo (Robot Dog)</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="21">Football</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8417">NFL Blitz</game><game id="21815">Backyard Football</game><game id="19324">Sports Illustrated for Kids: Football</game><game id="21098">Wii Sports Resort</game><game id="29744">Madden NFL 11</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/11/116631/1862731-jerry.jpg</image></root>