<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35624</id><name>Grand Prix Story</name><description>GaragesFirst Level GarageThe first garage you inhabit provides you with the ability to store two cars and to have one driver and support mechanics.Upon completing the first local grand prix, you are upgraded to the second garage. The second garage now allows you to hire a second driver. Additionally you can now house four cars and four mechanics per driver.Third Level GarageAfter clearing the Japan level grand prix, you move onto the world level and are now given the largest garage. It's now possible to build and store six cars as well as six mechanics per driver.Car BodiesBasicRoadsterThe Roadster is the most basic car. Better suited to asphalt then ice, but can be upgraded to be a passable vehicle. Allows two additional add-ons and can be successfully produced by a level 1 mechanic.Off RoadBuggyThe Buggy is the entry level off-road car. It allows 3 parts to be added on and is fair on dirt and ice. Requires a barely trained mechanic for optimal build. Unlocked by upgrading Roadster 25%. Upgrade 50% to unlock The Proto Car.Proto CarThe Proto Car is an upgraded buggy. Better overall stats but remains a good car for dirt and ice. Upgrade 50% to unlock The Super Car. Requires a good mechanic for optimal build.Super CarThe Super Car is the final upgrade to thebuggy. It carries 4 slots for add-ons and has very high speed and durability. Unmodified it is not suitable for ice. Requires expert mechanics for optimal build.Drag CarsDragsterThe Dragster is the entry level high speed car. It allows 2 parts to be added on and is weak on dirt and ice. What the car lacks in durability it makes up for in speed. Moderate mechanic required. Available by winning the Snowville GP. Upgrade to 50% to unlock the Cigar Car.Cigar CarThe Cigar Car is the second version of the Dragster. Improvement over all basic stats, remains unsuitable for any surface except for asphalt. Well trained mechanics needed. Upgrade to 50% to unlock the Spiral Car.Spiral CarThe Spiral Car is the third variety of the dragster. Equally upgraded in all stats with an additional expansion slot. Needs modifications for acceptable performance on dirt and ice. Very high to expert mechanic needed for best build.Open WheelWing CarThe Wing Car is the entry level open wheel car. Exchanging acceleration for control. In basic form, best used on asphalt. Unlockable by winning Japan GP. Upgrade 50% to unlock The Sonic Car.Sonic CarThe Sonic Car is an upgraded Wing Car. Greatly improves on the weak acceleration of the Wing Car, also not an ideal car for dirt and ice. Requires a good mechanic for optimal build. Upgrade 50% to unlock Aero Car.Aero CarThe Aero Car is the final form of the Wing Car. Highest default handling of the basic car bodies with moderate upgrades in durability and speed over the Sonic Car. Additional add-on slot. Very good to expert mechanic needed for optimal build.SpecialBanana CarThe Banana Car has modest stats but earns data and experience very quickly. Can be created in a New Game plus as the first car, albeit with very humble performance. Unlockable by placing first in the Chimp Island GP.Duck CarDuck Car. Maximize ad revenue while driving a duck. Unlockable by completing Autoburg Sponsorship.SL CarThe SL is a steam locomotive, exchanging any attempts at handling for raw acceleration and durability. Not suitable for dirt, but modest performance on ice. Unlockable by completing Kairo Insurance Sponsorship.Kairo CarThe Kairo Kar is a laughably fragile vehicle that will not even survive a lap around any track without significa upgrades. Even still, it's incredibly powerful and dirt cheap. S Rank! Unlockable by winning the Kairo Island GP.Mach Car, an obvious riff on Speed Racer. Posses no real weak point save for its difficult in construction and poor performance on dirt and ice. Unlockable by upgrading both the Spiral Car and the Aero Car to 50% each.RacetracksBloomtownZen GardenDusty PlainsSnowvilleSand BeachJapanHungaryEgyptBrazilGermanyEnglandU.S.A.Chimp IslandRussiaKairolandSpecial CharactersAdd OnsEach car will have a pre-determined number of 'slots' for tech add-ons. These add-ons will improve stats, give bonuses and features to cars that normally wouldn't have them (i.e. ice driving). All add-ons have a rank (the difficulty associated with installing them) as well as a deployment cost (the price to add to your car). Additional technology is usually available by winning races, pleasing sponsors or upgrading existing technology beyond 80%.ItemRankDescriptionCostRadial TiresDBasic tire, Bonus to Acc and Hndl.4,000Knobby TiresCImproves off-road driving14,000Studless TiresCImproves ice driving16,000Sports TiresCIncreases Hndl, Acc and bonus to on-road8,000Hi Grip TiresBIncrease Hndl16,000Slick TriesAIncrease Hndl, Acc, On-rd, negative off-rd  icy20,000V6 EngineEStarter Engine10,000V8 EngineDUnlocks by upgrading V6 80%16,000V10 EngineBUnlocks by upgrading V8 80%25,000V12 EngineAUnlocks by upgrading V10 100%40,000Seamless GearEBonus Acc6,000Speed GearCBonus Speed, Negative Acc10,000Power GearCBonus Acc, Negative Speed10,000Hi Speed GearCLarge Bonus Speed, Negative Acc17,00032 BitDIncrease qualifying race bonus9,00064 BitBIncrease qualifying race bonus13,000SuperchargerBHigher acc at low speeds12,000TurbochargerAHigher acc at low speeds15,000WingCBonus Hndl, Negative Speed8,000Big WingBBonus Hndl, Negative Speed15,000Aero BodyABonus Hnd and Dur15,000Lt ChassisCBonus Spd and Dur6,000Carbon ChassisBBonus Dur120,000Carbon BrakesBBraking increase6,000Gold EggBEarn XP faster20,000EmblemDImprove ad revenue2,000Hyper OilDBonus Spd, Acc and Hndl5,000CoatingDBonus Dur3,000Tire ChainsEImproves ice driving3,000SponsorsSponsors play a vital role in acquiring funds as well as unlocking special parts for your cars. In general, a sponsor will have a target that they wish to reach. They will pay you a semi-yearly revenue, plus bonus if you do well. Once they reach their target they will give you a reward and introduce you to a new sponsor. Higher race finishes as well as a driver with good appeal will please sponsors faster.SponsorTargetRevenueRewardBridgerock807,500Knobby Tire PlansMocha Cola13019,900Hyper Oil (see Errors)Dry Springs10513,50040,000 CashCarbucks15535,500700,000 CashCurry Coop18030,50040 Dev PointsFroggerade20533,000Drag Racing TrainingRace Trax25538,700EmblemSpongecorp23035,50032 Bit chipDairy Duke30542,800Powerslide TrainingCheapy P's28037,500Car Camera (see Errors)Honza Cars50542,500Carbon BrakesADD40553,00Watch Vids trainingRiver Bank48058,500Shop Class trainingNights Inn53048,000Gear Shift trainingMicrosloth58073,500Drift trainingMilky Milk35548,100Gold EggAckbar Oil60594,7002400k cashBob's Drugs38049,500Aerobics trainingChimp Labs43032,000SuperchargerKairo Group630122,500SL carPear Inc.45540,0004wdAutoburgDuck CarErrorsAfter clearing Mocha Cola you're informed you can now research Hyper Oil, but Car Camera appears in the research list. However researching "Car Camera" will give you the Hyper Oil item.The same is true after completing Cheapy P's, who give you Car Camera which appears as Hyper Oil in the research list.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="33312">Game Dev Story 2</game><game id="34336">Hot Springs Story</game><game id="35767">Pocket Academy</game><game id="35945">Soccer Club Story</game><game id="36075">Mega Mall Story</game><game id="36369">Pocket League Story</game><game id="36915">World Cruise Story</game><game id="37639">Dungeon Village</game><game id="37901">Cafeteria Nipponica</game><game id="37077">Epic Astro Story</game><game id="42759">The Sushi Spinnery</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/37185/1808691-image_thumb168.png</image></root>