<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35688</id><name>Hacker Evolution Duality</name><description>OverviewEveryone knows the futuristic pictures from movies like Mission Impossible or James Bond: Transactions are tracked back, voices been emulated to crack safes and with a blink of an eye remote servers been penetrated. In "Hacker Evolution Duality" you can now do all of that.In "Hacker Evolution Duality" you take over the role of Brain Spencer who uses his excellent programming skills to create an all-powerful artificial intelligence that can automatically perform hacking operations for which you would need dozens of human programmers. Unfortunately, an emerging company notices the potential of this AI and with it wants to get the lordship over the internet."Hacker Evolution Duality" starts with basic fundamental gameplay that players from titles like "CSI" or "Law and Order" should be familiar with: At the beginning simple puzzles must be solved, for example. In addition developer exoSyphen Studios also include basic firewall-crack tasks to get started. Later more complex security systems becomes a challenge. There also it the possibility of programming traps and convert common household appliances into dangerous weapons. For those whom get bored with the single player mode over time can furthermore engage in open-world multiplayer mode with like-minded people on hacking adventure.Key FeaturesRedesigned interface and gameplay; Replacing the text based console interface with a more easily understood and less cumbersome button driven GUILarge open world populated by AI hackersAmazing new graphics, sounds and animationsChoice of gameplay: pursue the game's objectives, or play a never-ending and evolving open gamePC System RequirementsOperating System: Windows XP / Vista / 7Processor: 1 GHz CPU or fasterMemory: 1 GB RAMHarddrive: 100 MB free disc memoryGraphic Card: OpenGL compatible video cardDirectX®: 8.0Sound Card: DirectX compatible sound cardMac System RequirementsOperating System: OS X 10.5.8, OS X 10.6.3 or laterProcessor: 1 GHz CPU or fasterMemory: 512 MB RAMHarddrive: 200 MB free disc memoryGraphic Card: 32 MB graphic card</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="389">Uplink: Hacker Elite</game><game id="32681">Hacker Evolution: Untold</game><game id="12952">BS Hacker: Replay</game><game id="8662">BS Hacker: Zero Expansions</game><game id="20814">Hacker</game><game id="7089">Hacker II: The Doomsday Papers</game><game id="42640">Hacknet</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4344/1816197-logo.jpg</image></root>