<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35842</id><name>Theatrhythm Final Fantasy</name><description>OverviewTheatrhythm: Final Fantasy is a 3DS rhythm game from Square-Enix. The game features chibi-style characters and music from throughout the primary Final Fantasy series in gameplay focused around music-themed combat. It was released in North America on July 3, 2012.PlotThe game's crossover storyline appears to take influence from the Dissidia: Final Fantasy crossover universe. The space between the goddess Cosmos and the god Chaos is known as Rhythm, which empowers the Music Crystal. This crystal fills the world with harmony, but when Chaos's forces cause disruption, it begins to lose its shine. The Final Fantasy characters must fight to restore it by gathering Rhythmia.Gameplay BasicsSimilar in nature to the Ouendan series, the rhythm-based gameplay involves tapping the stylus on the touch-screen in time with the music. On-screen prompts consist of three basic "trigger" types that correspond with a type of action that the player must take.TouchWhen these triggers appear, the player must simply touch the touch screen with the stylus and quickly release.SlideSlide triggers appear as circles with arrows inside them. To successfully hit a slide trigger, the player must slide the stylus across the touch screen in the direction indicated.HoldHold triggers appear as two circles connected by a colored beam. The player must touch the touch screen with the stylus when the first circle is highlighted and hold it until the second circle is highlighted.Music TypesThe music is split into three categories: battle, field, and event.Battle StagesA battle in Theatrhythm.In battle stages, the player fights against classic Final Fantasy monsters in a view reminiscent of Final Fantasy I-VI. There are four marker rails; one for each of the player's party members. As markers align with the circles, the player must touch, slide, and hold the stylus to the touch screen in time with the music. Successes result in the party dealing damage to the enemy on screen.Field StagesField stages see the characters explore to the tune of the games' field themes. The triggers move in a single track from left to right. In this mode, the when confronted with a hold trigger, the player must also slide the stylus up and down in order to keep it on the track.Event StagesEvent stages depict scenes inspired by events tied to the music. As the mark moves around the screen in a choreographed pattern to follow the triggers, the player must touch, slide, and hold the stylus to the screen as the appropriate triggers are highlighted.These stages feature montages of footage of major events from their respective games. As an example, footage of the ballroom dance between Squall and Rinoa that takes place early in Final Fantasy VIII is set against the song "Waltz for the Moon". These videos can be unlocked for viewing separate from the gameplay.Challenge ModeIn Challenge Mode, the player may play any Battle, Field, or Event stage separate from the main story. If the player achieves an "A" ranking, an increased difficulty level is unlocked. Similar to the Rock Band series, there is also a "no fail" practice option for Challenge Mode.Chaos ShrineIn the Chaos Shrine, the player can take on challenging Dark Notes; pairs of Field and Battle songs set to a challenging difficulty level. When the player receives a Dark Note, the songs associated with it are unknown until the player plays it for the first time. Dark Notes can be collected over time and traded over StreetPass.MusicThe music tracks included in the game, with play type, are:Final FantasyField typeBattle typeEvent typeSpecial typeMain ThemeXGurgo VolcanoXBattle SceneXChaos ShrineXOpening ThemeXPreludeXEnding ThemeXCornelia CastleXFinal Fantasy IIField typeBattle typeEvent typeSpecial typeMain ThemeXBattle Theme 2XRebel Army ThemeXPreludeXFinaleXFinal Fantasy IIIField typeBattle typeEvent typeSpecial typeEternal WindXBattle 2XElia, the Maiden of WaterXPreludeXEnding ThemeXReturn of the WarriorXFinal Fantasy IVField typeBattle typeEvent typeSpecial typeMain Theme of Final Fantasy IVXGiant's DungeonXBattle with the Four FriendsXBattle 1XTheme of LoveXPreludeXEnding ThemeXFinal Fantasy VField typeBattle typeEvent typeSpecial typeFour HeartsXMambo De ChocoboXBattle at the Big BridgeXMy Home, Sweet HomeXMain Theme of Final Fantasy VXThe New OriginXFinal Fantasy VIField typeBattle typeEvent typeSpecial typeTerra's ThemeXSearching for FriendsXDecisive BattleXThe Fierce BattleXDancing MadXCeles's ThemeXOmenXEnding ThemeXFinal Fantasy VIIField typeBattle typeEvent typeSpecial typeMain Theme of Final Fantasy VIIXJudgement DayXOne-Winged AngelXJ-E-N-O-V-AXThose Who FightXAerith's ThemeXPreludeXStaff RollXFinal Fantasy VIIIField typBattle typeEvent typeSpecial typeBlue FieldsXThe Man with the Machine GunXWaltz for the MoonXOvertureXEyes On MeXFinal Fantasy IXField typeBattle typeEvent typeSpecial typeOver the HillsXSomething to ProtectXBattle 1XBeyond the DoorXThe Place I'll Return to SomedayXMelodies of LifeXFinal Fantasy XField typeBattle typeEvent typeSpecial typeMi'ihen HighroadXSeymour BattleXSuteki Da Ne (Isn't it Wonderful?)XTo ZanarkandXSuteki Da Ne: Orchestral VersionXFinal Fantasy XIField typeBattle typeEvent typeSpecial typeRonafaureXAwakeningXFinal Fantasy XI Opening ThemeXVana'del MarchXVana'diel March #2XFinal Fantasy XIIField typeBattle typeEvent typeSpecial typeGiza PlainsXClash of SwordsXTheme of the EmpireXFinal Fantasy Theme - Final Fantasy XII VersionXEnding MovieXFinal Fantasy XIIIField typeBattle typeEvent typeSpecial typeSunleth WaterscapeXSaber's EdgeXBlinded by LightXDefiers of FateXFinal Fantasy XIII - The PromiseXEnding CreditsXDLCIn addition to the songs included with the game, Square Enix is releasing additional tracks as DLC. Each track is available for $0.99. All DLC tracks feature Normal, Expert, and Ultimate difficulty variants and are either Field or Battle stages. The first batch of DLC songs available for Europe and North America included:SongGameBattle Theme 1Final Fantasy IIThe Final BattleFinal Fantasy IVFighters of the CrystalFinal Fantasy XIFighting FateFinal Fantasy XIIIIn Search of LightFinal Fantasy VCosmo CanyonFinal Fantasy VIIRide OnFinal Fantasy VIIIA Fleeting DreamFinal Fantasy XJuly 12th DLC Update:SongGameBattleFinal Fantasy VISarutabarutaFinal Fantasy XIDesperate StruggleFinal Fantasy XIIISomnusFinal Fantasy Versus XIIIJuly 19th DLC Update:SongGameBattle 1Final Fantasy IIIFight On!Final Fantasy VIIBattle ThemeFinal Fantasy XIEtro's ChampionFinal Fantasy XIII-2July 26th DLC Update:SongGameCrystal CaveFinal Fantasy IIIThe Sanctuary of Zi'TahFinal Fantasy XIA Contest of AeonsFinal Fantasy XThe Archlyte SteppeFinal Fantasy XIIIAugust 3rd DLC Update:SongGameSunken ShrineFinal Fantasy IMovement in GreenFinal Fantasy XFight On!Final Fantasy VIIBattle ThemeFinal Fantasy XAugust 10th DLC Update:SongGameBattle ThemeFinal Fantasy XIMarch of the DreadnoughtsFinal Fantasy XIIIBattle 2Final Fantasy IVEsper BattleFinal Fantasy XIIPack-in ExtrasFirst-run copies of Theatrhythm included a special stylus and a sheet of stickers featuring the primary Final Fantasy characters in the Theatrhythm art style. The stylus end features a display that can be decorated with a sticker from the sheet.</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23676">Osu!</game><game id="7037">Osu! Tatakae! Ouendan</game><game id="11982">Elite Beat Agents</game><game id="254">Moero! Nekketsu Rhythm Damashii Osu! Tatakae! Ouendan 2</game><game id="30577">K-On! After School Live!</game><game id="43979">Hatsune Miku: Project Mirai 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2188530-box_trff.png</image></root>