<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35931</id><name>World of Battles: Morningstar</name><description>OverviewWorld of Battles is a F2P RTS that has a progression system similar to that of an MMO. Up to 8 players can partake in any one battle, and each player can control 16 sets of units per battle.GameplayThere are a number of different races, each is aligned as either good, evil or neutral. The races currently in the game are:KnightsDwaresElvesDark ElvesOrcsUndeadBeast FolkBarbariansAmazonsEach player is allowed 10 armies, meaning that they can experiment with races and unit compositions at their will. The combat is very similar to that of a Total War game. The functions of the game are like most RTS games, you have attack moving, boxing of units, control groups, hotkeys etc.Each race have unique units, however they all function the same and can be catagorised in this fashion - Infantry, pikeman, archers and cavalry. These can then be broken down into light and heavy versions, each with their own bonuses and drawbacks. The main variety to the units comes from "Master Units". These are special units that have unique abilities depending on what race it is from.F2P ModelWoB uses a F2P system. This means that anyone can play the game without spending any money. However, as with all F2P games, there is an item mall, where players can purchase units, abilites etc. A big issue with the F2P model in WoB is that it leans heavily into the "pay to win" formula. Those that pay are able to have each unit be a Master Unit for example, therefore their army will be far superior, and no amount of tactics will save the day. This comes with the F2P ground, however balancing this formula is what makes a F2P game successful.Army CustomizatonEach unit can be customized with a large variety of equipment, that can be won through battle, and ofcourse, bought through the item mall. The types if equipment available include:ShieldsArmour suitsHelmetsGreavesMountsAmuletsBeltsEarringsRingsForever UpdatingAs this is a F2P title, Frogwares will forever be updating the game with new content. This includes new units, single player challenges, equipment, clan modes and battles and new game modes.System RequirementsMinimal:CPU: Intel Pentium 4 3 Ghz, AMD Athlon 3000+RAM: 1024 MB (2048MB: Windows 7, Windows Vista)VGA: NVIDIA GeForce 6600GT or ATI Radeon X1600, 128 MBDX: DirectX 9.0 (2008 march)OS: Windows XP SP3, Windows Vista, Windows 7Optimal:CPU: Intel Core 2 Duo, AMD Athlon X2 3GHzRAM: 2048 MBVGA: NVIDIA GeForce 8800 series or ATI Radeon 4800 series, 512 MBDX: DirectX 9.0 (2008 march)OS: Windows XP SP3, Windows Vista, Windows 7</description><genres><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4867">The Lord of the Rings: The Battle for Middle-earth II</game><game id="19641">Medieval: Total War</game><game id="13076">Age of Mythology</game><game id="22310">BattleForge</game><game id="8727">Dreamlords</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/13692/2200410-header_292x136.jpg</image></root>