<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35994</id><name>Tap Sonic</name><description>Released for iOS in January 2011, Tap Sonic has been one of the highest grossing mobile apps in the Korean marketplace to date. The game itself will look familiar to fans of Rock Band or Guitar Hero with notes coming down anywhere from 4 to 6 lanes towards a timing line. Tap the notes with the proper timing and your score and combo increases. It's payment system is unique in that players don't pay for individual songs, rather you purchase points that can be spent on single plays of each song in the songlist. Single plays cost anywhere from 15 to 30 MP, with some songs that can be purchased for 800-900 MP to play infinitely. The game requires an internet connection in order to function.  Fans of the DJMAX franchise will be familiar with many of the songs available in the title as the top songs from the various DJMAX titles have been included as lower cost songs. Much of the songlist otherwise is made up of chart topping K-Pop tracks, classical music, and a handful of licensed songs. The game is due for an August release in North America and according to the official Facebook page, is planned to have all of the songs included in the Korean version of the title along with a number of popular English language songs. New songs are added to the title every Monday.  Song List (Korean Licenses)Song NameArtist NamePremium? ARainbow Free Song  Chu~♡f(x)Yes  Stay With Me30' Spring Yes  We No Speak AmericanoLPG   She IsClazziquai Yes  으라차차Rumble Fish   DOC와 춤을DJ DOC   Mona LisaMBLAQYes  Hello HelloF.T IslandYes  It's YouSuper Junior Yes  LOVE SONGBigbang   No. 1BoA Yes  Bangkok CityOrange CaramelYes  Nothing's OverInfinite    Rush (feat. 정인)   리쌍  Up All NightFrench Horn Rebellion Yes  Supa Dupa DivaDai*shabetYes  아잉♡ Orange Caramel   That's The Way I Like ItKC  The Sunshine Band   12:00The KOXX   High HighGD  TOP   AbracadabraBrown Eyed Girls Yes  To Me RainbowYes 안을까말까of BEAST Yes  Top StarTony AnYes  oH! aH!SS501   Bo Peep Bo PeepT-ara Yes  Way To GoGirls Generation Yes  Ring Ding DongSHINee Yes  GenieGirls Generation Yes  TonightBigbang   Can't Nobody2NE1   Sorry, SorrySuper Junior Yes  We No Speak Americano (Radio Edit)Yolanda Be Cool  DCUP Yes  JumpingKara Yes  Run To YouDJ DOC  Right NowPsy 어쩌다Brown Eyed Girls하루하루Bigbang좋은 날 아이유어머나!장윤정앵그리(angry) LPGSong List (DJMAX Original Tunes) Song NameArtist Name Premium?  고백, 꽃, 늑대  ReXYesCloser 3rd Coast Yes Your Own MiracleRuby Tuesday  Free Song AccessSphazer   Eternal Fantasy (Vocal ver.)XeoN   Eternal MemoryM2U  Yes LoverNDLee  Yes MemoirsM2U  Yes RememberLin-G  Trip (Tap Mix)NieN  Yes 설레임NDLee  YesTo YouSweetune  ForeverBexter  Yes Cosmic Fantastic LovesongDINY  YesDIVINE SERVICEElectronic BoutiqueFateSTiYesGET OUTNDLeeLet's go baby3rd CoastYesLuv Flow3rd CoastYesMASAICrooveMelodyBermei.inazawa/UCYesNever SayNDLeeYesPuzzlerElectronic BoutiqueYesSecret WorldSweetuneSomedayNieNsO mUCH iN LUV3rd CoastSunny SideCrooveSweet Shining Shooting StarCrooveYesThe Last DanceUrbatronic ChopsticksWatch Your StepXeoNYesYNDLeeYes 고백, 꽃, 늑대 Pt.2 ReXYesEvery MorningNDLeeAIForte EscapeYesBeyond The Future7 SequenceBrand New DaysPlanetboomYesBye Bye Love3rd CoastYesDear My LadyOriental ST8YesDesperadoCrooveFallen AngelDJ MochaFTRSupbabyLovely HandsPlanetboomMess It UpNautsMilesElectronic BoutiqueYesOBLIVIONESTiYesONNDLeeYesPDMTrishPlay The FutureUrbatronic ChopsticksYesRuti'nBexterYesShorelineOriental ST8STALKERNDLeeSunset RiderNautsSweet DreamLin-GYesSyrianaBexterYesThe Guilty (Tap Mix)P'sycho -RemiYesXlasher (Tap Mix)Hosoe ShinjiYesLadymade StarESTiAsk To WindForte EscapeYesAirwaveReXYesBurn It DownP'sycho-RemiChemical SlaveXeoNYesCherokeexxdbxxCoastal Tempo3rd CoastYesDual Strikers7 SequenceEnd Of The MoonlightForte EscapeYesGet On TopPlanetboomHexadElectronic BoutiqueYesHigherSupbabyJupiter DrivingxxdbxxYesKeys To The World (Tap Mix)PlanetboomYesLa Campanella (Tap Mix)CrankyYesMidnight BloodNieNMy AliasDayzYesNANO RISKDayzYesNB RANGERS: ReturnsNieNOut LawCrooveYesRockSTARMr. FunkyYesStarfishPlanetboomYesSuperSonicPlanetboomYesSuperSonic (Mr. Funky Tap Mix)Mr. FunkyYesVanish LadyElectronic Boutique 피아노협주곡 1번WavFactoryBEE-U-TIFULFirst AidD2First AidYesEnemy StormCrooveYesI Want YouLin-GYesLight HousexxdbxxYesMind ControlNieNYesNB POWERNieNYesRolling On The DuckNieNYesSeekerM2UYesSinESTiYesSon Of SunHosoe ShinjiYesStop3rd CoastWhiteblueZtsHeart Of WitchReXBlytheM2UYesCypher Gate7 SequenceYesFermionMakouThorXeoNYesHamsinMakouYesNightmareM2UYes</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="31632">Guitar Hero</game><game id="29073">Rock Band</game><game id="34039">Tap Tap Revenge 4</game><game id="29383">Tap Tap Revenge 3</game><game id="25484">Tap Tap Revenge 2</game><game id="21290">Tap Tap Revenge</game><game id="33636">Tap Tap Radiation</game><game id="2540">Pulse</game><game id="33349">jubeat plus</game><game id="40029">DJMAX Ray</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/23793/1847925-aaa.jpg</image></root>