<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3602</id><name>ESPN International Track &amp; Field</name><description>ESPN International Track  Field is a sporting game developed and published by KCEO for the PlayStation 2, and Dreamcast platforms.OverviewDeveloped by Konami Computer Entertainment Osaka and Published by Konami of America, ESPN International Track and Field is a track and field style sports game released September 26, 2000.Events100M Dash110M HurdlesLong JumpPole VaultJavelin Throw100M FreestyleWeight LiftingHorizontal BarTrap ShootingRhythmic GymnasticsNations Australia Canada United States of America China France Germany Great Britain Italy Kenya Japan Netherlands Russia SpainChampionship ModeIn Championship mode, the player has the option to play through all 10 events, or any event of their choice under the banner of their chosen nation. Entering any name is an option, otherwise the name will default to M. Greene, A. Boldon, or J. Hartwig (Maurice Greene, Ato Boldon, and Jeff Hartwig consulted on the game).A tutorial plays before each event, demonstrating the controls. During the event, you can review the controls from the menu.Every event can be played multiplayer. Up to four people can compete at the same time using the Multitap for PlayStation 2.TriviaIn the manual for ESPN International Track and Field, their is a portion of the text that refers to the purchased game as "Gradius III  IV," which was a compilation collection released for the PlayStation 2 earlier in the year 2000. The Copyright information is also in regards to Gradius III  IV, not to ESPN International Track and Field itself.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="42">Track &amp; Field</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7309">Stadium Events</game><game id="16391">Virtua Athlete 2K</game><game id="13877">Sydney 2000</game><game id="17259">Athens 2004</game><game id="6820">International Track and Field 2000</game><game id="22678">Summer Athletics</game><game id="15063">The Activision Decathlon</game><game id="30390">Triple Shot Sports</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4647/839963-258279_43468_front.jpg</image></root>