<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36028</id><name>Black Death</name><description>Black death is a survival horror game from the indie developer Darkworks.Main PlotOne city on the american north east coast is suddenly hit by a massive cloud of smoke,Mysterious swirls of this black smoke appear and infect everyone living in the city.The inhabitans mutate into strange creatures with various powers and group behaviours, they start to become violent and invade every part of the city.The player is a survivor who will try to stay alive and get rid of this very strange smoke.WeaponsThe game will have several futuristic guns and a few real guns. PistolJust a regular pistol that looks a lot like the one in F.E.A.R (AT-15)The pistol in 3rd person The Gun in Action           ShotgunA single barrel shotgun that looks like a mix of a older shotgun in 3rd person and in first person it looks like the one from DOOM 3           The Chemical Bloweris a gun that shoots a beam of mixed chemicals that can be for and example Motor oil and Fertilizer.            The Chemical blower in action           Mixing ChemicalsThe ammunition for the Chemical blower is different Chemicals that can be found around the map. You put them into a small Chemical mixer and then you got some ammunition for the Chemical Blower. Different chemicals make different effects.Cleaning Supplies Fertilizer  Motor Oil  Chemical Blender        Public Test(Prototype)The Chemical Blower Concept ArtThe game is released in a Prototype version that's a public test so all the game play mechanics will work correctly and feel okay.It can be downloaded here!In the prototype the health regeneration is done by a shot that the player injects into the arm.This injector can also be used to collect DNA samples from different mutants around the map.SoundtrackThe soundtrack is made by Low Distortion UnitSystem RequirementsOS: Windows 7, Windows Vista, Windows XPProcessor: Intel Core 2 Duo minimumRAM: 1GB minimum and 2GB are recommendedHDD Space: 500mbVideocard: DirectX 9.0c compatibleSoundcard: DirectX 9.0c compatibleIt's only tested with a X360 controller for PC</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20663">F.E.A.R. 2: Project Origin</game><game id="15596">F.E.A.R.: Perseus Mandate</game><game id="11787">F.E.A.R.: Extraction Point</game><game id="8804">Condemned: Criminal Origins</game><game id="20465">Condemned 2: Bloodshot</game><game id="19631">Cold Fear</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/10/101066/1850618-03_blackdeath_r_2011_06_24_11_29_38_97.jpg</image></root>