<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36025</id><name>Groove Coaster</name><description>OverviewGroove Coaster is a rhythm game that involves players interacting with the iOS device by tapping, holds, slides, scratching or rapidly tapping in beat to one of the songs in the included soundtrack. The goal is to hit enough notes to fill a meter to be able to complete a level in one of three difficulty levels to unlock the next song.The game was developed by the Space Invaders Infinity Gene team at Taito and it shows, as it shares a similar art style with Infinity Gene.Leveling SystemThe game has a persistent leveling system like that of Inifinty Gene in which a meter fills up between songs based on the score obtained from said song. When the meter fills up, the player is awarded a bonus such as new type of ship or a skin.RankingA grade from E-S is awarded based on score, number of notes hit, accuracy (the game grades taps either 'Good', 'Great' or 'Cool') having a combo and freestyling taps (which the game referes to 'ad-libs').ShipsThe player can choose one of a handful of ships, with most of them locked, and each has thier own type of bonus such as faster filling of the song completion meter to loosening the timing of getting a Great on notes. Ships based on various Space Invaders can be unlocked.ItemsItems can be purchased from the in game store for $0.99. Each item assists the player in playing such as making up to 10 missed taps turn in to 10 good taps.SkinsAn assortment of skins can be choosen before a song that changes the background and various effects.SoundtrackThere are 21 songs included with the game:TitleArtistDurationDifficultyThe BeginningCOSIO2:110Music Plot Type ZeroCOSIO1:051Play merrilyShohei Tsuchiya2:093StreetwalkerShohei Tsuchiya2:112Not get wishShohei Tsuchiya2:114Revenge Of ArkanoidLil'B1:262Happy Smiling -More Happy Mix-COSIO1:335Breach of faithShohei Tsuchiya2:194Invade YouCOSIO1:543Neptune DivingCOSIO1:316You've Gatta LuvShu Nakazawa1:327I CANNOT APECOSIO2:116Fun-HouseCOSIO1:567GekiShohei Tsuchiya1:467Cardiac RhythmCOSIO1:568Spring to mindShohei Tsuchiya1:345Eurythmics TripCOSIO1:467Just no friendShohei Tsuchiya1:508Protocol Signal GenerationCOSIO2:088Fess up!Shohei Tsuchiya1:396Thrash BeatCOSIO2:026There are more songs available via DLC obtained through the in-game store.</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7477">Phase</game><game id="21290">Tap Tap Revenge</game><game id="17695">musika</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/26/1850434-screen_shot_2011_07_30_at_11.19.49_am.png</image></root>