<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36058</id><name>Port Royale 3: Pirates &amp; Merchants</name><description>The campaign in Port Royale 3 effectively splits into two routes and gives the player a choice between playing as a tightfisted trader or a swashbucklin' adventurer out for plunder. The free-play mode returns, giving players more of a sandbox experience with promises that "Naval battles, coastal city sieges, raids and plunder" are featured. Port Royale 3 will feature a multiplayer mode, which Kalypso claims "will pit players head-to-head using commercial, economic and conquest simulations to allow for fast-paced gameplay."Features of Port Royale 3Two different single player campaigns: that of the dealer and the adventurer.Thrilling sea battles, coastal city-sieges, raids and looting await the adventurous player to wait while immense wealth and power to commercially oriented players.Sixteen different types of vessels, such as powerful galleons.Commercial space with 60 fully different cities of Port-au-Prince to Tortuga.Competitive multiplayer mode for up to four players.A fully simulated product cycle ensures a dynamic trading system, the prices are calculated--as in the real world--from a complex interplay of supply and demand.Port Royale 3 is being released first on PC and will see a later release for consoles.PC System Requirements:Minimum:OS: Windowx XP / Vista / 7Processor: Dualcore CPUMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: Shader Model 2.0 PCIe (Geforce 7 Series, Radeon X2000-Series)DirectX®: dx90cHard Drive: 3 GB HD spaceOther Requirements: Broadband Internet connectionRecommended:OS: Windows 7Processor: Quadcore CPUMemory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: Shader Model 3.0 PCIe, DirectX 10DirectX®: dx10Hard Drive: 3 GB HD spaceOther Requirements: Broadband Internet connection</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1415">Sid Meier's Pirates!</game><game id="23459">Dawn of Discovery</game><game id="995">1701 A.D.</game><game id="35875">Pirates of Black Cove</game><game id="41179">Caribbean!</game><game id="43340">Rise of Venice</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2323875-box_pr3.png</image></root>