<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3605</id><name>Ace Combat 2</name><description>Ace Combat 2 is released in 1997 for Playstation, and later again in 2005 for PlayStation 2 as part NamCollection to celebrate Namco's 50th anniversary. Ace Combat 2 continues it's predecessor's arcade style gameplay, but with numerous graphical improvements to both the models and environment. Notably, Ace Combat 2 was the first game in the series to incorporate Ace Pilots, distinguishable from ordinary pilots by being labelled on the HUD under various aliases. The player can unlock twice as many aircraft as Air Combat, ranging from the Multirole F/A-18E to Stealth Bomber F-117a Nighthawk. While the story is very basic, it lays the ground work for later games; similar maps and Aces are featured in it's successors. Depending on the player's actions there are three different endings.AircraftsA-4 SkyhawkF-4E Phantom IIMiG-21 FishbedKfir C.7A-6E IntruderF-16C Fighting FalconX-29AJ35J DrakenA-10A Thunderbolt IISu-25 FrogfootMiG-29A FulcrumF-14A TomcatTornado F.3F-117A NighthawkRafale MMiG-31 FoxhoundEF-2000 TyphoonJAS-39C GripenF/A-18E Super HornetSu-35 Super FlankerF-15S/MTDYF-23A Black Widow IIF-22A RaptorXFA-27AcesThe game features enemy "aces", or above-average skilled fighters. The players will be reward a medal by shooting them down in a mission, once all medal have obtained , they can be view in the Options Menu.Mission 2: Easy MoneyAce: 1F-4E Phantom II "Superfly"Mission 4A: Tin CastleAce: 1MiG-29A Fulcrum "Ricochet"Mission 4B: Opera HouseAce: 2Su-25 Frogfoot "D-Cowboy"Mission 6A: Midnight AssassinAce: 2F-117A Nighthawk "Razorback"Mission 6B: Bear TracksAce: 2F-117A Nighthawk "Razorback"Mission 7: SledgehammerAce: 1F-14A Tomcat "Z.O.E." (Captain)Mission 9: SwordsmithAce: 2F-16C Fighting Falcon "Tallman"F-16C Fighting Falcon "Metal Sphere"Mission 10: Toy BoxAce: 1MiG-31 Foxhound "Stalker"Mission 11: SeagullAce: 32 Rafale M "Hangmen" SquadronF/A-18E Super Hornet "Z.O.E." (Major)Mission 13: Power PlayAce: 1YF-22 Lightning II "Z.O.E." (Colonel)Mission 14A: El Dorado (Alphaville branch)Ace: 2Tornado F.3 "Max"Tornado F.3 "Goose"Mission 14B: Dark Star (Bellissima branch)Ace: 3EF-2000 Typhoon "Death Rave 2000 Squadron"Missoin 15A: St. Elmo's Fire (Alphaville branch)Ace: 3F-15E Strike Eagle "Xiao"F-15E Strike Eagle "Jian"F-15E Strike Eagle "Dao"Mission 15B: Dead End (Bellissima branch)Ace: 4YF-23A Black Widow II "Fox Force Four"Mission 19: KingpinAce: 1F-15S/MTD "Z.O.E." (General)Mission 21: Fighter's HonorAce: 1ADF-01 Falken ZOE "Z.O.E." (Commander)SoundtracksIn Ace Combat 2, it's was the first game to have huge leap for the Ace Combat series. The Rock/Electronic tunes were made specifically to raise the tension during gameplay and create a new gaming experiance.MainAerial HawkAim HighBear TracksBlow AwayBriefingDead EndDynapolisDystopiaEI DoradoElemental ParticleFire AwayFire YoungmanInto the GEOMelt DownNight and DayOn the SlyRising HighSunset GlowWarning LineOtherA Fresh YoungsterCompletionEnding 1Ending 2Ending AtractFailureLode StoneLogoMissionOpeningSelectInvitation PromoInvitation to Ace Combat 2Night ButterflyA.C. Revolution</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="24">Flight Simulator</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4928">F-22 Lightning II</game><game id="22030">Jet Impulse</game><game id="20458">Warhawk</game><game id="2139">After Burner II</game><game id="4589">Independence Day</game><game id="12271">A-10 Cuba!</game><game id="24983">Stormbirds</game><game id="18377">Heroes of the Pacific</game><game id="7790">AirForce Delta</game><game id="17739">AeroFighters Assault</game><game id="31133">Sidewinder 2</game><game id="4075">Wing Arms</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2092575-box_ac2.png</image></root>