<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36067</id><name>Destiny</name><description>OverviewDestiny was first teased in an easter egg in Halo 3: ODST.Destiny is an multiplayer-focused first-person shooter from Bungie, the original developers of the Halo franchise. It will be published by Activision and marks Bungie's first foray into development for Sony consoles since the release of Oni. It has currently been confirmed for release on the Xbox 360, Xbox One, PlayStation 3, and PlayStation 4. It was confirmed at E3 2013 that the game will be released sometime in 2014.Destiny is said to be Bungie's focus for the next 10 years, with the developer working to expand its universe beyond this first game. How those expansions will take shape and be sold remains to be seen, but the team has gone on-record and stated that Destiny will not require a monthly fee to play.Destiny is set in our solar system, and players will form groups and traverse the galaxy in player-owned ships to conduct first-person shooter missions on planets like Mars and Venus. Humankind has been beaten back into one long city that sits beneath the Traveler, a large, mysterious sphere that helped defend the human race--or what's left of it--from various alien threats. Players will take on multiple enemy races in Destiny, including time-travelling robots, hulking rhino men, and more.GameplayA fireteam of three players out in the worldUnlike Bungie's past work, the story in Destiny is built around custom characters. The game has a class-based system, and three classes--Hunter, Titan, and Warlock--have been revealed as of this writing. In addition to firing rifles, pistols, rocket launchers, and sniper rifles, players will also have access to magic-like abilities, granted by the Traveler.Three weapons can be equipped at a time, and more can be carried in the inventory. The three slots are called "primary", "special", and "heavy". Every player also has a small speeder bike vehicle currently called the Sparrow and can be used to traverse larger areas. Characters will also have access to their own customizable spaceship, but it will not be player controlled nor will there be space combat. It's more of a means to fast travel. Glimmer, small blue bits that drop from killed enemies, is a currency or crafting material needed to upgrade at least some, if not all, weapons that are upgradable.As an online-only game, Destiny will feature separate, third-person social spaces where players can collect, group up, and prepare for the missions ahead. Some mission zones will also be public spaces, allowing for players to encounter each other while out in the field and group up on-the-fly. Bungie has stated that the goal is to not show lobbies, matchmaking, or connection screens, instead delivering a more seamless experience. Player-versus-player combat will not be a factor out in the general world, but the game will feature some sort of competitive multiplayer component. Player counts for public spaces are not known at this time and will likely vary depending on the platform and network connection of the player.LootExotic Hunter cloaksDestiny is a loot driven game. Weapons, armor, and wearable items can be found in the world when players are on a mission or just exploring. When loot is collected from a killed enemy only one player needs to run over the glowing orb representing the loot and it will automatically be distributed among the group if the player isn't alone. All armor and clothing items will have properties that effect gameplay, but Bungie hasn't said to what degree. Exotic gear is the name Bungie has given to rare items within the world of Destiny. These items will have a unique look to them and special names.StoryThe Traveler floats above the last human citySome time ago, there was once a Golden Age of human spacefaring. A mysterious orb called The Traveler made its way to Earth, jumpstarting human technology and allowing them to colonize the worlds of the Solar System. But humanity was eventually pushed back by some unknown force, only surviving by the intervention and "sacrifice" of The Traveler, below which now sits humankind's last remaining settlement, a lone city.Now, in the present time, humans have managed to recover their technology to the point of being able to travel into space again, but they discover that their former colonies have now become occupied by several alien races, who are pushing towards conquering the last human city. Warriors known as Guardians are tasked with protecting the city and fighting against the aliens to order to restore humanity to its former glory.Ghost, voiced by Game of Thrones star Peter Dinklage, is a customizable AI companion issued to every Guardian in The City. It/He will do things for you like interacting with the environment to activate a building's lights and alerting you to incoming enemies. Bungie has alluded that Ghost may play a larger part in the story than his seemingly basic role may lead one to believe.SpeciesThere are several alien species fighting against humanity in Destiny, though they also have their own allies.Playable SpeciesPlayer race is purely a cosmetic choice and has no effect on gameplay.HumansA sapient species whose homeworld is Earth. They are described as "relatable, tough, and uncomplicated". Bungie drew inspiration for humans from such things as real-life military, sports stars, and action movie heroes.ExoA race allied with humanity. They are described as "sinister, powerful, and tireless". Bungie drew inspiration for the Exo from such things as Halo's Master Chief, The Terminator, and the undead.AwokenAnother race allied with humanity. They are described as "exotic, beautiful, and mysterious." Bungie drew inspiration for the Awoken from such things as elves, vampires, ghosts, and angels.Enemy SpeciesThe CabalBig, hulking bipeds that wear heavy armor and wield heavy weapons. So far, it is known that they occupy Mars.The FallenA six-limbed race (four arms, two legs) who have been extensive in their conquest of the solar system, having occupied all planets and moons that humanity had encountered. As their name implies, they were once a collective of noble houses that fell from grace into nomads. They also have an interesting death animation that looks like their soul is escaping from their bodyThe HiveSpace zombies. They are designed to capture a feeling of "undead royalty".The VexTime-traveling robots. Bungie claims that they have a very interesting fiction.Player ClassesThree classes have been revealed so far: the Hunter, the Warlock, and the Titan. All classes can use "space magic", and all classes can use all weapon types. A class is described by Bungie as a choice to "fine tune" your Guardian so that there will be little regret in a player's choice. A player is also able to have multiple characters.HunterA combination of speed and strength, their signature weapons appear to be sniper rifles and revolvers. Hunters can be recognized by their hooded capes and relatively light armor. Before becoming Guardians, Hunters were once outlaws who roamed the wastelands.They were designed to invoke the image of a Wild West outlaw and the classic bounty hunter. Some of their inspirations were Han Solo and Clint Eastwood's Man with No Name.Possible "space magic" abilities include:The Traveler's Light - Imbuing your weapons with powers temporarily (such as fire)Summoning small red orbs that seek out and attack enemiesBungie has described their armor to cloth ratio as 50:50.WarlockGuardians who have long studied The Traveler and are able to wield its gifts of "magic", alongside modern weaponry. Warlocks can be recognized by their long coats and rounded helmets.They were designed to invoke the image of a "space wizard". Some of their inspirations were Jedi Knights, Gandalf, and Morpheus.Possible "space magic" abilities include:Solar Flare - Conjure the power of the sun and release it like a grenade.Nova Bomb - Channel some of the Traveler’s mysterious forces and unleash them in an explosive, large area-of-effect attackGlide - Summons the forces around you to increase and sustain elevation after jumping.Bungie has described their armor to cloth ratio as 20:80.TitanGuardians who specialize in heavy armor and powerful weaponry. The first Titans built The Wall which protects the last city. Titans can be recognized by their full body armor and swept-back helmets.They were designed to invoke the image of the classic future soldier. Some of their inspirations include Halo's Master Chief, Stormtroopers from Star Wars, and other space marines from sci-fi.Possible "space magic" abilities include:A release of blue energy on the ground that has an area of effect.Bungie has described their armor to cloth ratio as 80:20.   LocationsEarthThe Last CityThe vast majority of the human race now resides in the City, built under the Traveler after it's sacrifice to save Earth's inhabitants. With a massive wall surrounding it, the Guardians are tasked with protecting this city.Overwatch District - An out of combat hub location where players are able to interact as well as travel to other locations in the solar system.The Tower - A place of residence for the Guardians.Old RussiaOld ChicagoThe ReefA debris field in orbit including a space station, and is home to the Queen of the Reef whom the player can receive bounty missions from.Mumbai PushLunaHellmouthA man made complex that goes into the moon's surface.MarsMars CityLike the Last City on Earth, this Martian city has multiple districts within it. However, it is also partially occupied by the Cabal, a race of large humanoid beastsDust Palace - A social district for players similar to that of Overwatch back on Earth.Exclusion Zone - Ruins beneath the Dust Palace and crawling with Cabal. It also houses Charlemagne's Vault which is filled with gold an loot for players to retrieve, and a bounty location for missions given by the Queen of the Reef.MercuryVenusShores of TimeJupiterSaturnCassini FleetA group of derelict ships in orbit around Saturn that can be scavenged by players.UranusNeptune FactionsNo information about factions has been revealed so far, other than their names and emblems.NameEmblemDead OrbitFWCNew MonarchyOsirisSeven Seraphs </description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="31772">Journey</game><game id="6582">Test Drive Unlimited</game><game id="32712">Phantasy Star Online 2</game><game id="9993">Halo 3</game><game id="35533">Halo 4</game><game id="2600">Halo: Combat Evolved</game><game id="30615">Gears of War 3</game><game id="20662">Gears of War 2</game><game id="35523">Defiance</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/6/63119/2553216-boxart+destiny.jpg</image></root>