<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36062</id><name>Nitronic Rush</name><description>OverviewNitronic Rush is a PC game made by Team Nitronic, a group of students from DigiPen Institute of Technology. It was made entirely from scratch in C++ and was released on PC as a digital download for free on 11/11/2011.GameplayNitronic Rush is described as an experimental survival driving game, where using the car's abilities (including boost, wings, and jump), you can avoid obstacles that the city throws at you. In many ways the game is a tribute to racing games of the 1990′s, but with fresh graphics, audio, and gameplay.Game ModesStory Mode: Play though six level of the main story campaign.Hardcore Mode: Intensely challenging, gravity-defying, parkour-inspired levels.Challenge Mode: Quick challenging levels that test specific skills.Stunt Mode: Race against the clock in different arenas to get the highest score.Old Levels: See a peek into how the story mode levels and music were developed over several iterations.The game also features a full achievement system. Here you can work on progressing in various skills of the game, as well as see stats on how you're progressing so far.DevelopmentFour programmers and a designer started the project the summer before Junior year at DigiPen, and after 17 months later there are 11 team members in total. This now includes four artists for concept art and some modeling, as well as a full time sound designer and an assistant composer.TechnologyThe entire game (including the advanced graphics, physics, and architecture) was developed from the ground up using C++ for the PC (Windows 7) platform. It was not created as a mod or using any pre-made engines such as Unity or Unreal.The graphics technology includes an advanced deferred lighting engine, bloom, motion blur, and particle engine all written from scratch.The physics technology includes Minkowski Portal Refinement, dynamic axis-aligned bounding box spatial partitioning, arbitrary mesh collision, and a full car suspension system also coded from the ground up.The music for the game was also entirely composed by team members Jordan Hemenway and M.J. Quigley. The game features a unique dynamically adaptive music system that allows music to change dramatically as the player progresses through the game and uses various abilities. The sound design also incorporates use of on-the-fly DSP, Dopper effects, side-chaining, and dynamic compression using the Audiokinetic Wwise API.PC System RequirementsOperating System: Windows XP, Vista, 7Processor: 1.7 GHz Dual Core or GreaterRAM Memory: 2 GBHard Disk Space: 1.0 GBVideo Card: 512 MB DirectX 9.0c compatible graphics cardDirectX®: 9.0cController: Xbox 360 controller or keyboardAudio Setup: High quality headphones or speakers</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="28194">TrackMania² Canyon</game><game id="20610">WipEout HD</game><game id="8949">S.T.U.N. Runner</game><game id="12857">N₂O Nitrous Oxide</game><game id="4388">Hot Wheels: Turbo Racing</game><game id="40779">Distance</game><game id="40348">TrackMania² Valley</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/38405/1853979-nitroniclogo.jpg</image></root>