<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36104</id><name>Card Hunter</name><description>OverviewCard Hunter is an online collectible card game with some twists:It’s free-to-play and you win cards by playing the game, not by buying booster packs.Search dungeons to find treasure and then equip your loot to build out your decks.Use your cards to move your characters and battle monsters’ decks.GameplayPlayers build a party of three members. Each member can be a male or female of the Dwarven, Elven or Human races. There are also three classes in the game consisting of Warriors, Wizards and Priests. Both the race and class of a character affects the cards available for use. Race modifies the characters deck like being able to use tricks for drawing cards, having enhanced movement or being more durable. Class affects specialization of a character:Wizards - long range attacks and AOE spellsWarriors - hard-hitting melee attacks and armorPriests - healing and buffing party membersEach party member has their own deck of cards they use in turn-based battles. Decks consist of Armor, Attack, Block, Boost, Drawback, Assist, Movement and Utility cards. The way to add or change cards within the deck are to obtain loot from treasure chests and equipping them to your party members. Different levels of rarity (Common, Uncommon, Rare and Epic) determine the quality of cards associated with them (Black, Paper, Bronze, Silver, Gold, Emerald and Amethyst). Card Hunter offers two modes of play; Campaign Mode and Multiplayer Mode. Campaign mode allows the player to level their heroes as well as obtaining loot. This loot can be carried over into Multiplayer Mode where all characters are at max level for a fair competitive environment. Players can have widely different parties because of the deck-building from different combinations of equipment and classes within the party.*Blue Manchu is currently working on a co-op mode against the AI. Design Consulting:Richard Garfield (Magic: The Gathering, Netrunner, Star Wars Trading Card Game, and SolForge) and Skaff Elias (Magic: The Gathering, and Star Wars Trading Card Game) are design consultants for Card Hunter to ensure the game has quality card collecting aspects. Payment ModelCard Hunter is a free-to-play game for browsers. Everything in the game is obtainable by looting chests or spending in-game gold at shops. Players have the choice of spending real-world money for pizza slices which can be spent on new character costumes, varying qualities of loot chests as well as multiplayer starter packs which contain 3 party members equipped with medium-grade items.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="13">Card Game</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="42624">Magic: The Gathering - Duels of the Planeswalkers 2014</game><game id="42033">Hearthstone: Heroes of Warcraft</game><game id="40643">Dominion Online</game><game id="42040">SolForge</game><game id="23609">Magic: The Gathering - Duels of the Planeswalkers</game><game id="37907">Magic: The Gathering - Duels of the Planeswalkers 2013</game><game id="32698">Disgaea 4: A Promise Unforgotten</game><game id="29233">Disgaea Infinite</game><game id="38393">Crimson Shroud</game><game id="24967">Disgaea 2: Dark Hero Days</game><game id="22722">Disgaea DS</game><game id="2652">Disgaea 2: Cursed Memories</game><game id="40157">Disgaea D2: A Brighter Darkness</game><game id="27994">Final Fantasy Tactics: The War of the Lions</game><game id="18540">Disgaea: Hour of Darkness</game><game id="9532">Disgaea: Afternoon of Darkness</game><game id="19864">Final Fantasy Tactics</game><game id="34301">Scrolls</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1992/2349312-ch_logo_paper.jpeg</image></root>