<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36133</id><name>Dynasty Warriors 7: Xtreme Legends</name><description>OverviewDynasty Warriors 7: Xtreme Legends is a standalone expansion to Koei's Dynasty Warriors 7. As with other Xtreme Legends titles, the game adds new playable characters and scenarios to the content of the core game, or it can be played on its own. It was released in North America on November 15, 2011.New CharactersDynasty Warriors 7: Xtreme Legends is the first Xtreme Legends of the Dynasty Warriors series to introduce new characters. A total of three new characters were added, all being of the Wei faction.Guo JiaMain Weapon: Orb and ScepterCao Cao's adviser who died young shortly after the Battle of Guandu. Deemed a genius tactician; Cao Cao lamented that the Battle of Chibi would've been won if Guo Jia had still been alive. Guo Jia was the winner of a new Dynasty Warriors character poll held in Famitsu magazine.Pang DeMain Weapon: Twin HalberdsWarrior of the Wei army, famous for his accomplishments, and subsequent death, at Fan Castle against the armies of Guan Yu. Pang De is returning to the series from Dynasty Warriors 5, after being one of the omitted characters from Dynasty Warriors 6.Wang YiMain Weapon: Twin SaiOne of the few women of the Three Kingdoms era to have actually participated in battle. She fought against Ma Chao after his defeat at Tong Gate. Her story line in Dynasty Warriors 7: Xtreme Legends, she joins Cao Cao with intentions of exacting revenge on Ma Chao for the death of her family.New FeaturesLegend ModeIn addition to new characters, Dynasty Warriors 7: Xtreme Legends also includes a Legend Mode, which in itself is split into two different scenario types:Hero StagesHero stages consist of the same seamless transition from cutscenes to gameplay just like the story mode in Dynasty Warriors 7. However, instead of focus on the kingdom as a whole, it will focus more on specific characters with more emphasis on the three new characters.Legend StagesLegend stages are stages that have been brought back from previous Dynasty Warriors titles, updated and remade to fit in with the rest of the game.New WeaponsOrb and ScepterTwin SaiScimitar (decloned moveset for Xiahou Dun)Dragon Spear (decloned moveset for Zhao Yun)Crescent Blade (decloned moveset for Guan Yu)Serpent Pike (decloned moveset for Zhang Fei)Treasure WeaponsMore powerful weapons can now be obtained through the completion of specific objectives and requirements must be met in order to obtain the desired weapon.PC System RequirementsCPU: Intel Core2Duo 2.4GHz or equivalentOperating system: Windows XP SP3/Vista/7Memory: 1 GBHard drive: 13 GB to free spaceDisplay with 1280  215; 720, High ColorVideo Card: 256 MB of memorySound card with DirectX 9.0c.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="37103">Sengoku Basara 3 Utage</game><game id="6513">Bladestorm: The Hundred Years' War</game><game id="38478">Sengoku Basara HD Collection</game><game id="37019">Dynasty Warriors Next</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/6228/2080470-dw7xl_u.s._box_art.jpg</image></root>