<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36147</id><name>Worms Crazy Golf</name><description>OverviewWorms Crazy Golf adapts traditional Worms combat gameplay to a more peaceful goal: sinking a short putt. Instead of blowing up enemy teams of worms, players of Worms Crazy Golf must choose the right club to get their ball from tee to hole in as few shots as possible, using explosive sheep, magnets, and mines as necessary to do so. Players control the power, angle, and spin of their shots, attempting to set up chain reactions that can help collect all the coins and crates on any given level while aiming for an Eagle or Birdie.The original release includes three 18-hole courses with different themes: Britannia, Pirate Cavern, and Graveyard. Each can be played either in the single-player career mode or in hotseat multiplayer. Single-player progress also unlocks special challenge levels, in which the player has a short amount of time to complete a special objective, like hitting all the explosive sheep scattered through a course, competing for a spot at the top of an online leaderboard.CustomizationPlayers can customize their golfer's voice, appearance, and set of clubs with unlockables, earned through hitting crates in hard-to-reach spots of each hole and paid for with coins scattered throughout the courses. Voices range from different nationalities like Italian and German to special choices like the Advertisement Spokesman voice. Worms can earn new hats of various sorts and special ball designs like the soccer ball or a monochrome ball. Different clubs have better ability levels in power, control, and accuracy, providing bonuses as the game goes on.Carnival Course DLCOn October 27, 2011, a free DLC pack was released featuring the Carnival Course. It includes 18 new holes, 5 new challenges with leaderboard support, and a new bouncy ball utility. Also included is 4 new hats, 3 new golf balls, and 2 speech banks.</description><genres><genre id="28">Golf</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20598">Hot Shots Golf: Out of Bounds</game><game id="5160">3D Ultra Minigolf Adventures</game><game id="5792">Worms Blast</game><game id="11999">Worms Forts: Under Siege</game><game id="11673">Lemmings Paintball</game><game id="15377">Sid Meier's SimGolf</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/15/155745/2168072-worms_crazy_golf_key_art.jpg</image></root>