<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36155</id><name>Cart Life</name><description>OverviewAn indie game with a lo-fi style to it, Cart Life is a management simulator centered around a person's working and personal life. Each of the playable characters are self-employed street vendors and every day they must earn income to pay for their expenses whilst at the same time deal with their own personal matters.The game is now available (free of charge) and can be found at: http://richardhofmeier.com/cartlife/GameplayEach character owns and personally runs a stall which acts as their primary source of income throughout the game. Depending on the stall, they sell certain items but they can expand their inventory to serve more customers. Money is highly important as everyday needs such as food and rent require payment otherwise they'll face eviction and/or poor performance at work. Besides that, careful management of sleep and their unique trait (such as the need to smoke) are just as important.Game play is quite open ended but fairly linear as players are allowed to travel to specific points throughout Georgetown using various modes of transport (taxi, train and walking). They can explore the town, talk to it's inhabitants, make friends or buy items for personal use or for restocking supplies. With enough money, upgrades can also be bought for the stalls. The game takes place over a week with each shop and NPC running on their unique schedule. Every now and again, scripted special encounters can provide bonuses or penalties depending on how they are handled.CharactersThere are three playable characters and each one has their own unique goal to achieve before next Monday as well as their own traits that require tending to.Melanie EmberlyMelanie and LauraA recent divorcee who had to quit her job at her office as a result. Now, Melanie runs a Coffee Hut. Her goal is to amass a sum of one thousand dollars in sales by custody hearing on Monday whilst at the same time take care of her daughter, Laura. She cares for her daughter deeply so it is important to pick Laura up from school every day. Melanie is a very friendly person and thus customers warm up to her easily. Her sister Gina cooks dinner every night.Andrus PoderAndrus PoderA immigrant hailing from the country of Ukraine. Andrus moved to the U.S. in hopes of starting a new life. He runs a newspaper stand that sells the local newspaper, The Georgetownian. He lives in at Breezy's Motel with his beloved cat, Mr Glembovski. Andrus has an excellent work ethic (meaning longer working days) and is not a picky eater therefore he does not get hungry as quickly as other characters. Unfortunately, he started smoking at a young age and thus craves cigarettes from time to time.Vinny*An owner of a bagel cart. Vinny must earn at least five hundred dollars to pay for his rent. Vinny has recently started to drink coffee and as a result he has become addicted to caffeine. While caffeinated, Vinny walks faster but lack of it leads to fatigue and impaired speed. He is an excellent baker which allows him to make a variety of bagels to sell.*Vinny is only available in the Everything Edition that can be purchase for $5 off the developer's site and also the Steam version of the game. System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Windows 95Hard Drive: 200 MB HD spaceAdditional: 640x400 ResolutionRecommended:OS: XP or BetterHard Drive: 200 MB HD spaceAdditional: 640x400 Resolution</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/4/47410/1861951-cartlife.png</image></root>