<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36185</id><name>Divinity: Dragon Commander</name><description>Gameplay SetupThe gameplay setup of Dragon Commander is going to feature elements from three genres melded into one: RTS, RPG, and Boardgame.In the RTS segment of the game, players will be allowed to directly participate in battles alongside whatever forces they have deployed as a jetpack-equipped Dragon. This jetpack will allow the dragon to swiftly move across the entire battlefield or effectively activate a bullet-time mode to help evade the storms of projectiles enemy fleets and bases will throw at you. The RTS elements come in with how players will be able to give orders to the squadrons of their army either directly from the dragon's 3rd person perspective or through a panned-out map. Each squadron must be led by a commander you find or recruit, with each one giving different bonuses and/or traits to their assigned squadron.Outside of the RTS battles, players will get to manage their Mothership. Within the Mothership are options for upgrading your units, talking with various characters on the ship and possibly dealing with their issues, and interacting with whatever princess you have chosen to bring aboard. The princess is particularly important with how she can unlock certain cards for you. These cards can be applied to any battles you begin and have various bonuses, such as increasing certain stats for your units, granting your dragon additional attack types, and spawning additional units or different unit types for your deployed army. The way the Mothership as a whole is setup has quite often been compared to the Hyperion from Starcraft 2's single player campaign.Finally, there is the boardgame-based strategic map from which players determine where they will send their armies to next. Some of the territories presented contain structures that provide various benefits, such as princess towers that give access to different princesses. Minimum System RequirementsWindows XP SP 3 (Windows 7 SP 1 recommended)2.6 GHz Core 2 Duo E6600 or equivalent or better (i5 2400 or equivalent or better recommended)2 GB RAM (4 GB RAM recommended)NVIDIA GeForce 8800 GT (512MB) or ATI Radeon HD 4850 or better (NVIDIA GeForce GTX 550 ti 1GB RAM or ATI Radeon HD 6XXX or better recommended)15GB HDD space (30GB recommended)DirectX 9.0c compatible sound cardMouseKeyboard LinksOfficial Website</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/23546/2526918-6484141225-itnTD.jpg</image></root>