<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36231</id><name>Legend of Grimrock</name><description>StoryA group of prisoners are sentenced to death and exiled to Mount Grimrock, a mountain filled with tunnels, dungeons and catacombs built by an ancient civilization that disappeared centuries ago. If the prisoners want to ever see daylight again they will need to build a Team and unravel Grimrock Mountain's mysteries to find the exit.Character GenerationCharacter Generation Screen.Legend of Grimrock features four Races and three classes to choose from, players can also use the predetermined party consisting of a Human Fighter, Minotaur Fighter, Human Rogue and Human Mage. Players will also have the option to select an "Old School Option" that will turn off Auto-Mapping completely, this feature can not be changed after starting the game.All the races can be any class in the game, though their stats will vary depending on the combination selected; A Minotaur Fighter will have more hitpoints than a Minotaur Mage and a Human Fighter for example.Mount Grimrock.The Game also features a Skill Point system, that vary depending on the class, being possible to allocate points into Skills such as Armor, Athletics, Swords, Magic, Assassination etc. These skills will determine the player proficiency in the respective areas, and the number of Skill points available at the start will also vary depending on the Race of the character.Each Character also start the game with 10 Stat points that can be spent across Strength, Dexterity, Vitality and Willpower.There is also the ability to select Traits, that give various bonus, like more Health, Resistance to Cold, Poison etc, and even more Skill Points to be allocated.On the table below you can see all the Races/Class combinations and their respective starting stats:Race/ClassFighterRogueMageStatsSkill PointsHumanHP: 60Energy: 50HP: 45Energy: 50HP: 35Energy: 50Strength : 10Dexterity : 10Vitality : 10Will: 104MinotaurHP: 70Energy: 42HP: 55Energy: 42HP: 45Energy: 42Strength: 15Dexterity: 6Vitality : 14Will: 71LizardmanHP: 60Energy: 47HP: 45Energy: 47HP: 35Energy: 47Strength: 10Dexterity: 12Vitality: 10Will: 93InsectoidHP: 55Energy: 60HP: 40Energy: 60HP: 30Energy: 60Strength: 8Dexterity: 11Vitality: 8Will: 143StatsHealth - Health is the ability of a character to resist pain and injuries, Vitality and Character class will affect the number of Health Points a character starts with, and the number gained by leveling up.Energy - Energy is used for Special attacks and Spellcasting, Willpower will determine the number of Energy Points a character starts with, and the number gained by leveling up.Strength - Strenght is the physical prowess of a character, it increases Attack power and carrying capacity.Dexterity - Dexterity affects movement and perception, it increases Accuracy and Evasion.Vitality - Vitality represents your overall Health and Stamina, it determines the number of Health Points a character starts with and the number gained by leveling up, it also improves resistances.Willpower - Willpower determines the character's ability to use Magic powers, it will determine the number of Energy Points a character starts with, and the number gained by leveling up.Attack Power - Attack Power determines how much Physical damage a character will do, it is based on Strength and equipped weapons.Accuracy - Accuracy affects the chance a character have to hit a target with melee attacks, it is based on Dexterity and equipped weapons.Protection - Protection decreases damaged received from enemy attacks, it is determined by Armor, Clothes and other defensive gear.Evasion - Evasion is the ability to avoid physical attacks completely, It is determined by Dexterity, equipped shields and other types of gear.Resist Fire - Resist Fire decreases damaged received from fire, steam and heat based attacks. It is determined by Dexterity and Race stats.Resist Cold - Resist Cold decreases damaged received from icy and cold attacks. It is determined by Vitality and Race stats.Resist Poison - Resist Poison decreases damaged received from poisonous attacks. It is determined by Vitality and Race stats.Resist Shock - Resist Shock decreases damaged received from lightning and electric attacks. It is determined by Dexterity and Race stats.Load - Load affects the Party's movement speed, if a character becomes Burdened movement speed slows down, if a character becomes Overloaded the whole Party can't move.SkillsFighter SkillsContar StoneskullAthletics - This skill represents the character's Physique, spending points in this skill will give bonuses to Strength, Vitality and Health.Armors - This skill represents the character's Armor and Defense, , spending points in this skill will give bonuses to Protection and Health.Axes - This skill represents the character's ability with Axes, it will increase Attack Power, Accuracy and the chance of performing special attacks when using Axes, spending points in this skill will give bonuses to Strength and Health.Maces - This skill represents the character's ability with Maces, it will increase Attack Power, Accuracy and the chance of performing special attacks when using Maces, spending points in this skill will give bonuses to Vitality, Health and will grant the Bash ability.Swords - This skill represents the character's ability with Swords, it will increase Attack Power, Accuracy and the chance of performing special attacks when using Swords, spending points in this skill will give bonuses to Strengh, Health and will grant the Slash ability.Unarmed Combat - This skill represents the character's ability with Unarmed attacks, it will increase Attack Power, Accuracy and chance of performing special attacks when fighting unarmed, spending points in this skill will give bonuses to Dexterity, Health and will grant the Jab ability.Rogue SkillsYennica WhitefeatherAssassination - This skill will give the character certain special abilities, spending points in this skill will give bonus to Strength and will grant the Backstab and Reach Attack abilities.Daggers - This skill represents the character's ability with Daggers, it will increase Attack Power, Accuracy and chance of performing special attacks when using Daggers, spending points in this skill will give bonuses to Dexterity, Energy and will grant the Stab ability.Dodge - This skill will improve the Rogue's defenses, spending points in this skill will give bonus to Evasion, Health and grants the Evade ability.Missile Weapons - This skill represents the character's ability with Missile Weapons, it will increase Attack Power, Energy, Dexterity and will grant the Quick Shot ability.Throwing Weapons - This skill represents the character's ability with Throwing Weapons, it will increase Attack Power, Strength, Health and will grant the Quick Throw ability.Unarmed Combat - This skill represents the character's ability with Unarmed attacks, it will increase Attack Power, Accuracy and chance of performing special attacks when fighting unarmed, spending points in this skill will give bonuses to Dexterity, Health and will grant the Jab ability.Mage SkillsSancsaron the WryAir Magic - This skill will determine the character's ability to cast Air based spells, as you spent points in this skill you gain access to new spells and the efficiency of air spells improves. it also improves the Resist Shock stat.Earth Magic - This skill will determine the character's ability to cast Earth based spells, as you spent points in this skill you gain access to new spells and the efficiency of earth spells improves. it also improves the Resist Poison stat.Fire Magic - This skill will determine the character's ability to cast Fire based spells, as you spent points in this skill you gain access to new spells and the efficiency of Fire spells improves. it also improves the Resist Fire stat.Ice Magic - This skill will determine the character's ability to cast Ice based spells, as you spent points in this skill you gain access to new spells and the efficiency of Ice spells improves. it also improves the Resist Cold stat.Spellcraft - This skill will improve the Mage's ability to cast spells, being able to cast more spells before running out of Energy. Spending points in this skill will give bonus to Willpower and will grant new spells.Staff Defense - This will improve the Mage's defenses, It gives bonuses to Evasion, Health and Protection.*In order to learn new spells the player will need to find a Scroll containing the Runes of the respective spell.TraitsTwo traits can be chosen per character at the start of each playthrough, during the process of character creation.TraitDescriptionEffectsAggressiveYou are full of rageAttack Power +4AgileYour reflexes are exceptionalDexterity +2AthleticYour body is muscularStrength +2AuraYou have a potent auraEnergy +15Cold-BloodedYou are naturally resistant to coldResist Cold +25Daemon AncestorYour Great Grandfather had fiery eyesResist Fire +25EvasiveYou know better to stay away from harmEvasion +7Fist FighterYou know how to survive tavern brawlsAttack Power +6Head Hunter(Minotaur race only)You are something of a trophy collectorAttack Power +3(per Skull in the inventory)HealthyYou are exceptionally healthyVitality +2Natural Armour(Insectoid race only)Your skin is very thick and armour-likeProtection +5Poison ResistantYou are naturally resistant to poisonsResist Poison +25SkilledYou are learnedSkill Points +3(at character creation)Strong MindYour mind is sharp as a needleWillpower +2ToughYou are exceptionally healthyHealth +15GameplayLegend of Grimrock's gameplay mixes old school Dungeon Crawling mechanics with puzzle solving and exploration. The game is played from a first person perpective (you never actually see your party) on a Grid-based movement style, similar to a Chess game, but unlike other games that utilize the same style of movement, the combat is always in real time and not turn based; this makes the game more dynamic and fast paced, with Circle straffing and strategic movement playing an integral part of combat.Combat is in real time.The game also focus heavily on exploration and puzzle solving, demanding players to be very aware of their surroundings, to avoid traps, find hidden levers, treasures, etc; sometimes resembling a point and click adventure game. A keen eye will often pay dividends in Legend of Grimrock.You control a party of four adventures that can be pre-made characters as well as a custom party made by the player, where your main objective is to reach the end of the Dungeon floor and move on to the next one. The party is split in front and back rows, with two characters occupying the first row and two on the back. Only characters on the front row can perform melee attacks, while the back row can use ranged and magic to fight enemies; though some skills and weapons will let players use melee attacks from the back row too. Players can move characters to the front and back rows at will, allowing for a more strategic style of play.Arrow interface allows for mouse control.Magic and Spells utilize a scroll/rune system, requiring players to find scrolls in order to learn new spells. Also everytime players need to cast a spell they are required to input the correct rune combination on the spell interface in real time.Players will use the WASD keys to navigate the grid, the Q and E keys to turn around, and the right mouse button for free looking (with the latter only available while standing still). There is also an option to enable arrow icons on the screen making possible to play the game only using a mouse.If a character in your party dies in combat, there are various save points that will revive them to full. To prevent character death, you can rest in between battles to regain health and spellpoints, but be careful; if you rest when enemies are around, they will ambush you in your sleep.The game also features food mechanics, where characters will starve if not fed. Characters will start felling hungry by doing actions such as moving, casting spells, swinging weapons, resting etc. Being hungry does not impose any penalties at first, but when characters enter the "starving" phase, they will stop regenerating Health and Energy if not fed, some enemies will drop food when killed, but supplies can get limited specially on the first levels of the game, making food a precious commodity.EnemiesDisplayed in alphabetical order.NameHealthDamage DealtAttack SpeedMovement SpeedEffects on PlayerDrops / LootCave CrabHighMediumMediumSlow------CrowernMediumMediumFastFast------Giant SnailVery lowVery lowSlowVery slow---Snail SliceGiant SpiderHighHighFastFastPoison status---GoromorgHigh(also has a magic shield)Very HighMediumFast------Green SlimeHighMediumMediumSlowDisease status---Herder (large)HighHighMediumMediumPoison statusHerder CapHerder (medium)MediumLowMediumSlow---Herder CapHerder (small)LowMediumMediumFastPoison statusHerder CapIce LizardHigh(immune to cold)HighFastFast---SteakOgreVery highVery highMediumMedium(has a charge attack)---Ogre HammerScavengerLowLowVery fastFast------Shrakk TorrLowLowVery fastVery fastDisease Status---Skeleton ArcherLow(immune to poison)LowLowFast---Frost ArrowsMedium(immune to poison)MediumMediumMedium---Legionary SpearLegionary ShieldTentaclesHighMediumFastStationary------UggardianHighVery HighMediumFast------Very HighVery HighMediumMedium(has a charge attack)------WyvernHighHighFastFast------PotionsAll potions require an empty flask in which to deposit your ingredients! Ingredients can be mixed and/or ground by finding a Mortar and Pestle in the first couple of levels.AntidoteIngredients: 1 slime bellEffects: cures any disease statusAntivenomIngredients: 1 cave nettle.Effects: cures any poison effect.Energy PotionIngredients: 1 blooddrop blossom.Effects: restores 75 Energy.Healing PotionIngredients: 1 tar bead.Effects: restores 50 HP.Poignant PotionIngredients: 2 cave nettles.Effects: inflicts poison status on the enemy.Speed PotionIngredients: 1 milkreed, 1 blooddrop blossom.Effects: cooldown times halved.Sulphurous PotionIngredients: 1 grim cap, 1 blooddrop blossom, 1 cave nettle.Effects: rage (attack power +10, evasion -10).Toorum ModeLegend of Grimrock has a secret mode that can only be unlocked after you've attained the "Buddies with Toorum" achievement, which pretty much consists of being able to find and take Toorum's remains back to a Crystal of Life, thus releasing his spirit. Now, once you've gotten this achievement, you can at any time start a new game (make sure you've got the "create characters" option active before you do, though!), write "Toorum" in the character name slot, press the "enter" key and voilá, your hear a sound that resembles a chime of sorts and the game immediately launches, giving you a brand new character with a brand new portrait and a particular set of skills to play with. Take note however that you will NOT have a party with you-- your playthrough with Toorum will be a "one-man army" kind of experience, which greatly changes the gameplay and drastically alters the overall experience, as you only have two hands to equip items into.Toorum's starting Stats, set of Skills and unique TraitsToorum, the character whose notes are scattered throughout the dungeon.Health: 95Energy: 55Strength: 18Dexterity: 15Vitality: 16Willpower: 12Skills: Armours, Axes, Swords, Earth Magic, Fire Magic, Spellcraft.Unlike a standard mage, Toorum cannot cast spells without having an orb or a staff equipped.Traits: Tough, Skilled, ThunderstruckThe thunderstruck trait is unique to Toorum and isn't even available in the game's regular mode; what thunderstruck does is it gives Toorum the ability to move at twice the normal movement speed.LinksOfficial WebsitePC System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Windows XP Service Pack 3CPU: Dual Core 2GHz Intel or 2.8GHz AMDRAM Memory: 2GBGraphics: ATI Radeon X1600 or NVIDIA GeForce 7600 or better (512MB graphics memory or more. Shader Model 3.0 needs to be supported). Minimum supported resolutions 1280×720 and 1024×768.DirectX: 9.0cDisk Space: 1GBRecommended:OS: Windows Vista or Windows 7CPU: Quad Core 2.66GHz Intel or 3.2GHz AMDRAM Memory: 4GBGraphics: ATI Radeon HD 2900 or NVIDIA GeForce 8800 or better (512MB graphics memory or more. Shader Model 3.0 needs to be supported)DirectX: 9.0cDisk Space: 1GB</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13839">Wizardry V: Heart of the Maelstrom</game><game id="4504">Wizardry III: Legacy of Llylgamyn</game><game id="7113">Wizardry IV: The Return of Werdna</game><game id="11906">Wizardry 8</game><game id="16625">Wizardry II: The Knight of Diamonds</game><game id="9180">Wizardry: Proving Grounds of the Mad Overlord</game><game id="18518">Dungeon Master</game><game id="11234">Eye of the Beholder</game><game id="1500">Eye of the Beholder II: The Legend of Darkmoon</game><game id="36425">Frayed Knights: The Skull of S'makh-Daon</game><game id="15771">Dungeon Master II: The Legend of Skullkeep</game><game id="18058">Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Eye of the Beholder</game><game id="28429">Wizardry: Labyrinth of Lost Souls</game><game id="14350">Etrian Odyssey</game><game id="20511">Etrian Odyssey II: Heroes of Lagaard</game><game id="29469">Etrian Odyssey III: The Drowned City</game><game id="37560">Etrian Odyssey IV: Legends of the Titan</game><game id="6413">Ultima Underworld: The Stygian Abyss</game><game id="8147">Ultima Underworld II: Labyrinth of Worlds</game><game id="38073">Malevolence: The Sword of Ahkranox</game><game id="24865">The Dark Spire</game><game id="36886">Game of Thrones</game><game id="40333">Goblet Grotto</game><game id="42030">Might and Magic X Legacy</game><game id="41709">Legend of Grimrock 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/81005/2175295-log.png</image></root>