<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36236</id><name>T.E.C 3001</name><description>Overview   The T.E.C. hauling mechanical tail In T.E.C. you play as a Tesla Energy Collector, a            robot that works in virtual reality to serve humankind. Your goal in each of the game's 21 levels is to accumulate energy in the form of picking up           batteries.  Every level has a  certain number of batteries in which you must grab in order to successfully complete the level, very similar to the Special Stages in   Sonic the Hedgehog 2. In addition to collecting energy, you goal is also to finish levels in as fast a time as possible. At the end of each level you are graded on how well you did based on the number of batteries picked up as well as the speed in which the level was beaten at.  T.E.C uses several different game mechanics. In one sense it is structure like a          platformer in, requiring the player to jump from track to track and collect items to increase the player's score. In another sense T.E.C. is much like a racing game with very defined paths or "tracks" that the player must operate on. Finally, the game also contains some aspects of games in the action genre. At several points, the player must guide the T.E.C. in         skydiving and wall-smashing in order to reach their goal.    An early version of the game's boosting arrows  T.E.C. share many similarities with the PC game                Fotonica. The most pronounced of which is that the player does not have to push a button or analog stick to make the robot move forward. Momentum is a constant. The only way to speed up is to run over green arrows that point forward, similar to a        boost pad in       F-Zero.  Conversely, the only way to slow down is to run over red arrows pointing backwards. Differing from Fotonica, T.E.C requires the player to choose between branching paths by steering like you would a car in a racing game.The game features very simplistic game play, the player can               jump,              double jump, slide and use a             turbo charge. These actions are all done using the face buttons or triggers. The game also lets the player to skydive and use jump pads in specific sections. Both allow the player to cross vast distances without a track to run on.    ReleaseThe game was released on August 25, 2011 as part of the     Indie Games Summer Uprising for 240      MS Points.  Title Update On February 1, 2012 Phoenix released a major title update. Included in the update are: 12 new bonus levels In-game achievements A Crysis-like voice-over indicating when T.E.C. passes checkpoints and collects batteries The ability to destroy T.E.C. 'Splosion Man style Several bug fixes  Unfortunately, the updates also requires you to restart the game from the beginning if you want the in-game achievements. You also must beat the game in order to access the bonus levels.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="35950">Fotonica</game><game id="17578">Rez</game><game id="20448">F-Zero GX</game><game id="4902">Mad Dash Racing</game><game id="28976">Canabalt</game><game id="39533">Harold</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/28463/1869999-boxart.jpg</image></root>