<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36237</id><name>Zero Escape: Virtue's Last Reward</name><description>OverviewZero Escape: Virtue's Last Reward is an adventure game by Chunsoft developed for the Nintendo 3DS and PlayStation Vita. Much like the previous game in the Zero Escape series the game revolves around nine people trapped together in an elaborate series of life-threatening puzzles, forced to cooperate. You are able to choose between Japanese or English voices.StoryThe cast of Virtue's Last Reward.A young college student, Sigma, awakens to find that he is one of nine people that were captured and forced to play the Nonary Game: Ambidex Edition, overseen by a rabbit-like AI calling himself Zero III. The goal of this Nonary Game is to raise enough “Bracelet Points” (BP) to access a door with the number 9 on it. To raise BP, participants are put into groups of three, where Sigma will either have a partner (a Pair) or be by himself (a Solo). Pairs and Solos choose whether to “Ally” or “Betray” each other. If both choose to "Ally", each will receive 2 BP. If one chooses "Betray", he or she gains 3 BP, and the other loses 2 BP. Finally, if they both choose "Betray", neither will gain or lose points. If anyone disobeys the rules, or if their BP falls to 0, they will die.The game has 24 endings, which determine which characters live and which ones die, among other things. Routes towards certain endings will be locked until conditions are fulfilled by obtaining a required ending.GameplayThe mechanics are similar to Nine Hours, Nine Persons, Nine Doors (999), where gameplay is divided into two sections: the story-driven "Novel" segments, and the puzzle-based "Escape" areas. The Novel portions of the game are fully-voiced, and choices are presented that will change numerous things such as character interactions and endings. Just like 999, the game must be played through multiple times in order to see the whole plot. However, Zero Escape: Virtue's Last Reward introduces a 'skip' feature that bypasses previously encountered paths and puzzles through an in-game flowchart.The 'Escape' portions have much in common with traditional PC adventure games. Rooms are examined for items and clues, with the ultimate goal of discovering passwords for a safe. Each safe has two available passwords, one of which gives access to the key to the room's exit, and a second, optional password for a hidden file. These hidden files contain background information on characters and the game's universe. However, if the game is set on the 'Easy' difficulty, a silver hidden file will be unlocked, opposed to a gold hidden file.CharactersPhi, the first NPC the player meets.Sigma - The main character of the game. A young college student. Voiced by Troy Baker (English) / Kosuke Toriumi (Japanese).Phi - An intelligent, but brash young woman. She is the first person Sigma meets in the Nonary Game, and she seems to know more than she's letting on. Voiced by Karen Strassman (English) / Chiaki Omigawa (Japanese).Dio - A vulgar and aggressive man, who constantly argues with Zero III, as well as the other participants. Voiced by Liam O'Brien (English) / Yoshimasa Hosoya (Japnese)Quark - The youngest participant of the group. He seems to have a history with Tenmyouji. Voiced by Erin Fitzgerald (English) / Rie Kugimiya (Japanese).Tenmyouji - A quiet, older man. He has much hostility toward most of the group. Voiced by JB Blanc (English) / Rokuro Naya (Japanese).Luna - A friendly and optimistic young woman. Laura Bailey (English) / Mamiko Noto (Japanese).Clover - A recurring character from 999. Nevertheless, she doesn't seem to know any more than the other participants about why they were abducted. Voiced by Wendee Lee (English) / Yukari Tamura (Japanese)Alice - A mature woman in exotic attire and another recurring character. Alice had a smaller role in 999, but this time she is a participant in the Nonary Game. She trusts Clover, as they have met before. Voiced by Tara Platt (English) / Atsuko Tanaka (Japanese).K - A large man seemingly trapped in a metal suit of armor. He has no recollection of who he is. Voiced by Travis WIllingham (English) / Daisuke Ono (Japanese).Zero III - Refers to both the rabbit-like AI that explains the rules of the Nonary Game to the participants, and the human who set up the entire game. The group thus begin calling the AI "Zero Jr.", and the host "Zero Sr." among themselves. Voiced by Cindy Robinson (English) / Tarako (Japanese).GlitchIt has been reported that saving during the Pressure Exchange (PEC) puzzle room could cause the game to crash and save files to become corrupted on 3DS copies of the game. Some reports have also mentioned crashes in the Crew Quarters. It is therefore recommended not to save during these puzzles (or safer yet, any puzzle room). No such problems seem to exist in the Vita version.SoundtrackDisc 1 Escape Side01Virtue’s Last Reward ～Orchestra～2:5402Ambidexterity4:3603Lounge4:1404Dispensary3:4605Cabin3:5006Gaulem4:0207Recreation4:5508Pantry4:2909Decompression4:0010Biology4:3311Treatment4:1112Biotope3:5113Data4:1414Annihilation4:3715Monitor4:4416Director4:5217Q5:33Disc 2 Story Side01Sinisterness2:3802Placidity4:1703Eeriness5:2204Strain5:3605Consternation4:5106Desperation4:4007Anxiousness4:1708Portentousness2:3909GLTM-KM5064:1910Confession4:2111Clarification4:2812Sublimity4:5013Divulgation4:3614Demise4:5915Blue Bird Lamentation3:1416Virtue Is Its Last Reward ～Piano～2:53</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2885">Remember 11: The Age of Infinity</game><game id="28224">Steins;Gate</game><game id="30817">Time Travelers</game><game id="37813">Detective Saburo Jinguji: Rondo of Vengeance</game><game id="32927">Layton Kyouju VS Gyakuten Saiban</game><game id="39383">Corpse Party 2: Dead Patient</game><game id="34205">The Walking Dead</game><game id="40699">Super Dangan Ronpa 2: Sayonara Zetsubou Gakuen</game><game id="41592">Sweet Fuse: At Your Side</game><game id="42383">No-One Has To Die</game><game id="1705">Yu-No: Kono Yo no Hate de Koi o Utau Shoujo</game><game id="43414">Hakuoki: Memories of the Shinsengumi</game><game id="21052">Time Hollow</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2339312-box_zevlr.png</image></root>