<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36241</id><name>Smite</name><description>Developed by Hi-rez Studios, the makers of Global Agenda and Tribes Ascend, Smite is a free-to-play MOBA game. Unlike its contemporaries, such as Dota 2, League of Legends, and others, Smite is played from a third-person perspective instead of the RTS-style camera other MOBAs use. As such, Smite combines the ability hot-key control style of those games with a WASD control scheme. This results in certain elements of the game feeling noticeably different compared to other MOBAs. Running away tends to feel tenser for instance, as you can't see exactly what abilities your enemies are using behind you.A few other differences Smite has from its contemporaries include:Due to the WASD control scheme and alternate camera, almost none of Smite's abilities can be 'locked on' to targets. As a result, many of the skills in Smite are essentially skill shots and must be aimed accordingly.Instead of a defenseless core building in each base, the standard Conquest mode of Smite has a Minotaur act as the final objective for each team. This Minotaur is fully capable of defending itself and will attack any enemies that enter its room. It's high attack power and health generally require most, if not all of the team to overcome with any efficiency- as lone heroes can be killed by the Minotaur surprisingly quickly- even at max level.Game ModesConquestThe standard 5 versus 5 game mode. The map consists of three lanes. Each lane has two towers, a phoenix, and has waves of allied minions marching towards the other team’s base. Between the lanes are areas populated with camps of neutral mobs which can be killed by both teams to gain experience, gold, and particular buffs. In this area are two special neutral monsters: the Gold Fury and the Fire Giant. Killing the Gold Fury gives experience and gold for the player’s entire team. Slaying the Fire Giant grants all live members of the player’s team a significant buff to damage, mana regeneration, and health regeneration. The end goal is to defeat the enemy team’s Minotaur. Player’s can weaken the Minotaur by engaging it while the enemy team’s phoenixes are dead.JoustThe dueling mode. Two players fight it out in a single-lane map that generally has the same structure as a lane in the conquest game mode. Victory is achieved by killing the other player’s Minotaur.ArenaThe team deathmatch type mode. Arena takes place in a smaller and more open map without the traditional three lanes of creeps with the only obstructions being a few pillars in the middle of the map and small walls on the edges of the map to distinguish the neutral monsters. Both teams starts off with 500 tickets with the winner being the first team to deplete the other team’s pool of tickets. The enemy team’s tickets can be depleted by killing their minions, escorting your minions to their side of the map, slaying enemy gods, and by destroying the towers outside the enemy’s spawn. Once a team is reduced to 20 tickets normal minions no longer affect the enemy team’s ticket pool.DominationDomination is a capture and hold mode. Both teams fight for control over three towers with the help of spawned waves of allied minions. When one team controls the majority of the towers the enemy team’s tickets periodically tick down by the amount of towers held. Each enemy god killed also reduces their ticket pool. The winner is the team drains the others ticket pool.AssaultThe all-random all-mid mode. Like the joust map, the assault map consists of one lane, but widened to accommodate a 5 versus 5 match. One difference is that the assault map does not have any neutral monsters for buffs or extra experience and gold. Each player’s god is chosen at random. Items that gain stats from killing enemy gods or minions are disabled in this mode. The only way for the player to return to the item shop is to die; there is no way to teleport back to base. Victory is achieved once the enemy Minotaur is slain.Match of the DayThis game mode changes daily and can range from a specific set of playable gods, usually themed or other unconventional conditions such as starting off a regular match of Conquest with 100,000 gold.CharactersAgni Fire-based mage character. His Noxious fumes ability can be combined with his other attack abilities to stun enemies. His Fire Rain ultimate can be used up to 3 times in quick succession if allowed to charge up.HinduAnhur Ranged physical carry. Proper use of the environment (or the obelisk spawned by his Shifting Sands ability) can allow him to stun enemies with his Impale skill.EgyptianAnubis Mage character. Anubis can easily slow enemies- if not stop them in their tracks outright- with his Grasping Hands and Mummify abilities. His Death Gaze ultimate allows him to land critical damage on his own as well.EgyptianAo Quang Mage character. Ao Quang's tornadoes allow him to excel at pushing whatever lane he is in. His Squall and Slither abilities give him some escape potential as well in 1v1s (Slither speeds him up, and a hit with Squall slows the enemy).ChineseAphrodite Support character. Aphrodite's abilities excel at healing whatever ally she bonds herself with and harassing or slowing down enemies. Her ultimate makes herself and soul mate briefly invincible.GreekApollo Ranged Physical Carry. At first glance, Apollo's skillset seems to call for closer-ranged combat than you'd expect from a physical carry as flimsy as him. However, the escape and mobility options his Mesmerize and Slide abilities offer cannot be underestimated. His chariot ultimate also allows him to strike almost anywhere he pleases in the late game.GreekArachne Assassin. Arachne has a surprisingly versatile skill set, able to support her allies by laying eggs to spawn annoying hatchlings, throwing webs to slow enemies down, and dragging stragglers in with her ultimate.GreekAres Tank. Ares is all about getting the enemy into disadvantaged positions with his ultimate, which grabs all nearby enemies with his chains and pulls them in after a brief delay. As such, he's fully capable of leading a charge.GreekArtemis Ranged physical carry. Be it with vine traps, arrow rain, or her Boar- Artemis has many options for harassing and slowing enemies, setting them up for a kill with her high power and fast physical attacks.GreekBacchus Tank. Getting drunk makes Bacchus tougher- so swilling his drink is fully advised. His abilities and ultimate are all about inconveniencing and hampering enemy movement- allowing his allies to finish them off.RomanBakasura Assassin. Bakasura pretty much belongs in the jungle due to his devour minion ability, which heals him and buffs a few of his stats- and allows him to go through the jungle faster than many other gods. Part of the effect of his ultimate is directly tied to how many minions he eats- as they are re-spawned as bile-formed apparitions of themselves that assist Bakasura in combat for their brief lifespan.(It only spawns a set number of minions though, its not limitless)HinduBastet Assassin. Bastet is all about hit and run attacks. Her pounce ability allows her to strike at one area, and then quickly return to her original position. This allows for all sorts of mind-games and movement shenanigans.EgyptianCupid Ranged physical carry. Cupid isn't just capable of putting out decent damage with his heart bombs. He also has a very fast dash maneuver and can spawn healing hearts to support his allies.RomanFenrir Assassin. Fenrir is a persistent beast- his abilities are all about buffing his strikes and keeping him right on an enemy regardless of how they attempt to maneuver. If he's not confident in acting alone, but really doesn't want an enemy to escape, his Ragnarok ultimate allows him to take one god right into his jaws and carry them back to the mercy of his own team...NorseFreya Mage/Physical Carry hybrid. Freya relies on a combination of magical power and attack speed to get the most mileage out of her abilities. She can buff her melee attacks with magic damage and range.NorseGuan Yu Tank. Guan Yu can support his allies with area-of-effect heals. He also excels at slowing and stunning enemies with his Warrior's Will dash and Tactician's Advantage ultimate. These abilities also give him a surprising amount of mobility.ChineseHades Tank. Relying on his toughness, silencing abilities, and dash to get into a good position- Hades is all about getting into the center of the enemy team and immobilizing them with his ultimate.GreekHe Bo Mage. He Bo has extensive harassment potential with his abilities, along with decent mobility from his Flood Waters and Crushing Wave.ChineseHel Mage/Support hybrid. Hel's ultimate allows her to switch between her light form and dark form. Her light form focuses on healing allies and support, while her dark form changes her abilities to focus on damage instead.NorseHercules Brawler. Hercules' passive and Mitigate Wounds abilities encourage him to take damage while being to able to keep going at higher and higher strength. His offensive abilities are capable of knocking his enemies all over the place.RomanIsis Mage.EgyptianKali Assassin.HinduLoki Assassin.NorseNeith Ranged physical carry.EgyptianNe Zha AssassinChineseOdin BrawlerNorsePoseidon MageGreekRa MageEgyptianSobek TankEgyptianSun Wukong AssassinChineseThor BrawlerNorseVamana TankHinduVulcan TankRomanXblanque Ranged physical carry.MayanYmir TankNorseZeus MageGreek</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="32887">Dota 2</game><game id="27328">Heroes of Newerth</game><game id="24024">League of Legends</game><game id="43487">Strife</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/13/135472/1870775-smite_online_game_screenshot.jpg</image></root>