<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36268</id><name>Q.U.B.E.</name><description>GameplayThe gameplay in Q.U.B.E. is centred entirely around your ability to manipulate the environment using your special gloves. By simply clicking on surfaces you can create stairs, ledges and jump pads to reach where you need to be.The Various Blocks in Play.Once you reach the half way point in the game though, the game starts presenting you with far more complex puzzles and more than doubles the amount of mechanics that can be combined into a single puzzle. You will start off by simply using the three primary extruding blocks, but eventually puzzles will incorporate beams of light that have to be directed using rotating blocks that sometimes must be aimed at coloured blocks in order to trigger the next step of the puzzle. Some puzzles use a system of magnetic walls that will push and pull blocks in a any given direction combined with the primary extruding blocks in order to proceed.There are also sections in the game where the visual style of the game will alter dramatically to have a significant impact on the puzzles and the players awareness. The usual light grey colour of the environment will be pitch black and only allow the player to see one coloured cube at a time until they have completed sections of the puzzle. There are also sections where the player must repair the various cubes that have been damaged in order to proceed by manipulating various cables that are placed in the environments.Very late in the game is when the player gains the ability to place these cubes on the environment themselves, certain key areas of the floors, walls and ceilings can be assigned the attributes of the basic red, blue and yellow blocks and the player must utilise their knowledge of the mechanics in order to succeed in solving these puzzles.Puzzle ElementsEvery puzzle in Qube is made up of a careful selection of the different ways the player has to manipulate the environment. While you only start out with the simple blocks that can be extruded from walls and ceilings, the game quickly expands to offer a multitude of different abilities that really put your mind to the test.Type of BlockFunctionRed BlockCan be extruded in increments of three.Blue BlockJuts out when the player steps on it, acting as a jump pad to reach higher areas and to launch ball-keys.Yellow BlocksA set of three blocks that will extrude 1 block in size depending on which one the player clicks. Unless the middle block is clicked in which case that will levitate by two and the sides by one.Green BlockThese only appear in certain areas where they can be used to give the player extra height or block paths in order to succeed.RotatorsWhen used these will orientate a part of the wall or ceiling in the specified direction.Key BallsThese will generate by the player and must be moved into specific areas in order to unlock and progress through multi-stage puzzles.Colored Key BallsThe same principal as the standard key balls, but these must be passed through translucent colored blocks that will then trigger uniquely colored switches.PC System RequirementsOS:Windows XP SP2 / Vista / 7Processor:2.0+ GHz (dual core recommended)Memory:1 GB RAMGraphics:NVIDIA 8000 series or higher (Shader Model 3 Compatible)DirectX®:dx90cHard Drive:1 GB HD space</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="33337">The Spire</game><game id="21169">Portal: Still Alive</game><game id="36234">Quantum Conundrum</game><game id="32844">Antichamber</game><game id="30785">The Ball</game><game id="41216">Magrunner: Dark Pulse</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2103141-box_qube.png</image></root>