<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36285</id><name>Onechanbara Z: Kagura</name><description>OverviewOnechanbara Z: Kagura stars two sisters from Romania on a quest to Japan in order to kill Aya and Saki (two protagonists from Onechanbara: Bikini Samurai Squad) for creating zombies all over the world. It is a hack and slash game based on combos.Onechanbara Z: Kagura features a Story mode, Missions mode, practice mode and a quest system that rewards you “dress up” items for doing certain things throughout the game on multiple playthroughs. The game also features a split screen mode called tag play where you can go through missions in co-op but no online support for this specific mode. It has been noted that the game also features a new graphics engine with self-shadows at 60fps allowing for much more fast and fluent combat. The game’s combat system and weapons system has been heavily overhauled for this entry in the series, offering the deepest combat the series has seen yet. QTE’s are a big part of gameplay with boss fights and become slightly more complicated as the game advances. Kagura also has a regenerating health system where you hold down the A  X button’s, but become much more vulnerable to attacks; adding a layer of strategy when having to do so.Characters both new and familiar appear in this installment of the Onechanbara series.KaguraShe was born between the mother of special bloods, and the father of vampires.Weapons:Kuro Bachi Kai (double swords): Effective against the strongest enemiesHydra Blade (chain and daggers): Best used again multiple foesExceed (boomerang): Best for combo movesSaayaSaaya is the youngest of the two sisters. She has the same bloodline as Kagura, but a different mother.Weapons:Jayson (chainsaw): Saaya's most powerful weaponOgre Hands (knuckles): Saaya's fastest weaponMorning Star (flail): Long range attacksUseful linksOfficial Website (Japanese)D3 Website (Japanese)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20710">Bayonetta</game><game id="20922">Afro Samurai</game><game id="16741">Devil May Cry 2</game><game id="890">Devil May Cry 3: Dante's Awakening</game><game id="6681">Devil May Cry 4</game><game id="36707">Devil May Cry HD Collection</game><game id="10037">Bullet Witch</game><game id="21876">Ninja Gaiden</game><game id="20553">Ninja Gaiden II</game><game id="18546">Ninja Gaiden Sigma</game><game id="25586">Ninja Gaiden Sigma 2</game><game id="35948">Lollipop Chainsaw</game><game id="39749">Ninja Gaiden 3: Razor's Edge</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2323873-box_ocbz.png</image></root>