<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36291</id><name>One Piece: Pirate Warriors</name><description>OverviewOne Piece: Kaizoku Musou (One Piece: Pirate Warriors) is a spin-off of        Koei's        Musou franchise based on the manga and anime        One Piece. Players take control of one of the crew members of the Strawhat pirates and a number of allies as they fight off waves of enemies and defend/take control of select regions on a given map. From the beginning of the adventures in the Romance Dawn Arc all the way to the latest adventure into the fearsome New World, follow        Monkey D. Luffy and his crew as they set forth on their grand adventure down the Grand Line.Game ModesMain LogThe Main Log is a story mode that is faithful to the manga. You mainly use the Straw Hat Pirates, going through a majority of the situations they went through in the manga, gaining their different abilities in the moments they got them in the story. This mode exclusively covers Luffy's journey however during key moments control will switch to an ally who must complete a set objective. It covers the Romance Dawn Arc (Monkey D. Luffy's beginning of his quest to become Pirate King) to the beginning of the New World Arc (set after the terrible events at Marineford and 2 year time skip). However certain arcs including Skypiea and Thriller Bark are not included in the game.Another LogThe Another Log mode allows the player to take control of any of the games 13 characters and do battle over a multitude of stages. The availability of stages on each character's path depends on when they were introduced into the story. This mode can also be played cooperatively, locally or taken online, allowing 2 players to work together to complete the stage. Characters can level up by defeating enemies and completing objectives in this mode. If played online, upon completion of a stage the player will receive ranking points. The highest ranking players can be viewed on the leaderboards.Challenge ModeThe Challenge Mode sends endless waves of enemies at the player, sending also boss characters to challenge the player. This mode has leaderboard support. Can you survive the hordes of enemies and claim the spoils of victory?Playable CharactersThe following characters are playable in the game:       Monkey D. Luffy       Roronoa Zoro       Nami       Nico Robin       Usopp       Sanji       Franky       Brook       Tony Tony Chopper       Boa Hancock       Whitebeard       Portgas D. Ace       Jinbei</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23839">Devil Kings</game><game id="29036">Fist of the North Star:  Ken's Rage</game><game id="32839">Dynasty Warriors: Gundam 3</game><game id="5552">Warriors Orochi</game><game id="32719">Dynasty Warriors 7</game><game id="6513">Bladestorm: The Hundred Years' War</game><game id="35965">Naruto Shippuden: Ultimate Ninja Impact</game><game id="38563">Fist of the North Star: Ken's Rage 2</game><game id="34360">Bleach Soul Resurrección</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2335742-box_oppw.png</image></root>