<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3629</id><name>After Burner</name><description>OverviewAfter Burner, is an arcade flight shooter, developed by SEGA and first released in 1987 in Japanese Arcades. It was designed by legendary Sega game developer Yu Suzuki. It was ported onto many systems, including Sega's own Sega Master System just a few months after the Arcade launch, but most of them weren't able to match the original Arcade version's visceral speed and graphical/sound quality.It is the first game among a series of franchise sequels such as After Burner II, After Burner III and the 2006 release of After Burner Climax which ran on the then newly developed SEGA Lindbergh arcade hardware. After Burner II was re-released in 2004 for the Playstation 2, in the SEGA AGES 2500 series of budget anniversary re-releases.After Burner Arcade MachineIn After Burner the player controls a F-14 Tomcat, a type of jet, and the object of the game is simply to shoot down other enemy jets while evading their return fire with deft maneuvers. The player-controlled Tomcat is equipped with a machine gun and a small number of missiles as a secondary weapon which replenishes after each completed stage.The original After Burner machine is a rarity, exclusively available in the Japanese Arcades. It was controlled with a simulating flight stick, with buttons that controlled the cannon and missile weapons. Movement such as dropping/gaining altitude and barrelrolling was also perfomed by movements with the flight stick.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11696">Captain Skyhawk</game><game id="8678">Top Gun</game><game id="13742">G-Loc Air Battle</game><game id="11622">Burning Force</game><game id="22852">1941: Counter Attack</game><game id="22966">EXO Squad</game><game id="17336">Lock On</game><game id="23098">M.A.C.H. 3</game><game id="8320">Galaxy Force II</game><game id="308">B-17 Bomber</game><game id="2627">Airstrike USA</game><game id="19666">Galactic Conqueror</game><game id="11869">Hellfire Attack</game><game id="5623">Thunder Blade</game><game id="6036">Space Harrier</game><game id="12420">Space Harrier II</game><game id="2139">After Burner II</game><game id="3845">After Burner III</game><game id="3142">Blue Lightning</game><game id="7182">Top Gun: Guts &amp; Glory</game><game id="38156">F1 Tornado</game><game id="38513">Alantia: Legend of Blue Star</game><game id="38514">Neural Gear</game><game id="39611">Falsion</game><game id="41197">Geimos</game><game id="13031">Galaxy Force</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2362832-sms_afterburner.jpg</image></root>