<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3633</id><name>Indiana Jones and the Fate of Atlantis</name><description>OverviewThe game's title screen.Indiana Jones and the Fate of Atlantis is a point-and-click adventure game that was released by LucasArts in 1992.Set during the years leading up to World War II, players take the role of Indiana Jones as he is caught in a race to find Atlantis before the Nazis can harvest the power of orichalcum, a legendary and powerful metal.A significant aspect to the game is the different routes in which a player can take to complete the game. This marks the first time multiple paths were featured in a LucasArts adventure game. The three different routes each involve different gameplay and different endings.This game was an unlockable game mode in the 2009 Wii game Indiana Jones and the Staff of Kings. The game can be played on modern PCs using ScummVM.A sequel was in the works, but it was cancelled and the story was reworked into two separate comics published by Dark Horse.StoryThe interior of Barnett College.Indiana Jones is asked to retrieve a strange idol from Barnett College, where he teaches. The man who asked Indy to find the artifact turns out to be Klaus Kerner, a Nazi agent. Klaus steals the idol and draws Indy into an adventure to uncover what it is the Nazis are after.In his search, Indy teams up with Sophia Hapgood, an old colleague who is also a target of Kerner because of the necklace she wears: an artifact that will help them uncover the final resting place of Atlantis. It is after meeting with Sophia that Indy learns of what the Nazis want with Atlantis and the power they would obtain if they were ever to get hold of a mineral called orichalcum.Another key to finding Atlantis, Indy learns, is in the legendary Lost Dialogue, a book of disputed existence by Plato. The story continues to unfold depending on which path the player chooses to take.GameplayThe general gameplay is set out like a traditional point and click adventure game. There are many puzzles, but the game also includes optional combat. In many situations a problem can be solved using puzzle solving, but sometimes the player can optionally solve a dispute with a fist fight.PathsThe game includes three distinct paths that the player can take. Each path includes different objects that the player can interact with, locations, and dialogue. The three paths are:Wits: A path with many puzzle solving elements.Fists: Fewer problems but with more fighting scenes.Team: The path that relies more heavily on Sophia Hapgood in some of the puzzles.Indy QuotientAs the player progresses they are rewarded with Indy Quotient (IQ) points. To receive the maximum 1,000 points the player will have to play through every path and see every alternative ending. In order to achieve this, the player must play through the game a minimum of three times.Steam Re-ReleaseIn 2009, Lucasarts re-released the game for the price of $4.99 on Steam.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14075">Gabriel Knight: Sins of the Fathers</game><game id="3019">The Secret of Monkey Island</game><game id="5729">The Curse of Monkey Island</game><game id="6728">Zak McKracken and the Alien Mindbenders</game><game id="10927">Loom</game><game id="13230">Grim Fandango</game><game id="17544">Broken Sword: The Shadow of the Templars</game><game id="7947">Lure of the Temptress</game><game id="9527">Flight of the Amazon Queen</game><game id="600">Future Wars</game><game id="1353">The Beast Within: A Gabriel Knight Mystery</game><game id="2845">Gabriel Knight 3: Blood of the Sacred, Blood of the Damned</game><game id="2614">The Dig</game><game id="10915">Beneath a Steel Sky</game><game id="21090">A New Beginning</game><game id="23532">Nikopol: Secrets of the Immortals</game><game id="21667">Gray Matter</game><game id="21421">Star Trek: 25th Anniversary</game><game id="13476">Igor: Objective Uikokahonia</game><game id="15719">Ringworld: Revenge of the Patriarch</game><game id="1845">Ripley's Believe It or Not!: The Riddle of Master Lu</game><game id="32592">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 1: It's About Time</game><game id="29490">Lost Horizon</game><game id="21174">Full Throttle</game><game id="2800">The Shivah</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4364/217929-indiana_jones_atlantis_1.jpg</image></root>