<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36381</id><name>DJMAX Technika Tune</name><description>OverviewDJ Max Technika Tune gameplayDJ Max Technika Tune is a rhythm game for the PlayStation Vita and is developed by South Korean developer Pentavision Entertainment with additional development by Neowiz's Mobile division. It was published by Pentavision in South Korea, Pentavision Global in North America, and Cyberfront in Japan.Unlike the Portable series it proceeds, DJ Max Technika Tune has a unique playstyle that takes advantage of the PS Vita's touchscreen to emulate the arcade experience of the Technika series. Whereas the Portable games have all played akin to Konami's Beatmania series, Technika requires the player to synchronously tap and interact with icons that appear on a timeline to play the notes in the song's chart.DJ Max Technika Tune was announced towards the end of 2011 to much anticipation in the rhythm game community. The popular arcade series saw its PlayStation Vita debut in South Korea on the 20th of September, 2012 when it released. Japan followed seven days later on the 27th of September, 2012 and the North American version released on the 26th of October, 2012. The game was made available in stores and on the PlayStation Network.GameplayEvery chart has been re-written to accommodate the game's 3-lane playfield, and repeater/hold notes have been reworked to make use of the rear touch panel during gameplay. The rear touch panel can be enabled or disabled in the options menu, with the assigned notes being playable on the front panel as well. As with previous portable DJMAX games, the title also includes a vast collection of unlockable songs and content, including music and videos from the game without the gameplay elements laid on top.Song ListGenreSong TitleArtistWestern HouseBack To LifeCROOVEMelodic TranceRenovationXeoNHouse DanceTake on MeCuveAni PopShining My BoyAstroKidAcid DanceThe MAXNDLeeArt CoreSilent ClarityTsukasaToy BoxA Song Of SixpencemakouDance FloorLuv YourselfNDLeeJungle PopNever SayNDLeeHappy CoreLight HousexxdbxxModern RockFallen AngelDJ MochaP-FunkGet On TopPlanetboomHiFi PopHello PinkyNieNTechno PopEnd Of The MoonlightForte EscapeRockOBLIVION (Rockin' Night StyleNieNClassic RemixMozart Symphony #40 1st MovementKim ChanghoonTranceACCESSSphazerMelodic TranceThorXeoNClassic RemixPiano Concerto No.1WavFactoryPop RockBrand NEW DaysPlanetboomModern RockForeverBexterAcid HouseYNDLeeHouse DanceI Want YouLin-GUrban PopRu'tinBexterK-PopRememberLin-GPlanet CoreKeys To The WorldPlanetboomBalaeric HouseShorelineOriental ST8Psychadelic TranceFermionmakouPiano BalladProposed, Flower, Wolf Part 1ReXFusion Hip HopFateSTiGabberSON OF SUNHosoe ShinjiDance PopFirst KissBJJAni PopCosmic Fantastic LovesongDINYTechno TranceDual Strikers7 SequenceJazz HouseCozy Quiltbermei.inazawaSymphonic RaveLa Campanella: Nu RaveCrankyFunky HouseLuv Flow (Funky House Mix)Paul BazookaHip HouseHanzup!Mr. FunkyReggaeton-LikePut Em UpmakouDance PopTripNieNIrish DanceEmblemmakouElectro HouseRockSTARMr. FunkyCute PopHeartbeat Part 2NDLeeRap MetalFeel Ma BeatNieNMelodic TranceXeusXeoNOriental FunkKung-Fu RiderAstroKidFusion HipHopGhostSTiElectro TanceDark PrismTsukasaRB SlowMy Heart, My Soul3rd CoastLight PopEGGNautsK-PopYou  MeNieNSoulful RBOoh La LaJulie C90's RockYou Should Get Over MeJessica WolffElectro HipHopIn The TDotMr. ThoroRaveSuperNovaCrankyJunknoAD2222CROOVEGabbaBamboo on BambooSampling Masters MEGAEuro DanceAngelLaurent Newfield  Ravenant80's DanceWanna Be Your LOVERLaurent Newfield  RavenantK-PopStepKaraK-PopPretty GirlKaraK-PopJumpingKaraK-PopMisterKaraK-PopLupinKaraLimited EditionA limited edition of the game was announced on the game's release in South Korea and featured, like the limited editions of its predecessors, a host of bonuses for fans of the series. Made available for pre-order on the game's official website, the Limited Edition of DJ Max Technika Tune featured:The DJ Max Technika Tune game with unique, optional packagingA two-disc soundtrackAn artbookA branded hand-strap and screen-cleanerA protective case for the PS VitaA pouch for the PS VitaCredit code for the Neowiz BUGS music networkThe North American version of the limited edition features all of the contents listen above, save for the Neowiz BUGS card. The edition's pre-orders for North America sold out in 8 hours with only 750 copies made available.</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11982">Elite Beat Agents</game><game id="42877">Cytus Lambda</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2338091-dj.png</image></root>