<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36396</id><name>Bravely Default: Flying Fairy</name><description>OverviewBravely Default: Flying Fairy is a classic-styled JRPG for the 3DS with randomly triggered encounters, a unique turn based combat system, and a job system similar to Final Fantasy V. The game was developed by Silicon Studio and Square Enix, who also published the title in Japan on October 11, 2012. Nintendo announced in 2013 that they would be localizing Bravery Default for western markets with a planned 2014 release for North America.An upgraded version of Bravely Default, subtitled For the Sequel, was released in Japan in late 2013. The enhanced edition featured several improvements over the original such as faster battles, optional difficulty levels, new story events, and touched-up background art as well as many others. All of the new content and improvements from For the Sequel is in the overseas editions of Bravely Default.GameplayBattle SystemThe battle system in BD:FF is a strict turn based battle system. It is not, for example, an active time turn based battle system like the ones used in later Final Fantasy games. However, what sets it apart is the ability to "Brave" or "Default."DefaultWhen the player "Defaults" he or she is basically blocking for that turn while at the same time storing power that can be used in a later turn when the player "Braves". Up to three turns can be stored.BraveWhen the player "Braves" they unleash all the power they had stored through defaulting. An extra layer of strategy is added by the fact that when the player "Braves" they can go into the negative up to three turns. So, if you have two turns stored through defaulting you can "Brave" for five turns.Enemies also fight under the same system.Development5pb. writer Naotaka Hayashi (best known for writing the Science Adventure series of visual novels) was hired to pen the scenario for Bravely Default. Square Enix producer Tomoya Asano was impressed by Hayashi's previous project Steins;Gate and praised the game for its likable characters and surprising narrative. Asano wished for Bravely Default to have similar kind of quality which is what lead to Hayashi being recruited. Asano requested that Hayashi put emphasis on the characters, with both the heroes and the villains having appeal, and to also raise the game's target age a bit higher.Digital ReleaseDue to overwhelming demand, Square Enix announced that beginning November 1, 2012, Bravely Default would be available on the Nintendo eShop. The version was available at a slight discount, coming in at 5,400 yen, compared to the boxed version being 6,090 yen.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="27186">Final Fantasy: The 4 Heroes of Light</game><game id="31809">Shin Megami Tensei IV</game><game id="4793">Final Fantasy V</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/82063/2539463-bdff.jpg</image></root>