<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36447</id><name>Rocketbirds: Hardboiled Chicken</name><description>OverviewRocketbirds: Hardboiled Chicken expands upon browser-based game Rocketbirds: Revolution! and features four new levels, cut scenes, weapons and a brand new co-op campaign. Set in Albatropolis, a land full of birds taken over by a totalitarian penguin regime, you play as Hardboiled Chicken and must assassinate the evil penguin leader Putzki. His mission will unlock the secrets to his past and uncover the real enemies of Albatropolis. In single-player mode you play as Hardboiled Chicken and destroy your enemies with weapons you collect and unlock in each chapter which include a pistol, machine gun, shotgun and grenades. The game is a 2-D side scrolling platformer with gameplay that revolves around solving puzzles and killing enemies. There are also jetpack sections in which you must shoot other enemies out of the sky.The 2 player local co-op campaign lets you play as a pair of Budgie commandos on a mission to save the general’s daughter. The same areas are visited as in the single player but they are all modified slightly and the puzzles involve both players working together. There are six playable characters and each one has a different weapon.It is playable in stereoscopic 3-D. The original soundtrack was made by the Los Angeles based Sci-Fi rock band New World Revolution.Vita VersionA port to the PlayStation Vita was released on the PlayStation Network on February 12, 2013. While it does not support cross buy, it is 20% off for those who own the PlayStation 3 version. It has been described by the founder of Ratloop Games as "the ultimate version." The Vita version includes new single player chapters, front and rear touch controls, online co-op, and a new "Hardboiled" difficulty. "Hardboiled" difficulty requires players to make it through the game with only a pistol and a large knife. Players can also tilt the Vita to cause the backgrounds to move up, down, left and right,The co-op campaign on Vita is the same as the PS3 version and features 2 new characters that can be downloaded. One character is only available for those who played the demo on the PlayStation 3 and the other is for people who purchased the PlayStation 3 version.SequelConcept art for the sequel, Rocketbirds 2: Evolution, was available to view under the extras tab in the Vita version.PC System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Windows XP (with Service Pack 3), Windows Vista, Windows 7Processor: Dual Core with 2.0 GHzMemory: 1 GB RAMHard Disk Space: Min 501 MB free spaceVideo Card: 256 MB RAM graphics card (GF 7600 GT / Radeon X1950)Direct X: DirectX 9.0cSound: DirectX 9.0c compatible sound cardXbox 360 controller /gamepad (for co ops local)Recommended:OS: Windows Vista (SP1), Windows 7Processor: Dual Core with 2.0 GHzMemory: 2 GB RAMVideo Card: 512 MB graphics card (ATi HD 3870 / Nvidia GeForce 9800 GT)Direct X: DirectX 9.0cSound: DirectX 9.0c compatible sound cardXbox 360 controller /gamepad (for co ops local)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5269">Oddworld: Abe's Oddysee</game><game id="19281">Oddworld: Abe's Exoddus</game><game id="25637">Shank</game><game id="17483">Out of This World</game><game id="758">Heart of Darkness</game><game id="1066">Flashback: The Quest for Identity</game><game id="26706">Shadow Complex</game><game id="40860">Bleed</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2348367-cover.png</image></root>