<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36473</id><name>Demolition Inc.</name><description>OverviewEarth has been purchased by the "Society for the protection of endangered planets" (S.P.E.P), who intends on revegetating it and turn it into an intergalactic recreation area. For the task they have hired Mike, an alien one man demolition crew, to rid the planet from civilization. To his disposal, Mike has a wide arsenal of items to destroy entire city blocks. With each block cleaned from buildings, grass and trees takes its place until the entire section is revegetated and Mike is payed for his work. Though he must hurry, for the Army gets called in the second the first accident happens and he has a limited amount of time to complete his task before they arrive and blow him out of the sky.The game is physics based, making every demolition different depending on how the player decides to tackle the challenge. Some are obvious chain reaction puzzles, while others come down to simply taking over a tanker and jumping a ramp into a skyscraper. As things are destroyed, a combo meter fills and the player's position on the leaderboard goes up, the more money he has in his pocket and how much time spent when the task is done.ItemsOil CloudFree (Acquired by collecting tokens)A cloud that creates an oil slick and makes it impossible for cars to steer. (also useful for drifting)Wheel GlueFree (Acquired by collecting tokens)Sticks a cars left or right front tire, making it swerve towards a desired location.Explosive CowFree (Acquired by collecting tokens)Cow that explodes when touched by cars or debris. Useful to create chain reactions.Car ControllerFree (Acquired by collecting tokens)When chosen, the player can control a car with A/D until he crashes or presses RMB.Earthquake Bomb$500,000 (One time use)Bomb that the player can drop at chosen location and create a small earthquake.Wrecking Ball$80,000 (One time use)Ball that the player can roll around and it gets bigger from debris.PC System RequirementsOS: Windows XP, Vista, 7Processor: Pentium 4 1.8+ GHz or equivalentMemory: 1 GB (2 GB recommended for Windows Vista and Windows 7)Hard Disk Space: 500 MBVideo Card: 256 MB video RAMDirectX®: 9.0cSound: DirectX 9.0c compatible</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="29">Bowling</genre><genre id="45">Block-Breaking</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="32409">Demolition Company</game><game id="17543">Destroy All Humans!</game><game id="34702">Burnout CRASH!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1366/1974845-dem_inc.png</image></root>