<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3649</id><name>Prism: Light the Way</name><description>OverviewPrism: Light the Way is a simplistic 2D-puzzle game developed by  Morpheme Wireless Ltd. and published by  Eidos Interactive for the  Nintendo DS. The title was released on October 17th, 2007 in North America, September 21st, 2007 in Europe and October 25th, 2007 in Australia. It was preceded by a  PC version on September 21st, 2007, and also released on mobile phones around the same time period.GameplayUsing the light emitted from the Bulboids, alongside a set of items collectively called Gluons, the task consists of guiding the beams to various Globos scattered around an area. Furthermore, Bulboids only emit white light, thus providing a need for the use of prisms to split the light into separate colors for each specifically colored Globos. Gluons  Accompanying the Bulboids and Globos are the Gluons, a set of items that can be used to redirect or break light into set colors.Later levels become gradually more complex.  Mirrors: These can be used to reflect the light in a 90 degree angle across the stage. Both sides are usable. Filter Blocks: Filter the color into the color of the block itself. Prisms: Prisms split pure light into different colors to be fed to hungry Globos. T-Splitters: Split the light into two directions. They cannot be rotated. Cycloids: Cycloids filter light in the same way as Filter Blocks, but will rotate through an assortment of differing colors.Globos and Bulboids in action.    In addition to the main single-player Puzzle mode, a handful of other modes are available. The aforementioned Puzzle mode contains 120 puzzles of increasing difficulty,   logging the best times of each individual puzzles on a scoreboard. Tutorial teaches the basics of the game, while Time asks you to complete random puzzles before the Globos explode. Infinite is an endless stream of puzzles and lastly Hyper tasks the player to light up randomly placed Globos in a single square room.Local wireless multi-player modes consist of Co-op, a mode where both players control a single screen and must manipulate objects to reach the Globos on both sides while the other half of the action is invisible, and a competitive game to determine which player can solve certain pre-set puzzles the fastest. All multi-player requires 1 game card. AchievementsAn in-game achievement system also keeps track of the more notable missions the player has undertaken.Completed all Puzzle levels. Collected all Bronze Medals in Time Mode.Collected all Silver Medals in Time  Mode.Collected all Gold Medals in Time Mode.Survived 300 seconds in Time Mode.Scored 25,000 points in Infinite Mode.Scored 100,000 points in Hyper Mode.Scored 1,000,000 points total.  TriviaThe title is a tribute to video game composer and musician  Richard Joseph. </description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="33376">RUSH</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2714/758244-prismgem.jpg</image></root>