<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3650</id><name>Tiger Woods PGA Tour 06</name><description>Xbox 360 Version Problems While the game itself was about as stable as every other entry in the Tiger Woods franchise, the addition of achievements into the mix and online play presented new problems.  The achievement system in the game was largely broken and featured many achievements (except the one for averaging under 1.75 putts) that simply would not unlock upon completing the required task.  Even achievements like playing in 5 online matches would not unlock and contrary to public expectations in this modern era of gaming, EA never rectified the problem with a simple patch.  The online play also did not function most of the time, and when it did, suffered from tremendous amounts of latency.  Roster                        Tiger Woods                        Stuart Appleby                       Ricky Barnes                      Rich Beem                     John Daly                    Chris DiMarco                   Luke Donald                   Jim Furyk                 Retief Goosen                Natalie Gulbis               Charles Howell III              Justin Leonard             Colin Montgomerie            Ian Poulter           Justin Rose          Adam Scott         Vijay Singh         Ty Tryon        Mike Weir      Jack Nicklaus      Arnold Palmer     Ben Hogan   Old Tom Morris  COURSES There are a total of 14 different courses that can be played on, New to the Tiger Woods games are: Central Park, Cog Hill, Doral Passatemp, Reflection Bay and Troon North -PinnacleBethpage Black Central Park Cog Hill Doral Greek Isles Kapalua Pasatiempo Pebble Beach Pumpkin Ridge Red Rock Creek Reflection Bay* Sahalee St Andrews Troon North - Pinnacle</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="28">Golf</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2573">Tiger Woods PGA Tour 2001</game><game id="2302">PGA Tour Golf: Tournament Course Disk</game><game id="5493">Tiger Woods PGA Tour 2000</game><game id="697">PGA European Tour</game><game id="6799">PGA Tour Golf</game><game id="1336">Cyber Tiger</game><game id="14247">PGA Tour Golf III</game><game id="1547">Hot Shots Golf: Open Tee</game><game id="21797">Golf</game><game id="6957">Outlaw Golf 2</game><game id="17375">Jack Nicklaus 6: Golden Bear Challenge</game><game id="10089">Jack Nicklaus 5</game><game id="19715">Jack Nicklaus 4</game><game id="2617">Jack Nicklaus' Unlimited Golf &amp; Course Design</game><game id="21379">ProStroke Golf : World Tour 2007</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2269430-box_twpgat06.png</image></root>