<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36649</id><name>Scoregasm</name><description>OverviewScoregasm is a top down dual-joystick shooter developed by Charlie's Games. It is set in a galaxy that consists of a network of different levels that the player moves through in a non-linear fashion, where they control a ship and shoot in order to rack up points. There is also the option of choosing which level to progress to by the player performing high combos and surviving the Scoregasm Frenzy stage. There are 42 levels and 43 challenge levels and 7 different endings to be discovered.The game was designed and made by Charlie Knight, with music by John Marwin, Highscoregasm, the online score system was created by Doug Livesy. It is available for Windows, Mac OS and Linux.GameplayThe player must control a ship and shoot using a close range attack, a powerful melee-style energy blast that destroys anything in close proximity to the player's ship including enemy bullets. They can use the close range attack defensively to keep enemies away when they're in a tight spot, or they can use it offensively by charging into groups of enemies and bullets like a battering ram. However the close range attack is limited, and will need to be charged by shooting more enemies. They can also use power ups by building combos which add bullets and missiles to their arsenal and power up their weapons automatically. Players may also choose pathways throughout the game by achieving combos higher than the exit targets on each stage and surviving Scoregasm Frenzy and picking one of three directions.The game has an online scoring system with tag-able online profiles and custom online friend groups.PC System RequirementsRecommended:OS: Windows XP+Processor: 2ghz or fasterMemory: 1gb RamHard Disk Space: 100mb Free SpaceVideo Card: 512mb PCIE2 level graphics cardAdditional: Supports Controllers including Microsoft Xbox 360 controller for Windows.Mac System RequirementsOS: Snow Leopard 10.6 or later.Processor: 2ghz Intel processor (PPC not supported)Memory: 512mb RAMHard Disk Space: 100mb disk space</description><genres><genre id="31">Dual-Joystick Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21167">Geometry Wars: Retro Evolved 2</game><game id="11099">Geometry Wars: Retro Evolved</game><game id="16151">Geometry Wars: Galaxies</game><game id="793">Super Stardust HD</game><game id="22671">Bullet Candy</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3699/2025292-scoregasm.jpg</image></root>