<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36700</id><name>Guild 01</name><description>OverviewGuild 01 is Level 5's latest project, and was announced on their live show October 15th. This 3DS title actually contains four complete, but very different, games. Behind each game is a team led by different well-known names from the Japanese entertainment industry. Level 5 has announced that Guild 01 is supposed to be the first in a series of game collections and they are planning the following releases.GamesKaihou ShoujoLiterally translated to 'Liberation Girl' (localized as Liberation Maiden), the first game is a shooter by Suda 51. It is set a hundred years in the future, in 'New Japan', where some 'invaders' are trying to destroy the revolutionary new natural resource called Shinjuu and occupying the country. You play as the current president of New Japan, a high school girl with the last name Shoko, and you have to repel the invaders and liberate your country with your flying mecha. It has been announced that not only Suda 51 but Grasshopper Manufacture will work on this game.Rental Bukiya de OmasseA twist on the classic JRPG-setting - you play as a father and son who own a weapon shop, and you rent weapons to various heroic adventurers. It is up to you to make sure the adventurers get the best and most suitable weapons, or they will perish on their quests, you will never see your weapons again and consequently loose money. Yoshituki Hirai, part of the Japanese comedy group American Zarigani, is leading this project.Air PorterAir Porter (Aero Porter) is what appears to be an airport-luggage-handling sim. You will need to make sure everything runs smoothly and that planes will arrive and depart on time, be rewarder through the game's combo system and expand, improve and customise your airport. If you get good enough, you will be asked to serve Air Force One. This game is made by Yukata 'Yoot' Saito.Crimson ShroudCrimson Shroud is an RPG with a dark fantasy setting, and it is being directed by Yasumi Matsuno, who was recently recruited by Level 5.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/97089/2169417-guild01.png</image></root>