<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36713</id><name>Toki Tori 2</name><description>OverviewToki Tori 2 is an open-world puzzle game from Two Tribes. The game was released on Wii U on April 4, 2013. An updated version with new features was also released on PC and Mac as "Toki Tori 2+" via Steam on July 11, 2013. Toki Tori 2+ was made available for Wii U owners of the game in September that same year as a free update along with replacing the existing Toki Tori 2 on the eShop as the main version.GameplayIn the original Toki Tori, players could use weapons and items whereas in Toki Tori 2, all of this has been taken away in favor of focusing entirely on chirping and stomping. The former is used to attract animals within a set radius. They will come toward Toki Tori and thus function as puzzle elements. The player can learn various songs (consisting of long and short chirps) that yield different results. Stomping takes care of the opposite need, getting animals away from Toki Tori. When dealing with stationary wild life, stomping might cause it to react in other ways.System RequirementsPCMinimumOS: Windows 7Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo or comparableMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: Geforce 8000 series (discrete) or Intel HD 3000 (integrated) GPUDirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 1 GB HD spaceController: Gamepad supportRecommendedOS: Windows 7Processor: Intel i5 or comparableMemory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: Geforce 9800 GT or better with 1 GB of dedicated VRAMDirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 1 GB HD spaceController: Gamepad support MacMinimumOS: Mac OS X 10.7 (Lion)Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo or comparableMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: Geforce 8000 series (discrete) or Intel HD 3000 (integrated) GPUHard Drive: 1 GB HD spaceController: Gamepad supportRecommendedOS: Mac OS X 10.8 (Mountain Lion)Processor: Intel i5 or comparableMemory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: Geforce 9800 GT or better with 1 GB of dedicated VRAMHard Drive: 1 GB HD spaceController: Gamepad support</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22664">Catrap</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/81005/2428586-tokitori2_whatsmyname.png</image></root>