<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36721</id><name>Code of Princess</name><description>OverviewCode of Princess is a side-scrolling action game developed by Agatsuma Entertainment for the 3DS. The game was released in Japan on April 19, 2012 and Atlus USA published it in North America on October 9, 2012.Story  GameplayMonsters are attacking the kingdom and princess Solange Blanchefleur de Luxe, equipped with a magical sword, is entrusted by her father to restore peace to the land!The gameplay of Code of Princess is very similar to Treasure's classic brawler, Guardian Heroes. The game's levels are made up of three 2D layers that the player can jump between. Defeating enemies gives experience points that strengthen your character and there are cooperative/competitive multiplayer modes for up to four players in local and online environments.DevelopmentThe cast of COP drawn by Kinu NishimuraCode of Princess was the first original game developed by Agatsuma Entertainment and a hand full of notable Japanese gaming veterans helped created the title. Former Capcom artist Kinu Nishimura, who worked on the Street Fighter series as well as the Overman King Gainer anime, designed the world and characters for Code of Princess. The game design was done by former Treasure developers HAN and Masaki Ukyo, who are both known for their work on the first Guardian Heroes. Tetsuhiko "HAN" Kikuch is credited with Code of Princess' original plan, enemy character design, and motion supervision. Masaki Ukyo worked on the game design, system programming, and player character creation.CharactersThere are four playable character in the primary story mode of Code of Princess. Additional characters are available for play in other modes.Solange Blanchefleur de Luxe: The princess of land who is tasked with defeating the monsters attacking her Kingdom.Ali-Baba: A lone thief that was once the leader of a group of bandits before being betrayed by her second-in-command.Allegro Nantabile Cantabile: An elf bard and trickster that fights using a guitar.Lady Zozo: A sorceress who turned herself undead in order to explore new forms of magic.</description><genres><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5901">Guardian Heroes</game><game id="11728">Panzer Bandit</game><game id="20733">Castle Crashers</game><game id="38031">Senran Kagura Burst</game><game id="35594">Dragon's Crown</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2303972-box_cop.png</image></root>