<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36763</id><name>Prison Architect</name><description>OverviewThe game is a complex prison management game, inspired by games such as Dwarf Fortress, Theme Park and Dungeon Keeper according to the alpha release developer video. Starting with a plot of empty land an a handful of workers you must create a working prison nothing in order to house ruthless convicted criminals and all their needs.GameplaySimilar to simulation games, Prison Architect lets you control, build, and create a prison from the ground up. You're in charge of housing prisoners safely and securely as well as staffing the prison so it continues to run smoothly. Each building you create can be turned into any type of room which includes offices for staff, cells for prisoners, showers and kitchens to keep prisoners satisfied, and security for everyone's safety. All the awhile your workers work in real time running down the building orders as you give them and you are given grants and a budget to balance in order to continually take care of your prison.All the while everything you build must have resources purchased and brought in. Your prison will need staff members who you will hire and coordinate. And through those staff members you can research new options for your prison like cameras, riot police, cloning buildings for easier construction, and maintenance staff.CellsAs soon as the game begins a clock begins counting down until your first round of prisoners arrive and you must be prepared to house them securely. There are three types of cells for holding these prisoners inside away from proper society.Holding Cell: At least a 5x5 building that must have a bench and toilet. Designed for holding 8 prisoners but only temporary with a lack of a bed which is required for prisoner's to get adequate rest. Best used in the initial phase of a prison until your workers have built individual cells. Housing too many prisoners together in one cell like this can lead to violence.Cell: At least a 2x3 size building that must have a bed and a toilet. These are only for one prisoner and provide the inmate the comfort of a bed. These help to separate individual inmates in case of fights, riots, or any prison emergency.Solitary: Another individual cell that has no size requirement and only needs a solitary door on it's entrance. Only used when prisoners get out of line or violent and only a few are really needed per cell block.Prisoner AmenitiesShowers: Unless you want some stinky prisoners a shower is needed. No size requirement but it does need a shower head hooked up to the water pump. Some drains added will also help with the flooding that can occur when too many prisoners are showering at once. The more shower heads the better since the shower is often times the place where fights and even riots break out.Canteen/Kitchen: Prisoners need a place to eat and a kitchen to cook (and even work in). The canteen can be any size and only needs a serving table to work but should also have either benches or tables and chairs so the prisoners have a place to sit and eat. Similar to the shower frustration about waiting too long for food or not having a place to sit could result in fights. The kitchen houses your hired cook and is where all the food is prepared. It should be placed nearby the canteen for easy access by the cooks.Yard: Exercise could turn a frustrated and violent inmate into a tired and willing one. Having an outdoor space, properly secured of course, is key for the yard. Also having a few payphones could help with homesickness and a weight bench with any exercise needs. A tree or two could also be nice for the prisoners but you don't have to placate to their needs every time.Common Room: When prisoners have free time their choices can be limited and thus boredom can set in. Having a room or building set aside with a TV, bookshelf, or even pool table for those well behaved inmates may keep their hands busy instead of watching them stab a guard.Visitation Room: A phone just isn't enough and families may want to visit their loved ones in prison sometimes. A room with a visiting table is all that is needed to prisoners can relieve their homesickness.Staff RoomsOffices: In order to properly run a prison you'll need staff around to keep things running smoothly. A good chunk of your staff (like your warden, psychologist, foreman, etc.) will require an office before they truly can begin work. Each office must be a 4x4 room with a desk, chair, and filing cabinet. Once your staff member has their very own office their work can begin and often times it means they can research more options for your prison.Storage: A room with no requirements where your construction workers will place their extra equipment, removing it from the deliveries area. This can remove unsafe and dangerous materials from a prisoner's violent hands.Cleaning Cupboard: Very similar to the storage room, this room is meant specifically for use by janitors. This room will house mostly bleach and other cleaning products janitors need for their jobs but prisoners could use for dangerous things.Infirmary: In order to treat some of the more serious injuries that can occur in a prison your doctors will need an infirmary The only requirement for this room is infirmary bed which will allow wounded prisoners a chance to rest up and heal.Morgue: Despite all your safety measures, locked doors, numerous guards, and hours of planning a death in your prisoner could be inevitable. There needs to be a place to place those bodies whether caused by an out of control prisoner of coming from the hands of the electric chair. This room only requires a cadaver slab in order to be considered a morgue.System RequirementsPCOS:XPProcessor:Intel Core2 Duo 2.4Ghz or Higher / AMD 3Ghz or HigherMemory:4 GB RAMGraphics:Nvidia 8600 / Radeon equivalent (2009 era)Hard Drive:100 MB HD spaceMacProcessor: 2009 era Macbook Pro, Core2 Duo processorMemory: 4 GB RAMHard Drive: 100 MB HD spaceLinuxOS: Ubuntu 12.04 or laterProcessor: Intel Core2 Duo 2.4Ghz or Higher / AMD 3Ghz or HigherMemory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: Nvidia 8600 / Radeon equivalent (2009 era)Hard Drive: 100 MB HD space</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6562">Theme Park</game><game id="21594">Slaves to Armok II: Dwarf Fortress</game><game id="17620">Dungeon Keeper</game><game id="23725">Prison Tycoon 4: SuperMax</game><game id="10364">Prison Tycoon</game><game id="22257">Prison Tycoon 2: Maximum Security</game><game id="22250">Prison Tycoon 3: Lockdown</game><game id="44272">RimWorld</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1326/2005326-prisonarch_logo.jpg</image></root>