<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36765</id><name>Grand Theft Auto V</name><description>OverviewGrand Theft Auto V (GTA V) takes the franchise back to the city of Los Santos previously seen in Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas. Unlike prior games in the series which focus on telling the story of a single player controlled character, GTA V features three central characters that the player is able to actively switch between at nearly any time during gameplay.Rockstar Games states that this will be their largest open world game to date, boasting a total area greater than those of GTA: San Andreas, GTA IV, and Red Dead Redemption combined. At a preview event in Spring 2013, reps said that the map in GTA V will be "five times bigger than Red Dead Redemption".A first for the franchise, players won't be restricted from certain areas in the game and can now explore the entire environment at their leisure.GameplayGameplay will be similar to that of previous installments in the franchise. Players will control one of three characters in a free-roaming open-world environment. GTA V will place a higher emphasis on heist missions, in which players can switch between the various protagonists on the fly, potentially allowing them to take control of a car or provide covering fire as they see fit. Players can also switch between the protagonists between missions at any time.Many of the game elements found in GTA IV will return, such as fake TV shows, minigames, clothing customization, and leisure activities, which now include tennis, yoga and base jumping. Dynamic missions have been introduced - similar to the random encounters of Red Dead Redemption, players may come across certain situations as they travel the world that they can choose whether or not to investigate.The customary bevy of vehicles and weapons will be available.StoryGTA V splits its story between three playable characters, each representing a different side of Los Santos. Each character will have their own missions and side stories, as well as their own daily routines when not controlled by the player. The story progresses as the player completes missions with all three, which can allow the player to have insight into the events even when their current character does not. The player can switch between each characters at any time.CharactersThe three playable protagonists of the game are a retired bank robber named Michael, a violent career criminal named Trevor, and a young repo man named Franklin. Each character will represent a different personality and angle of the world of crime in Los Santos.Michael De SantaMichael is a successful former bank robber in his early 40s, who decided to retire by making a deal with the authorities, and settled down with his family. Now, his marriage is in ruins and he is incapable of connecting with either of his two teenage children. Michael seeks to ditch his lush life in Rockford Hills and get back in the game.Trevor PhillipsTrevor is a violent drug addict, in his early 40s. He has worked with Michael in the past, and is firmly entrenched in a life of crime. He has experience as a former military pilot and is currently living in Blaine County. He is the 'loose cannon' of the group.Franklin ClintonFranklin works as a repo man for a luxury car dealership in South Los Santos. He is an ambitious hustler in his mid 20s who seeks fortune and only knows how to attain it on the streets. Franklin is fit and much more capable than Michael and Trevor.Game EnginePreliminary reports describe Grand Theft Auto V's graphics engine as a modified version of the Rage engine used in Grand Theft Auto IV. The engine was extensively modified for Red Dead Redemption after GTA IV and further refinements are reported to be made for GTA V and Max Payne 3.MultiplayerThe online multiplayer component, referred to as GTA Online, The online multiplayer component, referred to as GTA Online, will launch as a free download two weeks after the initial release of GTA V. The service officially launched on October 1st, 2013.In GTA Online, up to 16 players engage in co-op missions, competitive deathmatches and races, or free roam activities. An included in-game editor will also allow players to design their own missions to share with other players. Nearly all of the components from the single player game are accessible in GTA Online including side activities such as golf and tennis. Additionally, the multiplayer features player progression and persistence with each player earning reputation points and money to spend on clothing, properties, vehicles, weapons, and more. Some elements of the world will also be persistent among all players in GTA Online including for example the stock prices of various companies players can invest money into.GTA Online is set prior to the events of GTA V's single player and will feature interactions with some of its characters.Rockstar has stated that GTA Online will have extended support with additional content, including the possible addition of new areas at some point in the future.GTA Online launched on October 1st, 2013, but had some major server issues after it launched, mainly because of "millions" of people logging in to the service at the same time. Rockstar confirmed that they were having server issues the same day, and have been working to fix the server issues since. They have posted multiple blog posts about the progress, and almost all the server issues have been resolved. SoundtrackGTA V features 240 licensed tracks across 15 radio stations, and is the first game in the franchise to also feature an original score. The original score is produced by three separate composers, Edgar Froese of the electronic band Tangerine Dream, Woody Jackson who previously worked on the Red Dead Redemption and LA Noire soundtracks, and the hip-hop duo Alchemist and Oh No. Each composer's distinct sound is used to define the different characters and environments of the game.East LOS FMGenre: Various Mexican MusicDJ: Camilo Lara  Don ChetoLa Vida Boheme - Radio CapitalHechizeros Band - El SoniditoLa Liga ft. Alika - Yo Tengo El DonLos Buitres de Culiacan - El CocainoMexican Institute of Sound - Es-ToyNiña Dioz - Criminal SoundFandango - Autos, Moda, y Rock and RollDon Cheto - El TatuadoLa Sonora Dinamita - Se Me Perdió La CadenitaFiebre de Jack - She's a TeaseMaldita Vecinidad - PachucoMilkman - FrescoLos Tigres del Norte - La GranjaLos Angeles Negros - El Rey y YoFlyLo FMGenre: ElectronicDJ: Flying LotusFlying Lotus feat. Niki Randa - Getting ThereClams Casino - CrystalsFlying Lotus - CrosswervedFlying Lotus - Be SpinFlying Lotus - See Thru to UFlying Lotus - The DiddlerFlying Lotus - Computer Face RmxHudson Mohawke - 100hmFlying Lotus feat. Niki Randa - The KillTyler, the Creator - GarbageOutkast - Elevators (Me  You)Captain Murphy - Evil GrinFlying Lotus - Catapult ManDabrye - Encoded FlowMachinedrum - She Died ThereDJ Rashad - It's WackThundercat - Oh Sheit It's XFlying Lotus - StonecuttersShadow Child - 23Kingdom - Stalker HaAphex Twin - Windowlicker Rebel RadioGenre: CountryDJ: Jesco WhiteCharlie Feathers - Can't Hardly Stand ItJohnny Paycheck - It Won't Be Long (And I'll Be Hating You)Hasil Adkins - Get Out of My CarWaylon Jennings - Are You Sure Hank Done It This WayHank Thompson - It Don't Hurt AnymoreJerry Reed - You Took All the Ramblin' Out of MeJohnny Cash - General LeeOzark Mountain Daredevils - If You Wanna Get to HeavenWaylon Jennings - I Ain't Living Long Like ThisWillie Nelson - Whiskey RiverCW McCall - ConvoyVinewood Boulevard RadioGenre: Modern RockDJ: Stephen Pope and Nathan WilliamsShark? – California GrrrlsBass Drum of Death – Crawling After YouThee Oh Sees – The DreamWavves - Nine is GodFidlar - CocaineHot Snakes - This Mystic DecadeMoon Duo - SleepwalkerSam Flax - Fire Doesn't Burn ItselfThe Black Angels - Black GreaseMETZ - Wet BlanketCeremony - HysteriaTy Segall - Diddy Wah DiddyWest Coast ClassicsGenre: 90's RapDJ: DJ PoohInfo: DJ Pooh was a co-writer on GTA: San Andreas.The Dogg Pound - What Would You DoCompton's Most Wanted - Late Night HypeNWA - Gangsta Gangsta2Pac - Ambitionz Az A RidahDJ Quik - Dollaz  SenseDr. Dre ft. Snoop Dogg - Still D.R.E.King Tee - Played Like a PianoDr. Dre ft. Snoop Dogg - The Next EpisodeIce Cube - You Know How We Do ItKausion - What You Wanna DoKurupt - C-WalkMack 10  Tha Dogg Pound - Nothin' but the Cavi HitMC Eiht - Streiht Up MenaceNWA - Appetite for DestructionSnoop Dogg - Gin and JuiceThe Geto Boys - Mind Playin' Tricks on MeToo $hort - So You Want to Be a GangsterRadio Los Santos 106.1Genre: Modern RapDJ: Big BoyA$AP Rocky - r-caliMarion Band$ ft. Nipsey Hussle - Hold UpProblem ft. Glass Malone - Say That ThenYG - I'm a Real 1100s - Life of a MackAb Soul ft Kendrick Lamar - IlluminateBJ The Chicago Kid ft. Freddie Gibbs and Problem - Smoke and RideKendrick Lamar - A.D.H.D.Jay Rock ft. Kendrick Lamar - Hood Gone Love ItThe Game ft 2Chainz and Rick Ross - Ali BomayeFreddie Gibbs - Still Livin'Future - How It WasClyde Carson ft. The Team - Slow DownGucci Mane ft. Ciara - Too HoodGangrene - BassheadsChannel XGenre: PunkDJ: Keith MorrisCircle Jerks - Rock HouseThe Germs - Lexicon DevilYouth Brigade - Blown AwayThe Weirdos - Life of CrimeBlack Flag - My WarT.S.O.L. - Abolish Government / Silent MajorityDescendants - PervertSuicidal Tendencies - SubliminalFear - The Mouth Don't Stop (The Trouble with Women IS)Adolescents - AmoebaAgent Orange - Bored of youOFF! - What's Next? Blaine County Talk Radio 96.5Genre: TalkShows:1. Beyond InseminationHost: Duane Earl2. BCR Community HourHost: Ron Jakowski (Nervous Ron)3. Bless Your HeartHost: Bobby JuneWest Coast Talk Radio - WCTR 95.6Genre: TalkShows:1. ChattersphereHost: Michelle MinxCo-host: Lazlow2. Chakra AttackHost: Dr. Ray D'Angelo HarrisCo-host: Cheryl3. The Fernando ShowHost: Fernando MartinezSpace 103.2Genre: FunkDJ: Bootsy CollinsRick James - Give it to Me BabyEvelyn "Champagne" King - I'm in Love (12" Version)Eddie Murphy - Party all the TimeKleer - TonightD Train - You're the One for MeZapp - Heartbreaker, Pts. 1-2Kano - Can't Hold Back (Your Loving)One Way - Cutie PieStevie Wonder - SkeletonsBootsy Collins - I'd Rather Be With YouBernard Wright - Haboglabotribin'Sho Nuff - Funkasize YouTaana Gardner - Heartbeat (Club Version)Radio Mirror ParkGenre: IndieDJ: Twin ShadowBlack Strobe - Boogie in Zero GravityFeathers - Dark MatterPoolside - Do You Believe?Dan Croll - From Nowhere (Baardsen Remix)Jai Paul - Jasmine (Demo)DJ Mehdi - Lucky Boy (Outlines Remix)Yacht - Psychic City (Classixx Remix)The C90's - Shine A Light (Flight Facilities Remix)Twin Shadow - Shooting HolesTwin Shadow - Old Love, New LoveToro Y Moi - So Many DetailsMiami Horror - SometimesYeasayer - Don't Come CloseThe Chain Gang of 1974 - SleepwalkingBattle Tapes - Feel the SameLiving Days - Little White LieTony Castles - Heart in the Pipes (Kauf Remix)Age of Consent - ColoursFavored Nations - The Set UpNeon Indian - Change of CoastNite Jewel - Nowhere to GoHEALTH - High Pressure DaveThe Low Down 91.1Genre: SoulDJ: 'Mama G' Pam GrierMarlena Shaw - California SoulSmokey Robinson  The Miracles - Cruisin'B.T. Express - Do It ('Til You're Satisfied)Aaron Neville - HerculesWar - The Cisco KidThe Five Stairsteps - O-o-h ChildThe Delfonics - Ready or Not Here I Come (Can't Hide from Love)The Trammps - Rubber BandUndisputed Truth - Smiling Faces SometimesGeorge McCrae - I Get LiftedThe Soul Searchers - Ashley's RoachclipEl Chicano - Viva Tirado Worldwide FMGenre: LoungeDJ: Giles Petersoninc. - Cold AirMala - GhostSwindle - Forest FunkTom Browne - Throw DownDonald Byrd - You and the MusicCandido - Thousand Finger ManToro y Moi - Harm in ChargeKyodai - BreakingDjango Django - WaveformsGaslamp Killer - NissimOwiny Sigoma Band - Harpoon LandYuna - Live Your Life (Melo-X Motherland God Mix)Hackman - Forgotten NotesCashmere Cat - Mirror MaruTrickski - BeginningsGuts - Brand New RevolutionKiko Navarro  Tuccillo, Amor - Lovery (Slow Cuban Vibe Mix)Richard Spaven - 1759 (Outro) The Blue ArkGenre: ReggaeDJ: Lee "Scratch" PerryDennis Brown - Money in my PocketHalf Pint - Crazy GirlJoe Gibbs  The Professionals - Chapter ThreeLee Perry  The Full Experience - Disco DevilThe Upsetters - Grumblin' DubKonShens - Gun Shot a FireLee Perry  The Upsetters - I Am a MadmanProtoje - Kingston Be WiseGregory Isaacs - Night NurseYellowman - Nobody Move, Nobody Get HurtChronixx - Odd RasTommy Lee Sparta - PsychoJunior Delgado - Sons of SlavesVybz Kartel ft. Popcaan - We Never Fear Dem Soulwax FMGenre: TechnoDJ: SoulwaxMim Suleiman - "Mingi"FKCLUB - The Strange Art (ID Remix)Matias Aguayo - El Sucu TucuJoe Goddard ft. Valentina - Gabriel (Soulwax Remix)Daniel Maloso - Body MusicGreen Velvet  Harvard Bass - Lazer BeamsZombie Nation - TryoutsTiga - Plush (Jacques Lu Cont Remix)Pulp - After You (Soulwax Remix)The Hacker - Shockwave (Gesaffelstein Remix)Transistorcake - Mr.Croissant TakerGoose - Synrise (Soulwax Remix)Jackson and his Computerband - Arp #1Tom Rowlands - Nothing but PleasureJoe Goddard - GabrielFKCLUB - The Strange ActSupersempfft - Let's Beam Him UpFatal Error - Fatal ErrorPalmbomen - Stock (Soulwax Remix) Non Stop Pop FMGenre: PopDJ: Cara DelevigneCorona - The Rhythm of the NightModjo - Lady (Hear Me Tonight)Britney Spears - Gimmie MoreRihanna - Only Girl (In the World)Stardust - Music Sounds Better with YouJane Child - Don't Wanna Fall in LoveRobyn ft. Kleerup - With Every HeartbeatThe Blackout All-Stars - I Like it Like ThatKelly Rowland - Work (Freemasons Remix)Pet Shop Boys - West End GirlsAll Saints - Pure ShoresMis-Teeq - ScandalousAmerie - 1 ThingFergie ft. Ludacris - GlamorousHall  Oates - Adult EducationN-Joi - AnthemWham! - Everything She Wants  Los Santos Rock RadioGenre: RockDJ: Kenny LogginsSmall Faces - Ogdens' Nut Gone FlakeQueen - Radio Ga GaForeigner - Dirty White BoyThe Cult - RainSteve Miller Band - Rock 'N MeThe Alan Parsons Project - I Wouldn't Want to Be Like YouElton John - Saturday Night's Alright for FightingGreg Kihn Band - The Breakup Song (They Don't Write 'Em)Julian Lennon - Too Late for GoodbyesThe Doobie Brothers - What a Fool BelievesBilly Squier - Lonely is the NightBob Seger - Hollywood NightsBob Seger - Night MovesPhil Collins - I Don't Care AnymoreChicago - If you Leave Me NowDef Leppard - PhotographSteve Winwood - Higher LoveStevie Nicks - I Can't WaitDon Johnson - HeartbeatRobert Plant - Big LogGerry Rafferty - Baker StreetKenny Loggins - I'm Free (Heaven Helps the Man)Simple Minds - All the Things She Said Special and Collector's EditionRockstar Games has announced that the Special and Collector's edition of GTA V will be available for pre-order as of May 23, 2013 from participating retailers. The special edition is set to retail for $80 and Collector's edition for $150. In addition to any variation of a GTA V pre-order, customers will receive access to the "Atomic Blimp" as an in-game vehicle.Special EditionA full retail copy of Grand Theft Auto 5Collectible Steelbook featuring exclusive artworkExclusive 21.5” x 26.75” blueprint map with points of interest and fast-cash opportunities cryptically marked.25% regeneration increase to Michael, Franklin and Trevor's special abilities.Stunt plane trials across Los Santos and Blaine CountyBonus main character outfits, tattoos and special deals with stores across Los Santos and Blaine CountyFree exclusive weapons in Ammunation stores in single player: Pistol .50, Bullpop Shotgun and Melee HammerCollector's EditionEverything included in the Special Edition of GTA VGrand Theft Auto V security deposit bag and logo keyGrand Theft Auto V New Era 9FIFTY™ Snapback CapClassic characters from previous Grand Theft Auto games for use within the multiplayer customization systemSpecial vehicles and garage property including, 1930's style Hotknife and CarbonRS sports bike within single player as well as the Khamelion electric car in multiplayer</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25725">Saints Row: The Third</game><game id="25249">Red Dead Redemption</game><game id="38538">Watch Dogs</game><game id="4372">Maniac Mansion: Day of the Tentacle</game><game id="36277">Ryu ga Gotoku 5: Yume Kanaeshi Mono</game><game id="27487">Yakuza 4</game><game id="20679">Saints Row 2</game><game id="36884">Saints Row IV</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3699/2463980-grand+theft+auto+v.jpg</image></root>