<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36857</id><name>Krater</name><description>StoryBillions have died, and Earth destroyed. The Krater - founded by survivors of the nuclear war, born from the undergång when the old world died - is now the last bastion of hope in a land that was once called Sweden. The stalwart band of settlers not only discovered rich and fertile soil surrounding the Krater, but also treasures from the past, hidden away and buried deep within the Underside which stretches further than any man has been able to dig. Bandits, free-diggers and fortune seekers fight amongst themselves in endless dungeons and caves, and sinister forces draw near looking for the wealth and technology of the old world.GameplayKrater is heavily focused on exploration and combat. You explore post-apocalyptic Sweden via the worldmap, discovering hundreds of towns and dungeons, and often encountering random events which can either benefit or hinder your progress. Each location provides quests and side-missions which reward you with loot and blueprints, allowing you to upgrade your squad with better weapons, gadgets, boosters and implants. While your squad is limited to 3 members at a time, there are many towns in Krater that will let you recruit more soldiers, giving the freedom to swap in and out characters of your choosing. Each character is assigned a random allocation of stats and a specific class that dictates the character's playstyle.There are currently 4 classes in Krater:Bruiser- Soaks up damage and taunts enemies.Regulator- Stuns and slows targets.Medikus- Provides support and heals allies.Slayer- Deals lots of damage, naturally.Every character can be customised further with the use of boosters and implants, which can be crafted from blueprints found all over Krater, from enemies, loot containers, to quest rewards. Blueprints vary in rarity and quality, with the best blueprints requiring exotic crafting materials found in only the deepest, most dangerous dungeons.DLCFatshark AB will continue to support Krater with extra content after release, free of charge. As well as co-op support, there are plans for content to be released that further the narrative of Krater with story missions and extra side-quests, as well as more weapons, blueprints, and character classes.Shadows over SolsideThe first of three episodes set in the world of Krater. You arrive in Norrmalm, an active town close to the ridge that seperates Krater from the rest of the world. You will find many helpful people in Norrmalm willing to help guide you through your first steps in this bizarre region of post-apocalyptic Sweden. You may even find a couple of people willing to give you a job or two.Pledge of the PatriarchPlanned for a Q3 2012 release, the second episode of Krater will have you explore deeper into the region. No information has been released regarding the plot of Pledge of the Patriarch, though there are some hints as to what will be included:A new area has been opened up and is accessible to playersAn extra playable race with 4 new classesSeveral new enemy factions and monstersNew weapons, blueprints, upgradesCo-opPlanned for an October 23rd release, this update will not only provide co-op, but also gameplay tweaks, extra content, new areas to explore, new songs, an improved user interface, updated visuals and much more.SoundtrackChristian Gabel gave birth to the Krater soundtrack after the musician discovered abandoned artwork dating back to 1982 for a movie that never went into production. The concept work depicted scenes of a post-apocalyptic Karlstad, Christian's hometown. Inspired, Christian began experimenting with an 80s film score of his own, based on a ruined and desolate Karlstad. After a chance meeting with the musician and Fatshark AB, discussing music for an old-school role-playing game set in post-apocalyptic Sweden, Christian was hired to produce the soundtrack for Krater inspired by his previous film score.Track #TitleAuthor1.Welcome to KraterChristian Gabel2.TutorialChristian Gabel3.WorldmapChristian Gabel4.BloodclotChristian Gabel, remix by Jonas Hellberg5.Mines ExplorationChristian Gabel6.Mines BattleChristian Gabel, remix by Jonas Hellberg7.Caves ExplorationChristian Gabel8.Caves BattleChristian Gabel, remix by Jonas Hellberg9.Bunkers ExplorationChristian Gabel10.Bunkers BattleChristian Gabel, remix by Jonas Hellberg11.Random Encounters ExplorationSebastian Thott12.Random Encounters BattleSebastian Thott13.The Wasteland ExplorationSebastian Thott14.The Wasteland BattleSebastian Thott15.FabrikernaChristian Gabel, remix by Jonas Hellberg16.Future-Medievil-Bar-MusicJonas Hellberg17.DIYAlouatta18.Polischefens TangoLurken Boogie Band19.Din MedicinThe Nature20.Den enda dan jag hittills inte velat döSexpistolstanten  Mockfjärdsvapnet21.Parabolic HyperfliesAcegikmo22.Beers and NoodlesNordloef23.Dagarna gårÖstermalm24.Balladen om den vilsne vandrarenAnders och Karim Muammar, performed by Freddie WadlingPC System RequirementsMinimumOS:Windows Vista / Windows 7Processor:Dual Core 2.4GHz processorMemory:2 GB RAMGraphics:Shader 4.0 compatible card (minimum: Nvidia GeForce 8xxx, AMD Radeon 2xxx)DirectX®: DirectX11 drivers (the game support DX10 hardware)Hard Drive: 5 GB HD spaceRecommendedOS: Windows 7 (64 bit)Processor: Quad-core Intel or AMD CPUMemory: 4GBHard Disk Space: 5GBVideo Card: DirectX 11 compatible Nvidia or AMD ATI card, ATI Radeon HD6870 or higher, Nvidia GeForce GTX 460 or higher. Graphics card memory: 1 GBDirectX®: DirectX11 drivers (the game support DX10 hardware)</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11704">Fallout</game><game id="5559">Fallout 2</game><game id="196">X-COM: UFO Defense</game><game id="10865">Syndicate</game><game id="5985">Diablo</game><game id="3958">Nox</game><game id="19703">Darkstone</game><game id="20803">Diablo III</game><game id="6346">Fallout Tactics: Brotherhood of Steel</game><game id="18103">Bandits: Phoenix Rising</game><game id="14605">Dragonfire: The Well of Souls</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/23724/2018212-krater_logo_full.jpg</image></root>