<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36874</id><name>The Powder Toy</name><description>OverviewThe Powder Toy is a physics game similar to those like the falling sand game. Unlike the falling sand game, Powder toy simulates wind, air pressure, heat, and multiple forms of gravity. The game relies heavily on processor power, but the game requires very little on graphics.GameplayA complicated rocketThe game requires nothing more than a mouse to control it, but many keyboard commands are available for optional use. Players will find that they have a very large variety of materials, minerals, and tools at their disposal. They are all split up into twelve separate sections: Walls, Electronics, Powered Materials, Explosives, Gasses, Liquids, Powders, Solids, Radioactives, Special, Life, and Tools.Walls are materials that cannot be destroyed. They contain many different types, from regular to ones that only let certain things pass through. They can be used to assure peices of you creation to not fly off the sides or just to made something that cannot break. To erase walls, you must use a special type of eraser called the Wall Eraser.Electronics include anything that is a good conductor along with the 2 electricity tools. This includes a variety of metals along with switches and other things needed to create a circuit. This can be used to create complicated timed events and to just add things like lamps to creations focused more on design than simulation.Powered Materials Includes a few more electronic components used for creating circuits and lights, these can serve as fast acting power sources in your creations.Explosives are non-radioactive materials that can be used to caused anywhere from large to small explosions, many materials such as C-4 and Gun Powder can be set up to create deadly explosions. The tools used for creating fire is also located in this section, as fire is the main trigger for explosive objects.Gasses are any materials that float in the air and have light particles, what I mean is this is where the gasses are, such as Oxygen and Smoke. Many Liquids and Solids turn into gasses, and gasses can change the temperatures of things when is touches them, depending on the type of gas.Liquids are materials that cannot hold there own shape, any sort of liquid is kept there, such as water, lava, acid, and oil. There are many different types of liquids for you to use and many of them have varied properties.Powders are any material that consists of small grainy particles, this section consists of things such as yeast, concrete, dust, and snow. this section consists of things that seem to have little use, but they do contribute to the 'powder' feel of the game when used in the communities creations.Solids are any hard materials that keep there own shape. This section includes things such as ice, wood, iron, coal, diamond, and brick. There are many different types of solids for you to use and many of them have varied properties.Radioactive materials include any element or material that emits harmless or dangerous particles and waves into the air, such as uranium and plutonium. A few other things are placed in this section such as Neutrons and Photons. These are the types of materials that allow you to create enormous bombs, that can destroy entire creations, but in simulation fashion, the bomb has to be created using the correct materials, while the amounts do not matter.The famous creation 'Destroy-able City 5'Special materials include a large variety of materials that do a large variety of things. It includes a few miscellaneous things such as a stick man character you can put in your games if you wish to have your creation seem more like a level out of a game. It also includes "Portal In" and "Portal Out" which allow you to teleport particles from one location on the screen to another. This is a reference to the PC game Portal. It also includes other less important things such as a cloner particle.Life includes insanely deadly high temperature materials that use mathematical equations that randomly generate and grow when you place them, usually these grow rapidly and cannot be deleted, they destroy almost anything that is not a wall which means it could not really be used for any truly practical purpose.Tools includes things that do not add anything to the actual creation, they can change the temperature and gravity, and can also play with the air pressure.The game's heat visionMany other buttons are available, allowing you to change gravity and change your view of the creation to something else, whether it be more simple, or be focused on fire, or even be straight up heat vision.CommunityA creation created by a powder toy playerThe Powder toy has a semi-large community of people from all over the world constantly creating and uploading creations that include things from intuitive bombs to industrial cities to working jet engines. The community has a forum and a small modder base of people who add their own materials to the game, and the creators of Powder toy are known for adding materials created by the community to the actual games, always distributing a beta version of the game weeks before they decide to keep new features in.Walls:Conductive WallE-WallDetectorStreamlineSignFanLiquid PermeableAbsorbing WallEraserWallNon-Preamble WallSolid Preamble WallConductorE-HoleGas Preamble WallGravity WallEnergy WallTools:AirVacuumCoolHeatWindPositive GravityNegative GravityEdit Property ToolLiquids:Liquid OxygenLiquid NitrogenGlowDieselMolten WaxAcidLavaOilBizarrePasteSoapGelWaterSalt WaterDistilled WaterCarbonated WaterFreeze WaterSolids:BrickGooIceWoodPlantBreakable MetalWaxGlassNitrogen IceCoalSpongeVineFilterShieldPipeInvisibleQuartzIronDiamondDry IceFuseTitaniumLife:Game of LifeHigh LifeAssimilation2x2Day and NightAmoebaMovePseudoDiamoeba34Long LifeStainsSeedsMazeCoagulationsWalled CitiesGnarlReplicatorMysteryStar WarsLiving on the EdgeBrian 6FrogsLike Frogs RulePowders:DustStoneSnowConcreteSaltBroken MetalSandBroken GlassYeastFuse PowderBroken CoalFreezeGravityAnti-Air ParticleBroken QuartzBroken ElectronicsClay DustEqual VelocityMortvertSpecial:CloneBreakable CloneStickman 1Stickman 2Air VentVacuumConverterInsulatorVoidPortal INPortal OUTTronBlack HoleWhite HoleFighterRadioactiveUraniumPlutoniumNeutronsPhotonsAntimatterDeuterium OxideWarpIsotope-ZSolid ISOZSingularityElectronsExplosivesThermiteFireworksDestructive BombFirst Fireworks MadeRubidiumLiquid RubidiumC4NitroglycerinGunpowderFireC5BombLightningSub-Zero FlameGravity BombTrinitrotolueneIgnition CordPowered:Liquid CrystalPowered CloneHeat SwitchPressure PumpGravity PumpDelayStorePowered VoidBreakable Powered CloneGases:OxygenCarbon DioxideSmokeNoble GasPlasmaSteamGasBoyleHydrogenCaustic GasForce Creating:AcceleratorDeceleratorForce Ray EmitterRepellerElectronics;MetalElectricityP-Type SiliconN-Type SiliconNegative Temperature Coefficient ThermistorPositive Temperature Coefficient ThermistorElectrodeSwitchInsulated WireLightningTesla CoilInstantly ConductsWi-FiA-Type Ray EmitterElectromagnetic PulseMercuryWire</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="34987">Universe Sandbox</game><game id="30475">Minecraft</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/13/135732/2021348-the_powder_toy_1.jpg</image></root>