<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3689</id><name>Whacked!</name><description>Overview Whacked! is an action game based around a fictional game show and featuring a cast of abnormal cartoon characters. Gameplay involves moving your character around an arena and picking up weapons with which you can attack the other characters in the arena. Characters also have the ability to                    strafe and                   ground pound, and when characters take a sufficient amount of damage they are considered “whacked” and are temporarily removed from the game until they                  respawn. The game also contains                 power-ups via collectable question marks and big red buttons which will bestow effects such as                temporary invincibility or giving all players               homing missiles.   The game has six different gametypes; Combat in which players have to collect the required number of stars while whacking other characters to steal their stars, Dodgeball in which all characters can only attack with              dodgeballs and have a limited number of             lives, Grab ‘n’ Run in which players must pick up a trophy and attempt to hold it for as long as possible, Fragfest which is a            deathmatch mode,           King of the Hill in which players must stay in a specified area for a specified time and Chicken, a one-player mode in which players must run around the arena killing          chickens and collecting the stars they drop.  The eight playable characters in the game are Eugene, Charity, Lucky,         Lucy, Toof, Van, Otto and Lance with Lucy arguably being the title character. In terms of gameplay the characters are all identical apart from the fact that they will each perform a different      special attack for a limited time after an exclamation mark power-up is picked up. In addition to local and       online multiplayer there is also a five stage single-player mode. In the single-player mode the player chooses a specific character and runs through the game show (which is hosted by Van) in an effort to win their character the secret grand prize. In between each stage a short        cutscene or fake advertisement will be played. The cutscenes are different for each character but all characters follow a similar storyline which starts with them being interviewed by Van and ends with the show being cancelled, them being betrayed by Van who turns out to be an evil imp and them being dragged down into     hell. If players can beat Van in hell they win the grand prize which is exactly what the winning character desires.  Along with    Moto GP, Whacked! was the one of the two games that beta testers received a demo of in the beta test of   Xbox LIVE. Demos of Whacked! and Moto GP also came free with the Xbox LIVE starter kit for a year. Despite the games notable Xbox LIVE support it did not support online  voice chat.    Attacks and StagesWeaponsBee-Hive  Cactus  Cannon  Cleaver  Cluster Duck (a rubber duck grenade)  Dodgeball  Freeze Gun  Goodbye Doggie (a deployable attack dog)  Mallet  Missile  Pitchfork  Plunger Missile  Shish-Ka-Bob  Stapler  Star Mine  Stick of Reason (a baseball bat)  Sticky Bomb  The Shocker (a taser)  Yolk-O-Matic (a contraption which launches eggs)  Urp! (an ordinarily useless can of soda)   Exclamation Point AttacksCharity- Special stars appear which act as stars for Charity but star mines for everyone else.  Eugene- Whirls around attacking opponents with his spinning hat.  Lance- All opponents are given purple hats and now drop many stars when hit.  Lucky- Turns into a tornado.  Lucy- Can give opponents a kiss of death to send them flying.  Otto- Zs begin flying out of his body when he is near opponents. If they hit the opponents the opponents drop many stars.  Toof- Puts on a chef’s hat and all opponents become hamburgers.  Van- Two of his minions begin fighting alongside him.    StagesArctic Pipeline  Can Can  Car Crash  Christmas Tree  Club Bano  Death Wall  Hell  High Rise  Jeffrey’s Kitchen  Joyride  No Trespassing  Pirate Ship  Spacewalk </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20520">Hail to the Chimp</game><game id="19116">Cel Damage</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2276112-box_whacked.png</image></root>