<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37026</id><name>Tony Hawk's Pro Skater HD</name><description>OverviewThe Mall, one of the seven levels featured in THPS HDTony Hawk's Pro Skater HD is a downloadable skateboarding game for Xbox Live Arcade, PlayStation Network, and PC. It is a HD collection developed by Robomodo that features levels from Tony Hawk's Pro Skater and Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 2. Instead of porting the original games with HD graphics, Robomodo created a new engine within Unreal meant to emulate the physics of the original games. Gameplay features stop at Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 2, meaning only manuals and the Sloppy/Perfect judgement system made it into the game. Each level featured was re-created with new textures, and returning characters are modernized for their current real-world appearance.The game was announced at the Spike Video Game Awards 2011 and was released on the Xbox Live Marketplace on July 18th, 2012 for 1200 Microsoft Points. The PlayStation Network version was released the following month on August 28th, 2012. A PC version is also planned. It released to mixed reviews, some praising its well-executed throwback to classic Tony Hawk games with others criticizing its lack of content.GameplayDespite being built anew, the game is meant to emulate the physics and play style of Tony Hawk's Pro Skater and Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 2. Additions of the series such as reverts, spine transfers, walking, or skitching have not made it into the game, though the Revert will be added exclusively for future Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3 levels. The manual and landing judgement systems from THPS 2 are present, however, meaning combos can be continued on land and the game will reward/penalize your score for the quality of your landing. The landing judgement is seen in-game as "Perfect" or "Sloppy" next to the trick list. Also featured are nollies and stance switching, as they were present in the original THPS.The game features a variety of different modes for both single player and multiplayer, as follows:Single Player ModesCareerThe classic Tony Hawk experience. Players get two minutes to complete a run in which they attempt to knock out a list of predetermined objectives, ranging from high scores to collecting objects, or performing certain tricks over certain gaps. Runs can be repeated multiple times and an objective will clear from the level when completed. Cash icons are also scattered throughout the level as collectibles and they can be collected to both 100% a level and spend on stats, boards, or tricks in the Skate Shop. Beating a predetermined number of goals in one level will unlock the next one in the list.Career Mode is also where players can unlock cheats and secret characters. Completing the "100% Goals and Cash" goal in each level will unlock a new cheat for the player, for example.Single SessionLike career mode without the goals or unlocks. Players get two minutes to complete a run whilst attempting to reach as high a score as possible.Free SkateNo time limits or goals. This mode is intended for players to practice combo lines, relax, and discover secret areas.Big Head SurvivalA new mode to the series, Big Head Survival is a mode where the player's head is constantly increasing in size and must complete tricks and combos to make it shrink down. A percentage meter will display how close the player's head is to exploding with the difficulty increasing as time progresses. The player's head explodes into confetti when the meter reaches 100%.HawkmanReturning from Proving Ground, Hawkman is a mode where players need to collect colored tokens scattered across the level. Each color is associated to a type of trick, and the tokens are laid out across the level to purposely teach the player some of the highest-scoring lines in the level. Green Tokens are for Manuals, Yellow for Grinds, Red for Air, and Blue for Wallrides. There is a High, Pro, and Sick Score associated to how fast the player can collect all tokens.ProjectivesProjectives is a similar mode to Career, although the objectives are noticeably more difficult. This is the last mode unlocked and is a made-up word for "Professional Objectives". Tony Hawk seemed rather pleased with the name when talking about it in a post-release trailer.Multiplayer ModesTime AttackEssentially a multiplayer Single Session. Players have two minutes to put in the highest score possible. Combos can be continued past the timer expiration, though landing after the timer will immediately halt the player. The highest scoring player wins.GraffitiA classic mode from the original Tony Hawk games, Graffiti gets players to paint obstacles in the level to their assigned color by scoring on them within a two minute timer. Opposing players can then attempt to steal the obstacle from them by scoring a higher number of points on that obstacle, with any player being able to paint multiple obstacles at once by chaining them together with a combo. The total score of the player's combo is the score assigned to each individual object painted in their combo. When the timer runs out, the player with the highest number of obstacles their color wins.Big Head EliminationSimilar to the single player Survival variant, Big Head Elimination makes all players' heads increase at the same time. They must land tricks and combos to prevent their head from increasing too much and exploding. When their heads explode, they are eliminated from the match. The last surviving player wins.Free SkateNo objectives or time limits. This mode lets players explore levels, practice with each other, and mess about at their leisure.SkatersEric Koston at School 2Much like the classic THPS games, the HD version features a roster of professional skaters as well as a few secret ones.ProsAndrew ReynoldsChris ColeEric KostonLyn-Z Adams Hawkins-PastranaNyjah HustonRiley HawkRodney MullenTony HawkGeoff Rowley (DLC)Steve Caballero (DLC)SpecialsOfficer DickRobertaOllie The Magic BumTony Hawk (Low-Res 1999 version)LevelsTHPSMallDownhill JamWarehouseTHPS2HangarMarseillesSchool 2Venice BeachDownloadable ContentA $5 (400 MS Points) DLC pack containing select content from Tony Hawk Pro Skater 3, including the Airport, Los Angeles, and Canada levels, was released on December 4, 2012. The revert ability that made Tony Hawk 3 what it was came free for everyone and is currently usable on any level in the game, not just the THPS3 levels. It also includes new skaters, including Steve Caballero, Geoff Rowley, Chad Muska and Metallica band members James Hetfield and Robert Trujillo. The revert pack also added a song from Metallica's album Death Magnetic, "All Nightmare Long."SoundtrackThe game features a licensed soundtrack with half of the songs being from THPS1/THPS2 and the other half being new songs that have never been used in a Tony Hawk game before. It should be noted that of the returning songs only one is from the first THPS with the remainder being from THPS2.Returning Songs“Bring the Noise” - Anthrax featuring Chuck D“Superman” - Goldfinger“When Worlds Collide” - Powerman 5000“Heavy Metal Winner” - Consumed“May 16” - Lagwagon“No Cigar” - Millencolin“You” - Bad ReligionNew Songs“The Bomb” - Pigeon John“We the People” - Lateef the Truthspeaker“Marathon Mansion!” - Pegasuses-XL“Teenage Blood” - Apex Manor“Please Ask for Help” - Telekinesis“Flyentology (Cassettes Won’t Listen Remix)” - El-P featuring Trent Reznor“USA” - Middle Class RutIncluded with the Revert Pack"All Nightmare Long" - MetallicaSystem RequirementsMinimum (or Recommended)OS: Microsoft Windows(R) XP, Windows Vista(R) or Windows(R) 7Processor: Intel(R) Core(TM)2 CPU 6600 @ 2.40GHz (2 CPUs) -or- AMD(R) Athlon(TM) II X2 250Memory: 2 GB (Vista/Win 7)Hard Disk Space: 1.8 GB of free hard drive spaceVideo Card: 256 MB NVIDIA(R) GeForce(TM) 8600 GTS -or- 256 MB ATI(R) Radeon(TM) HD 3650 -or- equivalent graphic cardDirectX®: DirectX(R) version: 9.0c (included)Sound: DirectX 9.0c-compliant true 16-bit sound card</description><genres><genre id="23">Skateboarding</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5228">skate.</game><game id="30195">Shaun White Skateboarding</game><game id="18624">Thrasher Presents: Skate and Destroy</game><game id="5464">Grind Session</game><game id="2341">Mat Hoffman's Pro BMX</game><game id="7099">Mat Hoffman's Pro BMX 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2269421-box_thpshd.png</image></root>