<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37027</id><name>Command &amp; Conquer</name><description>OverviewCommand  Conquer, originally known as Command  Conquer: Generals 2, is a free-to-play sequel to Command  Conquer: Generals and the latest entry in the long-running Command  Conquer franchise.Development was handled by Victory Games (briefly known as BioWare Victory) using the Frostbite 2 engine. The game was officially unveiled via a trailer at the 2011 Spike TV Video Game Awards and was helmed by Jon Van Caneghem, who was billed as the Executive Producer.Command  Conquer was feature three factions and supports both cooperative and competitive online multiplayer.On October 29th, 2013, EA decided to terminate further development of the game while also stating they will refund all in-app purchases made up to that point. At the time the game was cancelled, it was officially considered in "closed alpha" testing. The final posting from EA states that they are looking into ways to "get the game back on track," but no further details have been given. It was subsequently confirmed that Victory Studios would close down with the game's cancellation.FactionsAt launch, Command  Conquer will feature three factions: the European Union, the Global Liberation Army and the Asia Pacific Alliance.European UnionThe European Union is designed to be accessible, with a range of units and abilities that should feel familiar to franchise veterans while maintaining flexibility for advanced players.Asia Pacific AllianceThe Asia Pacific Alliance are less technology advanced than the E.U., but make for it with the ability to quickly field large quantities of low-level units.Global Liberation ArmyThe Global Liberation Army is a terrorist organization who employ improvise warfare through black markets and makeshift weaponry, including suicide bombers and dirty bombs.</description><genres><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/26/2080019-ccgenerals2_screen2.jpg</image></root>