<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37124</id><name>Sonic the Hedgehog 4: Episode II</name><description>Episode MetalSonic The Hedgehog 4: Episode II returns to plot threads from Sonic CD, which, fiittingly, was released digitally in the time between Episode I and Episode II's release. Metal Sonic returns to the franchise, and is even playable in Episode Metal. Mimicking the Lock-On Technology created for Sonic  Knuckles, owners of both episodes on a single platform (whether it be PS3, Xbox 360, etc) can unlock Episode Metal, in which the players play as Metal Sonic and go through the four zones from Sonic 4 Episode I in reverse order.New Graphic and Gameplay EnginesFollowing criticism from the first title, Episode II features a new graphic engine and gameplay engine. However, despite this, Episode II has been criticized for still being too similar to Sonic The Hedgehog 4: Episode I, and not accurately enough recreating the physics of the classic Sonic titles. One of the criticism is that rolling down a downhill slope causes Sonic to come to a stop, rather than increasing momentum.MultiplayerWith the return of Tails to the title, the game now has co-operative play for 2 players. This is similar to how 2 players can play cooperatively in the classic Sonic titles Sonic The Hedgehog 2, Sonic The Hedgehog 3, Knuckles Chaotix, and even Sonic  Knuckles if connected to Sonic The Hedgehog 3.In addition to being able to play alone or with another player on the same screen, Sonic The Hedgehog 4: Episode II even can be played cooperatively online, a series first.Xbox Live Avatar ItemsFor Xbox 360 players, multiple avatar items were released for purchase on the Xbox Live Marketplace. All attire is available for both genders.The Tails Hoodie for WomenTails CostumeHalf-Pipe Special StageDrawstring Tails PlushieT-ShirtMetal Sonic ToyTails HoodieSonic HoodieGame CartridgeMetal Sonic HelmetCapsule ToyBadnik DuoPC System RequirementsMinimum System Requirements:OS: Windows® XP/ Vista SP2/ 7Processor: Pentium®4 3.2 GHz or Athlon™64 3000+RAM: 1GB for XP and 2 GB for Vista/7Graphics: 256 MB, GeForce® 7600 orATi Radeon™ X1300DirectX®: 9.0cSound: DirectX® compatibleHard Disk free space: 2 GBRecommended System Requirements:Processor: Intel® Core™2 DUO @ 2.4 GHz or Athlon™64 X2 4200RAM: 2 GBGraphics: 512 MB, NVIDIAv GeForce® 8800 or ATI Radeon™ HD 3800Sound: DirectX® compatibleHard Disk free space: 2 GB</description><genres><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="31721">Rayman Origins</game><game id="28906">Rocket Knight</game><game id="33330">Ms. Splosion Man</game><game id="31732">Donkey Kong Country Returns</game><game id="20975">Mega Man 9</game><game id="29413">Mega Man 10</game><game id="30945">Bionic Commando Rearmed 2</game><game id="20963">Wario Land: Shake It!</game><game id="836">Sonic Rivals</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2206928-sonic4.jpg</image></root>