<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37164</id><name>Disney Epic Mickey 2: The Power of Two</name><description>Overview Disney Epic Mickey 2 is a  third-person  adventure game published by  Disney Interactive. The game was made with the efforts of two developers;  Blitz Games Studios on the  Mac,  PC,  Playstation 3 and  Xbox 360, while  Avalanche Software developed the  Wii and  Wii U ports of the game. The lead designer was  Warren Spector, with  James Dooley composing the majority of the game's music. The game was released on November 18, 2012.PlotThe sequel picks up where its predecessor,  Epic Mickey, left off. The Disney characters are working hard at rebuilding the Disney Wasteland when  The Mad Doctor shows up, convincing  Oswald the Lucky Rabbit to join him to fight off any potential threats to their respective universe. Skeptical of the Doctor's intentions, Ortensia and Gus recruit  Mickey Mouse to return to the Wasteland in order to help Oswald and return the Wasteland to it's original state.Gameplay Epic Mickey 2 features similar gameplay to the original Epic Mickey, with improvements mostly being made to the technical aspects rather than mechanical. The camera is stated not to be bugged as was a common complaint in the original Epic Mickey. Changes made to the environment during gameplay are now permanent, meaning returning to a location later will have it just as the player left it before.The game features drop in-and-out  Co-Op with the second player getting a totally different set of abilities playing as Oswald the Lucky Rabbit. Oswald carries a remote control, using it in the same manner Mickey uses his paintbrush. The two characters can work together in Co-Op, achieving tasks only available when two players are playing.The game supports motion controls using  Move on the Playstation 3, and supports touchscreen capabilities on the Wii U.Wii U Version The Wii U announcement of the game promised the inclusion of  Two-Screen Multiplayer as well as  Off-TV Play and support for  Wii Remote  Nunchuck controls. A month later, the game was shown off to press and it was revealed that due to time constraints these features could not be implemented in time after all. Ultimately, the Wii U version will feature regular split-screen co-op on the TV as found in the other versions. This allows only the second player to control Oswald with a Wii Remote. In singleplayer, only the Wii U GamePad is supported.The frame rate during gameplay has been reported as a technical issue in the Wii U version of Epic Mickey 2. Specifically, when Mickey is using his brush to paint objects in the world the frame rate on the game drops substantially. This has not been reported as an issue on any other release of the game. PlayStation Vita VersionThe PlayStation Vita port announced by Disney's Twitter feed for UK announces no firm date, though the port is due "later this year," Disney says. This is the first handheld version of Epic Mickey 2; the game launched in November alongside a separate 3DS game, Disney Epic Mickey: Power of Illusion. A PlayStation Blog post confirms the port, at least for the UK. The Vita version will include touchscreen painting, tilt controls for racing, and online co-op.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2368426-box_em2.png</image></root>