<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37181</id><name>Test Drive: Ferrari Racing Legends</name><description>CampaignThe single-player campaign for Test Drive: Ferrari Racing Legends features 36 missions split between three Eras in Ferrari's history: The Golden Era (1947-1973), the Silver Era (1974-1990), and the Modern Era (1990-2011).  Each mission is comprised of a number of events that use a specific car from Ferrari's history and must be completed in order to progress to the next one.  Event objectives include winning races, completing time trials, and finishing laps in specific positions; higher difficulties require tougher objectives to be met, and each event also has a bonus objective (such as "do not damage the car").CircuitsThe range of circuits featured in the game include real and fantasy tracks across different eras. While some of the racetracks are taken from previous games made by developer Slightly Mad Studios, Ferrari Legends features several new additions, most notably several Italian circuits to go along with the Ferrari license. The announced list is as follows:Circuit de Catalunya – Spain GPCircuit de Catalunya – Spain NationalCircuit de Spa Francorchamps GP (1980) – BelgiumCircuit de Spa Francorchamps GP (2004) – BelgiumCasino Riviera-Cote d’Azur – FranceCote d’Azur Monte Grande – FranceCote d’Azur Monument Loop – FranceCote d’Azur Port Boucle – FranceDonington Park GP (2009) – United KingdomDonington Park National (2009) – United KingdomEnna Pergusa – ItalyFiorano – ItalyFiorano Alternate – ItalyHockenheimring – Germany GPHockenheimring GP (1982) – GermanyHockenheimring National – GermanyHockenheimring Short – GermanyImola (1981) – ItalyImola (2005) – ItalyMisty Loch – Scotland (fictitious)Monza GP (1958) – ItalyMonza GP – ItalyMonza Junior – ItalyMotorsport Arena Oschersleben – ItalyMotorsport Arena Oschersleben B – Course-ItalyMugello GP – ItalyMugello Short – ItalyNordschleife – GermanyNordschleife Aremberg – GermanyNordschleife, Karussell – GermanyNordschleife Nurburg – GermanyRoad America Circuit  – United StatesRouen (1956) – FranceRouen Short (1952) – FranceSilverstone GP (1959) – United KingdomSilverstone GP (1975) – United KingdomSilverstone GP (2009) – United KingdomSilverstone International (2009) – United KingdomSilverstone National (2009) – United KingdomSystem RequirementsMinimum:OS:Windows® XP (SP3), Windows® Vista (Service Pack 1) or Windows® 7 Operating SystemProcessor:Intel Core 2 Duo 1.6 GHzMemory:1 GB RAMGraphics:256 MB Graphics MemoryDirectX®:9.0cHard Drive:6 GB HD spaceSound:DirectX 9 Compatible Sound CardOther Requirements:Broadband Internet connectionAdditional:*Supported chipsets: ATI HD3 Series or greater; NVIDIA GeForce 8 Series or higher or greater Laptop versions of these chipsets may work but are not supported. Updates to your video and sound card drivers may be required.Recommended:OS:Windows® XP (SP3), Windows® Vista (Service Pack 2) or Windows® 7 Operating SystemProcessor:Intel Core 2 Duo 2.0 GHz / AMD X2 64 2.4GHzMemory:2 GB RAMGraphics:DirectX 9.0c Compatible 3D-accelerated 512 MB video card with Shader Model 3.0 or higherDirectX®:9.0cHard Drive:7 GB HD spaceSound:DirectX 9 Compatible Sound CardOther Requirements:Broadband Internet connectionAdditional:*Supported chipsets: ATI HD3 Series or greater; NVIDIA GeForce 8 Series or higher or greater Laptop versions of these chipsets may work but are not supported. Updates to your video and sound card drivers may be required.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="36993">Project CARS</game><game id="285">F355 Challenge: Passione Rossa</game><game id="32232">Ferrari: The Race Experience</game><game id="20936">Ferrari Challenge Trofeo Pirelli</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2160633-box_tdfrl.png</image></root>