<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37223</id><name>Resonance</name><description>OverviewAfter the death of a famous physicist, the race for his hidden legacy begins. In Resonance, the player takes control of four characters (swapping between them).GameplayResonance features a unique inventory system. Apart from the standard inventory slots any other adventure game might have, there are two additional ones representing short-term and long-term memory. The long-term memory events happen intermittently throughout the game and can be stored and played back at will in order to review past events or gain new clues to a puzzle. These memories can also be used in conversations with other characters in the game, as well as to interact with objects in the environment.Short term memories can be collected from environmental hotspots and stored for later use. An example of this mechanic is presented when a janitor stubbornly insists he had left a wrench the player needs to proceed in a cupboard where you can clearly see is not there. Upon further questioning, he recalls a time when he had to escape a dangerous situation by smashing through some glass with his wrench. The player can then collect this memory and use it on the janitor in order to have him remember that the wrench was in his pocket the whole time.LinksOfficial WebsitePC System RequirementsOS: Windows ME, 2000, XP or VistaProcessor: Pentium or higherMemory: 64 Mb RAMHard Disk Space: 1G Free SpaceVideo Card: Supports all DirectX-compatible video cardsDirectX®: DirectX 5 or aboveSound: Supports all DirectX-compatible sound cards</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2800">The Shivah</game><game id="33797">Gemini Rue</game><game id="32489">Puzzle Bots</game><game id="36748">Blackwell Deception</game><game id="24816">Emerald City Confidential</game><game id="4372">Maniac Mansion: Day of the Tentacle</game><game id="41722">Blackwell Epiphany</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/97089/2240228-resonanceposter.png</image></root>