<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37264</id><name>Dai-2-Ji Super Robot Taisen Z Saisei-hen</name><description>OverviewSuper Robot Wars Z2: Saisei-hen, yet another game in Namco Bandai's Super Robot Wars series, is the immediate sequel to Super Robot Wars Z2: Hakai-hen.Despite its billing as a two-part game, Saisei-hen is entirely independent of Hakai-hen. Players will receive a starting bonus in Saisei-hen based on how many times they have completed Hakai-hen, along with an extra bonus for playing all of Hakai-hen's scenarios, but unlocked machines and pilots will not transfer.Every series from Hakai-hen returns, with their sequels/second seasons debuting if applicable. Macross 7 makes its Z-series debut, with Dynamite 7 appearing for the first time in any SRW. The only completely new series, Tetsujin 28, is the 1980s incarnation of a robot series that predates even Mazinger. StoryThe game picks up where Hakai-hen left off with three prologue stages, concluding the initial Gundam 00, Code Geass, and Shin Getter Robo: Armageddon storylines. The first stage features the suppression of the Black Rebellion, the second stage features the Federation assault on Celestial Being and the Colony Gundams, and the final stage chronicles the Getter Team's and Team Dai-Gurren's encounter with Dr. Saotome and the Invaders.The game then skips forward one year, shifting focus to new pilot Esther Elhas. With her Brasta Es, she joins a new war against the A-Laws, Britannia, Vajra, and other malicious factions. Featured SeriesThe following anime series are featured in the game. Series that make their first Super Robot Wars appearance in this game are bolded. Mobile Suit Zeta GundamMobile Suit Gundam: Char's CounterattackNew Mobile Report Gundam WingAfter War Gundam XTurn A GundamMobile Suit Gundam SEED DestinyMobile Suit Gundam 00 (Season 2)Shin Mazinger Impact! Z ChapterGetter Robo ArmageddonInvincible Super Man Zambot 3Invincible Steel Man Daitarn 3Invincible Robo Trider G7Space Emperor God SigmaSpace Warrior BaldiosMessenger of the Sun Tetsujin 28 Six God Combination GodmarsCombat Mecha XabungleArmored Trooper VotomsArmored Trooper Votoms: The Last Red ShoulderArmored Trooper Votoms: Red Shoulder Document: The Roots of AmbitionArmored Trooper Votoms: Pailsen FilesSuper Dimensional Century OrgussSuper Beast Machine God DancougarDancougar NovaMacross 7Macross Dynamite 7Macross FrontierMacross Frontier The Movie: The Wings of Goodbye Dai-GuardThe Big OOverman King GainerSuper Heavy God GravionSuper Heavy God Gravion ZweiGenesis of AquarionCode Geass: Lelouch of the RebellionCode Geass: Lelouch of the Rebellion R2 Tengen Toppa Gurren LagannGurren Lagann The Movie: Childhood's EndGurren Lagann The Movie: The Lights in the Sky are StarsPsalm of Planets Eureka Seven: Good Night, Sleep Tight, Young LoversGameplay NotesSaisei-hen's gameplay mechanics are identical to that of its immediate predecessor.With Macross 7's introduction, the Song System from Super Robot Wars D and Alpha 3 makes a return. In this game, songs can target player units, the Vajra from Macross Frontier, and the game-original DAMON enemies. Player units receive a buff depending on the song used. For the Vajra, songs "attack" their Will; when reduced below 120, the Vajra will retreat. DAMON take direct damage from songs.Not all playable pilots from Hakai-hen return. For example, Athena Henderson is reduced to a cameo in one of Orguss's attacks.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="33701">Dai-2-Ji Super Robot Taisen Z Hakai-hen</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/16207/2235855-saiseihen.jpg</image></root>