<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37291</id><name>Hero Academy</name><description>OverviewHero Academy is a two player asynchronous tile based strategy game made by Robot Entertainment for iOS and PC via Steam. The game is set in a light-hearted fantasy world where humans, dark elves, dwarves and orcs meet up to fight on the academy playfields.GameplayEach game takes place on a nine by five square board where the teams start on opposite sides. Each turn consists of five action points players can spend on placing and moving characters, buffing them up and attacking. Each character can take and dish out varying amounts of damage, and each have their strengths and weaknesses.The goal of the game is to either kill all your opponents characters or break their Crystals. There are either one or two crystals per team depending on which board you´re randomly assigned, and the crystals take a considerable amount of damage.The bar at the bottom of the screen fills up with new characters and items between turns until the players “academy” is empty, represented by the number over the door in the bottom left corner. The board contains special tiles that grant either extra damage or defense to characters standing on them. One special tile also doubles damage to crystals whenever your team is occupying it.In App PurchasesThe game is free to download ($5 on Steam) and The Council is included, while Dark Elves, Dwarves and The Tribe can be bought for $2 each on iOS and $5 each on Steam which includes custom avatars for the team. The Team Fortress 2 team is unlocked when game is purchased for Steam, and accounts can be synced between platforms to make the TF2 team playable on iOS as well. Custom team colors and avatar pictures are also available for purchase in the iOS version, but these are purely cosmetic and do not affect gameplay. The teams are also balanced in a way that does not favor the paid teams over the free one.TeamsThe CouncilCharacter ArtNameClassDescriptionKnightFighterThe knight is a great fighter whose attacks knock enemies one space back.ArcherShooterThe Archer does great damage at range but does weak melee attacks.WizardCasterHe is a powerful spell caster that can damage multiple enemies in one attack.ClericSupportA character who revives and heals the team and can attack at range.NinjaSuper UnitHe has strong melee attacks and can teleport to allies.The Dark ElvesCharacter ArtNameClassDescriptionVoid MonkFighterHe does strong magical attacks that do splash damage.ImpalerShooterHas harpoon that can pull enemies closer.NecromancerCasterCan create phantoms from fallen unitsPhantomSummonedThe phantom the Necromancer createsPriestessSupport UnitShe can heal allies and weaken the other teams attacks.WraithSuper UnitHe can get more health by draining the K.O.'d units.The DwarvesCharacter ArtNameClassDescriptionPaladinFighterCan heal and revive allies while healing herself.GunnerShooterCan do high damage to nearby enemies and can do AOE damage at range.GrenadierCasterThrows molotovs to do AOE damage but has weak melee attacks.EngineerSupportCan shield an ally or the crystal.AnnihilatorSuper UnitDoes heavy damage with AOE knock back. His direct hit weaken physical defenses.The TribeCharacter ArtNameClassDescriptionWarriorFighterCan instantly K.O. any wounded (at or below 50% health) enemy unit. (25% for crystals)Axe ThrowerShooterDeals 100 extra damage to enemies above 50% health. (25% for crystals)WitchCasterExplodes fallen heroes at range to damage nearby enemies.ShamanSupportHealer whose healing spells chain through multiple allies, even heroes already at full health.ChieftainSuper UnitAOE fighter who can pull surrounding enemies close, or charge out to attack distant enemies.PC System RequirementsOS: Windows XP, Windows Vista, Windows 7Processor: 2GHz Dual CoreMemory: 2GB RAMHard Disk Space: 300MBVideo Card: Graphics: DX11  DX10 video cards, minimum resolution 1280 x 800DirectX®: 10</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20077">Battle Chess</game><game id="22718">Dofus</game><game id="19864">Final Fantasy Tactics</game><game id="23303">Wakfu</game><game id="8721">Final Fantasy Tactics Advance</game><game id="31582">Skulls of the Shogun</game><game id="37476">Triple Town</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/32858/2110266-003.png</image></root>