<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37304</id><name>Artemis: Spaceship Bridge Simulator</name><description>OverviewArtemis Spaceship Bridge Simulator is a Windows PC simulation game created and developed by Thomas Robertson. Its aim is to better simulate a Star Trek type bridge environment by allowing up to six players to network six separate computers together, although the game does support an online network.Version 1.0 was available for download October 17, 2010 for $40 along with a free demo version. Purchase of the full version allows for multiple installations for the computers in your bridge.GameplayOne of the simulation screensThe game supports 3-6 players, the first being the captain. The captain solely orders the crew of the bridge which are the other five players. His computer runs the simulation and is the "main screen," thus it may be important for the other players to see it.The other 2 required players are the Helm and Weapons. Helm steers and controls the ship, including warping, while Weapons loads and fires different torpedo and missile types.Finally, the remaining 3 players, while not required, do help aid the experience and make the social aspect of the bridge more interesting. Engineer controls energy allocation (like shields) and damage control (DamCom), Science uses the ship's scanners to determine friend or foe and hold the most overall information, and Communications (Comms) can talk to Starbase or other friendly ships, and can request foe surrender.PC System RequirementsIntel CPU - Pentium 4 2.4GHzAMD CPU - Athlon XP 2200+Nvidia GFX Card - GeForce 6600ATI GFX Card - Radeon HD 3400 SeriesRAM (Memory) - 256 MBHard Disk Space - 500 MBDirect X - 9</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16235">Star Trek: Bridge Commander</game><game id="19745">Star Trek: Starfleet Academy - Starship Bridge Simulator</game><game id="40751">Spaceteam</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/89459/2302142-artemis_logo.png</image></root>