<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37308</id><name>Rhythm Party</name><description>OverviewRhythm Party (Boom Boom Dance in Japan) is a rhythm game published by Konami and developed by the DanceMasters (Dance Evolution in Japan and Europe) team that allows players to have more freedom in their routines. A combo system, as well as implementing a simpler system for point scoring i.e. timed circles to place body parts enables the player to create their own dance for each song.GameplayCircles appear in the vicinity of the dance area, and players must put a body part inside the circle in time with the music. Players gain bonuses if they do various tricks such as: kicks, jumps, and spins. For each song the player also gets to choose one of five different filters which will give the players visual representation a distinct look. At the end of each song the player is graded on their performance with score raging from C to AAA. There are 4 different difficulties: Light, Standard, Extreme and Master with the last one being a free DLC.List of Songs (Title - Artist)Ten songs where included with the game from the get go. They included both licensed music from well known artists such as Lady Gaga and Bobby Brown as well as music composed internally by Konamis sound team.SongArtistBorn This WayLady GagaEvery Little StepBobby BrownY.M.C.A.The Village PeopleA Midnight RendezvousShaniceStill UnbreakableDes-ROW (feat. Vanilla Ice)Say A PrayerDes-ROW (feat. Maxi Priest)BefreeDes-ROW (feat. Vanilla Ice)Summer FairytaleDesign-MAD CrewHeartbreak (Sound Selektaz Remix)NAOKI (feat. Becca Hossany)All Thru the NightJun (feat. Lisa Lisa)Downloadable Song PacksFive song packs have since the release been made available as DLC. These packs cost 240 msp each and contains 3 songs.Song Pack no.1 (released February 15 2012):SongArtistKEEP IT REALNAOKI feat. TiffanyDM STARNAOKIUNBELIEVABLE (Sparky remix)Jun feat. Sarah-JaneSong Pack no.2 (released February 15 2012):SongArtistACTIVATIONJun feat. Kathy SledgePharaoh ★ LoveDes-ROWDiamond NightTOMOSUKE feat. Alexa SlaymakerSong Pack no.3 (released February 29 2012):SongArtistAll Around The WorldStacey QЁVOLUTIФNTЁЯRAEl ritmo te controlaJeanette HerraSong Pack no.4 (released March 14 2012):SongArtistINSIDE YOUR MINDLimahlThe SunbeamDes-ROW + XXbagRevenGSong Pack no.5 (released March 28 2012):SongArtistLame by MondayDes-ROW華爛漫 -Flowers- (2nd EDITION)TЁЯRALOVE IS THE POWER -Re:born-NMReceptionRhythm Party was largely overlooked at it's initial release and gamerankings.com only track 3 reviews of the game all of which gave the game a middling score of 65%. As of May 12 2012 it was the fourteenth least played XBLA game among the users on Giant Bomb.</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16519">Samba De Amigo</game><game id="31801">DanceMasters</game><game id="16620">EyeToy: Groove</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2121656-box_rparty.png</image></root>