<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37341</id><name>Spirit Camera: The Cursed Memoir</name><description>OverviewSpirit Camera: The Cursed Memoir is a game for the Nintendo 3DS from Nintendo and Tecmo Koei. A spin-off of the Fatal Frame series, Spirit Camera's gameplay makes heavy use of the handheld's AR camera functionality, as the player uses the 3DS itself as the Camera Obscura. The player uses the 3DS camera to interact with the "Diary of Faces"; a physical notebook that comes packaged with the game.Spirit Camera: The Cursed Memoir features a special connection to the Wii game Project Zero 2: Wii Edition. Players can unlock special content in Project Zero 2 by scanning the back of the instruction manual with the 3DS's AR Camera in Spirit Camera.PlotSpirit Camera's story sees the player come to the aid of Maya, a young woman that has been cursed by a mysterious woman in black and hides away in an old house.GameplaySpirit Camera uses the AR functionality, 3D cameras, and the gyro censors to create a "visceral" gaming experience. In the game's story and in most of the minigames, ghosts will appear in the player's environment, and try to attack them. The player must use the Camera Obscura to look around the environment and photograph them using the L and R buttons. The game utilizes the gyro censor to create and interactive experience while looking around the environment and fighting spirits. If the player looks up with the 3DS, the camera in the game will look up. The player must use the Camera Obscura to damage and defeat the evil spirits by photographing them. The player must use the gyro censors to look around the environment to find the spirits. Once the spirit is found, the player must focus the reticle of the camera on the spirit, the longer the spirit is in focus, the more damage the camera will cause. By keeping the spirit in front of the camera, players charge "Spirit Power". The default "Zero Lens" is the only lens that charges Spirit Power, but there are other lenses players can use throughout the game.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="34610">Face Raiders</game><game id="26599">Ghostwire</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2139807-box_sctcm.png</image></root>