<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3738</id><name>Boogie</name><description>OverviewBoogie is a karaoke and dance rhythm game published by Electronic Arts. The game was originally released for the Wii on August 7, 2007, with versions for the PS2 and DS released the following November. The WIi and PS2 versions were each released in a bundle that included a USB microphone accessory for the singing portions of the game. The game features thirty-nine songs on the soundtrack, all of which are covers. It features both competitive and co-op multiplayer local modes. Players also have the ability to create music videos.GameplayThe gameplay is similar to other games such as Singstar and Karaoke Revolution in the fact that it is karaoke based. In order to gain a score the player must sing in tune, and in time, with the lyrics presented.SingingIn Boogie's singing sections, the player must follow along with the lyrics and sing into the microphone and the game will gauge the player's pitch. The more in tune with the correct pitch level, the better the player's score.DancingThe Wii version of Boogie uses the motion controls of the Wii Remote. The Nunchuk can also be used, but isn't required. In the dancing portions of the game, the player must swing the Wii Remote up, down, left and right while staying in rhythm with the music. However repeated actions will reduce the player's score, so different movements and changes in dancing style will rack up a bigger score. When the player performs well, a gauge called the Boogie Meter fllls up, and when at maximum, the player can perform special dance moves by following on-screen prompts when a special move attempt is triggered. Failure to execute these prompts will cause the boogie meter to decrease, whereas successful execution will perform the special move.Extra components of gameplay that require the Nunchuk include the ability to control the player character's facial expressions in special solo sections as well as the ability to strike poses. Striking a pose mode requires tilting the Nunchuk to cause the on-screen character to point at sets of targets for extra points. The basic dancing controls from karaoke mode do not affect the score here.Story ModeThe story mode features five chapters, for each of the five characters. The player can only progress after obtaining the minimum score on the game. The player is rewarded tokens based on how well they perform, they can be used to unlock additional songs, stages and outfits in the in-game store.There are five characters which are:BubbaJetJuliusKatoLeaThe player can customise these characters in numerous ways such as clothing, hair, shoes, accessories and skin.SongsThe game features 39 songs, all are covers of the originals.ABC - The Jackson 5Baila Me - Gipsy KingsBoogie Oogie Oogie - A Taste of HoneyBrick House - The CommodoresCanned Heat - JamiroquaiCelebration - Kool  The GangDancing in the Street - Martha Reeves  The VandellasDancing Machine - The Jackson 5Don't Cha - Pussycat Dolls / Busta RhymesFergalicious - FergieGet Right - Jennifer LopezGet the Party Started - PinkGirls Just Want to Have Fun - Cyndi LauperGroove Is in the Heart - Deee-LiteI Want You Back - The Jackson 5I'm a Slave 4 U - Britney SpearsIt's Raining Men - The Weather GirlsKarma Chameleon - Culture ClubKung Fu Fighting - Carl DouglasLe Freak - ChicLet's Get It Started - The Black Eyed PeasLove Rollercoaster - Ohio PlayersLove Shack - The B-52'sMambo No. 5 (A Little Bit of...) - Lou BegaMilkshake - KelisOne More Time - Daft PunkOne Way or Another - BlondieOops!... I Did It Again - Britney SpearsPop Muzik - MSOS - RihannaStars - Simply RedThat's the Way (I Like It) - KC and the Sunshine BandTu y Yo - ThaliaU Can't Touch This - MC HammerVirtual Insanity - JamiroquaiWalking on Sunshine - Katrina and the WavesWe Are Family - Sister SledgeY.M.C.A. - The Village PeopleYou're The One That I Want - John Travolta  Olivia Newton-John</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5769">High School Musical: Sing It!</game><game id="20673">Guitar Hero World Tour</game><game id="20462">SingStar</game><game id="24294">Imagine Rock Star</game><game id="26806">Hannah Montana: Rock Out the Show</game><game id="29503">Dance Sensation!</game><game id="31218">Singstar: The Wiggles</game><game id="31787">SingStar Dance</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/10831/508452-938735_85830_front.jpg</image></root>