<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37476</id><name>Triple Town</name><description>OverviewTriple Town is a puzzle game in which the player must match objects to create the largest city. By matching objects, the player creates larger structures worth more points, which can then be matched into even larger structures as the game continues. The game ends when the player runs out of space to place objects. This is brought about faster by the bears, who amble around the maze until trapped, in which case they become a gravestone structure to be matched with other gravestones. A free-to-play version of the game exists on mobile devices and browsers, in which the player has a limited number of moves per day. Unlimited moves can be bought on mobile versions of the game for $3.99.The developer is working to add significant updates as time goes on. The Google+ version of the game is still labeled as being in "beta."Yeti Town LawsuitOn January 29, 2012, Triple Town developers Spry Fox sued the development team 6Waves LOLAPPS for a "blatant copy" of Triple Town in the form of 6Waves LOLAPPS' game Yeti Town. Beyond simple gameplay mechanics, Spry Fox claims that Yeti Town directly copies UI and language from the tutorial. Spry Fox developers David Edery and Daniel Cook also revealed that 6Waves LOLAPPS was originally slated to publish the mobile version of Triple Town:Second: what most people don't know is that 6waves was in confidential (under NDA) negotiations with us to publish Triple Town at the exact same time that they were actively copying Triple Town. We gave 6waves private access to Triple Town when it was still in closed beta, months before the public was exposed to the game. We believed those negotiations were ongoing, and we continued to give private information to 6waves, until 6waves' Executive Director of Business Development sent us a message via Facebook on the day Yeti Town was published in which he suddenly broke off negotiations and apologized for the nasty situation.6Waves LOLAPPS has since denied the allegations, but the lawsuit is still ongoing.System RequirementsPCMinimumOS:Windows XP or laterProcessor:2.33GHz or faster x86-compatibleMemory:1 GB RAMHard Drive:100 MB HD spaceAdditional:Requires mouse, trackpad or similar deviceRecommendedOS:Windows XP or laterProcessor:2.33GHz or faster x86-compatibleMemory:2 GB RAMGraphics:128MB of graphics memoryHard Drive:100 MB HD spaceAdditional:Requires mouse, trackpad or similar deviceMacMinimumOS:Mac OS X v10.6 or laterProcessor:Intel Core™ Duo 1.83GHz or fasterMemory:1 GB RAMHard Drive:100 MB HD spaceAdditional:Requires mouse, trackpad or similar deviceRecommendedOS:Mac OS X v10.6 or laterProcessor:Intel Core™ Duo 1.83GHz or fasterMemory:2 GB RAMGraphics:128MB of graphics memoryHard Drive:100 MB HD spaceAdditional:Requires mouse, trackpad or similar device</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="37291">Hero Academy</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/7/72296/2127509-triple_town_cover.jpg</image></root>