<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37547</id><name>WWE WrestleFest</name><description>OverviewWWE WrestleFest is a remake of the 1991 Technos Arcade game. Using a roster of current WWE Superstars and Legends, WWE WrestleFest is a faithful reproduction from its gameplay to its hokey presentation.Concurrent with the release of the game on iOS devices, WWE WrestleFest was announced to hit a variety of platforms by the end of 2012 including Xbox Live, PSN, Android and PC.GameplayWWE WrestleFest is true to its original arcade roots using only two attack buttons, an energy bar, and a simplistic grapple system.The two attack buttons are used to punch and kick. Wrestlers grapple automatically when they reach an appropriate range, while players mash on their buttons to "win" the grapple and perform moves. Signature moves are performed automatically when their opponent's energy bar has been depleted.The match is over when a submission is applied to deplete the opponent's remaining energy, or when a wrestler is pinned for a 3 count.FutureAfter numerous delays that eventually led to a release date in 2013, it was announced that THQ was going to file for bankruptcy. Once it was clear that THQ was not going to be able to save itself, there assets were sold off and eventually the WWE license went to Take Two. All mention of this game seams to have disappeared and the only one to see release, iOS, has been pulled from the App Store leaving it's future unclear.Game ModesExhibitionRoad To WrestlemaniaRoyal RumbleSaturday Night's Main Event TournamentTag TeamGauntlet MatchRosterJake "The Snake" RobertsJohn CenaRey MysterioThe RockRandy Orton"Macho Man" Randy SavageStone Cold Steve AustinUndertakerDLC*Alberto Del RioAnimalBatistaBig Boss ManBig ShowCody RhodesChristianCM PunkDaniel BryanDolph ZigglerDusty RhodesEdgeEddie GuerreroHawkKaneKevin NashKofi KingstonMark HenryThe MizMr. PerfectR-TruthRoddy PiperSgt. SlaughterShawn MichaelsSheamusSin CaraTed DiBiaseTriple HYokozunaZack RyderArenaSmackDownWrestlemaniaRawRoyal RumbleSaturday Night's Main EventDLC*Old Survivor SeriesWrestleMania 27WCW Nitro 1998Old Raw is WarOld SmackDown 1998Old SummerSlam 88*DLC packs cost $.99 and consist of 5 superstars and 1 arena each</description><genres><genre id="10">Wrestling</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22247">WWF Wrestlefest</game><game id="8027">WWF WrestleMania: The Arcade Game</game><game id="7485">WWF In Your House</game><game id="36608">Wrestling Manager</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2375835-orig_1345377636.jpg</image></root>