<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37565</id><name>Amnesia: A Machine for Pigs</name><description>OverviewA cart filled with pig carcases.Amnesia: A Machine for Pigs is a first-person survival-horror adventure game that was developed by thechineseroom and published by Frictional Games. It is the follow-up to the Amnesia: The Dark Descent. The game is set in the same universe as the first game, but follows a new protagonist, Oswald Mandus.The game was released for PC, Mac, and Linux on September 10, 2013.GameplayOswald illuminating an underground area with the lantern.A Machine for Pigs plays from the first-person perspective, focusing on exploration and occasional puzzle solving. The game also features enemy encounters; however, Oswald has no means of directly combating these adversaries and thus must attempt to evade or hide from them.Unlike the first game, A Machine for Pigs does not include any inventory or sanity meter. The game, however, does include collectible notes, audio logs, and personal notes from the protagonist. As well as this, players have access to a lantern that will be turned on as long as it is being held.StoryA Machine for Pigs will feature a new protagonist, Oswald Mandus; the game will be set on New Year's Eve 1899, roughly 60 years after the original game.System RequirementsPCMinimumOS: Windows VistaProcessor: 2.0 Ghz core i5 CPU or equivalent.Memory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: Mid-range NVIDIA GeForce 3x0 / ATI Radeon HD 5x00. Integrated Intel HD Graphics should work but is not supported; problems are generally solved with a driver update.Hard Drive: 5 GB available spaceRecommendedOS: Windows 7Processor: 2.0 Ghz core i7 CPU or equivalent.Memory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: High-range NVIDIA GeForce 5x0 / ATI Radeon HD 6x00. Integrated Intel HD Graphics should work but is not supported; problems are generally solved with a driver update.Hard Drive: 5 GB available spaceMacMinimumOS: OS X 10.6.8Processor: 2.0 Ghz core i5 CPU or equivalent.Memory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: Mid-range NVIDIA GeForce 3x0 / ATI Radeon HD 5x00. Integrated Intel HD Graphics should work but is not supported; problems are generally solved with a driver update.Hard Drive: 5 GB available spaceRecommendedOS: OS X 10.7.5Processor: 2.0 Ghz core i7 CPU or equivalent.Memory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: High-range NVIDIA GeForce 5x0 / ATI Radeon HD 6x00. Integrated Intel HD Graphics should work but is not supported; problems are generally solved with a driver update.Hard Drive: 5 GB available spaceLinuxMinimumOS: Major Linux Distribution from 2010.Processor: 2.0 Ghz core i5 CPU or equivalent.Memory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: Mid-range NVIDIA GeForce 3x0 / ATI Radeon HD 5x00. Integrated Intel HD Graphics should work but is not supported; problems are generally solved with a driver update.Hard Drive: 5 GB available spaceRecommendedOS: Major Linux Distribution from 2012Processor: 2.0 Ghz core i7 CPU or equivalent.Memory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: High-range NVIDIA GeForce 5x0 / ATI Radeon HD 6x00. Integrated Intel HD Graphics should work but is not supported; problems are generally solved with a driver update.Hard Drive: 5 GB available spaceLinkOfficial Website</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5651">Penumbra: Overture</game><game id="3346">Penumbra: Black Plague</game><game id="38450">Among The Sleep</game><game id="40089">Outlast</game><game id="33629">Dear Esther</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/81005/2530420-wwgbwz.jpg</image></root>