<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37580</id><name>Medal of Honor: Warfighter</name><description>PlotWarfighter follows main character Preacher as he and other playable characters navigate modern warfare.A man, his face hidden to the player, watches computer screens and calls operatives as a mission near a port becomes compromised. An undercover operative trains with an extremist group in Yemen. Preacher and his squad, one week before, fire upon militants in Somalia, helping a helicopter destroy a building. 8 weeks before (7 weeks before Somalia), Preacher and Mother, the squad leader, attempt to alleviate a hostage situation in the Philippines.Interspersed, in present day, is Preacher's attempt to reconnect with his ex wife and daughter, an attempt complicated by an apparent suicide bomb attack on his person, destroying the train he expected his family to arrive on. In Madrid, Preacher awakes to his ex-wife and child, he lying in a hospital bed.And there is more to tell...CharactersTask Force MakoMother • Preacher • Stump • Voodoo • Dingo • Tick • Tiger 12Task Force BlackbirdMother • PreacherTask Force GrizzlySgt. Wright • Sgt. Xaysana • LCpl. TranTask Force AtlasGreko • Maniek • Kaska • DiabelEnemySheik • Marwan al-KalifaMiscellaneousLena • DustyMissionsUnintended ConsequencesThrough The Eyes Of EvilShore LeaveHot PursuitChanging TidesRip CurrentHat TrickFinding FarazConnect The DotsHello And DubaiOld FriendsBump In The NightShut It DownDynamic Door BreachThe Dynamic Door Breach system is a new feature that only appears in the singleplayer campaign of Medal of Honor: Warfighter.The default door breach is the kick option but more can be obtained for every 4 head-shots the player acquires on enemies taken by suprise.KickTomahawkCrowbarShotgunDoor Knob ChargeFlex Linear ChargeSheet ChargeWeaponsHandgunsGlock 23Glock 18CHeckler  Koch HK45CM-45 MEUSOCSIG-Sauer P226RVickers Tactical Custom 1911Carbines and PDWsHeckler  Koch MP7A1AKS-47UDaniel Defense DDM4 MK18Daniel Defense DDM4 V1Heckler  Koch HK416CShotgunsAA-12Remington 870 MCSAssault RiflesAK-103 BullpupAK-104AKMAKU-94Bofors AK-5FN SCAR PDWFN SCAR-HHeckler  Koch G3A3Heckler  Koch G3KA4Heckler  Koch G36CHeckler  Koch HK416LaRue Tactical OBR 5.56Steyr AUG A3Light Machine GunsFN M240BFN M249E3 SAWHeckler  Koch MG4PKMPKP PechengSniper RiflesLaRue Tactical OBR 7.62M40A3 Sniper RifleMcMilan CS5McMilan TAC-50McMilan TAC-300Grenade LaunchersHeckler  Koch M320M79MGL Mk 1SRocket LaunchersMk 153 Mod 0 SMAWRPG-7Heavy WeaponsGeneral Dynamics GAU-17/AGeneral Electric GAU-8/A AvengerM320 Chain GunMk 19Grenades  MinesM67 Hand GrenadeM86 Pursuit Deterrent MunitionM83 Smoke GrenadeV40 MinifragFlashbangC4PDM 86Remote ChargeMeleeTomahawkHooligan ToolWeapon CustomizationOpticsOpticsDescriptionLow Power Dual SightsA Dual Scope that lets players toggle to side iron sights.Low Power SightsAn Optic or Optic pair that gives the player enhanced zoom capabilities.Reflex SightsLow power zoom but an increase in agilityIron SightsDefault sights, slight increase in agility.Barrel AssemblyBarrel AssemblyDescriptionClose Quarters Barrel AssemblyFor CQB players, Increase in agility.Standard Barrel AssemblyDefault assembly, able to mount a grenade launcher.Precision Barrel AssemblyFor Snipers, Effective range is increased but agility is severly reduced.Muzzle TypeMuzzleDescriptionSilenced MuzzleReduces weapon noise  agility.Standard MuzzleMuzzle break/flash hider is attached, Stealth is reduced.Receiver GroupReceiverDescriptionClose Quarters Receiver GroupIncreases players agility, lowers effective range. Not available for the EBR.Standard Receiver GroupDefault Reciever, Standardl effective range, lower agility.Precision Receiver GroupIncreased effective range but agility is reduced.CamoflagesCamoflage GroupTypesSandGrass, Spetsnaz Jungle, Grecko, Sand, GROM Pixel, AOR1, Chocolate Chip, White Honeycomb, Kangaroo, SASR Desert, Flat Gray, Sand Dune, Disruptive Brown, UDT, Combat Beige, MoH Bowflage.ForestPine Needles Green, Spetsnaz Urban, Green Mesh, OD, CADPAT, Green Grunge, AOR2, Zen Garden, DMP2, Flecktarn Green, Grass Dunes, Green Spots, M90 Woodland, Swedish Flat, South African 2000, Green Honeycomb.EarthBrown String, Spetsnaz Red, Ten Tiger, Dark Grunge, SEAL Brown, Erbsent, Flat Brown, Desert Spots, Digital Forrest Tiger, Jungle Path, Black Spray, Safari, SAS Fatigue, SAS Green, Black and Tan.SnowFinnish Snow, Winter Grunge, Snow Cell, GROM Snow Plum, Winter Sticks, Flat White, Tiger Cell WinterUrbanDisruptive Gray, Sky, Light Gray, Desert Spray, GROM Puma, Gray Tiger, Navy Tiger, Pink, Gray Digital, Flecktarn, Flecktarn Urban, Winter Night, Finnish Snow Night, UDT Gray.SpecialNo Camo, Brazilian Lizard, M90 NightVehiclesLand VehiclesMUSA RobotWater craftRHIBHelicoptersMH-6/AH-6 Little BirdAH-64D ApacheCH-47 ChinookMH-60 Blackhawk TransportMH-60L DAP BlackhawkAircraftA-10 Thunderbolt IIRQ-7 ShadowRQ-11 RavenSwitchblade UAVMultiplayerThe game's multiplayer mode is completely built around the concept of two-person fireteams. Players are automatically grouped with another player on the same team, and the other players silhouette is always visible, even through walls and other obstacles. If alive, players will be able to spawn on their squadmate, and if a player's squadmate is killed, getting a revenge kill on the player responsible allows the squadmate to instantly respawn.The multiplayer is class-based, with each class offering different weapons and support abilities and will use the Battlelog system that Battlefield 3 used.The special forces units listed in reveal trailer:SEAL Navy SEAL - (United States)GROM Grupa Reagowania Operacyjno-Manewrowego (Poland)SFOD-D 1st Special Forces Operational Detachment- Delta (United States)SAS Special Air Service (United Kingdom)JTF-2 Joint Task Force 2 (Canada)OGA Other Government Agency (United States)FSK/HJK Forsvarets Spesialkommando/Hærens Jegerkommando (Norway)SOG Särskilda Operationsgruppen (Sweden)SASR Special Air Service Regiment (Australia)ROKN UDT Republic of Korea Naval Special Warfare Brigade (Korea)KSK Kommando Spezialkräfte (Germany)GRUPPA ALFA Spetsgruppa A (Russia)ClassesClassClass SpecialityAssaulterGrenade LauncherDemolitionTank StanceHeavy GunnerBipod SetupPoint ManHeavy HittersSniperBipodSpecial OpsSpec Ops VisionMultiplayer Game Modes:Sector ControlTeam DeathmatchReal OpsHotspotCombat MissionHome RunMultiplayer MapsTungawan JungleSarajevo StadiumBasilan AftermathNovi Grad WarzoneSomalian StrongholdHarra DunesShogore ValleyAl Fara ClifsideZero Dark Thirty Map PackChitral CompoundDarra Gun MarketSoundtrackOfficial Soundtrack artworkLike the previous Medal of Honor. Ramin Djawadi returned to compose the score for Warfighter along with some additional tracks composed by rapper, Mike Shinoda. The soundtrack was released on September 25th, 2012 via iTunes and Amazons MP3 store.NumberTrack NameComposerLength1.For RabbitRamin Djawadi2:502.DeployRamin Djawadi2:393.NOC OutMike Shinoda4:074.Lena's ThemeRamin Djawadi3:265.Kit UpRamin Djawadi3:286.Restless NativesRamin Djawadi3:217.Blackbird on a WireRamin Djawadi3:208.Bridge the GapRamin Djawadi2:119.Saa'iqMike Shinoda4:3310.The RaidRamin Djawadi2:1711.Force MultiplierRamin Djawadi2:5412.Old Friend, New FoeRamin Djawadi3:0313.Victory at SeaRamin Djawadi3:0614.ResolveRamin Djawadi2:4415.Green LightRamin Djawadi4:3516.H.A.H.O.Ramin Djawadi2:4517.Medal RunRamin Djawadi2:1618.For MotherRamin Djawadi3:0519.Buzz in the AirRamin Djawadi2:1020.Lena's DreamRamin Djawadi2:2621.With HonorRamin Djawadi4:26 System RequirementsMinimumRecomendedCPU: 2.2 GHz dual core Intel or AMD CPU with 2.4 MB cacheRAM: 2GB of system memoryGraphics: DirectX 10 compatible card with 512 MB RAM or more. Nvidia 8-series or AMD Radeon 3000 series graphics cards.Operating system: Windows VistaDirectX compatible sound card8 GB of hard drive spaceCPU: 2.4 GHz quad core Intel or AMD processor, Core i5 or Phenom X4 or equivalentRAM: 4GBGraphics: DirectX 10 or DX11 compatible card with 1GB of video memory, Nvidia 400-series or AMD 5000-series.Operating system: Windows 7 64-bitDirectX compatible sound card8 GB of hard drive space</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="27006">Battlefield 3</game><game id="35129">Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 3</game><game id="38040">007 Legends</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/29794/2135931-mohwargenkeyart.preview.jpg</image></root>