<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37608</id><name>Proteus</name><description>OverviewProteus is an ambient, exploration based game in which the player explores a procedurally-generated island. Heavy emphasis is placed on the audio component of the game. The player's proximity to various objects, animals, and geological formations affect the soundtrack and audio score.The game was released via Steam for PC and Mac on January 30, 2013. PlayStation 3 and Vita versions will be cross buy and are due out Autumn 2013.AestheticVisualsMuch out of the ordinary occurs in Proteus' skies.Proteus employs a stylized, pixelated visual style. Gameplay takes place on a single island, but under certain circumstances time moves forward by a season, causing the terrain to shift between Spring, Summer, Fall, and Winter. Occasionally the player is exposed to psychedelic effects that link up with the audio experience.Although the game is 3D, much of the objects the player sees are made up of 2D planes. Animals, the leaves of trees, and the sun and moon "billboard" towards the player so that they always appear to face the camera.AudioWinter in Proteus carries a different musical theme than Summer.A primary focus of Proteus is the sound design. As the player moves throughout the island, he or she encounters many objects, animals, structures, and geographic features. Each of these influences the game's soundtrack created by David Kanaga. The player experiences the island in each of 4 seasons, each with their own emotional tenor and theme.ReceptionProteus is the IndieCade 2011 winner for Best Audio, an IGF 2012 Nuevo Finalist, the Amaze 2012 "Most Amazing Game," and an official selection for Lunarcade 2011.System RequirementsPCMinimumOS: Windows XP SP3Processor: 1.8GHzMemory: 3 GB RAMGraphics: Intel HD Graphics 3000Hard Drive: 100 MB HD spaceRecommendedProcessor: 2.2GHz Dual CoreMemory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: 512 MB NVidia or ATI graphics cardHard Drive: 100 MB HD spaceMacMinimumOS: 10.6Processor: 1.8GHzMemory: 3 GB RAMGraphics: Intel HD Graphics 3000Hard Drive: 250 MB HD spaceRecommendedProcessor: 2.2 GHzMemory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: 512 MB NVidia or ATI graphics cardHard Drive: 250 MB HD space</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="31772">Journey</game><game id="33629">Dear Esther</game><game id="37862">Kairo</game><game id="30475">Minecraft</game><game id="41515">Bientôt l'été</game><game id="22737">Yume Nikki</game><game id="38413">Lunnye Devitsy</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2418588-proteus_2012_08_17_96upub760729353_0001.png</image></root>