<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37659</id><name>Wreckateer</name><description>OverviewWreckateer is a Kinect physics-based action game developed by Iron Galaxy and published by Microsoft for the Xbox 360 (via Xbox Live Arcade) on July 25, 2012. Players, armed with a ballista, must use motion to fire large projectiles (and then use motion to guide the projectiles) at goblin-infested fantasy medieval castles.The game is the second of five games released for Microsoft's Summer of Arcade 2012 promotion. It was made free to all between November 15-16, 2012 to celebrate the tenth anniversary of the Xbox Live service.Wreckateer is one of the first games to make use of the Avatar FameStar program, in which players earn special points and avatar outfits (that can only be used in programs that support Avatar FameStar).Main FeaturesSix Shot TypesEvery shot can be controlled after launch, allowing the player to grab points, power-ups, and line up shots. Players have to execute with increasing mastery as the game becomes more difficult, and the prizes are harder to collect. Five of the shots have a special ability that exponentially increase the amount of damage that shots can deal.Sixty CastlesThat's sixty completely unique goblin-infested castles to demolish for sweet golden points- all different sizes, depths, and styles.GoblinsDem goblins! Infesting the Kingdom in a variety of colors and flavors, such as Farmer, Bunny, Secret Service, and Iron Galaxy's personal favorite; the Prom Goblin. There is even a Hot Goblin, gifted with explosive flatulence and a penchant for hitching a ride on a Wreckateer's shots before exploding in a most furious furp.MultiplayerLocal head-to-head multiplayer pits you against a friend. Both players have their own "instance" of the same castle and whoever wrecks the most wins.Playlist CreationSave lists of your favorite castles and quickly play them in one session. Wreckateer also comes pre-loaded with playlists such as "Iron Galaxy Faves" and "Stunt Flyin' Castles."Shot TypesShot TypeDescriptionBasic ShotThe bread-and-butter cannon balls that deal blunt-force damage.Bomb ShotShots plow through targets before triggering a massive explosion.Flying ShotAllows players to spread their arms and fly. The shot builds up explosive power the faster it dive-bombs.Lift ShotGiant, heavy shots with a short initial range but skips through the air like a stone when it's special ability is used.Speed ShotTake off like a bullet, travelling great distances and plowing through multiple targets.Split ShotCrack into four small projectiles that can be twisted, spread out, and pushed together to take out massive targets.Power UpsShot IconDescription5K IconCollect it in the air for a smooth 5,000 points.25K IconAn immediate bonus of 25,000 points.Bomb IconCollecting this bad boy turns any shot into a major explosive that detonates on impact.Lift IconGives the shot a short hop forward, granting it additional range and in-air control time.Speed IconShoots any shot forward with incredible speed. Gain extra distance and plow through multiple targets.E3 PresenceWreckateer was showcased live at E3 2012 during the Microsoft keynote, where two of the shot types were demoed live on-stage.Dave LangThe Original Lang Zone (PAX East 2012)However, this game is probably best known for coming from the mind of the man, the myth, the legend, Dave "The Lang Zone" Lang himself with no help, and indeed still no steak, from Kurt Tillmanns and the rest of Iron Galaxy.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20466">Boom Blox</game><game id="25193">Boom Blox Bash Party</game><game id="18059">PAIN</game><game id="30199">Angry Birds</game><game id="29901">Crush the Castle</game><game id="34702">Burnout CRASH!</game><game id="40581">Angry Birds Friends</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2232818-box_wreckateer.png</image></root>