<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37695</id><name>English Country Tune</name><description>OverviewEnglish Country Tune is a puzzle game developed and published by Increpare Games for the PC, Mac, iPhone, and iPad platforms.GameplayThe player flips a tile around a 3d cubic object to accomplish certain objectives (which vary widely in different sections of the game). Certain objects are impassable or will cut out sections of the player's tile, may paint or clean one side of the tile, or be painted in turn. Most objects only move due to the player's actions. The tile is fixed to the object and cannot jump or fall, but some items in the game experience gravity aligned to the tile's current orientation. Most collections of levels have some unique gameplay concept.The player can reset the level or undo their moves (including undoing a reset) at any time; there are no enemies in the game and it is impossible for the tile to 'die', but levels can easily become unwinnable. In certain cases the game will alert the player (such as if a ball which must end up in a specific location falls off the level), but not all. Most levels require the player to both complete the objectives and position the tile in a certain location.WorldsEnglish Country Tune contains 17 'worlds', each in turn containing a number of puzzles with a similar theme. Only one world is unlocked at the start, and worlds must be entirely completed before unlocking further worlds.Larva - Push spheres into transparent boxes. Larva are subject to gravity.Advanced Larva - 3D maps with larva only.Whale - manoeuvre a cube so that it is not aligned to any part of the level. The cube has lines emitting from each surface which can be interacted with, but the cube is not directly movable.Advanced Whale - 3D maps with whales only.L  W (Larva and Whale) - maps involving a combination of the spheres and cubes, which must generally be used in combination.Planting - The tile is painted green, and an impassable barrier grows on each square it touches. The aim is to cover all surfaces with the barriers.Adv Planting - More difficult maps in the same theme.Adv Cutting - Cut out sections of the tile to pass a shaped barrier and reach the end square.Portrait - Paint a number of tiles with black paint to create a shape the same as the player's tile.Half Sided - Similar to Planting, but only one side of the tile is painted. The first level requires the player to create an object which can be entirely painted with such a limitation, and then solve it.Freezer - Adds locations which will freeze and unfreeze the map when crossed. This alters certain objects, such as making larva passable and impossible to move.Resonator - Adds the only non-player-controlled moving entity, a series of tiles which move in loops and will transport the player's tile if it is encountered.Lesson - The player must design a level using resonators that fulfils certain constraints; this is the only level where the player doesn't use the tile.Freestyle A - A mixture of levels with any of the above gameplay concepts.Freestyle B - Further mixed levels.System RequirementsPCMinimumOS: Windows XPProcessor: 1.5 GHzMemory: 1 GBHard Disk Space: 300 MBVideo Card: Direct X9.0c CompatibleMacMinimumOS: OSX 10.4Processor: 1.5 GHzMemory: 1 GBHard Disk Space: 300 MB</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="31665">Puzzle Dimension</game><game id="17545">Sokoban</game><game id="43377">Sokobond</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/38405/2146925-ectlogo.jpg</image></root>