<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37717</id><name>Total War: Shogun 2: Fall of the Samurai</name><description>OverviewTotal War: Shogun 2: Fall of the Samurai is a standalone expansion to Total War: Shogun 2 released in March 2012. The game starts in 1846 at the outset of Boshin civil war and runs through the Meiji Restoration. There are six base playable factions, with four additional factions available as DLC. The base playable factions include the Aizu, Nagaoka, Joza, Choshu, Satsuma, Tosa with the Obama, Tsu, Saga and Sendai clans available as downloadable content.GameplayThe 19th Century brings new technology like steam-powered warshipsFeaturing the most modern setting yet in the Total War franchise, Fall of the Samurai introduces new units and technology to the series. Players can wield a variety of 19th century technology such as steam-powered warships, gatling-guns, and railways which allows for rapid troop movement.Mechanically, Fall of the Samurai is similar to Shogun 2, although The Creative Assembly has introduced a number of new mechanics such as allowing the use of artillery on the campaign map and allowing direct, 3rd-person control of certain artillery units on the battle map.FactionsFactions in Fall of the Samurai are either aligned with the Shogun or the Emperor.Shogunate ClansAizuNagaokaJozaiObama (DLC)Sendai (DLC)Imperial clansChoshuSatsumaTosaTsu (DLC)Saga (DLC)System RequirementsMinimumRecommendedOS: Windows 7 / Vista / XPOS: Windows 7 / Vista / XPProcessor: 2GHz Intel Dual Core processor / 2.6GHz Intel Single Core processor, or AMD equivalent (with SSE2)Processor: 2nd Generation Intel Core i5 processor (or greater), or AMD equivalentMemory: 1 GB RAM (XP), 2 GB RAM (Vista / Windows 7)Memory: 2 GB RAM (XP), 4 GB RAM (Vista / Windows 7)Graphics: 256 MB DirectX 9.0c compatible card (shader model 3)Graphics: AMD Radeon HD 5000 and 6000 series graphics card or equivalent DirectX 11 compatible cardDirectX: DirectX 9.0cDirectX: DirectX 9.0cHard Drive: 32 GB free hard disk spaceHard Drive: 32 GB free hard disk spaceScreen Resolution: 1024x768 minimumScreen Resolution: 1280x1024 minimumNotice: As a standalone expansion the game DOES NOT require the base game Total War: SHOGUN 2 in order to play.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="31531">Total War: Shogun 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2445/2149674-6419843389_bbf5b47157.jpg</image></root>