<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37725</id><name>Cubemen</name><description>OverviewCubemen is a tower defense/real time strategy hybrid developed and published by 3 Sprockets for the PC and Mac platforms.ModesCubemen currently features three modes, each one with a varying focus on either tower defense or strategy.Defense: A single player only mode which focuses the most on the tower-defense element of the game. The number of waves, types of units available, number of units available, and number of lives the player has are determined by which sub-mode players choose.Skirmish: A 2 player mode featuring a balanced mix of tower defense and strategy. The wave system used in the Defense mode is still present, but now both sides spawn the exact same waves.Mayhem: A mode for up to 6 players with settings for either 2 teams or free for all. The premise is similar to the Skirmish mode, in that all the bases spawn their own waves- but players must choose which base their waves will target while simultaneously supporting these waves with their tower units.Both Skirmish and Mayhem can be played in single player or have empty slots filled in by Bots- which have 3 AI difficulty levels available.Cubemen TypesThere are currently 8 types of cubemen that can be produced:PistolFlamethrowerGrenadier/Artillery/artillery/92-6671/Ice GunRocket LauncherLaser GunSniperMedicPC System RequirementsOS:Windows XP, or laterProcessor: Intel or AMDMemory:1GBHard Disk Space: 120MBVideo Card: Nvidia 8000, Radeon HD3000DirectX®:9.0cSound:anyMac System RequirementsOS:10.6, or laterProcessor: Intel OnlyMemory:1GBHard Disk Space: 120MBVideo Card: Nvidia 8000, Radeon HD3000DirectX®:9.0cSound: any</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23377">Swords &amp; Soldiers</game><game id="33376">RUSH</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/17/171291/2554106-9933193469-Cubem.png</image></root>