<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37747</id><name>Frogger: Hyper Arcade Edition</name><description>OverviewFrogger: Hyper Arcade Edition is an action game developed by Zombie Studios and published by Konami Digital Entertainment for the iPhone, iPad, Wii Shop, PlayStation 3 (PSN), and Xbox 360 (XBLA) platforms.In addition to classic Frogger, Frogger: Hyper Arcade Edition includes six additional game modes, twenty challenges, and the ability to change the style from the 8-bit style of the original arcade game to a next-gen style or to mimic the style of several other Konami games.GameplayGame ModesClassicIn classic mode, Frogger must dodge traffic and avoid water to get to the lily pads at the top of the screen.Tile CaptureA multiplayer mode where each player tries to paint the stage their frog's color by hopping on all the tiles that make up the stageBattle RoyaleA multiplayer mode where each player attempts to capture the lady frog in order to gain the ability to kill the other frogs. The last player to lose all of his or her lives wins.Lady Frog RescueA multiplayer mode where each player attempts to get the most lady frogs to the safety of the lily pads. In this mode, a frog can carry up to three lady frogs at a time.PaintIn paint mode, Frogger must avoid traffic while hopping onto colored tiles to make a pattern. If the player hops off the pattern, then the player loses a life.Twin FrogLike classic mode except instead of controlling one frog at a time, the player controls two frogs simultaneously.Frogger Freak OutIn Frogger Freak Out, the player plays a random game mode each round while scoring 100 points every round.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="32607">Pac-Man Championship Edition DX</game><game id="35732">Galaga Legions DX</game><game id="41489">PlayStation Home Arcade</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2166794-box_froggerhae.png</image></root>