<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37764</id><name>Disney Epic Mickey: Power of Illusion</name><description>OverviewDisney Epic Mickey: Power of Illusion (known in Japan as Disney Epic Mickey: Mickey no Fushigi na Bouken, translated to Disney Epic Mickey: The Mysterious Adventures of Mickey) is a 2D sidescrolling platformer developed by DreamRift (in collaboration with Junction Point) and published by Disney for the Nintendo 3DS on November 18, 2012. Released alongside Disney Epic Mickey 2: The Power of Two, the game is part of the Disney Epic Mickey series (starring Disney mascot Mickey Mouse) and borrows inspiration from Sega's 1990 platformer Castle of Illusion starring Mickey Mouse.Taking place after the events of Disney Epic Mickey 2: The Power of Two, the mysterious Castle of Illusion (run by the evil witch Mizrabel) has appeared in the Wasteland. After being called by Oswald the Lucky Rabbit (who believes to have seen other Toons, including Minnie Mouse, captured within the castle), Mickey must venture through the castle (with the help of both his magic paintbrush and his guide Jiminy Cricket) to rescue various Disney cartoon characters and stop Mizrabel's plans of using their essence to infiltrate the Cartoon World.While the game is a 2D platformer based on Castle of Illusion, the game uses a modified painting mechanic from the original Disney Epic Mickey, utilizing the Nintendo 3DS's touchscreen to let players sketch certain objects into existence (using paint) and erase certain objects out of existence (using paint thinner). As players rescue the various Disney cartoon characters, they will hang out in the Fortress (the game's hub area) and give side-quests and purchasable upgrades.The game is one of the first third-party titles (outside of Japan) to be available as a downloadable title in the Nintendo 3DS eShop, as well as the first to be simultaneously released in both retail and downloadable forms for the 3DS.</description><genres><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2372456-box_empoi.png</image></root>