<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37789</id><name>Justin Smith's Realistic Summer Sports Simulator</name><description>OverviewJSRSSS follows the same physics based gameplay style as Justin Smith's last game, Enviro-Bear 2010. Players try to win medals in Olympic summer sports by manipulating their competitor through touch controls. Players get to choose their nation out of a list of dozens. The physics are both a source of challenge and humor, as it is very difficult to control your olympian without fault. A simple, "DNQ" pops up any time the player does not qualify for judgement in an event. Five events are free to play, and another 10 can be bought for $1.99. There is also a practice mode to hone skills and play single events.EventsAll events are pay for download unless otherwise marked:EventDescriptionDisqualificationOpening Ceremony (Free)The Olympic Torch lighting! Fling around the torch bearer, four flag carriers, and a fighter jet to your heart's content.NoneJavelin (Free)Throw a javelin as far as possible. Drag your competitor and use the momentum to send the javelin soaring.Fault Line100m Dash (Free)Repeatedly touch and drag your runner to the finish line as fast as possible.Early StartEquestrian (Free)A horseback obstacle course with penalties for running into barriers.NoneDiving (Free)Jump off the high dive, do as many flips as possible, and land face first.Improper landingRowing (Free)Drag the boat and keep the rower on until the finish line.Touching WaterHammer ThrowWhip the hammer thrower around to get some sweet distance.Fault LineRacewalkingSlide across a hill in this speed walking race.Falling overArcheryShoot 10 arrows within 10 seconds and try to get the best score.NoneSwimmingGuide a swimmer through four laps.NoneKayak SlalomKayak through checkpoints to a finish line. Penalty points for missing checkpoints.NoneHigh JumpSet the jump bar as high as you'd like and then jump over.Hitting bar or failure to jumpPole VaultUse that pole! Jump as high as possible.Pole goes over fault lineWeightliftingLift a large weight bar into a weightlifters arms as fast as possible.Knocking over lifterRingsDo flips while suspended on rings. Then land once your power meter runs low.None.CyclingDrag your cycler through five laps of a course.None.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="28140">Enviro-Bear 2010</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/10/104847/2161200-mzm.rhqltnpm.png</image></root>