<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37860</id><name>Orcs Must Die! 2</name><description>OverviewOrcs Must Die! 2 is the sequel to  Robot Entertainment's 2011 action-  tower defense game, Orcs Must Die!. It features more of everything from the first game, including more levels, more traps, more weapons, more types of  Orcs to kill, and even a new 2-player  cooperative mode so that more players can kill Orcs at once.In tandem with the new coop mode, a second playable hero character has been included; an evil female Warmage, who can mind-control Orcs. The game's story picks up shortly after the conclusion of the previous game.The upgrade system is all-new. In addition to the 5-skull rating for each level, enemies will occasionally drop skulls. On top of that, bonuses are granted at the end of a level, based on the player's performance (for example, 2 skulls for not taking any damage).PlotTrapped in a world without magic and hunted by her former minions, the Sorceress, the antagonist from the first Orcs Must Die, manages to find a small, newly created rift. It transports her to the dwarven mines, where she stumbles upon the former War Mage, now working as a miner. The two form a team and seek discover the source of newly opening rifts while defending the world with an array of weapons and traps.GameplayGameplay in Orcs Must Die! 2 is similar to the original in the series. The game combines tower defense and third person shooting genres in one system. Each level consists of a single or multiple entrances for foes, and single or multiple exits which are to be defended. The player(s) can choose from multiple trap and weapon types as part of a load-out and use those traps and weapons to defend the exit from incoming "waves" of foes.Orcs Must Die! 2 includes the addition of cooperative mutli-player mode for each level and an additional player character. Players can choose the War Mage or Sorceress as their in game avatar, team-up with a friend or play each level solo. The choice has gameplay ramifications, as the choice of available traps and weapons changes slightly between characters.CharactersPlayable CharactersWar MageSorceressEnemiesOrcs - The "standard" humanoid enemy type, which may have a shield, crossbow, or various levels of armor.Kobolds - Small, fast creatures that may come equipped with explosives.Ogres - Large humanoids which come in standard, fire or frost versions.Trolls - Large humanoids that regenerate health over time.Elementals - Living embodiments of the elements of Earth, Fire or Water.Gnolls - Fast and dangerous humanoids with the ability to ignore barricades. Can come equipped with grenades.Goblins / Hobgoblins - Smaller humanoids who can disable traps, heal or raise their fallen comrades from the dead.Flying Enemies - Multiple types of flying enemies appear, based off of a wide variety of elements and other effects, such as fire, ice, poison and lightning.Mr. Moneybags - An "Endless Mode" only enemy that has large amounts of health, but is also worth significant amounts of coin.Ball and Chain - A large female humanoid capable of "buffing" her comrades, granting them the capability to do increased damage.Pre-order BonusPlayers who pre-order Orcs Must Die! 2 and already own the original Orcs Must Die! on Steam received bonus content. The content included the ability to play ten levels from the original, with the new traps/weapons and  co-op.Downloadable ContentMultiple content bundles have been released for Orcs Must Die! 2, which each adding new levels, enemies, traps and/or costumes for the playable characters.Fire and WaterFamily TiesAre We There Yeti?In addition to purchasable content bundles, additional costumes have been offered for the War Mage and Sorceress.Alienware CostumesHalloween CostumesSystem RequirementsOS: Windows XP, Windows Vista, Windows 7Processor: 2GHz Dual CoreMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: NVIDIA GeForce 6800 or ATI Radeon x1950 or better with 256MB VRAMDirectX: 9Hard Drive: 9 GB HD spaceAdditional: Broadband Internet connection recommended for co-op play.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7816">Tecmo's Deception</game><game id="7656">Kagero: Deception II</game><game id="6341">Deception III: Dark Delusion</game><game id="8088">Trapt</game><game id="34304">Iron Brigade</game><game id="34811">Sanctum</game><game id="32474">Dungeon Defenders</game><game id="37420">Sanctum 2</game><game id="36280">Go Home Dinosaurs!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8960/2280454-omd2.jpg</image></root>