<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37901</id><name>Cafeteria Nipponica</name><description>OverviewDeveloped by Kairosoft, Cafeteria Nipponica allows you to run a franchise of restaurants. In standard Kairosoft fashion, the game revolves around improving locations and perfecting recipes within a 15 year timeframe.GameplaySimilar to other games in the franchise, Cafeteria Nipponica focuses on the micro-management of a business. In this case, multiple restaurants. Focusing on designing menus, interior decorating, buying ingredients, developing and improving dishes and managing staff.RecipesResulting DishIngredient 1Ingredient 2Ingredient 3Fried RiceRiceCarrot-SpaghettiUdonHerbs-Seafood SoupUdonSecret Sauce-ShumaiRiceTop-Class Pork-KaraageToastBoned Chicken-SaladToastLettuce-ToastRiceFlour-OnigiriRiceDried Seaweed-Yaki OnigiriOnigiriSoy Sauce-OmletteRiceFresh Eggs-Rice OmeletteOmletteRice-Chicken BowlRiceBoned Chicken-Rice PorridgeHot PotOrganic Rice-Curry n' RiceFried RiceHot Spices-Indian CurryCurry n' RiceFlourHerbsFried UdonUdonSoy SauceCarrotChamponUdonCabbage-RamenUdonBoned Chicken-Japanese PastaSpaghettiMushroomSpinachMiso SoupSeafood SoupTofu-StewCorn ChowderBoned ChickenNorthern PotatoBird's Nest SoupShark Fin SoupCaviarFoie GrasHot PotSeafood SoupChinese CabbageBoned ChickenPork BunShumaiTop-Class Pork-TakoyakiPork BunFlourOcotopusHamburger SteakSauteed ChickenMarbled BeefCarrotPizza ToastToastTomato-ParfaitIce CreamCherries-Pork BowlChicken BowlTop-Class PorkOnionEel BowlChicken BowlTasty FishSecret SauceTuna BowlRiceTasty FishSoy SauceCrab Fried RiceFried RiceKing CrabMild VinegarBeef CurryCurry n' RiceMarbled Beef-Hayashi RiceCurry n' RiceTomato-YakisobaSobaCabbage-Pasta CarbonaraSpaghettiFresh MilkFresh EggsMeat Sauce PastaSpaghettiTop-Class PorkTomatoCorn ChowderSeafood SoupSweet Corn-YakitoriHamburger SteakTop Class ShrimpOrganic RiceTop Class SushiSashimiOrganic RiceSoy SauceFrench FriesToastNorthern Potatoes-Floor JobRequirementsSkillApprenticeCarry FoodManagerLvl. 5 ApprenticeExp UpPro StaffLvl. 5 ManagerWalk FastService MasterLvl. 5 ApprenticeGossipPerformerLvl. 5 Service Master/ManagerCarry FoodNinjaLvl. 5 Performer/Japanese CookWalk FastPopular StaffLvl. 5 Performer/Apprentice CookCenter of AttentionMaster FoodLvl. 5 Performer/ Expert ChefGossipMusicianLvl. 5 Sercive Master/ 5 Star ChefForeign LanguageRoller SkaterLvl. 5 Performer/Western CookWalk FastAnimal HandlerLvl. 5 Musician/Ninja/Pro StaffRelaxingKairo StaffLvl. 5 Animal HandlerSnack Info</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="35624">Grand Prix Story</game><game id="36075">Mega Mall Story</game><game id="37077">Epic Astro Story</game><game id="34336">Hot Springs Story</game><game id="36369">Pocket League Story</game><game id="37639">Dungeon Village</game><game id="36915">World Cruise Story</game><game id="35767">Pocket Academy</game><game id="36888">Oh! Edo Towns</game><game id="42759">The Sushi Spinnery</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/15/155886/2169742-icon.jpg</image></root>