<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37937</id><name>Lost Planet 3</name><description>OverviewLost Planet 3 is an action adventure game developed by Spark Unlimited. Formally known as Project Trucker, it's a prequel to Lost Planet: Extreme Condition and Lost Planet 2. Unlike Lost Planet 2, Lost Planet 3 focuses on the single player campaign, telling the story of the colonisation of EDN-III by Man.The game was revealed in Rome (Italy) during Captivate 2012. It was scheduled for a release on June 25th 2013 in the US (June 28th in EU), but was later pushed to a August 27th 2013 release instead (August 30th in EU).PlotJimLost Planet 3 puts the player in the shoes of Jim Peyton, a miner who has left his wife and kid on earth for EDN-III, where he must set up heat sources around the planet in order to make it livable. In order to make the planet livable, Jim mines the planet for thermal energy and sets up thermal posts (the same posts that players in previous Lost Planet games had to use to replenish their thermal energy). Jim is motivated strictly by money and works with Wayne's father (Wayne being the main protagonist of the first game). During his quest to make the planet hospitable, Jim must fight the Akrid (the evil alien species who lives on the planet) and weather extreme storms.The game's plot centers around a conspiracy. Upon setting up a thermal post, Jim discovers a door that suggests that his colony are not the first humans to have explored the planet.GameplayLike in previous games, Lost Planet 3 is a third person shooter coupled with light platforming segments. The player will navigate large, open environments as well as a hub world where players will pick up quests. Unlike in previous games, thermal energy is no longer a ressource that must be collected at thermal energy stations in order to stay alive. Instead, thermal energy is now a currency used to buy upgrades for weapons. Lost Planet 3 takes some cues from the Dead Space franchise by having the player's life meter on the back of the character. The game dynamically portrays the game's hud on the character and some cut scenes take place as video calls that the player watches while still controlling the character.LP 3 lets players control the Utility Rig, a giant mech that has a giant drill, useful for breaking things in the environments and facing the larger Akrids. The mech also has a claw that comes into use when fighting enemies. For example, the claw can be used to pin down a boss while Jim exits the mech to attack its now exposed weak spot. System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows XPProcessor: Dual core CPU 2.5 GHzMemory: 3 GB RAMGraphics: NVIDIA® GeForce® 9800 or better, ATI Radeon™ HD 4770 or betterHard Drive: 16 GB available spaceSound Card: Standard audio deviceRecommendedOS: Windows 7Processor: Quad core 2.7 GHz or betterMemory: 8 GB RAMGraphics: NVIDIA® GeForce® GTX 460 or betterHard Drive: 16 GB available spaceSound Card: Standard audio device</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20800">Dead Space</game><game id="25726">Red Faction: Armageddon</game><game id="38270">Dead Space 3</game><game id="31737">Resident Evil: Revelations</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2472246-box_lp3.png</image></root>