<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38006</id><name>Chivalry: Medieval Warfare</name><description>OverviewChivalry: Medieval Warfare is a multiplayer team-based first-person hack-and-slash game developed and published by Torn Banner for the PC (as a downloadable title via Steam, Gamersgate, and Gamestop) and as a retail title in Europe and Australia by Lace Mamba. Set in medieval times, it is a spiritual sequel to Age of Chivalry (a free mod for Half-Life 2 also developed by Torn Banner).ClassesThere are four distinct classes in Chivalry: Medieval Warfare. Each class has its own special ability and unique set of weapons.ArcherArcherThe archer is the ranged weapon specialist. He is best used in a support role to deliver damage to enemies from far to mid range. The archer is considerably more vulnerable in melee, when compared to the other classes. The archer's ability to inflict decent damage at long range makes him a great defensive class for harassing the enemy's front lines and keeping them off objective points. When using javelins the archer can be viable at melee range as well, thrusting them from behind a shield. Available weapons include bows, crossbows, javelins, slings, daggers, cudgels, and shields. The archer also gets a choice of various ammunition types for bows and slings.Special Ability: Rogue - Does +%50 backstab damage.Man-at-armsMan-at-armsThe man-at-arms is the lightest melee class, and relies heavily on evasion and speed abilities to land hits while trying to avoid enemy attacks. He specializes in one handed weapons and has the option of bringing a shield into battle. The man-at-arms is best played on the fringes of a battle. His speed allows him to move in and out of fights slipping in brutal hits. A good man-at-arms can evade the slow and heavy swings of a vanguard or knight, closing the distance rapidly to deliver the killing blow. Available weapons include swords, axes, clubs, staves, daggers, smoke bombs, fire pots, and shields.Special Ability: Elusive - Can perform dodgesKnightKnightThe most powerful tank melee unit on the battlefield. The knight's damage output and armour levels are offset by the lack of agility and generally slower weapons he wields. His weapons are typically slow and heavy, but absolutely devastating when they connect. Knights are slow moving, but they can take significantly more damage than the other classes. Knights often move the front line and charge into large groups. His imposing frame and plate armour make him ideal for standing ground and defending a point. Only a headshot from a heavy crossbow can kill a knight in one hit. Available weapons include one handed, bastard, and two handed swords, axes, hammers, flails, throwing axes, and shields.Special Ability: Tank – Can absorb additional damage and takes less stamina to block incoming blows.VanguardVanguardThe vanguard is an imposing aggressive force which forms the front line of an army. His weapons have extremely long reach and deal incredible damage. Generally making up a good portion of a team, the vanguard is typically the core warrior in battle. He has a large variety of weapons, most of which have extreme range (enough to kick an enemy away and still hit him with a swing). His charge ability can one-shot the lower armoured classes, though it can be supremely costly if missed. The vanguard is an all-around class capable of any role. Available weapons include poleaxes, polehammers, spears, greatswords, billhooks, throwing axes, and throwing knives.Special Ability: Charge - Can sprint attack into battle.WeaponsArcher BowsLongbow- A bow with a good mix of speed, damage, and range. Good for any situation. Unlocked by defaultShortbow- A smaller bow that does less damage and has less range, but a significantly faster fire rate. Unlocked after 50 bow killsWarbow- A large bow that does heavy damage and has a very long range, but a slow fire rate. Unlocked after 75 bow killsEach bow can use two types of arrows: Bodkin arrows do more damage to Knights and Vanguards, and Broadhead arrows do more damage to Men at Arms and other ArchersCrossbowsCrossbowmen may choose to equip themselves with either a pavise shield which can be deployed as cover, or extra crossbow boltsCrossbow- A crossbow with average damage and range, and a slow reload speed. Unlocked by defaultLight Crossbow- A crossbow with low damage and short range, but a significantly faster reload speed. Unlocked after 50 crossbow killsHeavy Crossbow- A crossbow that does massive damage, but has a very slow reload speed. Unlocked after 75 crossbow killsJavelinsJavelins are unique in that they may be thrown with the default attack, or used as a melee weapon by performing a stab. All types use the buckler shield in the off hand.Javelin- Javelins with average damage, range, and throw speed, as well as average melee damage. Five may be carried at once. Unlocked by defaultShort Spears- Javelins with low damage, but long range and short throw speed, as well as low melee damage but quick strikes. Unlocked after 50 Javelin kills (Thrown or melee)Heavy Javelins- Javelins with heavy damage, but slow throw speed and short range, as well as heavy and slow melee attacks. Unlocked after 75 Javelin kills (Thrown or melee)SlingAdded in Content Update 1, the Sling fires two types of projectilesRocks- Low damage, unlimited ammoSteel Balls- Higher damage, limit 20 ammoMan At ArmsMen at Arms specialize in one-handed weapons that may be used with either a small, fast buckler shield; or a larger, slower heater shield.SwordsBroadsword- Good all around sword that combines average reach, speed, and damage. Unlocked by defaultNorse Sword- A fast sword with shorter reach than the broadsword. Has low cutting damage, but very fast and damaging stabs. Unlocked after 50 Sword killsFalchion- A fast sword with the shortest reach of the three. Has poor stab damage, but very strong cutting damage. Unlocked after 75 Sword killsAxesHatchet- A very fast axe with low damage and short reach. Unlocked by defaultWar Axe- A slower, but more damaging axe with a very short reach. Unlocked after 50 Axe killsDane Axe- An axe that combines average speed, damage, and long reach. Unlocked after 75 Axe killsMacesMace- Good all around mace that combines average reach, speed, and damage. Unlocked by defaultMorning Star- A somewhat slow mace with long reach and good damage. Unlocked after 50 Mace killsHoly Water Sprinkler- A short mace with a low damage and very fast attack speed. Unlocked after 75 Mace killsQuarterstaffAdded in Content Update 1. The quarterstaff has a short reach and low damage, but an extremely high attack speed. Cannot be used with a shield.Vanguard GreatswordsGreatsword- A good all-around two-hander. Unlocked by defaultClaymore- A Scottish relic that trades reach and damage for speed. Unlocked after 50 Greatsword killsZweihander- A huge German sword that trades speed for incredible damage. Unlocked after 75 Greatsword killsSpearsSpears do not have overhead attacks, instead they have two stabs; a shorter range quick stab and a longer range slow thrustSpear- A very long reaching weapon primarily used for stabbing. Unlocked by defaultMilitary Fork- A very long reaching weapon with two tines. Trades damage for increased stab speed. Unlocked after 50 Spear killsBrandistock- A very long reaching weapon with three barbed points. Trades speed for damage. Unlocked after 75 Spear killsPolearmsBardiche- A long reaching weapon with an axe head. Has good chopping damage, but low stab damage. Has average speed. Unlocked by defaultBillhook- An English infantry weapon with a curved hook ending in a spike. Trades damage for speed. Unlocked after 50 Polearm killsHalberd- A weapon with slow, damaging strikes and stab attacks. Unlocked after 75 Polearm killsPolehammer- Added in Content Update 1, the Polehammer is faster than the Halberd, but does less damageKnightKnights have the unique ability to wield any of their two handed swords in one hand with either a Kite or Tower shield.Bastard SwordsLongsword- The longsword combines average speed, reach, and damage. Unlocked by defaultSword of War- The Sword of War sacrifices damage for increased speed. Unlocked after 50 Bastard Sword killsMesser- A large single edged weapon which trades speed for great chopping damage. Unlocked after 75 Bastard Sword killsHammersWarhammer- A one handed weapon with good speed and blunt damage. Unlocked by defaultMaul- A massive two handed warhammer. Incredibly slow, but very deadly. Unlocked after 50 Hammer killsGrand Mace- A large two handed mace. Has a moderately slow attack speed, but good damage. Unlocked after 75 Hammer killsWar AxesDouble Axe- A shorter two handed axe with good chopping damage and a faster attack speed. Unlocked by defaultPoleaxe- A slower two hander with good chopping damage and good stab damage. Unlocked after 50 War Axe killsBearded Axe- A long axe with a single edge that has good reach and damage. Unlocked after 75 War Axe killsFlailsAdded in Content Update 1, Flails are spiked balls on a chain that the Knight uses along side a bucklerLight Flail- A fast, low damage weapon.Heavy Flail- A slower, more damaging weapon.Secondary WeaponsVanguards have the option to use the Man at Arms' axes as a secondary weapon, and Knights may use either the Man at Arms' maces or swords as a secondary weapon. Daggers (Archer and Man at Arms)Broad Dagger- A short range weapon with average chopping and stabbing. Unlocked by defaultHunting Knife- A short range weapon with high chopping damage, but poor stab damage. Unlocked after 50 Dagger killsThrusting Dagger- A short range weapon with poor chopping damage, but high stabbing damage. Unlocked after 75 Dagger killsShortswords (Archer, Vanguard, and Man at Arms)Shortsword- An average weapon with longer range than a dagger, but lower speed. Unlocked by defaultSabre- A short range weapon with high chopping damage, but poor stab damage. Unlocked after 50 Shortsword killsCudgel- A short range blunt weapon that does more damage to armored targets (Vanguards and Knights). Unlocked after 75 Shortsword killsThrown Weapons Throwing Knives- Fast, moderately damaging thrown weapons with short range. Can be used by the Man at Arms and VanguardThrowing Axes- Slower more damaging thrown weapons with moderate range. Can be used by Vanguards and KnightsSmoke Pot- A thrown weapon that explodes into a cloud of thick smoke. Can be used by the VanguardOil Pot- A thrown weapon that explodes into a small circle of fire. Enemies within the radius when the pot is thrown are lit on fire for a few seconds, obscuring their vision and causing damage over time.Game ModesTeam ObjectiveAttack and defend style gameplay. The attackers on each map must accomplish a series of objectives unique to each map, ranging from setting a farm on fire to poisoning well water with diseased corpses. The defenders must prevent the attackers from completing these objectives within the time limit. Considered to be the core mode of Chivalry.Last Team StandingA battle mode with Counter-Strike style spawning rules. If a player dies, they must wait until the next round to respawn. The only objective is the kill the enemy to the last man.Team DeathmatchTraditional team deathmatch with a twist. Once a team reaches the kill limit, the opposing team does not respawn. The winning team must then fight to exterminate the opposing force to achieve total victory.King of the HillThe teams battle over a central platform, earning capture time when the opposing team does not control the platform. Hold the center for the allotted time to win.Capture the FlagThe classic two flag CTF setup. Players who pick up the flag are unable to use their weapons, but the flag acts like a Vanguard spear. A team's flag must be in their base in order for them to capture the enemy flag. First team to three captures wins.Free for AllTraditional deathmatch mode. The player with the most kills when time expires wins. Every man for themselves!DuelAdded in Content Update 1. Players enter a lobby where they may challenge other players to one-on-one combat, or join the pool and be automatically assigned opponents. The player with the most duel victories when time expires is the winner.EnvironmentsThe game initially included 7 different environments for player to battle in. Each stage includes their own unique objectives. A free content update on January 31, 2013 added 13 new maps: one team objective map, two maps which can play a variety of modes, and ten small maps for use with the newly added Duel mode.Stoneshill (Team Objective)The Mason Order has managed to sneak into the Stoneshill valley undiscovered aiming to end the still short rule of the Agathian steward residing here in his opulent Royal Palace. War comes to Stoneshill and it seems the quiet people of the sleepy village here are wholly unprepared. If the tenants of the Agathian Knighthood hold true, the Agathian forces stationed here will need to take up arms and face their fate, not only to ensure the safety of their named king’s subjects, but to ensure their continued claim to their homeland.The outside area, as well as the throne room can be used for Team Deathmatch and Last Team Standing.StoneshillMasonSlaughter the peasants and burn the village.Breach the keep with the battering ram.Kill the king.AgathaProtect the village and the peasants.Defend the keep.Protect the king.Arena (Various Modes)You have been chosen to lay your life down for the glory of the kingdom. The political whispers that haunt the streets of this once great capitol city will be settled here and now in the arena! Only death can reveal which faction has truest claim to the throne for the will of men is written in blood!ArenaAvailable ModesLast Team StandingKing of the HillTeam DeathmatchFree For AllBattlegrounds (Team Objective)The Agathian army finally makes a push to take back their capitol city. The fighting has raged for three days, the surrounding lands have been ravaged and the worst is still yet to come. As Agathian engineers put the final touches on their secret weapon the last remaining Mason resources are under threat with the Agathian army launching their final and most devastating assault on their once glorious city.BattlegroundsMasonDefend the farm, fields, windmill and fair.Stop the petard from reaching the gates.AgathaBurn down the farm, fields, windmill and the fair.Move the petard to gates and blow it open.Hillside (Team Objective)After returning to find their homeland occupied by the Mason Order, the Agathian ship armadas were denied passage through the straight that leads into the Agathian interior. By the cover of night an Agathian landing party has made it ashore, where they plan to secure the beach and signal to the warships via a bonfire when they are clear to advance. Will the Mason Order’s shore defense prove too much for the Agathian ships, or will the landing party provide distraction sufficient enough for the fleet to invade?The first and third objective area may also be used for Team Deathmatch and Last Team Standing.HillsideMasonPrevent a signal fire.Defend the trebuchets.Stop the Agathians from firing at the ships.AgathaLight a signal fire.Tear down the trebuchets.Shoot down the ships.Ruins (Various Modes)What was once the glorious and noble crusade of King Argon to take back the now ruined first city of Narem has deteriorated into a petty land battle of pride and hubris in it’s decrepit streets and alleys. Take the enemies flag and parade it through the streets in mockery before you burn it back at your base.RuinsAvailable ModesLast Team StandingCapture the FlagKing of the HillTeam DeathmatchFree For AllDark Forest (Team Objective)Having infiltrated Agatha through a secret mountain pass above the Stoneshill Valley, the Mason Order plans to poison the source of the agathian water supply here with the diseased corpses of Agathian peasantry. Is the Mason Order aware that the remaining heirs to the throne are hidden away in a cliffside fortress just beyond the pass? Agatha’s last hope is to hold their reservoir cistern against the Mason Order’s disease laden wagon and hope the order doesn’t discover what’s hidden just beyond it.MasonDark ForestPush the corpse wagon into the pass.Open the flood gates.Kill the nobles.AgathaStop the wagon from reaching the passDefend the flood gates.Keep the nobles alive.Moor (various modes)MoorA medium sized map, Moor is a large open field with wooden barriers sprinkled about.Available modesLast Team StandingCapture the FlagKing of the HillTeam DeathmatchFree For AllCitadel (Team Objective)A five stage Team Objective map which takes place in the Mason homeland. The Citadel looms in the shadow of an active volcano. Rivers of lava flow throughout the map. The Knights of Agatha assault the Mason Order's lands in order to free their people from slavery, and end the rule of the tyrant Lord Malric. Added as a part of Content Update 1AgathaCitadelTurn and fire the ballistas on the palisade wall to destroy itBreak the locks to free the slaves from their cagesDestroy the chains of the slaves to free themBreak down the doors to the CitadelKill Lord MalricMasonDefend the palisade wallsStop Agatha from breaking the locks on the cagesStop Agatha from breaking the chains of the slavesProtect the doors to the CitadelDefend Lord MalricFrigid (Various Modes)A snow covered map which features numerous environmental hazards from giant rolling snowballs to crushing log traps. Added as a part of Content Update 1.FrigidAvailable ModesTeam DeathmatchCapture the FlagLast Team Standing Argon's Wall (Various Modes)Argon's WallA medium sized map which takes place on an ancient wall built by King Argon of Agatha. The center of the map features an upper and lower portion, with the lower portion defended by pots of boiling oil which can be dropped from above. Added as a part of Content Update 1.Available ModesTeam DeathmatchLast Team StandingDuel MapsDuel maps are designed for one-on-one encounters in Duel mode, which was added as a part of Content Update 1. Bridge     Cistern     Courtyard     Dining Hall     Frostpeak   Mines Shaft Shipyard Throneroom Tower   System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Windows XPProcessor: Core 2 Duo E6600 (2.4 GHz) or AMD equivalent, or betterMemory: At least 2GBHard Disk Space: 3 GBVideo Card: ATI Radeon 3870 of higher, Nvidia Geforce 8800 GT or higherGraphics card memory: 512MB+Sound: Windows compatible sound cardRecommended:OS: Windows Vista / Windows 7Processor: 2.4 GHz quad core or betterMemory: 4 GB system RAMHard Disk Space: 9 GBVideo Card: DirectX 9 compatible with 768 MB video RAM or better (NVIDIA GeForce GTX 460 / ATI Radeon HD 5850)Sound: Windows compatible sound card</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="36170">War of the Roses</game><game id="25453">Pirates, Vikings and Knights II</game><game id="34889">Mount and Blade: With Fire &amp; Sword</game><game id="21192">Mount &amp; Blade</game><game id="1567">Die by the Sword</game><game id="40731">Dark Shadows - Army of Evil</game><game id="41473">Blade Symphony</game><game id="42292">Battle Cry Of Freedom</game><game id="22142">Darkfall</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2428386-box_chivalry.png</image></root>