<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3802</id><name>Blood Money</name><description>Blood Money is hailed as one of the best side-scrolling shoot-em-ups to be released for the Commodore Amiga. "The claws boss, the claws!"The graphics and sound are superb for the time and the gameplay is fluid, yet frenzied. Since there is no way to save your game, it quickly becomes an addictive and sometimes frustrating game to play. The difficulty ramps up considerably between levels and only the first two worlds are playable from the beginning. Once either of the first two worlds are completed, all 4 worlds are available to plunder. Gameplay of level 1 can be viewed hereGameplay of levels 2-4 can be viewed  hereThe game is segmented into 4 worlds, each navigated by a different vehicle:Metal World – HelicopterOcean World – SubmarineIce World – Jet Pack SuitRed World – Jet FighterA variety of enemies appeared unique to each level:Metal World – Glowing Orbs, Turrets, Robot Walkers, Spinning Shurikens, Floating Jaws, Orbiting Spheres, Red Jet Fighters, Triangular Spaceships,  Stationary Missile Launchers, Green Bubbles, Stationary MinesOcean World – Sea Cucumbers, Diagonal swimming Jellyfish, Vertical swimming Jellyfish, Crabs, Bubbles, Giant Crab ClawsIce World – Turrets, Dragons, Floating Mines, Ice Spikes, Bouncing Mines, Small Asteroids, Large Asteroids, Jet Fighters, Flack Cannons, Missiles, Sea SerpentsRed World – Worms, Spitting Plants, Stationary Mines, Spinning Blades, Floating Brains, Fire Serpents, Spinning Heads, Fire Ball ChainsThroughout each world, money is collected for downed enemies which can be spent in equipment stores along the way to power-up your vehicle. There are 8 power-ups available:Upward firing missilesDownward firing missilesBombsRear firing missilesMulti-shotSpeed upLimited time invulnerabilityExtra LifeStore NamesMetal World – Give 'em HellOcean World – Davey Jones's Equipment Locker (ironically both the pirate and the developer shared the same name)Ice World – Equipment Buy or Die!Red Monster – Monster Bashing EquipmentBosses end each level:Metal World – Floating Metal MachineOcean World – Sea SerpentIce World – Lip Like Alien with PustulesRed World – Floating BrainCreditsCoded by: Dave JonesGraphics by: Tony Smith</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11071">X-Out</game><game id="15077">Z-Out</game><game id="13745">R-Type</game><game id="4459">Armalyte</game><game id="6837">Menace</game><game id="27999">Apidya</game><game id="16456">Fortress Underground</game><game id="19398">Katakis</game><game id="37433">Sirius 7</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1987/771250-blood_money___front.jpg</image></root>