<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38075</id><name>Wordament</name><description>Overview"Great".Wordament is a free massively multiplayer online puzzle game (in similar vein to Boggle) developed and published by Microsoft on April 1, 2011 for Windows Phone. Players join continuous sessions (lasting two minutes, not including results) where everybody is given the same 4x4 puzzle board and must drag their fingers (or other pointers) horizontally, vertically, and/or diagonally across the letter grid to generate words. Points are given to the length of each unique word the player has generated, which is tallied at the end of the round and compared with other players in the post-round leaderboards (which, after a short amount of time, resets the game and point count).A year later, the game was re-released on the Windows Phone Marketplace to support Xbox Live, including new features such as gamertag support (with an optional "Guest Mode", which do not affect the gamertag's statistics), multiple languages (both in the user interface and in the puzzle boards), new sounds, updated graphics (including theme colors tied to the system theme), and 12 achievements worth 200 gamerscore. One achievement, World Champ, was unobtainable until May 6, 2012. A Windows 8 version of the game was released on October 26, 2012.iOSOn December 21, 2012 the game was released on IOS. This version allows you to log in with your Xbox account and includes 10 achievements. These achievements tie in to your profile and not Apple's game center, marking the first time you could get achievements on a non-Microsoft platform.BrowserOn January 31, 2013 Microsoft released the game on xbox.com. This version is the exact same as all the others and features the same achievement set as the iOS version.</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1071">Boggle</game><game id="35715">Quarrel</game><game id="35997">Text Twist 2</game><game id="25582">WordFu</game><game id="24778">Letter Zap!</game><game id="43305">I Suck At: Word Games</game><game id="43307">Twisted Letters</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2314088-box_wordament.png</image></root>