<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38107</id><name>Battle Dodgeball</name><description>OverviewBattle Dodgeball (or Battle Dodge Ball) is a dodgeball game from Sun L and Banpresto that pits heroes and villains from the Gundam, Ultraman and Kamen Rider universes against each other in dodgeball matches. Similarly to Technos's Super Dodge Ball, each combatant has a health meter which depletes whenever they are hit by the dodgeball. Stronger throws cause more damage and once a character's HP is depleted, they leave the arena.Teams have three members apiece, with an additional group of three identical "minor" characters that sit outside of the opponent's area and can try and hit them with any balls that leave their side of the court. During the single player mode the player can spend experience points they earn in matches to level up their characters' abilities, including the group of minor characters.The game is Banpresto's second SNES entry in the Compati Hero crossover franchise (the first being SD Great Battle), which frequently sets up battles between characters of the three franchises above. Battle Dodgeball would eventually be followed with a sequel, Battle Dodgeball II.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="3">Sports</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3552">Super Dodge Ball</game><game id="950">Kunio-kun no Dodge Ball da yo: Zenin Shūgo</game><game id="13484">Super Dodge Ball Advance</game><game id="36000">Super Dodge Ball</game><game id="21609">Super Dodgeball Brawlers</game><game id="20724">Double D Dodgeball</game><game id="12024">Panda Dodgeball</game><game id="20563">Pirates vs. Ninjas Dodgeball</game><game id="30858">XS Junior League Dodgeball</game><game id="33037">Zeebo Sports Queimada</game><game id="38108">Battle Dodgeball II</game><game id="13478">Nekketsu Koukou Dodgeball Bu Kyouteki! Toukyuu Senshi no Maki</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/14/149200/2187287-battle_dodgeball.jpg</image></root>