<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38125</id><name>NBA Baller Beats</name><description>OverviewNBA Baller Beats is a rhythm game developed by HB Studios and published by Majesco for the Xbox 360 on September 11, 2012. Using the Kinect, players dribble a real basketball to the beat of various popular tunes (while matching up special movements, including crossovers and pump fakes).NBA Baller Beats is the first game using the Kinect that requires players to use a physical object as a necessary gameplay peripheral. The game package is bundled with a replica Spalding basketball.The cover athlete is Deron Williams of the Brooklyn Nets.GameplayThe game, which comes with an official Spalding basketball, challenges players to dribble the basketball in time with one of the 30 available songs.On screen is a descending track with colour-coded moves for the player to follow (e.g. crossover, pump fake, behind-the-back) for a total of 20 moves. Matching up the movements with the on screen indicator racks up more points and combos.There are 3 difficulty modes available : Rookie, Pro and Baller; which dictate the speed of the descending track and complexity of moves required from the player.At the end of the round, the player is given a score along with pictures which have been taken during the course of the song which can be uploaded to Facebook.3 modes have been announced so far:Single Player - Go solo and practice your moves to unlock additional songsMove School - Practice modeMultiplayer - Head-to-Head mode against 8 players (non-simultaneous gameplay). Highest score wins.SoundtrackThe game includes thirty popular tunes to choose from, split up into three difficulty levels:Easy TracksArtistSong TitleConsequenceAccess HollywoodGorillaz (feat. Bobby Womack and Mos Def)StyloInterpolObstacle 1JusticeCanonKayne West (feat. Young Jeezy)AmazingMachine Drum (feat. Melo X)Let It (Edit Remix)QueenAnother One Bites The DustStatic RevengerMusic Makes Me Feel So GoodWiz KhalifaRoll UpYeasayerO.N.E.Medium TracksArtistSong TitleB.o.BSo GoodCee-LoIt's OkChromeoNight By NightCommonBlue SkyJanelle MonaeTightropeLMFAOParty Rock AnthemNajeeChampionship FeverOnyxSlamSantigoldDisparate YouthTiësto vs. Diplo (feat. Busta Rhymes)C'Mon Catch 'Em By SurpriseDifficult TracksArtistSong TitleCalling All CarsAutobioticsEric B.  RakimDon't Sweat the TechniqueLittle BarrieSurf HellMissy ElliottGet Ur Freak OnRise AgainstSatelliteRun DMCIt's TrickySkrillexBangarangThem Crooked VulturesNew FangWale (feat. Lady Gaga)ChillinYoung MCBust A Move</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre><genre id="22">Basketball</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2280494-box_nbabb.png</image></root>