<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38126</id><name>Survarium</name><description>OverviewAfter the cancellation of S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2, former GSC Game World developers formed Vostok Games and quickly announced Survarium, a free to play online shooter set in a post-apocalyptic world that retains many core elements found in the S.T.A.L.K.E.R. games.StoryThe world suffered an ecological crisis many years ago that caused trees to spread everywhere. The military was mobilized to fight back against the plague without much success. One day, scientists developed a "cure" that prevented the trees from spreading but all was not well. The trees eventually turned the cure against the human population, like a lethal allergy. Infected humans withered away within a day and thus a huge portion of the world's population was eradicated. Some survived and are not struggling to stay alive in this harsh, empty world without electricity or any other convenience.Gameplay ModesSo far, Vostok Games have talked about three game modes.Team Combat ModeThis appears to be the most traditional of all modes as players are split up into teams and have to retrieve a certain item and return it to their base and then guard it to keep it safe. It is possible that both teams lose.Cooperative PlaythroughPlayers are joined either by friends or strangers to complete a set of multiple missions in succession right after one another. However, each mission is supposedly going to be much harder than the one before it and objectives and other details may even depend upon what or how players did in the previous mission.Freeplay ModeIn this mode, designed for 20-40 players at a time, the world is free to explore without preset rules other than survival. It currently appears to be the most like a online version of S.T.A.L.K.E.R. gameplay as players can choose to travel completely on their own or ally themselves with other players and survive in the game world. The game also features a lot of RPG elements like experience points and stats that improve combat or healing abilities among others.</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11725">S.T.A.L.K.E.R.: Shadow of Chernobyl</game><game id="26119">S.T.A.L.K.E.R.: Call of Pripyat</game><game id="21302">S.T.A.L.K.E.R.: Clear Sky</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93998/2189073-screen_shot_2012_04_25_at_12.13.28_pm.png</image></root>