<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38141</id><name>Rayman Legends</name><description>OverviewRayman Legends is a sequel to Rayman Origins. On its lead-platform, the Wii U, It features asymmetrical co-op for up to five players total with one player using the Wii U GamePad and the remaining four either using Wii Remotes or Wii U Pro Controllers. In Japan, Rayman Legends is being published by Nintendo and thus remains Wii U exclusive in that region.Platform Exclusive ContentsWii U VersionAside from the touch-screen levels featuring Murphy that also appear in the Vita version, the Wii U release will receive an exclusive "Funky Ray" bonus costume to unlock for players who have downloaded and played the Rayman Legends Challenges App before 28 August, 2013. Players will also have the Online Challenges cups they earned and Level of Awesomeness transferred to Rayman Legends. Nintendo announced that the Wii U version will also have exclusive Mario and Luigi costumes for Rayman and Globox.PSVita VersionThis version will include the Murphy touch-levels as well as five exclusive levels that are designed for the back-touch pad of the Vita. Also, two exclusive costumes (a Prince of Persia costume for Rayman and a Splinter Cell costume for Globox) come with this version.HistoryOn April 27 2012, an internal demonstration video showing a sequel to Ubisoft's critical hit, Rayman Origins leaked to a French website, and spread its way around the internet from there.NFC Concept with a Rabbid figurine. Shortly after the leak occurred, Ubisoft confirmed the game's existence while emphasizing that the video was meant strictly for internal demonstration purposes. Videos like this are often made by development teams to show off their ideas. Thus, nothing shown in the video is confirmed to be included in the final game.In February 2013, shortly before the game was supposed to be released on Wii U Ubisoft delayed the game to September and announced PlayStation 3 and Xbox 360 versions to come at the same time. An Ubisoft rep later confirmed that the delay was strictly a business decision to accommodate the added platforms and has nothing to do with development issues since the Wii U version was ready to go. No details have been provided yet how the ports will handle the Wii U-specific features, if they are included at all.To soften the blow for those who had been anticipating the impending release of the game on Wii U, Ubisoft Montpellier's Micheal Micholic and Michel Ancel appeared in a video on Ubisoft's Facebook page announcing that they would be releasing the games challenge mode exclusively on the Wii U eShop in early April to make up for the delay. The Rayman Legends Challenges App contains the fully featured challenge mode from the main game including online leaderboards, ghost data and Wii U exclusive levels. Initially, the team said they were working on a second demo for the eShop but instead they chose to release the full standalone challenge mode for all Wii U users to download for free.PC System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows XP SP3Processor: Intel Pentium® IV @ 3.0 GHz or AMD Athlon® 64 3000 +Memory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: nVidia GeForce 6800GT or AMD Radeon X1950 Pro 256MB VRAM with Shader Model 3.0Hard Drive: 6 GB available spaceSound Card: DirectX Compatible Sound Card with latest driversRecommendedOS: Windows 7Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo E4400 @ 2.0 GHz or AMD Athlon64 X2 3800+@ 2 GHzMemory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: nVidia GeForce 9600GT or higher, AMD Radeon HD3850 or higher 512MB VRAM with Shader Model 4.0Hard Drive: 6 GB available spaceSound Card: DirectX Compatible Sound Card with latest driversAdditional Notes: Windows-compatible keyboard and mouse required, optional Microsoft XBOX360 controller or compatible</description><genres><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/82063/2539437-raymanlegendsclean.jpg</image></root>