<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38173</id><name>Sonic &amp; All-Stars Racing Transformed</name><description>OverviewSonic  All-Stars Racing Transformed is a sequel to Sonic and Sega All-Stars Racing. The game's newest feature is that each vehicle can now transform into three different types of transportation. New characters include Skies of Arcadia hero Vyse, and Gilius Thunderhead from the Golden Axe series. One of the more unusual character inclusions is that of real-life NASCAR racer Danica Patrick. There are more than twenty five characters with most of them having a different home track. Up to four players (or five on Wii U) can play at once in the game's campaign or dedicated multiplayer modes including online play.The PC version uses Steam for achievements and online play.CharactersRacerFranchiseAGESSegaAiAiSuper Monkey BallAlex KiddAlex KiddAmigoSamba De AmigoAmy RoseSonic the HedgehogAvatar (Xbox 360 Exclusive)Xbox 360B.D. JoeCrazy TaxiBeatJet Set RadioDanica PatrickNASCARDr. RobotnikSonic the HedgehogFootball Manager (PC Exclusive)Football ManagerGeneral Winter (PC Exclusive)Company of Heroes 2Gilius ThunderheadGolden AxeGumJet Set RadioJoe MusashiShinobiKnucklesSonic the HedgehogMee MeeSuper Monkey BallMetal Sonic (Wii U and Bonus Edition Exclusive) (DLC)Sonic the HedgehogMii (Wii U Exclusive)NintendoNiGHTSNightsPuddingSpace Channel 5RealaNightsRalphWreck-It RalphShadow the HedgehogSonic the HedgehogShogun (PC Exclusive)Shogun: Total WarSonic the HedgehogSonic the HedgehogTailsSonic the HedgehogSpy, Heavy, Pyro (PC Exclusive)Team FortressUlalaSpace Channel 5VyseSkies of ArcadiaWillemus (PC Exclusive)Total War: Rome IICourse ListDragon CupCourse NameFranchiseOcean ViewSonic the HedgehogSamba StudiosSamba De AmigoCarrier ZoneAfter BurnerDragon CanyonPanzer DragoonRogue CupCourse NameFranchiseTemple TroubleSuper Monkey BallGalactic ParadeSonic the HedgehogSeasonal ShrinesShinobiRogue's LandingSkies of ArcadiaEmerald CupCourse NameFranchiseDream ValleyNightsChilly CastleBilly Hatcher and the Giant EggGraffiti CityJet Set RadioSanctuary FallsSonic the HedgehogArcade CupCourse NameFranchiseGraveyard GigHouse of the DeadAdder's LairGolden AxeBurning DepthsBurning RangersRace of AgesSegaClassic CupCourse NameFranchiseSunshine TourSamba De AmigoShibuya DowntownJet Set RadioRoulette RoadSonic the HedgehogEgg HangarSonic the HedgehogDownloadable Tracks/Bonus TracksCourse NameFranchiseOutrun BayOutrunArena TracksCourse NameFranchiseNeon DocksSonic the HedgehogBattle BayAfter BurnerCreepy CourtyardHouse of the DeadRooftop RumbleJet Set RadioMonkey Ball ParkSuper Monkey BallGame ModesThere are a number of game modes that can be used in all of the game's tracks.Race CoursesArena CoursesRace CoursesArena CoursesRace CoursesArena CoursesArena CoursesVersion DifferencesPCFootball Manager, Shogun, and Team Fortress team are playable.The only version capable of running at 60 frames per second.There is no Bonus Edition of the PC version, leaving Metal Sonic and the Outrun Downloadable track as DLC only.Uses Steam for online support such as achievements and online play.Playstation 3No distinct differences from the other versions.Xbox 360Avatars are playable once unlocked.Wii UThe Wii U Game Pad provides a map on the screen.Miis are playable once unlocked.Up to five players can play on one console with one player on the Game Pad.If there is no player on the Game Pad, it turns into a map that can also provide a rear view if held up to the screen. It also shows a chase cam for items that are fired at other players. It also shows which player is in what place and what item they are holding. When playing with more than one player, the map will center around the lead human player.The Game Pad also provides for off-TV play by sliding down on the touch screen. Slide back up to return the screen to the TV.Motion controls can be used with Wii Remotes or the Wii U Game Pad.Contains two Party Game modes Ninja Tag and Banana Heist exclusive to this version. Neither mode can be played online however.Metal Sonic and the Outrun DLC are provided for free as the Wii U version does not support microtransactions.Playstation VitaEach race goes up to eight opponents as opposed to 10 on console versions.You cannot play World Tour mode with friends.Nintendo 3DSThis version is built from the ground-up separate from the other versions of the game.As a result, characters and tracks have lower detail due to system performance.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="31747">Mario Kart 7</game><game id="15990">Diddy Kong Racing</game><game id="5561">Diddy Kong Racing DS</game><game id="16588">Freaky Flyers</game><game id="18126">Kinetica</game><game id="41500">Mario Kart: Arcade GP DX</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2348795-box_saasrt.png</image></root>