<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38196</id><name>Yatagarasu</name><description>OverviewYatagarasu is a 2D fighting game developed by PDW/Hodapen for release in Japan in 2011. The game is available digitally for PC and physical copies can sometimes be obtained via the game's website. The game is highly reminiscent of Capcom's Street Fighter III: 3rd Strike, having had its development heavily advised upon by several high-profile Japanese 3rd Strike players.Versus screen featuring Shimo and Chadha.The game features a six-button control layout and assigns two of these buttons to high and low parry. Much like the Capcom games it is influenced by, Yatagarasu also features special moves, normal move cancels, super moves, super move cancels, and long, damaging combos.The game's animation style is also heavily influenced by Capcom's later 2D fighters, and features lavishly animated 2D sprite work, although the number of characters in Yatagarasu is considerably lower than any of those games.One notable feature of Yatagarasu is the ability to unlock match commentary by famed Japanese 3rd Strike players and commentators such as Tokido, KSK, and Kokujin. These announcer voices are unlocked via the game's arcade mode and replace the game's default announcer voice with each player's unique, boisterous Japanese match commentary.GameplayYatagarasu's gameplay can be described as deliberate compared to the games it is influenced by, with an emphasis on spacing and proper use each character's normal moves. Every normal move in the game is super cancellable, which can lead to extreme amounts of damage being dealt at mid-range via option selecting supers behind each poke. Throws are performed with light punch and light kick, and feature a whiff animation. Parrying is unique in that because it is mapped to a set of buttons, parries can be performed from crouch block at little risk; this can make predictable attacks very risky but also creates opportunities to throw opponents who fish for parries. The game also features universal overhead attacks that are performed in the same manner as those found in the Street Fighter III series.</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1615">Street Fighter III: 3rd Strike</game><game id="21948">Street Fighter III: New Generation</game><game id="22305">Street Fighter III: 2nd Impact</game><game id="1251">Super Street Fighter II Turbo</game><game id="22574">Melty Blood</game><game id="16793">Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/6685/2195732-dnjqj.jpg</image></root>