<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38206</id><name>The Elder Scrolls Online</name><description>The first online game in the Elder Scrolls franchise will cover the entire continent of Tamriel and feature three distinct player factions. Players will choose a faction and clash with the other two factions, the Empire and the Daedric Prince Molag Bal in an attempt to take control of the Imperial City of Cyrodil and stop Nirn from becoming merged with Oblivion. The Elder Scrolls Online will be a subscription based game consisting of purchasing the game with the first 30 days being free and $14.99, 12.99 Euros, and 8.99 Pounds per month. FactionsThe game features three distinct player factions each with three member races.Daggerfall CovenantThe Daggerfall Covenant consists of the Bretons, Redguard, and Orcs. The covenant is ruled by the Kings of High Rock which is lead by High King Emeric in Wayrest. The Kings of High Rock is an alliance by marriage of the Redguard and by extension a war treaty with the Orcs.The Daggerfall Covenant controls northwest Tamriel with a strong hold on High Rock and footholds in both Skyrim and Hammerfell.Aldmeri DominionThe Aldmeri Dominion consists of the High Elves, Wood Elves, and Khajiit. The Dominion is an alliance formed by the High Elves of Summerset who reached out to neighboring races when they learned of the fate of the Imperial City. They are led by Queen Ayrenn on the Altmer throne in Summerset. The Aldmeri Dominion has a tight hold on Summerset Isle with a strong foothold in Valenwood.Ebonheart PactThe Ebonheart Pact consists of the Nord, Dark Elves, and Argonians. Their alliance was forced by invasion of the Akavari slavemasters. They are lead by the governance of The Great Moot, a council of all three races lead by High King Jorunn of Eastern Skyrim. The Ebonheart Pact holds Morrowind with a foothold in Skyrim.</description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="24205">Star Wars: The Old Republic</game><game id="21223">Guild Wars 2</game><game id="10796">EverQuest</game><game id="27218">Two Worlds II</game><game id="41696">Deep Down</game><game id="41484">The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt</game><game id="35398">Dragon Age: Inquisition</game><game id="19783">World of Warcraft</game><game id="12376">The Lord of the Rings Online: Shadows of Angmar</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/176/2237362-clickhandler.ashx.jpg</image></root>