<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38327</id><name>Gone Home</name><description>OverviewGone Home is a first-person exploration game with adventure and visual novel elements from The Fullbright Company. The game is available for PC, Mac, and Linux; it was released via Steam on August 15, 2013.StoryIn the summer of 1995, a young woman named Kaitlin Greenbriar arrives at her family's new home after traveling in Europe for a year. When she finds the house deserted, Kaitlin begins searching the mansion, hoping to find out what happened to her parents and sister.GameplayGone Home is a first-person exploration game, in which the player is free to roam the halls of a large house. The game provides no explicit goals nor direct guidance as to where to explore.There is no combat and little in the way of traditional puzzles. The main method of interaction is exploring the house, moving and examining objects and reading notes and books. Finding certain notes activates pieces of narration, similar to audio logs.DevelopmentThe development of Gone Home is led by Steve Gaynor. In May 2012, he appeared in a Giant Bomb video interview to discuss the founding of The Fullbright Company and the early development of the game. Gaynor names "immersive simulations" such as System Shock, Deus Ex, and Bioshock as inspiration for Gone Home's first-person exploration, although his game has no enemies or combat. Another source of inspiration is the practice of urban exploration.The music is written by close friend of the company, Chris Remo.On February 16th, 2013, Johnnemann Nordhagen, co-founder of The Fullbright Company, revealed on twitter that "Sassy Magazine" was used as a major research feature. This statement was later confirmed by Steve Gaynor.System RequirementsPCMinimumWindows XP SP2 or higher1.80GHz Processor2GB MemoryIntel HD Graphics 40002GB HDD spaceMacMinimumOS X v10.7 Lion or higher1.80GHz Processor2GB MemoryIntel HD Graphics 40002GB HDD spaceLinuxMinimumglibc 2.11 or newer1.80GHz Processor2GB MemoryIntel HD Graphics 40002GB HDD space</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="41506">The Vanishing of Ethan Carter</game><game id="11546">Scratches</game><game id="38450">Among The Sleep</game><game id="33629">Dear Esther</game><game id="16298">The 7th Guest</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/30/2525683-2377481-gonehome_title.jpg</image></root>