<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38437</id><name>Castlevania: Lords of Shadow - Mirror of Fate</name><description>OverviewCastlevania: Lords of Shadow - Mirror of Fate (known in Japan as Castlevania: Lords of Shadow - Sadame no Makyou) is a 2.5D action-adventure platformer developed by MercurySteam and published by Konami for the Nintendo 3DS (in both retail and eShop form) on March 5, 2013. It is the follow-up game to Castlevania: Lords of Shadow, building up events for Castlevania: Lords of Shadow 2 while establishing the series' most prominent characters (in a surprising way) for the "Lords of Shadow" continuity.The gameplay mixes the combat engine of Castlevania: Lords of Shadow with the platforming of earlier 2D Castlevania games (such as Super Castlevania IV) and Metroidvania exploration of later 2D Castlevania games (such as Castlevania: Symphony of the Night).The game is set decades after Gabriel Belmont, a holy knight in the Brotherhood of Light, defeated the Lords of Shadow and The Forgotten One (while turning into a dark and powerful vampire, known as "Dracula"). Split into four Acts, players take control of four different protagonists in three different time periods:In the short Prologue chapter (set in 1046, a year prior to the events of Castlevania: Lords of Shadow), players control Gabriel as he sets out towards an unknown castle to capture a powerful monster known as the Daemon Lord. Unbeknown to him, his wife Marie (who is shown Gabriel's dark fate through a fragment of the Mirror of Fate) bears a child, Trevor, who is kept hidden from Gabriel in the Brotherhood of Light.In Act I (set in 1101), players control Simon Belmont, son of Trevor and a powerful barbarian (as he was raised by people native to the mountains following the disappearance of his father and the death of his mother at a young age). Armed with his leather whip (the Beast Hunter), he sets towards Dracula's castle to seek vengence for the fate of his parents.In Act II (set during the same time as Act I), players control Alucard, a mysterious vampire knight who awakens from a tomb in Dracula's castle unknown of his past. After learning his fate from the Mirror of Fate, he must traverse the castle to find and destroy his father (Dracula).In Act III (set in 1073), players control Trevor Belmont, a holy knight in the Brotherhood of Light, the son of Gabriel, and the father of Simon (alongside his wife, Sypha). After learning from the Brotherhood that his mother was murdered by his father, he ventures towards his father's castle to vanquish him.Along the way, Simon, Alucard, and Trevor encounter a mysterious figure (known as the Lost Soul), who advises and assists the protagonists throughout the game (while giving them information about their fate). Simon and Alucard also encounter monsters constructed by an evil villain known as the Toy Maker.HD VersionAfter being heavily rumored for a long time, it was finally confirmed that an HD version of Mirror of Fate will be available on XBLA and PSN on October 31, 2013.</description><genres><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21178">Ninja Gaiden: Dragon Sword</game><game id="31242">El Shaddai: Ascension of the Metatron</game><game id="20592">God of War: Chains of Olympus</game><game id="20710">Bayonetta</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/82063/2560038-castlevaniaclean.jpg</image></root>