<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38458</id><name>Ratchet &amp; Clank: Full Frontal Assault</name><description>Also known as Ratchet and Clank: QForce in Australia and Europe.OverviewTed Price who is the CEO of Insomniac Games announced the game on May the 30th 2012. Ted said that it would be available for download exclusively on the Playstation store. It would be a return to form and control like classic Ratchet and Clank games did. It would also be co-op and have online play, it would be the 11th instalment in this long running franchise.BetaA private beta was run for Playstation + members from late August to the 9th of September, codes were later give out from Insomniac games and the Playstation Network. It collected various data and featured one playable map.PlotThe game puts you and your team back in The Q-Force, who have not made an appearance since Ratchet and Clank 3. (Or Deadlocked/Gladiator but it was never mentioned.) The team members present are Ratchet, Clank, Captain Qwark, The Plumber, Barry (Starship Phoenix II's AI) and three Robot's Blip, Bleep and Bloop. Things are quiet in the galaxy, until you are approached by Sergeant Zurgo, he expressed a hatred for Captain Qwark and vowed to take him down.Zurgo had taken over the defence system for multiple planets, The Q-Force went to these planets and took them back, admits all of this Zurgo revealed himself to be Stuart Zergo. Stuart Zergo was the Q-Force fan that you encountered in Ratchet and Clank: Going Commando , Stuart used to idolise the Captain, but after he discovered Qwark was not the hero he thought he was. He then set out on a mission to kill Qwark.The team found a distress call on a small planet, when they got there they found The Plumber. He needed help fixing something, however The Plumber didn't know anything about The Q-Force. When they got back to the Phoenix they discovered that The Plumber on the ship was Zergo in a Hologuise. He then used a Hologuise to make himself Captain Qwark, he rang up the emergency services declaring that he was about to take down a planets defence system.The team set off to take him down, they met him and bested him at planet Balkai. He was then taken by Qwark, who then dropped him into a fiery pit accidentally.GameplayThe single player is a mixture of tower defence, exploration and shooting. You start off in your base, you set off into the planet finding weapon pods and killing enemies, every so often you will be told that there are enemies coming to your base to destroy your power cores. Once all your power cores are destroyed thats the end, you can spend bolts of barriers and turrets and over defences to keep enemies away. Your job is to get to follow the objectives until you can retake the planets defence system.MultiplayerThe multiplayer has 1V1 and 2V2, one team starts on one base and the other team on the other base. Each base is the same as in the single player, but throughout the map are node points which can be taken furing the first stage which is the recon stage, In this stage you (And your teamate) will try and take as many nodes as you can or stop your enemys taking nodes. Then after a few miniutes the squad phase will start, this phase gives you accsess to the enemy selection screen. In which you can spend bolts on enemys that you can send to the enemy base to attack it, throughout your base you can also again get turrets and barriers.Then the assualt phase starts, in this phase the main barrier to your base is down so your enemys can charge your base and attack, so can you. Nodes can not be taken during this time, but you can clear out the enemys surronding the nodes to make it eaiser to take them once the recon phase starts again. This will keep going on untill all the generators in your base has been destroyed or untill you destroyed theres, if you take too long Full Frontal Assualt phase starts, this is the assualt phase but it will not go back to any other phase.If you win a match you are given points that will increase your rank, the more points you have it will better indicate how good at the game you are. The game can also be played co-op, the single player seems to have been designed with this in mind as it does not scale down if you are playing solo. The game is beatable solo but very difficult.Cross PlayThe game is one of the game that features Cross Play Support, so you can fight against somebody on the Vita version through the PS3 version and vice versa. It is also apart of Sony's Cross Buy program so if you get the PS3 version you get the Vita version for free.The Vita version is not currently available but will be out in Spring 2013, and when released those who download it on day 1 will also receive Ratchet: Deadlocked for free. DLCThere is a whole batch of DLC for people who want skins to use in multiplayer, the skins are in a three pack and themed. So the classic pack features Helga, The Plumber and the Hotbot. Early next year we will see Metropolis come as free DLXC as a new map.WeaponsThe weapons of this game are a collection of past favorites, including:CombusterBuzz BladesPyro BlasterCryoshotDoppelbangerWarmongerPlasmabomb LauncherGroovitronMr. ZurkonSonic EruptorThundersmackBase DefensesWhile building up defenses, a player can choose from the following:Turrets:Combuster TurretPyro TurretWarmonger TurretCry TurretMines:Chrono MinePlasma MineGroovitron MineTransmorpher MineBarriers:Versa BarrierHeavy BarrierElectro BarrierGadgetsThere is also a small collection of gadgets that have returned for this game:Hover BootsGrind BootsSwingshotHacker </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20700">Brütal Legend</game><game id="35545">Fuse</game><game id="43219">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Into the Nexus</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2371664-box_racffa.png</image></root>