<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38466</id><name>Guardians of Middle-earth</name><description>OverviewGuardians of Middle-earth is a  MOBA-style game developed by  Monolith Productions, set in  J.R.R. Tolkien's  Lord of the Rings universe. Players participate in online objective-based competitive multiplayer matches, with the ultimate goal being the destruction of the opposing teams base, or the highest score after time expires.The game is a 5 vs 5 team-based effort played from an  isometric point of view, with each team made up of a mix of good and evil characters from the LotR fiction. Players may choose a game mode that will auto-fill empty slots with AI bots if there are not enough players to start a match. Each player chooses a Guardian that has unique abilities and attacks, and players work together to move across the map to the other team's base to destroy it. There is also a Survival Mode where up to five players take on waves of enemies trying to destroy their towers.VersionsThe game is available digitally via PSN or XBLM for $15, and at retail on PS3 for $30. The downloadable version excludes eight of the Guardians and the Survival Mode, which is all locked behind DLC (but available as a bundle with the season pass), while the retail copy includes this content in the package.The Season Pass is available for $15, and includes 8 Guardians and 1 game mode:BilboBertGreat GoblinThorinRadagastGloinBarrow-wight LordSnagaSurvival Game Mode GameplayThe game begins with each team starting in their base positioned in their half of the map. Various paths or "lanes" connect each base (there are 1-lane maps and 3-lane maps). The lanes are populated with towers, each protecting their corresponding teams half of the map. The player controlled "Guardians" move across the map eliminating towers and battling enemies with the ultimate goal of reaching and destroying the enemies base.The Guardians are aided by smaller AI controlled warriors that spawn in waves from fortifications called Barracks located at the bases, positioned at the mouth of each lane. These warriors are much weaker than the Guardians, but will spawn endlessly and march down their respective lane, automatically attacking enemy towers and drawing fire. As the round progresses and players level up their Guardians, they are also able to upgrade their towers and barracks to make them stronger. LoadoutsSelecting relics  gems in the loadout.Players are given loadout slots which they select in the lobby after selecting a Guardian. Loadouts are not Guardian specific, rather they can be matched with any character of their choosing. Loadouts consist of a number of different customizable options:BeltEach loadout has a "belt" in which Relics can be placed. Relics grant the players certain boosts to their abilities, health, speed, etc. Relics hold Gems, and the specific Gems slotted in the Relics are what determines the exact value of these boosts.CommandsCommands are very strong modifiers that have a temporary impact on a character's attributes, but have a much longer cooldown time, often 3-4 minutes or more. These commands can quickly save a player from death, or even deal a fatal blow during battle. When used properly, Commands can be a great asset to players.PotionsPotions are single use buffs that players can use at any time. Potions can grant any number of boosts, such as health, resiliency, etc. Once used they are gone for good, and new ones must be purchased in between matches...but since they are single use they typically cost less coins to purchase. PersistenceAlthough in-game Guardian levels reset before each match, the game does feature persistent leveling, awarding players XP and coins (and sometimes relics and gems) at the end of each match. As players level up, they unlock access to more commands, potions  loadout slots, all of which can be purchased using coins.If a player reaches maximum rank, they are even given the option to Prestige. GuardiansThere are dozens of playable Guardians to choose from, but only a handful are immediately available to new players. Additional Guardians are unlocked via either in-game currency or paid DLC.Each Guardian has one single basic attack, and four unique "Abilities," which can range from area of effect attacks,  buffs for teammates, speed boosts, or other various effects. These Abilities all have cooldown timers, but they are fairly short. As players level up their Guardian by destroying towers and killing opposing units, they put upgrade points towards increasing the power of these abilities. These in-match levels are not persistent, and reset before each match.Each Guardian belongs to one of five classes; Warrior, Enchanter, Defender, Striker, and Tactician. These classes give the player an idea what kind of abilities  play style they have. Defenders for example have more defensive attributes, such as healing  shielding teammates, where Warriors have more offensive abilities, such as attack power and shields. Enchanters have more magic based attacks, Tacticians typically have access to traps, and Strikers use speed and stealth to surprise their enemies.EnchantersAgandaur Dark Assault - Teleport, Damaging and RootingNorthern Bolt - Lightning attack with Ability DamageOvercharge - Enhances other Abilities, increases PenetrationShockwave - Area attack with Damage and SlowingBarrow-wight Lord Barrow's Torment - Damages Enemies initially and over timeChilling Touch - Reduces Enemy Guardian or Creature Attack Speed while increasing ownDrain the Soul - Life Steals from a single targetUndeath - Passive death Immunity, Teleport and Damage an Enemy while undeadGandalf Narya's Power - Blinds and damages EnemiesFireworks - Damages and Silences Enemies in an areaFlame of Anor - Creates Shield and reveals EnemiesGandalf's Might - Damages and Stuns a single Enemy Lugbol Ashen Wolf - Summons a wolf that Damages and TauntsFiery Grasp - Inflicts Damage and KnockupSnuff Them Out - Damages Enemies while restoring HealthFurious Flames - Line attack with True Damage and Blind Ori As It Is Written - Marks and Damages nearby EnemiesAncient History - Creates Damage ShieldLast Word - Damages nearby EnemiesDirge of Durin - Damages or Stuns nearby Enemies  Radagast Vibrant Glade - Increased Attack Speed, Reduced Controlling EffectsWhispering Leaves - Deals Ability Damage, briefly SilencesBlackbird Song - Deals True Damage and Blinds Enemy Guardians and CreaturesRoots of Greenwood - Roots Enemies, slows and deals Ability Damage Saruman Focused Magic - Stuns Enemy Guardian, deals area Ability DamageSpies of Saruman - Reveals, Slows and deals Ability Damage over TimeBurst Shield - Shield that detonates for area Ability Damage and SilencePower of the White Wizard - Channeled Ability Damage over Time DefendersEowyn Shieldmaiden - Shields self and nearby AlliesKnow My Fury - Roots nearby EnemiesGreat Renown - Heals Allies at the cost of own HealthI Am No Man - Damages targets and stuns all enemies Galadriel Golden Gaze - Causes Damage and Fear to nearby EnemiesLothlórien Grove - Damages Enemies, Heals Allies, all StealthPower of Nenya - Pulls, Stuns, and Slows close range EnemiesEvening Star - Restores Ally Health at the cost of own Great Goblin Dizzying Smash - Area attack that deals Damage and lowers ResistancesRamming Oppression - Target area attack with DamageAncestral Will - Restore Health and become immune to Damage for a brief timeGoblin Insult - Leap attack with Knockup, Damage and TauntMouth of Sauron Dark Shout - Medium range attack with Damage and FearWill of Sauron - Roots Enemy Guardian at Medium Range while draining the victim's HealthDeceitful Ways - Lifesteals and gains temporary InvulnerabilityStream of Lies - Area attack with Silence, Slow, and Ability Damage Witch King Malice - Causes Damage in area and improves next attackDespair - Slows a targeted Enemy and nearby EnemiesDarkness - Taunts an Enemy and Reflects DamageDeath - Causes Damage and reduces Enemy Healing  Wulfrun Arcane Arts - Shields self and Allies, removes Controlling EffectsWretched Vapors - Area effect that Damages and Knocks Enemies awayDefensive Chaos - Heals nearby AlliesDark Forces - Reduce Ally Cooldowns, enhance own Abilities StrikersBilbo Attercop! Attercop! - Damages and Taunts an EnemyGaffer's Home Cider - Attack Speed and Critical Hit chance increasesHobbit Sense - Enter Stealth for a brief timeSting - Teleport, Damages an Enemy, Immune to Root Frodo Heavy Burden - Gains Stealth at the cost of his HealthMithril Mail - Frodo briefly Shields himself and gains ResistancesLight of Eärendil - Blinds and Stuns nearby EnemiesSting's Bite - Damages and Slows an enemy Gollum Throttle - Single target attack with Damage and SilenceWe Are Starved - Roots an Enemy, causes Damage and Heals selfMy Precious - Defeat an Enemy with Damage and Attack SpeedCoward - Removes Controlling Effects and increases Movement Haldir Forest Sprint - Movement and Attack Speed IncreasesSea of Arrows - Area attack that inflicts Damage and Roots EnemiesTree Top Ambush - Teleports and Stuns on next attackWrath of the Elves - Ranged attack with high Damage Kili Wound - True Damage and Arrow that Stuns Guardians and CreaturesFlare - Blinds, then Reveals Stealthed or hidden Enemies in a small areaScout - Tumbles and clears himself of Controlling Affects, Movement increase if enemy markedMake it Count - True Damage and Slows Enemy GuardiansLegolas Silvan Agility - Teleport, Invisibility, increases Move SpeedWoodland Shot - Range attack causing Ability Damage, SlowGreenwood Blades - Damages, Roots, and Slows Enemies in close rangeElven Onslaught - Knockback, Ability Damage, reduces Resistances Snaga A Mouthful - Deals Damage and gains HealthRavenous - Stuns a marked targetFamished - Extra Damage and Resistances, Weakness against marked Enemy GuardianSalivate - Marks enemy Guardian and gains Movement and Attack SpeedUnglob Stick - Damages, Blinds, and Pulls Enemies closerHunt - Increases own Movement Speed, clears Controlling Affects, and is briefly invulnerableDrain - Persistent area that Slows and DamagesBite - Lifesteal, Damages and Stuns Enemy TacticiansBert Bonfire - Fire that Damages Enemies and TowersSpirits - Increase Movement Speed and ResistancesMutton - Pull, Stun and Damage EnemyStumbling Rage - Area attack with Fear and Damage Elrond Call of Rivendell - Increases Movement and Attack Speeds, DamageTake Refuge - Area effect increases Health and ResistancesElven Grace - Damages Enemies and give Stealth to AlliesHonored Guard - Summons an archer to Damage and Slow Enemies Felgrom Lob! - Area ranged attack with Damage and StunBurn! - Trades Damage to Enemies for loss of HealthTrap! - Explosive trap with Damage and KnockupKa-boom! - Sacrifice self to destroy Enemies Gothmog Black Land Banner - Trap that draws Enemy fireGrond's Blow - Rush attack with Knockup, Damage and StunWar-machine - Trebuchet that fires at EnemiesRain of Doom - Area attack that damages Enemy units and Structures Hildifons Dwarven-fire Flask - Deals Damage and reduces ResistanceTook's Wall - Trap that Damages and BlindsBrandywine Barbs - Trap that Damages and Slows EnemiesHalfling's Trap - Timed trap deals True Damage and Knockback Nori Dwarven Onslaught - Increase Basic Damage of nearby AlliesFortitude - Increases Allied Resistances, Slows EnemiesMan the Walls! - Nearby units and Structures gain ResistanceSwift Blow - Teleport then Damage Structures Runsig Catapult of Angmar - Catapult with increasing range, damage, HealthUnbending - Creates Shields for Allies and StructuresForceful Call - Increases Movement Speed and Health for nearby AlliesMarch of the Northmen - Speed increases for Allies and Structures  WarriorsArathorn Staggering Shot - Ranged attack with Ability Damage and StunChieftain's Focus - Damages Guardian or Creature, increases own Attack SpeedDúnedain Blade - Area attack that Damages and Slows EnemiesRanger's Strike - Damages and Slows Enemies, enter StealthBeregond Guard of the Citadel - Area attack with Damage and SilenceShield of Gondor - Shield that absorbs Damage and increases Movement SpeedTurning of the Tide - Deals Damage while removing Controlling EffectsNoble Sacrifice - Taunts Enemy Guardians and CreaturesGloin A Bit of Fire - Damages nearby Enemies and gives Glóin hasteDwarven Stubborness - Increased Resistances and lights Enemies on fire that strike himDurin's Line - Damages all Enemies in a Target AreaMighty Axe - Medium range area attack with Damage and Stun Mozgog Berserker Rage - Increases own Movement and Attack Speeds, HealthBrutal Draught - Trades Health for increased DamageVile Taunt - Taunts Enemies and reflects damageBloodied Blade - Area attack with Damage and Fear  Sauron Might of Barad-dûr - Target Area attack, Ability Damage, KnockbackShadow Walk - Teleport and gain StealthDark Lord's Reach - Damages and Roots a single EnemyThe Lidless Eye - Reveal, Damage, then inflict Fear  Thorin Wrath - Increase Movement and Attack SpeedsRevenge - Melee attack causing Ability and True Damage, can deal a Critical HitOakenshield - Creates a Shield and reduces Enemy Attack SpeedHeart of the Mountain - Increase Critical Hit chance Thrain Hammer Throw - Damages and Slows Enemies with ranged attackLethal Blow - Causes True Damage and Roots EnemiesDwarven Valor - Reduces Controlling Effects and DamageDurin’s Wrath - Reduce Resistances, Knocks Enemies into air  Ugluk Charge of the Uruk-hai - Roots target and causes Fear on nearby EnemiesOrcish Medicine - Regain Health at the cost of Attack SpeedWhite Hand's Whip - Damages, Slows and Knocks Enemy into airFury of Isengard - Single target attack with Damage and Knockback System RequirementsMinimumOS: 32-bit: Windows Vista, Windows 7, Windows 8 Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo, 2.4 GHz | AMD Athlon X2, 2.8 GHz or better Memory: 2 GB RAM Graphics: NVIDIA GeForce 8800 GTS | AMD Radeon 3850 or better DirectX: Version 10 Network: Broadband Internet connection Hard Drive: 8 GB available space Additional Notes: Windows XP and DirectX® 9.0c and below not supportedRecommendedOS: 64-bit: Windows Vista, Windows 7, Windows 8 Processor: Intel Core i5 750, 2.67 GHz | AMD Phenom II X4 965, 3.4GHz or better Memory: 4 GB RAM Graphics: NVIDIA GeForce GTX 560 | AMD Radeon HD 6950 or better DirectX: Version 11 Network: Broadband Internet connection Hard Drive: 8 GB available space Additional Notes: Windows XP and DirectX® 9.0c and below not supported</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="42065">Infinite Crisis</game><game id="24024">League of Legends</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2369635-wbi_192_atlas_xbox_pkg_m09_cropped.jpg</image></root>