<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38485</id><name>Digital Combat Simulator: Combined Arms</name><description>OverviewRather than focusing on a single aircraft, this addition to the Digital Combat Simulator series shifts attention to the ground, placing players in control of ground forces from either an overhead, real-time strategy perspective, or via direct control of a vehicle.FeaturesCombined Arms features four commander roles including:Ground CommandersJoint Terminal Attack Controller (JTAC)Game MastersObserversMission designers decide which of these roles will be available in their mission and how many multiplayer slots are allowed for each.The Command Map allows players to interact with the game like an RTS. From here, players set Rules of Engagement, formations, waypoints, and indirect fire missions. Units can also be told to follow roads.In addition, players can jump from the Command Map into most ground units and control them directly from a first-person perspective. Controllable units include:AAAShort Range SAMsTanksAPCsIFVsPlayers can give orders to other units while in the first-person role or while flying a DCS aircraft.Since the game is part of DCS World, Eagle Dynamics' unified DCS playing environment, multiplayer games can incorporate players using Combined Arms as well as Black Shark, A-10C Warthog, and P-51D Mustang simultaneously.System RequirementsRecommendedOperating system 64-bit: Windows Vista or 7Processor: Core 2 Duo E8400, AMD Phenom X3 8750, or betterMemory: 4GBHard disk space: 7 GBVideo: Shader 3.0 or better; 896MB NVIDIA GeForce GTX260 DirectX 9.0c or betterSound: DirectX 9.0c compatibleRequires internet activationMinimumOperating system: Windows XP, Vista, or 7Processor: Core 2 Duo 2.0 GHzMemory: 3 GBHard disk space: 7 GBVideo: 512 MB RAM card, DirectX 9 compatibleSound: DirectX 9.0c compatibleRequires internet activation</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16866">Battlefield 2</game><game id="16088">Battlezone</game><game id="17672">Battlezone II: Combat Commander</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/23546/2262003-box.jpeg</image></root>