<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38480</id><name>Injustice: Gods Among Us</name><description>OverviewSuperman vs Solomon Grundy.Injustice: Gods Among Us is a 2.5D fighting game developed by NetherRealm and published by WB Games for the Xbox 360, PlayStation 3, and Wii U on April 16, 2013. It is based on the DC Universe, filled with famous heroes and villains from various DC Comics franchises (such as Batman and Superman). It is also the second fighting game made by the team behind the Mortal Kombat franchise to feature characters from the DC Universe (the first being Mortal Kombat vs. DC Universe).In a plot involving parallel dimensions and shifting alliances, the game's storyline has various heroes and villains mysteriously transported into a near-future alternate universe where Superman has gone mad with power, establishing a new fascist regime known as One Earth (years after killing The Joker in cold blood, who previously destroyed Metropolis, along with Superman's love interest Lois Lane, in a nuclear blast). While most of the heroes (and some villains) have joined Superman's cause, others have formed a resistance, known as the Insurgency (led by that universe's Batman).GameplayHarley Quinn vs Batman.Though running on Unreal Engine 3, like Mortal Kombat, Injustice features a different control scheme including holding back to block rather than a block button as well as a dedicated button for interacting with the environments. This feature allows for the characters to perform maneuvers involving objects within the stage. However, different characters use the same environmental objects in different ways. A character with super strength like Solomon Grundy may pick up a car and smash an opponent with it, but someone like Batman would be unable to do so, and would instead smash his opponent's face into the hood of the car. There are three main attack buttons (light, medium, strong) and one "gimmick" button that performs character-specific tasks. For Wonder Woman, it performs a stance change between sword/shield and lasso. For Superman it burns a bit of meter to enhance damage for a set period of time.Additionally, stage transitions return from Mortal Kombat vs DC Universe, allowing players to move throughout various parts of each arena over the course of the fight. The game is expected to receive a T rating and will not feature Fatalities, but instead, elaborate and over-the-top super moves such as punching an opponent into space (which result in lethal injuries, otherwise known as Fatalities). The game will, however, feature a certain amount of blood as well as physical changes to characters to show damage.At EVO 2012, when a brief demo was shown explaining the classes of characters and some background-based mechanics, there appeared to be twenty four slots on the character select screen and fifteen slots on the arena select screen.StorySuperman and a select few other members of the Justice League have taken it upon themselves to rule over the planet Earth, as they have deemed humans unfit to govern themselves. Superman rules with an iron fist, using his massive army to keep the planet inline and to prevent crime no matter what the cost. Only Batman and his group of rebels dare to stand against this new regime in the hopes of freeing Earth from under the rule of the Man of Steel.The main story of Injustice is told through twelve individual character chapters following the characters the player chooses. The game begins with the Joker at the mercy of an enraged Superman as the psychotic clown basks in the his success of not only tricking Superman in to killing Lois Lane and their unborn child, but the complete annihilation of Metropolis by the hand of the Joker. Batman desperately attempts to calm Superman down, but ultimately his efforts prove fruitless as Superman punches the Joker through the chest.After that initial introduction the game cuts to the regular universe where the Joker hasn't detonated the bomb yet where a large scale battle is occuring between most of the heroes and villains in the game. The scene then cuts to Batman as he investigates the Joker's recent escape. After a battle with Deathstroke in Arkham the story moves forward to space and The Watchtower where Batman proceeds to fight Bane and Lex Luthor who are attempting to distract the Justice League while Joker sets up the nuke.Once the heroes realize the Joker's plot, they are quickly warped to Earth from the Watchtower in order to stop Joker. As Batman, Green Lantern, Green Arrow, Aquaman and Wonder Woman all speed towards the Joker to try and stop him, they are warped to the alternate universe, five years after the destruction of Metropolis. As in Mortal Kombat, once Batman's chapter ends control will switch to a new character to continue the story.CharactersThe game includes 24 playable characters, split up in the character select screen into heroes (left side) and villains (right side).Playable HeroesVoice ActorsAquamanPhil LaMarrBatmanKevin ConroyCyborgKhary PaytonThe FlashNeal McDonoughGreen ArrowMain: Alan Tudyk/Arrow: Stephen AmellGreen LanternHal: Adam Baldwin/John: Phil LaMarrHawkgirlJennifer HaleNightwingDick: Troy Baker/Damian: Neal McDonoughRavenTara StrongShazamJoey NaberSupermanGeorge NewbernWonder WomanSusan EisenbergPlayable VillainsVoice ActorsAresJ. G. HertzlerBaneFred TatascioreBlack AdamJoey NaberCatwomanGrey DeLisleDeathstrokeJ. G. HertzlerDoomsdayKhary PaytonHarley QuinnTara StrongThe JokerRichard EpcarKiller FrostJennifer HaleLex LuthorMark RolstonSinestroTroy BakerSolomon GrundyFred TatascioreDownloadable CharactersVoice ActorsLoboDavid SobolovBatgirlKimberly BrooksScorpion (Mortal Kombat)Patrick SeitzZodNolan NorthMartian ManhunterCarl LumblyZatannaLacey ChabertAlternate SkinsRegimeAquamanAresBaneBlack AdamCatwomanCyborgDoomsdayThe FlashGreen LanternHawkgirlKiller FrostNightwingRavenShazamSinestroSolomon GrundySupermanWonder WomanInsurgencyBatmanDeathstrokeGreen ArrowHarley QuinnThe JokerLex LuthorOtherAquaman: Flashpoint, Blackest NightAres: ClassicBane: Knightfall, LuchadorBatman: Arkham City, Batman Beyond, Blackest Night, New 52, Flashpoint, Red SonCatwoman: Arkham City, Selina Kyle, Ame-ComiCyborg: Teen TitansDeathstroke: Flashpoint, Teen Titans, Red SonDoomsday: Containment Suit, Blackest NightThe Flash: Elseworld, New 52, Blackest Night, Earth-2Green Arrow: The ArrowGreen Lantern: New 52, Yellow Lantern, Red Son, John StewartHarley Quinn: Arkham City, Classic, Ame-ComiHawkgirl: Blackest Night, Earth-2The Joker: Arkham City, Vacation, Final Confrontation, Red HoodLex Luthor: Kryptonite SuitNightwing: New 52Raven: Teen TitansShazam: New 52Solomon Grundy: Boss Grundy, Red Son,Earth-2Superman: Godfall, New 52, Lockdown, Red Son, Blackest Night, Cyborg Superman, Man of SteelWonder Woman: Flashpoint, Red Son, New 52, #600, Ame-ComiZod: Man of SteelStagesStageDescriptionArkham AsylumA psychiatric hospital that houses Gotham's most disturbed individuals, most of them put there by the Batman. This includes the likes of Killer Croc, The Penguin, The Riddler, Scarecrow and Two-Face, all of which will attack the fighters in this stage if they're not careful.AtlantisThe kingdom of Aquaman and home to the Atlantean people, this vast underwater city is ruled fairly by it's powerful king.BatcaveBatman's secret headquarters hidden deep within the caverns underneath Wayne Manor, and home to his vast array of gadgets, vehicles and mementos.Ferris AirwaysAn airfield located in Coast City, this is where Hal Jordan test pilots the many experimental aircraft designed by the aviation company Ferris Aircraft Inc.Fortress of SolitudeLocated within the Antarctic, this Kryptonian structure is the true home of Superman, and his main base of operations.Gotham CityThe home of Bruce Wayne, a crime infested city that must be defended night after night by the Dark Knight.Hall of JusticeFormer base of operations for many different Justice League teams, this landmark is the symbol of justice, and a monument to the heroes who have passed through it's halls. Features stage interactions with Giganta, Atom Smasher and Darkseid.Joker's AsylumArkham after being taken over by the Joker has fallen in to complete dissaray, with it's inmates running freely through it's halls.LexCorp HQThe home base of scientific mastermind Lex Luthor, where he spends his time running one of the Earth's largest corporations and plotting the death of Superman.MetropolisThe highly advanced city of Metropolis is a technological marvel and home to many heroes, most notably the Man of Steel himself.Stryker's Island PenitentiaryA maximum security prison for the worst of Metropolis' villain population, home to such supervillains as Parasite, Deadshot, Metallo and Gorilla Grodd.ThemysciraAlso known as Paradise Island, this island nation is the birthplace of Wonder Woman and her sisters the Amazons.WatchtowerLocated within the Earth's atmosphere, the scientific super-structure is the headquarters of the Justice League and many of Earth's mightiest heroes.Wayne Manor/ Wayne Manor (Night)The luxurious home of billionaire Bruce Wayne, this mansion has stood for decades as a Gotham City landmark.Special EditionsThe special editions detailed below were released for the PlayStation 3 and Xbox 360, while the Wii U only saw the release of the standard edition.Battle EditionPrice: US - $149.99The Battle Edition packaging includes an Injustice: Gods Among Us fightstick, as well as the 3 DLC skins also included in the Collector's Edition. According to a press release the fightstick "is a lightweight controller that boasts a non-skid foam underside, a lockout feature for the Start, Select and Guide buttons, as well as adjustable illumination for the buttons and joystick".This package will only be obtainable at EB Games and GameStop stores in the US and Canada.Collector's EditionsPrice: EU - £74.99/€99.99, US - $99.99The European and American Collector's Editions of the game vary slightly. The European package includes a steelbook and a "collector box", while the American version comes with a code for a Justice League movie download instead. The collector's figurine is also different in each version: the one in the European package has Batman grabbing Wonder Woman by the neck, while the American version has Wonder Woman grabbing Batman by the neck. A comic book based on the video-game will be included in both packages, as well as the 3 DLC skins also included in the Battle Edition. The two versions of the Collector's Edition are detailed below.EU Version.European VersionCollector's Edition BoxSteelbookInjustice Comic BookCollector's Figurine (23 cm)3 DLC Skins inspired by DC Comics' New 52American VersionUS Version.Digital Movie DownloadInjustice Comic BookCollector's Figurine3 DLC Skins inspired by DC Comics' New 52Special EditionPrice: UK - £42.99, AU - 79.95$AUDThe Special Edition includes the Red Son DLC Pack, and comes in a special edition red Steelbook. The pack includes three skins based on the Red Son Superman comic, as well as 20 additional missions set within the Red Son storyline.The Injustice: Gods Among Us Special Edition will be exclusive to EB Games stores in Australia and the UK.Pre-Order BonusesAs a bonus for pre-ordering, access will be granted to exclusive character skins and missions.Red Son PackRed Son DLC Pack Skins.Gamestop exclusive pre-order bonus based on the Red Son Superman comic.The Red Son pack includes alternate Red Son skins for Superman, Wonder Woman and Solomon Grundy.The pack also includes 20 additional missions based on the Red Son comic.Arkham City PackArkham City DLC Pack Skins.Wal-Mart exclusive pre-order bonus based on the game Batman: Arkham City.The Arkham City pack includes alternate Arkham City skins for Batman, The Joker and Catwoman.Blackest Night PackZombie Mode DLC.Best Buy exclusive pre-order bonus based on the Blackest Night comic.The Blackest Night pack includes a Black Lantern skin for Batman.The pack also includes a zombie mode where the fighters become undead.Downloadable ContentInjustice Season Pass.Injustice has a DLC Season Pass much like Mortal Kombat before it that ensures players access to the first four DLC characters upon their release and three skins based of the DC comics arc Flashpoint for the characters Wonder Woman, Aquaman and Deathstroke. The pass costs $14.99 and is now available for purchase.The characters that come with the pack are:LoboBatgirlScorpionZodiOS Card GameAt PAX East 2013, Injustice: Gods Among Us was announced for iOS devices. This is not a portable version of the console game, but actually a free-to-play collectable card-battle game. Players can sign in to their WBID accounts and unlock backgrounds, icons and costumes for the console version.Unlockables for ConsolesUnlockable Skins.There are many console items that can be unlocked in the ios version including; backgrounds, icons, portraits, and skins.Alternative skins include; Knightfall Bane, Batman Beyond, New 52 Green Lantern, Arkham Harley, and Prison Superman.System RequirementsMinimumRecommendedOS: 32-bit Windows 7 / Windows 8 / Vista OS: 64-bit Windows 7 / Windows 8 / Vista Processor: Intel® Core™ 2 Duo 2.4 GHz or AMD Athlon X2 2.8 GHzProcessor: Intel Core i5-750, 2.67 GHz or AMD Phenom II X4 965, 3.4 GHz or better Memory: 2 GB RAM Memory: 4 GB RAM Graphics: NVIDIA® GeForce™ 8800 GTS or AMD® Radeon™ HD 3850Graphics: NVIDIA® GeForce™ GTX 560 or AMD® Radeon™ HD 6950DirectX: Version 10DirectX: Version 11Network: Broadband Internet connectionNetwork: Broadband Internet connection</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25042">Mortal Kombat</game><game id="28437">Super Street Fighter IV</game><game id="32161">Street Fighter X Tekken</game><game id="35938">Ultimate Marvel vs. Capcom 3</game><game id="20449">Mortal Kombat vs. DC Universe</game><game id="30558">Sunday vs. Magazine: Shuuketsu! Choujou Daikessen</game><game id="34475">Hajime no Ippo: The Fighting!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2452962-box_ijgau.png</image></root>