<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38497</id><name>Need for Speed: Most Wanted</name><description>OverviewAn indirect sequel to both the original Need for Speed Most Wanted and Criterion's own Burnout Paradise, the game returns to the open world game play of the titles in the franchise, allowing the player to explore a large, modern city filled with events and shortcuts for the player to find. The stat tracking Autolog feature returns (which debuted in Need For Speed Hot Pursuit) keeping track of all accomplishments and comparing them to friends. Every vehicle in the game is unlocked from the start (with the exception of the top 10 most wanted racer's cars), requiring only that you find the vehicle first. This is a change from most other Need For Speed games, which usually had a system of classes for the player to work through to get progressively better cars along the way. The game's multiplayer is similar in structure to Burnout Paradise, giving players random events that start at different spots in the city that players have to complete either competitively or cooperatively.GameplayThe single player game immediately drops the player into the open world with the main task of beating the ten "Most Wanted" street racers in the City of "Fairhaven". In order to access these races, players must accumulate enough "Speed Points" to unlock them. Speed Points are gained by completing races, evading the cops, meeting objectives, taking down competitors and other various driving antics and maneuvers.Players can unlock additional cars by locating them within the city and simply pressing a button to get behind the wheel. Every car has its own set of progression, and unlocking each car's upgrades is done by winning races and completing objectives. Once discovered, these new cars are instantly accessible through the Easy Drive drop-down menu.The police play a large role in the single player game, pursuing the player if they see them do anything illegal, and are often integrated into race events. On higher alert levels, cops will set up road blocks and lay out spike strips. These obstacles are more easily overcome if the player has unlocked vehicles mods like re-inflating tires and heavy chassis, although there is virtually zero penalty for getting "busted."The game contains dozens of collectibles in the form of billboards to destroy, speed cameras for record-breaking competitions, and gates to smash through. When a player sets a record for distance during a billboard-smashing jump, their photo will be displayed on it for all their friends to see.MultiplayerThe multiplayer component of Most Wanted consists of up to eight players completing "Speedlists", which are sets of five events for players to compete in. Event types are highly variable; ranging from simple team-based checkpoint races, to things like all players meeting on top of a certain building, or collectively gathering a certain amount of "near misses" in a specific area. Players receive Speed Points for winning individual races, as well as for winning the full Speedlist.The game does not incorporate a lobby, and each event is immediately followed by another with the occasional "intermission" of a few minutes in-between events. All Speed Points for the player are shared between Single and Multiplayer, and as players win events and accumulate Speed Points, they unlock vehicle mods such as off-road tires, higher gears and other upgrades.Wii U VersionThe Wii U version of Need for Speed: Most Wanted utilizes the console's unique features in various ways. A new mode, called Co-Op Driver, is included in this version and it supports asymmetric gameplay functions in that it has one player racing with the Wii Remote or Wii U Pro Controller and another assisting with the GamePad by distracting cops, activating boosts, controlling traffic or selecting the time of day. Off-TV Play is supported by the game, as well. When players are not making use of that feature, the touch screen allows for instant access to carselection, tracking records or finding secrets around the city. The game also features Miiverse integration which ties directly into Autolog, displaying Mii characters on billboards and letting players post messages in Paradise mode.This version also includes the Ultimate Speed Pack (adding five new cars), which was available as $10 DLC on other platforms.On top of that, Need for Speed: Most Wanted on Wii U also features various graphical upgrades such as higher resolution textures from the PC version and improved lighting.Wii U Version DevelopmentCriterion had the game running on Wii U concurrently with the other versions and returned to it after those had shipped and everybody had actual hands on with the final retail system at home, Alex Ward of Vice President of Criterion said. The team had also been reading the various Iwata Asks interviews put out by Nintendo around the time of the system's launch to better understand the philosophy and really create a version of the game that is tailored to the system's strengths. Available CarsCar NameEngineHPW0-100 (s)Top Speed (km/h)ClassAlfa Romeo 4C Concept1.8-liter Turbocharged Straight-42005.0250SportsAriel Atom 5003.0-liter V85002.3281RaceAston Martin V12 Vantage6.0-liter V125104.1305SportsAudi A1 Clubsport quattro2.5-liter Straight-54963.7249CityAudi R8 GT Spyder5.2-liter V105683.8317SportsBAC Mono2.3-liter Straight-42802.8273RaceBentley Continental Supersports Convertible ISR6.0-liter W126404.0325Grand TourerBMW M3 E92 Coupé4.0-liter V84204.8249SportsBugatti Veyron 16.4 Super Sport8.0-liter Quad-Turbo W1612002.4431ExoticCaterham Superlight R5002.0-liter Straight-42632.8241RaceChevrolet Camaro ZL16.2-liter V85803.9296Muscle CarChevrolet Corvette ZR16.8-liter V86383.4330ExoticDodge Challenger SRT-8 3926.4-liter V84704.0293Muscle CarFord F-150 SVT Raptor5.4-liter V83207.2164SUVFord Focus RS5002.5-liter Straight-53505.6262CityFord Focus ST2.0-liter Straight-42526.7244CityFord GT5.4-liter V85503.7329ExoticFord Mustang Boss 302 (2012)5.0-liter V84444.0249Muscle CarHummer H1 Alpha6.6-liter Turbo Diesel V830013.5165SUVJaguar XKR5.0-liter V85104.6250SportsKoenigsegg Agera R5.0-liter Twin Turbo V811002.9418ExoticLamborghini Aventador LP 700-46.5-liter V127002.9349ExoticLamborghini Countach 5000 quattrovalvole4.7-liter V123754.9315SportsLamborghini Gallardo LP 570-4 Spyder Performante5.2-liter V105703.9323SportsLancia Delta HF Integrale Evoluzione 22.0-liter Turbocharged Straight-4 2125.7220CityLexus LFA4.8-liter V105523.6326ExoticMarussia B22.8-liter Turbocharged V64203.8249SportsMaserati GranTurismo MC Stradale4.7-liter V84604.4302Grand TourerMcLaren MP4-12C3.8-liter Twin Turbo V85923.1333ExoticMercedes-Benz SL65 AMG Black Series6.0-liter V126613.7320Muscle CarMercedes-Benz SLS AMG6.3-liter V85713.8317Grand TourerMitsubishi Lancer Evolution X2.0-liter Turbocharged Straight-43955.4249CityNissan GT-R (R35) Egoist3.8-liter Twin Turbo V65502.8315SportsPagani Huayra5.9-liter Twin Turbo V127203.3370ExoticPorsche 911 Turbo 3.03.8-liter Flat-65003.7312SportsPorsche 911 (991) Carrera S3.8-liter 6-Cylinder Boxer4004.3302SportsPorsche 918 Spyder Concept Study3.4-liter V8 plus 2 Electric Motors7183.2318ExoticPorsche Panamera Turbo4.8-liter Twin Turbo V85004.0303Grand TourerRange Rover Evoque2.0-liter Straight-42406.7217SUVShelby Cobra 4277.0-liter V84255.1262Muscle CarSRT Viper GTS8.4-liter V106403.3320Muscle CarSubaru Impreza Cosworth STI CS4002.5-liter Turbocharged Straight-43953.4349CityTesla Roadster Sport375 volt AC induction3003.7201SportsMost Wanted Top 10 ListNumberCarSP Needed10Alpha Romeo 4C Concept60,0009Shelby COBRA 427135,0008Mercedes-Benz SL 65 AMG220,0007Lexus LFA315,0006McLaren MP4-12C425,0005Porsche 918 Spyder Concept520,0004Lamborghini Aventador630,0003Bugatti Veyron Super Sports750,0002Pagani Huayra875,0001Koenigsegg Agera R1,000,000SoundTrackArtist TrackThe WhoBaba O'Riley (Alan Wilkis Remix)The WhoWon't Get Fooled Again (Cato Remix)Calvin HarrisWe'll Be Coming Back (KillSonik Remix)Dizzee RascalBonkersMadeon feat. Zak WatersThe CityMuseButterflies and HurricanesSkrillex (with The Doors)Breakin a Sweat (Original)NeroWon't You (Be There)Rudimental feat. John NewmanFeel The LoveSilent CodeNight TrainSilent CodeSpell BoundSilent CodeEast StarThe MaccabeesUnknowThe Joy FormidableLittle BlimpForeign Beggars feat. NoisiaContactFlux Pavilion feat. SwayDouble EdgeThe Chemical BrothersGalvanizeRiverboat GamblersBlue GhostsGreen DayStop When The Red Lights FlashIcona PopI Love ItAmbassadorsUnconsolableDispatchCircles Around The SunWe Are The OceanThe Road (Run For Miles)DJ Fresh feat. Dizzee RascalThe PowerRuN RIOTA Light Goes Off (RuN RIOT Mix)Heaven's BasementI Am ElectricDeadmau5 feat. Wolfgang GartnerChannel 42Above  BeyondAnjunabeachThe VaccinesBad MoodCD ProjectThe ChasePoliçaViolent GamesBassnectarEmpathyCrossesTelepathyBeware of DarknessHowlLower than AtlantisLove Someone ElseStrange TalkCast AwayLast DinosaursZoomAsherelShake The DustBand of SkullsYou're Not Pretty But...Dead SaraWeathermanPopeskaNow or NeverMutemathAlliesLimited Edition  PreorderThe Limited Edition of Need For Speed: Most Wanted includes many bonuses:4 hours of double speed points for multiplayer2012 Porsche 911 Carerra SMaserati GranTurismo MC Stradale - Both cars are decked out with an exclusive livery and performance modificationsPre-ordering from select retailers granted players exclusive vehicles with upgrades. 360/PS3 owners could order from Walmart.com to get both Power  Strike while GameStop orders get the Speed Pack. Preordering on PC (through Origin) granted players all three packs.Speed Pack: Caterham Superlight R500Power Pack: Ford F-150 RaptorStrike Pack: Mercedes-Benz SL 65 Black SeriesTriviaWhile the game doesn't have any story continuity with the original Need For Speed: Most Wanted, there are some references to it and it's characters, such as the "Callahan Industrial" area in the PS3/360/PC game, and the mobile/portable version includes an track named "Callahan District", both references to the 2005 game's antagonist Razor Callahan.PC System RequirementsMinimun RequirementsRecommended RequirementsCPU: 2 GHz Dual Core (Core 2 Duo 2.4 GHz or Athlon X2 2.7 GHz)RAM: 2 GBVGA: AMD: DirectX 10.1 compatible with 512 MB RAM (ATI Radeon 3000, 4000, 5000 or 6000 series, with ATI Radeon 3870 or higher performance)NVIDIA: DirectX 10.0 compatible with 512 MB RAM (NVIDIA GeForce 8, 9, 200, 300, 400 or 500 series with NVIDIA GeForce 8800 GT or higher performance)DX: DirectX 10.0OS: Windows Vista (SP1) 32-bitHDD: 20 GBODD: DVD Rom DriveMimimun Peripheral: Keyboard and MouseCPU: 2 GHz Quad Core (Core 2 Quad Q6400 2.13 GHz or Phenon 9550 Quad-Core)RAM: 4 GBVGA: AMD: DirectX 11 compatible with 2 GB RAM (ATI Radeon 6950/70 and 78xx/9xx)NVIDIA: DirectX 11 compatible with 1.2 GB RAM (NVIDIA GeForce 560/70 and 660/70/80)DX: DirectX 11OS: Windows 7 64-bitHDD: 20GB</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5648">Burnout Paradise</game><game id="37648">Forza Horizon</game><game id="21307">Juiced 2: Hot Import Nights</game><game id="36167">Asphalt: Injection</game><game id="35647">Ridge Racer</game><game id="42693">Forza Motorsport 5</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/89459/2223911-ex2it.jpg</image></root>