<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38491</id><name>Pro Evolution Soccer 2013</name><description>OverviewDeveloped and published by Konami, Pro Evolution Soccer 2013 is set to hit shelves worldwide on Fall 2012. Officially announced on April 18, 2012, it was also announced, during the Konami Pre-E3 Press Conference, that famous player Cristiano Ronaldo will be on the box's cover.With promises of focus on fan feedback and a return to the origins of the sport, PES 2013 will be based on 3 major features:PES FullControlPlayer IDProActive IDPES FullControlThis describes several new and improved features that gives the player more control about the players and the ball with the goal of giving total freedom over ball control. To achieve this goal, PES 2013 will present the players many features, like full manual shooting, manual passing and manual One-Two. A Dynamic First Touch feature will introduce players to many subtle ways to receive the ball, a new dribbling system will give players more attacking options and a new balanced defense system will give players a better sense to counter said attacking options.Player IDPlayer ID focus on the individual elements and movements that each player boasts:The best players in the world will be instantly recognizable, be it by their likeness or by their personal skills and tricks. These players will play and feel differently during the game from the regular players, from the way they run to the way they move and shoot the ball.This individuality has also been extended to the Goalkeepers. New animations and play styles will ensure that the keepers actions will fall in line with the real players. Again, the best goalkeepers will have specific animations and skills.ProActive IDThis system will enhance the speed and balance from the players movement, which results in a more realistic game experience. In-game tactics will also suffer improvements in order to ensure a better balance play between attack and defense.Voted by fans as the no.1 issue that needed improvement, Goalkeeper AI will be vastly improved. The development team has been working with real keepers to improve the AI process.PC System RequirementsMinimum Requirements:OS: Windows XP SP3, Vista SP2, Windows 7CPU: Intel Pentium IV 2.4GHz or equivalent processorRAM: 1GB RAMHDD: 8GB free hard disk spaceVIDEO: DirectX 9.0c compatible video card. 128MB Pixel Shader 3.0 (NVIDIA GeForce 6200 / ATI Radeon X1300 / Intel HD √ Graphics 2000/3000)SOUND: DirectX 9.0c compatible sound cardDirectX 9.0c or higher (included on Disc)800 x 600 monitor resolutionRecommended Requirements:OS: Windows XP SP3, Vista SP2, 7CPU: Intel Core2 Duo 2.0GHz or equivalent processorRAM: 2GB RAMHDD: 8GB free hard disk spaceVIDEO: DirectX 9.0c compatible video card. 512MB Pixel Shader 3.0 (NVIDIA GeForce 7900 or AMD/ATI Radeon HD2400 or better)SOUND: DirectX 9.0c compatible sound cardDirectX 9.0c or higher (included on Disc)1280 x 720 monitor resolution</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="40">Soccer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="36166">FIFA Soccer 13</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2323874-box_pes2013.png</image></root>