<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38531</id><name>Dance Central 3</name><description>Included songsDance Central 3 boasts a soundtrack that spans the '70s, '80s, '90s, '00s and beyond. The game's setlist features 46 songs on disc, 3 of which were included in the demo. Every song is unlocked from the start, except Tan-Step which becomes available after leveling up and unlocking M.O.C. Crew.ArtistSong TitleDifficultyDecadeChoreographer2NE1I Am The Best (Original Version)Legit2010sFrenchy Hernandez50 CentIn Da ClubSimple2000sDevin WoolridgeAfrojack ft. Eva SimonsTake Over ControlTough2010sSpikey SoriaAlexandra StanMr. SaxobeatTough2010sMarcos AguirreAlice DeejayBetter Off AloneWarmup1990sMarcos AguirreBackstreet BoysEverybody (Backstreet's Back)Tough1990sSpikey SoriaBelliniSamba De JaneiroLegit1990sDevin WoolridgeBlack Eyed PeasBoom Boom PowModerate2000sMarcos AguirreCali Swag DistrictTeach Me How To DougieTough2010sTorey NelsonCiara ft. Missy Elliot1, 2 StepSimple2000sChanel ThompsonCobra Starship Feat. SabiYou Make Me Feel...Off The Hook2010sTorey NelsonCupidCupid ShuffleModerate2000sDevin WoolridgeDaft PunkAround The WorldLegit1990sKunle OladehinDev Ft. The CataractsBass Down LowLegit2010sNick DeMouraEdward Maya  Vika JigulinaStereo LoveModerate2010sMarcos AguirreEnur ft. NatasjaCalabria 2008Legit2000sChanel ThompsonE.U.Da' ButtTough1980sRicardo Foster Jr.Flo Rida ft. SiaWild OnesLegit2010sKunle OladehinGloria GaynorI Will SurviveModerate1970sFrenchy HernandezHeavy D  The BoyzNow That We Found LoveLegit1990sChanel ThompsonJennifer Lopez ft. PitbullOn The FloorLegit2010sChanel ThompsonJ.J. FadSupersonicLegit1980sRicardo Foster Jr.Justin BieberBoyfriendModerate2010sNick DeMouraKaty PerryFireworkModerate2010sChanel ThompsonKelly ClarksonStronger (What Doesn't Kill You)Hardcore2010sSpikey SoriaLil Jon  The East Side Boyz ft. Ying Yang TwinsGet LowLegit2000sDevin WoolridgeLMFAOSexy And I Know ItHardcore2010sTorey NelsonLos Del RioMacarena (Bayside Boys Mix)Simple1990sFrenchy HernandezM-CueTan-StepHardcore2010sRicardo Foster Jr.Marcia GriffithsElectric BoogieTough1970sKunle OladehinMaroon 5 Ft. Christina AguileraMoves Like JaggerHardcore2010sDevin WoolridgeMartin Solveig ft. DragonetteHelloTough2010sMarcos AguirreMissy ElliotChing-A-LingTough2000sMarcos AguirreNew Kids On The BlockYou've Got It (The Right Stuff)Moderate1980sKunle OladehinNicki MinajStarshipsSimple2010sNick DeMouraPanjabi MCBeware Of The Boys (Mundian To Bach Ke)Legit2000sRicardo Foster Jr.Sean Paul Ft. Keysiha Cole(When You Gonna) Give It Up To MeSimple2000sMarcos AguirreShannonLet The Music PlayTough1980sRicardo Foster Jr.TLCAint 2 Proud 2 BegTough1990sFrenchy HernandezThe TrammpsDisco InfernoModerate1970sFrenchy HernandezUsherScreamLegit2010sUsher Raymond IV and Aakomon "AJ" JonesUsher Ft. Will.I.AmOMGOff The Hook2010sUsher Raymond IV and Aakomon "AJ" JonesVanilla IceIce Ice BabyModerate1990sMarcos AguirreVan McCoyThe HustleWarmup1970sMarcos AguirreVicki Sue RobinsonTurn The Beat AroundModerate1970sMarcos AguirreVillage PeopleY.M.C.A.Warmup1970sMarcos AguirreDownloadable ContentDownloadable songs from Dance Central and Dance Central 2 will work in Dance Central 3. The on disc songs from Dance Central and Dance Central 2 are available after purchasing disc export licences on the Xbox Live Marketplace.ArtistSong TitleCharacter  CrewDifficultyChoreographerRelease DateUsher ft. PharellTwistedDCI (Rasa)Off The HookUsher Raymond IV and Aakomon "AJ" JonesNovember 20, 2012UsherEuphoriaDCI (Rasa)Off The HookUsher Raymond IV and Aakomon "AJ" JonesNovember 20, 2012PSYGangnam StyleRiptide (Bodie)LegitDevin WoolridgeNovember 27, 2012Carly Rae JepsenCall Me MaybeFlash4wrd (Li'l T)Off The HookSpikey SoriaDecember 4, 2012Lady GagaAlejandroLu$h Crew (Angel)ModerateMarcos AguirreDecember 25, 2012Lady GagaPaparazziFlash4wrd (Taye)ToughMarcos AguirreDecember 25, 2012LMFAOSorry for Party RockingHi-Def (Mo)ModerateKunle OladehinDecember 31, 2012Nicki MinajWhip ItDCI (Lima)LegitMarcos AguirreJanuary 8, 2013Pitbull ft. Chris BrownInternational LoveHi-Def (Mo)LegitKunle OladehinJanuary 15, 2013Pitbull ft. T-PainHey Baby (Drop It to The Floor)Riptide (Bodie)Off The HookTorey NelsonJanuary 15, 2013The WantedGlad You CameLu$h Crew (Angel)SimpleMarcos AguirreJanuary 22, 2013Flo RidaLet It RollHi-Def (Glitch)LegitRicardo Foster Jr.January 29, 2013One DirectionWhat Makes You BeautifulLu$h Crew (Ms. Aubrey)SimpleMarcos AguirreFebruary 5, 2013Justin Beiber ft. Nicki MinajBeauty and a BeatLu$h Crew (Angel)LegitMarcos AguirreFebruary 12, 2013Justin Beiber ft. LudacrisAll Around The WorldRiptide (Emilia)LegitChanel ThompsonFebruary 12, 2013Ellie GouldingLightsHi-Def (Glitch)HardcoreRicardo Foster Jr.February 19, 2013B.o.B. Ft. Hayley WilliamsAirplanesDCI (Rasa)ToughTorey NelsonFebruary 26, 2013Drake Ft. RihannaTake Care LegitDevin WoolridgeMarch 5, 2013Rihanna Ft. Jay-ZUmbrella ToughChanel ThompsonMarch, 12 2013RihannaSOS LegitSpikey SoriaMarch 12, 2013FergieLondon Bridge ModerateMarcos AguirreMarch 19, 2013StoryDance Central 3 uses time travel in its storyline to justify the inclusion of popular dance crazes from the past like The Hustle, The Macarena and '70s dicso. Jeff Gerstmann of Giantbomb.com reported at E3 2012 that "dance crimes" were being committed throughout time, with additional revelations forthcoming at the show. The story is penned by Harmonix's own Eric Pope. Once the story mode is completed Master Quest is unlocked which features the games remaining songs sorted into character specific playlists.CrewsDance Central 3 features many crews from Dance Central 2 the new DCI Crew. Each crew is associated with a different decade of music and time period appropriate venues.'70s Lu$h CrewLu$h CrewMs. Aubrey and Angel are both returning from Dance Central 2. DCI Agent, Crew look, and DC Classic costumes can be unlocked for this crew.Decade: '70sVenue: Roller Disco '80s Hi-DefHi-DefMo and Glitch return from Dance Central 2. DCI Agent, Crew look, and DC Classic costumes can be unlocked for this crew.Decade: '80sVenue: Street Side '90s Flash4wrdFlash4wrdTaye and Li'l T return from Dance Central 2. DCI Agent, Crew look, and DC Classic costumes can be unlocked for this crew.Decade: '90sVenue: House Party '00s RiptideRiptideBodie and Emilia return from Dance Central 2. DCI Agent, and Crew look costumes can be unlocked for this crew. Emilia has a DC Classic costume that can also be unlocked.Decade: 2000sVenue: Dance Central Live DCI CrewDCI CrewRasa and Lima are your main contacts at DCI. There is only 1 alternate costume for this crew. This crew is new in DC3Decade: PresentVenue: DCI HQBonus CrewsBonus Crews are unlocked by earning stars and increasing your level.D-CoyDare and Maccoy return from the original Dance Central after being absent in Dance Central 2. There is only 1 alternate costume for this crew. Kichi  ShinjuNinja CrewShinju and Kichi return from Dance Central 2.     Jaryn  KerithThe GlitteratiDance Central 2 antagonists Jaryn and Kerith return. Crew look and Street Style costumes can be unlocked for this crew.  D-CypherD-CypherThe Robot crew returns from Dance Central 2. A battle damaged version of this crew can be unlocked.    Murder of Crows (M.O.C. Crew)Dr. Tan and Oblio form this crew and also unlock the bonus song "Tan Step". Each member of this crew has an alternate costume. Icon CrewIcon CrewMarcos and Frenchy return from Dance Central 2. They are named after 2 of the choreographers that worked on the game.Fitness ModeDance Central 3, like earlier iterations in the series, includes a fitness mode which tracks calories burned while playing and user specified goals for days active and calories burned in a given week. The number of calories burned while playing can be combined with other compatible titles and tracked using Kinect Playfit.Character BirthdaysDC3 has a secret achievement for playing In 'Da Club with any character on their birthday.CharacterBirthdayAngelFebruary 14Ms. AubreyOctober 20GlitchNovember 26MoNovember 11Li'l TOctober 30TayeMarch 9BodieNovember 23EmiliaFebruary 3LimaDecember 9RasaOctober 16DareFebruary 28MaccoyAugust 24KichiJuly 24ShinjuSeptember 2Jaryn  KerithJune 4CYPH-56  CYPH-78June 11Dr. TanDecember 31OblioDecember 25FrenchyApril 13MarcosApril 18</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2331093-box_dc3.png</image></root>