<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38627</id><name>Final Fantasy Dimensions</name><description>OverviewFinal Fantasy Dimensions is an enhanced port of the Japan-only episodic cellphone game Final Fantasy Legends: Warriors of Light and Dark. Warriors of Light and Dark was released in chapters from late 2010 to late 2011 at a rate of roughly one per month. For the Dimensions version, the chapters are being sold in bundles. The game was released on August 31, 2012.Compared to the original version, Dimensions has a completely remastered soundtrack, upgraded visuals, new touch controls, and when all bundles are purchased, the expected total cost will be lower. All totaled, Warriors of Light and Dark cost around $60 when all of the game's content was purchased.StoryLong ago, when the entire world was crumbling from war, the Avalon Empire rose up and brought an end to the conflict, ushering in a golden age of peace. However, after one of the crystals is shattered and the others begin to behave strangely, the world is plunged into a new conflict. Over the course of the story, the player will control two different groups, each with their own agenda; the Light Warriors lead by Sol and Dark Warriors lead by Nacht.GameplayThis game uses a five-person party with eight main party members divided into the two teams. For most of the game, players will swap between parties of Sol's four Warriors of Light and Nacht's four Warriors of Darkness. There are an additional ten characters that will swap in and out of the player's parties over the course of the game.After the prologue, each chapter features three to twelve dungeons, several side quests, and a post-chapter challenge dungeon. To maintain balance from one chapter to the next, levels and job levels are capped within each chapter. Players can hit a chapter's level cap and find all of the best equipment available and enter the subsequent chapter without being overpowered.Job SystemThe game uses a Job system similar to Final Fantasy III and Final Fantasy V. As the player's characters level up jobs, they will be able to switch to new jobs while retaining the abilities of their prior jobs. Eight jobs are available when the game begins. These jobs are:Black MageFreelancerMonkRed MageSummonerThiefWarriorWhite MageAs players progress through the episodes, more jobs will be unlocked. The Warriors of Darkness will gain access to the Dancer, Dark Knight, Magus, Ninja, and Ranger jobs. The Warriors of Light, on the other hand, will gain access to the Bard, Devout, Dragoon, Knight and Memorist occupations.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="35400">Chaos Rings Omega</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1992/2231903-ffd.png</image></root>