<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38787</id><name>Receiver</name><description>OverviewReceiver is a sci-fi first-person shooter with rogue-like elements. Wolfire initially created the game during a 7-day FPS challenge; they decided to continue to work on the game after the deadline, and subsequently released a commercial version of the game. Receiver was successfully greenlit by Steam on February 26, 2013; on April 30, the Steam version of the game was finally released for PC, Mac, and Linux.GameplayReceiver has three different weapons as of this writing: A Colt 1911 A1, Glock 17, and the Smith and Wesson Victory 10 Revolver. Known for the initially confusing though engaging process of operating the guns, Receiver focuses on destroying stationary turrets and pursuing droids whilst "absorbing" cassette tapes which explain the bizarre happenings of the game.WeaponsColt 1911 A1Colt 1911 A1The initial weapon added to Receiver, the Colt 1911 A1 boasts a great damage output as well as a respectable magazine size. The weapon can be considered a Jack of all Trades. Because of this, it is the easiest weapon for a beginner to utilize.Smith  Wesson Victory 10 RevolverAs it says in its namesake, the Victory 10 is a six shot revolver and the easiest weapon in the game to prepare and operate. With damage close to par with the Colt 1911 A1, the Victory 10's drawback is it's lowest in the game six shot cylinder. Reloading the Victory 10 has the potential to be unreliable as well, as it is likely not all the shells fired will clear from the weapon. The involved reloading process, even more so than the others, can turn a fight into a lost battle very quickly if the shells give the player problems. Despite this drawback it is a good weapon to use as long as the player reloads frequently and before entering a new area, as well as have a fallback plan in case you cannot finish a fight in six shots.Glock 17The only fully automatic weapon in the game, the Glock 17 is simple to use, as it is simple to reload. Not only is it simple to operate, it also comes with the largest magazine in the game. The Glock 17 magainze can double the amount of bullets the Colt 1911 A1 can hold. The main drawback is the weapon can seem weaker and overall clumsy compared to the previously mentioned weapons by a large margin. The fully automatic function, while the only weapon that can use it, is best left turned off as it eats through ammo at an alarming rate. Because of the awkward utilization, it can be one of the hardest weapons to use effectively in the game.ItemsFlashlightAn invaluable tool, the flashlight proves handy when trying to navigate the sometimes dark settings of Receiver. The use of the flashlight is self explanatory, equip it and the player begins to use it. The flashlight can, at times, become redundant and overall distracting, however. It can be drawn and holstered easily with little delay.Cassette TapesCassette Tape.The objective of the game is to "absorb" the 11 cassette tapes randomly scattered in the game world. When the player picks up a cassette tape, a voice begins to play. The messages given to the player by the cassette tapes is randomized and one can expect to hear something different with each life. The tapes are hard to miss as long as the player offers a glance to every corner of the level, as they emit a glowing light near it's position. The Tape can most likely be seen coupled with a flashlight or loose rounds for whichever weapon the player has equipped.EnemiesTurretThe turret is a stationary enemy which takes 360 degree turns around the legs it stands on, observing the area it is deployed in. The turret will not detect the player as long as no direct line of sight can be established. If detected, the turret will open fire a second or two afterwards. If the player is hit by a bullet it will cause a game over.DroneA Pursuing Drone.Much more difficult to deal with than the turret, the drone hovers above a level. Most likely drones can be found outside and occasionally in groups. Once the drone discovers the player, it will begin chase at a much quicker pace, equipped with a device that delivers a fatal electrical shock. To avoid the drone the player must break line of sight with the drone. This can most easily be done by entering a building or turning multiple corners inside of a building if the drone is encountered inside.System RequirementsPCMinimumOS:Windows XPProcessor:2.0 GHzMemory:1 GB RAMGraphics:Passmark G3D 250+Hard Drive:150 MB HD spaceRecommendedOS:Windows 7Processor:2.0 GHzMemory:2 GB RAMGraphics:Passmark G3D 1000+Hard Drive:150 MB HD spaceMacMinimumOS:10.6Processor:2.0 GHzMemory:1 GB RAMGraphics:Passmark G3D 250+Hard Drive:150 MB HD spaceRecommendedOS:10.6Processor:2.0 GHzMemory:2 GB RAMGraphics:Passmark G3D 1000+Hard Drive:150 MB HD spaceLinuxMinimumOS:Ubuntu 12.10Processor:2.0 GHzMemory:1 GB RAMGraphics:Passmark G3D 250+Hard Drive:150 MB HD space</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2481864-box_receiver.png</image></root>