<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38786</id><name>Naruto Shippuden: Ultimate Ninja Storm 3</name><description>OverviewThe story covers various events such as Kurama's attack on Konoha and the Fourth Shinobi World War. Many long-deceased friends and foes reappear as undead minions, controlled by Kabuto, who is partnered with Tobi.The game sports DLC, including at least costumes. One such costume, which is also a pre-order bonus, is one of DragonBall's Goku for Naruto.DevelopmentNaruto Shippuden: Ultimate Ninja Storm 3 was first announced by Namco Bandai Games in June 2012 in Shonen Jump. After the official announcement, Yusuke Sasaki from Namco Bandai promised improvements regarding the fighting system and the story mode. CyberConnect2 CEO Hiroshi Matsuyama also promised the return of "epic boss battles" that were absent in Naruto Shippuden: Ultimate Ninja Storm Generations.In January 4, 2013, Hiroshi Matsuyama also announced that there will be over 80 playable characters.RosterSasuke and NarutoNaruto Uzumaki (Pre-Time Skip, Shippuden, Sage Mode)Sasuke Uchiha (Pre-Time Skip, Shippuden, Taka)Sakura Haruno (Pre-Time Skip, Shippuden)Kakashi Hatake (Adult and Youth)YamatoSaiShikamaru NaraIno YamanakaChoji AkimichiRock Lee (Pre-Time Skip, Shippuden)TentenNeji Hyuga (Pre-Time Skip, Shippuden)Shino AburameHinata Hyuga (Pre-Time Skip, Shippuden)Kiba InuzukaMight GuyHashirama SenjuTobirama SenjuHiruzen SarutobiMinato NamikazeTsunadeDanzo ShimuraJiraiyaGaara (Pre-Time Skip, Shippuden, Shinobi General)TemariKankuroKiller BeeAyDaruiOhnokiMei TerumiMifuneObito Uchiha (Youth, Tobi, Masked Man, Rinnegan Tobi)Itachi Uchiha (Standard and Edo Tensei)Kisame HoshigakiKabuto Yakushi (Standard and Possessed)OrochimaruKarinSuigetsu HozukiJugoPainNagato (Edo Tensei)KonanYugito NiiYaguraRoushiHanUtakataFuuHanzo (Edo Tensei)Deidara (Edo Tensei)SasoriHidanKakuzuAsuma Sarutobi (Edo Tensei)Zabuza Momochi (Edo Tensei)Haku (Edo Tensei)KimimaroChiyoMadara Uchiha (Edo Tensei) Playable StagesKonohagakure (Normal, Destroyed, Construction, Part 1)Training FieldForest of DeathForest of Quite Movement (Day, Night)Forest of Dead TreesKonohagakure ForestChunin Exams StadiumChunin Exams Preliminary AreaMinato vs. TobiLookout TowerInn TownOrochimaru's Hideout (Normal, Destroyed)Five Kage Summit VenueStorm Cloud RavineSamurai Bridge (Bridge, River)The Coast of the Land of LightningCanyon of the Land of LightningSnowfieldSunagakureSunagakure GateLand of Lightning DesertFalls of TruthZabuza  Haku vs. KakashiTailed Beast TempleThe Uchiha HideoutAkatsuki HideoutFive-Seal Barrier CliffValley of the EndAmegakureMount MyobokuSpecial EditionIn October 28, London MCM Expo, CyberConnect2 CEO Hiroshi Matsuyama announced a European card edition, a poster, the games soundtrack, a copy of the game, and a Naruto or Sasuke 6"" Figurine. They also stated that those who pre-order will get five free downloadable costumes, including Armoured Naruto, Swimsuit Tsunade, Kimono Sasuke, Anbu Itachi and Schoolgirl Sakura. Also anyone who preordered the game received a Goku DLC costume for Naruto.</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="34360">Bleach Soul Resurrección</game><game id="35816">Naruto Shippuden: Ultimate Ninja Storm Generations</game><game id="30539">Naruto Shippuden: Ultimate Ninja Storm 2</game><game id="21425">Naruto: The Broken Bond</game><game id="15928">Naruto: Rise of a Ninja</game><game id="31233">Dragon Ball: Raging Blast 2</game><game id="26565">Dragon Ball: Raging Blast</game><game id="690">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai Tenkaichi</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/16/164924/2411471-storm3crop.jpg</image></root>