<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38860</id><name>Home</name><description>OverviewIn Home, the main character wakes up in a mysterious house and must figure out why he is there and what is happening. Home takes a little over an hour to finish, and the game suggests you finish it in one sitting with headphones on and the lights turned off.GameplayHome takes place in a 2D world. The player controls an unnamed character equipped with a flashlight. Home has few controls: the left, right, and up arrow keys and the space bar. Pressing left or right moves the character in those directions; pressing up makes the character shine his flashlight upward. The player can interact with highlighted objects by pressing the space bar. Interacting with items usually results in a description of the item. Occasionally, the game will allow the player to further interact with items through a "Yes/No" prompt. Home has few traditional puzzles. The true puzzle in Home is trying to figure out what is going on. Home never explicitly tells you its story. Instead, Home lets you piece together several pieces of the story while omitting critical details. Through your actions playing the game, Home encourages you to construct your own story. After you finish Home, it suggests you go to homehorror.com/whathappened. On the site, you can submit your interpretation of the game's story or read others' interpretations.System RequirementOS: Windows XP, Windows 7Processor: Core 2 Duo or aboveMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: Graphics card with 256 MB RAMHard Drive: 300 MB HD spaceSound: Soundblaster or equivalentOS: OS 10.7 Lion or aboveProcessor: Core 2 DuoMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: Graphics card with 256 MB RAMHard Drive: 50 MB HD space</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="37794">Lone Survivor</game><game id="31949">Clock Tower: The First Fear</game><game id="43488">Postmortem</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/11/117587/2306492-homeboxc.jpg</image></root>