<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38870</id><name>East Vs. West</name><description>OverviewEast Vs. West is a game developed by BL Logic, who previously developed a game based on Hearts of Iron 2 called Arsenal of Democracy. It will be released on the PC and will be released 2013.GameplayThe game will be focused on the cold war between the United States and the Soviet Union, though other nations will be playable as well, and they will largely be allied with one or the other in some form or another. The game is based on the Hearts of Iron 3 version of the Clausewitz Engine, but will be more focused on diplomacy, espionage, and proximity wars rather than all out fighting. The United Nations plays a large focus in the diplomacy aspect of the game. Espionage will be utilized with cards representing spies, sending spies out to complete missions in a country; though that country may play a counter espionage card to stop you if they see it happening.Nuclear weapons are in the game, and can be launched; however, this will all be tracked by the Doomsday Clock, which indicates how likely WWIII will be. Forcing a change in the UN, being a bully to other nations, and blatant power moves will all make the clock tick down. War can be automated, in depth, or anywhere in the middle. Research will also be vital to keeping a country militarily competent.Countries have three tiers of decisions: national ideas, which serve as the basis of your nation (which may not be easily changed), policies, which are more dynamic and may change when a new political party comes into power, and laws, which are more static. There are political parties, which may be dealt with by curbing the people's power or allowing them to come into power, which may change the nation's policies and strategies.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2348414-east.png</image></root>