<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38889</id><name>Back to the Future: The Game</name><description>OverviewBack to the Future: The Game is an episodic game that consists of 5 episodes that were released monthly between December 2010 and June 2011 for the PC and Mac. Playstation 3 and iPad versions of the episodes were also released but about a month after the PC and Mac versions. A retail disc version was released for the Playstation 3, Wii, and PC on October 25, 2011.The episodes are:Episode 1: It's About TimeEpisode 2: Get Tannen!Episode 3: Citizen BrownEpisode 4: Double VisionsEpisode 5: OutatimePC System RequirementsMinimum:OS: XP Service Pack 3 / Vista / Windows 7Processor: 1.8 GHz Pentium 4 or equivalentMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: ATI or NVidia card w/ 256 MB RAMDirectX®: Direct X 9.0cHard Drive: 2 GB Space FreeSound: Direct X 8.1 sound deviceRecommended:OS: XP Service Pack 3 / Vista / Windows 7Processor: 2.7 GHz Pentium 4 or equivalentMemory: 3 GB RAMGraphics: ATI or NVidia card w/ 512 MB RAMDirectX®: Direct X 9.0cHard Drive: 3 GB Space FreeSound: Direct X 8.1 sound deviceMac System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Snow Leopard (10.5.8)Processor: 2.0 GHz Pentium or equivalentMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: ATI or NVidia card w/ 256 MB RAMHard Drive: 2 GB Space FreeNot recommended for MAC Minis or early-generation MacBooksRecommended:OS: Snow Leopard (10.5.8)Processor: 2.3 GHz Pentium or equivalentMemory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: ATI or NVidia card w/ 512 MB RAMHard Drive: 2 GB Space FreeNot recommended for MAC Minis or early-generation MacBooks</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="32592">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 1: It's About Time</game><game id="33417">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 5: OUTATIME</game><game id="33414">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 2: Get Tannen!</game><game id="33415">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 3: Citizen Brown</game><game id="33416">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 4: Double Visions</game><game id="32796">Tales of Monkey Island</game><game id="29474">Sam &amp; Max: The Devil's Playhouse</game><game id="6049">Sam &amp; Max Save the World</game><game id="24684">Sam &amp; Max Beyond Time and Space</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3699/2474977-back+to+the+future+-+the+game+-+pc+cover.jpg</image></root>