<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3895</id><name>Special Forces: Nemesis Strike</name><description>Overview  Meet Raptor: He likes to shoot things  Nemesis Strike is a cover-based shooter based on the series of            Metal Slug-like shooters for the         GBA,        Counter Terrorism Special Forces. Whereas the Game Boy games draw from Metal Slug, the console iteration abandons the 2D for the 3D and adopts game play for     Splinter Cell and     kill.switch. The game was released as CT Special Forces: First for Effect in other territories.    Like in the 2D games, you play as two characters, Raptor and Stealth Owl. Raptor is a straightforward solider and has equally straightforward game play. He has an over shield which protects him from gunfire. This shield does not recharge on its own but must be charged at battery station strewn throughout the levels.     Meet Stealth Owl: He also shoots things, but does so while invisible.  The second character, Stealth Owl, also uses these battery station but does not have a shield. Instead, Stealth Owl can turn invisible at will. Also, like his       Third Echelon counter part, Stealth Owl has several vision modes: night vision, thermal, and sonar.   Skydiving is the most original aspect of the game  Both characters have the occasional vehicle sequence, but at the beginning of each of Stealth Owl's missions the player is treated to the game's most unique aspect: skydiving. In order to infiltrate enemy compounds undetected, Stealth Owl will skydive out of a jet where he is often assaulted by enemy skydivers or attacked by missiles.  Criticisms Special Forces Nemesis Strike is a budget title and as such retains many of the characteristics of a cheaply made game. It was not received well   critically with many reviewers citing issues with the game's  AI. Often enemies could see you even if you were cloaked and enemy dialogue could be heard even if all the enemies in an area were dead. The games visuals also criticized for being out-of-date. There is also an issue with voice acting missing from some cut scenes.  PC Requirements Minimum System Requirements OS: Windows 98/ME/2000/XPProcessor: Pentium III 1GHz ProcessorRAM: 128MB RAM (256MB for 2000/XP)Hard Drives Space: 3.5GBVideo: GeForce 3 or ATi Radeon 8500Sound: DirectX compatible cardDirectX: 9Recommended System Requirements OS: Windows 98/ME/2000/XP Processor: Pentium 4 or AMD Athlon 1.5GHzRAM: 128MB RAM (256MB for 2000/XP)Hard Drives Space:3.5GB   Video: GeForce 5000 or Radeon 9000 Sound: DirectX compatible cardDirectX: 9</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5961">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell</game><game id="12354">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Chaos Theory</game><game id="1152">kill.switch</game><game id="12388">Metal Gear Solid 2: Sons of Liberty</game><game id="12231">Gears of War</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2478689-box_sfns.png</image></root>