<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38992</id><name>War Thunder</name><description>War Thunder is an MMO-style combat game taking place during World War II and the Korean War between 1939 and 1953. Like its primary competitor WarGaming.net, War Thunder will eventually span all three major types of warfare (aerial, naval, ground). The first type being focused on is aerial combat.Aerial CombatThe aerial portion of War Thunder was originally called World of Planes. The name was changed due to perceived confusion with WarGaming.net's World of Warplanes. It features period accurate planes and locations from 1939 to 1953. Many historical battles from the second world war and the Korean war are represented as maps.There are multiple difficulty modes depending upon how much realism you desire. Arcade mode is essentially a more simplistic multiplayer shooter while historical battles mode will require more advanced techniques like taking off and landing during battles and realistic damage modelling.There are five countries represented in War Thunder; United States, United Kingdom, Soviet Union, Japan, and Germany. There are two more planned countries which have yet to be included in the game; Australia and Italy. Each have their own unlock trees and sets of planes. As one is levelled, that progress is not transferred to the others. Within each nationality the player has a hangar holding 3-7 planes of their own with many levelling and customisation options. Researching planes and upgrading crews use a mixture of various currencies; some earned in gameplay, some purchased with money.AlphaThe War Thunder aerial alpha ran from October 2011 to March 2012.BetaCrashing without a tail in the beta.The closed beta began in March 2012 and concluded in October 2012. On Nov. 1, 2012 the game entered open beta. Gaijin Entertainment has stated the stats and progression earned by players during the open beta will not be reset when the game goes into full release. Purchasable upgrades and currency were also live as of the open beta. The game is downloaded via Gaijin's website as a free client, but on Feb. 26, 2013 the game passed Steam Greenlight and is due for release in the coming months.AircraftHere is a list of currently available and planned aircraft as of the beta release. Italics = Planned, but not in yet. Bold = Premium Content.Germany (Air Arm, Luftwaffe)Arado 234Bf.109E-3Bf.109F-4Bf.109F-4/tropBf.109G-10Bf.109G-2Bf.109G-6Bf.109K-4Bf.110C-4Do-217E-2Do-217E-4Do-217J-1Do-217J-2Do-217K-1Do-217M-1Fw 190 D-13 DoraFw.190A-5Fw.190D-12Fw.190F-8He-112A-0He-112B-0He-112B-1He-112B-2He-112V-5He-51A-1He-51B-1He-51B-2He-51C-1He-51C-1/LHe.111H-16He.111H-2He.111H-6He.162A-2Hs.129B-2Ju.87B-2Ju.87D-3Ju.87D-5Ju.87G-1Ju.87R-2Ju.88A-4Me.163BMe.262A-1aMe.410A-1Me.410A-1/U2Me.410A-1/U4Me.410B-1Me.410B-1/U2Me.410B-2/U4Me.410B-6/R3Ta.152H-1Do-217N-1Ju.87G-2He.111H-3Fw.190D-13Captured:Wellington Mk 1CP-47DLa-5FN Japan (Imperial Japanese Army/Navy Air Service, 大日本帝国陸軍航空部隊)A5M4A6M2 ZeroA6M2-N ZeroA6M3 ZeroA6M5 ZeroB5N2D3A1F1M2G4M1H6K4Ki-200Ki-43-IIKi-49-IKi-49-IIAKi-49-IIbKi-61-Ia-HeiKi-61-Ia-KoKi-61-Ia-OtsuN1K2-JN1K2-JaA6M3 mod 22Ki-10Ki-49-llb/LG5N1G8N1A6M5 KoFw.190-A5Bf.109E-3Ki-45 koKi-45 otsuKi-45 teiKi-45 heiHagiri's A5M4  Captured:F4U-1a   United Kingdom (Royal Air Force)Beaufighter Mk.VICBeaufighter Mk.XBlenheim Mk.IVBoston Mk.IDB-7Dewoitine D.520Gladiator Mk.IIGladiator Mk.IIFGladiator Mk.IISHavoc Mk.IHellcat F Mk.IHurricane Mk.IHurricane Mk.IIBLancaster Mk.IIIMeteor F.3Meteor F.4 LWMeteor F.4 SWMeteor F.8Mosquito FB Mk.VISea Meteor F.3Spitfire Mk XVISpitfire Mk.ISpitfire Mk.IISpitfire Mk.IXSpitfire Mk.VBSpitfire Mk.VCSwordfish Mk.ITempest Mk.VTyphoon Mk.IATyphoon Mk.IBTyphoon Mk.IB/LWellington Mk.IcWellington Mk.Ic/LWellington Mk.IIIWellington Mk.XMustang Mk 1AFury Mk IFury Mk IINimrod Mk ITuck's Gladiator Mk.IIDewoitine D.521    United States (United States Army Air Forces)A-20GB-17EB-17E/LB-17G F-86A-5F2A-3F4F-3F4F-4F4U-1AF4U-1D F6F-3OS2U-1OS2U-3P-26A-33P-26A-34P-26A-34 M2 P-26A-35P-26B-35P-40E-1P-47D ThunderboltP-51D-5 MustangSBD-3 TBF-1CP-39N-0P-39Q-5P-63P-38GF2A-1 B-25J-1B-25J-20B-24DPBY-5 CatalinaPBY-5a CatalinaXP-38G A-26C-45Spitfire Mk IXXP-55 AscenderXP-50Thach's F2A-1 BuffaloP-36 Rasmussen's P-36A Hawk Captured:Ki-61-lbA6M2Bf.109F-4   USSR (Military Air Forces, Военно-воздушные силы СССР)I-153PI-16 Type 28IL-10IL-2 SturmovikIL-2MIL-4La-5FNLa-7LaGG-3MiG-15MiG-9P-39K-1P-39Q-15Pe-2 (1-20)Pe-2 (110-204)Pe-2 (205-358)Pe-2 (21-82)Pe-2 (83-109)Pe-2 (359+)Pe-3Pe-3 earlyPe-3bisPo-2SB 2M-100SB 2M-100ASB 2M-100A (Span)SB 2M-103SB 2M-103 MV-3SB 2M-103USB 2M-103U MV-3SB 2M-105Su-2Su-2 M-82Su-2 MV-5SU-2 TSS-1Tu-2Yak-1BYak-3Yak-7BYak-9TI-15I-153 M-62I-16 Type 18MiG-9/LBB-1Ar-2Yer-2Tu-2STu-2S-44Tu-2S-59Yak-9PYak-15Yak-15PMig-3-15Lagg-3-66PBY-5aP-40E-1P-63A-5Zhykovsky's I-153-M62I-15bisLa-7B-20    Australian planes are included under UK:Australia (Royal Australian Air Force)Beaufighter Mk.21Beaufort Mk.VIIIBoomerang Mk.IBoomerang Mk.IIWirrawayItalian planes are included under Germany:Italy (Italian Royal Air Force, Regia Aeronautica Italiana)Naval CombatNot much is currently known of the upcoming naval combat.Ground CombatThe first two countries that will have playable ground vehicles are Germany and the Soviet Union. The other countries will be added over time.Here is a list of the currently confirmed set of vehicles.GermanyAssault GunTank DestroyerLight TankMedium Tank Heavy TankStug III Asuf.AJgdPz 38tPz.Kpfw II Ausf.CPz.KpfW.III Ausf.EPz.KpfW.IV Ausf.FPz.KpfW.VI Ausf.HStug III Asuf.CStug IVPz.Kpfw II Ausf.FPz.KpfW.III Ausf.FPz.KpfW.IV Ausf.F2Pz.KpfW.VI Ausf.EStug III Asuf.FJgdPz IV L48Pz.Kpfw.35tPz.KpfW.III Ausf.JPz.KpfW.IV Ausf.GPz.KpfW.VI Ausf.B (P)Stug III Asuf.GPz IV L70Pz.Kpfw.38tPz.KpfW.III Ausf.LPz.KpfW.IV Ausf.HPz.KpfW.VI Ausf.B (H)Stug III Asuf.G (skb)Jadgpanther Pz.KpfW.III Ausf.MPz.KpfW.V Ausf.DPz.KpfW.VI Ausf.B mit KwK 46StuH III Asuf.GFerdinand Pz.KpfW.III Ausf.NPz.KpfW.V Ausf.A  Elefant Pz.KpfW.IV Ausf.CPz.KpfW.V Ausf.G  Jagdtiger Pz.KpfW.IV Ausf.EPz.KpfW.V Ausf.F     Panther II Soviet UnionSelf-propelled gun Light Tank Medium Tank Heavy Tank ZIS-30SU-100T-26BT-5T-28T-34-85 D-5TT-34IS-1SU-76SU-122T-40BT-7T-28ET-34-85 ZIS-53KV-1 L11IS-2 year 43SU-76MSU-152T-50BT-7AT-34 L11T-44KV-1 ZIS-5IS-2 year 44SU-85ISU-122T-60BT-7MT-34 F34T-54 year 47KV-1EIS-3SU-85MISU-152T-70 T-34-57T-54 year 49KV-2IS-4  T-80 T-34 year 42T-54 year 51KV-85  System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows XP SP2, Windows Vista SP1, Windows 7, Windows 8Processor: 2,2 GHzMemory: 1 GB RAMGraphics: Nvidia GeForce 7XXX series or higher; AMD Radeon 1XXX series or higherDirectX: Version 9.0cNetwork: Broadband Internet connectionHard Drive: 8 GB available spaceRecommendedOS: Windows 7,Processor: dual-core 2,4 GHzMemory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: Nvidia GeForce 460 or higherDirectX: Version 9.0cNetwork: Broadband Internet connectionHard Drive: 8 GB available space</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre><genre id="24">Flight Simulator</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/13/138444/2295942-w_warthunder_keyart_small.jpg</image></root>