<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>39117</id><name>Planets Under Attack</name><description>OverviewPlanets Under Attack is a strategy-adventure game where the goal is to develop and expand your own planet while attempting to conquer others. The game was developed by Targem Games and published by TopWare Interactive. It was released on October 16, 2012 for the Mac, PC, PlayStation 3 (via PlayStation Network) and the Xbox 360 (via Xbox Live Marketplace).GameplayThe game operates around a real-time strategy mechanic, with the player starting off as relatively weak but over time develops their own planet(s) and "space fleet", with the ultimate goal of controlling as many other planets as possible. Planets are conquered by winning certain challenges. The game consists of 32 levels to conquer to become "ruler of the galaxy".The following is a list of the different types of planets encountered in gameplay, and are named literally for explanation:MetropolisSpace FortressBank PlanetRobot PlanetPowerplantThere are six different types of gameplay, including:EliminationThe goal is to capture all planets, eliminating all other players in the process.CaptureFirst player to capture a specific planet wins.DominationPlayers must capture and hold a specific planet until no opponents remain.King of the HillSimilar to Domination, but with a loss of points if the player does not retain control of the specific planet.Pay BackIdentify a special type of planet and transfer as much funds as possible to it.InsecticideCapture and destroy planets that are hatching alien eggs.Planets Under Attack has been compared with Omni Creative's Eufloria due to it's many similarities both in presentation and gameplay.Multiplayer is comparable to singleplayer, but with two players adjusting strategy against each other in real-time to conquer the other. Cooperative play is also available.CharactersPlanets Under Attack features many characters to progress its story.Mr. GoodmanThe player's "alter ego", and a space trader.Mr. NorrelA capitalist by definition, and Mr. Goodman's tutor.MechanicusA robot defined by his good nature.DestroboAn evil robot focused on aggression and destruction.Arrrgh'ah'astA fly-like alien that possesses great knowledge of the universe.Strange DeviceAn ancient alien artifact.Greedy ThomasMr. Goodman's rival, driven only by money.ZombieA former human transformed by ancient technology.PC System RequirementsMinimumOS:Windows XP SP2 / Vista / 7Processor:1.5 GHz Single Core CPUMemory:512 MB RAMGraphics:Graphics card with Shader 3.0 support and 128 MB RAMDirectX®:9.0cHard Drive:300 MB HD spaceRecommendedOS:Windows XP SP2 / Vista / 7Processor:Intel Core 2 Duo or AMD Athlon 64x2Memory:1 GB RAMGraphics:Graphics card with Shader 3.0 support and 256 MB RAMDirectX®:9.0cHard Drive:300 MB HD spaceMac System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Snow Leopard (10.6.X)Processor:2 Ghz IntelMemory:512 MB RAMGraphics:Open GL 2.1 / Shader Model 3 capable graphics card with 256 MB video RAMHard Drive:600 MB HD spaceOther Requirements:Broadband Internet connectionRecommended:OS:Lyon (10.7.X)Processor:Core 2 Duo 2GHzMemory:1 GB RAMGraphics:Open GL 2.1 / Shader Model 3 capable graphics card with 512 MB video RAMHard Drive:600 MB HD spaceOther Requirements:Broadband Internet connection</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="29083">Mushroom Wars</game><game id="40275">Frontline Tactics</game><game id="34704">Warlords</game><game id="898">Democracy 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2323877-box_pua.png</image></root>