<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>39138</id><name>Loren The Amazon Princess</name><description>GameplayIn this game you play as Saren or Elenor, two heroes joining in the search for Queen Karen. You will fight monsters, discover new places, find romance and defeat the evil Fost! The game features different endings and you can engage in more than six romances. The battles are old school turn based using a portrait system. The overall art is inspired by manga art. The game contains some nudity. A "cover up" option is available to make the game more appropriate for a younger audience.Game FeaturesOld school battle system: the core of the game, the battle system is turn based and it's extremely detailed offering lots of strategic options, but at same time easy to pick up, thanks to the user-friendly interfaceOriginal Soundtrack: composed by Matthew Myers and performed by Cristina VeeDetailed inventory system: manage a full party of characters, equip weapons, armors and jewellerySkills-based RPG: discover all the powerful skills of each one of the 13 recruitable characters. Each character has a unique specialization skilltreeHigh replayability: make choices that will have an impact in the story and the final outcome!Lots of romance options: as either Elenor or Saren you can experience 12 unique romances, including all possible gender combinationsEpic setting: fight an army of demons, undead and other mythical creatures while collecting money and glory!Beautiful artwork: featuring manga artwork, hand drawn backgrounds and a charming user interface and iconsHuge map and story: travel across the region of Aravorn, from snowy mountains to desolate deserts, from vampire-infested castles to lizard-infested swamps !System RequirementsWindows 2000/XP/VISTA/W7Mac OS 10.4+ or LinuxCPU 1.6 Ghz - 1Gb RAM</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/11/117587/2277456-480x600loren.jpg</image></root>