<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>39155</id><name>10000000</name><description>Overview10000000 merges match 3 game play together with character progression and a dash of Bejeweled. The player is set as a hapless would-be hero locked in a vast dungeon, and the only way to escape is to achieve an arbitrary score of ten million points in a single run-through. While the player plays match three with the sliding tiles to gain resources and attack on the lower portion of the screen, an avatar of the player progresses left-to-right through a 2D representation of a dungeon on the top of the screen - the player must choose which type of tiles to connect in the lower screen in order to overcome the obstacle facing the avatar on the upper section of the screen.GameplayThe screen consists of three sections. The top contains the player's collected materials (Experience, Wood, Stone, and Gold), shield count, and held items. Just below that is the dungeon, where the player scrolls to the right and is stopped by wicked creatures, chests, and doors. The core gameplay takes place though the final door, this consists of match-3 gameplay, similar to that of Bejewelled.Rather than matching similar tiles as quickly as possible, the goal is to match the corresponding icons for a particular action at the appropriate time to swing a weapon at an enemy, use a key to unlock a chest and door, gather stone and wood, or boost shield count. It is impossible to complete the dungeon on the first rank; however, as players gain resources, they can exchange them for stronger weapons, armor, and other benefits.A rank system exists that provides the player specific missions to complete in order to progress to a new rank. Bonus multipliers increase with each rank, making it easier to stay alive longer, gather more resources, and score more points. Once the player reaches ten million points in a single run, the door will open to escape the dungeon. The player is then given the opportunity to continue playing.TilesThere are several different tiles that the player must match in order to initiate their given ability. They will be needed to be matched in pairs of three or more in order to clear from the board and gain their benefit.Sword: Swing the basic weapon at the enemy. (4+ matching tiles grants damage bonus)Stave: Shoot the magical weapon at the enemy. (4+ matching titles grants magical effect and damage bonus)Keys: Unlock an encountered chest or door. (4+ matching tiles unlocks two locks instead of one)Chest: Chance at gaining an item. (4+ matching tiles "double chance")Stone/Wood: Gain a small amount of the corresponding material. (4+ matching tiles earns higher yield)MaterialsThe player will be required to collect a variety of materials to spend on upgrades of their stats. How the player collects these materials is different for every type.Experience: Earned from killing an enemy.Wood: Earned from matching 3+ tiles of wood.Stone: Earned from matching 3+ tiles of stone.Gold: Collected from unlocked chests and killing an enemy.Shields: Player's defence counter. Enemies do not affect players countdown timer if shield deflects damage count. Stronger enemies destroy more shields.SanctuaryThe game will begin with the player trapped inside of a small dungeon that has several doors that are sealed shut as well as the main door to enter the dungeon. Each door can be unlocked by spending enough materials to repair it and the player will be able to purchase the benefits from within.Trainer: Purchase special benefits to aid the player in their journey. (Purchased with experience)Blacksmith: Upgrade weapon type, damage, and critical strike chance. (Purchased with gold)Shieldmaker: Upgrade shield type, count, and maximum. (Purchased with gold)Armorer: Upgrade armor type, damage reduction, and enemy attack delay. (Purchased with gold)Staffmaker: Upgrade stave type, magical damage, and special effect chance. (Purchased with gold)Alchemist: Choose potions that both buff  de-buff the player. (No purchase necessary, activated, unlocked)AlchemistWhen the player unlocks the Alchemist they are able to activate several different combinations of buffs and de-buffs to help in the dungeon crawl.PotionEffectPeasant's Tonic+50% Stone and Wood0% Experience gainedGambler's Brew+25% Chance to Critical or Special Strike-25% DamageFlask of Security+15% ScoreChests and Doors have one lock extraPotion of MidasReceive 20% of Wood and Stone as Gold0 Wood and Stone gatheredBottled WindRanged attacks do 0 damage (enemy)Other attacks do +30% damage (enemy)Hero's Elixir+15 % Score+50% Enemy ToughnessPhilanthropic BrewReceive 20% of Wood and Stone as experience0 Wood and Stone gatheredPotion of InvulnerabilityDouble Shields per match and Max Shields0 Gold, Experience, Wood and Stone gatheredPotion of Holdfast+15% ScoreEnemies hit 30% harderItemsThrough out the dungeon crawl players will gather items from chests and backpack tiles.Food: Restore a portion of the players countdown timer.Weapons: Harms enemy, not capable of critical strike.Orbs: Like weapons, chance of magical effectSkeleton Key: Automatically unlock a chest or doorScrolls: Sword, Stave,  Keys. Transforms random tiles into corresponding tile of scroll.System RequirementsPCMinimumOS:Windows XPProcessor:Core2DuoMemory:1 GB RAMGraphics:Any 3D capable cardDirectX®:9.0cHard Drive:50 MB HD spaceRecommendedOS:Windows 7Processor:Core2DuoMemory:2 GB RAMGraphics:Any 3D capable cardDirectX®:9.0cHard Drive:2 GB HD spaceMacMinimumOS:OSX 10.5Memory:1 GB RAMGraphics:Any 3D capable cardHard Drive:50 MB HD spaceRecommendedOS:OSX 10.8Processor:IntelMemory:2 GB RAMGraphics:Any 3D capable cardHard Drive:1 GB HD space</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2915">Chuzzle Deluxe</game><game id="29289">Puzzle Quest 2</game><game id="20567">Puzzle Quest: Galactrix</game><game id="24934">Puzzle Quest Chapter 1: Battle of Gruulkar</game><game id="28329">Gyromancer</game><game id="34229">Dungeon Raid</game><game id="23282">Henry Hatsworth in the Puzzling Adventure</game><game id="14169">Bejeweled</game><game id="2755">Super Puzzle Fighter II Turbo</game><game id="42137">Dungeon Hearts</game><game id="42019">Scurvy Scallywags</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2413873-mzl.iliubzcw.png</image></root>