<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3916</id><name>DiRT</name><description> OverviewDiRT, known as       Colin McRae DiRT outside of North America, is the sixth Colin McRae rally racing game from      Codemasters. The game was released in North America on Xbox 360 on June 19, 2007 in America and on June 15, 2007 in Europe, the PS3 version released on September 1st in North America and September 14th in Europe.DiRT is an   off-road oriented racing game that features both the standard rally races from previous games where only the player's car is on the track and they are timed from point to point against 20 other competitors, but also expands further to include many forms of off-road racing styles including CORR racing and Hill Climb events. Neon EngineDiRT uses the Neon Engine, notable in that it was co-developed by Sony Computer Entertainment and is based the PhyreEngine, Sony's free cross-platform engine.CareerDiRT's primary mode is the career mode.  Progression in the game is tracked by a pyramid, and each tier of the pyramid lists the available events.  The bottom portion, with the most events, are the easiest, with the relative difficulty increasing with higher tiers.  You progress in the career mode by completing events and unlocking new ones as you make your way up the pyramid.  Each event pays in cash which in turn will allow you to purchase new vehicles and liveries for your current ones.MultiplayerThe multiplayer portion of DiRT is based off of a match making system.  The player will be placed in a room of other competitors; in the room, the players will vote on which event to race in.  A handful of different events are listed, each event having a designated course and car.  Once an event has been voted for the players are simultaneously connected to the server where each player will race alone.  The top right of the corner, of the screen, has a live tracker displaying the current times of the competitors running closest to you; the driver who completes the leg with the quickest time wins the event.VehiclesCitroën C2Front Wheel Drive Renault Clio Opel Corsa Citroën C2 Suzuki Swift Four Wheel DriveFiat Grande PuntoEvo IX Peugeot 207 Cup  Subaru Impreza WRX STi Spec-C  Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution IX  Peugeot 307 Citroën C4 Concept Colin McRae R4  ClassicToyota CelicaToyota Celica GT-Four  Subaru Impreza 1995 WRX-RA STi version II  Peugeot 205 T16 Lancia Delta S4 Rear Wheel DriveFiat 131 Abarth Lancia Stratos McRae Motorsport Escort Mk2 Renault 5 Maxi Turbo New Stratos by Fenomenon CORR Super BuggyAaron Hawley Super BuggyChevy Silverado Scott Schwalbe Super Buggy  CORR Pro 4Chevrolet Silverado Toyota Tundra Class 1 BuggyMcMillin Racing Car Ickler Jimco buggy Hill Climb Big RigKenworth T2000 Freightliner Century Class S/TToyota Celica GT Pikes Peak Hill Climb UnlimitedMitsubishi FTO Peugeot 405 T16 Pikes Peak Audi Quattro S1 Pikes Peak Suzuki Escudo Toyota Celica GT Pikes Peak Toyota Tacoma Rally Raid T1Mitsubishi L200 Triton Rally Raid UK Desert Warrior Dakar Nissan Pickup BMW X3 CC X-Raid Volkswagen Race Touareg 2 Mitsubishi Montero EVO MPR11 Rally Raid T4Kamaz 4911 MAN TGA Rallycross ModifiedLotus Exige Audi TT Rallycross SupercarsSaab 9-3 T16 Citroën Xsara 4x4 T16 Xbox 360 Game InstallationDiRT requires 6.4GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD.  PC System RequirementsMinimumRecommendedOperating System: Windows XP Processor: Pentium 4 @ 3.0GHz or Athlon 64 3000 Video Card: GeForce 6800 / Radeon X1300 or above RAM Memory: 1 GB Hard Drive Space: 4 GB Sound Card: DirectX 9.0c compatible  Operating System: Windows XP / Vista Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo @ 2.66Ghz or Athlon X2 3800 Video Card: GeForce 8800 or Radeon X1950 or above RAM Memory: 2GB RAM Hard Drive Space: 6 GB Sound Card: DirectX 9.0c compatible </description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20729">GRID</game><game id="6499">RalliSport Challenge 2</game><game id="8944">RalliSport Challenge</game><game id="6276">Rally Trophy</game><game id="20132">Sega Rally Revo</game><game id="5881">Forza Motorsport 2</game><game id="14757">WRC II Extreme</game><game id="15490">Xpand Rally</game><game id="20451">MotorStorm: Pacific Rift</game><game id="20933">Baja: Edge of Control</game><game id="5977">Need for Speed III: Hot Pursuit</game><game id="23461">FUEL</game><game id="1052">Super PickUps</game><game id="23921">MotorM4X</game><game id="8844">Need for Speed: Carbon</game><game id="12976">Need for Speed: Most Wanted</game><game id="13734">TOCA Race Driver 3</game><game id="25226">Need for Speed World</game><game id="25424">MotorStorm: Arctic Edge</game><game id="24793">MotorStorm</game><game id="24995">Forza Motorsport 3</game><game id="6829">Need for Speed: V-Rally 2</game><game id="31982">WRC: FIA World Rally Championship</game><game id="34427">Sega Rally Online Arcade</game><game id="34757">Test Drive V-Rally</game><game id="36993">Project CARS</game><game id="37743">F1 2012</game><game id="33118">GRID 2</game><game id="9110">Xpand Rally Xtreme</game><game id="43066">Trigger Rally</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/13158/960580-gb.png</image></root>