<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>39194</id><name>The Sims 3 Seasons</name><description>OverviewThe Sims 3 Seasons expansion pack adds seasons along with weather effects to the world of The Sims 3. Players can go bobbing for apples, snowboarding, and swim in the ocean. The game also includes new seasonal specific events like a spring fling, and a fall festival. With seasons, there is a new lot designed as a 'Central Square' for each world designed for seasonal festivals. Each season brings new festivals with different festival items. However, there is no new world included with Seasons.AchievementsNameDescriptionMedalNotesA Gnome For Every SeasonCollect all four seasonal gnomesPlatinumAlien Tech ExpertHave your Sim use the UFO to abduct someone, invade a lot, and travel to spaceGoldBottomless StomachHave your Sim win both the Hot Dog and Pie Eating contests.SilverBronzed!Have your Sim keep a tan for 3 Days in a rowBronzeCannonball!Have your Sim do a cannonball off a diving boardBronzeEgg-cellent CollectorHave your Sim find a Festival Egg in an Egg HuntBronzeFair SkinnedHave your Sim get SunburnedBronzeFestival ChampHave your Sim win an apple bobbing contest and a game of horseshoesSilverFestival FanaticHave your Sim attend the Spring, Summer, Fall, and Winter FestivalsSilverFestival FunHave your Sim enter a Haunted House, get face painted, and eat a snow coneBronzeFestive PlannerHave your Sim throw a Pool Party, Costume Party, Feast Party, and a Gift Giving PartySilverFlower PowerHave your Sim collect a wildflowerBronzeHappy Holidays!Have your Sim get a greeting card picture taken and post it onlineBronzeHarsh WeatherHave a Sim freeze to death and another die from heat or fireGoldKaboom!Have your Sim set off a FireworkBronzeLove  DedicationHave your Sim celebrate a wedding anniversarySilverNice Arm!Have your Sim win a water balloon fight and a snowball fightSilverPlaying With NatureHave your Sim use Dr. F's Climatron Control Unit to alter the weatherGoldPrettiest Sim At The DanceHave your Sim attend a Spring Dance and become Spring King or QueenSilverPrize WinnerHave your Sim collect and cash-in some festival ticketsBronzeSavvy BuilderPlace a blueprint using Blueprint ModeBronzeSeasonal WooHooHave your Sim WooHoo in a leaf pile and an iglooSilverSlacker!Have your Sim call in sickBronzeSmoocher!Have your Sim kiss under a mistletoeBronzeSnow SculptorHave your Sim make an igloo, a snowman, and a snow angelBronzeSpooky Day ShenanigansHave your Sim smash a pumpkinBronzeSpooky SculptorHave your Sim carve a pumpkinBronzeStar-Crossed LoversHave your Sim meet an alien, WooHoo with the alien, and have an alien baby.GoldSun WorshipperHave your Sim get a sun tanBronzeThe Language Of LoveHave your Sim send and receive a Love letterBronzeThirds? Fourths?Have your Sim get "Stuff" at a Feast PartyBronzeTrick or TreatHave your Sim Trick or Treat at a houseBronzeWinter ShminterHave your Sim throw a pool party, swim in the ocean and barbeque while snow is on the ground in the winter.Silver</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2351666-seasons.png</image></root>