<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>39301</id><name>Europa Universalis IV</name><description>OverviewEuropa Universalis IV is the latest game in Paradox Interactive's long running Europa Universalis franchise. It was released for PC, Mac and Linux on August 13th, 2013. The game's time frame is set from 1444 to the late 18th century. Like previous games in the series, any nation in the world active during its time frame is playable. As a sandbox game with no true goal, the player will be able to conduct war, diplomacy, trade, and many other managerial aspects of running a country. Europa Universalis IV will use an improved version of Paradox's Clauswitz engine, and bring in UI improvements learned from Crusader Kings II.GameplayThe game is very similar to the previous Europa Universalis 3, but it takes all of the expansions from that game as a baseline for EU4. The game features the ability to play as anyone in the world, from one of the warring Daiymo's of feudal Japan, to the Ottoman Turks, even to the Iroquois of North America. Some countries, however, are higher tier countries, which means that they have much more decisions, events and ideas than others.The game can be played in many different ways, but all of them are dependent on one thing: the new monarch points system. This system has 3 different points, seperated into Military, Diplomacy and Administrative. All 3 points are used for tech upgrades and buildings, but are also used for other things; Administrative is used to core provinces (make provinces officially part of your country) and improve stability, Diplomacy is used to spread your culture to other provinces and lower war exhaustion, Military to enact war taxes and recruit generals and admirals.These monarch points are also tied into the Idea Groups. The Player will get their first group at admin level 4, and these groups will help them specialize their nation with bonuses. For Example, a player playing a colonization nation will probably pick the Exploration idea group, which allows them to recruit explorers to explore the oceans, and allows for colonists. A person playing in Eastern Europe, with very little colonization aspirations, might pick a military group such as Quality or Offensive. Some nations also have unique idea groups for themselves, which unlock based on how many regular ideas the player has unlocked.Trade is one way to expand an empire, and it's one of the things that has been massively changed from EU3. There are trade nodes, which are static areas where trade centers. This trade can either stay there, or be sent upward (the trade ends at 2 nodes, however, which cannot be sent up; Venice and Antwerp). If the player has more provinces in the Wien trade node, they will want to collect from there, but they might also want to send up trade from Constantinople with their other merchant. Each node has trade value, which is how much a node is valued all together, and trade power, which indicates how much money each nation is getting (this can be improved by light ships as well as building trade buildings).The colonization game is one way to expand, and it's one that hasn't changed much from EU3. Each nation has a colonial range (which is improved by Diplomacy tech), but no nation can explore Terra Incognita (land/ocean that is invisible) without explorers. Of course, the Terra Incognita goes away after it's been explored by someone in your tech group after 50 years, so a player can wait until then. You also have colonists, which you can send to a province. These provinces will continue to grow without the colonist there, so a nation can recall them and send them somewhere else, but they will do so much more slowly. Once a colony gets 1000 people, it is now considered a regular province, but instead of the nation getting tax money from them, they get tariffs, which are protected by big ships. Eventually, in the late 1700's, the colonists will usually band together and attempt to rise up to govern themselves, which if they succeed will form a new nation that is based on a real nation today.Warfare also hasn't changed much, but as of 1.2 each battle is much more deadly than it's ever been before. As opposed to Crusader Kings 2, the only army the player has is a standing one. Having a casus belli isn't required, but without it a nation gets -2 stability. The new feature that was added to impede a nation's ability to blob (get bigger) is the coalition. It's an alliance that only works against one country, and can be joined by as many countries as is needed. A belligerent France might get a coalition army against all of the Holy Roman Empire, spain, England...The UI has been much improved. It's easy to see what the player needs to do in order to succeed; the player now gets a choice of three missions to undertake instead of one, which might give them ideas on what to do. If the player has rebels, they can be brought to a screen that will tell them how to deal with them and why it's happening. The economy works a monthly basis, instead of a yearly basis ala EU3. Expansions  DLCThe game launched with one minor expansion, Purple Phoenix. This adds events to the ailing Byzantine Empire, and allows the restoration of the Theme system as well as many other events.They also released The Star and the Crescent in the Digital Extreme Edition pack, an event pack for Muslims. This includes many things about such things as Pilgrimages, controlling the two holy cities of Mecca and Medina, and holy wars.Their next was American Dream, which adds events to the USA.The first major expansion for Europa Universalis IV, Conquest of Paradise, is slated for December 11, 2013 and features new national ideas for Native American tribes and new Native American content, greatly expanded colonial politics and interactions, and an option to play with a randomized New World, allowing for a true Age of Discovery with a new seed every game for players to explore and conquer.Smaller DLC:The Horsement of the CrescentThe Conquest of Constantinople (Music)The Winged HussarsNational MonumentsThe 100 Years War (Unit)National Monuments IISystem RequirementsPC System RequirementsMinimumRecommendedOS: XP/Vista/Windows 7/Windows 8OS: XP/Vista/Windows 7/Windows 8Processor: Intel Pentium IV 2.4 GHz or AMD 3500+Processor: Intel Pentium IV 2.4 GHz or AMD 3500+Memory: 2 GB RAMMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: NVIDIA GeForce 8800 or ATI Radeon X1900, 512mb video memory requiredGraphics: NVIDIA GeForce 8800 or ATI Radeon X1900, 1024mb video memory requiredDirectX: 9.0cDirectX: 9.0cHard Drive: 2 GB HD spaceHard Drive: 2 GB HD spaceSound: DirectX-compatible soundcardSound: DirectX-compatible soundcardOther Requirements: Broadband Internet connectionOther Requirements: Broadband Internet connectionAdditional: Controller support: 3-button mouse, keyboard and speakers. Internet Connection or LAN for multiplayerAdditional: Controller support: 3-button mouse, keyboard and speakers. Internet Connection or LAN for multiplayerMac System RequirementsMinimumRecommendedOS: Mac OS X 10.6.8 or betterOS: Mac OS X 10.6.8 or betterProcessor: Intel Core Duo Processor (2GHz or better)Processor: Intel Core Duo Processor (2GHz or better)Memory: 2 GB RAMMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: ATI Radeon HD 6750 / NVIDIA GeForce 320 / NVIDIA GeForce 9600 or higher, 1024MB graphics memory requiredGraphics: ATI Radeon HD 6750 / NVIDIA GeForce 320 / NVIDIA GeForce 9600 or higher, 1024MB graphics memory requiredHard Drive: 2 GB HD spaceHard Drive: 2 GB HD spaceOther Requirements: Broadband Internet connectionOther Requirements: Broadband Internet connectionAdditional: GLSL 1.3, OpenGL 2.1. Controller support: 3-button mouse, keyboard and speakers. Internet Connection or LAN for multiplayerAdditional: GLSL 1.3, OpenGL 2.1. Controller support: 3-button mouse, keyboard and speakers. Internet Connection or LAN for multiplayerLinux System RequirementsRecommendedMinimumOS: Ubuntu 12.04 LTSOS: Ubuntu 12.04 LTSProcessor: Intel Core Duo Processor (2GHz or better)Processor: Intel Core Duo Processor (2GHz or better)Memory: 2 GB RAMMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: ATI Radeon HD 6750 / NVIDIA GeForce 320 / NVIDIA GeForce 9600 or higher, 1024MB graphics memory requiredGraphics: ATI Radeon HD 6750 / NVIDIA GeForce 320 / NVIDIA GeForce 9600 or higher, 1024MB graphics memory requiredHard Drive: 2 GB HD spaceHard Drive: 2 GB HD spaceOther Requirements: Broadband Internet connectionOther Requirements: Broadband Internet connectionAdditional: GLSL 1.3, OpenGL 2.1. Controller support: 3-button mouse, keyboard and speakers. Internet Connection or LAN for multiplayerAdditional: GLSL 1.3, OpenGL 2.1. Controller support: 3-button mouse, keyboard and speakers. Internet Connection or LAN for multiplayer</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="39594">March of the Eagles</game><game id="23460">Hearts of Iron III</game><game id="36365">Sengoku</game><game id="27917">Victoria II</game><game id="32622">Crusader Kings II</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2331106-box_eu4.png</image></root>