<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>39452</id><name>Hotline Miami</name><description>OverviewThe protagonist using an enemy as a human shield whilst shooting at another.Set in the neon-soaked underground of the 1980s, Hotline Miami is a surreal tale of blood, guns and masks. Focusing on raw brutality and skull-crushing close combat, the game forces players to use their wits to choreograph their way out of impossible situations. It was developed by  Dennaton, a collaboration between designer Jonatan Söderström and artist Dennis Wedin.Hotline Miami features over 20 levels and features 35 unique weapons. It also boasts 26 different masks which alter the gameplay and provide fresh challenges. ReleasesThe game was released on  Steam and  GOG on October 23, 2012 for the  PC, and March 19th 2013 for the  Mac. On February 19th, 2013 a port to Vita and PlayStation 3 was officially announced, being developed by Dutch developer Abstraction Games. They were released on June 25, 2013 and support Sony's Cross Buy program.GameplayHotline Miami is a top-down close quarters action game that combines reflexive real time combat and a need to tactically plan your approach to each level. The player is a nameless, silent protagonist. Each mission begins at the player's apartment, with a message on the answering machine. After receiving the location of your job you walk out to your  DeLorean and are transported to the level where the action takes place.You must choose a mask to wear at the start of each level. These masks are fashioned after animals and confer bonuses to the player such as faster walking, further viewing distance, or the ability to start the level with a weapon already in hand. Each mask is named and they can be unlocked by a combination of high scores and as pick ups within the missions themselves.The game features copious amounts of blood.Most missions are a two level buildings, a series of rooms filled with criminals and guard dogs, all of whom you must kill to progress and all of whom can kill you with a single stroke or bullet. The player can use any method within his means to kill each enemy, including but definitely not limited to, a barehanded knockdown, a one hit kill from any of the games melee weapons, impalement from a throwing knife or at a distance with one of the game's many firearms. Any weapon in the game can be picked up and used to either attack or be thrown, inflicting a kill or knock down depending on the type of weapon and which part of it hits the enemy. If an enemy is knocked-down you must approach and finish them. This can mean embedding a katana into their head, cutting their throat, or bashing their brains out with a bat. Each kill is rewarded with points which contribute to your level score.Hotline Miami combines elements of stealth gameplay (silent kills, line of sight, alerting enemies to your presence) with rapid arcade style action. Whenever you are killed, a quick press of the R button returns you to the beginning of the floor; it's not uncommon for a life to last but a few seconds. This absence of hit points and the very fast reaction time of the enemy AI means that every encounter must be dealt with a combination of planning and reflexive response, giving the gameplay a distinct, satisfying flow. Upon clearing the whole building the music dies down and the player can safely backtrack through their trail of carnage to return to the entrance and complete the chapter. Finally, your level points are accumulated and tallied and you are given a grade score for the level; you might unlock a mask or weapon.StoryHotline Miami takes place in 1989 throughout the titular city of Miami, Florida. The player assumes the role of a nameless anti-hero, starting the game in a derelict basement, being instructed in the finer points of murder by a homeless man. After a vague, dreamlike confrontation with a trio of masked individuals, the player is thrust into a flashback of his "first encounter" with the rooster mask and the game begins in earnest. It is not clear how stable the main character's mind is throughout the game; now and then he will appear to hallucinate and see characters whose jaws are barely hanging on or who have bullet holes in their faces. The game implies that everything you are seeing is on a VHS tape which is periodically fast-forward, rewound, and mysteriously edited.The story develops in various ways as each mission unfolds. You glimpse portions of the story through the environmental details of your home, the newspaper clippings of your exploits, the messages left on your machine and surreptitious, the post-mission payment pick-ups in the form of some free goods at one of four rotating businesses (including a VHS Rental and Pizzeria). Through these glimpses it ultimately becomes clear that the criminals you kill each night are affiliated with the Russian Mafia. Discovering who is providing the work and ordering the hits remains the primary story goal of the game up to and beyond the final chapter.EndingsHotline Miami has three separate endings. The first is the resolution of the main character's story. After completing the 15th chapter and defeating the (supposed) final boss there is a cut-scene and the credits sequence begins. Then the tape rewinds, and three more missions that task the player to find out who is behind the answering machine messages become available. The twist comes in that you are now controlling a character who had been previously encountered as a boss. Completing these chapters and defeating another boss will unlock the second ending. The third ending can be seen by using a computer terminal in chapter 19 and inputting a password. This password is gained by collecting the letters (signified by small purple pixels with a white dot in the center) in each level and placing them in order in the pause menu "Puzzle" screen. Once unlocked this password will automatically be entered into the terminal on the next play through and award the final ending.ChaptersMetro (Prelude)No Talk (Chapter One)Overdose (Chapter Two)Decadence (Chapter Three)Tension (Chapter Four)Full House (Chapter Five)Clean Hit (Chapter Six)Neighbors (Chapter Seven)Push It (Chapter Eight)Crackdown (Chapter Nine)Hot  Heavy (Chapter Ten)Deadline (Chapter Eleven)Trauma (Chapter Twelve)Assault (Chapter Thirteen)Vengeance (Chapter Fourteen)Showdown (Final Chapter)Safehouse (Chapter Sixteen)Fun  Games (Chapter Seventeen)Prank Call (Chapter Eighteen)Resolution (Chapter Nineteen)Highball (Bonus Chapter)MasksThe mask selection menu.There are 26 masks available in the game. Each mask, with the exception of Richard, provides some bonus or modification to gameplay. These masks are unlocked by either achieving high scores or finding them as pick-ups within the levels.Mask NameAnimalDescriptionLocationRichardRooster(no bonus)Default maskRasmusOwlAn Eye for SecretsAchieve high score in MetroTonyTigerFists of FuryAchieve high score in No TalkAubreyPigMore GunsAchieve a high score in OverdoseDon JuanHorseLethal DoorsAchieve a high score in DecadenceGrahamRabbitWalk FastAchieve a high score in TensionDennisWolfStart with KnifeAchieve a high score in Full HouseGeorgeGiraffeLook FurtherAchieve a high score in Clean HitTedDogDogs Don't AttackAchieve a high score in NeighborsRufusElephantSurvive One BulletAchieve a high score in Push ItRamiCamelExtra AmmoAchieve a high score in CrackdownWillemMonkeyRip and StealAchieve a high score in Hot  HeavyPeterUnicornQuiet GunshotsAchieve a high score in DeadlineZackFrogLonger Combo WindowAchieve a high score in AssaultOscarMoleDarknessAchieve a high score in VengeanceRickFoxGood ShotAchieve a high score in SafehouseBrandonPantherWalk FasterAchieve a high score in Fun  GamesCharlieOctopusMore Melee WeaponsKitchen area in SafehouseLouieChameleonHard to SpotBeat the game with the normal endingPhilFishFrench TranslationUnderground section of ResolutionNigelBatReversed ControlsBeat the game with the secret endingEarlWalrusSurvive Two BulletsSecond floor in OverdoseJonesAlligatorMore GoreSewer drain in Full HouseCarlGrasshopperStart with DrillDance room in first floor of Push ItJakeCobraKilling ThrowsNW top floor in Hot  HeavyRichterRatStart with Silenced UziNE top floor in AssaultRussellBullRaging BullNext to dumpster in Metro (PS3 exclusive) MusicSince its release Hotline Miami's soundtrack has won numerous awards and accolades and for many fans of the game it is large contributor to the title's success. Song TitleArtist1.Horse SteppinSun Araw2.HydrogenM.O.O.N.3.ParisM.O.O.N.4.CrystalsM.O.O.N.5.VengeancePerturbator6.Deep CoverSun Araw7.MiamiJasper Byrne8.HotlineJasper Byrne9.Knock KnockScattle10.Musikk per atomatikkElliot Berlin11.Miami DiscoPerturbator12.ReleaseM.O.O.N.13.A New MorningEirik Suhrke14.FlatlineScattle15.Silver LightsCoconuts16.DaisukeEl Huervo feat. Shelby Cinca17.CrushEl Huervo18.ElectricDreamsPerturbator19.Inner AnimalScattle20.It's Safe NowScattle21.To The TopScattle System RequirementsPCMinimumOS: Microsoft® Windows® XP / Vista / 7Processor: 1.2GHz processorMemory: 512 MB RAMGraphics: DirectX 8-compatible graphics card with at least 32MB of video memoryDirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 250 MB HD spaceRecommendedOS: Microsoft® Windows® XP / Vista / 7Processor: 1.4GHz processor or fasterMemory: 1 GB RAMGraphics: DirectX 8-compatible graphics card with at least 32MB of video memoryDirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 250 MB HD spaceMacMinimumOS: Mac OS 10.6+Processor: 2.4 GHz Intel Core 2 Duo or betterMemory: 1 GB RAMHard Drive: 130 MB HD spaceRecommendedOS: Mac OS 10.6+Processor: 2.8 GHz Intel Core 2 Duo or betterMemory: 2 GB RAMHard Drive: 130 MB HD space*Only the Windows version has native controller support</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13567">Grand Theft Auto</game><game id="31558">Retro City Rampage</game><game id="15736">Take No Prisoners</game><game id="7382">Loaded</game><game id="2893">Re-Loaded</game><game id="15891">Postal</game><game id="6108">Manhunt</game><game id="40739">Teleglitch</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2343271-hotline_miami_poster_728x1024.jpg</image></root>