<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3954</id><name>Europa 1400: The Guild</name><description>OverviewEuropa 1400: The Guild is a simulation game set in the middle ages, your objective in the game is to gain both money and power by correctly managing their chosen business and getting elected to goverment offices.  GameplayWhen starting a new game you can choose your parents which will give your character different stats in several attributes that can make your character more suited for a specific line of work. After you have choosen your business you start the game, you can run your shop doing everything from buying materials in the town marketplace to hiring workers. Besides running your business you can engage in varied activities like for example updraging your house, hire spies to snoop on people, blackmail, accuse someone of a crime, run for office, Etc. Regardless of what type of action you are performing you have a time limit that runs from the morning to the late evening in game time, this time frame is considered as one year. Once the time limit runs out you get a detailed report of your earnings and are able to start the next period. Occupations There are various types of jobs you can choose to run, some legal some not. Here's a list of them: BlacksmithJoinerStone MasonAlchemistPerfumerLandlordThiefPreacherMoney LenderRobberGuardsmanTrader</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2875">Knights of Honor</game><game id="8760">1503 A.D.: The New World</game><game id="23459">Dawn of Discovery</game><game id="23547">Anno 1701: Dawn of Discovery</game><game id="3992">1193 Anno Domini - Merchants and Crusaders</game><game id="995">1701 A.D.</game><game id="2161">1701 A.D.: The Curse of the Dragon</game><game id="6442">1503 A.D.: Treasures, Monsters and Pirates</game><game id="6724">1602 A.D.</game><game id="14065">Medieval Lords: Build, Defend, Expand</game><game id="14385">Medieval Lords: Soldier Kings of Europe</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/15/155745/2170755-7484_europa_1400_les_marchands_du_moyen_age_the_guild_pc.jpg</image></root>