<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>39586</id><name>Middle Manager of Justice</name><description>OverviewMiddle Manager of Justice is free-to-play time-management simulation layered with some light RPG progression.The game launched officially in December of 2012, though it was accidentally released a few months earlier. It is available for iOS devices. Android versions are currently not planned but will be considered down the line.GameplayThe Middle ManagerThe action in Middle Manager of Justice falls in to one of two halves: base management, and patrol.Base ManagementThe game starts off in the base management mode. As the manager of a sort of "Super Hero Office" it is your task to hire heroes, schedule their activities, and develop them and the office in order to expand city territory that your branch is responsible for. As progress is made, new facilities can be added to the base, allowing for more activities to be delegated to your heroes.HotheadThere are six rooms which can be added to the base. These range from a training room which allows heroes to raise base stats, to a research lab where they can unlock new equipment or consumables. There is some flexibility in which order rooms are added, and to where resources are allocated when adding or upgrading workstations to rooms, which gives the game a slight Theme Hospital feel.An overview of the baseWhile in base management mode, the player must also give the heroes (and their avatar) tasks to work on, or they will stand around doing nothing in the center hall. All tasks take a set amount of time, which can be skipped using currency which can be purchased for real money, or won in-game. The main conflict of the game arises from trying to efficiently assign tasks to the heroes and manager, in an effort to stay ahead of crime happening in the city.Both the player's avatar (the manager) and the employed heroes level up and have abilities which can be unlocked and improved. Once a character has unlocked an ability, they can spend time at home base in order to improve (level up) that specific ability. Each ability has two or three tiers, which can be gated by level. Heroes can also raise their base stats by spending time to improve them, but the number of times they can do this is limited to five sessions per level. Max level is currently capped at 15.PatrolHero selection interfaceWhile the player has the game running, crimes will start to spring up in the city. These crimes come with a timer, and as they are neglected, the happiness of the territory being victimized decreases, which in turn lowers the yield of coins received from the territory. This section of the gameplay is most like other free-to-play games like Jurassic Park: Builder, where the player is encouraged to return to the screen often to collect in-game currency.The player can dispatch up to four heroes to stop a crime taking place, and has the choice to watch the event or delegate it. If the player decides to watch, they effectively control the heroes in an active-time battle somewhat like those in Chrono Trigger (though much more simplified.) Alternatively, the player can delegate the fight, meaning it will auto-resolve with a percentage chance of success, after a set amount of time, allowing the player to spend more time doing other things.Masked MummyAll time-sensitive actions occur in real-time while the game is being played, so the player must hop back and forth between the city map and the base to make sure they are not leaving heroes idle, nor allowing too much crime to go unpunished. The game pauses when not being played, so no progress (for good or ill) occurs while the game is closed.Superheroes@ManSurge ProtectorCrimebot@Man uses advanced gadgetry and social media connectedness to thwart evil.Captain Premium has been fighting crime since before you were born. He mostly consults these days, but for the right coin he'll knock some heads for you.Crimebot was created by Cranium for the purposes of evil, but installed the evil chip upside down. Now Crimebot is all about justice.Galaxy Girl's planet was destroyed while she was vacationing on earth. Bummer for her, but great for your branch! She is now a cosmic force for hire!Hot Head has a short fuse. When he gets hot under the collar, flames erupt! He goes to anger management, but it isn't helping.Masked Mummy was exhumed while building the foundation of the Giza Branch of Justice. He wears a mask to conceal his identity.Surge Protector accidentally knocked multiple appliances into the bathtub at the exact time of a lighting strike. Did she die? Nope. Super Powers.Sweet Justice lucked out when he bought a vintage costume on an auction website and found it to be imbued with power. He donned it to become... Sweet Justice!The Cosmic CrowbarRoomsCubicles and GymBedroom: Heroes reser here to restore their healthCubicles: Heroes do sales work here to bring in some extra incomeLab and BedroomGym: Heroes train up their stats here with intense workoutsLab: Heroes do research here to unlock new itemsPractice: Heroes can train and discover new abilities hereRec Room: Heroes hang out here to improve moraleCurrencyThere are two types of currency used in the game: coins and Superium.Coins are generated by the territories protected by the player and must be harvested regularly by tapping on them in the city map. Coins are used to upgrade the base as well as buy equipment or consumables for heroes.Superium is the premium currency in the game, which can be purchased for real world money, or can be found in-game for defeating boss battles (usually 10 Superium per victory). It can be used to purchase hero booster packs, which give the player the choice to hire one of three randomly selected heroes (out of a larger hero pool) or to speed up tasks. The player is not required to ever purchase Superium in order to play the game.Premium Currency Exchange rateItemAmount ReceivedPriceDollop of Superium15 Superium$0.99Bucket of Superium85 Superium$4.99Crate of Superium200 Superium$9.99Vat of Superium450 Superium$19.99Coin Copier2 for 1 earned currency$1.99Hero PacksEcono-Hero Pack: This is a rough economy but luckily there are still some low level heroes that will work for you on the cheap (Level 1 Hero for 10 Superium).Adequate Hero Pack: Have a little expendable income? Maybe it's time to get some heroes with a little more experience (Level 5 Hero for 20 Superium).Deluxe Hero Pack: Headhunter fees, relo packing, signing bonuses... if you want senior level heroes on your team, you're going to have to pony up (Level 10 Hero for 30 Superium)!</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="38711">Pocket Planes</game><game id="37630">The Simpsons: Tapped Out</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2393381-mzl.kelrmzif.png</image></root>