<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>39594</id><name>March of the Eagles</name><description>OverviewMarch of the Eagles is a grand-strategy game, based on the Europa Universalis series, focusing on Europe between 1805 and 1820; specifically the Napoleonic Wars. The player is able to control any European nation during the time frame. The game has taken a lot of the political and trade strategy elements from the Victoria games and added them to the Europa style of Grand Strategy, and given more of an emphasis to the 'combat' side of things.FeaturesThe game is based on the Napoleonic Wars, and as such is much more war focused than most of the other grand strategy games that Paradox develops; it is also much shorter, spanning only 15 years at most. The map is based on Europe, stretching from Portugal to the Urals. Though you can play any European nation that existed in the time frame, only 8 can win on their own. Those countries are:AustriaFranceGreat BritainPrussiaRussiaSpainSwedenThe Ottoman EmpireAny other country must ally with one of the main countries to win. Each main power has it's victory conditions, which require them to have 7 specific land provinces and 7 specific port provinces, each unique to the country in question; though if the game ends before this happens, the country with the most prestige will end up the winner. Each main country also has their own ideas, which impact the country as a whole; the Ottoman Empire, for example, has an idea that lowers revolt risk. The game also features historical events. The multiplayer allows for up to 32 players to join.Warfare is the main focus of the game, and as such is very intricate and complex. You must build your armies, and you must decide on the armies' composition. Each standing army has 3 brigades, as well as reserves, and each of those brigades may be lead by a commander. The commander has 3 stats; Offensive, which determines how effective your army is at killing the other's troops; Defensive, which determines how much men you lose, and Maneuver, which impacts how fast the army is and how much attrition it suffers. They also have traits, which improves stats, which are earned by successfully completing battles (or unsuccessfully). Each flank of an army can decide on individual tactics they wish to employ during the battle, including holds, feints and counters. There is a supply chain system, so that players who wish to invade deep into a country must protect the chain to keep the army supplied; otherwise the army's morale lowers and they gain less reinforcements. The game also features naval combat.System RequirementsMinimumOS:Windows XP/Vista/7Processor:Intel® Pentium® IV 2.4 GHz or AMD 3500+Memory:2 GB RAMGraphics:NVIDIA® GeForce 8800 or ATI Radeon® X1900 video card, 512Mb graphics memory required with a resolution of at least 1024 x 768 or greaterDirectX®:9.0Hard Drive:2 GB HD spaceSound:DirectX® CompatibleOther Requirements:Broadband Internet connectionAdditional:3-button mouse, keyboard, speakers, Internet connection for multiplayerRecommendedAdditional:3-button mouse, keyboard, speakers, Internet connection for multiplayer</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="27917">Victoria II</game><game id="23460">Hearts of Iron III</game><game id="39301">Europa Universalis IV</game><game id="32622">Crusader Kings II</game><game id="29207">Europa Universalis: For the Glory</game><game id="32847">Europa Universalis III: Divine Wind</game><game id="36365">Sengoku</game><game id="19845">Crusader Kings</game><game id="18641">Victoria: Revolutions</game><game id="18049">Victoria: An Empire Under the Sun</game><game id="37997">Mount &amp; Blade Warband: Napoleonic Wars</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2348411-eagles.png</image></root>