<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>39682</id><name>Call of Juarez: Gunslinger</name><description>OverviewCall of Juarez: Gunslinger is a downloadable game for PS3, Xbox 360,  PC and the fourth game in the Call of Juarez series. The game goes back to the times of cowboys and outlaws, with the player portraying famous bounty hunter Silas Greaves. The game’s story is unfolds through a series of flashbacks while Silas recalls his adventures to a group in a saloon, which is provided as dynamic narration throughout the game. Over the course of the game Silas will interact with many of the iconic legends of the Old West such as Billy the Kid, Jesse James, Butch Cassidy  the Sundance Kid, and more.GameplayThe game is a linear first person shooter, where players work their way through 14 levels by completing objectives, and often ending a level with a pistol duel. All kills net the player XP, while stringing together multiple kills and performing headshots gives the player bonus points. XP goes towards assigning points to three different skill trees; dual-wielding (handguns), long-range (rifle), or close-quarters (shotgun).Players can also enter Concentration Mode once its meter is full, which is a brief bullet time that also highlights enemies. If a player is about to die, they can be given one last chance to dodge what would otherwise be a fatal bullet by leaning left or right, giving them a second chance to finish the fight. Collectibles are scattered throughout each map called Nuggets of Truth, which are bits of trivia about the Old West and the outlaws you encounter throughout the story. They are accessible upon finding and anytime after in the pause menu.If you don't attain them all the first time, you can always nab collectibles through another play-through, or through the game's challenging New Game Plus mode.ReceptionCall of Juarez: Gunslinger scored well among critics and sits just below 80 on Metacritic. Though the game's specific success (or lack thereof) in sales is unclear, Ubisoft has said that it's "very happy" with the game's reception.System RequirementsMinimumProcessor: 2 GHz Intel® Core™2 Duo or 2 GHz AMD Athlon™ 64 X2Video Card: 512 MB DirectX® 9.0c–compliantMemory: 2 GB RAMOS: Windows® XP (SP3) / Windows Vista® (SP2) / Windows® 7 (SP1) / Windows® 8HDD Space: 5 GB HD spaceSound: DirectX 9.0c–compliantRecommendedProcessor: 3 GHz Intel® Core™2 Duo or 3 GHz AMD Athlon™ 64 X2 or betterVideo Card: 1024 MB DirectX 10–compliant or higherMemory: 4 GB RAMOS: Windows® 7 (SP1)HDD Space: 5 GB HD spaceSound: 5.1 surround sound</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25066">Call of Juarez: Bound in Blood</game><game id="21191">Call of Juarez</game><game id="8873">GUN</game><game id="36055">Borderlands 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2457093-box_cojgs.png</image></root>