<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>39698</id><name>Planetary Annihilation</name><description>OverviewPlanetary Annihilation is a game created by Uber Entertainment, initially funded by the public. The game will be designed and developed in the spirit of Total Annihilation, a successful RTS game from the late 90's in which you start with a single über-unit called Commander that has to conquer the map by creating units and (re-)using resources. The game will allow you to conquer not only pieces of land, but entire planets and solar systems. The game will allow the player to zoom all the way from solar-system level to ground unit level. KickstarterThe game was announced as a Kickstarter project, with an initial funding request of $900,000. The project raised over $2 million before pledges were locked, reaching enough to add planet types such as Ocean and Metal planets, and an Orchestral soundtrack rather than Midi. Pre ReleasePre-orders for the game opened on January 16, 2013. Users who funded the Kickstarter over $60, and those who pre-order the game will gain access to the alpha and beta tests.The Alpha was released around June 7th, 2013.The Beta is planned to be released around September, with the full game in December. GameplayTotal AnnihilationBeing a spiritual sequel to TA, PA features many of the same mechanics, some expanded upon:It uses a flow economy, which produces and uses resources constantly, when your stockpile is empty your production is crippled dependent on the negative amount.It has a focus on macro-, rather than micro-management.There is a wide range of units, split across Bots, Vehicles, Amphibious Vehicles, Planes, Ships and Submarines, with orbital combat planned for either release or a later expansion.Buildings and units are split across 2 tech levels (Normally referred to as T1 and T2), with Advanced buildings and units being stronger/more powerful/brilliant for specific uses.Defenses are more powerful than other RTS', with players having to attack with a larger force and using the terrain/planet to strike at the opponents' base. Planetary AnnihilationThe newer bits and pieces of PA are focused around the amount of units that a player can control:There is one 'Race' of units and buildings, with other races not being developed by Uber, but which can be added by the modding community after release.There will be inter-planetary combat between planets/moons, with it being Invasions and Game-enders, rather than with spaceships and assault pods.The planet types (Earth-Like, Desert, Ice, Water, Metal, Gas) will be randomly generated for each match, however Players can use a generator to bring in their own and set-up their own maps.ChronoCamUnlike other RTS', PA will feature a replay system that allows spectators/players to at any point go back through the game, and either view or give commands to units whilst the game is still playing, an example being to see how a unit was destroyed, or to see that cool explosion one more time. ModdingOne aim of the game is to allow it to be extremely moddable, allowing the community to add in their own races, units, planets, scenarios and entire game modes if they choose to; with another aim being to make it relatively easy.During the Alpha there has already been a set of mods made (Albeit simple ones), one changing the strategic icons to those used in Supreme Commander, another looking into making the game colour-blind friendly, and one adding in a building to show how it's done.System RequirementsPCMinimumOS: Windows Vista SP2 64-bit Processor: 32 or 64-bit Dual Core or better Memory: 4 GB RAM Graphics: Shader 3.0 DirectX®: 9.0c Hard Drive: 2 GB HD space RecommendedProcessor: Quad Core Memory: 8 GB RAM DirectX®: 9.0c Hard Drive: 2 GB HD space MacOS: OS/X 10.7 or 10.8 (64-bit) Processor: 64-bit Dual Core better Memory: 4 GB RAM Graphics: Shader 3.0 Hard Drive: 2 GB HD space LinuxOS: Ubuntu 12.04/13.04, Linux Mint 14  15 Processor: 64-bit Dual Core better Memory: 4 GB RAM Graphics: Shader 3.0 Hard Drive: 2 GB HD space </description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3594">Total Annihilation</game><game id="19680">Total Annihilation: Kingdoms</game><game id="1901">Supreme Commander</game><game id="29806">Monday Night Combat</game><game id="18048">Supreme Commander: Forged Alliance</game><game id="5921">M.A.X.: Mechanized Assault and Exploration</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/11/117587/2313052-pa_logo.jpg</image></root>