<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>39762</id><name>Pokémon Mystery Dungeon: Gates to Infinity</name><description>OverviewThe five playable Pokémon in Gates to InfinityPokémon Mystery Dungeon: Gates to Infinity (ポケモン不思議のダンジョン マグナゲートと∞; Pokémon no Fushigi no Dungeon: Magnagate to Mugendai no Meikyuu, "Pokémon Mystery Dungeon: Magnagate and the Infinite Labyrinth") is the fourth installment in the Pokémon Mystery Dungeon crossover series of roguelike role-playing games, developed by Spike Chunsoft and published by Nintendo for the Nintendo 3DS. It was first released in Japan on November 23rd 2012, followed by a release in North America on March 24th 2013, and finally in Europe and Australia on May 17th and May 18th 2013 respectively. Considering the two duos Blue/Red Rescue Team and Explorers of Darkness/Time as four separate entries in the franchise makes Gates to Infinity the sixth Pokémon Mystery Dungeon game to be published for a Nintendo handheld console, and the ninth overall entry, counting the Japan-exclusive WiiWare titles Pokémon Fushigi no Dungeon: Ikuzo! Arashi/Mezase! Hikari/Susume! Honoo no Boukendan.As in previous Pokémon Mystery Dungeon installments the player takes direct control of a person who has been turned into a Pokémon, and is transported into the Pokémon world where he/she immediately finds a sidekick companion who becomes an invaluable friend to the protagonist throughout their adventures together. This time around the playable Pokémon are Pikachu, Snivy, Tepig, Oshawott and Axew. The player still cannot directly select which Pokémon to use, however, for the first time in the franchise's history, there is no personality quiz to determine the player's Pokémon - instead, a photo of the player taken using the 3DS front-facing camera determines the main character.Local Multiplayer is a first for the Pokémon Mystery Dungeon SeriesPokémon Mystery Dungeon: Gates to Infinity debuts a slew of features for the Pokémon Mystery Dungeon franchise. It is the first game in the series to include Pokémon from the Unova Region, and also the first one in the series to include polygonal graphics to be released outside of Japan. The game also makes frequent use of both cameras on the Nintendo 3DS console and one of its key mechanics makes use of the handheld's augmented reality capabilities. Online functionalities have been implemented in preceding titles, but Gates to Infinity premiered a co-op multiplayer mode for the franchise. The game's multiplayer functionalities are limited to a four-player local multiplayer mode, which in Gates to Infinity is dubbed "Companion Mode". Another new online functionality is the ability to revive other players' Pokémon by using StreetPass.GameplayAs with the titles that preceded it, Gates to Infinity's gameplay features a crossover of two gameplay styles, merging the Mystery Dungeon franchise's staple strategic mechanics with the Pokémon universe.When in a dungeon, Gates to Infinity adopts a turn-based gameplay which has the protagonist, along with a party of allies, traverse several randomly generated dungeons consisting of various floors, each with only one exit which leads to the next floor. All movement within dungeons is grid-based, and any attack or any move from one grid-tile to another counts as a turn. The dungeons are populated by items, traps and rival Pokémon that have a chance of joining the player's party upon being defeated (if there is an available slot). When outside a dungeon, the player's Pokémon can freely roam around Post Town, accompanied by its sidekick Pokémon, visiting shops, accepting quests, and managing party members, among other activities.As in most Pokémon games, the Pokémon in a player's party can evolve, which causes their stats to increase. Also as in most Pokémon games, stats consist of Hit Points (HP), Attack (Atk.), Defense (Def.), Special Attack (Sp. Atk.), Special Defense (Sp. Def.) and Speed (Spd.). The player's Pokémon starts at level 7, instead of level 5 as was the case with other games in the series.New FeaturesMagnagatesYour morning cup of joe will open portals just fineThe eponymous gates lead to special dungeons where the player can control a Pokémon other than the default one. Some of these special dungeons house Legendary Pokémon such as Lugia, Ho-Oh and Kyurem.These portals can be opened by selecting the "Discover a Magnagate" function in the main menu. The game then uses the Nintendo 3DS camera and the console's augmented reality capabilities to detect circular objects. When one is detected, a portal materializes on top of the item, and the player's Pokémon jumps in.Face-Detection SystemAt one point during the game's opening dream sequence, the game will analyze the player's facial features (using the 3DS front-facing camera) in order to determine which Pokémon will be attributed.This is a departure from the series' staple method of choosing a Pokémon depending on the answers to an introductory personality quiz.Polygonal EnvironmentsThe fully polygonal 3D environments and character models are yet another, and more immediately noticeable, departure from series standards, as Gates to Infinity will be the first fully 3D Pokémon Mystery Dungeon game released for a handheld console (the Japan exclusive WiiWare titles had polygonal graphics).New Online/Connectivity FunctionalitiesThe game will include online functionalities which had never been seen in a previous entry in the Pokémon Mystery Dungeon series, such as an online local co-op mode that can feature up to four players and the ability to save fainted Pokémon via StreetPass connectivity.Online options that had been present in other games, which are mostly asynchronous multiplayer features such as Wonder Mail, are also present in Gates to Infinity.LocationsPost TownPost Town is the game's main city, where the player can shop for items, recruit new members, talk to the townsfolk, etc. Shops and offices at Post Town include:Post TownQuagsire Assembly: Here the player can manage party members;Scraggy's Savvy Moves: Here Pokémon the player has recruited can either forget moves or remember ones that have been forgotten;V-Wheel: At this spinning wheel, owned by a Victini, the player can change the day's V-Wave, which is a "mysterious wind" that boosts the power of a Pokémon type;Azumarill's Request Board: Here the player can take requests before venturing into dungeons.Pokémon ParadisePokémon Paradise acts as the player's base. When it is first encountered it is but a barren wasteland, but it can be built up using items found on expeditions.DungeonsBelow are some of the early dungeons the player will come across. Though the Japanese version of the game has been released, as of this writing the dungeons bellow are the only ones that have had English names officially announced by Nintendo.Dungeon NameNo. of FloorsNotesRagged Mountain5 FloorsFirst region in the game.Stony Cave5 Floors--Hazy Pass8 FloorsWild Pokémon include: Wooper and Audino.Stompstump Peak7 FloorsWild Pokémon include: Bagon and Tympole.Desolate Canyon7 FloorsWild Pokémon include: Croagunk and Blitzle.Forest Grotto8 FloorsWild Pokémon include: Foongus, Litwick, and Croagunk.PlotThe opening dream sequenceOne day, the game's protagonist has a dream where a voice calls out to him/her, tasking the dreamer with the deed to save the Pokémon world. In the dream the main character is met with a reflection of his/her own face, and then this reflection turns into a Pokémon.After having this dream, the protagonist wakes up falling from the skies as a Pokémon, quickly crashing on the surface of a foreign region. When the newly-transformed protagonist comes to, another Pokémon is worriedly trying to help this crash landed outsider. This Pokémon will become the protagonist's invaluable friend and sidekick throughout the game's main story.DLCDownloadable content for Gates to Infinity will include "new dungeons to explore, new items and new Pokémon to interact with". While Japan 12 DLC dungeons have been released, ranging in cost from 150 to 300 yen ($1.60 to $3.20), only 7 dungeons have so far been released in the US, with prices ranging between 2.00$ and 3.50$.These additional can be purchased as soon as the "DLC" option in the main menu is unlocked, but can only be played once the player has completed the game's main story.Below is a list of additional DLC dungeons with an officially announced US release date. The difficulty level listed for each dungeon is as determined by the game's official website.Launch Day DLCPoké ForestDescription: Poké Forest is full of money, in the form of coins and gold bars. Enemies are powerful though often sleeping, in which case they can be avoided.Price: Free for download until April 30th 2013, and 2.00$ starting May 1st 2013Difficulty: Not specifiedFloors: Not specifiedPika LandDescription: A dungeon inhabited by many Pikachu, where "moves level up more quickly than usual", and where items not discoverable in the main storyline dungeons can be found.Price: $2.00Difficulty: ♦♦♦Floors: 12Mt. TravailDescription: Mt. Travail is yet another dungeon where Pokémon's moves "level up more quickly". Valuable items in this dungeon include Training Switches, manuals, and seeds.Price: $2.50Difficulty: ♦♦Floors: 20Skill TreasuryDescription: Skill Treasury is plentiful with Treasure Boxes, which pack valuable items. It is possible to acquire every Team Skill from the Treasure Boxes in this dungeon.Price: $2.50Difficulty: ♦♦Floors: 15April 4th, 2013 DLCIvy ParkDescription: Ivy Park has a high population of Snivy. The dungeon also features the Grass Tile, which permanently boosts the stats of a grass type Pokémon while in the dungeon.Price: $2.00Difficulty: ♦♦♦Floors: 12Scalchop BeachDescription: Scalschop Beach has a high population of Oshawatt. The dungeon also features a Water Device.Price: $2.00Difficulty: ♦♦♦Floors: 12Kecleon BazaarDescription: The Kecleon Bazaar dungeon features many Kecleon Shops, where players can purchase rare items such as TMs.Price: $2.50Difficulty: ♦♦Floors: 20Ultimate WildsDescription: Spanning 99 floors, Ultimate Wilds is the longest, and allegedly hardest dungeon available for Gates to Infinity. It is also the most expensive, at the price 3.50$. Upon completing the dungeon, players are rewarded with the Courage Crown, a special in-game item.Price: $3.50Difficulty: ♦♦♦♦♦Floors: 99April 18th, 2013 DLCAxe RockDescription:Take a trip through the Axe Rock dungeon to encounter many Axew. Axe Rock is also a great place to level up your moves and track down lots of good items! Be sure to return to the dungeon after you beat the main story for even better opportunities to explore its depths!Price: $2.00Difficulty: ♦♦♦Floors: 12Mount TepidDescription:Befriend many Tepig when you explore the depths of Mount Tepid! This 12-floor dungeon is filled with the Fire-type Pokémon, as well as plenty of good items for you to collect. Don't forget to look for a Fire Device, which will permanently boost the stats of the Fire-type Pokémon you give it to.Price: $2.00Difficulty: ♦♦♦Floors: 12Treat RoadDescription:In some dungeons, you need to keep your Belly full. Discover a new type of food that's great for those dungeons: Donuts! Explore Treat Road and find exclusive Mini Donuts, Donuts, and Big Donuts that will keep your Pokémon's hunger at bay. Your Pokémon will also earn Exp. Points when they eat the Donuts you find along Treat Road.Price: $2.50Difficulty: ♦♦♦Floors: 20Strongest TrailDescription:Prepare for another stupendous challenge when you enter Strongest Trail, a 60-floor dungeon filled with some of the toughest Pokémon found anywhere! If you can make it all the way through Strongest Trail, you'll be rewarded with the exclusive Persistence Crown!Price: $3.00Difficulty: ♦♦♦♦♦Floors: 60 ReceptionThe game currently holds a Metacritic score of 64 out of 100, a reception which the online review-aggregator labels as "mixed or average", thereby making Gates to Infinity the Pokémon Mystery Dungeon game with the highest metascore yet.However, it notably has the lowest Metacritic user score a Pokémon Mystery Dungeon game has garnered to date, scoring only an average 7.0 out of 10. This is a notch down from previous Pokémon Mystery Dungeon games which had received a user score ranging between 7.7 and 7.8. While this reception is equally labeled "mixed or average", all other Pokémon Mystery Dungeon games had received a "generally favorable" average user score.PublicationScoreDestructoid8/10Game Informer6.75/10GameSpot5.0/10IGN4.5/10Fan reaction and critical reception of Pokémon Mystery Dungeon games has been disparate since the franchise's first installments. For every new installment online aggregators demonstrated polar opinions between the professional scores and the user scores.Destructoid's Chris Carter echoed the reception of the franchise's fans, in that he found Gates to Infinity to be a welcome addition to the franchise, praising it's "beautiful-looking" visuals, but remarked it's not the best in the series, particularly making note of the toned down difficulty by calling it "an easier adventure". Publications constituting the opposing take on the franchise often found the game to be tedious, such as GameSpot which labeled the game's dungeon crawling as "simplistic".Criticism of Lower DifficultyCritics and fans have criticized the game's noticeably lower level of difficulty, in comparison to previous entries in the series. Several changes to some of the game's core gameplay mechanics indicate the game's difficulty has been toned down from previous Pokémon Mystery Dungeon installments, potentially with the intent of appealing to a broader demographic.Hunger is no longer a factor in the majority of dungeons, and it only starts being implemented once the main storyline has been cleared. Players will no longer lose any items when their party is wiped out inside a dungeon - items are only taken away if the player attempts to steal from a Keckleon shop and is defeated by the irate shop-owner. IQ points, a stat from previous Pokémon Mystery Dungeon games which affected several skills and stats, have now been replaced by Team Skills, which apply to the team as a whole while IQ points were attributed to each Pokémon individually. As a less impactful change, Wonder Orbs are now also usable during boss fights.External LinksOfficial WebsiteOfficial Japan WebsitePokémon Mystery Dungeon: Gates to Infinity at Nintendo.com </description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="40257">The Guided Fate Paradox</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2412938-box_pmdgti.png</image></root>