<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>39815</id><name>Kingdom Hearts HD 1.5 ReMIX</name><description>OverviewKingdom Hearts HD 1.5 Remix is a PS3 compilation of Kingdom Hearts Final Mix, as well as Re: Chain of Memories in which both games have trophy support. The game will also include HD versions of scenes from 358/2 Days that can be viewed in a movie player.DetailsThis version of the original Kingdom Hearts not only contains all of the additions and enhancements added to the PS2 version of Kingdom Hearts Final Mix but also contains a number of brand new gameplay tweaks based on later entries in the series. For a full breakdown of what those changes are please consult the Kingdom Hearts game page.Kingdom Hearts Re: Chain of Memories is mostly the same game it was on the PS2, but has some minor visual changes.Kingdom Hearts 358/2 Days is not playable due to the complications of porting a DS game's control scheme to a home console. However, redone HD cutscenes and even new scenes are available for view in the game, adding up to approximately 3 hours (2 hours and 50 minutes) of footage. This feature also supports trophies.The collection contains 66 rearranged/remixed music tracks across the three games (the majority of which were done for Kingdom Hearts Final Mix though) recorded with live instruments. These new arrangements were over seen by series composer Yoko Shimomura.It has been revealed that one custom Playstation 3 theme each will be unlockable by completing both games. A third Playstation 3 theme will be unlocked if the player watches all the cutscenes from 358/2 Days.Western VersionsOn February 25th 2013, it was announced that the collection would be coming to North America and Europe in addition to Japan. This marks the first time Kingdom Hearts Final Mix will be released outside of Japan and the first time Re: Chain of Memories will be available in Europe. The Western version of the game will be released on September 10, 2013.European LocalizationWhile the North American version will likely rely solely on English voiceovers and English text, the European version will have a slightly different set of options:For Kingdom Hearts Final Mix, the voiceover options will be in English, French and German, while the subtitles and text options will be in English, French, German, Italian and Spanish.For Re: Chain of Memories and 358/2 Days, the voiceovers will be in English only, while the subtitles and text options will be in English, French, German, Italian and Spanish.Pre-Order BonusesBy pre-ordering the collection in North America and Europe, fans will receive a limited edition artbook containing art from the three games included in the collection (including some art that has never before been released officially outside of Japan.)    Additionally by pre-ordering the collection, fans will also receive an exclusive PS3 Dynamic Theme. This theme was available to Japanese audiences who pre-ordered from 7-11 and is a separate from the three unlockable themes the player can get by completing the three games in the collection.Possible 2.5 RemixFrom the minute Square Enix announced 1.5, many have thought that a second HD Collection or 2.5 will be soon to follow. While this has yet to be confirmed, in 1.5 the general credits sequence for the collection shows footage from Kingdom Hearts II Final Mix, Kingdom Hearts Birth by Sleep Final Mix and Kingdom Hearts Coded. This suggests that these three games will be the ones included in a second Kingdom Hearts HD Collection.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="15">Compilation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21094">Star Ocean: The Last Hope</game><game id="32906">Rune Factory: Tides of Destiny</game><game id="25769">Tales of Graces</game><game id="36336">Tales of Graces F</game><game id="20836">Tales of Vesperia</game><game id="42795">Tales of Symphonia Chronicles</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2536364-box_khhd15r.png</image></root>