<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>39854</id><name>Brothers: A Tale of Two Sons</name><description>OverviewBrothers: A Tale of Two Sons is a critically-acclaimed adventure game by Starbreeze Studios. It was developed in collaboration with Swedish filmmaker Josef Fares, who internationally is best known for his film Zozo. It was the first release in the 2013 Summer of Arcade, hitting XBLA on August 7th, 2013. It was later released on Steam for PC and PlayStation Network on September 3rd, 2013.GameplayEach of the brothers is controlled by one dual stick, which means that there is no switching between them, because both are being controlled at all times. The brothers can perform various unique interactions with things in the environment. The game's puzzles revolve mostly around traversal and the mechanics that come from the dual stick controls.StoryThe game revolves around two brothers, whose father is dying, and who can only be saved by a very unique and rare medicine in a far off land. The brothers decide to take action and venture on to save their father.System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows XP SP3Processor: 2.4 GHz Dual Core ProcessorMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: NVIDIA GeForce 8600 /ATI Radeon HD 2600DirectX: Version 9.0Hard Drive: 2 GB available spaceAdditional Notes: Initial installation requires one-time internet connection for Steam authentication; software installations required (included with the game) include Steam Client, DirectX 9, Microsoft .NET 4 Framework, Visual C++ Redistributable 2010, and AMD CPU Drivers (XP Only/AMD Only) </description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6133">Fish Fillets</game><game id="36242">To the Moon</game><game id="37467">Driftmoon</game><game id="32155">Recettear: An Item Shop's Tale</game><game id="42053">Evoland</game><game id="28142">Chantelise</game><game id="36680">Cave Story 3D</game><game id="32085">Bastion</game><game id="21406">Fragile Dreams:  Farewell Ruins of the Moon</game><game id="33629">Dear Esther</game><game id="21120">Flower</game><game id="31772">Journey</game><game id="30380">Limbo</game><game id="42482">Isaac the Adventurer</game><game id="35512">Papo &amp; Yo</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2478646-box_bros.png</image></root>