<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>39902</id><name>Liberation Maiden</name><description>OverviewOriginally part of the Guild 01 collection, Suda 51's Liberation Maiden was released as a standalone 3DS eShop title in Europe on October 4, 2012 following its announcement via a European Nintendo Direct presentation. The game's North American release date is October 25, 2012.GameplayThe player takes control of Shoko Ozoro and her mechanized suit, the Liberator. The 3DS Circle Pad is used to control Shoko's movement while the L button can be used to put her into a strafing mode. Players must use the touch screen to aim the Liberator's reticule at enemies at which point they will be targeted. When the touch screen is released, the Liberator will fire at all targeted enemies.The main goal of each level is to destroy a set amount of Lesser Spike's in order to disable the main force field and gain access to the final Spike. Each level also contains sub-missions which can be completed to receive a higher score. Levels can also be "purified" by Shoko by destroying enemies and objects within overrun areas throughout. Again, this results in a higher score. When a level is completed, it is unlocked in Stage Attack mode and can be replayed in order to try and get a higher score.The game plays very similarly to Kid Icarus: Uprising sharing the same control setup. Unfortunately for left-handed gamers, there is no option to use the A/B/X/Y buttons or Circle Pad Pro when playing Liberation Maiden.GalleryThere are a total of 30 unlockable honors within the game. Each honor can be "liberated" when the set task is complete:Made preparations for warManeuvered in strafing modeReached the edge of the combat zoneAttacked with the Liberator's bladeCompleted a Sub MissionUsed all attack variantsCleared Stage 1Cleared Stage 2Cleared Stage 3Cleared Stage 4Cleared Stage 5Destroyed 300 tanksDestroyed 50 battleshipsDestroyed 50 cannonsDestroyed 30 submarinesDestroyed 100 WalkersDestroyed 50 supply trainsPlayed a total of two hoursPlayed a total of four hoursCompleted over 50 chains100% Purification in Stage 1100% Purification in Stage 2100% Purification in Stage 3100% Purification in Stage 4Completed over 100 chainsCleared a stage without taking damagePlayed the game over 10 times in Normal modePlayed the game over 10 times in Hard modeCleared Stage 1 in Story ModeObtained 100% Approval Rating</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="31734">Kid Icarus: Uprising</game><game id="17578">Rez</game><game id="7393">Sin &amp; Punishment</game><game id="32190">Bulk Slash</game><game id="21238">Metal Wolf Chaos</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/97089/2349930-image2.png</image></root>