<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>40015</id><name>Megpoid the Music</name><description>OverviewMegpoid the Music is a rhythm game developed by ParaPhray for the Playstation Portable. The game focuses on Internet Co., Ltd.'s Vocaloid, GUMI, and features 30 tracks from GUMI's solo catalog from various artists in the Vocaloid community. The game was released only in Japan on March 28th 2013 for the PSP. GameplayLike most rhythm games, Megpoid the Music has the user tapping buttons in time as prompts pass a certain point on the screen. All eight of the PSP's face buttons are used (D-pad + 4 buttons). Unlike its big sister Project Diva, button positions remain static at the left side of the screen and button prompts scroll in from the right. Based on your timing of the button press, more points are awarded. Button prompts appear as taps and holds, both with single and multiple buttons. Players must pass each song before the next is unlocked.There are 4 difficulty settings available in the game. Which one is selected will determine the number of buttons used:Easy - Only Circle and Right are used.Normal - Only Triangle, Circle, Up, and Right are used.Challenge - Only Triangle, Circle, Square, Up, Right, and Left are used.Expert (unlocked after passing each song) - All of the face buttons are used. Song ListMegpoid the Music features some of the more popular songs from GUMI's solo catalog. No songs included in the game feature any of her crossovers with other Vocaloid characters.NOTE: All song appear in an edited format, cutting each of the songs down to about a minute and a half run time. While most of the edits have been handed tastefully, some of them are jarring Song NameEnglish NameProducerPV Link雨が降ってIt is rainingrerulili ロゼッタRosettamonaca@10日P 恋はきっと急上昇☆Love is Surely Soaring☆Noboru↑ ずっとこのままZutto Kono Mamarerulili blue birdblue birdTokuP キリトリセンCuttoff line40mP VERSUSVERSUSUmetora カーニバルCarnivalotetsu 十面相10 FacedYM モザイクロールMosaic rollDECO*27 人生リセットボタンLife Reset Buttonkemu エレクトリック・スターElectric StarHachioujiP 次咲く花の色はTsugi Saku Hana no Iro waTakanon 大空色のHi-To-MiThe Sky Color Pupil Hi-To-MiArukaP EAT MEEAT MEOSTER project レクイヱムRequimPeperon 祭囃子Festival MusicbuzzG キッチンでカッパがタニシ茹でてるKappas are Boiling Slugs in my KitchenIeno Urade Manbouga Shinderu-P ラッパ吹きの少年The Trumpet-Playing BoyPIROPARU raid of glassraid of glassmaya ディストピア・ジパングDystopia ZipangucosMo@Bousou-P カトレアCattleyaYuzuhiko スリープ・スカイ・ウォークSleep Sky WalkYuuyu 会いたいI want to meet youDios/SignalP Happy x ShinyHappy x ShinyBinio メグメグ☆ファイアーエンドレスナイトMegu Megu☆Fire Endless Nightsamfree HolographyHolographyダルビッシュP × Silent Symphonia KiLLER LADYKiLLER LADYHachioujiP 天ノ弱A Born Coward164 ?????のカヴァリエール Maiden Knight </description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23769">Hatsune Miku: Project DIVA</game><game id="30355">Hatsune Miku: Project DIVA 2nd</game><game id="38236">Hatsune Miku: Project DIVA F</game></similar_games><image>NONE</image></root>