<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4017</id><name>Star Wars: Jedi Starfighter</name><description>PlotStar Wars: Jedi Starfighter takes place both before and during the events of Episode II. In the game         Adi Gallia is tasked with testing out the new        Jedi Starfighter, and investigating suspicious activity of the Trade Federation and the Separatists Movement. During her mission, she meets up with  Nym, a returning character form the first game. Nym is a space pirate, forced off of his base by the Trade Federation, along with his crew. Having similar goals, they join up together and investigate the mysterious activity in the system. Eventually they split up after having a disagreement; Gallia wanted to focus on her mission, while Nym was more concerned with finding a new home. However when Gallia is facing defeat during the final battle, Nym and his men arrive and save the day.  GameplayBeing an arcade style game, Star Wars: Jedi Starfighter was very much about taking on large groups of enemies, assaulting large ships, and navigating the environment. Ammo was unlimited, shields recharged, and special abilities operated on a cool down, which all contributed to much less serious gameplay experience. The game also allowed you to issue commands to your wing mates,  Missions very broken down into both primary and secondary objectives. Players could earn bonuses for completing these bonus objectives, which gave them a bronze, silver, or gold ranking at the end of the mission. The mission types were varied, including assaulting targets, aerial dog-fighting,     escorting other ships, and defending locations.   ShipsUnlike the      original game, Jedi Starfigher only had two playable characters with a single ship each. The Jedi Adi Gallia flew a new experimental Jedi Starfighter, which was designed to both be a nimble and powerful ship, but also to focus the Jedi pilot's force abilities to work with the ship. Some of these abilities were a force shield that could both absorb and reflect enemy fire, force lightening that would chain between nearby ships, the ability to concentrate and    slowdown time, and the ability to launch a devastating shockwave out from the ship. Returning character Nym still flies his heavy armed fighter/bomber The Havoc, although it has some new abilites since the last game, including guided missiles, and smart bombs. The game also features several   unlockable ships, including  Boba Fett's ship Slave I, and the precusor to the X-Wing, the Z-95 Headhunter.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="24">Flight Simulator</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13998">Star Wars: Starfighter</game><game id="1715">Star Trek: Invasion</game><game id="4231">Star Wars: Rogue Squadron II: Rogue Leader</game><game id="4544">Colony Wars: Vengeance</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2285710-box_swjs.png</image></root>