<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>40313</id><name>Dynasty Warriors 8</name><description>OverviewDynasty Warriors 8 is the latest entry in the Dynasty Warriors series. The game features the largest playable roster in the series to date with new and returning characters, as well as the return of the Jin faction first introduced in Dynasty Warriors 7.A Playstation 4 version of the game will be released with the launch of the PS4 in Japan on February 22, 2014. A Vita version was also announced.New CharactersIn addition to the brand new characters listed below, Dynasty Warriors 8 retains characters added to Dynasty Warriors 7's Xtreme Legends and Empires expansions, such as Wei's Guo Jia and Shu's Xu Shu.WeiYue JinWeapon: Twin HookswordsGeneral who served under Cao Cao since very early on, he is recognized as one of Wei's Five Generals, along with Zhang Liao, Zhang He, Xu Huang, and Yu Jin.Li DianWeapon: Wheel HalberdGeneral who served Cao Cao and Wei since its earliest years, known for his calmness and being scholarly. Made up one-third of the trio that defended Hefei from the massive Wu army, along with Zhang Liao and Yue Jin.WuLu SuWeapon: RakeAn adviser of Wu ho was instrumental in the alliance between Wu and Shu and matters concerning Jing Province.Han DangWeapon: Short JiVeteran general of Wu, serving Sun Jian, Sun Ce, and Sun Quan.ShuGuan XingWeapon: Wing BladesSecond son of Guan Yu who survived Fan Castle and went on to avenge his father's death alongside Zhang Bao.Zhang BaoWeapon: Snake BladeSong of Zhang Fei and an oath brother to Guan Xing. Along with Xing, avenged his father's death and was a key player in Zhuge LIang's quelling of the Nanman rebellion.Guan YinpingWeapon: Double-sided MaceDaughter of Guan Yu and younger sister of Guan Ping, Guan Xing, and Guan Suo.JinZhang ChunhuaWeapon: Wire ClawsWife of Sima Yi.Jia ChongWeapon: TomahawkClose ally of Sima Zhao.Wen YangWeapon: JavelinGreat warrior compared to Zhao Yun.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2478655-box_dw8.png</image></root>