<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>40611</id><name>Edelweiss Eiden Fantasia</name><description>OverviewEdelweiss Eiden Fantasia is a fan disc of Edelweiss, featuring story paths for 2 popular minor characters from the parent title, Sakura Takase and Rin Fujisaki. Edelweiss Eiden Fantasia was first released in Japan for the Windows PC on August 29th, 2008 by Overdrive. It was later translated and released in English on March 20th, 2010 by MangaGamer.PlotSakura's Arc"If you fall for me, you lose!" The bet is placed between Sakura and Kazushi!Kazushi and Sakura are good friends. It was certainly more of a friendship than a romantic relationship, but that all changed with one exchange."If I got serious, it would be a piece of cake to make Kazushi fall for me.""Yeah, right! If you think you can, then go ahead and try."One picked a fight, the other bought it, and so their love game began. With bets riding on who will win, outsiders begin to help and sabotage both sides, getting everyone involved! Who will be the winner in the end? And what will ever happen to their true feelings?!Rin's ArcEiden Island threatens to sink! Will a talking Johnny save the world?Through their work as class representatives, Kazushi and Rin have grown closer to one another. Just as they began to have feelings for each other, something terrible happens to Kazushi's crotch! His thick Johnny grows a face…and worse, it starts speaking too!!Kazushi takes off from school to deal with the shock, but Rin soon uncovers the change in his Johnny. She decides to help him and they begin to work towards finding a cure while keeping it out of sight. Although he has to worry about his Johnny, Kazushi begins to enjoy his secret life with Rin. Neither of them ever believed it would develop into a huge incident that shook the peace of Eiden Island...HeroinesSakura Takase is very friendly and sociable. She loves to tease her friends, and her main target is Rin.Rin Fujisaki is mild-mannered, shy, and polite. She is a close friend of Sakura and is the main target of her teasing.GameplayEdelweiss Eiden Fantasia is a visual novel with 2 story paths with their own ending and a few dialogue options. Each story path focuses on each heroine. Edelweiss Eiden Fantasia starts with a short prologue, followed by the option to choose a story path.System RequirementsRequired CPU:Pentium III 800MHzRecommended CPU:Pentium 4 1.4GHzRequired Memory:256MBRecommended Memory:384MBRequired Resolution:800x600Required Colors:16bit colorsRecommended Colors:24bit colorsRequired Graphics:4MB VRAMRecommended Graphics:32MB VRAMRequired HDD Free Space:1GBDirectX:DirectX 8.1, Direct3DCreditsProducer / Original Character Designersun NarasakiScreenplayShinji KatakuraMusicTeam NGXmilktub</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="27631">Edelweiss</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/13/134142/2373256-cover.png</image></root>