<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>40803</id><name>Street Fighter X Mega Man</name><description>OverviewOriginally known as Mega Man vs. Street Fighter, the game has classic NES-style graphics, eight new weapons, and casts Street Fighter characters as the eight "Robot" Masters. Mega Man retains many of the abilities he has in later entries in the series, including the ability to slide, charge his mega buster, and ride the Rush Jet.The game is available for free through the Capcom Unity website. It was released exactly 25 years after the Japanese release of the original Mega Man on the Famicom.The game was originally announced at the Street Fighter 25th Anniversary tournament series grand finals, after Capcom representatives promised the unveiling of a never seen before game.GameplayMuch like classic Mega Man titles, you are given a choice between the initial eight bosses and their respective stages. The stages are based off of Street Fighter stages linked to the respective bosses, with 8-bit remixes of their character themes accompanying each.Every boss has a set list of patterns much like other Robot Masters in the series, but they also have a super meter that will fill as you injure them. Once the bar is full, they can unleash a devastating attack.When the eight "Robot" masters are defeated, Mega Man takes on Shadaloo, opening up four more stages (and four more Street Fighter characters to face) much like his encounters with Dr. Wily in the past.MastersRyuThe main protagonist of the Street Fighter series. He was introduced in the original Street Fighter uses Shotokan karate. His level is inspired by his Japan stage from Street Fighter II, with his boss room directly mirroring it. He is shown using his Tatsumaki ability to attack and move across the stage.If Mega Man defeats Ryu, he will obtain Ryu's famous Hadouken.Chun-LiThe main female protagonist of the series. An Interpol investigator, she was introduced in Street Fighter II and uses Tai-Chi. She is able to use her Tenshokyaku ability in the Street Fighter X Mega Man trailer.Mega Man gains her signature Lightning Kick ability upon defeating her.BlankaThe Brazillian feral man introduced in Street Fighter II. He fights with a savage self-taught fighting style that involves him hurling himself at his opponent and producing electricity. How he will fight in Street Fighter X Mega Man is unknown.Defeating Blanka will, oddly, give Mega Man the ability to drop fruit on his enemies, harkening back to Blanka's Tropical Hazard move in the Alpha series.DhalsimDhalsim is a Yoga master that was introduced in Street Fighter II. His fighting style includes spitting fire, teleporting, and using his stretchy limbs to hit opponents from far away.Mega Man is granted the Yoga Inferno technique when he beats Dhalsim.RolentoOriginally a member of the Mad Gears gang from the Final Fight series, he made his debut in Street Fighter Alpha 2 alongside Final Fight protagonist Guy. Rolento uses his special forces training, along with his staff and explosives, to fight.The Mine Sweeper ability is obtained by Mega Man after this battle, allowing him to chuck explosives.RoseAn Italian fortune teller who uses a mysterious fighting style using "Soul Power". She is able to produce and reflect fireball, as well as enchant her scarf with her soul power. She first appeared in Street Fighter Alpha 2.Rose's Soul Satellite, which summons orbs that circle around her, is given to Mega Man upon defeating her.UrienA mysterious man who was born into and taught to fight by a cult called the Illuminati, the main antagonists of Street Fighter III. He was introduced in Street Fighter III: Second Impact.When Mega Man defeats Urien, he gains access to the Aegis Reflector ability, which reflects all projectiles and damages enemies.Crimson ViperA technology expert that is an agent of S.I.N., a division of the infamous Shadaloo and the antagonists of Street Fighter IV. She uses her various gadgetry to electrify enemies with her fists, spew fire from her legs, and create explosions through her Seismic Hammer ground pound.Mega Man gains the Optic Laser upon beating C. Viper, a move of hers that has only been featured in Ultimate Marvel vs. Capcom 3.System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows XP/Vista/Windows 7/Windows 8Processor: Intel Pentium 4 2.0 GHz and upMemory: 1 GB RAMGraphics: DirectX 9.0c/Shader3.0 and up supportedVideo: NVIDIA GeForce 6600 and up,VRAM: 256MB and upSound: DirectSound, DirectX9.0c Compatible Audio</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8605">Marvel vs. Capcom: Clash of Super Heroes</game><game id="9309">Marvel Super Heroes Vs. Street Fighter</game><game id="29286">Castlevania: The Adventure ReBirth</game><game id="20483">Bionic Commando Rearmed</game><game id="26376">Contra ReBirth</game><game id="22845">I Wanna Be The Guy</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/13/136764/2385016-sfxmmtitle.gif</image></root>