<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>40865</id><name>The Binding of Isaac: Rebirth</name><description>OverviewArtstyle Concept featuring Judas and The Duke of Flies.After the great success that was The Binding of Isaac; the game's creator, Edmund McMillen, confirmed on his blog that Isaac will be remade. Or to be more precise, de-made. The recreation of the game as well as the publishing will be handled by Nicalis while McMillen retains 100% creative control.The Binding of Isaac: Rebirth will feature a "de-made" art-style similar to Gameboy Advance games. When asked about this on a Twinfinity livestream, he said it was because he thought "it would be fun". Rebirth will also be built from the ground up on a new engine rather than Adobe Flash, which caused limitations to the original game.Although graphically it could be considered "de-made" the game it self maintains all of the original content from The Binding of Isaac and its Expansion. Rebirth is receiving a similar expansion sized dose of new content. Featuring some new characters, special rooms, enemies, bosses, challenges and a new final chapter. At least a hundred new items are being introduced. Rewards for completing bosses/floors/runs under certain times, and other player actions. Attention has been paced to buff some of the under powered items.(Lemon Mishap) Changes to existing bosses.(Scolex)The game is confirmed to release on the PC and Sony consoles (PS3 and VIta). They are currently trying to work with Nintendo to release the game on their platforms.As of July, the game is expected to come out in early 2014.FeaturesConfirmed FeaturesThe remake will be fully re-tuned, balanced, and improved.Ability to save and return to a play session.The game will feature two player local Co-op Multiplayer.A hundred or more new items.Similar amount of new content as Wrath of the LambPlanned FeaturesAllow players to compete in fair races in Rebirth. Although there is no online multiplayer, players will be able to get a seed code for a particular Isaac run. Send that code to a friend, and when entered in into the game it will generate the same rooms, enemies, items, and floor maps for both players. This will make it possible for players to share runs and thus make it a more fair competition.New cutscenes and voiceovers may be created. McMillen does not want to completely remake the same cutscenes in a different style. They may reuse the old ones and add to them, or remake them all. McMillen also would like to get more of Matthias Bossi's narration in the game (the voice of the intro cutscene).CharactersThe Binding of Isaac: Rebirth will feature two new main Characters. Their names have been hinted as biblical. There will also be a new character that is meant as a more challenging way to play. Requiring tokens to play and starting the game with random items.ItemsTeased New ItemsTiny PlanetA small moon shaped object which gets embedded in Isaac's head. It maximizes the range stat but makes all tears revolve around Isaac's body, much like an attack fly. The idea is that there will be a ton of tears revolving around you, much like the Duke of Flies' flies. Each tear will rotate around you roughly twice and the idea is that it changes the whole dynamic of play. If you have laser it will make a ring of laser.Bomb UpgradeAn item that causes Bombs to explode in a cardinal cross pattern (similar to the Bomberman franchise)</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="31">Dual-Joystick Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="35899">The Binding of Isaac</game><game id="44190">Pixel Boy</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/16/163828/2388558-tumblr_me8mxz9muy1rq0wgw.png</image></root>