<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>40906</id><name>MyCoke</name><description>OverviewTurning decibels into items!MyCoke, previously known as Coke Music or Coke Studios, was an MMO chat game utilized in the marketing of the Coca-Cola brand. Made by Studiocom using core technology from the Sulake Corporation, famous for a similar title - Habbo Hotel. Later developing it's own engine, called Galapagos, the service launched Version 2 of the game in late 2004. On December 6, 2007, MyCoke was shut down, however, users were highly encouraged to join CC-Metro, a part of the 3D world There, a similar experience to Second Life.The Log-In ScreenUsers, after creating their "V-Ego" avatar, could claim product codes from retail Coca-Cola products that would give them in-game currency, called decibels. These could be earned through a handful of mini-games within the game, and could be used to purchase various items to decorate interiors and trade. The main focus relied upon socializing, mixing music, and decorating the interiors of private rooms. The music mixing was tied into the game and presented in public rooms, where the user could receive "Thumbs Up" votes that earned them 10 decibels per thumb.The game was only available (online) between 10:00 AM and 2:00 AM (EST).RoomsMoscow Public RoomThe player could walk, wave, dance, shout, whisper, and play music in their own virtual rooms. Public Rooms were available, often imitating landscapes from around the world, including Sydney, London, Alaska, Miami, Rio de Janeiro, and more. Furni (in-game furniture) could not be placed in these areas, however, this was a place for all to meet.In-game catalogThe Private Rooms allowed for customization of up to 20 rooms to place furni. This included wallpaper, floor tiles, and usable furniture. Users often touted rare items such as Coca-Cola Couches (referred to as CCs) and pinball machines - some of the more expensive items in the catalog. As a result of the tradable furni, it was not uncommon for players to create rooms full of furni as storage. In addition to these storage spaces, it was also quite common for users to create mazes with the furniture. By being able to move the furni in realtime, contests were held with prizes ranging from Coca-Cola coolers to retro mini-bars. Promotional items were introduced into the economy as the game was sponsored by affiliated corporations like American Idol, while also promoting Batman Begins, FIFA, and Shark Tale.Often users would horde items for trade in their Private RoomsGames and DecibelsThere were a number of ways users could earn decibels - the currency of MyCoke.In-game Furni"Thumbs Up" votes from other users while performing their music made in the in-game Trax machine. Users were given 10 decibels for every "thumb."Drinking Virtual Coca-Colas would net users 10 decibels (up to 100 per day). These could be found in any of the game's vending locations.Surveys provided the users with a chance to receive 200 (originally 500) decibels per month. Usually this was tied to a third-party product.Creating accounts gave 5000 decibels to the users. Typically this could be gamed, where users would make multiple accounts and purchase furni to transfer to their main account.Within the game were actual mini-games that used their "V-ego" in competition against other users for both decibels and furni. The games that were accessible while the main servers were full included:Alaska Public RoomV-ego San: a rock-paper-scissors sumo wrestling game, where a move was chosen before each turn. After repeatedly winning, users could be rewarded with decibels along with furni, starting at a tatami mat and eventually leading to a gong.Uncover The Music: a matching game. Decibels were rewarded upon victory.MyCoke Coaster: two teams of two players would race each other in a game that tested both memory and speed. Decibels were rewarded upon victory.Recycler: a single-player game where the player would have to maneuver around obstacles in a factory setting. The game was timed and the objective was to get the highest score. A specific amount of points would net the user themed items in the form of a robot statue or gear chair.Quiz Game: two players competed against one another to see who could answer correctly first. Decibels were rewarded upon victory.Similarities to Habbo HotelFurni TradingSittingFunctioning (turning lights on and off)Creating and managing a room Flooring and WallpaperDeleting entire roomsKicking playersMoving and rotating furniSittingPlayer-owned and Public Rooms A main view and main menu to choose these options fromRoom ratingsSquare-by-square walking spacesStrong language filtersBots (found in Public Rooms)Currency (decibels) Catalog for purchasing furniChoice of Male and Female Avatar Ability to change clothes (and color)Infinite inventory spaceAbility to move your avatar with a clickMotto's (blurb-like; edit your motto from the main menu and it would be visible in the studio)Talking and shoutingDancing and waving optionsStaying idle for a length of time (half hour) results in the avatar closing its eyes (sleeping animation)Making and sharing musicOperated by Sulake Corporation (for a short time on Coke Studios)Designed by Pixel art</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23072">Habbo Hotel</game><game id="40002">Pixeline: Star Hotel</game><game id="22581">PlayStation Home</game><game id="2268">RuneScape</game><game id="20237">Second Life</game><game id="22991">There</game><game id="17463">The Sims</game><game id="2473">The Sims 2</game><game id="20581">The Sims 3</game><game id="1842">The Urbz: Sims in the City</game><game id="35494">Wooz World</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/7030/2391783-mycokepic5jy_2.jpg</image></root>