<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>41088</id><name>Pokémon X/Y</name><description>OverviewThe game's starter Pokémon: Chespin (grass), Fennekin (fire), and Froakie (water).Pokémon X and Pokémon Y was released to the Nintendo 3DS worldwide on October 12, 2013. This marks the sixth generation of Pokémon games, and the first mainline Pokemon games to feature full 3D polygonal graphics. The game features a large number of new Pokémon (including the new starter Pokémon, Chespin, Fennekin and Froakie), as well as returning Pokémon such as Pikachu, Lucario, and the Pokémon Red/Blue starters, Bulbasaur, Charmander and Squirtle. It also introduces the all-new Fairy Type; the first new Pokémon type since 2000's Pokémon Gold/Silver. Other major new mechanics include Mega Evolution - a new temporary power-up that can change the stats, abilities and even Types of select Pokémon, including Blastoise, Mewtwo and Garchomp - Pokémon-Amie (a Nintendogs-esque tool for interacting with Pokémon via the 3DS touchscreen), trainer customization (allowing control over the hairstyle, clothing and skin tone over your player character) and Super Training, giving more in-depth information on each Pokémon's unique specialties.SettingA player character roller skating in an area reminiscent of Paris, France.Pokémon X  Y is set in the region of Kalos, a new region inspired by the country of France. The French inspiration is particularly noticeable in Lumiose City, a new city heavily reminiscent of Paris, down to the large, Eiffel Tower-esque landmark in the city center.As in previous Pokémon games, the Kalos region features a variety of different climates and terrains, including beaches, frigid mountains, grasslands and a desert. Kalos is notable for the large amount of rivers running throughout the region.Previous inspirations for the Pokémon games were various regions of Japan (Kanto, Johto, Hoenn, Sinnoh) and The United States of America (Unova).StoryThe Japanese logos (Pocket Monsters X and Pocket Monsters Y).The 'X' and 'Y' of the titles suggests a theme of genetics, because of the X and Y chromosomes. Additionally, the games' Japanese logos both contain a DNA double helix.Changes and New Editions from Previous Games in the SeriesPokémon X and Y make several significant changes from previous games in the series. Most notable amongst these is the transition to fully 3D polygonal visuals in both the overworld and in battles. This sees battles being somewhat more animated than in previous games, similar in presentation to the Pokémon Stadium games.The games are also the first to see a simultaneous worldwide release, a big change from the games' usual Japan-first release dates.A total of 69 new Pokémon have been added bringing the total number of Pokémon to 718.This generation also adds "Fairy" as a Pokémon type. New Pokémon, like Sylveon, and existing ones, like Jigglypuff and Marill, will fall into this category. Fairy-type moves are "super effective" against Dragon-type Pokémon.Now players can walk in 8 different direction unlike the previous 4 directions from the older games. There will also be the ability to ride some Pokémon in certain situations though the exact details are unknown at this point.The ability to have battles in the Sky is also added, it will be similar to previous environments but only flying types and those that can levitate will be able to participate.Horde Encounters can now take place where the player can take on up to 5 wild Pokémon in battle. These will serve as a fast way to gain experience but the player's Pokémon will have to withstand all the attacks of the wild Pokémon.A new method of evolution has been added; Mega Evolution allows certain Pokémon to evolve to different, powerful, forms such as MegaMewtwo, MegaBlaziken, and MegaLucario among others. To Mega Evolve these Pokémon, they need to be holding a special Mega Stone item unique to their species. Mega evolution seems to be a temporary change in form, beginning when the Pokémon begins battle and ends when they leave it.X Exclusive PokemonStaryu - StarmiePinsirHoundour - HoundoomPoochyena - MightyenaAron - Lairon - AggronSawk Swirlix - SlurpuffClauncher - ClawitzerXerneasY Exclusive PokemonShellder - CloysterHeracrossLarvitar - Pupitar - TyranitarElectrike - ManectricPurrloin - LiepardThrohSpritzee - AromatisseSkrelp - DragalgeYveltal</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="33382">Ni no Kuni: Wrath of the White Witch</game><game id="41934">Youkai Watch</game><game id="16234">DemiKids: Dark Version</game><game id="15485">DemiKids: Light Version</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/82063/2482818-pokemonxy.jpg</image></root>