<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>41146</id><name>Game Dev Tycoon</name><description>OverviewGame Dev Tycoon is a tycoon-style title which puts the player in control of their own video game development franchise which spans a user-determined time range of 25-35 years at the dawn of the PC era. Players have the ability to create and market new titles, build their own game engines and even embark on larger projects like constructing a video game delivery network. Game Play DetailsThe player begins by choosing a company name, character name and basic avatar styles. Development is done by a single employee working out of a garage in the beginning, who hand-codes basic game types for either the PC platform or the "G64" platform. As the player gains research points and experience they are able to unlock new abilities, such as better graphics and audio programming skills, the ability to construct a game engine and more. Each game release rewards the player with skill points and, depending on critical reception of the title, both loyal fans and money. The object is to create the best game company at the end of the allotted time, although game play extends beyond the base timeframe. Release DetailsGame Dev Tycoon was released exclusively on Windows 8 in early 2013 and will be available as Windows 7 and Mac OSX releases in the Spring of 2013.A free demo which allows for basic game play for 5 years is available for Mac and PC.The game is currently listed in the Steam Greenlight program. The developers said if you buy a copy of the game now they will send you a steam code if it passes Steam Greenlight.System RequirementsPCMinimumOS: Windows XP SP3 Processor: 2 GHz dual core Memory: 2 GB RAM Graphics: Hardware Accelerated Graphics with dedicated memory Additional Notes: minimum resolution of 1024x768RecommendedOS: Windows 7/8 Memory: 4 GB RAM Graphics: Hardware Accelerated Graphics with 2GB memoryMacMinimumOS: Mac OS 10.7.5+ Processor: 2 GHz dual core Memory: 2 GB RAM Graphics: Hardware Accelerated Graphics with dedicated memory Additional Notes: minimum resolution of 1024x768RecommendedOS: Mac OS 10.8 Memory: 4 GB RAM Graphics: Hardware Accelerated Graphics with 2GB memory</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="42505">GameBiz 3</game><game id="32908">Game Dev Story</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2481853-box_gdt.png</image></root>