<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4114</id><name>Desperados 2: Cooper's Revenge</name><description>StoryCooper's brother, Marshal Ross Cooper, has been killed by a criminal known as Angel Face and John wants to avenge him. He gathers his friends once again and together they start looking for any clue that would lead them to Ross' killer. Soon they find out John's brother was killed because he was investigating evil plans between soldiers and the Indians.Characters John CooperBounty hunter and leader of the gang, wielding a rapid firing Remington Army 1875 and throwing knives. He can carry unconscious or dead bodies. In this sequel he can't climb walls or mountains like he could in the first game. He carries a pocket watch that plays a tune after a short period, used to distract or lure guards. He and Sam share the same strike power, being able to knock most enemies out with one single blow, although not permanently. His outfit is exactly the same as the one from the original game.   Kate O'HaraA professional gambler. Beautiful and seductively charming she has a knack for luring guards ready to ambush or knock-out with a kick. She does not have her poker cards to attract the enemies attention in this game. The mirror from the first game was replaced by a make-up powder, which Kate blows at her opponent's eyes. The make-up doesn't have the great range the mirror had, but its blind effect lasts longer and it doesn't need a sunny spot to work. Kate can also pretend she is fainting, attracting the attention of enemies such as soldiers. She can also tie knocked out opponents with a rope, and is the second most silent character in the game, only after Hawkeye. She also carries a powerful but short range Derringer. She wears a dress similar to the one she was first seen with in the original game.Doc McCoyA physician and scientist. He wields a powerful Cold Buntline Special which he employs crafted high-precision bullets essentially turning a revolver into a sniper rifle. He also carries vials of knock-out gas that can be thrown or carried by balloons. He is able to revive unconscious characters and heal wounded allies. He doesn't have his Scarecrow Substitute ability anymore, but can tie knocked out characters with a rope this time around. Together with Kate, he has the weakest strike power between the game's protagonists, needing two strikes to knock enemies out, and is an accomplished lockpick and safecracker. His outfit is exactly the same as the one from the original game.  Samuel WilliamsCooper's African-American friend. Obsessed with explosives, heavy weapons (and pretty women) he wields dynamite, nytroglicerin and can use a bunch of dynamites in the same fashion he used barrels of TNT in the first game. He does not carry a rattlesnake in a sack like before though, neither is able to  use fixed Gatling guns.  He also has a long range Winchester rifle. His outfit is the one that changed the most from the first game: now he wears a hat and an orange shirt. His voice is the one that changed the most too (due to voice actors changes), but his quotes are very similar to the ones from the first game: "Kid's play!" and "That was easy!" are some examples. He can still tie opponents with a rope.   Pablo SanchezA Mexican bandit leader. He has tequila which can be used to attract and inebriate enemies. He does not fake siestas like he could in Wanted Dead or Alive anymore. He carries a sawn-off shotgun that can hit multiple enemies at once and is able to carry Gatling guns. He can still carry bodies or knocked out people, both enemy and friendly units, however this time he can only carry one person. He still uses stones to knock out enemies. Together with Hawkeye, he has the strongest strike from the game, permanently knocking enemies out without killing them.HawkeyeIndian member of the team and the son of Indian chief White Wolf. He is equipped with a Bow  Arrow, a Tomahawk, an Indian War Cry ability that distracts enemies, and Witchcraft Healing powers. He can also bring his hand down on an enemy's head like a Karate chop, permanently knocking them out. He is first seen in an army camp. Cooper wants to interrogate him, but Hawkeye is being held captive by the soldiers. As Cooper, Kate and Doc try to free him, they discover that the indians are planning an ambush on a caravan Sam and Sanchez are protecting. As the soldiers leave to their headquarters (with Hawkeye with them) the team splits up: John and Doc go warn Sam and Sanchez, while Kate follows the soldiers and tries to free Hawkeye. She succeeds reaching his cell, however, he is so weak he cannot even stand up. When the others show up, Doc is able to cure Hawkeye, which leads to him joining the team.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8873">GUN</game><game id="9608">Helldorado</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/7/73970/2289614-desperados2_front.jpg</image></root>