<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4124</id><name>The King of Fighters '97</name><description>Overview The King of Fighters '97 is a 2D 3-on-3 fighting game developed and published by                       SNK for the                      Neo Geo. It is the fourth installment in the                     King of Fighters series, featuring new teams, two distinct playing styles, and the conclusive part of the "Orochi Saga". Despite the events of                 King of Fighters '96, where Orochi servant                Goenitz caused destruction before being defeated, the King of Fighters tournament only grew in popularity. The story involves the "New Faces Team", three bandmates (                   Yashiro Nanakase,                   Shermie, and                  Chris), who enter the tournament and is later revealed to be the last three servants of Orochi, using the tournament to ressurect Orochi.  Along with the New Faces Team, three characters from               Fatal Fury 3 and the              Real Bout Fatal Fury series form the '97 Special Team:             Ryuji Yamazaki,            Blue Mary, and           Billy Kane.          Kasumi Todoh of the Women Fighters Team was replaced by         Chizuru Kagura.        Shingo Yabuki makes his debut in The King of Fighters '97 with no team association. The Boss Team and Iori Team disbanded, with       Iori Yagami as a playable character with no team association. A special version of Kyo Kusanagi (with movesets prior to      The King of Fighters '96) is playable as a secret character, alongside secret versions of Iori,     Leona, and the New Faces Team.  This is also the only King of Fighters game where there is only battle music for certain characters (such as Kyo and the '97 Special Team). For the rest of the characters, only ambience can be heard.Gameplay While the gameplay is similar to the previous installments, one mechanic unique to The King of Fighters '97 (and its sequel) is the ability to choose between two distinct play styles:  Advanced Loosely based on   The King of Fighters '96, the advanced mode uses a revamped power gauge that charges whenever the player strikes the opponent or performs a special move. Players can stock up to three consecutive gauges, which can each be discarded to either perform their Super Special Move or enter a "MAX" mode, a special state where their offense and defense are improved. Pressing Light Punch and Light Kick and a joystick direction performs a roll forwards or backwards.Extra Based on the installments prior to The King of Fighters '96, where there is one power gauge that can only be filled by manually charging it up or defending your opponent's attacks. Once the gauge is filled, the player enters "MAX" mode automatically. Players can only perform Super Special Moves when they are in "MAX" mode (which depletes the gauge) or when their life gauge is 25% or less (as indicated by it flashing red). Pressing Light Punch and Light Kick performs a quick dodge.Characters Japan Team    Kyo Kusanagi (also has an EX version)                                                                                                                                                 Benimaru Nikaido                                                                                                                                                Goro Daimon     Fatal Fury Team                                                                                                                                               Terry Bogard                                                                                                                                              Andy Bogard                                                                                                                                             Joe Higashi     Art of Fighting Team                                                                                                                                            Ryo Sakazaki                                                                                                                                           Robert Garcia                                      Yuri Sakazaki     Ikari Warriors Team                                                                                           Leona (with a cursed Leona fighting as a sub-boss)                                                                                                                                     Ralf Jones                                                                                                                                   Clark SteelPsycho Soldier Team                                                                                                                                          Athena Asamiya                                                                                                                                        Sie Kensou                                                                                                                                       Chin Gentsai Women Fighters Team     Chizuru Kagura                                                                                      Mai Shiranui                                                                                     King     Korea Team                                                                                                                                Kim Kaphwan                                                                                                                               Chang Koehan                                                                                                                              Choi Bounge New Face Team    Yashiro Nanakase (with enhanced abilities as a sub-boss)    Shermie (with enhanced abilities as a sub-boss)    Chris (with enhanced abilities as a sub-boss, transforms into Orochi for the boss) '97 Special Team                                Ryuji Yamazaki                               Blue Mary                              Billy KaneOther     Iori Yagami (with a cursed Iori fighting as a sub-boss)                            Shingo Yabuki</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8680">Street Fighter Alpha 3 MAX</game><game id="3185">ClayFighter 63 1/3</game><game id="243">Street Fighter II: The World Warrior</game><game id="11156">X-Men vs. Street Fighter</game><game id="7751">Art of Fighting Anthology</game><game id="3744">Def Jam: Fight for NY</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="1328">Street Fighter Alpha 3</game><game id="19134">Street Fighter Alpha 2</game><game id="1615">Street Fighter III: 3rd Strike</game><game id="11802">Street Fighter Alpha: Warriors' Dreams</game><game id="16793">Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="22362">Street Fighter II': Hyper Fighting</game><game id="18484">Killer Instinct</game><game id="21952">Killer Instinct 2</game><game id="10614">Killer Instinct Gold</game><game id="21277">Ultimate Mortal Kombat</game><game id="17631">Groove on Fight: Gouketsuji Ichizoku 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/678/429614-kof97_boxartneogeo.jpg</image></root>