<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>41346</id><name>Shin Megami Tensei X Fire Emblem</name><description>OverviewSome of the SMT characters shown in the debut teaser trailer.Shin Megami Tensei X Fire Emblem is a joint venture between Nintendo and Atlus, announced at the Nintendo Direct on January 23, 2013. The upcoming Wii U game is a crossover between Atlus's Shin Megami Tensei series and Nintendo's Fire Emblem franchise, and is being codeveloped by Atlus and the Nintendo studio Intelligent Systems. The first teaser trailer for the game didn't show any gameplay, but rather preexisting artwork of characters from both franchises. The game has been classified as an RPG on the Index Corporation website.Shin Megami Tensei X Fire Emblem is an early example of a new initiative by Nintendo to partner with and provide assistance to third parties in order to produce platform exclusives. Though Nintendo has finite resources to produce games internally, they can share resources with third-party studios to assist in the development of external projects, resulting in collaborations such as this Shin Megami Tensei/Fire Emblem crossover.Nintendo's Hitoshi Yagami, while not speaking at length about the game, hinted in a July 2013 interview at a possible direction that the game will take:"For a long time, I’ve wanted to create a Fire Emblem in our times, in the real world. Imagine a Pegasus that comes from the sky and lands on Building 109 of Shibuya, Tokyo. I always thought that would be incredible. At the same time, I know it’s hard because of how Fire Emblem is. I visited many companies to express these ideas. When I went to Atlus, I was told that Shin Megami Tensei together with Fire Emblem is what I wanted. So, I soon said that to Intelligent Systems and started this very special collaboration. Oops! I shouldn’t say that the game takes place in the real world. We haven’t announced it, right?"The Shin Megami Tensei series is frequently set in varying incarnations of modern Tokyo, but whether the game will actually be set in Tokyo either whole or in part is unknown.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23693">Cross Edge</game><game id="37959">Project X Zone</game><game id="9369">Namco x Capcom</game><game id="37054">Pokémon Conquest</game><game id="26556">Trinity Universe</game><game id="30364">Ys vs. Sora no Kiseki: Alternative Saga</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/16/164924/2419533-shinten.png</image></root>