<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4134</id><name>Norse by Norse West: The Return of the Lost Vikings</name><description>Norse by Norse West: The Return of the Lost Vikings adds in a bunch of new abilities for the original lost Vikings, but also throws two new characters into the mix: Fang and Scorch.Character Abilities:All Versions: Erik the Swift has the ability to     double jump due to his rocket boots, which allows him to not only break walls in front of him, but also above him. On top of this, he now has the ability to swim.Baleog the Fierce now has a robotic arm, rather than a bow and arrow as in the previous game. It allows him to grab things from a distance, as well as swing from special orbs.Olaf the Stout is given the ability to shrink to a much smaller size, allowing him to get into much smaller spaces. He is also given the ability to fart, which allows him to break through blocks underneath him, as well as give him extra lift and speed while he is parachuting with his shield.Fang, a werewolf, can run and jump, attack enemies with his claws, and cling onto walls.Scorch, a dragon, has the ability to fly for short periods of time, glide in the air similarly to Olaf, and shoot fire projectiles.SNES Only:In the SNES version of the game, more abilities can be unlocked at the beginning of the game by killing Erik on the first level by double jumping off of Olaf's shield and falling to his death. This gives the following abilities only found in the SNES version:Erik can now shoot sparks from his hands.Baleog can slide across the ground while slashing his sword, making him temporarily invincible.Olaf can attack enemies by     teleporting into them.Fang can "electrify" himself while he's standing still, allowing him to become temporarily invincible.Scorch can fly indefinitely.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4036">Project Eden</game><game id="7817">Fantasy World Dizzy</game><game id="1446">Lemmings</game><game id="8671">Gobliiins</game><game id="1798">Gex</game><game id="24739">Trine</game><game id="15000">Donkey Kong 64</game><game id="19990">Maui Mallard in Cold Shadow</game><game id="18350">The Adventures of Lomax</game><game id="27812">Transformers Animated: The Game</game><game id="2263">Little Magic</game><game id="31661">Trine 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/14/149200/2266461-lost_vikings_2_a.jpg</image></root>