<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>41402</id><name>Sonic Tweet</name><description>By allowing the account @SONIC_TWEET_JP to read and use one's tweets (after downloading the app, of course), players could help Sonic defeat different variations of Robotnik from various 16-bit entries of the series. The game had numerous restrictions to prevent cheating, but essentially, one word of a player's tweets was selected at random and assigned a value, which would be how much damage Robotnik would receive. Defeating Robotnik would yield a random trading card from one of 35 different Sonic games. Players also received experience points and could level up for the chance to do more damage to Robotnik. Three times a day, up to five cards per time, players could trade cards with other players.Sonic Tweet was available starting July 5, 2011. On the 18th of the same month, the app overloaded due to too many players attempting to access it. It remained unavailable until August 9, 2011, when it returned and granted all players with a free Sonic the Hedgehog card #19 for their patience.Sonic Tweet ended on December 31, 2011.Below is a list of all of the possible cards in the series, listed by game:Sonic the HedgehogMotoraGaniganiBatabataBeetonMeleonPukupukuNalBasaranArmaMogurinTontonRockyPickyCuckyRickyPeckyFlickyDr. EggmanSonic the HedgehogSonic the Hedgehog (Game Gear)MotoraBeetonBatabataGaniganiMeleonYadrinRockyPeckyCuckyRickyPeckyPockyFlickyDr. EggmanSonic the HedgehogSonic the Hedgehog 2AiaiPiranhaBunbunTsuntsunGholaOctarZakinKani PunchDawsonKamakillerKokekkoZauraMecha SonicDr. EggmanMiles "Tails" ProwerSonic the HedgehogSuper SonicSonic the Hedgehog 2 (Game Gear)GamegameDrillinNew MotoraButonZaririnTarabanBombMeleonArijigoku MechaGachau MechaMecha ButaMecha SonicDr. EggmanMiles "Tails" ProwerSonic the HedgehogSonic the Hedgehog CDAntonMosquiPatabataKamakamaKumokumoNoronoroSasoriMechabuBatapyonEGG-HVC-001Dr. EggmanMetal SonicAmy RoseSonic the HedgehogSonic  TailsBane MotoraBeatonTsunotsunoHopping Egg VulcanDokabutonFroggerKiller TurkeyKamado MaxGreat Bane Motora GoldDangerous Ball TowerDr. EggmanMiles "Tails" ProwerSonic the HedgehogSonic DriftDr. Eggman  Egg TyphoonAmy  BreezeTails  MTP-01 WhirlwindSonic  CycloneSonic the Hedgehog 3SaicloneSaruderJawzunHarisenboTogemaneKamakiriHalogenMoeveShell StarPenpenDendenDr. EggmanKnuckles the EchidnaMiles "Tails" ProwerSonic the HedgehogSonic  KnucklesMogumoguKekkoHiddenTonbarTefutefuPonponChuchuSkorpMambaGardiEggRoboDr. EggmanKnuckles the EchidnaMiles "Tails" ProwerSonic the HedgehogSonic  Tails 2BomberberryKamekaRabibinPenguin BomberSpidal TapMecha HiyokoBomblurMetal SonicDr. EggmanKnuckles the EchidnaMiles "Tails" ProwerSonic the HedgehogSonic Drift 2Knuckles  TempestDr. Eggman  Egg TyphoonAmy  BreezeMetal Sonic  Blue DevilTails  MTP-02 Whirlwind S7Sonic  CycloneTails' SkypatrolBarunganBifuraiTobikoshi CrowMinokichiGonTashaCapture BerryBound HeadHanerutonDorigameCarrotiaBearengerFockewulfWitchcartMiles "Tails" ProwerTails AdventureJuniperBomb Nage SentouinJump SentouinShogyokuteki SentouinToseki SentouinMecha Golem No. 5Dr. FukurokovBattle Cuckoo 16thGrand Battle Cuckoo 15thMiles "Tails" ProwerSonic LabyrinthFlowerwaPeppepeToririKabutotoOctotoTakokoRobototoDragogoGaikokoMecha GorillaKani PearlNeedle ManSmiley BombDr. EggmanSonic the HedgehogG SonicAiaiHalogenOctopusGholaEgg SaucerDr. EggmanKnuckles the EchidnaSonic the HedgehogSonic REggRoboMetal KnucklesTails DollMetal SonicDr. EggmanAmy RoseKnuckles the EchidnaMiles "Tails" ProwerSonic the HedgehogSuper SonicSonic AdventureKikiEgg KeeperRhinoTankSpinnerSpiky SpinnerChaoDr. EggmanBig the CatE-102 GammaAmy RoseKnuckles the EchidnaMiles "Tails" ProwerTikalChaos 0Perfect ChaosSonic the HedgehogSonic Adventure 2GUN BeetleGUN HunterBooBigfootKing Boom BooEgg GolemHero ChaoDark ChaoMaria  Prof. RobotnikAmy RoseRouge the BatKnuckles the EchidnaDr. EggmanMiles "Tails" ProwerShadow the HedgehogSonic the HedgehogSonic AdvanceGamigamiKikiKerokeroSenbonRhinoTankTentouMoguSlotoHanabiiDr. EggmanKnuckles the EchidnaAmy RoseMiles "Tails" ProwerSonic the HedgehogSonic Advance 2KurakuraKoraStarHammerheadBellPiko PikoPenEgg Hammertank 2Egg BombertankDr. EggmanCream  CheeseKnuckles the EchidnaAmy RoseMiles "Tails" ProwerSonic the HedgehogSonic BattleChaos 0E-102 GammaDr. EggmanRouge the BatCream  CheeseShadow the HedgehogAmy RoseKnuckles the EchidnaMiles "Tails" ProwerEmerlSonic the HedgehogSonic HeroesCameronEgg KlagenFalcoEgg FlapperEgg BishopEgg HammerE-2000Egg AlbatrossEgg HawkDr. EggmanMetal SonicTeam ChaotixTeam RoseTeam DarkTeam SonicSonic Advance 3SpinnerApeGekogekoStingerMinimoguGemerlDr. EggmanCream  CheeseKnuckles the EchidnaAmy RoseMiles "Tails" ProwerSonic the HedgehogShadow the HedgehogGUN HeishiGUN BeetleEgg PawnBlack BullEgg BreakerMaria RobotnikShireikanDr. EggmanCharmy BeeEspio the ChameleonVector the CrocodileRouge the BatAmy RoseKnuckles the EchidnaMiles "Tails" ProwerSonic the HedgehogDoom's EyeBlack DoomShadow the HedgehogSonic RushEgg PawnFlapperCannon FlapperEgg BishopMega Egg HammerEgg TurtleEgg ScarabEggman NegaDr. EggmanKnuckles the EchidnaCream  CheeseMiles "Tails" ProwerBlaze the CatSonic the HedgehogSonic RidersAiAiE-10000GDr. EggmanNiGHTSCream the RabbitRouge the BatUlalaE-10000RAmy RoseShadow the HedgehogStorm the AlbatrossWave the SwallowKnuckles the EchidnaMiles "Tails" ProwerJet the HawkSonic the HedgehogSonic the HedgehogEgg GunnerEgg RounderIblis BiterIblis TakerIblis GolemEgg GuardianEgg CannonEgg GenesisEgg CerberusIblisMephilesDr. EggmanAmy RoseBlaze the CatRouge the BatE-123 OmegaKnuckles the EchidnaMiles "Tails" ProwerSilver the HedgehogShadow the HedgehogPrincess EliseSonic the HedgehogSonic to Himitsu no RinguRed DjinnBlue DjinnGreen DjinnRafflesiaGolem DjinnGargoyle DjinnSlime DjinnSkeleton DjinnSand ScorpionCaptain BemothKing ShahryārSinbadAli BabaErazor DjinnShahraSonic the HedgehogSonic Rush AdventurePirate GunPirate HoganPteraTriceratankGhost RexGhost PendulumGhost KrakenGhost PirateGhost WhaleJohnnyCaptain WhiskerBlaze the CatMarine the RaccoonMiles "Tails" ProwerSonic the HedgehogSonic Riders: Shooting Star StorySCR-HDSCR-GPAmigoNiGHTSBilly HatcherSilver the HedgehogCream the RabbitDr. EggmanRouge the BatBlaze the CatAmy RoseShadow the HedgehogStorm the AlbatrossWave the SwallowKnuckles the EchidnaMiles "Tails" ProwerJet the HawkSonic the HedgehogSonic World AdventureEgg FighterEgg LauncherRed Killer BeeNightmareAero ChaserBig MotherMiles "Tails" ProwerDr. EggmanProfessor PickleAmy RoseDark GaiaChipSonic the WerehogSonic the HedgehogSuper SonicSonic to Ankoku no KishiFish Ones (Aka)Soldier Ones (Ken)Soldier Ones (Yari)Eyeball OnesGiant OnesNimueKajiyaPercivalGawainLancelotBlack KnightMerlinaCaliburnSonic the HedgehogSonic the Hedgehog 4: Episode 1MotoraMeleonHarisenboBatabataStingerPukupukuHalogenMogurinUnidusKamakillerKani PunchDr. EggmanSonic the HedgehogSonic ColorsEgg PawnEgg PawnEgg PawnSpinnerStingerWispWispWispWispCubotOrbotDr. EggmanYackerMiles "Tails" ProwerSonic the HedgehogSonic Free RidersE-10000GBlaze the CatSilver the HedgehogVector the CrocodileCream the RabbitAmy RoseE-10000BRouge the BatShadow the HedgehogOmochaoDr. EggmanStorm the AlbatrossWave the SwallowKnuckles the EchidnaMiles "Tails" ProwerJet the HawkSonic the HedgehogTrivia/NotesOddly, despite the game featuring cards for two games in which he is prominent, Fang the Sniper does not get any cards.</description><genres><genre id="36">Text Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/16/164924/2422299-tweet.gif</image></root>