<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>41416</id><name>The Mighty Quest for Epic Loot</name><description>GameplayThe attack portion of the game. The gameplay of The Mighty Quest for Epic Loot is split into two parts, attack and defence. In the attack portion of the game, the game plays like a traditional Action-RPG such as Diablo. It is played from an isometric view and the players main goal is to get to the player made castles ''treasure room'' which will reward them with loot, gold and experience. Once the castle has be conquered, players can leave a rating and a comment for the creator of the castle to see. There are 3 main classes for attack mode, each with distinct personalities and skill trees.The Archer - (Blackeye Bowgart) - specializes in crossbows and ranged combat.The Knight - (Sir Painhammer) - specializes in swords and melee combat.The Mage - (The Earl of Evilosity) - specializes in powerful spells and ranged combat. In the defence portion of the game, it plays more like a tower defensive game, in which players must construct a castle placing various traps, minions and obstacles to protect the loot they have gained from being stolen. People will actively try to invade your castle to obtain your loot, so you must perfect your castles layout to make it as difficult for them as possible. Pricing modelThe game is free-to-play and therefore has an in-game premium currency that can be purchased using real money. Certain things able to be purchased with the premium currency contain loot, inventory slots, hero skins and weapons. Closed betaAt the E3 Ubisoft press conference 2013, the first trailer was shown and it was announced that the game was available for closed beta. There are two ways people can currently get into the beta, sign up and wait to be accepted or purchased one of several packs that would allow them instance access to the beta and several other perks.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5985">Diablo</game><game id="32255">Torchlight II</game><game id="25983">Torchlight</game><game id="8638">Titan Quest</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/15/154509/2422948-600full_the_mighty_quest_for_epic_loot_cover.jpg.png</image></root>