<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>41457</id><name>Arabian Fight</name><description>This 1991 Arabian-themed beat 'em up was known for featuring 4-player co-op gameplay and impressive pseudo-3D sprite-scaling effects. As a result, the game was never ported to home systems because the advanced pseudo-3D effects produced using the 32-bit Sega System 32 arcade system was too complex for home systems at the time.A similar (though technically less sophisticated) game released the following year was Taito's 1992 Arabian-themed beat 'em up, Arabian Magic, which also featured 4-player co-op gameplay.PlotThe corrupt Sheikh Sazabiss has abducted Princess Lurana, and he is utilizing every unscrupulous means of power he has at his disposal to achieve his ultimate ambition of conquering the world. The quartet of warriors; brave Sinbat (not a misspelling of "Sinbad"), courageous Ramaya, fearless Goldor and valiant Datta, now bravely come face-to-face with Sheikh Sazabiss.As they battle to save Princess Lurana, the foursome encounter opponent after opponent. Freely using magic, their most prized possession, they journey to the infamous castle of Sazabiss to save Princess Lurana from the pirate ship and release planet Earth from the hands of Sheikh Sazabiss.GameplayArabian Fight uses an Arabian theme, with similarities to Arabian Nights stories such as Sinbad. The gameplay is very similar to many beat 'em ups of the generation, and to Sega's other side-scrolling beat 'em ups Golden Axe and Streets of Rage, using three action buttons, one to punch, one to kick and one for a special attack; in this case, magic based, similar to Golden Axe special attacks. Characters can also throw their opponents. Items can be collected from chests, as well as some enemies, to give extra points, restore health and grant the character their special attack.Four players may play at once with one of four selectable characters, Sinbat, Ramaya, Goldor or Datta: Sinbat is the game's young, handsome hero, Ramaya is the game's young, attractive female, Goldor is the game's muscle character, who appears to be older than Sinbat and Ramaya, and Datta is a spiritual-looking bald man.The game is visually impressive, using sprite-scaling techniques to allow characters to move to the far back of the screen and give a feeling of perspective. The game also makes use of the foreground, something rarely done at this time, characters become large anime animations to perform special attacks very close to the screen, some so close that only their torso and head will fit. Likewise, enemies will jump from the foreground to fight; characters cannot be hit while in these animations.CharactersSinbatRamayaGoldorDattaPrincess LuranaSheikh SazabissSega System 32 hardwareMain CPU: 32-bit NEC V60 @ 16.108 MhzSound CPU: 8-bit Zilog Z80 @ 8.054 MhzFM Sound Chip: 2x Yamaha YM3438 @ 8.054 MhzPCM Sound Chip: Ricoh RF5C68 @ 12.5 MhzResolution: 320x224Colour: 16-bit colour (16,384 colours) </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="29497">OSman</game><game id="24632">Violent Storm</game><game id="41205">Gaia Crusaders</game><game id="2536">Altered Beast</game><game id="21832">Golden Axe: The Revenge of Death Adder</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/97089/2425550-poster.png</image></root>