<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>41518</id><name>Assassin's Creed IV: Black Flag</name><description>OverviewTechnically a prequel to the previous game in the series Assassin's Creed III, this game tells the story of Edward Kenway, father of Haytham Kenway and grandfather of Connor Kenway. Edward is an Assassin who also dabbles as a Privateer (read: Pirate). He is described as a brash, charismatic, reckless, cocky genius of a pirate. He has been deemed a pirate first and foremost, while being an assassin is most definitely a secondary characteristic.Development began in the summer of 2011 by an entirely new team, as the game was being penned by the scriptwriter of Assassin's Creed: Revelations.The game will ship on both current and next gen consoles, with PS3 and PS4 versions including "60 minutes of exclusive gameplay" featuring Aveline de Grandpre from Assassin's Creed III: Liberation. Despite these claims of exclusivity, this content will also be available on PC. SettingThe game primarily takes place in the 18th century in locations across the Caribbean, including Haiti, Jamaica, the coast of Florida, Cuba, the Bahamas, and Nassau. The year is 1715, piracy in Black Flag is serious, eschewing the comedic tropes many associate with the era in favor of a more realistic take on pirates--the kind that murder and pillage. The pirates in the game will be based in reality, featuring the famous Black Beard. Other pirates named include Charles Vane, Calico Jack, Anne Bonny, Ben Hornigold, and a different take on the now-famous Jack Sparrow. A focus upon real-world occurrences, just as in previous games, will be a primary motivation for the narrative - including Bartholomew Roberts' assault on 42 Portuguese ships, the marooning of Charles Vane, and the Spanish Armada shipwreck.Stormy seasGameplayShip-boarding gameplayThe game is an open-world naval experience with seamless boarding, tropical storms, harpooning (for whales), and underwater gameplay (exploring shipwrecks - with enemies including sharks). Approximately 40% of the game will occur across the sea, as the other 60% will remain on land - with "50 unique locations" including fisherman villages, jungles, temples, plantations, forts, complete islands, and Mayan ruins. Each of the areas have different gameplay focuses. For example, the Mayan ruins will be based around puzzle solving and platforming, while the Coconut Islands will be inhabited by enemies to fight. The three largest cities, however, are Naussau (the pirate haven), Kingston (a lively, dangerous town), and Havana (the capital of Cuba). The open world will remain dynamic, as some help has been provided by the team that worked on Far Cry 3's open world design. Aiding in the way that the world's systems interact, storms will be random, forcing Edward into fight or flight scenarios.With the addition of free aiming, Kenway can carry up to four guns and use them in one go. Cutlasses, daggers, swords, and all of the other weapons of the time will be available, but the rest of his armory can be upgraded to have these four pistols at his disposal for chaining attacks. Another large part of the upgrading and customization will be through Kenway's ship - the Jackdaw. Even the crew will be an important, upgradable asset to Edward. A spyglass will be used to spot distant ships and islands.As in previous games, there will still be present day gameplay, except this time the player takes on the role of an Abstergo Industries employee, rather than as Desmond Miles. The Templars once again return, with a pirate hunter serving as the main antagonist. MultiplayerThe multiplayer side of Assassin's Creed 4 features six different competitive game modes, a 4 player co-op mode, and introduces Gamelab, a way to create custom matches:Free-For-All modesDeathmatch - The player is given an assassination contract of another player. This mode is played on smaller maps, where the compass and lookalikes are both turned off.Wanted - Much like Deathmatch except you are working within a full map, lookalikes are turned on and you have a compass to help you find your mark.Assassinate - In this mode, no contracts are given, instead players have to discern who other real players are based on their behavior, and assassinate them.Team ModesManhunt - This mode is split into two rounds. In one round one team are the hunters and the other team is the prey. In the second round, the roles are reversed.Artifact Assault - This mode is essentially Capture The Flag. Players are not allowed to assassinate while in enemy territory.Domination - This mode is a version of Conquest, where teams must capture and hold specific points on the map.Wolfpack - This co-op mode tasks players to work together to take down NPCs within a time limit. Synchronized assassinations aren’t necessary, but if players don’t time kills properly, other targets will flee, wasting precious time as you hunt them down to finish the job.GamelabGamelab gives the player the opportunity to build their own custom multiplayer modes by tweaking over 200 different parameters, such as scoring, ability sets, time limits, weapons, etc. The best community-made modes will grow as they gain followers, and Ubisoft will promote the most popular ones into the public playlist.System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows Vista SP2 or Windows 7 SP1 or Windows 8 (both 32/64bit versions)Processor: Intel Core2Quad Q8400 @ 2.6 GHz or AMD Athlon II X4 620 @ 2.6 GHzMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: Nvidia Geforce GTX 260 or AMD Radeon HD 4870 (512MB VRAM with shader Model 4.0 or higher)Hard Drive: 30 GB available spaceSound Card: DirectX Compatible Sound Card with latest driversAdditional Notes: Windows-Compatible keyboard and mouse required, controller optional.RecommendedOS: Windows Vista SP2 or Windows 7 SP1 or Windows 8 (both 32/64bit versions)Processor: Intel Core i5 2400S @ 2.5 GHz or better or AMD Phenom II x4 940 @ 3.0 GHzMemory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: Nvidia GeForce GTX 470 or AMD Radeon HD 5850 (1024MB VRAM with Shader Model 5.0) or betterHard Drive: 30 GB available spaceSound Card: DirectX Compatible Sound Card with latest driversAdditional Notes: Supported video cards at the time of release: Nvidia GeForce GTX 260 or better and GeForce GTX 400, GTX 500, GTX 600 and GTX 700 series. AMD Radeon HD4870 or better and Radeon HD5000, HD6000 and HD7000 series. Note: Latest GeForce drivers tested: 327.23 for all series. Latest Radeon drivers tested: 13.1 for Radeon HD4000, 13.4 for Radeon HD5000, HD6000 and HD7000 series on Vista and 13.9 for Radeon HD5000, HD6000 and HD7000 series on Win7 and Win8. Laptop versions of these cards may work but are NOT officially supported.</description><genres><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25249">Red Dead Redemption</game><game id="32933">Far Cry 3</game><game id="18508">The Legend of Zelda: The Wind Waker</game><game id="1415">Sid Meier's Pirates!</game><game id="16331">Sid Meier's Pirates!</game><game id="42245">Batman: Arkham Origins</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/82063/2557106-ac4clean.jpg</image></root>