<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>41545</id><name>Pokémon Rumble U</name><description>OverviewPokémon Rumble U, the third entry in the Pokémon Rumble series, is a Wii U eShop exclusive title developed by Ambrella and published by Nintendo, due for release on April 24th 2013 in Japan. The game will feature 4-player mutliplayer, and will be able to display up to 100 Pokémon onscreen simultaneously. Pokémon Rumble U will also be the first Wii U title to make use of the natively supported NFC capabilities of the GamePad. Nintendo will release Pokémon figurines which translate into playable in-game equivalents when placed on the gamepad's NFC sensor.Pokémon Rumble U's first western release announcement came out of Nintendo of Europe which announced the game for release on the European Wii U eShop on August 15, 2013. Shortly thereafter, Nintendo of America announced that the game would launch on August 29, 2013 in North America and that the NFC figurines  would be available via GameStop at $3.99 a piece. Details for the availability of the figurines in Europe will be disclosed later, NoE said.PlotThe plot will feature Pokémon dolls trying to make their way back to a Pokémon store, fighting several bosses along the way. One confirmed boss is Chandelure.Near-Field CommunicationThere will be seven figurines available at launch, one of which has not yet been revealedOn launch day there will be 7 figurines available for purchase in Pokémon Centers for 200 yen each, one of which is a "special" figurine. So far The sextet of figurines comprises Bulbasaur, Pikachu, Torchic, Lucario, Victini, and Piplup.Rumble U is priced ¥1800 (around $19), and individual figures ¥200 each (around $2).Similarly to Skylanders, progress made with characters is recorded within the respective figurines.</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/82063/2516405-pokemon_rumble_u_logo.jpg</image></root>