<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4161</id><name>NiGHTS: Journey of Dreams</name><description>Overview NiGHTS: Journey of Dreams is the semi-sequel, semi-remake to          NiGHTS: Into Dreams on the          Sega Saturn in 1996. It shares some of the basic gameplay elements with the original NiGHTS, with some key additions. Players are given the option to choose between one of two characters: a young boy named Will, or a young girl named Helen. Each level starts off in full, free-roaming 3D. Like the original NiGHTS, Will and Helen have the ability to "Dualize", which will transform them in to the form of the flying jester, NiGHTS. As NiGHTS, the perspective of the game shifts from 3D to side-scrolling          2.5D on a looping, circular track. As NiGHTS, a timer begins to count down. If the timer reaches zero, the player will fail the given challenge and will be asked if they would like to try again.  Unlike the singular goal in the original NiGHTS, there are five varying mission types in Journey of Dreams, three of which being the most common: Chase, Link, and Boss. Chase missions most closely replicate the gameplay of the original Sega Saturn game, where players are tasked with chasing down a giant bird as NiGHTS, stealing a key it holds, and using that key to unlock the cage blocking the way to the next segment of level. Once three prisons have been unlocked, the player then faces off against a Boss. Link Missions involve NiGHTS flying behind a creature called an Octopaw, who creates rings in the sky. For every ring NiGHTS flies through, his Link counter goes up. The player has five tries to create the highest Link possible. Boss Missions pit the player against an even harder version of the boss they face at the end of a Chase mission.  Also included is the ability to visit a "Nightopian Garden". Similar to the Chao Garden in the          Sonic Adventure series, the Nightopian Garden is a space that houses Sonic Team's unique "A-Life" creatures, and the player is given the ability to visit and interact with these creatures by giving them gifts. Using the Nintendo Wifi Connection, players can even visit their friend's Nightopian Garden.   Plot The evil king of nightmares, Wizeman the Wicked wants to merge two planes of reality - the secret dream world of "Nightopia" and the human world. In doing so, he hopes to spread his evil influence and conquer both realms. To do so, Wizeman must collect rare dream energy in the form of "ideya" - sphere-like crystals that represent various emotions, denoted by their color. Wizeman creates an army of nightmaren and enlists them to harvest ideya from the dreams of all the people in the real world.  But there are two special dreamers in particular - William Taylor and Helen Cartwright. Both of them have been saved from their nightmares by NiGHTS, a playful jester who leads them both to Nightopia. Not long after Will and Helen make friends, however, Reala catches up with NiGHTS - and imprisons him for his insubordination against Wizeman. Reala steals all of Will and Helen's dream energy, save for one very rare, very powerful type: the red ideya of courage. Using it to free NiGHTS from his prison, the three team up to assault Wizeman's minions, recover their ideya, and stop his evil plot once and for all.  Levels Will  Pure Valley (Boss: Donbalon) Lost Park (Boss: Chamelan) Delight City (Boss: Cerberus) Bellbridge (Boss: Reala and Wizeman) Helen  Aqua Garden (Boss: Girania) Crystal Castle (Boss: Bomamba) Memory Forest (Boss: Queen Bella) Bellbridge (Boss: Reala and Wizeman)Development History After the release of the original         NiGHTS: Into Dreams on the Sega Saturn, the question would always come up in interviews every few years: "Will there ever be a sequel?"     Yuji Naka was adamant: he frequently related NiGHTS to the way Steven Spielberg treats the movie E.T.: The Extra Terrestrial: NiGHTS was his "perfect game", and in his eyes, creating a sequel that does not cheapen the impact of the original game would be difficult, if not totally impossible. Still, he did admit that over the years, many prototypes for "NiGHTS 2" were considered, including a      Sega Dreamcast version using a tilt sensor that plugged in to the controller's VMU port, tentatively called "Air NiGHTS". But, none of the "NiGHTS 2" prototypes ever got to a point he was satisfied with, and the game remained in limbo. In Mid 2006, Yuji Naka announced his resignation from       Sonic Team and Sega in order to start his own indie development studio,        PROPE. Almost immediately after his departure, rumors began to circulate that a NiGHTS sequel was already in production. It would seem as though Sonic Team director    Takashi Iizuka had wasted no time: no longer under the jurisdiction of Yuji Naka, nobody was to tell Iizuka "No" regarding a NiGHTS 2 project. Barely even nine months out from Naka's departure, Sega announced the production of Journey of Dreams for the Nintendo Wii.  According to a blog from a disgruntled Sega of Europe employee, Journey of Dreams began its life as an Xbox 360 and Playstation 3 title. However, Sega of Japan did not hold too much faith in the project - the original NiGHTS, while artistically impressive, did not do too well in terms of sales figures, and Journey of Dreams was coming more than a decade later. They saw the game as Takakshi Iizuka's "pet project", something that is typically avoided by most publishers. Still, they allowed the project to continue (albeit with a limited budget and tight deadlines) as respite from the assembly line of constant Sonic games the team had been forced to work on for so many years. The 360/PS3 version was reportedly far enough along that a significant chunk of the game was playable, when Sega of Japan uprooted the entire project. Having seen the runaway success of Nintendo's Wii console, Sega felt Journey of Dreams would be less of a gamble there, and forced Takashi Iizuka and Sonic Team to change platforms or face cancellation. They begrudgingly agreed, and with even less time and less money to complete the game, they did the best they could to finish up what they had.   SoundtrackNiGHTS ~Journey of Dreams~ Original Soundtrack Music in Journey of Dreams was composed by a wide arrange of musicians, some returning from the original NiGHTS soundtrack, including the main composers          Naofumi Hataya,          Tomoko Sasaki and          Fumie Kumatani. Joining them were          Kenichi Tokoi,          Tomoya Ohtani, Hideki Kobayashi, Teruhiko Nakagawa,          Tatsuyuki Maeda,          Jun Senoue, and          Yutaka Minobe.   After          NiGHTS into Dreams, Sasaki and Hataya were always hopeful for a sequel, exchanging New Years cards every year which all contained promises that they would make the sequel that year. When          Takashi Iizuka asked them to compose, they gladly agreed. The game contains one vocal track with two remixes:"Dreams Dreams", Original song by Tomoko Sasaki, with arrangement by Yutaka Minobe, featuring the vocal talents of Robbie Wyckoff, Fiancis M. Benitez, Riley O' Flynn, and Victoria Ashby."Dreams Dreams: Sweet Snow", Original song by Tomoko Sasaki, with arrangement by Tomoko Sasaki and Naofumi Hataya, featuring the vocals of Jasmine Allen. NiGHTS ~Journey of Dreams~ Original SoundtrackRelease date: January 16, 2008Total length: 191:28  Disc 1:NiGHTS: Journey of DreamsSolitudeEloquent EchoDrifting DonbalonEloquent Echo: Fluffy CatchEloquent Echo: River RescueDrifting Donbalon: Hard VersionWandering WildnessCacking ChamelanWandering Wildness: Bomb PanicWandering Wildness: Coaster RescueCacking Chamelan: Hard VersionDreams Dreams: Located Link Mix (Instrumental)NiGHTS And RealaElectrical EntertainmentClashing CerberusElectrical Entertainment: Neon City BattleElectrical Entertainment: Broadway GuideClashing Cerberus: Hard VersionGrowing WingsPersona Non GrataD'Force MasterWin a GoalDreams Dreams: Will Version  Disc 2: Dreams Dreams: Adult VersionConscienceSweeping SeashoreGiant GiraniaSweeping Seashore: Aqua ChallengeSweeping Seashore: Marine EscapeGiant Girania: Hard VersionCrystal ChoirBony BomambaCrystal Choir: Labyrinth GuideCrystal Choir: Jewel FeverBony Bomamba: Hard VersionMerry Memory Go RoundQueen Bella's BallMerry Memory Go Round:Forest AdventureDreams Dreams: Sky ConcertQueen Bella's Ball : Hard VersionCrusing TogetherNiGHTS And Reala : Theme of A Tragedic RevengeSonatinas for Two ViolinsApplauseDreams Dreams: Helen VersionOn The Way BackMemento of NiGHTSDreams Dreams: Sweet SnowFragmented NiGHTS Disc 3:Dreams Dreams: Kids VersionNiGHTS : Journey of Dreams (Short Version)Gate Of Your DreamEncounterWhen The Night FallsSweeping Seashore: in DaylightCowardly CustardCatch Me If You CanDuel in DreamAl-Di-La: Lavender VersionReala ReturnsPeaceful MomentAl-Di-La: Sandal Wood VersionBad NewsTwist of FateAl-Di-La: Peppermint VersionCaptiveSuspicionBeliefAl-Di-La: Bergamot VersionPrecious OrgelSentimental SeparationThank You NiGHTSDreams Dreams: Located Link MixDreams Dreams: Sweet Snow (instrumental)Dreams Dreams (instrumental)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13158">Sonic Adventure DX: Director's Cut</game><game id="19060">Sonic Adventure 2</game><game id="6845">Sonic Adventure 2: Battle</game><game id="12739">Super Paper Mario</game><game id="16094">Super Mario Galaxy</game><game id="9676">NiGHTS into Dreams...</game><game id="17085">Magic Carpet</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2340616-box_njod.png</image></root>