<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>41695</id><name>inFamous: Second Son</name><description>OverviewTaking place in Seattle 7 years after inFAMOUS 2, this game stars a new character named Delsin Rowe who has the ability to absorb Conduits powers. He finds this out when he absorbs a Conduits power to direct, manipulate and transform into smoke. The story is based on the real world dilemma of people giving up freedom for improved security.StoryThe third game in the inFAMOUS series stars a brand new character named Delsin Rowe, a 24 year old Native American who believes he's destined for greatness. Only problem is, that hasn't come yet. He grew up just outside of Seattle where he first gains his powers. After helping a man escape from a fiery bus wreck, he starts absorbing the mans power to direct, manipulate and transform into smoke. His main power is to absorb other Conduits powers.It's been 7 years since Cole MacGrath used the RFI to wipe out all Conduits on the planet and the world has changed. Not all the Conduits were destroyed from the blast and those who weren't killed are now being caught and imprisoned by the Department of Unified Protection (DUP) - a government agency created to make sure the catastrophic events that took place in Empire City  New Marais never happens again. After DUP finds out about Delsin and tries to capture him, he decides to fight back and show he's not going down without a fight.GameplayAs expected from a game in this series, the path the gameplay will take depends on the decisions the player makes throughout the story. DevelopmentNot unlike the Uncharted franchise, The Last of Us, and other games of the same vein, inFamous: Second Son relies very heavily on motion-capture technology generate the most lifelike characters possible. The character models of Delsin and Reggie Rowe are based entirely on their voice/mo-cap actors: Troy Baker and Travis Willingham, respectively. It is unconfirmed whether this trend will extend to the rest of the game's cast.</description><genres><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="33345">Prototype 2</game><game id="35559">Sly Cooper: Thieves in Time</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8169/2570983-91itpmyw4gl._sl1500_.jpg</image></root>