<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>41753</id><name>Cross Country USA</name><description>GameplayUsed as a teaching tool for children to explore cross-country road trips, Cross Country USA is an 18-wheeler long haul simulator. Players choose from a list of travel scenarios (like transporting goods from Washington State to Florida) and must plan their trip in the most effective way possible while getting plenty of rest.While plotting the quickest route between two locations, players pick up small hauls and navigate major cities. Along the way, drivers can be waylaid by inclement weather or assaulted by hitchhikers if they choose to pick them up.Picking up hitchhikers doesn't always end in assault, however. Some traveling companions will wave you off when you drop them off at their destination, others even award the player with $100.Commodity ListWhile traveling to the end destination, players are tasked with picking up various commodities. Retail versions of Cross Country USA actually came with a physical commodity list detailing which cities you could pick up necessary items in. This feature is not available anywhere in the game though several dedicated players have sourced out item locations through trial and error.CommoditiesAvailable CitiesAircraft PartsSan Diego, CA, Seattle, WA, Dallas, TX, Harford, CTApplesSpokane, WA, Grand Rapids, MI, Rochester, NYBeefOmaha, NE, Dallas, TX, San Antonio, TXBeerMilwaukee, WIBooksNew York City, NYCamerasRochester, NY, Binghampton, NYCarsDetroit, MI, Toledo, OH, Cincinatti, OH, Indianapolis, INChemicalsLouisville, KY, Wilmington, DE, Newark, NJClothingLos Angeles, CA, New York City, NYCoalRock Springs, WY, Sheridan, WY, Charleston, WVComputersSan Francisco, CA, Boston, MACopperSalt Lake City, UT, Yuma, AZ, Tucson, AZ, Las Curces, NMCornNorth Platte, NE, Des Moines, IA, Peoria, ILCottonPhoenix, AZ, Amarillo, TX, Jackson, MSFertilizerTampa, FLFurnitureGrand Rapids, MI, Greensboro, NCGlassCharleston, WV, Philadelphia, PAGoldSalt Lake City, UT, Rapid City, SDGraniteAugusta, GA, Concord, NHHogsDavenport, IA, Dubuque, IAIronDuluth, MNJewelryProvidence, RILeadCoeur d'Alane, IDLeatherManchester, NHLumberEugene, OR, Portland OR, Seattle, WAMaple SyrupBurlington, VTMarbleKnoxville, TN, Montpelier, VTMilkMinneapolis, MN, Eau Claire, WI, Madison, WIMolybdenumPhoenix, AZ, Denver, CONatural GasShreveport, LA, Las Cruces, NM, Oklahoma City, OKOrangesLos Angeles, CA, Tampa, FLOilHouston, TX, Shreveport, LAPaperEau Claire, WI, Philadelphia, PA, Bangor, MEPeanutsMontgomery, AL, Macon, GAPotatoesSpokane, WA, Pocatello, ID, Bangor, MERiceHouston, TX, Baton Rouge, LA, Little Rock, ARRubberChicago, IL, Dayton, OHSaltBaton Rouge, LA, Binghampton, NYSeafoodSan Diego, CA, Boston MASheepSacramento, CA, Albuquerque, NM, Flagstaff, AZSilverCoeur d'Alane, ID, Tucson, AZ, Reno, NVSoy BeansJefferson City, MO, Des Moines, IA, Springfield, ILSteelBirmingham, AL, Gary, IN, Cleveland, OH, Baltimore, MD, Pittsburg, PASulfurEl Paso, TX, New Orleans, LATextilesAtlanta, GA, Greensville, SC, Charlotte, NC, Roanoke, VATobaccoBowling Green, KY, Greensborgo, NC, Raleigh, NC, Richmond, VAUraniumAlbuquerque, NM, Casper, WYVegetablesSacramento, CA, Madison, WI, Miami, FLWheatGreat Falls, MT, Bismark, ND, Topeka, KS, Wichita, KSWineSan Francisco, CAWoolCasper, WY, Austin, TXZincSt. Louis, MO, Nashville, TN, Allentown, PA  </description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="8">Educational</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/26802/2442459-cross+country+usa.jpg</image></root>