<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>42086</id><name>CSI: Deadly Intent</name><description>Following the twists of the story. CSI: Deadly Intent is an all-new immersive experience thanks to intriguing cases written with CSI show writers, a new rendering engine allowing for more realistic graphics, improved lighting effects, and enhanced character acting and lip sync with the voices of the actors from the show. 

JOIN THE NEW CSI FAMILY... and partner with the cast of the new CSI Season 9. For the first time, team up with new characters such as Ray Langston (Laurence Fishburne) and Riley Adams (Lauren Lee Smith). Be prepared to work with your partner as a real team, working together on the crime scene or helping each other during tough suspect interrogations.

PUT YOUR EXPERTISE TO THE TEST... as you play one of the most skillful forensic experts to join the Vegas CSI team. For the first time ever, help other detectives in their investigations and gain their respect through your actions and teamwork.


Collect evidence at the crime scene 
Dust for fingerprints 
Search for items that might be related to the case 
Unveil hidden evidence through observation 
And much more... 
Utilize an improved interrogation system for more realistic character interactions 
Ask the right questions and use evidence collected at the crime scene to get the truth 
Analyze the evidence with the latest technology: 
DNA analysis 
Microscopic analysis 
And much more... 
CSI:Deadly Intent er en helt ny opplevelse takket være spennende saker skrevet med CSI: Vis forfattere, en ny gjengivelsesmotor som gir mer realistisk grafikk, bedre lyseffekter samt bedre karakterskuespill og leppesynkronisering med stemmene til skuespillerne fra serien.

For første gang kan du slå deg sammen med nye figurer som Ray Langston (Laurence Fishburne) og Riley Adams (Lauren Lee Smith). Gjør deg klar til å samarbeide med partneren din som et ordentlig lag, som jobber sammen på åstedet eller hjelper hverandre under røffe forhør av mistenkte.


CSI:Deadly Intent är en helt ny fördjupad upplevelse tack vare spännande fall som skrivits för CSI: visa författare, en ny renderingsmotor som möjliggör mer realistisk grafik, förbättrade ljuseffekter och förbättrade karaktärer som agerar och läppsynkar med skådespelarnas röster från showen.

För första gången: nya figurer som Ray Langston (Laurence Fishburne) och Riley Adams (Lauren Lee Smith).Var beredd på att arbeta tillsammans med din partner som ett verkligt team på brottsplatsen eller hjälpa varandra vid tuffa förhör av misstänkta.


CSI: Deadly Intent er en ny fordybende oplevelse takket være spændende sager skrevet til CSI: show tekstforfattere, en ny præsentationsmaskine, som tillader mere realistisk grafik, forbedrede lyseffekter og forbedret personspil og talesynkronisering med de rigtige skuespilleres stemmer fra showet.

Dan team med nye karakterer som Ray Langston (Laurence Fishburn) og Riley Adams (Lauren Lee Smith). Vær forberedt på at samarbejde med din partner som et rigtigt team på kriminelle gerningsstederog hjælp hinanden under de skrappe afhøringer af mistænkte.


CSI: Deadly Intent on täysin uusi mukaansatempaava elämys, sillä sen käsikirjoituksen ovat kirjoittaneet CSI-televisiosarjan käsikirjoitukset. Uusi pelimoottori tekee grafiikasta todentuntuisempoaa, parantaa valotehosteita ja saa näyttelemisen näyttämään aidommalta. Hahmojen ääninä käytetään televisiosarjan näyttelijöiden ääniä.

Liittoudu uusien hahmojen kanssa, kutan Ray Langston (Laurence Fishburne) ja Riley Adams (Lauren Lee Smith). Valmistaudu toimimaan kumppanisi kanssa aitona tiiminä. Teette yhteistyötä rikosten tapahtumapaikoilla ja autatte toisianne hankalissa epäiltyjen kuulusteluissa.</description><genres /><image>http://thegamesdb.net/banners/boxart/thumb/original/front/9595-1.jpg</image></root>