<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4228</id><name>Haven: Call of the King</name><description>OverviewHaven: Call of the King is a single-player PlayStation 2 game developed by Traveller's Tales and published by Midway. that is a combination of action, puzzle, and shoot-'em-up styles. Releases were also planned for the Xbox and GameCube by Xicat Interactive, Inc., but they were cancelled. It is rated T for Teen due to Mild Violence by the ESRB. The game was intended to be the first chapter in a trilogy of games, but was a commercial flop upon release. As a result, the story was never finished.The intro movie shows Lord Vetch for the first time when he gets a call from the Overlord. The Overlord tells Vetch that there is a boy who knows about the Golden Voice. The Overlord asks if he should be executed, but Vetch thinks Haven should be watched closely instead. At the end of this call, the game shows Haven in his house building a robot bird. When it fails to work, he pounds it and it comes to life, creating Talon. He exits his house, but his boss is outside. Apparently, Haven had accidentally hurt his boss's foot with his pickaxe, thinking it was a rock then claiming anybody could have made that mistake. When Talon trips the boss causing him to fall into a bucket of feathers, Haven runs into a cave where a guard is asking Chess questions. The guard tries to shoot Haven, but misses causing the cave to collapse.This is the first time the player gets to play Haven. The player must get Haven to escape the mine without being crushed by rocks. At the end of the mine, another cutscene shows him tripping over a rock.(this is unpreventable). He then wakes up in Doctor Spong's office where Talon stops to recharge. When he exits the house, the game begins.By the end of this game, Haven is chained to a rock, the king is killed, Vetch escapes, and it's revealed that Chess is a traitor. If the player has collected all of the runestones, completed all the runes challenges and has all of the black diamonds, an alternate ending can be viewed.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3438">MediEvil II</game><game id="15212">Ratchet &amp; Clank Future: Tools of Destruction</game><game id="4966">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Up Your Arsenal</game><game id="4618">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Going Commando</game><game id="8837">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Size Matters</game><game id="18745">Ratchet: Deadlocked</game><game id="21000">Secret Agent Clank</game><game id="10384">Jak II</game><game id="14623">Jak and Daxter: The Precursor Legacy</game><game id="9669">Jak 3</game><game id="20640">Kung Fu Panda</game><game id="609">Rayman 2: The Great Escape</game><game id="5821">Rayman 3: Hoodlum Havoc</game><game id="6833">Rayman: Hoodlum's Revenge</game><game id="4236">Rayman Rush</game><game id="159">Ty the Tasmanian Tiger 2: Bush Rescue</game><game id="11667">Ape Escape 2</game><game id="7298">Pitfall: The Lost Expedition</game><game id="18376">Looney Tunes Back in Action</game><game id="12885">Pac-Man World 3</game><game id="7975">SpongeBob SquarePants: Creature From the Krusty Krab</game><game id="10541">SpongeBob SquarePants: Revenge of the Flying Dutchman</game><game id="1999">Ice Age 2: The Meltdown</game><game id="1534">The Incredibles: Rise of the Underminer</game><game id="7954">Over the Hedge</game><game id="20349">Disney's The Haunted Mansion</game><game id="17133">Tak and the Power of Juju</game><game id="1274">Tak 2: The Staff of Dreams</game><game id="7836">Spyro the Dragon</game><game id="1753">Spyro: Year of the Dragon</game><game id="1563">Spyro 2: Ripto's Rage</game><game id="6134">The Legend of Spyro: The Eternal Night</game><game id="15249">Spyro Orange: The Cortex Conspiracy</game><game id="20908">The Legend of Spyro: Dawn of the Dragon</game><game id="3883">The Legend of Spyro: A New Beginning</game><game id="8420">Spyro: Enter the Dragonfly</game><game id="10579">Spyro: Season of Ice</game><game id="12209">Spyro: A Hero's Tail</game><game id="13370">Spyro 2: Season of Flame</game><game id="20205">Bubsy in: Claws Encounters of the Furred Kind</game><game id="2931">Super Mario 64</game><game id="19060">Sonic Adventure 2</game><game id="13371">Ape Escape</game><game id="7961">Ape Escape: On the Loose</game><game id="15479">Ape Escape Academy</game><game id="3075">Frogger: The Great Quest</game><game id="15353">Sly Cooper and the Thievius Raccoonus</game><game id="15573">Sly 2: Band of Thieves</game><game id="16337">Sly 3: Honor Among Thieves</game><game id="8660">Crash Bandicoot 2: Cortex Strikes Back</game><game id="7380">Crash Bandicoot</game><game id="12909">Crash Bandicoot: Warped</game><game id="68">Crash Bandicoot: The Wrath of Cortex</game><game id="732">Crash Bandicoot Purple: Ripto's Rampage</game><game id="9546">Klonoa: Door to Phantomile</game><game id="7212">Klonoa 2: Lunatea's Veil</game><game id="15644">Klonoa: Empire of Dreams</game><game id="3457">MediEvil</game><game id="7804">Rocket: Robot on Wheels</game><game id="20330">Gex 3: Deep Cover Gecko</game><game id="15991">Chameleon Twist 2</game><game id="12614">Sphinx and the Cursed Mummy</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2160109-box_haven.png</image></root>