<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4249</id><name>The King of Fighters '94</name><description>Overview The King of Fighters '94 is a 2D 3-on-3 fighting game developed and published by                         SNK for the                        Neo Geo. It's the first game in the continuing                  King of Fighters franchise. The idea was to develop a crossover fighting game featuring not only characters from SNK's fighting franchises                       Fatal Fury and                      Art of Fighting, but also                     Ikari Warriors,                    Psycho Soldier, and some of SNK's sports games. The story of the game revolves around ruthless arms dealer                   Rugal Bernstein, who decided to host a tournament (dubbed King of Fighters) to bring together the strongest fighters from all over the world (though, as we later learn, for a sinister purpose).Gameplay The King of Fighters '94 plays like a traditional 2D fighting game, using four buttons (two punches and two kicks). Pressing Light Punch and Light Kick simultaneously performs a dodge, avoiding the opponent's attack. Pressing Strong Punch and Strong Kick simultaneously performs a stronger attack. Pressing Strong Punch from far away performs a taunt. Double-tapping forward or backward on the joystick performs a quick dash.  The power gauge and super moves takes elements from both the                 Art of Fighting and                Fatal Fury games. Each player has a power gauge on the bottom of the screen, which can be charged by holding down Light Punch, Light Kick, and Strong Punch simultaneously. Once the gauge is filled, the player's basic attacks become stronger for a short time. Players can also perform a "Super Special Move" either during this state, which consumes the entire gauge, or when their life gauge is 75% empty and flashing red.  Instead of a best-of-three fights between two fighters, teams of three compete against each other in single elimination rounds. (Though some versions of the game allow you to play traditional best-of-three fights between two fighters) The players, after choosing their team, choose the order that the characters will fight. The winner of each fight receives some health back (if needed) and goes on to fight the next person on the opposing team. This continues until all the characters of one team are eliminated. Characters The King of Fighters '94 allows the player to select from eight different teams, each consisting of three characters. Though these groups represent different countries around the world, there are some teams where none of the character's nationalities match the team's country (most notably Italy, Mexico, and Brazil)                                       Japan (Japan Team)                                                      Kyo Kusanagi                                                    Benimaru Nikaido                                                   Goro Daimon                                      Italy (Fatal Fury Team)                                                  Terry Bogard                                                 Andy Bogard                                                Joe Higashi                                     Mexico (Art of Fighting Team)                                               Ryo Sakazaki                                              Robert Garcia                                             Takuma Sakazaki  Brazil (Ikari Warriors Team)            Heidern                                        Ralf Jones Clark Steel                                     China (Psycho Soldier Team)                                            Athena Asamiya                                           Sie Kensou                                          Chin Gentsai                                 England (Women Fighters Team) Yuri Sakazaki                               Mai Shiranui King                                U.S.A. (American Sports Team)                             Heavy D!                            Lucky Glauber                           Brian Battler  Korea (Korea Team)                                   Kim Kaphwan                                  Chang Koehan                                 Choi BoungeOther                          Rugal Bernstein (boss)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19200">Fatal Fury Special</game><game id="15408">Rival Schools: United by Fate</game><game id="12125">Capcom Fighting Evolution</game><game id="3185">ClayFighter 63 1/3</game><game id="243">Street Fighter II: The World Warrior</game><game id="11156">X-Men vs. Street Fighter</game><game id="7751">Art of Fighting Anthology</game><game id="14669">Virtua Fighter Animation</game><game id="3744">Def Jam: Fight for NY</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="16793">Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors</game><game id="19134">Street Fighter Alpha 2</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="22362">Street Fighter II': Hyper Fighting</game><game id="18645">Dragon Ball GT: Final Bout</game><game id="18484">Killer Instinct</game><game id="21952">Killer Instinct 2</game><game id="10614">Killer Instinct Gold</game><game id="21277">Ultimate Mortal Kombat</game><game id="5640">Capcom vs. SNK: Millennium Fight 2000 Pro</game><game id="20456">Street Fighter IV</game><game id="34232">Burning Fists: Force Striker</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1614/840764-kof94_ng_us.jpg</image></root>