<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4257</id><name>Gunple: Gunman's Proof</name><description>OverviewGunple: Gunman's Proof is an action-adventure game released for the Super Famicom in Japan in 1997. Due to waning interest in the SNES in the United States, this title never saw a western release. The game offers Legend of Zelda style dungeon crawling fused with Commando-esque top down shooting spiced up with a unique sci-fi/western motif that pits cowboys against space aliens.PlotIn the year 1880, two meteors crash down on Strange Island just off the American west coast. The people in the area took little notice of the event however as they were too busy with their frontier lifestyle. A short time later, strange incidents start occurring. Monsters start attacking people in the village and leaving behind an odd crest that reads "demiseed". Eventually, a third meteor crashes down and people in the are become even more worried. One day, a curious teenage boy living in Bronco Village decides to sneak out of his house and venture out to investigate. During his expedition, a flying saucer crashes right in front of him. Two aliens come out of the craft and identify themselves as members of an intergalactic law enforcement agency. Space Sheriffs Sub-Zero and Goro explain that all of the problems occurring on Strange Island are due to Demi, an interstellar criminal that escaped from justice and is hiding out on Earth. Sub-Zero and Goro need to stop Demi and locate their fellow Space Sheriff, Mono, that came ahead of them. Unfortunately they are unable to survive for long in Earth's atmosphere. So Sub-Zero goes ahead and enters the young earthling's body and lends him all of his powers. Zero's fellow law enforcement agent stays behind to repair their damaged flying saucer. It's at this point that the adventure begins with Zero and his young Earthling host setting out to take out Demi's secret hide-outs and defeat the intergalactic criminal mastermind once and for all.GameplayThe progression in the game is very similar in style to The Legend of Zelda: A Link to the Past. Our alien-infused hero travels from dungeon to dungeon via an overworld. In each dungeon, you are presented with a labyrinth of enemy filled rooms to make your way through before facing off with that dungeon's boss. Along the way, you'll be picking up various new weapons, tools, and power-ups.The combat is very similar to a lot of top-down shooters like Commmando. There is a wide range of weapons from revolvers and shotguns to bazookas and flamethrowers. In addition to guns, there is a close combat punch attack. This attack can be powered up with new gloves and combos. In addition, there's an assortment of grenades and bombs that can do large amounts of damage.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10276">The Legend of Zelda: A Link to the Past</game><game id="3645">The Legend of Zelda: Link's Awakening</game><game id="35064">The Legend of Zelda: A Link to the Past &amp; Four Swords</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5822/427744-gunman_box.jpg</image></root>