<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4277</id><name>Golden Sun: The Lost Age</name><description>This traditional-style role-playing game continues the story of its predecessor,      Golden Sun, while expanding your abilities and allowing you to battle with up to eight players as you traverse seas, mountains, and skies in order to save the fantasy land of Weyard.Story The game picks up right after the events of the first Golden Sun. The Venus Lighthouse has just been lit and                Felix,               Jenna,              Sheba and Kraden set out to light the remaining Elemental Lighthouses, rendering the player's efforts in the first game to prevent exactly that from happening a gigantic waste of time. Their adventures take them across new lands where few have been before. On their journey they meet             Piers, a mysterious man from the equally mysterious Lemuria. They discover shocking truths about Weyard during their adventure.  CombatFelix using the magical attack, Ragnarok! A classic turn-based combat system is used, but with some interesting quirks. At the beginning of every turn you choose the moves for all your characters and then the battle begins. Every character used in battle has magical abilities called Psynergy. HP and PP are the health and magic counters used. As your characters fight they level up and gain new Psynergy. As you progress through the game you acquire creatures called Djinn, which alter stats and can change the "class" of party members, and be used to cull powerful summons.  Characters  Felix     Felix is a Venus (earth) Adept was previously an enigmatic character thought to be an antagonist. Jenna is a Mars (fire) Adept who also made a brief appearance in the first game. Sheba, a Jupiter (wind) Adept, made a much smaller cameo in the first game but is a core character in this one, though despite the promise of a pivotal sub-plot (thought to have "fallen from the moon") little of her back-story is dealt with. Shortly into The Lost Age the party is joined by a Lemurian Mercury (water) adept Piers, who reveals the threat of Weyard's disintegration without alchemy. The former party (           Isaac,           Garet,          Ivan,         Mia) also join late in the game.  Like in the first game, two Mars Clan from Prox (    Agatio and    Karst) act as apparent antagonists, but after the party discovers Prox - on the edge of the disintegrating Weyard - their true mission to save their people is revealed.   Djinn   Djinn are the magical creatures that were unleashed on the world after Issac entered Sol Sanctum and removed the elemental stars. Each Djinn is aligned to an element, which in turn is aligned to a planet.  Some Djinn are only available by entering a code obtained by completing the original Golden Sun   New Djinn Venus (Earth)        The Venus lighthouse powers the Earth element, and each of the Djinn that use it. Echo Iron Steel Mud FlowerMeldPetraSaltGeodeMoldCrystal   Djinn of Earth         Mars (Fire)         The Mars lighthouse powers the Fire element, and each of the Djinn that use it.      Cannon  Spark  Kindle  Char  Coal RefluxCoreTinderShineFuryFugue Djinn of Fire        Jupiter (Wind)         The Jupiter lighthouse powers the Wind element, and each of the Djinn that use it.      Breath  Blitz  Ether  Waft  Haze  Wheeze Aroma  Whorl  Gasp  Lull   Gale Djinn of Wind     Mercury (Water)         The Mercury Lighthouse powers the Water element, and each of the Djinn that use it.     FogSourSpringShadeChillSteam Rime Gel EddyBalmSerac  Djinn of Water     Summons           Earth  Venus: one Venus Ramses: Two Venus  Cybele: Three Venus  Judgement: Four Venus     Fire  Mars: One Mars    Kirin: Two Mars    Tiamat: Three Mars    Meteor: Four Mars   Wind   Jupiter: One Jupiter    Atalanta: Two Jupiter    Procne: Three Jupiter    Thor: Four Jupiter   Water   Mercury: One Mercury    Nereid: Two Mercury    Neptune: Three Mercury     Boreas: Four Mercury Djinn  Multi Types Zagan : One Venus,One Mars     Megaera: One Mars, One Jupiter     Flora: One Venus, Two Jupiter    Moloch: Two Mercury, One Jupiter    Ulysses: Two Mercury, two Mars    Haures: Three Venus, Two Mars    Eclipse: Two Mercury, Three Jupiter    Coatlicue: Three Mercury, Three Jupiter    Daedalus: Three Venus, Four Mars    Azul: Three Venus, Four Mercury    Catastrophe: Three Mars, Five Jupiter    Charon: Eight Venus, Two Jupiter    Iris: Four Mercury, Eight MarsData Transfer     Golden Sun: The Lost Age allowed players to transfer their data from the        Golden Sun into The Lost Age by one of two possible methods.  The first was by the use of a GameBoy Advance Link cable between two Gameboy Advances as well both Golden Sun and Golden Sun: The Lost Age. The second was a password system which allowed the player to transfer data depending on their preference. There were three different types of passwords (Bronze, Silver  Gold) which varied in length, and hence varied the amount of information sent across.   Password Types    BronzeCharacter levelsDjinn obtained Silver All Bronze dataCharacter stats  GoldAll Silver dataItems  EquipmentCoins Data transfer was required for the player to obtain all the Djinn in The Lost Age and to access two hidden summons, Charon  Iris.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17928">Final Fantasy I &amp; II: Dawn of Souls</game><game id="6336">Final Fantasy VI</game><game id="20829">Final Fantasy IV</game><game id="9249">Chrono Trigger</game><game id="15629">Breath of Fire</game><game id="3093">Breath of Fire II</game><game id="21463">Final Fantasy III</game><game id="12264">Lufia: The Ruins of Lore</game><game id="4793">Final Fantasy V</game><game id="13561">Riviera: The Promised Land</game><game id="19425">Dragon Quest VI: Realms of Revelation</game><game id="22703">Dragon Quest IV: Chapters of the Chosen</game><game id="16319">Lunar: Dragon Song</game><game id="8307">EarthBound</game><game id="16201">Shining Soul</game><game id="21240">Black Sigil: Blade of the Exiled</game><game id="7856">The Legend of Zelda: Four Swords Adventures</game><game id="23983">Mario &amp; Luigi: Bowser's Inside Story</game><game id="15439">Mario &amp; Luigi: Partners in Time</game><game id="9306">Mario &amp; Luigi: Superstar Saga</game><game id="19349">Breath of Fire III</game><game id="9177">Breath of Fire IV</game><game id="13053">Final Fantasy VII</game><game id="12277">Final Fantasy VIII</game><game id="8825">Final Fantasy IX</game><game id="11237">Final Fantasy X</game><game id="17473">Lufia: The Legend Returns</game><game id="26932">Glory of Heracles</game><game id="9896">Beyond the Beyond</game><game id="16949">Phantasy Star Collection</game><game id="267">Golden Sun</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/82063/2267403-2267402-561356_51278_front.jpg</image></root>