<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4284</id><name>NASCAR SimRacing</name><description>-CreationNASCAR SimRacing was created by EA Tiburon and published by EA for the PC and saw official market release on February 15th, 2005.FeaturesNASCAR-licensed Racing: Hit the track with the cars/trucks from the NASCAR Nextel Cup Series, NASCAR National (Busch) Series, and the NASCAR Craftsman Truck Series on all official 2004 NASCAR tracks.Official NASCAR Drivers: Take on official NASCAR drivers from the top three national racing series, from Jeff Gordon to Ron Hornaday to Chad Chaffin and all drivers in-between. Also features special "Fantasy" drivers. Single Player: Take to the track against the field of NASCAR drivers. Do you have what it takes to run with the big dogs?Career Mode: Fight your way to the top of the NASCAR ladder from humble beginnings.Online Multiplayer: Take the race online against fellow drivers.ModificationsIn tradition with the wildly popular NASCAR Racing 2003 Season, NASCAR SimRacing offered some modification to the game in the form of new carsets and paint schemes that were created by several sim racing online communities and could be added to the game. Players could go and add new content to the game, however, what they could add to the game was limited in comparison to what NR2k3 offered.End of Online ServiceIn the fall of 2006, EA Sports had the online racing servers for NASCAR SimRacing shut down for good. The shutdown only affected the online portion of the game, and the rest of the game (single player and career modes) were still playable.In the end, NASCAR SimRacing turned out to be the last NASCAR game that would see release on the PC, due to EA Sports deciding to focus their efforts into the console versions of their NASCAR games. In 2009, NASCAR stripped EA of the exclusive rights to the NASCAR brand that they had bought back in 2003, thus ending any development or release of future NASCAR games from EA.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5856">NASCAR Racing 2003 Season</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2210278-box_nascarsr.png</image></root>