<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4301</id><name>Area-51</name><description>StoryAs Ethan Cole (and part of Bravo squad), you are sent into Area 51 to check out an unknown virus plaguing the secret government base. Once inside, the team discovers that the virus is turning people into murderous mutants. Your team gets picked off one by one and eventually you are alone and infected with the virus. It's up to you to continue your decent into Area 51 to look for a cure, see who spread the virus, learn why they did it, and stop them from spreading it outside of the base.LevelsWelcome to DreamlandThe Hot ZoneThe SearchThey Get BiggerThe Last StandOne of ThemInternal ChangesLife or DeathDr. CrayHatching ParasitesProject Blue BookLies of the PastBuried SecretsNow BoardingThe GraysDescentThe AscensionThe Last ExitMultiplayerThe game includes your expected multiplayer modes [Deathmatch, Team Deathmatch, Capture the Flag, Hold (Territories)] but also a special mode called "Infected". Basically it pits humans against players that are mutated with the deadly virus from the story's campaign. Create A Match settings allow you to control how often people can mutate, add passwords (make private games), add voice chat, and order of maps to be played. 2 - 16 players allowed in each game.Available Weapons:*NOTE: NPCs will not die if you attack themPistolSub Machine Pistols (Dual Wieldable)Automatic Shotguns (Dual Wieldable)Sniper RifleBBG (Alien Rifle that shoots exploding rounds in bursts)Messon Canon (the mother load, basically an alien gun that kills everyone and everything near it)Frag GrenadesJB Grenades (Jumping Bean)Large TurretsMovieBefore the game's release, Area 51 was optioned for a full motion movie. Producer Christian Peters put it like this, "Area 51 brings some of the most cutting edge technology to the gaming world. Bringing the game's riveting and suspenseful concepts to the big screen will be an exciting motion picture breakthrough." Donald De Line (another producer) said that he excited to bring Area 51's provocative story and dynamite action to the big screen for gamers. Two years later, Grant Morrison (comic book icon/screen writer) claims that he has finished his first draft of Area 51 for Paramount Pictures. More confirmations came in, like the characters Dr. Cray and Mr. White being in the movie, showing that the producers really have faith in the film adaptation. They are fully dedicated to the source material and do not want to disrespect it or as they put it, "I think it's always important to honor the source of one's material, and only by playing games can a filmmaker know what makes them tick and how best to translate game effects into the very different language of Hollywood Drama." (Statement said by Morrison.) The movie was expected in late 2009, but never saw release.ScanningThroughout the game, the player could collect files, pictures, and other interesting items (indicated by sign around it) by scanning it with his or her... scanner. When the scanner is equipped, a translucent bar is added to the player's HUD. The bar changes in color and height from light blue, to deep red. This bar indicates how near or far a player is, to a scannable clue; Red when very close, and blue when very far. Items that are scanned are viewable in-game and provide insight into the workings of Area 51, as well as proving necessary to unlocking secret videos recorded by Dr. Cray and Mr. White.PC System RequirementsMinimumWindows 2000/XPIntel Pentium III 1.4GHz or AMD Athlon 2000+ or Sempron 2200+ Processor256MB RAM64MB ATi Radeon 9500 or nVidia GeForce 3 Class Video CardDirectX 9.0bDirectX compatible Sound Card3GB Hard Disk Space16X DVD-ROM Drive or 4X CD-ROM Drive</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18569">BlackSite: Area 51</game><game id="21912">Planetside: Core Combat</game><game id="21150">Showdown: Scorpion</game><game id="16238">Alien Shooter 2</game><game id="6948">Dark Colony</game><game id="17533">Deus Ex</game><game id="9883">Deus Ex: Invisible War</game><game id="25091">Deus Ex: The Conspiracy</game><game id="21121">The Conduit</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1803104-box_area51.png</image></root>