<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4327</id><name>Roberta Williams' Phantasmagoria</name><description>OverviewRoberta Williams' Phantasmagoria is a 1995 horror-themed adventure game from Sierra Entertainment. Versions were produced for DOS, Windows, Mac, and the Sega Saturn console. Like the company's previous adventure titles such as the King's Quest series, Phantasmagoria is a point-and-click adventure in which the player must solve puzzles in order to advance the story. The game is notable for its use of full-motion video and digitized actors. It also features graphic content that was a source of controversy upon its release, much like Mortal Kombat, which caused its own uproar through the depiction of graphic violence. The game was re-released through Good Old Games on February 11, 2010.StoryThe story of Phantasmagoria centers on Adrienne Delaney, a writer who purchases the large mansion of a magician from the 19th Century. Adrienne and her husband, Donald Gordon, did not know that the magician, Zoltan Carnovasch, was into black magic and summoned a spirit, which possessed him and caused him to murder his wives. Adrienne and Donald purchased the house with the hopes of "getting in the mood" for writing her next novel.Adrienne unknowingly releases the spirit during her exploration of the house and its artifacts allowing the spirit to possess Donald. Donald begins to become aggressive towards his wife culminating in him raping her. Additionally, Adrienne begins to hear strange music and receives strange messages from a fortune-telling machine that is located in the house.Adrienne discovers Harriet and her son, a homeless family who have taken up residency in the manor's barn.While researching the home's history, Adrienne discovers that Zoltan's wives all died in ways related to their personalities. Hortencia, a gardener, was stabbed with gardening tools. Victoria, an alcoholic, is killed with a wine bottle. Lenora has her neck snapped in one of Zoltan's machines, and Regina is forced to eat animal entrails until she suffocates. Adrienne views these acts as she begins to see ghostly visions of the murders in the house.Adrienne learns that Zoltan met his end when his last wife, Maria, discovered that he was a murderer and planned to kill him with the help of her lover, Gaston. The plan goes wrong and Maria and her lover are the ones who end up being killed. Before he dies, Gaston is able to kill Zoltan, thus ending Zoltan's murdering ways. A young boy named Malcolm was the only witness to the Zoltan, Maria, Gaston, tragedy and Adreinne goes to seek him out. Even though he is now 110-years old, he remembers the incident and informs Adrienne how she must deal with the evil spirit which is possessing her husband.Upon returning to the mansion Adrienne discovers that Harriet is dead since Donald, her possessed husband, is wearing Harriet's hair and scalp. Adrienne ultimately ends up killing her husband resulting in the spirit being released. She is able to trap the spirit back in the house before leaving, thus ending the game.GameplayPhantasmagoria is played like a standard "point and click" adventure game. Items can be collected and added to the player's on-screen inventory. Puzzles are solved using both inventory items and environment variables. Players that become stuck in the game can click on the Hintkeeper, a red skull displayed in the UI, for assistance. The Hintkeeper provides advice for every step of the game.CharactersAdrienne Delaney(Playable Character), novelist who purchases an old mansion as inspiration for her new novel.Donald GordonAdrienne's Husband who becomes possessed by a spirit and goes insane.HarrietHomeless woman, who lives with her son (Cyrus), in a barn on the mansion's grounds.CyrusA Large homeless boy, probably in his mid-to-late teens, who lives with his mother (Harriet), in a barn on the mansion's grounds.Zoltan Carnovasch19th Century magician who was the original owner of the house purchased by Adrienne.HortenciaWife of Zoltan, murdered with gardening tools by her husband.VictoriaWife of Zoltan, murdered with a wine bottle by her husband.LenoraWife of Zoltan, murdered by having her neck snapped in one of her husband's magic apparatus.ReginaWife of Zoltan, murdered by being forced to eat animal entrails until she suffocates.MariaWife of Zoltan, plots to kill him with her lover. Plan does not work, she is killed.GastonMaria's Lover, plots to kill Zoltan with Maria. He is ultimately killed in the process, but not before he murders Zoltan.System RequirementsPC Requirements486/25 DOS or 486/66 Windows (Pentium recommended)8 MB or more (16 MB recommended)CD-ROM: 2X speed (4X speed recommended)HARD DISK SPACE: 5 MB for small install (10 MB compressed)OS: MS-DOS 5.0 or higherWINDOWS: Windows 3.1 or higherVIDEO CARD: 640x480 256 colors SVGAOTHER REQUIREMENTS: Mouse, Soundcard with DACMAC Requirements68040 25 Mhz Processor8 MB with 5000 KB freeCD-ROM: 2X speed (4X speed recommended)HARD DISK SPACE: 30 MBOS: System 7.1 or aboveDISPLAY: 13" monitor (256 color or greyscale)MOUSE: required</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1353">The Beast Within: A Gabriel Knight Mystery</game><game id="3181">Burn: Cycle</game><game id="7427">Sewer Shark</game><game id="18648">Night Trap</game><game id="12998">Sherlock Holmes: Consulting Detective</game><game id="16298">The 7th Guest</game><game id="224">Star Trek: Klingon</game><game id="8124">Sherlock Holmes Consulting Detective: Collection</game><game id="10912">Sherlock Holmes Consulting Detective: Volume III</game><game id="1182">Sherlock Holmes Consulting Detective: Volume II</game><game id="10169">Phantasmagoria: A Puzzle of Flesh</game><game id="20146">Shivers</game><game id="10546">Shivers 2: Harvest of Souls</game><game id="1724">The 11th Hour</game><game id="13504">MTV's Club Dead</game><game id="10187">Zork Nemesis: The Forbidden Lands</game><game id="2695">I Have No Mouth, and I Must Scream</game><game id="2333">Dark Seed</game><game id="16020">Dark Seed II</game><game id="19359">Waxworks</game><game id="22">The X-Files Game</game><game id="28104">Tengai Makyou: Karakuri Kakutoden</game><game id="7727">Noctropolis</game><game id="15611">Ripper</game><game id="20231">Hell: A Cyberpunk Thriller</game><game id="20056">9: The Last Resort</game><game id="37068">Last Half of Darkness</game><game id="20982">Alan Wake</game><game id="507">Riana Rouge</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15693/1393329-phantasmagoria_1_a.jpg</image></root>