<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4372</id><name>Maniac Mansion: Day of the Tentacle</name><description>OverviewManiac Mansion: Day of the Tentacle is a sequel to the 1988 Maniac Mansion. Designed by industry veterans Tim Schafer and Dave Grossman, Day of the Tentacle is considered one of the best adventure games ever made. Originally released in June of 1993, Day of the Tentacle soon gathered lasting critical acclaim and a dedicated fan base.Story"I feel like I could.... TAKE ON THE WORLD!!"Day of the Tentacle begins with Green and Purple Tentacle standing next to a stream of contaminated water behind Doctor Fred's mansion. After drinking some of the contaminated water, Purple Tentacle gains a pair of arms and a vastly-increased intelligence, and resolves to take over the world. Green manages to inform his friend, Bernard (who was one of many possible protagonists in the original game), who immediately sets out for the mansion with friends Laverne and Hoagie in tow.Doctor Fred plans to send the three of them back in time to yesterday to turn off the contamination machine and prevent Purple's mutation from occurring, but each of the three characters become trapped in a different time period due to a fake diamond-related mishap. Here is where the majority of the game takes place, with Hoagie trapped in colonial times, on the day of the signing of the Declaration of Independence, Bernard stuck in the present, and Laverne thrown in the distant future, where Purple has succeeded in conquering the world, which is now run by intelligent tentacles who keep humans as pets. In order to save the world Bernard, Laverne, and Hoagie must interchange items and find the parts to fix the time machine in order to return to the present time and stop Purple Tentacle.GameplayHancock, Jefferson, Washington and Hoagie.Day of the Tentacle was one of the first games to feature a puzzle structure based on time travel and alternating characters. In order to solve puzzles it may be required to exchange items with characters in different time periods in order to solve puzzles. For example, the player must freeze a present day hamster in order to retrieve and revive it in the future to power a machine.As in other post Loom LucasArts adventure games it is impossible for the player to die or get into an unsolvable solution. The game runs on the sixth version of the SCUMM engine, which requires the player to select actions or items from the bottom of the screen and then select a point of interest in the world to interact with.LegacyDay of the Tentacle is arguably one of the best point-and-click adventures released by LucasArts, utilizing the SCUMM engine originally conceived for Maniac Mansion. The game still remains fun today thanks to its funny and interesting premise and extremely sharp writing. It's also worth noting that the game included the original Maniac Mansion, which was playable inside the game by accessing a computer found in Weird Ed Edison's room in the mansion, albeit with reduced graphics quality compared to the real game. A very inventive and extremely generous Easter egg.TriviaThe game's Triangle Box.In the SNES and Genesis game Zombies Ate My Neighbors a level titled "Day of the Tentacle" can be unlocked with a password as a bonus level. The enemies are tentacles identical to the ones featured in this game.In the adventure game A Vampyre Story, there is a Day of the Tentacle reference by looking at the windows in the study.The original Maniac Mansion is included in the game. It is accessible by using the computer in Weird Ed Edison's room.The original CD-ROM release of the game came in a large triangular box instead of a standard one.When Hoagie suggested to use Ed Edison's pet hamster for his band to "bite its head off," it was a tribute to Ozzy Osbourne, famed Heavy Metal musician who was known for chewing a dead crow's head off on stage.When Laverne sees Purple Tentacle in the future, she says "Great Scott," which is referring to the famous Doc Brown from Back to the Future.When Bernard, Hoagie and Laverne entered the same Chron-o-Jon at the same time, Dr. Fred Edison said, "didn't you see The Fly?" He was referring the movie of the same name where a scientist's molecular structure had been fused with a fly through an experiment and became a fly monster. The three protagonists eventually became a three-headed monster, despite Dr. Fred's warning.In the game Ben There, Dan That, The cover art Of DOTT can be seen in the living room."Chuck the Plant" first seen the the original Maniac Mansion is featured in Day of the Tentacle in other SCUMM games as well as Lone Survivor.Possible Re-releaseIn The Secret of Monkey Island: Special Edition, an intriguing Easter egg led many to speculate that a special edition of this timeless classic may be in the works. On Monkey Island, in front of the Great Monkey Head, a tentacle statue stands in place of the "Sam and Max" statue featured in the original game. Purple Tentacle also replaced a Max costume in Lechuck's Revenge: Special Edition.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10528">Monkey Island 2:  LeChuck's Revenge</game><game id="3019">The Secret of Monkey Island</game><game id="11852">Sam &amp; Max Hit the Road</game><game id="21174">Full Throttle</game><game id="2037">Maniac Mansion</game><game id="5729">The Curse of Monkey Island</game><game id="399">Full Throttle</game><game id="10915">Beneath a Steel Sky</game><game id="9345">Zack &amp; Wiki: Quest for Barbaros' Treasure</game><game id="5781">Torin's Passage</game><game id="2906">Psychonauts</game><game id="13230">Grim Fandango</game><game id="4084">Broken Sword II: The Smoking Mirror</game><game id="11734">Leisure Suit Larry: Love for Sail!</game><game id="7088">Toonstruck</game><game id="8178">Freddy Pharkas: Frontier Pharmacist</game><game id="209">Tiny Toon Adventures: The Great Beanstalk</game><game id="8759">The Longest Journey</game><game id="6351">Discworld II: Mortality Bytes!</game><game id="21914">A Vampyre Story</game><game id="7947">Lure of the Temptress</game><game id="9527">Flight of the Amazon Queen</game><game id="22601">No Action Jackson</game><game id="600">Future Wars</game><game id="5925">Space Quest I: Roger Wilco in the Sarien Encounter</game><game id="8384">The Adventures of Willy Beamish</game><game id="14441">Pajama Sam 2: Thunder and Lightning Aren't so Frightening</game><game id="22160">Laura Bow: Colonel's Bequest</game><game id="21090">A New Beginning</game><game id="8430">Pajama Sam: No Need to Hide When It’s Dark Outside</game><game id="7900">Pajama Sam 3: You Are What You Eat From Your Head To Your Feet</game><game id="2373">Freddi Fish and the Case of the Missing Kelp Seeds</game><game id="15666">Freddi Fish 2: The Case of the Haunted School House</game><game id="9720">Freddi Fish 3: The Case of the Stolen Conch Shell</game><game id="10911">Freddi Fish 4: The Case of the Hogfish Rustlers of Briny Gulch</game><game id="7662">Freddi Fish 5: The Case of the Creature of Coral Cove</game><game id="14824">Spy Fox in "Dry Cereal"</game><game id="13465">Spy Fox 2: Some Assembly Required</game><game id="5914">Spy Fox: Operation Ozone</game><game id="13134">Putt-Putt Goes to the Moon</game><game id="11177">Putt-Putt Joins the Parade</game><game id="3785">Putt-Putt Saves the Zoo</game><game id="10431">Putt-Putt Joins the Circus</game><game id="15183">Putt-Putt Enters the Race</game><game id="931">Putt-Putt Travels Through Time</game><game id="23532">Nikopol: Secrets of the Immortals</game><game id="6728">Zak McKracken and the Alien Mindbenders</game><game id="23778">Strong Bad's Cool Game for Attractive People Episode 3: Baddest of the Bands</game><game id="21667">Gray Matter</game><game id="3603">Duckman: The Legend of the Fall</game><game id="21421">Star Trek: 25th Anniversary</game><game id="24962">Full Throttle: Payback</game><game id="2690">Armed &amp; Delirious</game><game id="18976">Alien Incident</game><game id="19401">3 Skulls of the Toltecs</game><game id="8664">5 Days a Stranger</game><game id="27322">Time Gentlemen, Please!</game><game id="28084">Ben There, Dan That!</game><game id="30008">Sam &amp; Max Episode 301: The Penal Zone</game><game id="15330">Tony Tough and the Night of Roasted Moths</game><game id="31965">Revenge of the Balloon-Headed Mexican</game><game id="37214">The second guest</game><game id="31979">Edna &amp; Harvey: The Breakout</game><game id="38144">Leisure Suit Larry in the Land of Lounge Lizards RELOADED</game><game id="1917">Hugo's House of Horrors</game><game id="39486">Broken Sword: The Serpent's Curse</game><game id="40113">Edna &amp; Harvey: Harvey's New Eyes</game><game id="37223">Resonance</game><game id="38390">The Cave</game><game id="36765">Grand Theft Auto V</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4938/609071-day_of_the_tentacle_box_front_6534x8205.jpg</image></root>