<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4384</id><name>Command &amp; Conquer</name><description>OverviewBase-building is at the heart of Command  ConquerCommand  Conquer (also known as Command  Conquer: Tiberian Dawn) is a critically-acclaimed real-time strategy game developed by Westwood Studios and originally released in 1995. The first entry in the long-running Command  Conquer franchise, it is often credited, along with Westwood's previous game Dune II and Blizzard's Warcraft II, with popularising the genre and establishing many conventions which still exist today.Command  Conquer is set in an alternate history 1995 and focuses on the conflict between the GDI, a multinational military organization, and the Brotherhood of NOD, an ancient and mysterious terrorist group lead by the enigmatic Kane. The two factions primarily vie for control of the mysterious substance Tiberium, which acts the as game's sole resource.The game was released as freeware on its 12th anniversary and can be downloaded from EA's official website.FactionsCommand  Conquer documents the First Tiberium War, which pits the Global Defence Initiative (GDI), lead by General Mark Sheppard, against the Brotherhood of Nod, lead by Kane. Players can take control of either faction in the single-player campaign or multiplayer skirmishes.Global Defense Initiative (GDI)The Global Defence Initiative (GDI) is a military alliance of Western nations operating under the auspices of the UN Security Council. GDI commanders field an array of mostly conventional units, who fare well in a head-to-head confrontation but lack flexibility compared to Nod.   Brotherhood of NodThe Brotherhood of Nod is an ancient and mysterious terrorist group devoted to its charismatic leader, Kane. Nod are masters of asymmetric warfare, with units that, while generally weaker than their GDI counterparts, excel in unconventional warfare.   PlotCommand  Conquer is well known for its mix of unintentionally hilarious FMV and CGI cut-scenesA mysterious alien plant-like crystal, named Tiberium, has been discovered by Doctor Ignatio Mobius on the banks of the river Tiber in Italy. Kane, leader of the secretive Brotherhood of Nod, disputes this, claiming that the substance was in fact first discovered by Nod, and named by Kane after the Emperor Tiberius. Tiberium Crystals are easy to harvest and full of potent elements, and so it rapidly becomes the most valuable mineral in existence. Both the Global Defence Initiative (GDI), a military alliance of Western nations operating under the auspices of the UN Security Council, and the Brotherhood of Nod begin harvesting Tiberium to fund their respective war efforts.Kane, the leader of Nod, wants to spread Tiberium throughout the entire world, having humans accept it and live with it, while using it to create an army to rival that of the GDI. On the other hand, the GDI has found Tiberium to be deadly to humans and wishes to remove it from Europe, also using Tiberium as a resource to fund their defense. These two powerful forces, funded by Tiberium, have just started what will be known as the first Tiberium War. Will you fight as a Global Defense Initiative Commander or a Apostle of Kane, showing GDI's lies for what they are and spreading Kane's message of Tiberium.EndingsThe GDI campaign is officially the canon ending for the game as the events is Tiberian Sun (the next game in the series) follow on from it.GDIAt the end of game, GDI forces destroy the heart of the Nod empire at the Sarajevo Temple of Nod. The base can either be destroyed by an ORCA attack or by an Ion Cannon. In both cases, the final cut-scene show Kane inside the base when it's leveled and he is assumed to be dead.NodIn this ending, the Brotherhood of Nod successfully capture the codes to access the GDI's Ion Cannon. The player can then choose to destroy one of four historical world landmarks — the Eiffel Tower, Big Ben, the White House or the Brandenburg Gate.CharactersGDI CharactersGeneral Mark SheppardGeneral SheppardSupreme Commander of the GDI and hero of the First Tiberium War, General Sheppard played a pivotal role in defeating the Nod. During the game Sheppard is put in the spotlight after his forces are accused of a civilian massacre in Poland. Eventually, due to his persuasion and charisma, the charges are dropped and it is discovered that the whole event was fabricated by the Nod to discredit the GDI and cut of their funding. The plan backfire against the Nod and General Sheppard is able to lead the GDI to victory.Colonel J.C. CarterColonel CarterA GDI field commander who gives missions and briefings to the player. During the game, he plays a big role in battles taking place in Estonia in which he requires your assistance to overcome the Nod forces.M.O. MorelliM.O. MorelliLeader of the GDI air force and an experienced pilot, Morelli is a cool head who provides you a few missions during the game. In the First Tiberium War, she is responsible for helping you with the defense of Bialystok and recovering nuclear material from the Brotherhood of Nod.Dr. Ignatio MobiusDr. MobiusThe world's foremost expert on Tiberium, Dr. Mobius was the first person to discover the mutagenous substance (a claim disputed by Kane). He is known to be quite a mad scientist and needs protection from Nod forces during the game.Nod CharactersKaneKaneThe Supreme Leader of the Brotherhood of Nod, Kane is a devious and ruthless man who will do anything to accomplish his goals. He believes that Tiberium is the future of mankind and that only Nod can harvest its true potential.SethSethSecond in command and Kane's right-hand man. In the campaign, Seth is your immediate superior and tasks you with most of your missions. As the game progresses, he becomes increasingly jealous of you and the attention you are getting from Kane for being so successful. Eventually, he tries to send you on a suicide mission to destroy the Pentagon but Kane steps in and shoots him. The player is then promoted to Seth's position.Greg BurdetteGreg BurdetteA reporter working for the WWN network, Burdette is secretly working for the Nod. During the first Tiberium War, he films a report claiming that GDI troops slaughtered innocent civilians in Bialystok, Poland. In reality, the whole report was created behind a green screen under the guidance of Kane. The anti-GDI propaganda temporarily works and GDI's funding is cut by the UN.OthersFemale ReporterFemale ReporterAn unnamed female reporter who appears at the end, newscasting the conclusion of the game on national television. Depending on the player's actions, the Female Reporter will broadcast different story on each play through. She talks in a very slow and off-beat tempo.SoundtrackThe CD coverThe soundtrack is composed by Frank Klepacki and published by Westwood Studios. The double-CD soundtrack consists of 22 tracks with a combined duration of approximately 72 minutes. The soundtrack was bundled with some of the collector's editions of the game. On November 1, 2005, the soundtrack was made available on iTunes — fully remastered with some enhancements made in to each song (eg. extra vocals)."Act on Instinct" (2:45)"No Mercy" (3:21)"Industrial" (2:52)"Iron Fist" (3:29)"We Will Stop Them (Deception)" (3:07)"Radio" (2:59)"On the Prowl" (2:59)"Recon" (4:18)"Drone" (4:13)"In the Line of Fire" (2:02)"Prepare for Battle" (3:27)"Depth Charge" (4:12)"Rain in the Night" (2:34)"Creeping Upon" (3:39)"Target (Mechanical Man)" (2:49)"Just Do it Up (Just Do it)" (2:20)"CC Thang" (3:10)"To Be Feared" (2:41)"Drill" (4:28)"Full Stop (Warfare)" (5:02)"In Trouble" (3:07)"Air Strike" (3:11)System RequirementsDOSWindowsProcessor: 486 DX2/66 or higherProcessor: Intel Pentium 60 MHzRAM: 8 MBRAM: 8 MBDisk Space: 30 MBDisk Space: 30 MBGraphics Card: VGA Video Card (320x200 pixels 256 colors)Graphics Card: 1MB Direct Draw compatible video card (640x480 pixels 256 colors)Sound Card: 100% Sound Blaster compatible sound cardSound Card: 100% DirectSound / Windows 95 compatible sound cardOS: MS-DOS 5.0 or higherOS: Windows 95 or higherCD Drive: Double SpeedCD Drive: Double SpeedEVA Game InstallerEVA InstallerOne unique feature of the DOS version of Command and Conquer was the game installer. In the game itself, the Electronic Video Agent (commonly referred to as EVA) is an AI which processes and conveys information to commanders on the battlefield. In the installer, EVA speaks to the player guiding them through the installation process as if they were connecting to a sophisticated military network.TriviaBecause of strict laws in Germany and the possibility of it being outlawed, all soldiers were replaced with robots which didn´t spill red blood when killed and a different sound effect was added. All FMV was dubbed in German too.</description><genres><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14236">Dune II: The Building of a Dynasty</game><game id="19680">Total Annihilation: Kingdoms</game><game id="13062">StarCraft</game><game id="5415">StarCraft: Brood War</game><game id="21982">Small Soldiers: Squad Commander</game><game id="17353">Star Wars: Force Commander</game><game id="20103">Warcraft II: Tides of Darkness</game><game id="14805">KKND2: Krossfire</game><game id="1552">Dune 2000</game><game id="13125">Aliens Versus Predator: Extinction</game><game id="8421">Outlive</game><game id="4602">10six Online</game><game id="724">Perimeter: Emperor's Testament</game><game id="20952">World in Conflict: Soviet Assault</game><game id="15270">This Means War!</game><game id="20381">Star Command: Revolution</game><game id="29066">Dune: The Battle for Arrakis</game><game id="20287">KnightShift</game><game id="28423">Command and Destroy</game><game id="2710">Baldies</game><game id="4926">KKND: Krush, Kill 'N' Destroy</game><game id="33907">APOX</game><game id="18237">Mission: Humanity</game><game id="15235">Dark Reign: The Future of War</game><game id="5205">Dark Reign: Rise of the Shadowhand</game><game id="4397">KKND: Krush Kill 'n Destroy Xtreme</game><game id="38867">Total War: Rome II</game><game id="40429">Echelon: Explore, Discover and Eliminate</game><game id="5921">M.A.X.: Mechanized Assault and Exploration</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2130/184700-cncbox.jpg</image></root>