<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4417</id><name>Premiere</name><description>A very colorful side scrolling platform game. You play Glutch Gable in a quest to find his missing movie reels. As it turns out, the six film reels have been strategically placed in six different film sets around the studios. Each set has a different theme, from cowboy western to sci-fi adventure. Clutch must take on all manner of baddies who are out to prevent him finding the reels.  The nasties in the game are relevant to each set; for example in the western you have cowboys and indians, tumbleweed and circling vultures, while in the black-and-white setting you'll find mummies, moving hieroglyphics and slinky black cats. The music also fits the bill perfectly, with some natty tunes belting out of your Amiga monitor which really add to the atmosphere of the game. Passing through one of the doors in each set will take you 'backstage', away from the film scenario and into a world of scaffolding, props and film cameras. Some of the nasties can be found here as well (rehearsing, I suppose) and they're just as deadly as their Equity card carrying colleagues. Help is at hand in the form of a variety of weapons which may be picked up along the way and can be used to vanquish any foe you come across. From the six-shooter of the westworld to the magic spells of fantasyland, they are always there in great abundance. After each level a bonus game must be completed before the film reel can be retrieved. This takes the form of a short scene from a film which must be acted out by Clutch himself. For example, at the end of the black-and-white film level our hero must ride a truck along a railway line, collecting ammo and dodging various obstacles, while the sci-fi scene ends with a scrolling shoot-em-up. This all adds to the fun of the game, providing a much-needed break from the platform sections.  </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>NONE</image></root>