<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4522</id><name>Medal of Honor: Allied Assault</name><description>OverviewMedal of Honor: Allied Assault is a first-person shooter set during WWII. It was developed by 2015, created by Steven Spielberg, and published by EA. The game runs on a modified version of the Quake III Arena engine. Allied Assault was the first Medal of Honor game released for Windows and the only one to have been ported over to Linux. Members of the development team at 2015 later went on to create Infinity Ward, developers of the very popular Call of Duty franchise.Single PlayerStorming Omaha BeachPlayers take the role of Lieutenant Mike Powell, an agent of the Office of Strategic Services (OSS) , as he takes on six missions across Europe and North Africa. Each mission has multiple objectives that need to be completed. Though generally on his own against the Germans, Powell will sometimes have the support of Allied troops on the battlefield.Mission 1: Lighting the Torch (November 7th 1942)This mission takes place across the Algerian coast and Arzew. During the mission, Powell's squad is ambushed, and he must finish the remaining objectives on his own. He also receives aid after he releases an ally, Maj Grillo, from a POW cell.Mission 2: Sculttling the U-529 (Febuary 12th 1943)In this mission Powell cntinues to Norway with the objective of destroying a prototype Radar Detector. Maj Grillo sacrifices himself to let you into the compound.Mission 3: Operation Overlord (June 6th 1944)One of the most famous missions from the Medal of Honor series has Powell storming Omaha beach in Normandy. After the intense battle Powell must link up with the 101st Airborne Division.Mission 4: Behind Enemy Lines (June 22nd 1944)Powell must infiltrate behind enemy lines to learn more about the "King Tiger" tank the Germans are producing.Mission 5: (August 20th 1944)Throughout this mission Powell must protect an Allied tank crew fighting to get through the French town of Brest. Once the town is safe, the team must take out a bridge to claim victory.Mission 6: Return to Schmerzen (January 18th 1945)In this mission Powell must infiltrate and destroy the fictional Fort Schmerzen, a mustard gas producing facility. This facility was one of the missions in Medal of Honor for the Playstation.MultiplayerAllied Assault also featured a very popular multiplayer mode that supported up to 64 players at the same time. The game modes include:Free-For-AllTeam DeathmatchRound Based Team DeathmatchObjectiveWeaponsAlliedColt .45Silenced PistolM1 GarandSpringfield 1903Thompson Submachine GunBrowning Automatic RifleMk. II Hand GrenadeBazookaShotgunAxisWalther P38Kar-98kMP-40STG-44StielhandgranatePanzerschreckExpansion PacksMedal of Honor: Allied Assault has two expansions, Medal of Honor: Allied Assault - Spearhead and Medal of Honor: Allied Assault - Breakthrough.</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14912/775477-mohaa.png</image></root>