<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>453</id><name>Need for Speed: High Stakes</name><description>OverviewNeed for Speed: High Stakes (also known as Need for Speed Road Challenge in Europe) is the sixth installment of the Need for Speed series, and was published by Electronic Arts in 1999. It features a large amount of high performance vehicles, exotic cars and law enforcement cruisers in North American and European locations. High Stakes added a new tournament mode titled High Stakes, as well as two new pursuit modes, Getaway and Time Trap.The game also featured a simple damage system - in High Stakes mode, you would have to spend your career earnings in order to fix any damage to your car after races.  While graphically similar to the previous game in the series, Hot Pursuit, High Stakes had a number of small improvements including the addition of driver models to the cars.CarsClass AAAMclaren F1 GTRMercedes CLK-GTRLa Niña (bonus car)Pursuit La Niña (bonus car) Class AABMW M5 (E39)Ferrari F50Ferrari 550 MaranelloLamborghini Diablo SVPorsche 911 Turbo (993) (standard  bonus car)Pursuit BMW M5Pursuit Lamborghini Diablo SV (bonus car)Pursuit Porsche 911 Turbo Class AChevrolet Camaro Z28 (standard  bonus car)Chevrolet Corvette (C5)Jaguar XKRPontiac Firebird (T/A)Pursuit Corvette (C5)Pursuit Camaro (bonus car) Class BBMW Z3 Mercedes SLK 230 TracksHigh Stakes features 19 tracks, 10 new, and 9 returning from the previous game in the series. AquaticAtlanticaCeltic Ruins *Country WoodsDolphin Cove *Durham Road *Empire CityHome TownKindiak Park *Landstrasse *Lost CanyonsRaceway *Raceway 2* Raceway 3 *Redrock RidgeRocky PassRoute Adonf *Snowy Ridge*Summit  * new tracks PC Requirements Windows 95/98/Me/XP (Home Edition); Pentium 200 (Min.); 4x CD-ROM drive (Min.); 32MB RAM (Min.); 2MB DirectX 6.1 compatible graphics card (Min.); DirectX 6.1 compatible sound card; 100Mb free hard drive space.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11055">NASCAR 08</game><game id="2416">Gran Turismo</game><game id="20038">NASCAR: Dirt to Daytona</game><game id="941">Project Gotham Racing</game><game id="19809">Project Gotham Racing 3</game><game id="8930">Rage Racer</game><game id="8437">TOCA 2: Touring Car Challenge</game><game id="20729">GRID</game><game id="7019">Ridge Racer V</game><game id="16276">Ford Bold Moves Street Racing</game><game id="20919">Ford Racing: Off Road</game><game id="7431">Ford Racing</game><game id="12950">Gran Turismo 3 A-Spec</game><game id="7777">Juiced</game><game id="10124">Midnight Club: Street Racing</game><game id="284">NASCAR 2005: Chase for the Cup</game><game id="17872">TOCA Race Driver 3 Challenge</game><game id="8438">NASCAR 06: Total Team Control</game><game id="20484">Burnout</game><game id="13514">Burnout 2: Point of Impact</game><game id="8459">Burnout Dominator</game><game id="16492">Burnout Revenge</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4908/377503-nfs_high_stakes_box.jpg</image></root>