<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4588</id><name>Gold Medal Challenge '92</name><description>OverviewGold Medal Challenge '92 was a Capcom game that was released shortly before the 1992 Summer Olympic Games in Barcelona. There were 12 countries represented in the game, with 18 different events to compete in. The majority were Track and Field events, but also included Swimming, Weightlifting and Gymnastics. Gold Medal Challenge '92 had a battery back-up system that allowed the user to save their progress in the World Tournament mode as well as any world records set while playing. The game allowed up to 8 human players to control different countries with 2 players competing at the same time in an event. Game ModesWorld Tournament World Tournament ran through every event on the game. It was broken up into different programs. Each program consisted of 3 events and 1 round of the Marathon. After each program, an updated medal table would be shown. Also, after each program, the player had the ability to save progress.Training Practice mode. The Marathon event was not available to practice.Total Record The player could view their best scores and see how the matched up the pre-loaded world records. Game PlayTrack and Field / Weightlifting These events were controlled by alternately pressing the A and B buttons back and forth as quickly as possible. The d-pad controlled different movements such as jumping, throwing, lifting or getting out of the starting blocks in a race.Swimming Swimming used a rhythm button pressing method where the A button was pressed along with the swimmer's movements in the pool. The d-pad was used to jump into the pool as well as turning around after 50 meters.GymnasticsGymnastics used a combination of button mashing to gain speed, then pressing a specific button to get your gymnast to do a specific movement (flips, somersault, etc) after hitting the vault.Marathon Marathon was a unique game type that was part of the "Special Program" which occurred after every 3 events in World Tournament mode. In Marathon, the player didn't control the runner. Instead, the player chose a speed at which the player would run for a certain distance for that round. The runner had a set energy bar, so based on a few factors (how much speed, elevations) the energy bar would drop at varying rates. When the runner's energy bar went empty, the runner would drop to the lowest speed possible and normally fall way behind. EventsTrack 100 Meter Dash200 Meter Dash400 Meter Dash4 x 100 Meter Relay110 Meter HurdlesMarathonField Long JumpTriple JumpHigh JumpJavelin ThrowShot PutSwimming 100 Meter Freestyle100 Meter Breast100 Meter Backstroke100 Meter Butterfly200 Meter Medley (50 Meters of Each)GymnasticsVaulting HorseWeightlifting CountriesThere were 12 countries to choose from, the only differences between countries were the character models.Countries The United States of AmericaRussiaChinaCanadaGreat BritainFranceGermanyRomaniaBulgariaHungarySpainJapan</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2361762-nes_goldmedalchallenge92.jpg</image></root>