<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4607</id><name>Solitare</name><description>Overview  Windows 3.1 version     The Microsoft Windows version of Klondike solitaire (known simply as Solitaire) is included with every version of Microsoft Windows since Windows 3.0. Originally developed as a learning tool to help new Windows users unfamiliar with the mouse, it became known as one of the most played PC games of all time. It is widely known for being a distraction in businesses worldwide.  Gameplay The game plays similar to Klondike solitaire, using a deck of traditional playing cards. The objective of the game is to move all the cards from the deck into four "suit stacks" on the top-right corner of the screen. You start with a setup of cards with seven rows (with each row having one card more than the previous row, starting with one card) called the "row stacks". The only card flipped up is the last card you drew for that row. The rest of the deck on the top-left corner of the screen along with the "waste deck".  The game can be timed, which has a direct impact on one of the scoring systems. You can also choose whether to have the Deck draw one card at a time or three cards at a time. (In which you can only choose the top card in the set of three cards) There are three options for scoring:  Standard - The default score method. Starts from 0 on every game and the score is never below 0. Moving a card to the suit stack gives you 10 points. Moving a card from the deck to the row stack gives you 5 points. Moving a card from the suit stack to the row stack removes 15 points. If you are playing with the Draw One option for the deck, you lose 100 points every time you reset the "waste deck" to the deck. If you are playing with the Draw Three option for the deck, you lose 20 points every time you reset the "waste deck" to the deck, but you are granted three free resets. If the game is timed, you lose 2 points every 10 seconds of play and receive a bonus at the end of the game (depending on the length of the game).Vegas - You start a game with a debt of $52. Moving a card to the suit stack wins you $5. If you are playing with the Draw One option for the deck, you can only go through the deck once. If you are playing with the Draw Three option for the deck, you can only go through the deck three times. The scoring can be cumulative.None - There is no score or unique rules.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="13">Card Game</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4032">Minesweeper</game><game id="17554">FreeCell Pro</game><game id="14057">3D Pinball</game><game id="23218">Fairway Solitaire</game><game id="481">Accordion</game><game id="11873">Memory</game><game id="9819">Manga Solitaire</game><game id="33515">Tri-Peaks</game><game id="25288">Spider Solitaire</game><game id="32726">Faerie Solitaire</game><game id="32316">FreeCell</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1389181-solitaire_icon.png</image></root>