<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4608</id><name>World War III: Black Gold</name><description>StoryA secret United Nations think-tank researching world oil production has arrived at a shocking conclusion that the oil reserves have plunged to perilously low levels and within a few years all oil reserves will run out. Without the time required to switch to an alternative energy source for most of the developed world, the UN General Assembly called for all oil fields to be placed within their control to stop the total collapse of the world economy and stop the pandemonium and anarchy expected by such a crisis. With OPEC countries unwilling to hand over the oil supply the UN drafts a resolution to forcible capture all oil reserves in the world beginning with Middle East. Play as the USA, Russia or Iraq and help defend and take over as many resources as you can.GameplayCampaignTutorial modes exit of all 3 classes and each class (USA, Russia, Iraq) have 2 campaign modes. At the beginning of the game only USA campaign mode 1 is available for the player. This must be first completed before Russia mode 1 and Iraq mode 1 are unlocked. After all campaign mode 1's are completed, campaign mode 2 is unlocked for USA. Completing USA mode 2 unlocks subsequent campaign modes.SkirmishStart a single player game using network scenario which can be edited using in-game map editor. There are 3 skirmish modes each with different victory conditions.Destroy StructuresVictory Condition - Destroy all enemy buildingsTechnology - Use monies available to research and build new technology, weapons and vehicles.Economy - Gain more money by capturing oil fields and building oil mines and oil shafts. Supply power to then by building generators for constant production.Limited Cost BattleVictory Condition - Destroy all enemy buildingsTechnology - Use monies available to research and build new technology, weapons and vehicles.Economy - You have limited amount to money to win the battle with. There is no way of earning more money meaning careful planing and expenditure of available resourcesTech WarVictory Condition - Destroy all enemy structuresTechnology - All technologies are available from the start to both parties. No need to research new technologies, weapons or vehicles.Economy - Gain more money by capturing oil fields and building oil mines and oil shafts. Supply power to then by building generators for constant production.MultiplayerTest your skills again human opponents using a LAN based network.OnlineUsing WarNet you can play online joining existing channels or creating new ones. Play with up to sixteen players, each color coded. Make and break alliances as you go. Choose existing game modes or create new game ones. All online stats are tracked with WarNet's battle statistics option.ClassesAll 3 classes are well balanced and each have their own advantage but all have the same basic use of technology. All three sides use tanks and helicopters as their main armament. Russians are good are manufacturing vehicles as well as have to most knowledge of using chemical weapons to kill enemies and capture their vehicles. The Iraqis get truck bombs and SCUD missile launchers for their ambush style attack but can also procure chemical weapons. The US gets long-range motors that can deliver air strikes from F-15's and B-2 bombers but can also stealth technology for ambush and sneak attacks.USAThe USA has fast production capacities as well as a large group of skilled scientist and engineers. This makes then quickly unlock new technologies. Good intelligence enables them to study future battle areas well in advance of the enemy. Logistics is a hindrance due to war taking place far away from home, this makes Americas was effort primarily a question of transport, supply and movement.RussiaRussia has a huge stockpile of military equipment such as vehicles and weaponry however some of it is outdated and not as modern as its enemies. The use of internationally banned weapons still plays a big part in their strategy. Old technologies have its advantages as it’s inexpensive to produce and easily repairable making it very effective on the battlefield. Neglection of scientific research has lead to a slow development of new technologies.IraqIraqi military power is weak. It has a large army but suffers from shortages and generally has very little to no equipment. Foreign companies wanting to make huge monetary gains will break the arms embargo and supply an assortment of goods for the right price. With the greatest knowledge of the local terrain, locating oil reserves and exploiting them is an easy task. Furthermore its forced can perfectly camouflage into the landscape and deal kamikaze like blows and ambushes to the enemy. Units USA M1025A2 HummerStatsArmor: NoneSpeed: FastWeaponry: M60 or machine gun or M29 grenade launcherAdditional Equipment: Screemer, Advanced Sensors Unit RussiaUAZ-469StatsArmor: NoneSpeed: FastWeaponry: 7.62 PK machine gunAdditional Equipment: None  IraqWillisStatsArmor: NoneSpeed: FastWeaponry: Machine gun, launcher for 9M111 anti-tank missilesAdditional Equipment: Filter, Decoy shooter  USAM1 Abrams  StatsArmor: Heavy made of steelSpeed: LimitedWeaponry: 120-mm gunAdditional Equipment: Filter, Decoy scooter FCROther Fleet: M2 Bradley, AMX Leclerc, M109 PalladinRussiaT-80StatsArmor: Heavy, made of steelSpeed: SlowWeaponry: 125-mm gunAdditional Equipment: Filter, Decoy scooter, FRCOther Fleet: 2S3 Akatsai, BRT-60PBIraqT-72StatsArmor: Medium-heavy, made of steelSpeed: SlowWeaponry: 12-mm gunAdditional Equipment: Filter, FRCOther Fleet: Scorpion  USAAH 64 ApacheStatsArmor: Heavy, syntheticSpeed: FastWeaponry: (2 mounting bars) 30mm-M230 gun, smartHellfire or Stringer Missiles, dumb Hydra rockets.Additional Equipment: Decoy shooter, FRCOther Fleet: AH1 Cobra, RAH 66-Commanche, UH-60 Backhawk, CH47D Chinook RussiaMi-26StatsArmor: Medium-heavy, made of steelSpeed: FastWeaponry: (2 mounting bars) Chain-firing gun or smart anti-tank missiles - 9P149 type Sthurm, or non-guided UB-32'sAdditional Equipment: Decoy shooter, FRCOther Fleet: Ka-50 Kamov, Ka-29 TB, Mi-26, Mi-8 IraqMi-6StatsArmor: Medium-heavy, made of steelSpeed: FastWeaponry: NoneAdditional Equipment: NoneOther Fleet: SA-330 Puma  USACamcopterStatsArmor: NoneSpeed: FastWeaponry: NoneAdditional Equipment: None Other Fleet: Patroit Russia9P117 SCUDStatsArmor: Light, made of steelSpeed: SlowWeaponry: SCUD missilesAdditional Equipment: Filter Other Fleet: BM-21 Rocket Artiller, ZRK-SD RombIraqAl HusseinStatsArmor: Very light, made of steelSpeed: SlowWeaponry: Al Hussein missilesAdditional Equipment: Filter Other Fleet: Astros, Type 63 USAChallengerStatsArmor: Light, made of steelSpeed: ModerateWeaponry: NoneAdditional Equipment: Filter Other Fleet: M113 APC, Miner, Engineering Unit RussiaEngineering Unit IMR-2MStatsArmor: Light, made of steelSpeed: ModerateWeaponry: NoneAdditional Equipment: None Other Fleet: GMZ-3, ZSU-23-4 Shilka IraqEngineering Unit DachsStatsArmor: Medium-heavy, made of steelSpeed: ModerateWeaponry: NoneAdditional Equipment: FilterOther Fleet: Roland II, Fuchs A4, 40 Ford Pickup, Ural-375, EPG, Miner  StructuresLike Units structures are also class based and each class has slight variations. TurretThe basic structures which all classes get are Power Generation, Airports, Landing zones, Supply centers, Nests and Shafts. The others depend upon the military capability of the nation. The US has variations of Turrets and a lot of protective structures such as Jammers and Bomb control whereas Russia has more attacking structures like anti-rocket and tank cannons. Iraq has more espionage based structures such as saboteur and spy centers.System RequirementsMinimumPentium II 266 MHz64 MB RAM3D graphics card with 8MB4x CD Rom driveDirect X 8.0800MB hard diskspaceRecommendedPentium III 500 MHz or higher128 MB RAM800MB hard diskspace3D graphics card with 16MB8x CD Rom drive or faster16 BIT PCI soundcardDirect X 8.0 or higher</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2826">Wargame Construction Set III: Age of Rifles 1846-1905</game><game id="17561">Earth 2140</game><game id="18072">Command &amp; Conquer: Red Alert 2</game><game id="3711">Real War</game><game id="15500">WarCommander</game><game id="5817">WarGames: Defcon 1</game><game id="39305">Wargame: AirLand Battle</game><game id="35658">Wargame: European Escalation</game><game id="7489">Act of War: Direct Action</game><game id="2478">Act of War: High Treason</game><game id="17004">Warzone 2100</game><game id="9955">War Inc.</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4527/1247887-460178.jpg</image></root>