<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4680</id><name>Zoo Tycoon 2</name><description>OverviewZoo Tycoon 2 is a sim game developed by Blue Fang Games and published by MacSoft and 1C Company for the PC and Mac platforms.GameplayThere are a number of gameplay modes in the game, and each has differing limitations.A free-form game allows you to create the zoo of your choice, the only restrictions being space, animals and objects. The players money supply is unlimited, and all items are available from the beginning from the game (except items that have be to unlocked in the other game modes). Free-form games begins with an empty zoo, to which the player adds animal exhibits and guest facilities, hiring employees to staff and maintain them. The player chooses a plot of land for their zoo to be built upon the at the start of the Free-form game, and each land represents a different biome.Each plot of land is also a different size. The player must accommodate their animals with spacious enclosures, adequate food and water, animal enrichment objects, shelters for them to sleep or gain privacy in, and environments. The player must also provide for the guests, which is done by placing food and drink stands, bathrooms, picnic areas, seating, trash and recycling bins and playground around the zoo. The player can create a range of elevated and lowered terrain types, including hills, valleys, cliffs and ditches. In addition to free-form mode, there is also a campaign mode in which the player chooses a campaign to play through and is placed in the shoes of an average zoo owner and is assigned different goals to complete; these goals may include having to breed tapirs, train dolphins, rescuing abused animals and more.There is also a challenge mode in which the player has a limited amount of money with which goals must be completed.AnimalsAfrican ElephantAmerican BeaverBengal TigerBlack RhinocerosCheetahChimpanzeeCommon PeafowlCommon ZebraDromedary CamelEmperor PenguinGemsbokGiant PandaGreater FlamingoGrizzly BearHippopotamusIbexJaguarLionMooseMountain GorillaNile CrocodileOkapiOstrichPolar BearRed KangarooRed PandaReticulated GiraffeRing-tailed LemurSnow LeopardThomson's GazelleAnimals available via DLCAddaxAsian ElephantAsiatic Black BearBlack LeopardMusk OxReceptionThe game received mixed reviews from various gaming websites and publications. Upon release the game was heavily criticized for the many apparent bugs.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="8">Educational</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20682">Viva Piñata: Trouble in Paradise</game><game id="2236">RollerCoaster Tycoon</game><game id="6097">Zoo Tycoon: Dinosaur Digs</game><game id="3799">The Movies</game><game id="12881">Vegas Tycoon</game><game id="11069">Jurassic Park: Operation Genesis</game><game id="42908">Zoo Tycoon</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/56/668314-938891_86167_front.jpg</image></root>