<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4702</id><name>BurgerTime</name><description>The original Burgertime was an arcade game released in 1982. A platform based game, the stages were a series of platforms with sections that where made of components of a mighty hamburger. These were composed in the level vertically so that as the player walked across them they would drop until eventually making a complete sandwich. The finished burger itself was such a titan that it dwarved the player himself. Of note, the servers who would carry this burger to the customers where never shown.Obviously, the player controlled the feisty Peter Pepper, a chef whose objective was to walk, climb and scurry all over the platforms in order to build his burgers. As the chef walked completely across the top of the layer, it would drop one level below..thusly knocking the layer beneath down one level also. After all the layers have been dropped onto the platters awaiting below, the burger is complete and there is much rejoicing. But the struggle continues until all hamburgers are completed, only then is the level clear. And our hero earns a brief rest before the next stage begins.As with most of the games of the time, the levels become more complex and difficult as you progress. This is accomplished through varied platform layouts, more enemies(covered later), and an ever increasing number of burger components. Just like in real life, no one orders a plain cheeseburger for long. While the chef fights to keep his customers fed and happy, he is besieged by three malcontents of the food industry. Mr. Hot Dog, Mr. Pickle and Mr. Egg. These 3 can be killed temporarily by dropping a layer of the burger on top of them but it is a short solution as they reappear at the edge of the screen after a short time. A crafty chef can also make the fiends chase him across a partially walked across layer and then complete it as the enemy steps on to it. The layer will then drop along with the enemy whose weight causes it to drop 2 levels as opposed to just one. An added benefit to this technique is that it temporarily stuns the enemy. And if you a a real stud, you may crush other enemies beneath the falling enemy and burger as well. Instilling a lifelong guilt in him for crushinThe Title screeng his comrade in arms. Peter Pepper also has a small supply of pepper he can throw in the enemies face to render them harmless for a few seconds. Additional pepper can be acquired by picking up ice cream and other items that will randomly spawn on the level. How the chef can turn a dairy product into pepper is another testament to his awesome skills.Pizza Time, the hotly anticipated sequel was in development when the video game market went into a decline, and sadly was never released.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5289">Mr. Wimpy: The Hamburger Game</game><game id="14580">Pressure Cooker</game><game id="311">Donkey Kong</game><game id="22073">Fast Food</game><game id="14419">Popeye</game><game id="18057">Beef Drop</game><game id="16881">Super Drinker</game><game id="11482">MacAttack</game><game id="30098">Burger Boy</game><game id="9536">Bear Bovver</game><game id="40123">Iron Chef</game><game id="30097">Burgerkill</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2366947-intv_burgertime_none.jpg</image></root>