<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4725</id><name>Metroid Prime 3: Corruption</name><description>OverviewMetroid Prime 3: Corruption is the tenth game in the Metroid series, and the final game in the Metroid Prime trilogy. Like the other games in the Metroid Prime series, Corruption was developed by Retro Studios. Corruption sees the series make its first transition from the GameCube onto the Wii.along with the first implementation of motion controls which would later be brought to updated versions of Metroid Prime and Metroid Prime 2 for the New Play Control series and Metroid Prime Trilogy release.Samus AranThe main difference between Corruption and the previous Prime games is its control scheme. Corruption makes substantial use of the motion sensing Remote. While the player still has the option to lock-on to any opponent on the screen and strafe around that foe, the control scheme allows you to freely fire at any on-screen enemy by simply pointing the remote at the screen, while using Wii Remote gestures for contraptions such as levers and the grapple hook. The standard gameplay elements of the Metroid series are still largely present in Corruption. The player once again takes the role of bounty hunter Samus Aran, who visits multiple planets this time around. As expected, Samus explores different areas while earning new abilities that allow her to overcome previously impassable environmental obstacles.GameplayCorruption is a traditional first-person shooter, similar to the previous two Metroid Prime games. Corruption is controlled using the Wii Remote's motion sensor. The player can aim and shoot using the Wii Remote and Nunchuk combination (the Nunchuk's analog stick controls movement while the Wii Remote controls viewpoint). The Wii Remote also controls other actions, such as jumping and firing.Corruption takes place across a variety of planets in the world of Metroid Prime. Several of these planets have been overtaken by Phazon, an incredibly dangerous substance that Samus has been exposed to (thus granting her special Phazon based abilities). She can go into a hyper mode, in which her Phazon meter keeps her in that mode. She is much more powerful in this mode, and can destroy Phazon corrupted objects and enemies.The game also contains a variety of puzzles relating to Samus' abilities. For example, she uses her Morph Ball ability to go into smaller areas and use the bomb to trigger certain events. Samus' visor has many of her other abilities, in addition to having the heads-up display. Other visors can be unlocked, from an X-ray visor to a heat vision visor.PlotGandrayda has shape-shifting abilities.Corruption stars Samus Aran, the main protagonist of the Metroid franchise. Samus Aran and three other bounty hunters (Gandrayda, Ghor, and Rundas) are called to the Galactic Federation for a meeting with the leader of the organization, Admiral Dane. He briefs the bounty hunters on a crisis that has been occurring in the galaxy. Admiral Dane says that many of the Aurora Units (biological supercomputers that are linked in a network across the galaxy) have contracted a computer virus, causing them to malfunction. The meeting ends when the fleet is attacked by Space Pirates.On Norion, there is a Galactic Federation naval base. This base is being barraged by attacks from Space Pirates. The bounty hunters are all sent to Norion to help defeat the attacking Space Pirates. While fending off the Space Pirates, Samus learns of a large, Phazon-covered asteroid called a Leviathan Seed that is about to crash into the planet. After getting all of the defense systems online and preparing for departure, the group is attacked by Dark Samus, who leaves all of the bounty hunters unconscious (save for Samus, who triggers the defense system just in time).Dark SamusSamus stays unconscious for a month. When she wakes up on a Galactic Federation ship, it is revealed that she has been corrupted with Phazon, the incredibly mutagenic substance that Dark Samus specializes in. To combat this Phazon, Samus is given a Phazon Enhancement Device (PED) that allows her to use the Phazon produced by her body as a power source. The other bounty hunters had awakened much earlier, and were already sent off to investigate other planets. Samus is initially sent to two planets, Bryyo and Elysia, to search for these missing bounty hunters. Here, she finds that to combat the Phazon corrupting the galaxy, she must destroy all of the Leviathan Seeds embedded in various planets.The Space Pirates are intent on stopping Samus from attaining this goal, however, sending forth various creatures that have been exposed to this mutagen. Samus also encounters her fellow bounty hunters, who, unable to control their PEDs, were completely corrupted. As the game progresses, Samus gradually becomes further corrupted with Phazon. After investigating the Space Pirate Homeworld, Samus finds that all of the Phazon has been coming from Phaaze, a planet accessible only via a wormhole created by a modified Leviathan. There, she confronts Dark Samus and a corrupted Aurora Unit 313. She defeats them in combat, and as a result Phazon is eradicated from the galaxy. The game ends with Samus flying off into space, with a ship resembling Sylux's (a bounty hunter from Metroid Prime: Hunters) ship following her.WeaponsPower BeamQuickest to fire, and also quickest moving but has the lowest damage per shot, good to use on fast moving enemies. The charged version is simply more powerful, and is the quickest to charge of all the beams.MissilesSlower to fire, it is also much more powerful than the power beam.Hyper ModeA super powerful mode that injects phazon into your suit. It is incredibly powerful, but can only be used for 10 seconds, or complete corruption will occur.Grapple LassoA new weapon in Metroid Prime 3. It allows you to latch on and pull off shields of enemies and pieces of metal in front of openings.Grapple SwingThis attachment to the grapple lasso lets you grab onto poles hanging from the roof and then swing while attached. It is also used in Elysia to slide on transit poles to get from side to side.Morph Ball BombsWhile in morphball mode, you can drop 3 bombs at a time. They are used for killing enemies, destroying debris, and activating switches. They are crucial to solving puzzles.Upgrades/New WeaponsPlasma BeamThis beam has the same rate of fire as the power beam, but is more powerful and can melt certain enemies. It is also used as a welder to fix destroyed panels.Nova BeamThe final upgrade to your regular beam, it is green in color and is has a high rate of fire. It can be used with the X-Ray Visor to shoot invisible targets, as well as activate switched through special doors made of Phazon or target weakpoints in certain enemies.Ice MissilesThe upgrade to the missiles lets you shoot beams that are ice cold and can freeze and slow down enemies. It can freeze lava temporarily.Seeker MissileA multi-targeting upgrade that enables you to lock on to five objects at one. Usually used to blast open doors with obvious markings.Boost BallAn upgrade to the morph ball that lets you temporarily shoot forward in a burst of speed.Spider BallAn upgrade to the morph ball that lets you stick to specific tracks and ride along them to other places.Screw AttackIt lets you wall jump up identifiable Screw Attack points, plus cover huge gaps (up to five mid-air jumps are allowed)Grapple VoltageAnother upgrade to the grapple lasso that lets you give or steal power to turn on or turn off power panels. You can also use it to steal health from enemies.Hazard Suit This suit upgrade lets you walk without punishment through areas with acid rain. It also provides protection against other hazards such as Fuel Gel.Hyper Mode UpgradesHyper MissileThis lets you shoot missiles in hyper mode. They are very powerful but use a chunk of your health.Hyper BallThis Morph ball attack sends strings of phazon at enemies around you. It will lock on and cause major damage if kept on an enemy.Hyper GrappleThe grapple lets you inject enemies with phazon and overload them to the point of exploding.VisorsX-Ray VisorA visor that lets you see invisible targets, use scrambled HUD machines, and see echoes.Command VisorThis visor lets you call in your ship for bombing runs, to pick up specific things, and to land in specific areas so you can either take off or save.Scan VisorThis visor lets you scan things to gather more information about the world around you, the enemies you are fighting, and the past of the planet through lore articles.Combat VisorYour regular visor that lets you use all of your weapons.ExtrasWhile Metroid Prime 3 is primarily a single player endeavor, completing certain tasks in the game can earn you special vouchers. These vouchers can be traded with friends and used to unlock extras and bonus content, such as concept art. These vouchers are also used alongside Red, Blue and Gold Tokens you get along the way in the game by scanning enemies, lore, passing certain events and defeating bosses. You can defeat bosses in Hypermode for an additional Gold Token per boss and events.Concept GallerySamus PackageIncludes 12 pieces of concept art, showing off the various gear used in the game.Creature Package 1Includes12 pieces of concept art, varying from early allies and enemies to early bosses.Creature Package 2Includes 12 pieces of conceprt art, mainly showing enemies and bosses from the second half of the game.World Package 1Includes 12 pieces of concept art showing off locations from the first half of the game.World Package 2Includes 8 pieces of concept art showing off locations from the second half of the game.Storyboard Package 1Includes 7 storyboard concepts from the game.Storyboard Package 2Includes 5 storyboard concepts from the game.Bonus GalleryShip Bumper StickersBy turning this feature "On", stickers appear on Samus' ship based on save files on your Wii's System Memory. Stickers are from Nintendo's 1st Party games on Wii including , Excite Truck, Wario Ware: Smooth Moves, Galaxy, and Metroid Prime 3 itself. Also included is a Retro Studios sticker.Screen-Shot ToolBy turning this feature "On", at any time during the game, you can Press Up on the Directional Pad to take a photo which is sent to your Wii Message Board.Mii BobbleheadBy turning this feature "On", a Mii Bobblehead will appear inside Samus' ship corresponding to the Mii picked for your Save File.Diorama 1This diorama portrays the opening major boss battle.Diorama 2This diorama portrays Samus on the planet Bryyo.Diorama 3This diorama portrays the second major boss battle.Diorama 4This diorama portrays a minor boss battle that occurs on the planet Elysia.Diorama 5This diorama portrays another minor boss battle on the planet Elysia.Diorama 6This diorama portrays part of the final boss battle in the game.Soundtrack GalleryThe soundtrack gallery includes 15 songs from the game as follows:MP3 Title MusicIn the CockpitGF Battle ThemeBryyoBryyo Thorn JungleThe CorruptionSkyTownSteamlordValhallaMetroid Battle ThemeHeliosPirate HomeworldGandraydaOmega RidleyPhazeCritical Reception Metroid Prime 3: Corruption was critically acclaimed, scoring an average of 90% on review compilation databases GameRankings and Metacritic. It was praised for its advanced, intuitive controls, impressive technical and artistic visuals, and an outstanding single player campaign. It was criticized, however, for a lower difficulty, overall similarity to the previous two installments in the series, and minor gripes with the context-sensitive motion gesturing.Trilogy Re-ReleaseOn August 24th, 2009, Metroid Prime 3: Corruption was re-released on the Wii in North America as part of the Metroid Prime Trilogy along with the first two games updated with motion controls.</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20333">Geist</game><game id="17280">BioShock</game><game id="25327">Nerf N-Strike</game><game id="7712">Red Steel</game><game id="11454">Resident Evil: The Umbrella Chronicles</game><game id="26706">Shadow Complex</game><game id="1339">Star Wars: Republic Commando</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2392952-metroid_prime_3_corruption_02_artwork.jpg</image></root>