<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4728</id><name>LMA Manager 2001</name><description>LMA Manager 2001 is the sequel to the hit football (soccer) management game, LMA Manager. It was released on 16 March, 2001 on the PlayStation. It is based on the 2000/2001 football season.New FeaturesNew country, Scottish leagues are now playable.Updated for the 2000/2001 football season.Full European transfer market.Improved graphics with better animations in the 3D match engines.Expert Mode.Game ModesThere were not too many new game modes in LMA Manager 2001. Here are the LMA game modes and the '01 game modes;Full Game: Manage a team from either the English or Scottish Leagues. All of the tactical, financial and transfer are up to the user. The game begins during the pre-season friendlies stage.Expert Mode: A harder version of the full game mode. All of the player stats and abilities are hidden from the player. This means the player must scout more and provides a challenge for hardcore fans.Quick Start: This mode is the Full Game mode expect all of the tactical, financial and transfers/contracts are left up to the AI backroom staff. The game beings after the pre-season friendlies stage, letting the player dive straight into the season.Challenge Mode: This lets the player take over a club and the is give a specific challenge. For example, you start with a club with ten games left and must avoid relegation.LeaguesScottish leagues were added to the game, added to the English leagues. Here is the list of playable leagues:English Premier DivisionEnglish Division OneEnglish Division TwoEnglish Division ThreeScottish PremiershipScottish First DivisionScottish Second DivisionScottish Third DivisionReceptionLMA Manager 2001 didn't stray far from the LMA formula. There were not many new features introduced in the game. It was an improvement over the original game but there are still a few bugs. The 3D match engine is very un-realistic., with insane shots and crosses. The game still built off LMA Manager and let the series continue for the last PlayStation and first PlayStation 2 LMA game, LMA Manager 2002.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="40">Soccer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8108">Championship Manager Season 97/98</game><game id="3753">FIFA Manager 07</game><game id="13578">Championship Manager 2</game><game id="15731">Championship Manager 96/97</game><game id="12974">Championship Manager 2: Scandinavian Leagues</game><game id="5444">Championship Manager 4</game><game id="20279">Championship Manager 5</game><game id="27051">Championship Manager 2007</game><game id="10532">Championship Manager 3</game><game id="16216">Championship Manager '93</game><game id="3248">Championship Manager: Season 1999/2000</game><game id="5605">FIFA Manager 06</game><game id="24888">FIFA Manager 09</game><game id="20784">Football Manager 2008</game><game id="22117">Worldwide Soccer Manager 2006</game><game id="13818">Football Manager</game><game id="23498">Football Manager 2009</game><game id="22169">Football Manager Live</game><game id="2662">Football Manager 2</game><game id="8454">Premier Manager 2000</game><game id="5762">Premier Manager 3</game><game id="1467">FA Premier League Football Manager 2000</game><game id="10527">Premier Manager 2005-2006</game><game id="6697">Premier Manager Ninety Nine</game><game id="17239">Premier Manager 3 De-Luxe</game><game id="7009">Premier Manager 97</game><game id="13">Premier Manager 98</game><game id="4805">Soccer Team Manager: English and Italian Leagues</game><game id="30751">Football Manager 2011</game><game id="33212">Football Manager 2012</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9261/310575-51mryr8fr4l._sl500_aa280_.jpg</image></root>