<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>476</id><name>Grand Prix 3 Season 2000</name><description>Overview Grand Prix 3 2000 Season is the only add-on for Grand Prix 3. The add-on brought extra features and circuits to the game. These included enhanced 3D car graphics and circuits and two additional circuits ( Sepang in Malaysia, Indianapolis in USA ), improved artificial intelligence and full 3D spatial sounds as well as and updated car simulator. Additional features included a new race mode, debris collision, enhanced replay system and a special Formula 1 reference section.   Features 2000 Season data (22 drivers, 11 teams), including car performances and car liveriesNew circuits: Sepang in Malaysia, Indianapolis in USA and updated 3D graphics on other tracksNew game mode: 'Quicklaps' enables up to 22 players to challenge for the fastest lapDebris collision, Pit car radio chatter, full use of EAX enhancements; reflections from the track features and tunnel reverbEnhanced replay control facilities and improved sound system including full 3DGPaedia, a section providing in depth information on the 2000 season Teams and DriversFerrariMichael SchumacherRubens BarrichelloMcLaren - MercedesMika HakkinenDavid CoulthardWilliams - BMWRalf SchumacherJenson ButtonBenetton - PlaylifeGiancarlo FisichellaAlexander WurzBAR - HondaJacques VillenueveRicardo ZontaJordan- Mugen HondaHeinz-Harald FrentzenJarno TrulliArrows - SupertecPedro de la RosaJos VerstappenSauber - PetronasPedro DinizMika SaloJagaur - CosworthEddie IrvineJohnny HerbertMinardi - FondmetalMarc GeneGaston MazzacaneProst - PeugeotJean AlesiNick HeidfeldCircuitsAustralia - MelbourneBrazil - InterlagosSan Marino - ImolaGreat Britain - SilverstoneSpain - CatalunyaEurope - NurburgringMonaco - Monte-CarloCanada - MontrealFrance - Magny-CoursAustria - A1-RingGermany - HockenheimHungary - HungaroringBelgium - Spa-FrancorchampsItaly - MonzaUnited States - IndianapolisJapan - SuzukaMalaysia - Sepang</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8360">F1 World Championship Edition</game><game id="14919">Grand Prix Challenge</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1330/1387026-grand_prix_3_2000_season.jpg</image></root>