<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4762</id><name>Street Fighter Alpha Anthology</name><description>OverviewStreet Figher Alpha Anthology consists of  Street Fighter Alpha,  Street Fighter Alpha 2, Street Fighter Alpha 2 Gold,  Street Fighter Alpha 3, and  Super Gem Fighter.  Street Fighter Alpha Released in 1995, Street Fighter Alpha features a redrawn look for the cast, and the game takes place in between the original Street Fighter  Street Fighter II. The game reintroduce some of the characters from the original Street Fighter who didn't appear in Street Fighter II - Birdie, Adon, - and also introduces Final Fight characters into the Street Fighter universe. The game also brings Charlie - who is the dead friend of Guile from Street Fighter II - and Dan, a joke character of several SNK characters.  Street Fighter Alpha  Street Fighter Alpha 2 Released in 1996, Street Fighter Alpha 2 features many brand new gameplay elements such as Air-Block, Alpha Counters, Fall Breaks, and custom combos. Also the player can have three levels of supers in a match. The game also introduces Sakura to the Street Fighter series and brings back Zangief, Dhalsim and Akuma from Street Fighter II and Gen from the original Street Fighter.Rolento also joins the cast as the third Final Fight character to to be featured in a Street Fighter game. Street Fighter Alpha 2       Street Fighter Alpha 2 Gold Street Fighter Alpha 2 Gold is a update of the game that was never released in the U.S. The game features a remix soundtrack and brings back Cammy from Super Street Fighter II.Street Fighter Alpha 2 Gold      Street Fighter Alpha 3 The final game in the Alpha series, released in 1998. The game brings back everybody from Street Fighter II and introduce another Final Fight character to the roster, Cody. The gameplay features adds in a whole lot to Street Fighter Alpha 3; such as, "Guard Breaks" it's where the player has a guard meter during a match, if the player blocks too much the player will get stun which will leave him or her for an opening for a attack. The game also features three different fighting style known as "Ism". The fighting styles are based on previous Street Fighter games.  Street Fighter Alpha 3        Super Gem Fighter Mini Mix Super Gem Fighter is a fighting game that features the "Super Deformed" characters from Puzzle Fighter. The fighting in the game is very simple. The game also has Gems that the player can pick up in the middle of a fight to power up his or her character. Super Gem Fighter Mini Mix      </description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre><genre id="15">Compilation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10218">World Heroes Anthology</game><game id="17194">Fatal Fury: Battle Archives Volume 1</game><game id="7751">Art of Fighting Anthology</game><game id="14669">Virtua Fighter Animation</game><game id="1329">Pocket Fighter</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="22843">Fatal Fury: Battle Archives Volume 2</game><game id="22820">Red Earth</game><game id="12125">Capcom Fighting Evolution</game><game id="10574">X-Men: Children of the Atom</game><game id="22953">Ultimate Fighter</game><game id="16200">The King of Fighters: Neowave</game><game id="20456">Street Fighter IV</game><game id="11189">Tekken 3</game><game id="32744">Mortal Kombat Arcade Kollection</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2160118-box_sfaa.png</image></root>