<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>478</id><name>Z</name><description>CGI Cutscene, Commander Zod Z became very popular amongst strategy fans and in 2001, a modern 3D-accelerated sequel was published by               EON Digital Entertainment. The sequel was called               Z:Steel Soldiers, differentiating itself from the first game. Unable to satisfy the expectations of fans, the sequel was criticized for adapting modern RTS mechanics that were very different from the first game.StoryZ is a riotous race for supremacy between armies of space-faring robots with the personalities of humans. Your aim, as the commander of your robot forces, is to annihilate the enemy forces and to conquer each planet that you land on. The enemy on each planet are disposed of in one of two ways. You can either destroy all of their soldiers, or if you can break through their defences walk one of your robots straight into their headquarters and blow it sky-high.  The action is fast and furious. Be prepared to make life and death decisions on the spur of the moment. Remember, in Z, hesitate and you've had it. Experience the war alongside the trigger-happy              Commander Zod and two notorious robot slackers from the Red Faction, Brad and Allan.GameplayZ isn't a traditional real-time strategy game. Unlike similar games, the objective is to defeat the enemy by capturing territory and either destroying all the enemy units or by sending one of your own inside their headquarters. The original game is also extremely slow, with emphasis on strategy and building tension, but with Z95, they offered the option for faster gameplay. Along the way, the action is complimented by the voices of your comrades and overall the experience is much more light-hearted than other RTS games, Along the way the action is complimented by the voices of your comrades and overall the experience is much more light-hearted than other RTS games, but still provides a very good challenge.GameplayWhile other RTS games usually focus on gathering resources and building your base and army, these elements are handled automatically and the gameplay focuses on action and micro management. Instead of creating buildings, you capture the territory that a building is encompassed by and it will automatically begin producing units for you. This is an interesting mechanic because an enemy can potentially capture your territory right before your units are produced and vice versa. You are able to choose what units are manufactured by each individual factory, but the rate of production is determined by how powerful the unit is, how much territory your team has captured and how much damage that building has taken. The terrain can be deformed, with sometimes surprising results. Rocks can be exploded and the debree will fly up in the air and can kill units if they get crushed by it, the same is true for anything that explodes. Humourously enough, if your units are bored and decide to shoot at near-by lizards, it is possible for them to fall on your units too. Bridges can be destroyed to distract the enemy, factories can be destroyed to delay reinforcements.Z brings a lot of personality to the genre, your units will respond to your orders and decisions - Expressing calmness, anger, terror, anxiety and desperation. This acts as a way of communicating with the player on a more understandable level and less intruding manner. For example, if you send weak units against more powerfuls ones they will respond hesitantly and if you're about to be defeated, your units and the commentator will curse at you. They will also express delight if you win and anxiety to move in if the enemy is vastly outnumbered. Voice acting keeps the game HUD fairly minimal allowing the player to concentrate on the action. The environments are very much alive, unlike other RTS games with wonderful animation and interactivity, the A.I. demonstrates intelligence on it's own whether that's taking flags and capturing vehicles or interacting with each other and their envrionments while idle, this makes micro management less frustrating when you have multiple enemy encounters at different locations.FeaturesIntuitive control interface, pick up and play Detailed graphics and animation Many different capturable buildings like factories, radar and repair installations 6 robot types and 11 types of hardware from tanks to artillery Over 30 minutes of animated cutscenes with voice-overs Conditional music system blends one theme into another to fit the action Fast and Frantic gameplay with up to 4 players over the Internet or Local Area Network Real-time sprite scale and rotation enabled through automatic hardware scaling  Expansion-Pack onlyImprovements made to the A.I. and unit balancing Three levels of difficulty and three speed settings Up to 4 player multi-player support with a single CD-ROM (ZExpansionXP improves multiplayer support) 35 single player, 25 two player, 15 three and four-player maps. Multi-Player level editor Bonus Windows 95 theme pack included  WorldCombat takes place on several planets, with 4 missions on each. When one is successfully captured, a space ship transports the robot army to another. Worlds are divided into the following types:  DesertA dry, open and scarcely vegetated environment, in which units have little trouble moving around freely. The player encounters rivers and islands as they progress through the battles on this planet. Some territories are controlled by flags on islands. VolcanicA much more hostile environment. Lava flows are an impassable barrier. ArcticA frozen world of snow and ice spanned by glacial rock formations.  JungleA verdant world of menacing swamps and impenetrable chasms. Crocodiles in the swamps eat robots hanging around the mud. CityA decaying industrial complex where danger lies around every corner. Monsters in sewers will ambush robots moving through water.  UnitsAble to capture vehicles and artillery. Collect grenades and travel through swamps. GruntsCGI Cutscene, Brad and AllanWeakest units, quickest to build. Equipped with rifles, they can be useful to have besides a vehicle so that if the driver is sniped, you have more units to control the vehicle. Grenades make them significantly more powerful. Other than out of desperation, these guys are best avoided in favour of stronger units. PsychosModerately powerful, slower but also quick to build. They carry rapid-fire machine guns and can quickly eliminate un-guarded grunts. ToughStrong and as implied, they have the best armour. Not very intelligent, they carry missile guns comparable to the turrets of a tank, however they are unable to snipe enemies out of their vehicles and should be put aside if you hope to capture vehicles instead of destroying them. SniperEquipped with a rifle, they are able to shoot enemies out of their vehicles and artillery guns from a distance and more effectively than grunts, making them less of a target. Extremely intelligent. PyrosExpensive but effective, especially against tanks. These units are semi-intelligent and only slightly less protected than Toughs. LaserThese units carry lasers. Vulnerable due to their slow reloading time, however their weapon packs quite a punch. They aren't very intelligent and take the longest time to build.  VehiclesDrivers can be shot out of vehicles, allowing them to be captured by the enemy. JeepCommon early in the game, but are generally ignored in favour of tanks later on. Jeeps carry machine guns and they are fast, it is possible to dodge grenades and wipe out weaker units. Light TankThe lightest tank is also the fastest of the bunch, will easily make mince meat of large groups of grunts but may struggle against any kind of artillery or multiple jeeps. Vulnerable to being taken over, thus becoming a tough enemy unless you keep your own robots nearby. Medium TankFaster than Heavy, stronger than Light. May be preferable over Heavys when speed cannot be entirely compromised. Heavy TankStrong but very slow to build. On top of their tough armour, they also have extended firing range making them effective against almost anything. Mobile MissileVery expensive compared to other vehicles. They'll take a long time to build and they're extremely slow but pose a huge threat, capable of destroying missile artillery with ease due to maneuverability. APCUse to transport and protect your robots, the vehicle adapts to the units it carries and it's weapons will vary as such. CraneThe crane is used to repair destroyed buildings and bridges. Vehicles still need to use the repair factories.  ArtilleryEffectiveness of artillery is based on the intelligence of the robot unit operating it. GatlingGatling guns are equipped with machines guns which offers rapid fire but it cannot resist a lot of damage, usually being destroyed by even the weakest units. GunA gun is turret equipped with rockets that is capable of destroying light tanks, they are faster than Howitzer and Missile artillery and have better armour than gatling guns. HowitzerExcellent range and good damage. While they're slow to build and weaker than the gun, the enemy usually won't get close enough to deliver enough damage. Extremely slow rate of fire may allow units to get close enough to deal considerable damage. MissileStronger than heavy tanks, high armour for an artillery. Generally equal to the mobile missile but being stationary puts it at a disadvantage.  WeaponsThere are six different weapons, some are used by multiple unit types.  RifleUsed by the grunt and the sniper, the rifle doesn't offer much damage against robots, but when aimed at a vehicle driver too busy to defend himself, can kill him and make the vehicle unoccupied and available for capturing.  Machine GunWith its increased fire rate, the machine gun easily gives the psycho a serious edge over rifle units. Missile GunThe most damaging robot weapon, the toughs weapon is extremely powerful, comparable only to the tank's turrets. Flame GunWith a good fire rate, the flame gun is one of the tanks worst enemies, and can easily put down robots.  LaserThe most powerful robot weapon, with high reload and tank-piercing properties, the laser weapon is a sight to behold.  GrenadeAvailable scattered around the map, the grenades can be thrown at long range and enable weak robots to destroy rocks, buildings and bridges, and inflict serious damage on tanks. Never try to pick grenades with a tough or robot that already carries grenades, or else...  StructuresThere are eight different kinds of structures. HeadquartersYour fortress can have up to 4 artillery units deployed on it's corners, if an enemy destroys your headquarters or sends a unit inside, the game will automatically end. RadarOnce captured, you will have an overview of the entire map. If your radar is destroyed, you will not be able to easily keep track of your territory and enemy. Robot FactoryBuilds robot  and artillery units, can be destroyed. Vehicle FactoryBuilds vehicle units, can be destroyed. Repair FactorySend vehicles to the repair factory to have them repaired, the penalty for manufacturing new vehicles can be high so it is useful to keep your units in good condition. BridgeUsed by units to cross swamps, robots are capable of moving through the swamps but this can be dangerous. However if destroyed, vehicles will either be forced to change their route or to repair the broken bridge in order to cross it. RocksAct as a barrier. Can be destroyed by tanks or robots equipped with grenades. SwampCan be hazardous and only robots can cross them. There is a chance that robots will be eaten by crocodiles.  DevelopmentZ was in development for roughly 3 years and was likely influenced by       Dune 2, a game that popularized the RTS genre.ReceptionThe game was known best for it's sense of      humor, excellently rendered cinematics and it's polished graphics and animation.It was released alongside other big names in the real-time strategy genre, such as   Warcraft 2 and    Command  Conquer.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18930">Company of Heroes</game><game id="21175">Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War II</game><game id="11439">Herzog Zwei</game><game id="36296">AirMech</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/17009/822535-zboxart.jpg</image></root>