<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4820</id><name>Dungeon Keeper 2</name><description>OverviewDungeon Keeper 2 is a PC game developed by Bullfrog Productions and published by EA in 1999. It is the sequel to the well received Dungeon Keeper and once again focuses on the player, The Keeper, defeating valiant heroes as well as other enemy keepers. Dungeon Keeper 2 featured a more light-hearted tone compared to its predecessor with many humorous aspects added to creature's personalties as well as lines dropped by the omnipresent Mentor which continuously gives the player hints through the campaign.GameplayPlayers are in control of a dungeon and their goal is to defeat the opposing hero/keeper in order to gain victory. They must manage gold and mana reserves as they construct their dungeon and attract creatures into it with different rooms attracting specific creatures. Once a player has creatures in their dungeon they must then manage the creatures and make sure that they are well fed, have a lair in which to sleep in and are paid their wage on pay-day. Creatures can be used both in combat and in the actual dungeon with some being able to research spells and craft items for the player.During the game the player is guided by a deep and evil voice known only as "The Mentor" who teaches the player the basics such as construction and combat and provides useful hints and warnings throughout the game for things like payday or when new species of creature enters your dungeon. The Mentor also gives humorous briefings and explanations of the story along with random useless jokes.Changes from Dungeon Keeper (Original)Dungeon Keeper used sprites whereas Dungeon Keeper 2 is rendered with 3D polygons.Several new creatures, rooms, spells and traps have been introduced as well as new gameplay mechanics.Spells are now cast with mana instead of gold.Dropped creatures are temporarily stunned making them vulnerable if dropped too close to enemies.The Horned Reaper is now only available to summon via mana rather than being attracted.TriviaPeter Molyneux created the first Dungeon Keeper, but he had no direct role in this sequel.The game also had a planned sequel, Dungeon Keeper 3. A trailer was even included in Dungeon Keeper 2, but it never came to fruition. Bullfrog Productions dissolved before the sequel could be finished.The Mentor will drop random lines to amuse you:"One of your imps does a great impression of you. He can even do the ears.""The very rock yawns with anticipation of your next fascinating move.""Micro-piglets stalk your dungeon. Beware!""Your creatures are pleased with your dungeon's effciency.""Your creatures like your style.""Your creatures rate you as their all-time favourite keeper."If you play the game and your computer's time is set to 3 AM extra Mentor lines will unlock:"You know that downy-soft item of furnicture in the next room? It has the power to cure fatigue and restore vitality.""Your nocturnal perseverance has earned you a hidden gaming tip. GO TO BED!"My Pet DungeonMy Pet Dungeon is a sandbox game mode in which the player is tasked with creating and maintaining a custom build dungeon with specific goals to accomplish.MultiplayerFour maps were initially shipped for the limited multiplayer mode. A subsequent patch increased the number to 8.CampaignSet in the land of Harmonia, Dungeon Keeper 2's campaign spans across twenty levels each of which introduce new rooms, creatures, spells and traps which the player then learns how to use to full extent. The objective of each level is usually to defeat a Hero or an enemy keeper in order to claim portal gems. Once all twenty portal gems are gathered then the entrance into the outside world will be opened.The campaign is presented through a map which the player travels across conquering each land as they progress throughout the campaign.Corrupt MapPure MapLevel One: Smilesville - "Warcry"Hero: Lord Antonius (Level 1)Rooms Introduced: Hatchery, Lair, Portal, Dungeon HeartCreatures Introduced: Imps, Goblins, Dwarves, HornyItems Introduced: Magical ItemsCinematic: Hot LipsLevel Two: Sing-Song - "Enchantments"Hero: Lord Darius (Level 1)Rooms Introduced: Training Room, LibraryCreatures Introduced: WarlocksSpells Introduced: Create Imp, ThunderboltCinematic: NunchakuLevel Three: Ramshackle - "Greed"Hero: Lord Avaricious (Level 1)Rooms Introduced: Workshop, TreasuryCreatures Introduced: Troll, Firefly, ThievesTraps Introduced: Sentry TrapItems Introduced: Wooden DoorCinematic: All ChangeLevel Four: Shadygrove - "Snipers"*Hero: Lord Ludwig (Level 2)Rooms Introduced: Guard RoomCreatures Introduced: Dark ElfSpells Introduced: PossesionCinematic: Game, Giant(*Players are unable to construct a certain room but are able to capture it.)Level Five: Elmshadow - "Fear"**Hero: Lord Constantine (Level 4)Creatures Introduced: Skeletons, WizardsRooms Introduced: Prison, Wooden BridgeTraps Introduced: Fear TrapCinematic: Baked Beans?(**This level features an unlockable secret level.)Level Six: Sweetwater - "Besieged/Rout"***Hero: Lord Ironhelm (Level 4)Creatures Introduced: Mistress, Bile DemonRooms Introduced: Torture ChamberSpells Introduced: HealTraps Introduced: Barricade, Alarm TrapItems Introduced: First Part of Horny Talisman(*** Players are able to chose multiple paths and can chose how to complete this level.)Level Seven: Emberglow - "Caverns"Hero: Lord SigmundCreatures Introduced: Salamanders, GiantsSpells Introduced: Sight of Evil, Call To ArmsCinematic: Split PersonalityLevel Eight: Snapdragon - "Aftermath"Hero: Lord Titus (Level 5)Creatures: RogueRooms Introduced: Casion, Stone BridgeTraps Introduced: Gas TrapItems Introduced: Second Part of Horny TalismanCinematic: Divided AttentionLevel Nine: Silverstream - "Ambush"Hero: Lord Voss (Level 5)Items Introduced: Braced DoorCinematic: Quick ReleaseLevel Ten: Woodsong - "Smash"Hero: Lord RoninKeeper: AsmodeusCreatures Introdcued: ElvesTraps Introduced: Spike TrapCinematic: Chicken  HydeLevel Eleven: Sparklydell - "Carnage"***Keeper: Kronos, Belial, Raksha, MorganaItems Introduced: Steel Door, Third Part of Horny TalismanCinematic: Here Chicky, Chicky(*** Players are able to chose multiple paths and can chose how to complete this level.)Level Twelve: Goldenglade - "Scavange"Keeper: MalachaiCreatures Introduced: VampiresRooms Introduced: GraveyardCinematic: Feel The PainLevel Thirteen: Cherish - "Conversion"Keeper: MalleusCreatures Introduced: MonksTraps Introduced: Freeze TrapCinematic: A Day At The OfficeLevel Fourteen: Peachtree - "Reap"Hero: Lord Tiberius (Level 7)Creatures: Summonable HornyItems Introduced: Magic DoorCinematic: ChangesLevel Fifteen: Fluttershine - "Crusade/Storm"***Hero: Lord Vulstag (Level 7)Creatures Introduced: Black Knight, FairyRooms Introduced: Combat PitCinematic: Ashes to Ashes, Dust to Dust(*** Players are able to chose multiple paths and can chose how to complete this level.)Level Sixteen: Stonekeep - "Creep"Hero: Lord Pureheart (Level 9)Spells Introduced: Create GoldItems Introduced: Secret DoorCinematic: Director's CutLevel Seventeen: Moonshine - "Angelic"Keeper: Harkan, CarrionCreatures Introduced: Dark AngelRooms Introduced: TempleCinematic: BoneshakerLevel Eighteen: Cherry Blossom - "Brotherhood"Keeper: NemesisSpells Introduced: InfernoCinematic: Dazed  ConfusedLevel Nineteen: Butterscotch - "Interception"Hero: Tristran, Felix, Balder (Level 6, 6, 5.)Cinematic: Outtake 1Level Twenty: Heartland - "Regicide"Hero: King Reginald (Level 10)Creatures Introduced: Stone KnightsCinematic: Hot Lips but with Bullfrog logo instead of lips.Due to some error the following creatures, rooms, traps, spells etc. are not in the following list:KnightPikemenTurncoat SpellGuard Post (Trap)Trigger TrapBoulder TrapLightning TrapFireburst TrapSecret LevelsThere are two secret levels that can be unlocked on Dungeon Keeper 2.GolfUnlocked by: Magical ItemDescription: Play a three round game of gold for relaxation.Imp InvasionUnlocked by: Full MoonDescription: Stop the imps from taking over your rooms.EndingShiny.After the player defeats King Reginald they still have to fight their way past two Stone Knights. The only way to kill these Stone Knights is to summon Horny and have him defeat them. Once they are beaten the game will cut to a cinematic of Horny fighting the Stone Knights after inserting the final portal gem into the locking mechanism. After defeating the knights, Horny gazes at the doorway to the Overworld and steps through it, concealed by a blinding light.CreaturesImpWorker units which maintain your dungeon's walls by reinforcing them with magic. They will also dig out earth ang gold for you as well as claim land.GoblinOn his own he is a cowardly beast but in a horde he becomes a useful fighting force.Attracted by: Lair, HatcheryWarlockNeccessity's the mother of invention, so 'tis said, and you may find your needs addressed by Warlocks wise who plough through ancients texts and research new spells for you.Attracted by: LibraryHates: WizardsFireflyThe swift light firefly's essential as an airborne scout. His eyes are yours to penetrate dark places and report.Attracted by: Lair, HatcheryDark ElfHer sniping skills as sharp as the bolted arrows which she shoots. She serves you well in line behind your fighters, and excels in duty as a guard.Attracted by: Guard RoomHates: Elven ArcherSkeletonThis fearless set of bones needs neither sleep nor nurishment, it's only urge to kill, and when in battle marches forth and slays without remorse.Created in: PrisonSalamanderA graceful ancient lizard who cannot be harmed by fire. He'll even wade through lava streams with no impediment.Attracted by: Training RoomRogueHe is talented at forcing entry and when possesed can walk unseen.Attracted by: CasinoHates: ThievesBile DemonAcquaint yourself with him - a slavenly beast, whose girth impedes, but size and suborness bear him fruit in battle.Attracted by: WorkshopVampireA beast who's cheated death. And if you train and nurture him, he'll learn to do your bidding.Attracted by: GraveyardHates: MonksDark MistressDangerous and beautiful, The Mistress enjoys torturing your captives and can prove a most terrifying asset on the battlefield.Attracted by: Torture ChamberTrollA hard working creature, the troll will construct many things for you in his workshop.Attracted by: WorkshopHates: DwarvesBlack KnightMartyrs of a long failed crusade the black knight longs for the heat of battle and to destory all goodly things in its path.Attracted by: Combat PitHates: KnightsDark AngelServants to the Dark Golds of Old they are highly respected creatures and are the most powerful creature any Keeper could dream of commanding.Attracted by: Dark TempleHorny"Need a little help from time to time? I'm yours to call. But when I come, I come to kill. So make sure it's your enemies I slay. For if the fodder's insufficient and your minions block my wall I'll have their blood for breakfast."Created by: Horny Talisman  100,000 ManaThe Maiden of the Nest (Made Available via 1.7 Patch)Half human and half spider, The Maiden will assist your Warlocks in the Library however she is a force to be reckoned with on the battlefield as well.Attracted by: TempleRoomsEach room has its own unique icon (except Dungeon Heart and Portal as they are not eligible for construction:)CasinoA place where creatures can relax for a moment from their busy lives to gamble and consume alcoholic beverages.Combat PitThis room is an arena where your creatures prove their prowess in such martial sports. Place two or more therein and watch them fight each other unto death. And thus the victor's trained to higher levels in combat skills.GraveyardHere's where bodies of the dead are brought to fester. Left to rot in unmarked graves, their gory offerings entice vampires.HatcheryA place where creatures subdue their hunger.LairA place where creatures come to rest and restore vitality.LibraryWhere Warlocks wise can hone their evil craft perfecting spells for you to cast at goodly foes.PrisonA place where imps will drag wounded victims. They'll rot and perish and turn into skeletons.Stone BridgeStrong and durable it can be placed on lava and will endure.The TempleA place of worship within the Dungeon where your creatures may pay homage to the Dark Gods of Old. Place a creatures there and it gains extra happiness and also generates more mana.Torture ChamberThe prisoners within, subjected to extremes of agony, will either die revealing secrets as they do, or switch alliegiance to your side.Training RoomA place where fighting creatures hone their skills.TreasuryA place to store extra gold.Wooden BridgeUsed to transport creatures across water and lava but will eventually be destroyed by lava.WorkshopA place where trolls will come for fabrication of the doors and traps which help defend your evil underground creation.Guard RoomHere you may place creatures to take up guard duty. They'll keep a watchful eye around the guard room and report back any intruders.Dungeon HeartThe most precious of all rooms in a dungeon. Without it, there is no dungeon.PortalA gateway in which creatures enter and leave your dungeon.System RequirementsProcessor: Pentium II 166 MHzRAM Memory: 32 MBVideo Card: 2 MB VRAMHard Drive Space: 300 MBDirectX: 6.0</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16988">Populous: The Beginning</game><game id="401">Startopia</game><game id="18490">Majesty: The Northern Expansion</game><game id="11751">Majesty: The Fantasy Kingdom Sim</game><game id="14484">Dungeon Maker: Hunting Ground</game><game id="20682">Viva Piñata: Trouble in Paradise</game><game id="24642">Dungeon Maker II</game><game id="21594">Slaves to Armok II: Dwarf Fortress</game><game id="15960">Evil Genius</game><game id="18623">Black &amp; White</game><game id="32321">Dungeons</game><game id="33406">Overlord: Raising Hell</game><game id="16258">The Vault of Darkness</game><game id="8460">Diggles: the Myth of Fenris</game><game id="17680">Pharaoh</game><game id="738">Black &amp; White 2: Battle of the Gods</game><game id="1128">The Settlers II: 10th Anniversary</game><game id="3642">The Settlers II: 10th Anniversary - Vikings</game><game id="16757">Tropico: Paradise Island</game><game id="32326">Tropico 4</game><game id="24458">Tropico 3</game><game id="14638">Northland</game><game id="1489">8th Wonder of the World</game><game id="7965">Tropico 2: Pirate Cove</game><game id="11466">CivCity: Rome</game><game id="6645">Caesar III</game><game id="5652">Caesar II</game><game id="12757">Tropico</game><game id="30573">Tropico 3: Absolute Power</game><game id="4102">Emperor: Rise of the Middle Kingdom</game><game id="18721">Cultures</game><game id="19132">Cultures 2: The Gates of Asgard</game><game id="5457">Cultures: Die Abenteuerbox</game><game id="21454">Majesty 2: The Fantasy Kingdom Sim</game><game id="29811">Majesty 2: Kingmaker</game><game id="36948">Majesty 2: Monster Kingdom</game><game id="36949">Majesty 2: Battles of Ardania</game><game id="6210">Populous</game><game id="10562">Populous II: Trials of the Olympian Gods</game><game id="31820">Majesty 2: Pocket Kingdom</game><game id="39287">Impire</game><game id="39648">Maia</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/864/643444-dungeon_keeper_2.jpg</image></root>