<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>485</id><name>Delta Force: Black Hawk Down</name><description>OverviewDelta Force: Black Hawk Down is not based on the movie, or the book, but rather it is completely based of the 1992 Battle of Mogadishu. While trying to be different then average first person shooters at the time, the game had its shortcomings: the predictable AI, the toned down weapons, but most noticeably the color contrast. This would allow hidden enemies to appear, or the player wouldn't even see them. The game also splits into two different perspectives, one which is more of a tutorial mode, and the second which is actually gameplay, and campaign.  PC System Requirements VIDEO CARD: Direct 3D video card with 32MB required. 64MB or greater recommended. Compatible 3D cards include: Nvidia TNT2, GeForce series, ATI Radeon series. For a list of supported 3D cards visit www.novalogic.com. OPERATING SYSTEM: Windows® 98, ME, 2000, XP CPU TYPE  SPEED: Minimum - Pentium® III 733 MHz equivalent Recommended - Pentium® 4 1.4 GHz equivalent HARD DRIVE SPACE: 750MB available SYSTEM MEMORY: 256MB or greater required CD-ROM SPEED: 4x or greater CD-ROME drive DIRECTX: DirectX 8.1 required SOUND CARDS: Windows® compatible. CONTROLLERS: Windows® compatible mouse INTERNET PLAY: Up to 32 simultaneous players via NovaWorld *(Internet service provider required) LAN PLAY: Up to 50 simultaneous players via IP LAN. May require dedicated server. NOTE: Some multiplayer features may only be available through NovaWorld.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7887">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six</game><game id="6246">SOCOM: U.S. Navy SEALs</game><game id="15152">Delta Force: Task Force Dagger</game><game id="5722">Counter-Strike: Condition Zero</game><game id="11663">Half-Life: Counter-Strike</game><game id="20665">Far Cry 2</game><game id="8369">Black</game><game id="25246">Battlefield: Bad Company 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1789585-box_dfbhd.png</image></root>