<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4857</id><name>Medal of Honor: Frontline</name><description>PlotStorming the beaches of NormandySet at the beginning of WWII you follow James Patterson, a young lieutenant in the 116th Infantry division. Cheating death and escaping the German lines after a failed air drop, Jimmy wants another crack at the Germans... the hard way, by storming the beaches at Normandy. You're thoroughly introduced to the German war machine in missions ranging from infiltrating a weapons facility to hijacking the newest plane the Luftewaffe has to offer.GameplayYou will play as a covert spy in many missionsThe player uses a handful of period weapons ranging from the Army standard Colt .45 to the German MP40 machine gun. The life meter and ammo count make up your HUD as you pass from objective to objective along your mission. There's also a mission rating and medals system that takes your performance in each mission and gives you medals accordingly, which adds some replay value depending on your desire for achievement.CampaignThe campaign itself consists of 19 missions in which youStorm the Beaches of NormandySeize the Nijmegen BridgeInfiltrate a secret weapons facilitySabotage U-BoatsStow away on a armored trainHijack the Nazi's newest experimental planeAnd a handful of other missions that let you dish out the damage to the Germans.HD Re-releaseAt Sony's 2010 E3 press conference it was announced that a high-definition remastered version of Medal of Honor: Frontline would be included as part of the Medal of Honor reboot Limited Edition exclusively on the PS3. The game will run in 3D.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1629">Call of Duty</game><game id="3232">Call of Duty: Finest Hour</game><game id="2347">Call of Duty 2</game><game id="16711">Call of Duty 2: Big Red One</game><game id="7524">Call of Duty 3</game><game id="12633">Call of Duty: United Offensive</game><game id="20777">Call of Duty: World at War</game><game id="27006">Battlefield 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1988889-box_mohf.png</image></root>