<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>487</id><name>WWE WrestleMania 21</name><description>Match TypesSingles MatchTag Team MatchHandicap MatchTriple Threat MatchFatal Four-way MatchBattle RoyalRoyal RumbleLast Man Standing Match*Bra  Panties Match*Cage Match*Hell in a Cell Match*Ladder Match*Table Match*TLC Match**Note: these matches can only be played with a maximum of 2 players in exhibition modeCareer ModeCareer mode has one of your created wrestlers go through a year of the WWE. As you play through your wrestler becomes United States champion, WWE Tag Team champion(with Booker T), Intercontinental champion, World Heavyweight champion and WWE champion. It begins with your wrestler starting on Velocity as a heel. About halfway through your wrestler is attacked by Evolution and is put out of action for a month, during that time Eric Bischoff becomes your personal coach and helps you get revenge by putting you in matches against legends. Eric Bischoff then gives you members of Evolution one by one. It all ends at Wrestlemania in a Last Man Standing match against Kurt Angle.Playable RosterBatistaThe Big ShowBooker TBubba Ray DudleyCharlie HaasChavo GuerreroChris BenoitChris JerichoChristianD-Von DudleyEddie GuerreroEdgeEugeneGarrison CadeJazzJohn Bradshaw LayfieldJohn CenaKaneKurt AngleLitaMatt HardyMiss JackieNidiaRandy OrtonRene DupreeRey MysterioRhynoRic FlairRob Van DamScotty 2 HottyShawn MichaelsShelton BenjaminSpike DudleyStacy KeiblerTajiriThe HurricaneTriple HTrish StratusThe UndertakerVal VenisAndre the Giant (Legend)The Big Show 2003 Version (Legend)Bret Hart (Legend)Jimmy Snuka (Legend)Mankind (Legend)Rey Mysterio Gold Attire (Legend)The Rock (Legend)ArenasMost arenas have different color lighting that makes them stand out from each other.An example of the lighting (Velocity arena)Smackdown! (Blue Lighting)Raw (Pink Lighting)Heat (Orange Lighting)Velocity (Green Lighting)Royal Rumble (Yellow Lighting)No Way Out (Yellow Lighting)Wrestlemania XX (Purple Lighting)Backlash (Blue Lighting)Judgement Day (Purple Lighting)Bad Blood (Red Lighting)Vengeance (Red Lighting)Summerslam (Light Blue Lighting)Unforgiven (Yellow Lighting)No Mercy (Dark Purple Lighting)Survivor Series (Dark Yellow Lighting)Armageddon (Orange Lighting)GymnasiumWrestling ClubTraining FacilityCivic CenterIndustrial Basement</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre><genre id="10">Wrestling</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2308">WWE Day of Reckoning</game><game id="13445">WWE Raw 2</game><game id="27639">WWF RAW</game><game id="28430">WWF Royal Rumble</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2139905-box_wwewm21.png</image></root>