<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>489</id><name>ClayFighter</name><description>OverviewClayFighter is a 2D fighting game developed by Visual Concepts and published by Interplay for the Super Nintendo Entertainment System in November 1993 (and later for the Sega Genesis in 1994). It is one of the first games to use claymation for player characters, as players fight each other as mutated circus employees (after a meteor, made of clay, crashes on the grounds of an American circus).The game receieved an enhanced version exclusive to the SNES, titled ClayFighter: Tournament Edition, on May 1994. This version fixed numerous glitches while adding new game modes. ClayFighter later spawned a franchise, including two sequel installments: ClayFighter 2: Judgement Clay and ClayFighter 63⅓.CharactersHelgaA fat opera singer. She can attack by throwing herself at her opponents, stabbing with the horns atop her helmet, and singing for a sonic scream. She is the first foe you encounter in 1-Player mode.TaffyAn anthropomorphic piece of taffy whose attacks mainly involve stretching and twisting his body.BonkersA crazy clown who throws pies, turns cartwheels, and smashes with a big hammer.Bad Mr. FrostyA Snowman with an attitude. With his special attacks, he can throw snowballs, spit sharp balls of ice, slide along the ground with a kicking attack, and turn himself into a snow boulder and roll into his opponent. Bad mr. Frosty has become a mascot for the ClayFighter series, appearing on every boxart todate.Ickybod ClayA ghost with a jack-o-lantern head. He can teleport, and throw balls of ghost goo at his opponent.Blue Suede GooA fat Elvis look-alike . He throws musical notes as projectiles and uses his hair as a blade to cut opponents.BlobA blob made of clay. His specialty is changing into objects to attack with, such as a buzz saw that cuts his opponent in half.TinyA wrestler character who, oddly enough, doesn't use very many wrestling moves. He can use his fists to run across the screen and punch, as well as roll into a ball and throw himself at foes.N. BossHe is the final boss, and looks like a necklace. He only attacks with projectiles copied from other characters and has a grab attack. He doesn't look to be made out of clay. His inclusion in the game was rumored to be a last minute decision, because he is the only non claymation fighter, and his powers are all copied assets.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14078">Primal Rage</game><game id="16444">Eternal Champions</game><game id="1167">Virtua Fighter Kids</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="16793">Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="18484">Killer Instinct</game><game id="1942">Ballz 3D: Fighting at its Ballziest</game><game id="22362">Street Fighter II': Hyper Fighting</game><game id="14097">The Neverhood</game><game id="4896">Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Tournament Fighters</game><game id="14880">Tuff E Nuff</game><game id="36652">Fight 'N' Jokes</game><game id="39308">Spitting Image</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2370458-genesis_clayfighter_2_cropped.jpg</image></root>