<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4896</id><name>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Tournament Fighters</name><description>OverviewTeenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Tournament Fighters is a fighting game featuring characters from the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles franchise that was released on the NES, SNES, and Sega Genesis.PlotsNES Version PlotThe turtles have been challenged by Shredder, but in order to fight him, they decide to have a tournament between themselves to see who is ready for the encounter.SNES Version PlotA tournament has been organized and fighters from all over have entered, Shredder of course being one of them. The turtles decide to enter the tournament in order to stop Shredder and prove their strength in battle.Genesis Version Plot Master Splinter is kidnapped by four purple turtles. When the real turtles find out, Krang appears and tells the turtles that he has Splinter with him and that the only way to rescue him is to go to Dimension X and meet Krang.One of the unique features of the SNES version was the different turbo speeds. At the highest setting, this game was faster than street fighter II turbo at the highest setting. Endings (NES)The endings on the NES version are basically the same for all four of the turtles. The only difference is the portrait of the turtle which you used to beat the game. In the ending the winning turtle accuses Shredder of being up to one of his lousy tricks. Shredder says you have not seen the last of him, he then gets up and runs off screen. Splinter comes floating into the screen, drops down in front of the turtle and says "You have performed well my sons. Now let us celebrate our victory." Endings (SNES)CharacterEnding RaphaelRaphael gives his thanks to Splinter and April by giving them a pile of gifts. Raphael then tells them he is happy to have friends as good as they are. MichelangeloMichelangelo decides to take a vacation in the Bahamas to do some surfing, then invites the other turtles to come along. LeonardoLeonardo says his daily training has paid off, and now he must set new goals and set out to achieve those goals. Leonardo then goes right back into his training. DonatelloDonatello goes back to working on his latest invention which then blows up. He then says he might have some money left over to start a new invention. AskaAska is happy to be able to finally realize her dream of teaching younger people in the ways of Ninjitsu. The then exclaims she will have the best dojo in the entire world. ShredderShredder says he knew he would win the tournament and that he has defeated the turtles for the last time. He now has his sights set on conquering Earth. WarWar exclaims that he won and that has shown the other fighters not to mess with an intergalactic life form. ArmaggonArmaggon exclaims that it is only natural that he won the tournament and that he is the strongest living being on the planet and must now conquer it. WingnutWingnut only entered the tournament to pound some heads. He pounded everyone else and ended up winning and now will be able to waste even more money. Chrome DomeChrome Dome now has the money to purchase the necessary computers in order to extract his faulty program. He will finally be able to exist in peace. Critical ReceptionElectronic Gaming Monthly gave the SNES version review scores of 9,8,9 and 9 out of ten. Ed Semrad wrote, "This has got to be one of the best fighting games next to Street Fighter 2, (and in some cases better than SF2). The voices are crisp and clear, plus the control is absolutely wonderful! Another factor that I truly like is the story mode set up with dialog boxes unraveling the whole plot! There are plenty of combos that will get you going! Another great hit from the pros at Konami".</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="243">Street Fighter II: The World Warrior</game><game id="2178">Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3</game><game id="8161">Street Fighter II Turbo: Hyper Fighting</game><game id="23038">Tatsunoko Fight</game><game id="28102">Kabuki Ittou Ryoudan</game><game id="4855">Shaq Fu</game><game id="14078">Primal Rage</game><game id="18484">Killer Instinct</game><game id="489">ClayFighter</game><game id="2396">Fatal Fury</game><game id="2760">Art of Fighting</game><game id="16400">Aggressors of Dark Kombat</game><game id="18554">World Heroes</game><game id="18830">Final Fight Revenge</game><game id="35506">Fighting For One Piece</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2364663-snes_tmnttournamentfighters.jpg</image></root>