<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4899</id><name>The Gladiators: Galactic Circus Games</name><description> OverviewThe Gladiator: Galactic Circus Games is an RTS game based in the 1970's. You take control of Greg Callahan, an, astronaut sent on a mission to explore a black hole discovered by the United States Military. When the mission goes wrong Greg is thrown into the very black hole he was sent to explore. He is captured by an alien race and taken to their homeworld.  Upon arrival into the alien homeworld Greg's crew is slaughtered leaving him alone to be executed. However his life is spared when the princess of the aliens gives him a chance to compete in the Deathbowl (the equivalent of a Roman gladiator arena) for a chance to become the ruler of their world. Example of a cutsceneGameplay At the beginning of your battles you are thrust into the center of a brightly colored arena with a rowdy crowd awaiting the demise of one side or the other. You start with a small amount of troops. You will need to spend some time gathering power-ups such as reinforcements, health, armor , or an increase in your weaponry. You can also get "joker cards" which will allow you to choose any of the power-up types aswell as more units. You do not have to build a base or gather any supplies / resources in this game. Screen capture of a battle The objective of each level is to capture the spawn points that allow for the creation of more units. At the beginning of the battle all spawn points are held by the enemy, meaning that you must make an assault. The spawn points are surrounded by building that can be used to your advantage when the enemy counter-attacks. Controlling these buildings and high-points is very important in Gladiator. After you capture a spawn point you continue through the level capturing points until you reach the finish. You'll find yourself traversing a variety of different terrain throughout the levels.  Multiplayer Online muliplayer is available. Eight maps are open for play. </description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/33306/951951-gladiatorsthegalacticcircusgames_pc.jpg</image></root>