<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4969</id><name>Big Red Racing</name><description>OverviewBig Red Racing is a racing game, released in 1996 for  MS-DOS. It was developed by             Big Red Software, a then small british software house who would later merge with  Epic Pic in 1995 to create current Publisherhouse             Eidos Interactive.In Big Red Racing you chose between 8 different vehicle classes, each consisting of 2 different vehicles to choose from, a total of 16 racers. Each course in the game have predetermined which class of vehicles the player can race with. There are a total of 24 courses to race in. Most tracks are located in various locations on earth, such as            England,           USA,          Japan, Kenya,         China,        Russia and other distinct places, each course with a fitting level design for that locations specific geography. There are also courses with are not on Earth, these levels are locaed on the Moon,       Mars and      Venus.Big Red Racing is a comical game, something noticable right from the get-go. There are burping sounds, screams and other comical sound effects when selecting an option in the games menu. There are also announcers who shout out ridiculous comments during races. The actual racing is  performed on courses, where the player has to race around them in a number of laps. Even so, a big part of Big Red Racing is the offroad racing part of it. On many courses the player can at any time leave the designated racing area and race around jumping feverishly, crashing into other players or obstacles. In some tracks you could travel outside the mini-map displayed in   the upper-left corner and discover new areas with jumps and various obstacles.A Jeep   Vehicles There are 8 vehicle groups in the game, each containing two different vehicle types. Each course uses only one of these groups. These are: City, mini vehicles.    Car (Mini)     Car (Volkswagen Beetle)      Dirt  Four Wheel Drive Off-Roader   (    Jeep)     Customized All-Terrain Military   Personnel Carrier (6 Wheeled ATV)      Helicopter   (Failed) Prototype:   Radar-Invisible    Helicopter     Trimmed-Down Pilot-Training     Helicopter      Planet, futuristic vehicles.    Jet-Propelled Hover Vehicle     All-Terrain Vehicle      Rig   Monster Truck     Customized Rig (Semi-trailer   truck)      Snow  Snow Plough     All-Terrain Miniture Snow Vehicle       Quarry, quarry vehicles.    Excavator (Backhoe)     Dumper Truck (Dump truck)      Water  Inflatable Motor Boat     Semi-Amphibious Hover Craft        Courses There are a total 24 courses in Big Red Racing from the globe, the moon, Venus, and Mars. Each course has has a humorous subtitle, usually a parody of a famous phrase or film. These are: Kenya (The Coffee Ground): Rig  track    England (The Dirt Circle): Dirt  track    Chile (Reservoir Dodge): Ruff  track    United States(Wet  Wild):  Water track    Australia (Road Rage): City track    Mexico (Margarita Meander): Dirt  track    Egypt (The Tomb): Quarry track    Ireland (Lucky Leprechauns): Rig  track    China (Under The Bridge): Water  track    U.S.A. (Excellent Adventure): City  track    Arctic (Frosty's Revenge): Snow  track    Germany (Sound of Munich):  Helicopter track    Japan (Karma Corners): Dirt track    Russia (Lenin's Leap): Snow track    Italy (The Italian Job): City  track    Norway (Fjord Escort): Helicopter  track    Mars (Red Planet Roller Coaster):  Planet track    Spain (Spanish Inquisition): Rig  track    Scotland (Highland Fling): Snow  track    Venus (The Fly Trap): Planet track    India (Hot Water Wander): Water  track    France (French Frolics): Quarry  track    Hawaii (Hawaii-5-O): Helicopter  track    Moon (Lunar Loops): Planet track   </description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12544">Wacky Wheels</game><game id="19071">Super Mario Kart</game><game id="13737">Slipstream 5000</game><game id="2140">Micro Machines</game><game id="7317">Micro Machines V4</game><game id="20350">Micro Machines 2: Turbo Tournament</game><game id="496">Micro Machines V3</game><game id="12798">Micro Machines: Military</game><game id="1659">Jupiter's Masterdrive</game><game id="18026">Rock 'n Roll Racing</game><game id="1166">Badlands</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1927/191910-217_1.jpg</image></root>