<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4970</id><name>Burnout Legends</name><description>The first Burnout game not made by Criterion (only DS version, PSP Version was developed by Criterion), Burnout Legends brings all that fans loved from the first three games to the PSP. The World Tour mode is similar to that of the Burnout 3 version, save the world map. Here players are given a series of events for a specific car type. Once players have won a gold in the grand prix for said series, the next is unlocked. Most cars are unlocked through progression in the World Tour mode.Burnout Legends also sees the return of a Burnout 2: Point of Impact game mode, Pursuit mode. Here the player takes control of a police car and must smash into an opposing vehicle. Taking this car out before it has reached the finish line will result in a victory. Legends also features the typical game modes:Race - Race against 3 rivals around the track to win the event.Eliminator - Every lap the last place car is removed from the race.Face Off - Race against a legend car to win the car.Time Attack - The goal is to complete a lap as fast as you can. You can do as many laps as you like.Burning Lap - Time attack in world tour where the player tries to complete a lap by the medal time.Road Rage - Continually Takedown three opposing vehicles until the time runs out, or you crash out.Crash - Intentionally crash your car into a puzzle of vehicles. The more you crash, the more cash you get.All of these modes are also available in the games local multiplayerLocationsIn Burnout Legends, most of the tracks are taken from all previous Burnout games from Burnout 1, 2 and 3. The tracks are divide in 3 different regions of the game: USA, Europe and the Far East/Asia.USAWaterfront (PSP only) - Waterfront from Burnout 3: TakedownDowntown - Downtown from Burnout 3: TakedownSilver Lake - Silver Lake from Burnout 3: TakedownAirport T1  T2 - Airport Terminal 1  2 from Burnout 2: Point of ImpactAirport T3 (PSP Only) - Airport Terminal 3 from Burnout 2: Point of ImpactPalm Bay Marina - Palm Bay Heights from Burnout 2: Point of ImpactBig Surf Shores - Big Surf Shores from Burnout 2: Point of ImpactInterstate Loop - Interstate Loop from Burnout 2: Point of ImpactSunrise Valley Downtown - Sunrise Valley Downtown from Burnout 2: Point of ImpactEuropeWinter City (PSP only) - Winter City from Burnout 3: TakedownAlpine (PSP only) - Alpine from Burnout 3: TakedownRiviera - Riviera from Burnout 3: TakedownVineyard - Vineyard from Burnout 3: TakedownHarbour Town - Harbour Town from BurnoutFar East/AsiaGolden City - Golden City from Burnout 3: TakedownDockside - Dockside from Burnout 3: TakedownIsland Paradise - Island Paradise from Burnout 3: TakedownVehiclesThere are a total of 89 cars to unlock in five categories: Compact, Muscle, Coupe, Sport, and Super. This is done by performing certain tasks in the World Tour, such as getting a certain amount of gold medals, or all signature takedowns.This game also has "Collector's cars." There are 5 special cars for each class, however you only have one on the game (like Collector Car 3). To get the other four, you have to beat a player in a multiplayer mode while using your collector car against one another. Who ever wins gets the others' car added to their collection.Compact SeriesCompact Type 1Awarded: At start of compact seriesCompact Type 2Awarded: At start of compact seriesCompact Type 3Awarded: At start of compact seriesCompact CopAwarded: Bronze in Silver Lake or Airport Terminal 1  2 PursuitLegend CompactAwarded: Gold in InterstAte Loop Legend Face-OffGangster LegendAwarded: Gold in Palm Bay Legend Face-OffDominator CompactAwarded: At 10,000 Burnout PointsTuned CompactAwarded: For 5 Gold MedalsAssassin CompactAwarded: At 15 TakedownsCompact Collector 1Awarded: For winning a collector challenge raceCompact Collector 2Awarded: For winning a collector challenge raceCompact Collector 3Awarded: For winning a collector challenge raceCompact Collector 4Awarded: For Gold in Silver Lake EliminatorCompact Collector 5Awarded: For winning a collector challenge raceMuscle SeriesMuscle Type 1Awarded: For unlocking Muscle SeriesMuscle Type 2Awarded: For unlocking Muscle SeriesMuscle Type 3Awarded: For unlocking Muscle SeriesMuscle CopAwarded: For Bronze in Harbour Town or Sunrrise Vally PursuitClassic LegendsAwarded: For Gold in Big Surf Legend Face-Off.Legend J-MuscleAwarded: For Gold in Airport 1 2 Legend Face-OffDominator MuscleAwarded: At 25,000 Burnout PointsTuned MuscleAwarded: For 20 Gold MedalsAssassin MuscleAwarded: At 30 TakedownsMuscle Collector 1Awarded: For Gold in Harbor Town EliminatorMuscle Collector 2Awarded: For winning a collector challenge raceMuscle Collector 3Awarded: For winning a collector challenge raceMuscle Collector 4Awarded: For winning a collector challenge raceMuscle Collector 5Awarded: For winning a collector challenge raceCoupe SeriesCoupe Type 1Awarded: For unlocking Coupe SeriesCoupe Type 2Awarded: For unlocking Coupe SeriesCoupe Type 3Awarded: For unlocking Coupe SeriesCoupe CopAwarded: For Bronze in Big Surf Shore or Sunrise Valley PursuitLegend PickupAwarded: For Gold in Airport 3 Legend Face-OffLegend SUVAwarded: For Gold in Sunrise Legend Face-OffDominator CoupeAwarded: At 50,000 Burnout PointsTuned CoupeAwarded: For 40 Gold MedalsAssassin CoupeAwarded: At 60 TakedownsCoupe Collector 1Awarded: For Gold in Winter City EliminatorCoupe Collector 2Awarded: For winning a collector challenge raceCoupe Collector 3Awarded: For winning a collector challenge raceCoupe Collector 4Awarded: For winning a collector challenge raceCoupe Collector 5Awarded: For winning a collector challenge raceSports SeriesSports Type 1Awarded: For unlocking Sports SeriesSports Type 2Awarded: For unlocking Sports SeriesSports Type 3Awarded: For unlocking Sports SeriesSports CopAwarded: For Bronze in Dockside or Island Paradise PursuitLegends Oval RacerAwarded: For Gold in Sunrise Valley Legend Face-OffLegend RoadsterAwarded: For Gold in Big Surf Shore Legend Face-OffDominator SportsAwarded: At 100,000 Burnout PointsTuned SportsAwarded: For 50 Gold MedalsAssassin SportsAwarded: At 100 TakedownsSports Collector 1Awarded: Awarded For Gold in Sunrise Valley EliminatorSports Collector 2Awarded: For winning a collector challenge raceSports Collector 3Awarded: For winning a collector challenge raceSports Collector 4Awarded: For winning a collector challenge raceSports Collector 5Awarded: For winning a collector challenge raceSuper SeriesSuper Type 1Awarded: For unlocking Super SeriesSuper Type 2Awarded: For unlocking Super SeriesSuper Type 3Awarded: For unlocking Super SeriesSuper CopAwarded: For Bronze in Winter City or Island Paradise PursuitLegend Super CarAwarded: For Gold in Airport 3 Legend Face-OffLegend Hot RodAwarded: For Gold in Palm Bay Legend Face-OffDominator SuperAwarded: At 200,000 Burnout PointsTuned SuperAwarded: For 75 gold medalsAssassin SuperAwarded: At 150 TakedownsSuper Collector 1Awarded: For Gold in Dockside EliminatorSuper Collector 2Awarded: For winning a collector challenge raceSuper Collector 3Awarded: For winning a collector challenge raceSuper Collector 4Awarded: For winning a collector challenge raceSuper Collector 5Awarded: For winning a collector challenge raceRace SpecialCustom Coupe UltimateAwarded: For collecting a Medal in every Race EventOval Special RacerAwarded: For collecting all Signature TakedownsClassic Hot RodAwarded: For collecting all Special Event PostcardsEuro Circuit RacerAwarded: For collecting all Takedown TrophiesUS Circuit RacerAwarded: For Gold in Super GPWorld Circuit RacerAwarded: For Gold in Special GPCop RacerAwarded: For Gold in all Pursuit EventsGangster BossAwarded: For Gold in all Race EventsHeavyweightHeavy Pick-UpAwarded: At $1,000,000 in Crash ModeTrash TruckAwarded: At $90,000,000 in Crash Mode4WD RacerAwarded: At $2,000,000 in Crash ModeSUV DeluxeAwarded: At $5,000,000 in Crash ModeFiretruckAwarded: For collecting all Crash Gold Medals4WD Heavy DutyAwarded: At $10,000,000 in Crash ModeB-Team VanAwarded: At $15,000,000 in Crash ModeDelivery TruckAwarded: At $20,000,000 in Crash ModeTractor CabAwarded: At $30,000,000 in Crash ModeLongnose CabAwarded: At $50,000,000 in Crash ModeCity BusAwarded: At $70,000,000 in Crash ModeSignature TakedownsGetting all the signature takedowns unlocks the Oval Special RacerGone Fishin' - Takedown a rival over cliff by Silver Lake's trailer parkHomewrecker - Takedown into a motorhomePillar Driller - Takedown into pillar in DowntownHit the Split - Takedown into the center divide at tunnel entrance in DowntownTruck Torpedo - Takedown into a big rig carrying a speedboatEuro Tram Ram - Takedown into a Winter City tramSnowed Under - Takedown into a snowplowPaid the Price! - Takedown into an Alpine TollboothRiviera Roustabout - Takedown into the roundabout in RivieraGatecrasher - Takedown into Vineyard's Town Gate wallGrapes of Wrath - Takedown into a wine truckMarket Stalled - Takedown at the Golden City Market PlaceTuk-Down - Takedown into a Tuk-TukShip Wreck - Takedown at the port in at DocksideRumble in the Jungle - Takedown on the Island Paradise off-road sectionCatch the Tour Bus - Takedown into one of the parked tour buses in Island ParadiseTaxi Takedown - Takedown into a TaxiTow Away Zone - Takedown an opponent in front of the Terminal Building on Airport Terminal 1  2Bridge Over - Takedown over the edge of Harbor Town bridgeMedian Mash - Takedown into Palm Bay MedianSoundtrackSong - Artist (Album)Almost Here - The Academy Is... (Almost Here)Bundy - Animal Alpha (Pheromones)Red Flag - Billy Talent (Billy Talent II)Fear and Loathing - The Black Velvets (The Black Velvets)Wake the Dead - Comeback Kid (Wake the Dead)Riot Radio - The Dead 60s (The Dead 60s)Tuned to a Different Station - Dogs - (Turn Against This Land)The Hey Man! - Emanuel (Soundtrack to a Headrush)Ink - Finch (Say Hello to Sunshine)I Want - Goldfinger (Disconnection Notice)Today - Junkie XL (Today)Straight to Video (KMFDM Remix) - Mindless Self Indulgence (Straight To Video: The Remixes)Nü Rock - Morningwood (Morningwood)Heard That Sound - MxPx (Panic)Shot Down - Nine Black Alps (Everything Is)Do What You Want - OK Go (Oh No)Shotgun - The Outline (You Smash It, We'll Build Around It)Stand Up - Pennywise (The Fuse)Band-Girls - Money - Tsar (Band-Girls-Money)The Great Escape - We Are Scientists (With Love and Squalor)Lights and Sounds - Yellowcard (Lights and Sounds)PS Vita CompatibilityDespite not being in the official compatibility list, Burnout Legends can be played on the PS Vita. To do this, the user must first download the game to the PS3. From there, go to Content Transfer on the PS Vita and select the game for transfer. Once complete, the game will show up on the Vita's menu.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="859">FlatOut 2</game><game id="12142">Full Auto 2: Battlelines</game><game id="21606">Crash Time: Autobahn Pursuit</game><game id="13776">Destruction Derby 2</game><game id="786">Destruction Derby</game><game id="13177">FlatOut</game><game id="6836">FlatOut: Ultimate Carnage</game><game id="7019">Ridge Racer V</game><game id="5977">Need for Speed III: Hot Pursuit</game><game id="7777">Juiced</game><game id="11625">Ridge Racer DS</game><game id="10124">Midnight Club: Street Racing</game><game id="9813">Crashday</game><game id="16728">Powerslide</game><game id="689">Jak X: Combat Racing</game><game id="20998">FlatOut: Head On</game><game id="25627">Smash Cars</game><game id="25424">MotorStorm: Arctic Edge</game><game id="20451">MotorStorm: Pacific Rift</game><game id="20698">Wheelman</game><game id="20418">Midnight Club II</game><game id="5875">Midnight Club 3: DUB Edition</game><game id="20927">Midnight Club: Los Angeles</game><game id="21114">Midnight Club: Los Angeles Remix</game><game id="27802">Sideswiped</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1777749-box_boutleg.png</image></root>