<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5307</id><name>Make My Video: Marky Mark and the Funky Bunch</name><description>OverviewIn this game, the player is put in the role of video editor for Marky Mark (Mark Wahlberg) and his Funky Bunch. As the game's setup, some teenagers (one of them portrayed by actor Seth Green) are arguing about the ideal contents of a Marky Mark video. After having witnessed the discussion, the player is able to select between three music videos to edit.When the Make My Video series went into development, Digital Pictures operated under the assumption that music video shoots produced a wealth of unused footage, which would serve to populate the series' core gameplay mechanic. However, they soon discovered that this was not the case. Instead, they populated the non-music video footage options with royalty-free videos, including political speeches and black-and-white stock films.GameplayVideo editing in action.The selected song's music video is played while the player edits the video on the fly. Players are able to switch between video clips by pressing corresponding buttons on the controller. The player is given a selection of clips, between videos of the group itself, stock footage, movie clips, and are given the ability to alter them with special effects. The player is furthermore given the ability to freeze an image and toggle lyrics on and off.When the music video's duration is up, the "level" is completed and the player's mix will be replayed on the screen. After the player's mix has be evaluated by a group of girls sitting in a bathroom, he will then be able to select a new video to edit.SoundtrackThe song selection consists entirely of just three songs.Good VibrationsI Need MoneyYou Gotta Believe</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18613">Power Factory Featuring C+C Music Factory</game><game id="10517">Make My Video: INXS</game><game id="10670">Make My Video: Kris Kross</game><game id="13898">Moderngroove: Ministry of Sound Edition</game><game id="23882">DJ Hero</game><game id="7794">Mary-Kate And Ashley: Magical Mystery Mall</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14761/1052104-front_cover.jpg</image></root>