<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5402</id><name>Golden Axe II</name><description>OverviewGolden Axe II is a side-scrolling 2D Brawler developed by   Sega released for the   Sega Genesis in 1991. Unlike   Golden Axe, with was ported to a large amount of consoles, Golden Axe II was exclusively a home console release. It did eventually find a release on other consoles a decade and a half later in 2006, appearing in the   Sega Genesis Collection for the   PlayStation 2. And in   Sonic's Ultimate Genesis Collection in 2009 for the   Xbox 360 and   PlayStation 3. It is also available as a stand-alone digital download on the   PC. GameplayLike the previous game in the series, Golden Axe II is a 2D brawler, in vein of   Final Fight, but with 'hack-n-slash' elements similar to   Knights of the Round. The game features a singleplayer or two-player co-operative mode. Players can choose between 3 characters:   Ax Battler: The Barbarian  Gilius Thunderhead: The Dwarf  Tyris Flare: The Amazon The player can choose between three difficulty settings: Easy, Normal and Hard. However, when playing on Easy the game can only be played up to the end of Level 5.Golden Axe II plays mostly the same as its predecessor and thus reuses some mechanics. The player can restore their life meter by eating foods scattered throughout the level and dropped by various enemies. Magic can be used once the player has collected a Magic Book, found throughout the level and by defeating Wizards. At the end of each level, Wizards will attempt to steal from the player. The player can also attack the wizards to regain their items and obtain additional ones as well.  Green Wizards will drop magic books, while Red Wizards will drop food. The player can hold up to 8 Magic Books. The more Magic Books the player has, the more powerful the spell they cast can be. By holding down the magic button, it will charge until the player lets go. The first spell only requires one, with the next powerful spell requiring four, then subsequent spells requiring an additional book.Gameplay in The Duel The Duel     A gamemode returning from the Genesis version of the previous game, the player fights through 15 increasingly challenging duels against a group of enemies. The player's life carries through subsequent stages, so risk increases the worse the player performs. After completion, or death, the player receives a rank depending on how well they performed. In two player mode, players fight alone to the death.Battle 1: LongmoanBattle 2: Longmoan, Chicken BizarrianBattle 3: LizardmanBattle 4: 2x Longmoan (Green)Battle 5: 2x Longmoan (Red Armor), Chicken BizarrianBattle 6: 2x Skeleton Battle 7: 2x Longman (Gray Armor), Chicken Bizarrian, Dragon BizarrianBattle 8: 2x Lizardman (Red) Battle 9: 2x MinotaurBattle 10:  Headless KnightBattle 11: 3x Longmoan (Gold Armor) Battle 12: 2x Lizard (Purple) Battle 13: 2x Minotaur (Purple) Battle 14: 3x Neo SkeletonBattle 15: 2x Headless Knight (Red)   LevelsLevels Ravaged Village Boss: Minotaur  Ruins Boss: Headless Knight  Tower The stage has many opportunities to knock enemies off ledges for instant kills.  Boss: 3x Lizards (Purple) Dragon's Throat Cave Boss: 2x Minotaur (Red), 2x Lizard (Red) Castle Gates Boss: 1x Longmoan (Gold), 2x Heninger (Gold), 2x Headless Knight (White)Castle Boss: 3x Lizard (Red), 1x Headless Knight (Gold) Dark Guld's Chamber Boss: Dark Guld Enemies Enemies Longmoan The most common and simple enemy in the game. However, they can still be fearsome in numbers even towards the end of the game due to their dash attacks. Heninger  Skeleton Neo-SkeletonA more powerful and agile version of the Skeleton.  Wizard When defeated, they drop items. Lizard-Man  Minotaur First appearing as a boss at the beginning of the first level, by level 3 they become common enemies.       Headless Knight Another enemy that starts off as a boss on the second level, before becoming a regular enemy.   Dark Guld The final boss of the game.Bizarrian Chicken Bizarrian Dragon Bizarrian.  Bizarrians are mounts ridden by the enemy, but can be knocked off and used by the player. They can jump, tail-whip and in the case of the dragon bizarrians, breath fire. They will flee if they are left alone for several moments, or attacked too many times.  SoundtrackGolden Axe II was composed by   Naofumi Hataya, his debut soundtrack for Sega. It did not see an official release until 2008, when it was compiled in the 3 Disc set Golden Axe: The Music.   Golden Axe: The MusicReleased: February 21, 2008 Golden Axe II:Character Select  Raveged Village  BossMagician StageCrystalAncient RuinsEnemy's HeadquartersDragon's ThroatBossThe Castle GateCastle Of Dark Guld  DeathadderAllclearStaff  RollResultGame Over  </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6100">Realms of Chaos</game><game id="15143">Knights of the Round</game><game id="16733">Blades of Vengeance</game><game id="4325">Magic Sword</game><game id="2442">Rastan</game><game id="18097">Rastan Saga 2</game><game id="7711">Super Double Dragon</game><game id="22872">Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Shadow Over Mystara</game><game id="22870">Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Tower of Doom</game><game id="2596">Alien Storm</game><game id="3340">Sega Smash Pack</game><game id="25800">Warrior Blade - Rastan III</game><game id="14351">Golden Axe</game><game id="1831">Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles III: The Manhattan Project</game><game id="7950">The Peace Keepers</game><game id="42036">Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Chronicles of Mystara</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2370590-genesis_goldenaxe2.jpg</image></root>