<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5507</id><name>Descent II</name><description>OverviewDescent II title screenDescent II is a 1996 first-person shooter. It was developed by Parallax Software and published by Interplay. It was released on MS-DOS, Windows 95, Mac OS, Mac OS X and Amiga. A PlayStation port of the game was also planned, but due to Sony's policies regarding ports from other platforms at the time, as well the platform's limited hardware and controller, the game was remade from scratch with 36 new levels and released under the name Descent Maximum in the US (it was still released as Descent II in Europe).As of 2006, the game is available on the online game service GameTap, and since 2008 it has been available on GOG as a bundle with the first game. In the game, players take control of the Material Defender on another mission given to him by the Post Terran Mineral Corporation (PTMC).Descent II was originally planned as an expansion to Descent, but it eventually evolved into a full game. It was followed by Descent³ in 1999. StoryAfter what the Material Defender thought was the end of a long day, having destroyed all the mines in the solar system, he returns to a Post Terran Minerals Corporation (PTMC) base located in the asteroid belt. Eager to get his money and return home, Dravis confronts him with a new mission stating that, "The PTMC reserves the right to keep you on retainer for up to 72 hours, post-mission." Material Defender then has a warp core retrofitted onto his ship that extends his reach to distant planets with PTMC mines outside the solar system.GameplayThe ship's cockpit, the most common view as you play the game. The upper bar (just below the window) displays your current energy, which powers your primary weapon and can be used to regenerate shields, and just below it your current shield power is displayed. The displays to the sides show your currently selected primary (left) and secondary (right) weapons, and the colored buttons the to far right show which of the colored keys, which are sometimes scattered across the level and may be required to access some areas, you have found. The Descent series is known for popularizing the use of full 3D rendering, allowing for six degrees of rotation. As the player explore tunnels and mines as the Material Defender, many enemies must be destroyed in order to proceed. A variety of weapons and upgrades can be gathered to further speed up the destruction of these foes. To find the core of the level, certain color-coded keys have to be found as well. Once the core is found and destroyed, a countdown timer begins, and the player has a certain amount of time to find the exit, and escape the level. Every four levels, instead of a core reactor, there is a boss. The boss must then be defeated as a core reactor would be destroyed. There are six bosses in total throughout the game.Saving can be done at any time. It saves the exact location of the player, all items, weapons, enemies, and the Guide-Bot.The Guide-Bot is a new feature in Descent II. It serves as a companion robot that leads the player to objectives in the mission. The Guide-Bot shoots flares that can injure both the player and enemies. It is invulnerable to laser fire, but a large amount of missiles from the player or enemies can destroy it.Another new appearance in the game is the Thief-bot, which will roam around the level, sneak up on the player and steal some of their weapons or equipment, but never downright attacking the player. When fired upon, the Thief-bot will try to run away, and the player has to chase it down if they want to return their precious equipment.PlanetsZeta AquilaeQuartzonBrimsparkLimefrost SpiralBaloris PrimeOmega (divided into two: Puuma Sphere and Tycho Brahe)LevelsLevel 1: Ahayweh GateLevel 2: Turnabout BoreLevel 3: Wenl MineLevel 4: Robby StationSecret Level 1: Segment CityLevel 5: Seaspring GorgeLevel 6: The WellLevel 7: Coralbank QuarryLevel 8: Riverbed MineSecret Level 2: Hurdle ChaseLevel 9: Firewalker MineLevel 10: Lavafalls Extraction Ctr.Level 11: Coalbank ShaftLevel 12: Magnacore StationSecret Level 3: Mephisto HardcoreLevel 13: Sleetstone TunnelsLevel 14: Arcticon CorridorLevel 15: Icehammer CavernsLevel 16: Terrafrost CatacombsSecret Level 4: Galacia CavernsLevel 17: Y'tor IIILevel 18: Drec'nilbie K'luhLevel 19: Nep-Hilim S'crubLevel 20: Gytowt StationSecret Level 5: Ascent Level 1Level 21: N'neri RingLevel 22: Kwod A'riorLevel 23: IwihmlLevel 24: Tycho BraheSecret Level 6: Chain ReactionMusicThe PC version of Descent II featured two different options for music playback, the player could either choose to listen to the redbook CD audio on the game discs, or an optional MIDI soundtrack available for users who couldn't play CD audio (which often required a special audio cable between the CD-ROM drive and the sound card in 1996), or hadn't done a full install, requiring the game to load from the disc during play. Unlike Descent 1, where the PS1 and Mac versions had CD audio remixes of the PC version's MIDI music, Descent II's CD music is entirely different from the MIDI music. Like Descent 1, there were separate MIDI songs for every level in the game, but only 12 (in some releases, only 8) CD tracks, making the music repeat after a few levels.The game's redbook soundtrack was largely composed by Interplay's in-house musicians Brian Luzietti, Larry Peacock and Johann Langlie, but a selection of licensed music by Nivek Ogre of Skinny Puppy, Mark Walk and Type-O Negative also were included (some of it was re-used from the Mac and PlayStation versions of Descent, which also had redbook audio, unlike the original PC release). The music during the game's cutscenes were composed by Peter Rotter.Many releases and re-prints of Descent II and it's expansion pack Vertigo have slightly different track lists, some with the songs in different orders, or with slightly extended mixes of some songs. The original release combines the title song and the next song, Crawl, into the same track (track 2, as track 1 on Redbook discs are used for the game data), while the Descent Definite Collection and Infinite Abyss releases split them up into separate CD tracks. The track names for the music were supplied in the game's read-me file. Track listing for all the known variations are listed below:Original SoundtrackGame DataTitle by Brian LuziettiCrawl by Brian LuziettiGlut by Ogre of Skinny Puppy  Mark WalkGunner Down by Brian LuziettiCold Reality by Larry Peacock, Brad Cross, and Leslie SpitzerRatzez by Nivek Ogre/Skinny Puppy  Mark WalkCrush by Brian LuziettiUntitled Track by Mark MorganHaunted (Instrumental Remix) by Type O NegativeAre You Descent? by Ron ValdezTechno Industry by Johann LanglieRobot Jungle by Johann LanglieDefinite Collection/Infinite Abyss Soundtrack (Descent II)Game DataGame DataTitle by Brian LuziettiCold Reality (Extended Remix) by Larry Peacock, Brad Cross  Leslie SpitzerCrawl (Extended Remix) by Brian LuziettiGunner Down (Extended Remix) by Brian LuziettiRatzes (Extended Remix) by Nivek Ogre/Skinny Puppy and Mark WalkTechno Industry (Extended Remix) by Johann LanglieAre You Descent? (Extended Remix) by Ron ValdezRobot Jungle (Extended Remix) by Johann LanglieDefinite Collection/Infinite Abyss Soundtrack (Descent II: Vertigo)Game DataCrush by Brian LuziettiGlut (Extended Remix) by Nivek Ogre/Skinny Puppy and Mark WalkHaunted (Instrumental Version) by Type-O NegativeNew Track #1 (Uncredited - Cutscene music from Descent 1 for PS1)Untitled Track by Mark MorganNew Track #2 (Uncredited)New Track #3 (Uncredited - Track from the Mac version of Descent 1)The uncredited tracks are likely by Brian Luzietti, Larry Peacock or Johann Langlie.New WeaponsThe game has all of the weapons from the previous game, with ten new weapons.Primary WeaponsSuper Laser- Will instantly boost the Laser level to level five, but it can be upgraded to level six (yellow and white lasers respectively).Gauss Cannon- Fires explosive Vulcan Ammo, using up a larger amount of ammo. It fires at a slower rate than the Vulcan Cannon, though, so overall it uses less ammo.Helix Cannon- A fast-firing, rotating cannon that is similar to the Spreadfire Cannon.Phoenix Cannon- Fast-firing energy bolts that bounce of walls, allowing the player to hit enemies multiple times.Omega Cannon- This cannon shoots homing lightning bolts that temporarily blinds the target.Flare- Flares can be fired to light up dark areas. It only costs one energy per two shots to fire.Secondary WeaponsFlash Missile- A weak missile that temporarily stuns the target.Guided Missile- Can either be guided by the player or turned into a regular homing missile.Smart Mine- Similar to a Proximity Bomb; releases homing pulses.Mercury Missile- Fastest of all missiles, but it doesn't home in on targets.Earthshaker Missile- Initial impact shakes the entire level; it leaves an afterburner trail and releases smaller homing missiles.ItemsShield- The trademark blue spheres. Varying amounts of these are scattered around the level, depending on what level the player is on.Energy- Flashing yellow stars that give certain amounts of energy.Afterburner- Allows for the player to go quicker.Converter- Transfers energy into shield at a rate of two energy to one shield.Cloaking Device- Makes the player invisible for about thirty seconds.Headlight- Improves lighting by a lot, but steadily uses energy.Extra Life- A green sphere with the ship inside it. Gains the player an extra life.Invulnerability- Makes the player invincible for about thirty seconds.Ammo Rack- Doubles the amount of ammo space.MultiplayerLike Doom, Descent offers excellent competitive or co-op multiplayer game play over a LAN. Descent is also touted as being one of the first games that allowed on-the-fly joining of multiplayer games, whereas in Doom it is presumed that all players have to be queued prior to initiating the match. With the advent of the Internet, IPX emulators such as Kali and Kahn which actually combined better compression for IPX games with its own IRC network for users to meet in a standalone client, more and more people began to play Descent and Descent II over the Internet. Descent II was especially popular online due to its support for short packets and variable packet rate -- options which were crucial for smooth Internet play.ReceptionIf you don't like Descent at least a little bit, make no mistake, there is something wrong with you. Descent II's huge replay value and absolutely insane network play should ensure its popularity for a long timeChris Hudak, Gamespot, May 1996Descent II was mostly met with critical acclaim, with the only real contention being the few changes to the formula from the original, as well as the lack of outdoors areas. Gamespot's Chris Hudak gave the game a score of 9.2, praising the network play, the addition of the guide bot and the soundtrack.Descent Mission Builder 2An authorized level editor for descent 1 and 2 gave users the tools necessary to design, create and implement levels for the commercial versions of Descent and Descent II, and was shipped with some releases of Descent II and Vertigo. The original Descent Mission Builder was also available as a separate retail release. Levels consist of a series of cubes that the player gets to texture, light up and join with other cubes, the cubes' size can be changed, as can their shape, and the faces can be turned into triggers, doors and destructible walls. Blinking sequences for the flickering lights could also be created in the editor. This program is also capable of converting original Descent missions into Descent II missions, import player created textures (as .BMP files) or new music (only replacing the PC version's alternate MIDI soundtrack, not the redbook audio).Descent II: The Vertigo seriesDescent II: Vertigo Series is an add-on for Descent II containing twenty additional levels (and three secret levels), plus the officially licensed Descent II: Mission Builder. Remixed versions of some music tracks from the original Descent II were also included on the CD in Redbook CD-audio format, an interesting addition to what is a simple level pack. It was lauded for its creative level design and the introduction of many exotic robots and two new bosses though some levels also borrowed robots from Descent. "Flickering" lights were also a new feature to visual effects. Descent II Vertigo was included in the Descent Definite Collection, but not in any subsequent releases, including the 2008 GOG.com release.Minimum System RequirementsProcessor: Intel 486DX 50MHz or fasterGraphics: 256 color VGA or SVGA monitorMemory: 8MB for DOS or 16MB for WindowsOperating System: DOS 5.0 or Windows 95Hard Disk Install Requirement: At least 30MBOptical Drive Speed: 2x CD-ROMMiscellaneous: Spare time... lots of it.Recommended System RequirementsProcessor: Intel Pentium 90MHz or fasterMemory: 16MB RAMSound Card: Stereo 16-Bit sound card with MIDI supportOptimal game controller: A joystick with twist functionHard Disk Install: Full install at 300MBMiscellaneous: A player who is not prone to motion-sicknessSource code releaseHere, finally, is the source for Descent II. We've been so busy with Descent 3, Mercenary, FreeSpace, FreeSpace 2, and several other projects that we haven't given much thought to this old code. But I know that many of you are eager to get it, so here you go.We were amazed and impressed at the cool things people did with the Descent source we released a few years ago. It touches us deeply how devoted some people are to the Descent series, and we look forward to seeing what people can do with this Descent II source.Outrage Games at http://www.descent2.com/ddn/sources/descent2/On December 15, 1999, Outrage Games (formed after Parallax Software was closed down, most of the team split into either Outrage or Volition) released the source code for Descent II on the Descent Developers Network, stripped of proprietary code they didn't own the copyright for, such as the audio and modem communication libraries. The code was released under a license only including the source code, not the assets (textures, music, cutscenes, models or levels) for the game, which had to be acquired from a legal copy of the game, and the code was only allowed to be used for non-commercial, non-revenue generating purposes. The original Descent source code had previously been released under the same license in 1997.With the source code available, several source ports of the game became available, porting the game to run in Linux and other operating systems and platforms, even making it to the PSP homebrew community. Today there are primarily two active source port projects for Descent and Descent 2, D2X-XL (http://www.descent2.de/d2x.html) which aims to expand the game with modern rendering and shader technology, including support for Track-IR and the Oculus Rift, and the DXX Rebirth project (http://www.dxx-rebirth.com/), which aims to stay as close as possible to the look and feel of the original 1996 release, while being compatible with modern operating systems and hardware.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="520">Terracide</game><game id="12541">Freespace 2</game><game id="15636">Forsaken</game><game id="7747">John Romero's Daikatana</game><game id="21912">Planetside: Core Combat</game><game id="23436">Shattered Horizon</game><game id="10309">Descent: Freespace - The Great War</game><game id="19585">Descent: Freespace: Silent Threat</game><game id="33201">WarpSpeed</game><game id="20444">Tigershark</game><game id="7008">Hellbender</game><game id="38837">Retrovirus</game><game id="18105">Terminal Velocity</game><game id="1784">Fury³</game><game id="4814">Archimedean Dynasty</game><game id="7272">Adrenix</game><game id="25726">Red Faction: Armageddon</game><game id="14009">AquaNox 2: Revelation</game><game id="5042">AquaNox</game><game id="27454">Miner Wars 2081</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/7465/677143-descentii_dos.jpg</image></root>