<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5561</id><name>Diddy Kong Racing DS</name><description>OverviewDiddy Kong Racing DS, is a remake of the Nintendo 64 classic, Diddy Kong Racing. The game was developed Rare and published by Nintendo, which also made it Rare's first game on the DS. This brought a minor change the characters in the DS version, compared to the Nintendo 64 game, due to Rare's departure to Microsoft. Banjo and Conker were taken out and replaced by two Donkey Kong characters, Tiny and Dixie Kong. The game also has some changes to the gameplay and design of the game as well. This included slight changes in some of the course designs, new music, Nintendo Wi-Fi compatibility, vehicle customization, a custom track editor, new items, and two new unlockable characters.AdventureThe main feature of Diddy Kong Racing is its adventure mode. In this mode players must win races though 5 different worlds and collect golden balloons to advance through the game. In between, the DS version offers new challenges set by Taj the elephant. One of them has the player using the microphone to blow out torches in a set amount of time and another has players popping balloons, using the DS touch screen. The game also features a new coin system. Coins are spread around courses and the player can collect them and use them to buy or unlock new items in the game.MultiplayerThe game offers Single-Card wireless play, Multi-Card wirless play and an online mode, through the Nintendo Wi-Fi Connection. In multiplayer, players can race, have a battle or play a Wish Race (custom track maker).CharactersMain CharactersPipsyTiptupDiddy kongDixie KongTiny KongTimberBumperKrunchUnlockable CharactersDrumstickTajT.TWizpigItemsThroughout races there are different coloured balloons, that players can hit. These give the player a weapon, which they can use to help them win the race. The more you collect of a specific coloured balloon, the better your weapon will be.Red Balloons - These contain missiles and get more powerful, depending on how many red balloons you collect.Blue Balloons - These contain boosts and increase in speed, depending on how many blue balloons you collect.Green Balloons - These contain oil slicks, land mines and bubbles traps, depending on how many green balloons you collect.Yellow Balloons - These contain shields, which increase in protection, depending on how many yellow balloons you collect.Rainbow Balloons - These contain magnets that pull you towards other races, these increase in power, depending on how many rainbow balloons you collect.The DS version also features a new item, called a Power-Up Token. These are scattered around tracks and once collected, they will upgrade your current weapon.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6539">Mario Kart DS</game><game id="19071">Super Mario Kart</game><game id="18757">Mario Kart: Double Dash!!</game><game id="16769">Mario Kart: Super Circuit</game><game id="20645">Mario Kart Wii</game><game id="4622">Pocketbike Racer</game><game id="14277">Banjo-Pilot</game><game id="11174">LEGO Racers</game><game id="20906">Cocoto Kart Racer</game><game id="13178">Speed Punks</game><game id="6368">Mickey's Speedway USA</game><game id="26848">ModNation Racers</game><game id="22190">Street Racer</game><game id="32225">Crash Bandicoot Nitro Kart 2</game><game id="21285">Rollcage Stage II</game><game id="1145">Pokémon Dash</game><game id="31747">Mario Kart 7</game><game id="38173">Sonic &amp; All-Stars Racing Transformed</game><game id="40574">Monster High Skultimate Roller Maze</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2267071-box_dkrds.png</image></root>