<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>557</id><name>WCW vs. the World</name><description>Overview  WCW vs. The World is a wrestling game published by THQ and developed by the AKI Corporation; it is the first game they had developed that was released outside of Japan. As the title implies it features some key WCW superstars and pits them against wrestlers from five different wrestling federations. The game features 14 WCW superstars and 39 other superstars from around the world. All of these 39 superstars are under alias names because THQ was not able to obtain the rights to use their names.Wrestling Leagues The game features wrestlers from 6 different wrestling federations including WCW:WCW (World Championship Wrestling)Chris Benoit Dean Malenko Eddie Guerrero Hulk Hogan Lex Lugar Masahiro Chono Ric Flair Rick Steiner Scott Steiner Lord Steven Regal Sting Ultimo Dragon The Unknown  Jeff Jarrett (Unlockable)  Empire Wrestling Federation (All Japan Pro Wrestling)Bear Breath (Gary Albright) The Count (Stan Hansen) Fujigami (Tatsumi Fujinami) Kapuna (Toshiaki Kawada) Mongrel (Jumbo Tsuruta) Sam Song (Kenta Kobashi) Samoa (Giant Baba) Siberia (Steve Williams) Wu Fang (Mitsuharu Misawa)  Samurai Wrestling Federation (Pancrase / Universal Wrestling Federation)200 Wins (Yoji Anjoh) Akira (Akira Maeda) Billy Gaijin (Scott Norton) Kaiji (Yoshiaki Fujiwara) Konaka (Shiro Koshinaka) Moma (Nobuhiko Takada) Sherlock (Ken Shamrock) Thunder Dome (Bas Rutten) Uraki (Masakastsu Funaki) Yamagiwa (Kazumo Yamazaki)  Dead or Alive (Frontier Martial Arts Wrestling / WAR)Blackheart (Tarzan Goto) David Harley (Sabu) Habanero (Hayabusa) Kim Chee (Koji Kiato) Puchteca (Atsushi Onita) Saladin (Genichiro Tenryu)  Independent Union (Michinoku Pro Wrestling)Black Belt (TAKA Michinoku) Black Ninja (The Great Sasuke) Mukluk (Kensuke Sasaki) Shaolin (Jinsei Shinzaki) El Bolador (Hiroyoshi Tenzan)   Neo Strong Wrestling (New Japan Pro Wrestling)Abispa (Jushin "Thunder" Liger) Bad Blood (The Great Muta) Bolt Jamison (Kensuke Sasaki) Dakota (Hiroshi Hase) Dojo (Shinya Hashimoto) Mad Oahu (Riki Chōshū) Mongol (Keiji Mutoh) Overdose (Road Warrior Hawk) The Turk (Dynamite Kid) </description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12592">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2008</game><game id="18801">WWF War Zone</game><game id="21620">WWE Day of Reckoning 2</game><game id="26888">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2010</game><game id="9216">Power Move Pro Wrestling</game><game id="13440">Backyard Wrestling: Don't Try This at Home</game><game id="18333">Backyard Wrestling 2: There Goes the Neighborhood</game><game id="12836">Tecmo World Wrestling</game><game id="28430">WWF Royal Rumble</game><game id="23212">Virtual Pro Wrestling 64</game><game id="23213">Virtual Pro Wrestling 2: Ōdō Keishō</game><game id="14786">WCW vs. nWo: World Tour</game><game id="3667">WWF Wrestlemania 2000</game><game id="11394">WWF No Mercy</game><game id="21526">Ultimate Muscle: Legends vs. New Generation</game><game id="35032">Kinnikuman Muscle Grand Prix Max 2: Tokumori</game><game id="31109">Kinnikuman Muscle Grand Prix MAX</game><game id="3744">Def Jam: Fight for NY</game><game id="22083">Def Jam: Fight for NY: The Takeover</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2409920-box_wcwvtw.png</image></root>