<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5571</id><name>Dirge of Cerberus: Final Fantasy VII</name><description>OverviewDirge of Cerberus: Final Fantasy VII is Square Enix's PS2 entry in the Compilation of Final Fantasy VII. The game is set one year after the film Final Fantasy VII: Advent Children and casts the player in the role of Vincent Valentine as he assists the World Regenesis Organization in stopping the remnants of an old Shinra super-soldier project called Deep Ground. The game also explores Vincent's once enigmatic past in great detail, particularly in regards to his time as a Turk and his relationship with Lucrecia.Instead of an RPG, Dirge of Cerberus is an action game with a heavy emphasis on gunplay and weapon customization mixed with RPG concepts such as leveling up and using magic. Over the course of the game, Vincent can acquire and upgrade a variety of firearm types including a pistol, shotgun, rifle, and machine gun. Upgraded weapons allow for better accuracy, more attack power, and reduced recoil. There is also a brief section in which the player takes control of Cait Sith that is more focused on basic stealth gameplay.Introduction of Deep GroundConcept art of generic Deep Ground soldiers.Deep Ground is the name of the secret military unit that serves as the game's antagonists. The name "Deep Ground" was taken from the fact that the program to develop these soldiers was housed in an underground facility deep beneath Shinra Headquarters. The program was so heavily classified that of the company's top-level executives, only President Shinra, Heidegger and Scarlet were aware of its existence, and the project became dormant and forgotten once all three of them died. It wasn't until three years after the events of Final Fantasy VII that Deep Ground emerged as a threat led by a core group of especially powerful super-soldiers known as the Tsviets.Multiplayer ModeWith the release of Dirge of Cerberus in Japan, a multiplayer mode was available through Square Enix's PlayOnline service. The Hard Disk Drive attachment for the PlayStation 2 was necessary for the online mode. For 800 yen a month, players could take their own character and progress through online modes such as a Team Deathmatch, Team Base Storm, Team Capsule Run, Team Survival Mode, and a special single-player timed survival mode.Also, several special missions were added through the online component. These were added episodically through version update patches every 4-6 weeks, and told an additional story about the Deep Ground group. These events took place during the timeline of the original Final Fantasy VII.Unfortunately, the price Square Enix was asking for to allow players to play an online shooter put the game in a bind, as most other PlayStation 2 shooters that had online play did so for free. As a result, the game's online component acquired a low subscriber base during its time in service. The online component was discontinued on September 29, 2006 ater only seven months of operation.The online mode for the game was removed in the North American and European markets due the lack of HDD support, and the overall negative reaction the PlayOnline service had received after the release of Final Fantasy XI. The additional missions were added as bonus missions in the "Extra Missions" mode for the two regions.SoundtrackFFVII Dirge of Cerberus Original Soundtrack CoverComposed by: Masashi Hamauzu, GacktMixed by: Masashi HamauzuSung by: Gackt (Disc 2, tracks 17 and 22)Released: 15 February 2006Disc 1No.Track NameTrack Length1Flickr1:282Calm Before the Storm2:213Trigger Situation2:054Prologue of "DIRGE of CERBERUS"2:475Fragment of Memory4:016Fearful Happening3:537WRO March2:228Azul the Cerulean2:159Fight Tune "Arms of Shinra"3:1310Abhorrence Whirls3:4311Silent Edge3:0512Undulation1:0513Counteroffensive2:2014Ten Year Reunion3:3115Fight Tune "Girl Named Shelke"2:5516Fight Tune "Killing One Another"2:1117Uneasy Feelings2:5118Memories with Lucrecia1:1119Sneaky Cait Sith3:5720Darkness2:2021Lifestream4:0922Rosso the Crimson1:2423Mysterious Ninja1:1224Ninja Girl of Wutai1:2425Sudden Parting1:1026Discovery in Sadness1:2527A Proposal2:1728High-Spirited0:4129Return to the Subject2:5530Marching Tune #00:55Disc 2No.Track NameTrack Length1Return to the Origin2:062Marching Tune3:503Fight Tune "Crimson Impact"1:534Under a Full Moon1:245Trespasser4:036Transformation into Chaos1:177Splinter of Sadness2:038Deep Darkness of Shinra3:559Lucrecia Crescent3:3310Forgotten Tears1:3611Fight Tune "Messenger of the Dark"2:4012Awakening1:4413Fight Tune "The Immaculate"5:0314Finally Reborn1:3615The Last SND1:3716Everyone's Help1:4417LONGING (GACKT)4:0018Terminus3:0219Quickening3:0020Death and Rebirth1:0721Chaotic End4:2822REDEMPTION (GACKT)4:0523Hope of the Future3:51</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13072">Devil May Cry</game><game id="9037">Gungrave</game><game id="16741">Devil May Cry 2</game><game id="890">Devil May Cry 3: Dante's Awakening</game><game id="36707">Devil May Cry HD Collection</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2179479-box_ff7doc.png</image></root>