<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5640</id><name>Capcom vs. SNK: Millennium Fight 2000 Pro</name><description>Overview Released in 2001, Capcom VS SNK: Millennium Fight 2000 is a Capcom fighting game that was powered by the NAOMI Hardware for the Dreamcast  PlayStation. The updated version included two more characters - Joe Higashi  Dan Hibiki.Gameplay The gameplay in the game is styled more after the SNK games rather than the Capcom games. The game uses four buttons instead of six - Light Punch, Hard Punch, Light Kick, Hard Kick. Techniques can be done using combinations of those four buttons.Capcom VS SNK has a couple of basic moves. The First is the Roll mechanic which is done by pressing the Light punch and Light kick simultaneously. It temporarily renders the player's character invincible and it's useful for evading attacks. Some other basic moves include Throw and Tech Throw; the Throw is done by pressing forward or back on the D-Pad or Joystick and pressing Hard punch or Hard kick simultaneously. The Tech Throw is a cancel Throw that is done by pressing forward or back when the player is about to be thrown. The other basic moves in the game is dashing or running that the player can choose to use in the options menu. The Dash is done tapping forward or back on the Joystick or D-Pad and same thing for the run.Ratio System Before a match, the roster is broking up into four Ratio tiers; each character is place in the Ratio tiers in terms of their offense and defense. The player is given four "points" and can spend those points by picking their characters; for example, Ryu  Kyo. So the player can spent all four points by picking Ryu  Kyo and have a team of two. Or can have a team of four if the player decides to pick just the Ratio one character like Sakura  Yuri.Ratio 1: Weak Offense, Weak DefenseRatio 2: Average Offense, Average DefenseRatio 3: Strong Offense, Strong DefenseRatio 4: Strongest Offense, Strongest DefenseGroovesThe Grooves. The game features two "Grooves" that the player can select before he or she picks her characters. Each Grooves determine how the special meters are used during a fight. Capcom Groove: The Capcom groove is similar to the      Street Fighter Alpha super meter were the players is given three levels of super.SNK Groove: The SNK groove, based on the super meter in      The King of Fighters '94, is used by charging up the character by pressing the Hard punch and Hard kick button simultaneously. The other feature of the SNK groove is when the player's health bar gets decrease at a certain point where it's blinking, the player can perform unlimited amounts of super moves. Presentation The Sakazaki stage All of the SNK characters are fully redrawn for the game and some of the Capcom characters as well. But as for the rest of the characters have not been redrawn; their sprites have been taken from where they originated -   Street Fighter Alpha and  Darkstalkers. 3D visual have been used for the projectiles attacks and other effects to give the game a unique look. The stages have special intros for all the stages - which is a bit of a nod to some of the SNK fighting games. Some of the stages have neat little effects; for example, in the Sakazaki stage, when a character gets slammed into the ground, the roof starts to slowly collapse.CharactersCapcom      Ryu (Street Fighter)     Ken Master (Street Fighter)     Sagat (Street Fighter)     Gulie (Street Fighter II)Ryu,  SNK style.     Dhalsim (Street Fighter II)     Chun-Li (Street FIghter II)     Cammy (Street Fighter II)     Blanka (Street Fighter II)     Balrog (Street Fighter II)     Zangeif Street Fighter II)     E. Honda (Street Fighter II)     Vega (Street Fighter II)     Sakura (Street Fighter Alpha II)Character select screen.     M.Bison (Street Fighter II)     Morrigan (DarkStalkers)     Akuma (Super Street Fighter II Turbo)     Evil Ryu (Street Fighter Alpha II)     Dan Hibiki (Street FIghter Alpha)SNK      Kyo Kusanagi (King of Fighters '94)     Terry Bogard (Fatal Fury)     King (Art of Fighting)Kyo, Capcom style.     Vice (King of Fighters '96)     Ryuji Yamazaki (Fatal Fury 3)     Yuri Sakazaki (Art of Fighting 2)     Benimaru Nikaido (King of Fighters '94)     Raiden (Fatal Fury)     Kim Kaphwan (Fatal Fury 2)     Ryo Sakazaki (Art of Fighting)     Iori Yagami (King of Fighters '95)     Mai Shiranui (Fatal Fury 2)     Rugal Bernstein (King of Fighters '94)     Orochi Iori (King of Fighters '97)     Nakoruru (Samurai Shodown)     Joe Higashi (Fatal Fury 2)     Geese Howard (Fatal Fury)Soundtrack ListThe soundtrack CD.Ryu - "Fist Explsion"Sagat - "Naked Blow"Final Fight - "Needle"Capcom - "Keep my Fire"OSAKA - "O-s-a-k-a"Terry - "Higher and Higher"Pappao Cafe - "Sonic Party"Sakazaki - "Scarp Beats"SNK - "B.B"M.Bison - "Sigh"Geese - "Vigor Force"Morrigan - "Deserted Chateau remix"Nakoruru -  "Silent Hill"Akuma - "Worth of my Fist"Ayutayaisaki - "S.F.2 Ryu remix" </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15408">Rival Schools: United by Fate</game><game id="18484">Killer Instinct</game><game id="7751">Art of Fighting Anthology</game><game id="3744">Def Jam: Fight for NY</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="19134">Street Fighter Alpha 2</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="21948">Street Fighter III: New Generation</game><game id="22305">Street Fighter III: 2nd Impact</game><game id="1615">Street Fighter III: 3rd Strike</game><game id="1251">Super Street Fighter II Turbo</game><game id="20456">Street Fighter IV</game><game id="13875">Plasma Sword: Nightmare of Bilstein</game><game id="21699">The King of Fighters '98 Ultimate Match</game><game id="21519">The King of Fighters XII</game><game id="5030">The King of Fighters XI</game><game id="16407">Samurai Shodown II</game><game id="5692">Samurai Shodown</game><game id="4249">The King of Fighters '94</game><game id="17678">The Last Blade</game><game id="10674">Garou: Mark of the Wolves</game><game id="34082">Skullgirls</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2179473-box_cvsp.png</image></root>