<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5688</id><name>Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3</name><description>OverviewNow you can skate with your friends!Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3 is a skateboarding game developed by Neversoft and published by Activision (under their Activision o2 label) for the PlayStation 2 (on October 28, 2001), GameCube (on November 13, 2001), and Xbox (on March 4, 2002). The third installment of the long-running Tony Hawk franchise and the sequel to Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 2, Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3 adds new skaters and levels while introducing new gameplay elements (such as new hidden variations of normal tricks and the Revert, a ground trick that can be executed as soon as the player hits the ground from a quarter-pipe, allowing them to continue from a Vert combo chain), and online multiplayer for up to four players (PlayStation 2 and GameCube versions only). The Career Mode currency system from the predecessor is removed (unlocking levels now just require objective completion, while stat increase points and new decks are gained by picking up special pickups scattered throughout levels).The game was ported to the PlayStation In October 29, 2001 (by Shaba Games), PC in March 28, 2002 (by Gearbox), and Nintendo 64 in August 20, 2002 (by Edge of Reality). The PlayStation and Nintendo 64 versions run on a slightly-modified Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 2 engine (still adding gameplay elements like the Revert), changing the level structure of most levels while replacing the secret Cruise Ship level with a new Downhill level. Some of the levels in the original version are believed to be released as downloadable content in Tony Hawk's Pro Skater HD for the Xbox 360 (via Xbox Live Arcade), PlayStation 3 (via PlayStation Network), and PC (via Steam).Handheld versions were released on both the Game Boy Color on November 15, 2001 (developed by HotGen) and the Game Boy Advance on March 4, 2002 (developed by Vicarious Visions). Both games are played in a 2D isometric viewpoint, featuring many elements from the console versions.Like Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 2, this game features crossover characters from different franchises as playable skaters. Darth Maul (a Sith apprentice from the Star Wars franchise), Wolverine (a superhero from the X-Men franchise), and Kelly Slater (a surfer from Kelly Slater's Pro Surfer) are included as hidden unlockable skaters. The PC version of the game features Doom from Quake III: Arena (as Doom Guy).GameplayRevertThe revert is a move that allows players to link vert tricks into a new or in-progress combo. It is a flatland trick that is performed immediately when landing off of a vert surface like a quarter-pipe or pool lip. The more times it is used in a single combo, the slower the player's speed will be when exiting the revert. To link vert tricks into a combo, a manual must be performed immediately after the revert animation.Open EnvironmentsDespite Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 2 featuring large, open-ended levels, THPS3 used it's current generation of systems' power to its advantage and brought the large-scale environments to life. Areas were now filled with NPCs, moving cars that would stop at obstacles, complex animated objects and real-time level shifting. Every level in THPS3 features a large or minor-scale change that can be triggered through the player's actions and either unlocks a previously hidden area or completely changes a part of the level altogether. These could either be part of a level goal or simply a hidden secret for the player to discover.Trick ModifiersOne other major addition to the game was the Trick Modifier system. This is a system that has been with the franchise since, although being refined in THPS4 and perfected in Tony Hawk's Underground. The trick modifier system are "Hidden moves" that can be performed by actions on the face buttons. For example, hitting the button combination for a kickflip while hitting the flip trick button twice will perform a Double Kickflip. Hitting it three times will perform a Triple Kickflip. Though THPS3 refers to them as Hidden Moves (An on-screen pop-up appears with a bonus score being awarded), they have become the standard in the series for performing modified versions of standard tricks.Network PlayA breakthrough addition to the series is the addition of online multiplayer. This would later be refined in later entries of the franchise but the base concept remains the same. The game allows for up to 4 players in one lobby and drops them in a Free Skate session. The host then decides which game type will be played. The various game types can be found below. Players could either play through a Broadband connection or, on the PlayStation 2 and GameCube, a dial-up connection.Game ModesTony Hawk's Pro Skater 3 features a wide variety of game modes thanks to the addition of Network Play. Some new, some returning from past entries.Single-player ModesCareer ModeThe same as it's always been in the series. The player is given a list of goals within a level and a two-minute timer to complete them. The level can be retried multiple times to complete the goals. Completing goals unlocks more levels until the last competition level is beaten. A few changes have been made to the Career Mode in THPS3, however. They are:Cash is no longer required to progress within the career mode. The collectible is entirely gone from the game.Stat points are no longer purchased but are, instead, hidden inside levels as collectibles. There are 5 per level. Collecting one lets you assign one stat point wherever the player wishes to.Decks are no longer purchased but are collected. One "Deck" collectible is hidden in each level and collecting it unlocks one deck for the selected pro skater.Collect S-K-A-T-E is now different depending on the selected pro skater. Street skaters will have their letters on lower, more technical areas of the level while vert skaters will have them on more vert/gap oriented areas. All-around skaters will have a mixture of both.Skater-specific goals. Much like the Collect S-K-A-T-E separation, certain level-based objectives will be dependent on the selected skater's specialty.Single SessionGives the players a two-minute timer without goals to set high scores.Free SkateAllows the player to freely roam levels, find gaps and search for secrets.Multiplayer ModesGraffitiBoth players compete in the level against the clock to capture as much territory as possible. Performing a trick on an object will paint it the player's color and painting as much of the level as possible is the objective. Players can re-capture an object by scoring higher than the previous player's object score.Trick AttackPlayers compete against each other to score the highest. The player with the highest score when the timer runs out wins.HORSEPits players against each other to see who can pull off the best trick sequence. Players have 10 second turns and start at key points within each map. When one player pulls of his trick, the next player must score higher. This keeps going until one of the players screws up, getting the first letter of HORSE (Or a custom word chosen at the beginning of the game).Slap!Slap! requires players to skate around and, quite literally, slap each other the most. Simply running into each other causes players to slap each other, though the fastest one will come out the victor. The other will bail and fall to the floor. The player with the highest amount of slaps at the end of the timer wins.King of the HillKing of the Hill places a floating crown in the level. When a player collects it, it appears over his head and he must hold onto it the longest. If another player rams into him, he gains control of the crown. The objective is to hold the crown the longest, hitting preset timer scores.LevelsThe FoundryLocation: An indoor metal foundry.The Foundry is a level set in, wait for it, metal foundry. It features multiple stories, catwalks and large jumps and pipes. The level has a large set of metal, ceiling-suspended catwalks, girders, pipes and airborne rails that can be grinded as well as a large cauldron. The cauldron is the level's destructible object. When grinding the top of a nearby control booth, the bucket flips over itself and falls into the cauldron, creating a rail-based jump gap. There are also other heightened ledges and platforms, a large sunken quarter pipe and an electricity turbine that can be entered when complete a Career objective named "Un-jam the 5 Valves".Goal List:NameDescriptionHigh ScoreTrick up to a score of 10,000 points.Pro ScoreTrick up to a score of 30,000 points.Sick ScoreTrick up to a score of 50,000 points.Collect S-K-A-T-ECollect the S K A T E letters scattered throughout the level.Get the Secret TapeCollect the Secret Tape.Cannonball over the Half-Pipe (Vert Skaters)Perform a Cannonball over the large, sunken half-pipe at the beginning of the level.50-50 TC's Rail (Street Skaters)Perform a 50-50 Grind on one of the rails near the raising platform control station.Soak the ForemanPerform a grind on the control panel of the platform-raised pool.Grind the Molten BucketAs the bucket is dumping molten metal, jump up to the rails on the side and grind them.Un-jam 5 ValvesSimply grind 5 wall-mounted valves.100% Goals, Stats and DeckComplete all the goals, find all the hidden stat points and find the hidden deck.CanadaLocation: An outdoor skatepark located in a woody, snow-filled, lakeside park.Canada is one of the game's larger levels, featuring extremely open areas that form both an outdoor park and skatepark. Part of the level is a parking lot featuring a handful of jumps and rails, a skatepark featuring a set of massive bowls, quarter pipes and half-pipes as well as a amerindian totem pole that totally isn't a stereotype at all. Next to the skatepark is a forested area featuring a wood-build catwalk that circles through trees above a set of quarter pipes and directly next to that area is an above-ground/water platform. The platform is on two levels, the first level being a simple plank board leading up to a quarter pipe. A canadian man peeing in the water stands at the top of the QP. A switch nearby activates access to the upper-level that leads to a wooden tube-like pipe slanted down from a mountain-track mining-cart rail. The rail leads to nowhere. The level's destructive element is quite banal, simply being the ability to knock the head off of the totem pole.Goal List:NameDescriptionHigh ScoreTrick up to a score of 35,000 points.Pro ScoreTrick up to a score of 70,000 points.Sick ScoreTrick up to a score of 120,000 points.Collect S-K-A-T-ECollect the S K A T E letters scattered throughout the level.Get the Secret TapeCollect the Secret Tape.Melon Grab Over the Blade (Vert Skaters)Perform a Melon grab over the roll-in at the start of the level.Nosegrind Around the Horn (Street Skaters)Perform a Nosegrind around the wooden catwalks found in the forested area.Get Chuck UnstuckSimply ram into the poor gentleman who's tongue is stuck onto a pole.Bury That Bully!Jump into the snowy tree behind a bully that is throwing snowballs at kids.Impress The SkatersThere are five skaters located throughout the skatepark. Perform a combo over 2,500 points near them to impress them. Impress all 5 to complete the objective.100% Goals, Stats and DeckComplete all the goals, find all the hidden stat points and find the hidden deck.Rio - Competition LevelLocation: A skatepark located in the high mountains of Rio de Janiero.Rio is the first of three competition levels. Like previous games, a one-minute timer is given to three rounds. The score from the best two out of three rounds is tallied and the skater with the highest score wins the gold. The level itself is set in a high-mountain area of Rio. The O Cristo Redentor statue is visible from the level. The level itself is generally comprised of bowls, quarter-pipes and half-pipes. A series of ledges, wires and rails circle the level that provide, to skilled players, an opportunity to pull-off a near-infinite combo. There's a hidden backyard pool and ledges that can be grinded on nearby houses. The destructible object in the level is a wooden platform that is supported by a ladder. When the ladder is hit by the player, it collapses and turns into two ledges that add to the infinte combo mentioned above.SuburbiaLocation: A suburban neighborhood.Suburbia is located in a neighborhood cul-de-sac and is split into 4 distinct areas. The first is the Trailer Park. It features a large, wooden half-pipe and sits next to trailer homes. The trailer homes have wooden planks and ramps next to/on them allowing them to be used as jumps and/or platforms. The trailer park area is also surrounded by a wooden quarter-pipe that sticks to the location's fence. The second area is the family homes. There are two. The first is a two-storey house that has a large, empty underground pool and is surrounded by a grindable fence. The second is a large, upper-class home. It has an accessible driveway, a green Jeep Wrangler parked in the driveway and has a backyard entirely covered in quarter-pipes. The third area is an under-construction home. The house also has a pool in it's backyard and is basically a large, wooden skeleton that can be grinded. Here is where you find an axe, needed to access the fourth area: the Haunted House. The haunted house is boarded-up. There is a Career Mode goal where a man will chop down the boards when given an axe. Doing this unlocks the house's backyard that is filled with quarter-pipes. The area instantly turns dark when you enter it and there are a number of zombie hands that burst out of the ground. The player can then jump into the house to find "spooky" hidden secrets.Goal List:NameDescriptionHigh ScoreTrick up to a score of 55,000 points.Pro ScoreTrick up to a score of 110,000 points.Sick ScoreTrick up to a score of 200,000 points.Collect S-K-A-T-ECollect the S K A T E letters scattered throughout the level.Get the Secret TapeCollect the Secret Tape.Nosegrab Between the Ramps (Vert Skaters)Perform a Nosegrab in the air while transferring between two Trailer Park quarter pipes.Heelflip the Trailer Hop (Street Skaters)Perform a Heelflip over one of the trailer homes.Squash 5 PumpkinSmash 5 pumpkins scattered throughout the level.Help the Thin ManFind the axe at the construction site and give it to the Thin Man waiting by the Haunted House.Restore Power to the DishGrind the electrical wire that's filled with branches leading up to the upper-class home.100% Goals, Stats and DeckComplete all the goals, find all the hidden stat points and find the hidden deck.AirportLocation: An indoor, straight-line airport.Airport is a level that is akin to the Downhill Jam and Mall levels from Tony Hawk's Pro Skater. Like those levels, Airport is built in a single straight line that leads to a dead end. Unlike those levels, the level doesn't end when reaching the bottom. The level consists of four floors. The first floor is where the baggage room, helipad and main corridor are. The corridor has a automated walkway and access to bathroom facilities. The baggage room is exactly what it sounds like. It can be accessed through the helipad, which can be accessed from the baggage claim counter at the start of the level. The second level consists of another walkway, metal detectors and more bathrooms. The third level drops down from a large escalator and consists of a series of benches, a large half-pipe and a giant, window-walled atrium. The atrium contains a series of rails that support 10 flags. The fourth level is underneath the end of the level. Players can drop down to a level below the atrium where there are a numerous amount of baggage carts, quarter-pipes and ramps.Goal List:NameDescriptionHigh ScoreTrick up to a score of 75,000 points.Pro ScoreTrick up to a score of 150,000 points.Sick ScoreTrick up to a score of 300,000 points.Collect S-K-A-T-ECollect the S K A T E letters scattered throughout the level.Get the Secret TapeCollect the Secret Tape.Airwalk Over an Escalator (Vert Skaters)Perform an Airwalk over one of the level's escalators at the end of the level.Crooked Grind Around the Baggage Claim (Street Skaters)Perform a Crooked Grind around the Baggage Claim wheel.Visit 10 CountriesGrind through/over 10 flags that hang off of the rails in the Atrium.Get the Tickets to Your Skate BuddyGrab the tickets at the beginning of the level and bring them to a skateboarder at the end of the level whilst avoiding obstacles along the way.Stop the PickpocketsThere are 5 pickpockets located in the level, each dressed in black and holding sacks of money.100% Goals, Stats and DeckComplete all the goals, find all the hidden stat points and find the hidden deck.Skater Island - Competition LevelLocation: A real-world skatepark located in Rhode Island.Skater Island is the second competition level. It was a real-world skatepark located in Rhode Island, USA. In May, 2004, the part closed due to the roof collapsing. It features a large half-pipe, two wooden bowls and a stretch of street funboxes and rails. The level also features two outdoor areas. The first can be accessed through a door at the end of the level that leads to an exterior funbox and a selection of rails. The second area can be accessed by grinding a pirate flag found in the level. A pirate ship outside the level blows cannons into the wall and creates a path to the ship. The ship has a selection of quarter-pipes and ramps. The blown wall is this level's destructible element.Los AngelesLocation: An outdoor, fictional downtown area of Los Angeles.Los Angeles is one of the biggest level of the entire game. It is split into 6 different areas. The first, the level's start point, is the Complex. It is near a high-raised area that leads directly to the Complex building. The building has a series of planters that can be grinded or aired over as a gap and is directly next to two large staircases. There is a wire that leads up to the top of the building onto it's roof. This area leads directly into the second area, the streets.The streets circle around the level, near the movie theatre, the inset building, the fire truck and the Car Wash. In the middle of the level is the third area, the Art Park. The park holds weird, stupid post-modern sculptures that act as half-pipes, tunnels and quarter-pipes. Next to this area is the Car Wash, the fourth area. The car wash can be entered (for no reason) and has ramp-like walls. It's rooftop has a half-pipe and the area surrounding the car wash is walled in quarter-pipes. Directly next to this area is the Apartment Buildings, the fifth area. It has a large fountain, a rooftop half-pipe and a raised area featuring a host of ledges. There is a hidden, underground half-pipe here. The sixth and final area can be accessed through the roof in the first area. It's the over-head highway. At the start of the level, the highway is inaccessible since cars pass too fast to allow players to cross it. The level's destructible element is the trigger of a massive earthquake that wrecks most of the level. This causes the highway to break into several sections, allowing the player to access and cross it.Goal List:NameDescriptionHigh ScoreTrick up to a score of 100,000 points.Pro ScoreTrick up to a score of 190,000 points.Sick ScoreTrick up to a score of 400,000 points.Collect S-K-A-T-ECollect the S K A T E letters scattered throughout the level.Get the Secret TapeCollect the Secret Tape.One Foot Japan the Tower Poppin' Transfer (Vert Skaters)Perform a One Foot Japan from the lower quarter-pipe onto the roof half-pipe in the apartments.Varial Kickflip the Tower Rails Gap (Street Skaters)Perform a Varial Kickflip in the air while grind-transfering a set of stair rails.Get Chuck UnstuckSimply ram into the poor gentleman who's tongue is stuck onto a pole.Free Ballin'Jump onto the two balls in the Art Park.Start the EarthquakeGrind the four "____tremor!" rails in the level to trigger the earthquake.Block the Car ChaseThis goal requires the "Start the Earthquake" goal to be complete. Once that is done, go up to the highway and grind on a loosely-hanging billboard so it smashes a runaway car in the streets below.100% Goals, Stats and DeckComplete all the goals, find all the hidden stat points and find the hidden deck.Tokyo - Competition LevelLocation: A Tokyo, high-tech skatepark.Tokyo is the third and final competition level. It is set at night in a large, enclosed, Shibuya-like area of Japan. It features a lot of vert bowls, half-pipes and quarter pipes. Most of it's edges are lined in neon and there are a few arc-shaped rails and overhead walkways. Tokyo features an incredible amount of hidden areas. Glass windows, electronic billboards and overhead half-pipes all decorate the level as secret areas. There's an airborne blimp that floats in the sky that supports a suspended, holographic-like platform that makes cool computer noises when riding on it. Tokyo is arguably the most visually impressive level of the game.Cruise ShipLocation: A cruise boat.Cruise Ship is an unlockable, technically secret, level. However, it features actual Career Mode goals. The ship itself features an upper deck with a pool and water-slide. The lower level has a party deck with patio chairs and tables along with a large, oversized wedding cake. The lowest level is the side of the ship which features a vegetation atrium, the front of the ship that has a perfect, Titanic-esque point and is filled with ramps and quarter-pipes as well as a museum dedicated to the ship. The side opposite of the atrium is a hallway with doors to cabins and rescue boats. The player can jump off the ship but will fall into a hazard and respawn on the boat.Goal List:NameDescriptionHigh ScoreTrick up to a score of 150,000 points.Pro ScoreTrick up to a score of 225,000 points.Sick ScoreTrick up to a score of 500,000 points.Collect S-K-A-T-ECollect the S K A T E letters scattered throughout the level.Get the Secret TapeCollect the Secret Tape.Invert the High Wires (Vert Skaters)Perform an Invert liptrick on the high wires above the pool. The pool needs to be drained first.Noseblunt an Awning (Street Skaters)Perform a Noseblunt Slide on one of the shop awnings.Impress the Neversoft GirlsPerform a high-scoring combo infront of the 7, at-the-time-hot bikini-clad ladies with Neversoft logos on their 'assets'.Raise the FerryWallride the control panel in the pilot's cabin.Trash the MuseumBreak the ropes holding down the propeller in the ship museum.100% Goals, Stats and DeckComplete all the goals, find all the hidden stat points and find the hidden deck.Secret LevelsOil RigOil Rig is a console-exclusive map that is locked to Xbox players only. This map would later appear in Tony Hawk's American Wasteland as it's own section in Los Angeles.Exclusive to the XBOX version.WarehouseComplete the game 100% three times. From Tony Hawk's Pro Skater.Warehouse is situated in a dark warehouse and features a hill drop, walls decked with quarter-pipes, a boxed-up taxi cab and a large half-pipe sitting underneath a glass-walled overhang.BurnsideComplete the game 100% six times. From Tony Hawk's Pro Skater.Burnside is located underneath a highway and is a replica of an actual skatepark. It features a variety of vert structures such as bowls, quarter pipes and snake bowl-like areas. It is the second competition level.RoswellComplete the game 100% nine times. From Tony Hawk's Pro Skater.Roswell is situated in a dark, enclosed area of (presumably) Area 51 and features a wide selection of half-pipes, quarter-pipes, rails and bowls. One of it's bowls rests on top of a missile silo and a secret area can be opened to find an alien in captivity.Secrets(Warning! Following text contains spoilers!)You can unlock a lot of content by finishing to career mode over and over again.Secret videosPro Bails - Get medals in all three competitions using anyonePro Bails 2 - Get three gold medals with a Created SkaterTony Hawk - Get three gold medals with Tony HawkSteve Caballero - Get three gold medals with Steve CaballeroRune Glifberg - Get three gold medals with Rune GlifbergEric Koston - Get three gold medals with Eric KostonBucky Lasek - Get three gold medals with Bucky LasekBam Margera - Get three gold medals with Bam MargeraRodney Mullen - Get three gold medals with Rodney MullenChad Muska - Get three gold medals with Chad MuskaAndrew Reynolds - Get three gold medals with Andrew ReynoldsGeoff Rowley - Get three gold medals with Geoff RowleyElissa Steamer - Get three gold medals with Elissa SteamerJamie Thomas - Get three gold medals with Jamie ThomasNeversoft Bails - Get three gold medals with Darth MaulNeversoft Makes - Get three gold medals with WolverinePro Retro - Get three gold medals with Officer DickKickflip Contest - Get three gold medals with Private CarreraNeversoft Friends - Get three gold medals with Ollie the BumSlater - Get three gold medals with Kelly SlaterNeversoft Retro - Get three gold medals with DemonessDay in the Life - Get three gold medals with Neversoft EyeballSecret levelsThe Cruise Ship - Get medals in all three competitions using anyoneWarehouse (From THPS1) - Complete the game 100% three timesBurnside (From THPS1) - Complete the game 100% six timesFreeway (From THPS beta ) - Complete the game nine timesSecret CharactersDarth Maul - Complete the game 100% one timeWolverine - Complete the game 100% two timesOfficer Dick - Complete the game 100% four timesPrivate Carrera - Complete the game 100% five timesOllie the Bum - Complete the game 100% seven timesKelly Slater - Complete the game 100% eight timesThe Demoness - Complete the game 100% ten timesDoom Guy - The Protagonist of the original Doom is an exclusive skater in the PC version of the gameX-Ray the Skeleton - An exclusive skater in the Xbox version of the gameCheatsSnowboard Mode - Complete the game 100% eleven timesAlways Special Mode - Complete the game 100% twelve timesPerfect Rail Balance Mode - Complete the game 100% thirteen timesSuper Stats Mode - Complete the game 100% fourteen timesGiant Mode - Complete the game 100% fifteen timesSlowmo Mode - Complete the game 100% sixteen timesPerfect Manual Balance Mode - Complete the game 100% seventeen timesTiny Mode - Complete the game 100% eighteen timesMoon Physics Mode - Complete the game 100% nineteen timesExpert Mode - Complete the game 100% twenty timesFirst Person Mode - Complete the game 100% twenty-twoSoundtrackThe Adolescents - "Amoeba"AFI - "The Boy Who Destroyed the World"Alien Ant Farm - "Wish"Bodyjar - "Not the Same"CKY - "96 Quite Bitter Beings"Del tha Funkee Homosapien - "If You Must"Guttermouth - "I'm Destroying the World"House of Pain "I'm a Swing-It"KRS-One - "Hush"The Mad Capsule Markets - "Pulse"Motorhead - "Ace of Spades"The Nextmen - "Amongst the Madness"Ozomatli - "Cut Chemist Suite"Ramones - "Blitzkrieg Bop"Red Hot Chili Peppers - "Fight Like a Brave"Redman feat. DJ Kool - "Let's Get Dirty"The Reverend Horton Heat - "I Can't Surf"Rollins Band - "What's the Matter Man"Xzibit - "Paparazzi"Zebrahead - "Check"</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="23">Skateboarding</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2570">Aggressive Inline</game><game id="5228">skate.</game><game id="20661">Skate 2</game><game id="21495">Skate It</game><game id="21001">Skate Park City</game><game id="8819">Skate or Die</game><game id="18624">Thrasher Presents: Skate and Destroy</game><game id="6737">Dave Mirra Freestyle BMX: Maximum Remix</game><game id="11794">Skate or Die 2: The Search for Double Trouble</game><game id="21758">ESPN X-Games Skateboarding</game><game id="1013">The Simpsons Skateboarding</game><game id="21988">Airblade</game><game id="7099">Mat Hoffman's Pro BMX 2</game><game id="9279">Kelly Slater's Pro Surfer</game><game id="18636">Tech Deck Skateboarding</game><game id="25647">Transworld Surf: Next Wave</game><game id="25743">Sunny Garcia Surfing</game><game id="12117">JSRF: Jet Set Radio Future</game><game id="28135">Skate 3</game><game id="30195">Shaun White Skateboarding</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2106408-box_thps3.png</image></root>