<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5695</id><name>Starshot: Space Circus Fever</name><description>StoryStarshot pitches you into the exciting adventures of a space circus in the 32nd century. Space Circus is the biggest circus vessel in the Universe, but at the beginning of the adventure, things are not going too well. The Space Circus has been overtaken by it's rival, Virtua Circus, run by the infamous Wolfgang von Ravel. Virtua Circus which, thanks to its new spectacular virtual show, is a sell-out. Intro Cinematic, Tensun in the distanceStarcash and Captain NobrakesSpace Circus is also riddled with debt and is being chased by the Intergalactic Bank, which has threatened to send out its fearsome Robot-Bomb bailiffs. To save the Space Circus from bankruptcy or even destruction, you play the part of Starshot, the Space Circus's star-juggler who has the ability to manipulate the stars and bring them down on your enemies. You're going to travel through distant galaxies in search of the most extraordinary performers, to help put on the best circus show in the history of the Universe. But be careful, because Wolfgang von Ravel and his henchmen are sworn to ensure your demise! Watch the story unfold through interaction with other characters, in-engine cutscenes and specially pre-rendered cinematics, all beautifully animated and voice acted! GameplayThe player controls Starshot, the Space Circus's star-juggler.Exploring planet Tensun   You begin each mission inside the Space Circus, you are briefed by your boss and from here you can get useful information from the other crew members. There are also other robots who will tell you which planets have Mega Fuel and the news robot will inform you of other circus activities on a planet. After an inital attack by Virtua Circus on one of your vessels, Starshot is sent down to the planet to investigate the incident alongside his two fellow sidekicks, WillFall and WillFly.   Starshot is able to collect stars and bring them down on his enemies. When killed, they will drop useful items that the player can pick up and other items can be found scattered accross the land. You are also equipped with a number of acrobatic manuvers which help to transverse the game's frequent jump puzzles .  Starshot is able to interact with many characters on his journey consisting of seven different planets with many different characters, they will often explain the situation or give new objectives to Starshot. There are many touches that add to the gameplay, for example if you attack a child or destroy their sand-castles, the police officers on Tensun will let you know about it and will be more inclined to attack you. On another planet, if you are told not to enter an area, you will be attacked only if you dis-obey the order. Many of the missions have puzzle elements where you will need to manipulate the features of the environment in order to defeat the enemy.Starshot and WillFall    WillFall is a disposable robot that mostly finds himself falling off of ledges uncontrollably. Your other companion, WillFly is able to carry Starshot accross the world, provided that the player has collected enough fuel to last the journey, which adds a degree of freedom not seen in other platformers. This is useful under circumstances where travelling by foot would otherwise be time-consuming, difficult and dangerous. The camera was however poorly designed after the N64 version, before mouse controlled cameras and dual analogues were being used for this purpose. This can make the jump puzzles a little more difficult and the camera can be awkwardly positioned during combat at times, but doesn't entirely ruin the experience thanks to the broad design of the game's locations.The Space Circus Crew Starcash   Your boss, who will give you missions. Captain Nobrakes   Pilot of the Space Circus, consult him about travelling to different planets. Starshot and WillFall   Star-Juggler and Disposable robot, choose them to explore the planet. Strategorik   Tells you about your mission and your objectives. Encyclopedo   Find out more about the planet you are about to explore. Mega Fuel   Find out which planets have Mega Fuel that can be obtained. Headsortails   An amusing robot with no real purpose other than playing heads or tails. News Robot   Informs you of other local circus activities on a planet.VersionsTwo versions of Starshot were produced for the Nintendo 64 and PC.There were many major additions made to the PC version that are missing from the Nintendo 64 version due to the limitations of the cartridge technology. The PC version included pre-rendered cinematics, full voice acting (The characters would otherwise babble incoherently in the N64 version), improved music quality and better visuals. This version supports software and 3DFX rendering, the latter can be achieved on modern computers through GLIDE emulation.The PC version of the game was unusual because it was designed to run straight from the CD-ROM, much like you would expect from a console. This was funnily described as out of fashion by the developers in the readme file, however booting games this way never caught on in the PC gaming market.Starshot is such a high-tech game it doesn't install to your hard drive (that would be too passé). You may however copy some files to your disk so as to speed up loading, just in case you weren't entirely satisfied with the amazing speed you can already see, but then we're getting off the subject.If the PC version will not run, make a backup copy of "Glide.iCD" and delete the one in the game folder. In order to do this, you will have to copy the entire game to your harddrive. Alternatively, you can access the starshot exectuable from command prompt and add "soft" as an extra parameter (soft is the shortened term used for the Software Renderer, Soft.iCD)ReceptionStarshot recieved mixed reviews, scoring an average of 59 on MobyGames. The game was praised for it's interesting presentation and story, but criticized for it's lack of innovation in the genre and frustrating jump puzzles. Many reviewers cited that it missed the wave of early 3D platformers like Mario 64, released two year earlier. Others thought it was better suited to the Playstation rather than the PC or Nintendo 64.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10920">Banjo-Kazooie</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/486/545871-starshot_manual.png</image></root>