<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5708</id><name>Metroid II: Return of Samus</name><description>StoryA Metroid attacking Samus.In the first game  Samus prevented the Space Pirates from using the newly discovered Metroid race for their own evil purposes. To prevent such an incident from happening again the Galactic Federation sent teams to the home planet of the Metroid,  SR388, to destroy the species. None of the teams survived, so they sent in bounty hunter Samus Aran to destroy the Metroids.During the game Samus destroys every Metroid on the planet, discovering and eliminating each of the creature's  different forms.At the end of the game Samus defeats the final boss, the Queen Metroid. When traveling back to her ship she discovers a Metroid egg which proceeds to hatch in front of her. The floating hatchling decides to mark Samus as it's mother, and Samus spares its life. The hatching Metroid leads Samus out of the tunnels, helping her escape from the planet.GameplayThe game plays much like the first  Metroid game did. The player must explore whatever part of the planet they currently have access to until they discover whatever they need to proceed further. Usually this involves finding a powerup that will allow them to bypass some obstacle that was previously impassable. However, in this game it is also necessary to destroy every single Metroid within Samus' reach. Doing so will trigger earthquakes which will affect the level of the magma that restricts Samus' progress into the deepest parts of the planet. The Metroids gradually mutate under the unstable planet's radiation and become more dangerous as the game goes on, so arming Samus as much as possible is important.Progression in this game is fairly more linear as that of the other Metroid games. The game doesn't typically require you to back track. Unlike the first game, you can save at various points in the game.GraphicsBeing on the original  Game Boy the game had a monochrome presentation. The result of such a limited color pallet was added detail to Samus's suit, such as the large shoulder-guards which have since remained a consistent part of her design ever since. Other notable aspects of the presentation are the different sprites for each of the  Metroid's different forms.</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21761">Metroid</game><game id="14216">Castlevania: Symphony of the Night</game><game id="1850">Ninja Gaiden III: The Ancient Ship of Doom</game><game id="19801">Mega Man X2</game><game id="7391">Mega Man 7</game><game id="16948">Mega Man X3</game><game id="19934">Scurge: Hive</game><game id="10975">Castlevania: Dracula X</game><game id="15092">Turrican</game><game id="24425">Rockman &amp; Forte: Mirai kara no Chousensha</game><game id="6630">Aquaria</game><game id="7743">Metal Slug: 2nd Mission</game><game id="2664">Phantom 2040</game><game id="17825">Ninja Gaiden: Shadow</game><game id="26706">Shadow Complex</game><game id="4778">Kid Icarus: Of Myths and Monsters</game><game id="35901">Aliens: Infestation</game><game id="37673">Guacamelee!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1810915-box_metroid2.png</image></root>