<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5722</id><name>Counter-Strike: Condition Zero</name><description>OverviewCounter-Strike: Condition Zero is a modern-military first-person shooter developed by Valve (in collaboration with Rogue, Gearbox, Ritual, and Turtle Rock) and published for the PC by Valve (on Steam) and Sierra (on retail) on March 23, 2004. An update to Half-Life: Counter-Strike, Counter-Strike: Condition Zero features updated graphics, new artificial intelligence, and two unique single-player campaigns (one based on the multiplayer game mode, known as Tour of Duty, and one completely separate expansion, known as Counter-Strike: Condition Zero - Deleted Scenes).DevelopmentThe game is known for spanning through four development teams in the four-year development period between 2000 and 2004. Rogue was originally hired to create a single-player version of the original game. After the producer left during development, Valve took it from their hands and gave its current state to Gearbox (the developer of the expansion packs to Half-Life). As Gearbox overhauled the graphics, added bot AI, and created a single-player mode (in which players progress through matches as a counter-terrorist against AI opponents, unlocking maps and more efficient teammates by performing certain actions), they missed their development deadline and production of the game was given to Ritual.As Gearbox used their work to develop the Xbox version of the original Counter-Strike, Ritual completely re-made the game into an original 20-level single-player campaign (with a secondary multiplayer mode). After review copies of the completed game came back with mediocre results, Valve retracted the completion status and Ritual's share in the development as dropped. New production of the game was then given to Turtle Rock, who finished the game with an updated Gearbox version (including new AI) while including the single-player campaign of the Ritual version as an expansion (known as Counter-Strike: Condition Zero - Deleted Scenes).Tour of DutyThe main single-player campaign of Counter-Strike: Condition Zero is the Tour of Duty mode, in which players playUnlike the other Counter Strike games, Condition Zero offers a single player mode which is basically the same as the multiplayer version of the game only your teammates and the opposing team are replaced with AI or Bots. The player battles the Bots to unlock different modes and more intelligent AI. You may also choose your teammates from a menu.The Campaign is split into 6 parts named "Tours of Duty" and each one of these parts include 3 maps. You must beat each map to progress to another "Tour of Duty", To beat one map you must be ahead of the Terrorists by 2 wins and You must have atleast won 3 rounds. You must also complete special challenges which involve tasks like getting a specific amount of kills with a certain weapon or winning around by defusing the bomb. If you haven't completed these challenges in your match, It will go on until you have.Tour of Duty BotsAlliesPlayers must choose their own counter-terrorist allies in Tour of Duty. The player is considered the "commander" of the squad.Gus (1 point) - Bad skill. Moderately cooperative. Very aggressive. Prefers using the Tactical Machine Pistol.EnemiesIn Tour of Duty, players always face teams of enemy Terrorist bots. The amount of bots (and which ones you fight) are determined by the map, the campaign difficulty, and whether the mission has been completed before. All enemies are pretty cooperative with each other, with the exception of the elite enemies.Easy enemies have 0% firing accuracy, 0.5 second reaction time, and 1.5 second aiming delay. They cannot detect footsteps at all.Weasel - Very passive. Prefers using the Scout.Lunatic - Aggressive. Prefers using the M4A1 (picked up) and the Dual Elites.Crackpot - Moderately aggressive. Prefers using the UMP.Outcast - Aggressive. Prefers using the MAC-10.Fair enemies have 25% firing accuracy, 0.4 second reaction time, and 1 second aiming delay.Madman - Aggressive. Prefers using the MAC-10.Rat - Very passive. Prefers using the MP5 Navy.Screech - Moderately aggressive. Prefers using the P90.Worm - Very passive. Prefers using the MP5 Navy.Splinter - Passive. Prefers using the Scout.Normal enemies have 50% firing accuracy, 0.4 second reaction time, and 0.7 second aiming delay.Freak - Moderately aggressive. Prefers using the AK-47.Maniac - Very aggressive. Prefers using the P90.Psycho - Passive. Prefers using the AWP.Tough enemies have 60% firing accuracy, 0.3 second reaction time, and 0.35 second aiming delay.Rebel - Moderately aggressive. Prefers using the AK-47 and Desert Eagle.Fiend - Very aggressive. Prefers using the AK-47 and Dual Elites, and will pick up the M4A1 and use it unsilenced.Vandal - Very passive. Prefers using the AK-47 and P228, and will pick up the M4A1 and use it silenced.Hard enemies have 75% firing accuracy, 0.25 second reaction time, and have no aiming delay.Razor - Passive. Prefers using the AWP and Desert Eagle.Bandit - Very passive. Prefers using the P90 and Dual Elites.Raider - Moderately aggressive. Prefers using the AK-47 and P228. Will pick up the M4A1 and use it unsilenced.Blade - Very aggressive. Prefers using the AK-47 and P228.Snake - Very aggressive. Prefers using the AK-47 and Dual Elites.Very Hard enemies have 80% firing accuracy, 0.25 second reaction time, and have no aiming delay.Nails - Passive. Prefers using the AWP and Dual Elites.Hammer - Moderately aggressive. Prefers using the M249 and P228.Crank - Very passive. Prefers using the M249 and Desert Eagle.Cutter - Moderately aggressive. Prefers using the AK-47 and Dual Elites.Fanatic - Very aggressive. Prefers using the AK-47 and P228.Expert enemies have 90% firing accuracy, 0.2 second reaction time, and have no aiming delay.Hyena - Moderately aggressive. Prefers using the P90 and Desert Eagle.Wolfhound - Very aggressive. Prefers using the M249 and Dual Elites.Panther - Very aggressive. Prefers using the AK-47 and P228.Crow - Moderately aggressive. Prefers using the AWP and Desert Eagle.Elite enemies have 100% firing accuracy, 0.2 second reaction time, and have no aiming delay.Jackal - Very cooperative. Very aggressive. Prefers using the P90 and Dual Elites.Hawk - Moderately cooperative. Moderately aggressive. Prefers using the AWP and P228.Spider - Very cooperative. Very passive. Prefers using the AK-47 and Desert Eagle.Tiger - Very uncooperative. Very aggressive. Prefers using the AK-47 and Desert Eagle.System RequirementsMinimum: 500 mhz processor, 96mb ram, 16mb video card, Windows 2000/XP, Mouse, Keyboard, Internet ConnectionRecommended: 800 mhz processor, 128mb ram, 32mb video card, Windows 2000/XP, Mouse, Keyboard, Internet Connection</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11663">Half-Life: Counter-Strike</game><game id="3874">Quake III Arena</game><game id="20676">SOCOM: U.S. Navy SEALs - Confrontation</game><game id="21218">Black Powder | Red Earth</game><game id="17729">The Orange Box</game><game id="11245">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six: Critical Hour</game><game id="2692">FBI Hostage Rescue</game><game id="8266">Tactical Ops: Assault on Terror</game><game id="24363">PaperMan</game><game id="485">Delta Force: Black Hawk Down</game><game id="4158">Bet on Soldier: Blood Sport</game><game id="24587">Cube 2: Sauerbraten</game><game id="21591">Combat Arms</game><game id="20655">Battlefield: Bad Company</game><game id="14782">Far Cry</game><game id="7334">Crossfire</game><game id="26423">Call of Duty: Black Ops</game><game id="8632">Soldier of Fortune: Payback</game><game id="32288">Sudden Attack</game><game id="1773">Global Operations</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/201/670174-front.jpg</image></root>