<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>577</id><name>Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone</name><description>OverviewHarry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone is the video game based off the best selling book and box office hit movie of the same title. What started as a novel craze and moved into every other medium, Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone is the first entry into the seven part Potter series.StoryThe Philosopher's Stone maintains the passive narrative of the novel. Harry attends classes, and earns points for Gryffindor house based on the quality of his work, while the story waits for something to happen.While the stories of video game and novel Harry Potter hit the same main points, the actual worlds differ greatly. For example, video game Gringotts seems to provide money based on the amount a person can gather from the scattered vaults while being hurdled past them at breakneck speeds and dodging intentionally placed beams of wood. Even before that, the goblins force their patrons to collect documents scattered on their waxed, slippery floor. All just to strap into the mine cart in the first place.While the game is not technically proficient, or for the most part fun, it still appeals to the younger Potter audience eager to try their hand in the Wizarding world.CollectiblesHarry Potter may choose to collect four types of Bertie Bott's All Flavor Beans. The video game Weasley twins trade them for secret phrases Harry needs to get past four portraits. Harry steals an unknown someone's hidden property, such as the Nimbus 2000, from behind these portraits.There are also 24 Famous Witches and Wizards cards to collect. They can be obtained by either finding them hidden throughout Hogwarts or will be awarded to you for completing certain tasks.</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="24375">Billy the Wizard: Rocket Broomstick Racing</game><game id="3438">MediEvil II</game><game id="2064">Back to Stone</game><game id="10281">Bully</game><game id="16741">Devil May Cry 2</game><game id="41414">UltraMan Chou Toushi Gekiden</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2285656-box_hpatss.png</image></root>