<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5782</id><name>Tiny Toon Adventures: Babs' Big Break</name><description>OverviewTiny Toon Adventures: Babs' Big Break is a platformer for the Nintendo Game Boy. Using one of three available characters, the player must traverse through four stages, culminating in a fight against Montana Max. Along the way, players can collect gems that can be used to play one of two mini-games, Montana Mash and Race, which can earn you extra lives.GameplayThe gameplay in Babs' Big Break is very similar the Mario titles: items fall from boxes when they are hit by players, enemies die when jumped on, hollow tree stumps send the character to the underground, and endless pits cause the player to die. Babs' Big Break slightly expands on this formula, however, including dynamic environments, such as traveling train cars that lose ambient light when passing under a bridge. Switches and buttons are also used to open doors and gates, specifically in the haunted woods level. The haunted woods level also features the classical piece of music In the Hall of the Mountain King.CharactersDespite the title of the game, Babs is not a playable character in Babs' Big Break. Instead, the player can chose to control either Buster Bunny, Plucky Duck, or Hamton Pig at will. Each of the characters has their own unique projectile weapon that they can use to knock over enemies:Buster - A carrot. It flies like an underhand softball toss, and can reach high places.Plucky - A pineapple. It bounces off the floor, walls, and ceiling.Hamton - A watermelon. It's tossed like a bowling ball, and rolls along the ground.Occasionally, obstacles will call for the aide of additional characters. Dizzy Devil is able to burrow under a mountain to progress to the next stage, while Furrball can sneak under city pipes to progress the player. Dizzy is also called upon during a cafeteria boss level, where the player needs to make Dizzy eat all of the chicken and goodies while avoiding spikes and other traps. Shirley the Loon also provides way to traverse a large pitfall. Her psychic abilities allow the player to cross on a floating carpet.Montana Max is naturally the game's enemy, using his disposable wealth to threaten the player in the final levels. Once in his mansion, Montana drives a large steamroller from side to side of the screen, while the player is forced to keep up with the auto scrolling level.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/19306/1397099-babs.jpg</image></root>