<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5802</id><name>Captive 2 - Liberation</name><description>OverviewLiberation was the spiritual successor to Captive. Released on Amiga 1200 and the CD32 "games console", it attemped to introduce "sand box" gameplay years ahead of its time. Set in a futuristic city of tall buildings and hover cars, but its main view is best described as "Grey".BackgroundThe player (you) were free thanks to your troop of four robots (events played out in Captive). Now, you had tasked yourself to bring down the evil corporation that had kept you captive. The main view showed a first person view of the robots environment, surrounded by icons representing each robot. The player had to guide his robots around the city searching for clues as to the whereabouts of enemies of the corporation. Again, your robots could be upgraded from armour, to weapons to "accessory" upgrades like vision enhancement.All of the buildings could be entered and searched. You could also enter the sewers, although this often meant certain death due to the strength of the enemies down there. Your robots could fight, interrogate and bride the city inhabitants in order to find these clues. To conclude a level, your party would find that levels hidden rebel.ProblemsUltimately, the games was just was too ambitious for the hardware it was running on. In stark contrast to Captive, Liberation suffered from software bugs and slow and clunky animation. I loved Captive so much that this was a massive, massive disappointment. Maybe I am being unfair, and I must confess I never did play it on the CD32.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9575">Captive</game><game id="1388">Bloodwych</game><game id="18518">Dungeon Master</game><game id="9045">Hired Guns</game><game id="15771">Dungeon Master II: The Legend of Skullkeep</game><game id="11076">Dungeon Master: Chaos Strikes Back - Expansion Set #1</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/7/73970/1288173-captive2_liberation_front.jpg</image></root>