<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5811</id><name>Baseball Stars</name><description>OverviewBaseball Stars, the 1989 release from SNK marked the first time console gamers were given almost infinite customizing in a sports sim. The game stands out on its own merit although it featured absolutely no MLB stadiums, players or teams. The game succeeded in every way through its seemless gameplay, adaquate graphics and player/team creation and customization. It is widely believed amungst many as not only the greatest baseball video game for the Nintendo Entertainment System, but maybe the greatest Baseball game of all time.GameplayBaseball Stars allows players to choose one of eight teams to play with or they can go through the process of creating a team from the ground up. The player can choose team jersey, color, logo, gender, statistics, and names. It was the first sports game to have a role playing element in which, through the use of money spending you could boost attributes of your players.Once you've chosen your team, Baseball Stars allows you to choose one of two game settings. One is Vs. play, were you square off against a friend or the computer in a single game contest. Vs. mode also allows the player to create a custom tournamant of up to 25 games in a bracket style showdown. The other is Season play, were you are entered in a full season of baseball and stats are tracked. You are able to see how your players are hitting and follow their progression.TeamsBaseball Stars featured eight teams in addition to the user created teams. The eight built-in teams are:American DreamsBrave WarriorsJapan RobinsWorld PowersGhastly MonstersLovely LadiesSNK Crushers</description><genres><genre id="34">Baseball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20835">MLB 08: The Show</game><game id="18255">The BIGS</game><game id="8283">Bases Loaded</game><game id="21659">Super Bases Loaded</game><game id="7502">Bases Loaded II: Second Season</game><game id="14136">Bases Loaded 3</game><game id="6808">Bases Loaded 4</game><game id="22596">Roger Clemens' MVP Baseball</game><game id="5992">Major League Baseball</game><game id="16272">Tecmo Baseball</game><game id="7266">Ken Griffey Jr Presents Major League Baseball</game><game id="3894">Ken Griffey Jr.'s Winning Run</game><game id="22848">MLB '98</game><game id="5259">Super Baseball 2020</game><game id="25999">Dynamite Slugger</game><game id="34331">R.B.I Baseball 4</game><game id="25267">Jikkyou Powerful Pro Yakyuu 3</game><game id="41423">Shin Moero!! Pro Yakyuu</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2366255-nes_baseballstars.jpg</image></root>