<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5826</id><name>Bimini Run</name><description>OverviewBimini Run is a third-person naval combat game developed by Microsmiths and published by Nuvision for the Sega Genesis on October 10, 1990. The game is set in the sun drenched tropics, a place of romance and intrigue. As expert motorboat driver and wealthy self-made adventurer  Kenji Ohara (who, according to the game's manual, likes fast cars, fast boats and fast women, but not necessarily in that order), players set out in the large, open archipelago to rescue his sister, Kim Ohara, from the evil Dr. Orca, with Kenji driving his red powerboat and his partner, Luka, manning the weaponry.GameplayThis game is played with a behind-the-back perspective of your speedboat. In each level you race to catch henchmen that are responsible for the kidnapping of Kenji’s sister. You also have access to an overhead map that will allow you to negotiate the waters and help you keep a close eye on the enemy’s distance from your boat. If the henchmen get to far away from your boat you will have to start the level over.You also need to avoid obstacles such as sailboats, rocks, islands, reefs and sand bars while trying to catch Dr. Orca’s evil henchmen. The game takes place of six chapters of gameplay.With limited fuel for your speedboat you will need to catch the enemy as fast as possible in order to complete each chapter. You will also need to watch out for enemy helicopter gunfire and even an attack from deadly sea creature. Difficulty settings could be chosen either as a normal setting or a more difficult setting. You could also adjust the amount of speedboats you had in your life reserve of three, fire or even seven. You could even alternate turns with a friend. Weapons included a bazooka, a gas gun that allows you to stun enemy boats, and a gun to shoot down enemy helicopters and boats.ReferenceAccording to Mr. Jeff Gerstmann, Bimini Run for the Genesis is the "best mission-based boating game bar none", even better than Blood Wake.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8018">Blood Wake</game><game id="15842">Hydra</game><game id="34047">Aqua Jack</game><game id="13924">Cobra Triangle</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/23093/2384846-bimini_run_cover.jpg</image></root>