<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5828</id><name>Steel Battalion</name><description>OverviewA Japanese mecha game with a twist. Here you actually control the mech, called Vertical Tank, with an actual cockpit-controller. This controller also works on the sequel, Steel Battalion: Line of Contact, and is required to play these games.ControllerThe cockpit controller.The cockpit-controller made for Steel Battalion has about 40 buttons and two control sticks. Because of the size of the controller, it was made in small quantities, making this game quite a collectors item. It has later been re-released in limited quantites in the US for the normal retail price (about 200$) The controller has everything you need to control the VT, and you must use everything, from starting it up to shutting down or ejecting in the worst case scenario.Your vehicle, the Vertical TankThe Vertical Tank, or VT, is the primary vehicle in Steel Battalion. The VTs are bipedal walking weapons-platforms, and they come in three different types. Throughout the game you unlock new generations, making them better in every way.Operating system, startup sequence and combat functions all change from generation to generation.The Light VTs are the mobile class, mostly used for hunting down fleeing enemies, or attacking bases after their main defenses are taken out. These VTs can be airdropped, making them a valuable tactical asset.The Middle VTs are the main offensive force. They are both agile, while also having decent weapons and good armor. The Heavy VTs have the best armor and firepower. But due to their weight and low mobility, they are mostly used for base defenses and the like.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19719">Chromehounds</game><game id="17675">Armored Core 4</game><game id="13759">Cyber Troopers Virtual-On Marz</game><game id="2296">Custom Robo</game><game id="15116">Armored Core 3</game><game id="4819">Cyber Troopers Virtual-On: Oratorio Tangram</game><game id="13931">MechWarrior</game><game id="9122">Front Mission Online</game><game id="15264">Krazy Ivan</game><game id="24285">Battle Rage: The Robot Wars</game><game id="25609">Chou Soujuu Mecha MG</game><game id="26830">Mobile Suit Gundam: Bonds of the Battlefield</game><game id="210">Battlecorps</game><game id="24075">Infinite Space</game><game id="4051">Phantom Crash</game><game id="7104">Gungriffon</game><game id="34412">Hawken</game><game id="7531">Shattered Steel</game><game id="27284">MechWarrior Online</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2232814-box_sb.png</image></root>