<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5960</id><name>Shrek SuperSlam</name><description>OverviewShrek SuperSlam is an action game developed by 7 Studios and Shaba Games and published by Activision for the Nintendo DS, Game Boy Advance, PC, PlayStation 2, Gamecube, and Xbox platforms.GameplayShrek Super Slam supports up to 4 players in its various arenas. Its point-oriented structure is similar to games such as Smash Bros and Playstation All Stars.The focus in Super Slam is on hitting opponents to build up a Slam meter. Once players fill their slam meter- they can perform that character's slam attack to gain points. Players receive a single point for every opponent they hit with a slam attack. Being hit by an opponent's slam makes you lose a point.There are a few ways to counter enemy slams- though the ease of pulling this off varies greatly from character to character. Along with using dodge maneuvers or the environment to make enemies waste portions of their slam meter, hitting an opponent who has a full slam bar also works towards depleting it.As the match goes on and more slams end up connecting- the various arenas in the game take structural damage. On occasion- this will actively change the level design slightly, or spawn new items and throw-able debris. While these items can easily be used to fill a slam meter from a distance, players must be wary of the game's reflection mechanic- which allows characters to immediately send a ranged attack back at its sender if they block at the moment the projectile lands. Reflected projectiles can be continuously reflected- which can result in crazy makeshift tennis matches. But each subsequent reflection further increases the speed of the projectile until it finally hits someone or is evaded.CharactersShrekFiona (human)Fiona (Ogre)DonkeyPuss In BootsGingerbread ManPrince CharmingPinocchioRed Riding HoodThe Black KnightCaptain HookRobin HoodThe Big Bad WolfCyclopsG-nomeDronkeyQuasimodoLunaHumpty DumptyStory ModeThe story mode of Shrek Super Slam is presented as a short series of bedtime stories a few of the characters provide in an attempt to lull Donkey's Dronkeys to sleep. The matchups that result from these stories include:Sheriff Gingerbread Man vs. Cowboy Puss In BootsDonkey vs Prince CharmingGingerbread Man vs G-nomeFiona (human) vs Kung Fu Master Humpty DumptyShrek and Fiona (Ogre) vs. QuasimodoPinocchio vs The Black KnightDonkey vs Captain Hook, Humpty Dumpty, and Gingerbread ManPuss In Boots vs Evil Scientist Pinocchio, Puppet Shrek, and Puppet Fiona (Ogre)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="38140">PlayStation All-Stars Battle Royale</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2284710-box_shrekss.png</image></root>