<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5964</id><name>The King of Fighters '99</name><description>Overview The King of Fighters '99 is a 2D 3-on-3 fighting game developed and published by                     SNK for the                    Neo Geo. It is the sixth installment of the                   King of Fighters series, featuring new characters, a new story arc, and a new "Striker" system. The story takes place two years after the events of                  The King of Fighters '97, where main characters                 Kyo Kusanagi and                Iori Yagami are nowhere to be seen after defeating               Orochi. A new, more secretive, King of Fighters tournament is created by a mysterious syndicate known as NESTS.  The main protagonist of the "NESTS arc" is              K', a young man who is captured by NESTS, stripped of his memory, and injected by the DNA of Kyo Kusanagi (which gives him his fire abilities). K', along with his friend,             Maxima, sets out to destroy the syndicate. Kyo and Iori are only playable as secret characters, though two clones of Kyo (based on previous installments) are playable from the start.            Goro Daimon,           Chizuru Kagura, the New Face Team,          Ryuji Yamazaki, and         Billy Kane are absent in this installment.        Takuma Sakazaki returns to the Art of Fighting team while       Kasumi Todoh returns to the Women Fighters team. Other than K' and Maxima, new characters debuting in the series include      Whip,     Jhun Hoon,    Bao, and   Li Xiangfei (from  Real Bout Fatal Fury 2: The Newcomers).Gamplay FeaturesKOF 99 introduced the gameplay feature of "strikers". When the player picks the three characters for their team, they must also choose a fourth character as a striker. With a command, the striker will appear on screen to deliver a single special attack and then immediately leave. If the opponent can hit the striker it will force them to leave without attacking. This is very similar to the assist attacks in the                                      Marvel Vs Capcom series. The striker system was also used in                                      KOF 2000 and                                      2001 before being dropped.The player has the typical power gauge that is used to perform super attacks. Introduced in this game is the ability to perform two other moves as well. "Armour Mode" will use three stocks from the power gauge. Being in Armour Mode makes the character glow yellow and boosts the power of their attacks for a limited time."Counter Mode" also uses three stocks from the power gauge. This allows the player to perform as many special moves as he or she wants before the gauge drains.The King of Fighters '99 EvolutionThe Dreamcast version of The King of Fighters '99.While the PlayStation version was a port of the Neo Geo game, the Dreamcast version was given several original additions. All the backgrounds were recreated in 3D and included a new anime intro.     Characters  Hero Team                       K'                      Maxima                                                                                                                                                                                       Benimaru Nikaido                      Shingo Yabuki     Fatal Fury Team                                                                                                                                                                                     Terry Bogard                                                                                                                                                                                    Andy Bogard                                                                                                                                                                                  Joe  Higashi                      Mai Shiranui     Art of Fighting Team                                                                                                                                                                                 Ryo  Sakazaki                                                                                                                                                                                 Robert Garcia                                                                         Yuri Sakazaki                      Takuma Sakazaki     Ikari Warriors Team                                                                                                                              Leona                                                                                                                                                                          Ralf Jones                                                                                                                                                                        Clark Steel                      WhipPsycho Soldier Team                                                                                                                                                                               Athena  Asamiya                                                                                                                                                                             Sie  Kensou                                                                                                                                                                            Chin  Gentsai                      Bao Women Fighters Team                                                                                                                         King                                   Blue Mary                                  Kasumi Todoh                      Li Xiangfei     Korea Team                                                                                                                                                                     Kim Kaphwan                                                                                                                                                                    Chang Koehan                                                                                                                                                                   Choi Bounge                      Jhun HoonOther                         Kyo Kusanagi (secret character) (two clones of Kyo based on the previous installments are playable from the start)                                        Iori Yagami (secret character)                      Krizalid (boss)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1615">Street Fighter III: 3rd Strike</game><game id="8680">Street Fighter Alpha 3 MAX</game><game id="243">Street Fighter II: The World Warrior</game><game id="11156">X-Men vs. Street Fighter</game><game id="7751">Art of Fighting Anthology</game><game id="2760">Art of Fighting</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="22362">Street Fighter II': Hyper Fighting</game><game id="21277">Ultimate Mortal Kombat</game><game id="20616">Super Street Fighter II Turbo HD Remix</game><game id="22305">Street Fighter III: 2nd Impact</game><game id="5692">Samurai Shodown</game><game id="16407">Samurai Shodown II</game><game id="2612">Marvel vs. Capcom 2: New Age of Heroes</game><game id="8605">Marvel vs. Capcom: Clash of Super Heroes</game><game id="13327">Art of Fighting 2</game><game id="20456">Street Fighter IV</game><game id="29169">The Fallen Angels</game><game id="22394">Slap Happy Rhythm Busters</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1418244-box_kof99_ng.jpg</image></root>