<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5985</id><name>Diablo</name><description>OverviewReleased in 1997 for the PC (and later the original Playstation), Diablo is a dark, gothic-fantasy game blending RPG and arcade elements to create an addictive, highly re-playable game.The original game was known for endless mouse-clicking " hack and slash" action in a single dungeon consisting of 16 levels. The dungeon is located under the town of Tristram, a sparsely populated town which consists of 6 NPC's who serve primarily as shop keepers to buy and sell adventuring equipment to the PCs and give out the occasional quest. Critics of the game will point to this lack of interaction within the game and the focus on mouse-clicking, killing things and taking their stuff as weaknesses in the game, while fans of the game will point to these same elements as the core of the game's addictive gameplay. Owners of the game could create a "spawn" version for their friends to use. The spawned version was mostly an extensive demo.Diablo was both popular and influential, spawning a number of sequels and spin-offs, including Diablo: Hellfire, a licensed add-on to the original game produced by Sierra Entertainment rather than the original development team of Blizzard North.Finally the game spawned two direct sequels: Diablo II (which saw an official expansion created by Blizzard) and Diablo III.GameplayDiablo had three character classes available for play, each with their very own character attributes, traits and specializations:Rogue -- these master archers have a slight level of magic, but are not nearly as expertise as that of the SorcererSorcerer -- this ultimate master of the magic arts is trained to use pure magic to smite foes rather than combatWarrior -- the pure melee combat warrior, he is the master of weaponryThe Sorcerer Master of magic artsDespite using a class-based system, character development was very free-form and was left largely up to the player. There were only a few elements directly tied to character class: each class had a skill available at 1st level that improved as the character gained level; the character's class determined his starting and maximum attributes; the character's class determined how many hit points and magic points were gained with each level increase; finally, a character's class determined his starting equipment. Of these, the two that had the strongest effect on gameplay were the starting and maximum attributed and the advancement of hit points and magic points upon gaining a level.The Silent RogueThe Powerful Lone WarrorAttributes in Diablo were the primary limitation on a character's abilities. A high Strength score would allow a character to wear heavy armor and melee weapons, a high Dexterity allowed a character to use devastating ranged weapons and a high magic allowed the character to learn high-level spells. Thus the Rogue class began the game with the highest Dexterity, the Sorcerer with the highest Magic and the Warrior with the highest Strength. These classes could also achieve a much higher maximum attribute in these areas, allowing them to attain the most powerful weapons suited to their character class.Still, a Warrior could concentrate on Magic and become reasonably proficient in its use, a Sorcerer could work on Strength to wear heavy armor and so forth, allowing a player a great degree of flexibility in tailoring his character to his preferred play-style. This was one of the many game elements that increased re-playability.Quest MonstersThe Butcher Emerging From his LairThe Butcher: A Demon killing the townspeople of Tristram. First (optional) boss.King Leoric: The former king of the land. Corrupted and twisted by Diablo. Now he wanders as a giant skeleton with his crown on his head.Gharbad the Weak: Offers the adventurer a magical item for mercy, then deems them unworthy.Snotspill: a Kobold that stole Ogden's sign.Zhar the Mad: Crazed sorcerer who gives the adventurer a spellbook.Warrior of Blood: Steel Lord who guards the entrance to the 14th level.Lachdanan: Blood Knight who seeks retribution which can be obtained by giving him the golden elixir.Archbishop Lazarus: a Priest who performed the ritual to tie the Lord of Terror to Leoric's son.Diablo The Lord of Terror: Demon who possessed the prince of the land. Main antagonist of the franchise.Magic ItemsDiablo also featured an extremely diverse array of magical equipment, with magic items being powered by a prefix and suffix. Since the power of each prefix and suffix was variable and they could be found in any combination, this led to a stunning variety in type and power of equipment. There were also extremely rare unique items that had individual names, a unique appearance and abilities that were not found in normal items.Since these items were generated randomly as they were dropped in the game, a player never knew what item could be in the next chest or held by the next monster. This increased both the addictive nature of the gameplay as well as the replay value. Indeed, a player could continue to play the same character, moving to a higher difficulty level with the same character, where the monsters would be more powerful but would drop items of increasing rarity.SpellsSpells are used to cast magic which is important in this game as they are frequently used throughout the game. It is not character dependant and are often found in spell books, staves and scrolls. Each class has their own unique spell as well.Column HeadColumn HeadApocalypse - All enemies in the area can be damaged.Blood Star - Fires a star at a target whilst it is slow, it's mana consumption is low too.Blood Spirit - Summons a spirit that homes in target, a very strong spell.Chain Lightning - Similar to Lightning but creates more than one bolt and homes in on the monsters.Charged Bolt - Launches several bolts on the ground, perfect for crowd control.Disarm Trap - Rogue's skill, grants the ability to see traps and disarm them.Elemental - A fire elemental in the form of a person runs forward and aims towards the nearest monster which deals splash damage.Fireball - Stronger version of fireball which creates a bigger ball of fire than firebolt and deals extra damage.Firebolt - Launches a single small ball of fire at the enemy.Fire Wall - Creates a wall of fire which damages enemies in a line.Flame Wave - Fires a flame attack in the form of a wave capable of damaging multiple enemies.Flash - Radius attack that first attacks the player in front and sides and even attacks behind the player.Golem - Summons a golem used for attacking enemies.Guardian - Summons a Hydra that shoots firebolts at enemies nearby. Perfect for detecting enemies.Healing - Grants the player healthHeal Other - Used in multiplayer, it grants health to other players.Holy Bolt - Fires a bolt as holy damage, perfect for undead monsters and Diablo.Identify - Used to identify items.Inferno - Fires a flame for a short distance.Infravison - Grants the ability to see through walls and detect enemies.Item Repair - Give the ability to repair item but also decreases the maximum durability (Warrior's Skill).Lightning - Shoots a Lightning bolt at the player's direction.Mana Shield - Upon casting this spell, all damage is taken from mana as opposed to health.Nova - Creates a ring of lightning that damages enemies within a radius.Phasing- Faster version of teleporting but it randomly moves the player on the map.Recharge Staves - Sorcerer's skill, gives the ability to recharge staves but reduces the maximum charges every time it's used.Resurrect - Used in multiplayer to bring back a dead player.Stone Curse - Destroys the enemies defense upon casting.Telekinesis - Used to interact with certain objects from a distance like opening a chest or pulling a lever.Teleport - Can teleport around the area, perfect for evading battles.Town Portal- Creates a portal to go back to town.RandomnessA final element of the game that increased replay value was the fact that the dungeon maps were randomly generated every time a player started a new game. Because of this, it was impossible for a player to have an advantage in a second or third game because he knew where quest objectives were. This required each new game's dungeon to be mapped anew (which the game assisted with through an auto-map feature), meaning the player never knew where critical quest objectives or opponents could be found.In addition to the level randomization, many other aspects of Diablo's gameplay could change from game to game:Monsters on each level of the dungeon would vary, meaning a player might face entirely different opponents, requiring different tactics and abilities to succeed.As mentioned above, the way magic items were generated meant that a player was unlikely to see the same item twice over the course of multiple games not every quest was available in every game, meaning different tasks and rewards for each instance of the world.The quests in Diablo were also handed out randomly by the NPC's throughout the town. Usually all quests could not be completed in one playthrough.These random elements made each game of Diablo feel fresh and different and led to many late nights playing the game, something players of other Blizzard games were used to as well.PortsThe PlayStation North American Box ArtIn March 1998, Electronic Arts released Diablo for the PlayStation. The PlayStation version lacked the key component of being able to go online. The work around was to allow two players the ability to play on the same screen at the same time, something the PC version lacked. However save games for Diablo were very large; a single save game could take as many 10 blocks on a PlayStation memory card.Early MORPGA final element of the game that increased its appeal was the free multiplayer component, available through Blizzard's Battle.net servers.As a multi-player game, Diablo's gameplay changed radically and resembled what we today would recognize as a Multiplayer Online RPG or MORPG. In fact, Diablo and Ultima Online could be seen as the two games that most strongly influenced the most popular online games of all time, Everquest and Blizzard's own World of Warcraft.In multi-player, players could team up and the number of players in the dungeon made creatures more powerful. Item drops were also increased based on the size of the player party. Many elements of the modern MMORPG were introduced into this environment, such as player to player economies, where rare items were bartered or bought with enormous sums of gold.Another unfortunate element of MMOs was introduced here, with players cheating to gain a competitive advantage over other players, or to get the rarest of the rare items. Blizzard's experience running Battle.net and managing both the economy as intended but also cheating was to prove invaluable in their development of World of Warcraft.InfluenceDiablo inspired a host of imitators who sought to recapture its addictive, simple gameplay. The most important of these are probably Baldur's Gate: Dark Alliance and its sequel on the PS2. Other games to follow Diablo in the Action RPG genre on consoles include Champions of Norrath and its sequel Champions: Return to Arms, which were Action RPGs set in Norrath, the world of the popular MMO Everquest.The action RPG was adapted to other genres as well. Some were extremely well-done such as the super-heroic X-Men Legends, X-Men Legends II and especially Marvel Ultimate Alliance all three set in the Marvel Comics universe.Less successful was the attempt to turn the classic Fallout RPG's into action RPG's with the Brotherhood of Steel game for the PS2.The action RPG has also returned to its PC roots with games such as Titan Quest, Fate  Torchlight, a workmanlike attempt to recapture the magic of Diablo on the PCs.Critical ReceptionDiablo was widely praised by critics, with a Metacritic average of 94. Many critics gave the game perfect or near perfect scores. Notably, Computer Gaming World, an influential game review magazine for PC games gave the game a perfect score of 100.Game review site Gamespot gave the game a 9.6 which makes it one of the highest-rated computer games in the history of the site.SoundtrackCover ArtThe soundtrack for Diablo was composed by Matt Uelmen.Track No.Song TitleRunning Time01Intro01.3402Into Town04.4903Dungeon04.2504Catacombs05.5105Caves04.5906Hell04.1507The Nest04.0008The Crypt02.35System RequirementsPCWindows 95 or better60 MHz Pentium or better8 MB RAM (16 MB for multiplayer)SVGA compatible graphics card (640 x 480 maximum)2X CD-ROM driveMacPower Macintosh or compatible (Diablo is not compatible with Mac OS X Lion)8 MB RAM with virtual memorySystem 7.5 or higher2X CD-ROM drive</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13091">Baldur's Gate: Dark Alliance</game><game id="7386">Divine Divinity</game><game id="5153">Sacred</game><game id="633">Avencast: Rise of the Mage</game><game id="1714">Throne of Darkness</game><game id="20531">Kingdom Under Fire: Circle of Doom</game><game id="3958">Nox</game><game id="20499">Too Human</game><game id="9989">Hellgate: London</game><game id="8736">Blood Omen: Legacy of Kain</game><game id="21229">Mythos</game><game id="11521">Record of Lodoss War</game><game id="5767">Ultima Online</game><game id="13217">Champions of Norrath</game><game id="2890">Arkadian Warriors</game><game id="4038">Castle of the Winds</game><game id="3156">Champions: Return to Arms</game><game id="8638">Titan Quest</game><game id="7527">Marvel Ultimate Alliance</game><game id="21733">DeathSpank</game><game id="2059">Dungeon Siege</game><game id="13293">Dungeon Siege: Legends of Aranna</game><game id="11620">Dungeon Siege: Throne of Agony</game><game id="9745">Dungeon Siege II: Broken World</game><game id="20612">Space Siege</game><game id="15672">Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles</game><game id="22309">Rogue</game><game id="16689">Brave Soul</game><game id="11704">Fallout</game><game id="7308">The Summoning</game><game id="22892">Shadow Tower</game><game id="22927">Dragonfable</game><game id="23073">The Bibleman</game><game id="13114">Mage Knight: Apocalypse</game><game id="19848">Summoner</game><game id="11806">Silverfall</game><game id="14565">Dungeon Lords</game><game id="19703">Darkstone</game><game id="21334">The Lord of the Rings: The Two Towers</game><game id="2025">Revenant</game><game id="11345">Depths of Peril</game><game id="18067">Alien Earth</game><game id="3018">Meat Puppet</game><game id="10935">Darklands</game><game id="20579">Shining Force EXA</game><game id="8102">The Bard's Tale</game><game id="23868">2Moons</game><game id="21544">Hinterland</game><game id="24116">Kivi's Underworld</game><game id="4673">Fate</game><game id="1206">Gauntlet 4</game><game id="24408">Metal Black: Alternative</game><game id="24801">Angels Online</game><game id="3819">Zombie Shooter</game><game id="25290">Fate:  Undiscovered Realms</game><game id="10846">Avatar: The Last Airbender</game><game id="10473">The Witcher</game><game id="25983">Torchlight</game><game id="27654">Underworlds</game><game id="1143">Alien Syndrome</game><game id="9789">Beyond Divinity</game><game id="8428">Arcus Odyssey</game><game id="22850">Myth of Soma</game><game id="29421">Greed Black Border</game><game id="29823">Grim Dawn</game><game id="21633">Soma Bringer</game><game id="16603">Restricted Area</game><game id="7584">Etrom: The Astral Essence</game><game id="3634">Redmoon</game><game id="31134">Hazen: The Dark Whispers</game><game id="28868">Dungeon Hunter</game><game id="32255">Torchlight II</game><game id="32378">Dimensity</game><game id="32416">DeathSpank: Thongs of Virtue</game><game id="32085">Bastion</game><game id="33311">Epic Dungeon</game><game id="28914">Magicka</game><game id="12">Blade &amp; Sword</game><game id="32130">Darkspore</game><game id="32562">Path of Exile</game><game id="34531">Mission Europa</game><game id="30545">Pets Vs. Monsters</game><game id="33494">Dungeons &amp; Dragons Daggerdale</game><game id="35449">The Baconing</game><game id="35468">Crimson Alliance</game><game id="37313">Hack, Slash, Loot</game><game id="36857">Krater</game><game id="35509">Silent Hill: Book of Memories</game><game id="31832">Konung III: Ties of the Dynasty</game><game id="5776">Legend of the North: Konung</game><game id="3549">Konung 2: Blood of Titans</game><game id="38446">Divinity: Original Sin</game><game id="6585">NightStone</game><game id="20901">Sacred 2: Fallen Angel</game><game id="20718">Dungeon Siege III</game><game id="1727">Dungeon Siege II</game><game id="39513">Sacred 3</game><game id="37209">R.A.W.: Realms of Ancient War</game><game id="13762">Titan Quest: Immortal Throne</game><game id="42003">Chasm</game><game id="41416">The Mighty Quest for Epic Loot</game><game id="8590">Dawn of Magic</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2243596-diablo.jpg</image></root>