<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6007</id><name>Knife Edge: Nose Gunner</name><description>Knife Edge: Nose Gunner is a rail shooter  for the Nintendo 64 released by  made by Kemco in the U.S. in 1998.         The game describes a "New Frontier Plan" announced by the United States at the end of the 20th century; an ambitious program to enable humans to migrate to Mars. The United States Congress approved an enormous budget for the National Aeronautics and Space Agency to initiate development of this program. Other technologically-advanced countries also participated in the plan. Through an unprecedented cooperative effort, the New Frontier Plan members had built an orbiting space station; life on Mars would soon be a reality. This plan for developing Mars was officially named the "Mars Frontier Project" (MFP). At the end of the 21st century, a domed structure called the "Plant" was built on Martian soil, and colonization finally began. The first wave of colonists applied themselves to terraforming the planet for human survival; adjusting the atmosphere and securing water resources. Half a century passed. On Mars, the air was breathable, and oceans formed as the southern ice caps continued to melt. Trees and shrubs gradually flourished; Mars was evolving from a planet of red dust into a lush, green environment. At the beginning of the fifth emigration wave, MFP officials received an alarming report from the Martian colonists; "Unknown lifeforms were appearing near one of the colonies." Upon receiving the reports, key government officials on Earth were alarmed. To protect the colonists, the United Nations established a military relay station on the Martian moon Phobos and built a military post on Mars itself. This was the opportunity that restless armed forces worldwide had been awaiting. One day troops patrolling an undeveloped part of Mars discovered ancient ruins with what appeared to be signs of alien life. A reconnaissance unit was immediately dispatched; they reported that the ruins were of a civilization destroyed around the 11th century, Earth time. One theory was that the restored atmosphere had awakened the previously dormant Martian creatures, who had been sighted in the area in the past. Soon after this the trouble began. First, communications from one of the other colonies was suddenly cut off. Then, one after another, each of the other colonies as well as the military post lost all communication channels. An investigative party could leave immediately from Earth but would require several days to reach Mars. The United Nations therefore ordered a test squadron for a new type of experimental assault aircraft, stationed on Phobos, to investigate and eliminate the disturbances on Mars. Soon after the squadron was airborne, transfer station monitors received the final communication from the military post on Mars: “Mayday! Mayday! What is that?! It’s crawling on the surface… It’s attacking!! Mayday, mayday!”</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/10831/468601-197742_27920_front.jpg</image></root>