<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6074</id><name>Day of Defeat</name><description>OverviewDay of Defeat was the third mod-turned-into-game from Valve after Team Fortress Classic and Counter-Strike. It is considered one of the World War II greats along with its contemporaries Battlefield 1942 and Medal of Honor Allied Assault. Day of Defeat was rated as one of the top 10 most played Half-Life modifications by GameSpy as of 2008. The game was so popular in fact that it was remade on the Source engine and was released as Day of Defeat: Source in 2005.HistoryBeginnings As a ModA Merging of IdeasAfter the release of Half-Life in late 1998 a large modding scene started to develop around Valve's game thanks in part to a bonus CD which included the "Worldcraft" level editing program. In the spring of 1999 Valve released Team Fortress Classic as a precursor to what was then the thought-to-be-upcoming Team Fortress 2. It would inspire modders even further to develop incredible maps and models.It was around this time in the spring of 1999 that John Shull (known as Fuzz to the DoD community) would start working as a map maker for a new Half-Life mod named World War Three. When the other two members of the WW3 team decided to focus on their studies and give up the mod they gave everything they currently had to Shull. Shull brought Jon Kaczmarski (Pr0fit) on board to continue work on the codebase.Simultaneous with these developments there was another modder named Little Squirrel who had begun work on a World War II mod named Day of Defeat. Squirrel was merely a coder and did not have any map makers or artists. This is the summer of 1999 and two men named Minh Le and Jess Cliffe are releasing the first beta of a small mod named Counter-Strike. Their instantaneous success inspires many modders. Shull, recognising that he needs a more limited scope and a full time coder, and Squirrel realising he needs map makers and artists, decide to merge World War Three and Day of Defeat into one mod.Alpha and BetaClass selection during alphaThe Day of Defeat team was picking up steam rapidly and added several new members to prepare their alpha product; Agent (models, animations), Thunder Weenie and Wheels (historians and sound), Kamikaze (textures and maps), and Axis (code). Axis and Thunder Weenie would see the project through all the way to the Valve days. Alphas 1, 2, and 3 were privately tested in early 2000.The general public was first able to get their hands on Day of Defeat with Alpha 4, released on Apr. 8, 2000. The alphas only had four classes available, all with different running speeds; Support, Sergeant, Sniper, and Rifleman. There were only a few maps available and most of the art was temporary. Alpha 6 was the next public release on Sep. 27, 2000. It would see bug updates and tweaks through three more versions ending with Alpha 6.8 on Nov. 6, 2000.The team worked hard on refining the alpha and getting a solid grouping of maps together for the first beta release on Jan. 12, 2001. Iconic maps such as dod_caen, dod_omaha, and dod_snowtown made their debut in Beta 1. There were ten maps now in all and Day of Defeat had quickly started to gain popularity as a significant mod. Several team members left to focus on college, but the core group actually grew slowly with the additions of Waldo (who would eventually take over), Mugs, and Das.Beta 1 had several iterations through the rest of 2001, but Beta 2.0 was where the modern Day of Defeat started to come to fruition. Beta 2 was released to the public on Feb. 6, 2002. It did away with the variable run speeds and added several new classes. New sniper rifles, machine guns, weapon sway, and recoil were also first introduced here. Most of the well known Day of Defeat maps made their first appearance in Beta 2 or 2.1 (May, 2002), including; dod_avalanche, dod_anzio, dod_overlord, dod_thunder, and dod_zafod.Beta 3.1In March of 2002, Valve unveiled Steam which was meant to be exclusively a digital distribution platform. Half-Life mods would continue to use WON, for the time being. Beta 3 was released on Jul. 11, 2002 and would be the final series of beta for the Day of Defeat team. It finalised a lot of the class structures, added para_ maps, and introduced famous maps such as para_glider and para_kraftstoff. Beta 3.1 would be the final release from the mod team as amateurs on Aug. 8, 2002.Hired by Valve and Moved to SteamPicked UpFrom late 2002 to summer 2003 the remaining mod team would be hired by Valve to create a retail version of Day of Defeat, much as Valve had previously done with Team Fortress and Counter-Strike. The mod was still free to people who owned Half-Life and moved to version 1.0 on May 1, 2003. A boxed copy of Day of Defeat hit store shelves on May 6, 2003, distributed by Sierra (Activision-Vivendi). This release saw an overhaul of the graphics to be more on par with a full retail game and a stronger set of maps. The community for Day of Defeat grew exponentially during this period.Steam and the End of DevelopmentRetail DoDThe much awaited version 1.1 caused some outrage when it was announced that Valve would not be releasing a WON-based version of 1.1, but only a Steam version. At the time Steam (in beta) was very unstable and not liked by many gamers. It was seen as a slight against Day of Defeat, and eventually Counter-Strike as well (for version 1.6). Steam improved, though, and after an initially rocky start, the community embraced 1.1 on Steam and abandoned the old WON servers of 1.0.Day of Defeat would see two final releases, 1.2 and 1.3 finishing by Jul. 7, 2004. The game had a dedicated competitive scene by now and had gained a following about a third of the size of Counter-Strike's. The remaining members of the original mod team would start work at Valve on Day of Defeat: Source (initially intended to ship with Half-Life 2 and Counter-Strike: Source). Day of Defeat would still get occasional updates along with GldSrc, but it was essentially finished at 1.3. GameplayDay of Defeat is a first-person multiplayer only shooter that takes place in the western European theatre of World War II. Players choose between two teams: Allied (American or British, depending on the map) or Axis (German, even on Italian maps) to complete a series of objectives.A round begins with two opposing teams starting simultaneously in their respective spawn areas of the map. The round ends when one of the teams complete their objectives. Players respawn when a reinforcement timer ticks down which is usually set between 10-20 seconds, but can be different depending on the server side setting.Points are awarded to each player and their respective team based on their kills and captures of the map's given objectives. If neither team achieve their objectives by the time the game clock expires the winning team will be decided based on their overall score.Game ModesConquestConquest is perhaps the most common mode of Day of Defeat. There are three to seven flags to capture on a given map. Players can capture a flag by standing near the flag for a certain amount of time. Certain flags require more than one player to capture. Flags are presented as either uncaptured (grey), Axis (red), or Allies (green). Some maps do not allow a captured flag to be recaptured by the defending team, which can be seen as more akin to rush mode in Battlefield than classical conquest.Destroy TargetPlayers destroy a target by planting a bomb on it. The bomb can be obtained from the spawn area or it can be picked up from the body of a dead team mate. To plant the bomb, the player simply has to stand within the designated bomb area. Once planted bombs cannot be defused and will detonate in a sizeable explosion. In certain maps, players may destroy targets using rocket launchers.Capture TargetThis is a variation of the conquest mode. Instead of a flag, a target can be captured. This usually includes an important military target within the context of the map.Capture ItemPlayers attempt to capture an item and return it to a designated location. For instance, on dod_jagd the allies must steal some secret documents from the axis and get them back to the allied base before the axis can destroy the British tanks. This is essentially capture the flag with historical context.ClassesRiflemanA medium to long range class with incredible stopping power, but little close quarters defense.American: M1 Garand, two Mk 2 grenades, M1911, knifeBritish: Lee-Enfield, two Mills bombs, Webley Mk IV, knifeGerman: Kar98k, two stielhandgranates, Luger, spade / knifeStaff SergeantA medium range class with fast firing semi-automatic weapons.American: M1 Carbine, two Mk 2 grenades, M1911, knifeBritish: N/AGerman: K43, two stielhandgranates, Luger, spade / knifeMaster SergeantA close to medium range class with very fast firing rates from SMGs.American: M1 Thompson, Mk 2 grenade, M1911, knifeBritish: Sten, Mills bomb, Webley Mk IV, knifeGerman: MP40, stielhandgranate, Luger, spade / knifeSergeantAn American-only class with the famous grease-gun. Good at close range and CQB.American: M3, Mk 2 grenade, M1911, knifeBritish: N/AGerman: N/ASniperThe long range class with a scoped rifle. Very slow rate of fire, but almost always one hit kill.American: M1903, M1911, M1918 trench knifeBritish: Lee-Enfield with scope, Webley Mk IV, knifeGerman: Kar98k with scope, Luger, spade / knifeSupport InfantryA medium range class with extraordinary force, but high recoil and reload times.American: BAR, Mk 2 grenade, M1911, knifeBritish: Bren, Mills bomb, Webley Mk IV, knifeGerman: MP44, stielhandgranate, Luger, spade / knifeMG34-SchützeA German-only class with a slightly lighter machinegun than the dedicated class.American: N/ABritish: N/AGerman: MG34, Luger, spade / knifeMachine GunnerA tactical class tasked with shutting down enemy advances and providing suppressing fire.American: M1919, M1911, knifeBritish: N/AGerman: MG42, Luger, spade / knifeFG42-ZweibeinA German-only class restricted to paratrooper maps. Medium range power.American: N/ABritish: N/AGerman: FG42, stielhandgranate, Luger, knifeFG42-ZielfernrohrA German-only class restricted to paratrooper maps. Medium to long range power.American: N/ABritish: N/AGerman: FG42 with scope, stielhandgranate, Luger, knifeBazookaA very situational class which can take down some objectives with its primary.American: Bazooka, M1911, knifeBritish: PIAT, Webley Mk IV, knifeGerman: Panzerschreck, Luger, spade / knifeMapsAnzioAnzio is one of the most played maps in Day of Defeat. It features a beachhead and urban environments.Allied Objectives: Capture the 5 flag pointsAxis Objectives:Capture the 5 flag pointsAvalancheAvalanche is usually considered the de_dust of Day of Defeat. It's easily the most played map and is virtually synonymous with Day of Defeat to most people.Allied Objectives:Capture the 5 flag pointsAxis Objectives:Capture the 5 flag pointsCaenCaen was one of the first maps introduced during the alpha of Day of Defeat. It features heavy fighting in a long range city environment.Allied Objectives:Capture the 5 flag pointsAxis Objectives:Capture the 5 flag pointsCharlieOriginally called Overlord during the alpha and beta stages, Charlie is the ultimate D-Day map. It shows the allied assault on the beaches at Normandy.Allied Objectives:Destroy the shingle to move up the beachDestroy the two 88 'flak' gunsDestroy the Axis radio towerDestroy the artillery bunkerAxis Objectives:Defend the beachOnce the beach defenses are breached, fall back and defendChemilleOne of the less popular maps, Chemille is mostly made up of close range fighting in a destroyed French city.Allied Objectives:Capture the 4 flag pointsAxis Objectives:Capture the 4 flag pointsDonnerDonner was originally called Thunder during the beta. It was redone to have more sunlight. It's a player favourite and has some of the most intense street fighting.Allied Objectives:Capture the 5 flag pointsAxis Objectives:Capture the 5 flag pointsEscapeOne of the most unique maps, Escape features opposing objectives of destruction. The Axis artillery can actually rain down upon the Allied spawn in Escape, making their advance dangerous.Allied Objectives:Destroy the two Axis Nebelwerfers with satchel chargesAxis Objectives:Destroy the bridge with TNTFlashA small farming town is taken over during the map Flash. It's likely the smallest map and has nothing but a linear march with few side-paths.Allied Objectives:Capture the 5 flag pointsAxis Objectives:Capture the 5 flag pointsFlugplatzAnother very unique map, Flugplatz takes place in an Axis airfield. This was originally a para_ map which means the German players here can use fallschirmjäger weapons like the FG42.Allied Objectives:Capture the 6 flag pointsAxis Objectives:Capture the 6 flag pointsForestForest is a map which encourages slow advances and sniping. There are plenty of places to hide in the forest and the trench warfare encourages defending.Allied Objectives:Capture the 4 trenchesAxis ObjectivesCapture the 4 trenchesGliderGlider was the first para_ map for the Day of Defeat beta. It was changed to an objective map for full retail. Fun fact; Nick Taylor was once murdered so many times during a clan match in the connecting hallways that FuzzDad (creator of dod_glider) added a ladder to the spawn area just for him.Allied Objectives:Destroy the '88' flak cannonDestroy the "Freya" Radar setDestroy the Radio room inside the castleCapture the German forward supply houseCapture the German bunkerAxis Objectives:Clear the area of Allied paratroopersJagdJagd is a map with seemingly two different modes active. For the British, it's a capture item map, while for the Germans it is a destroy target map. Because of this, it can be frantic and engaging.Allied Objectives:Recover and return the plans from the downed gliderDefend the Cromwell tanksAxis Objectives:Stop the British from recovering the battle plansDestroy both British Cromwell tanksKaltA very basic map, similar to Flash. Kalt is a W shaped map with mostly-linear points to capture. The main strategy happens around the middle point on a bridge.Allied Objectives:Capture the 5 flag pointsAxis Objectives:Capture the 5 flag pointsKraftstoffAnother old para_ map means Kraftstoff is dominated by Germans with FG42s. It's a basic objective map in a large burnt city.Allied Objectives:Defend the Fuel TruckDefend the Fuel DumpAxis Objectives:Capture the Fuel TruckCapture the Fuel DumpSwitchOne of the later additions to the game, Switch quickly gained a strong following. It's a very long map with lots of points to capture.Allied Objectives:Capture the 6 flag pointsAxis Objectives:Capture the 6 flag pointsVicenzaLots of bazookas and panzerschrecks are used on this map in which there are four separate explosive objectives. It's a large map that can be overwhelming to new players.Allied Objectives:Destroy the King Tiger with Bazookas or satchel charges.Prevent the Axis troops from destroying the two Allied jeeps.Axis Objectives:Destroy the Allied Jeeps with Panzerschrecks or satchel charges.Prevent the Allies from destroying the King Tiger tank.ZalecZalec is another snow map (like Kalt), but unlike the others has a large focus on sniping and stealth. There are numerous snipers' nests located all over the city.Allied Objectives:Capture the fountain near the clock towerDestroy the three Axis PanzersCapture the Zalec churchAxis Objectives:Defend the fountainIf the fountain is captured, fall back to the PanzersIf the tanks are destroyed, fall back to the churchSystem RequirementsPC System RequirementsMinimum: 500 mhz processor, 96mb ram, 16mb video card, Windows XPRecommended: 800 mhz processor, 128mb ram, 32mb+ video card, Windows XPMac System RequirementsMinimum: OS X Snow Leopard 10.6.3, 1GB RAM, 4GB Hard Drive Space, NVIDIA GeForce 8 or higher, ATI X1600 or higher, or Intel HD 3000 or higherLinux System RequirementsMinimum: Linux Ubuntu 12.04, Dual-core from Intel or AMD at 2.8 GHz, 1GB Memory, nVidia GeForce 8600/9600GT, ATI/AMD Radeaon HD2600/3600 (Graphic Drivers: nVidia 310, AMD 12.11), OpenGL 2.1, 4GB Hard Drive Space, OpenAL Compatible Sound Card</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7524">Call of Duty 3</game><game id="2347">Call of Duty 2</game><game id="12716">Battlefield 1942</game><game id="19181">Return to Castle Wolfenstein</game><game id="12633">Call of Duty: United Offensive</game><game id="3617">Brothers in Arms: Earned in Blood</game><game id="16752">Medal of Honor: Rising Sun</game><game id="15195">Hour of Victory</game><game id="4389">Red Orchestra: Ostfront 41-45</game><game id="25262">Battlefield 1943</game><game id="20777">Call of Duty: World at War</game><game id="9223">World War II Combat: Iwo Jima</game><game id="20980">The History Channel: Battle for the Pacific</game><game id="6026">Medal of Honor: Airborne</game><game id="9137">Brothers in Arms: Road to Hill 30</game><game id="20834">Brothers in Arms: Hell's Highway</game><game id="33357">Darkest Hour: Europe 44-45</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/13692/923150-day_of_defeat_coverart.png</image></root>