<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>61</id><name>NBA Street V3</name><description>OverviewNBA Street V3 is the third game in EA Sports Big's style focused basketball series. It is the first game in the series to feature online play in the Playstation 2 and Xbox versions. The game also includes a "trick stick" which allows players to perform crossovers with the right analog stick. Holding any of the turbo buttons while moving the trick stick allows for various moves. The more turbo buttons held down, the harder the trick the baller will try to perform. DJ Bobbito Garcia returns as the game's announcer.Gamebreakers also received a major update from the previous games. When a gamebreaker is used inside the 3 point line, the player enters into a dunk mode almost identical to the system used in dunk contests. The player can use the trick stick to do mid-air tricks before finishing the gamebreaker or they can pass it to another baller who can continue the gamebreaker. Doing more tricks before finishing the gamebreaker translates into more points added to the player's score and subtracted from the opponents. If a player intiates a gamebreaker outside the 3 point line, the selected baller will shoot the ball for a minimum amount of points added and subtracted.Dunk ContestsDuring dunk contests, players can place obstacles in front of the rim(such as tables or even refrigerators), or bounce the ball off the backboard while moving the analog stick in mid air to perform different dunks. A panel of three judges each give scores from 1 to 10 based on the difficulty of the dunk.Creation ModesNBA Sreet V3 features many creation modes, including returning ones as well as new ones. The character creator and team creator return from previous games in the series. New to the series are the shoe creator and the court creator.SoundtrackArtistSong Title24K feat. Elephant ManMove Out (Remix)Ak'SentBounceAli VegasI Am Street (NBA Street V3 Mix)Beastie BoysAn Open Letter to NYCDe La SoulMe, Myself and IDirtbagI Ain't Going NowhereDon YuteA Lot of Girls (NBA Street V3 Mix)Duece Poppi feat. TrinaTo The Floor (NBA Street V3 Mix)Guerrila BlackTrixxHouse of PainJump Around (Pete Rock Remix)MC LyteRuffneckNittyHey BittyShellsLadies and GentlemenUnlockable CharactersOne special feature unique to the GameCube version of the game were the appearances of Mario, Luigi and Princess Peach from the Mario universe as playable characters. This is widely considered an attempt to make up for the GameCube's lack of online play.All three versions of the game have the Beastie Boys as an unlockable team.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="22">Basketball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21470">NBA 2K8</game><game id="9938">NBA Ballers</game><game id="20917">NBA 2K9</game><game id="20819">NBA Live 09</game><game id="7437">NBA Live 07</game><game id="20685">NBA Ballers: Chosen One</game><game id="7206">NBA Live 06</game><game id="21363">NBA 2K6</game><game id="9866">NBA Street Vol. 2</game><game id="7982">NBA Street</game><game id="10302">NBA Street Homecourt</game><game id="16928">NBA Jam</game><game id="14792">NBA Jam Tournament Edition</game><game id="4632">NBA Showtime: NBA on NBC</game><game id="2725">NBA Jam Extreme</game><game id="20342">NBA Jam 99</game><game id="18341">Space Jam</game><game id="27646">NBA Jam</game><game id="29664">NBA Jam</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2246602-box_nbastr3.png</image></root>