<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6221</id><name>Star Wars: Super Bombad Racing</name><description>OverviewStar Wars: Super Bombad Racing is a kart racer in the vein of the Mario Kart series of games. Super Bombad Racing was aimed at kids with an art style that featured large heads on small bodies. It was seen as average by critics and the general public. FeaturesAfter a player has finished his race in multiplayer the player's character keeps driving in an automated racing visual animation called "droid cam".Playable CharactersEach character rides a signature kart and has a special ability that only they can perform (listed below in parenthesis). Boba Fett and the Armored Assault Tank (AAT) do not have special abilities as they were unfinished characters only available through cheat codes. The Kaadu and Shaak cheats reskinned all racers to those forms and characters maintain their original special abilities.Anakin Skywalker in his pod racer (energy coupler)Obi-Wan Kenobi in the Radiant VII (force levitate)Darth Maul in a Sith Infiltrator (double bladed lightsaber is thrown)Yoda in his floating Jedi Council chair (inverts opponent's controls)Sebulba in his pod racer (throws out junk that homes in on nearest racer)Boss Nass in a Gugan Manta Ray (spits goo that obscures vison)Jar Jar Binks in a bongo (spits out his tongue)Queen Amidala in the Naboo Royal Starship (blinding light blast)Darth Vader in a TIE Advanced (unlockable) (miniature Death Star attacks the current leader)Boba Fett in Slave I (unlocked via cheat)AAT (unlocked via cheat)Kaadu (unlocked via cheat)Shaak (unlocked via cheat)Courses Courses are divided into races and combat arenasRacesCircuit One: Naboo SwampDune SeaTheed CityCircuit Two: PodraceOtoh GungaMos EspaCircuit Three: CoruscantPower StationDroid Control ShipArenasNaboo BattlefieldJedi TempleGreat Pit of CarkoonHoth Asteroid</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8422">Sonic Drift</game><game id="19071">Super Mario Kart</game><game id="6196">Crash Team Racing</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2285713-box_swsbr.png</image></root>