<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6242</id><name>Billiards</name><description>Game ModesNine BallThis game is played with object balls 1-9. Pocket the object balls from the lowest number to the highest number. The player who pockets the 9-ball wins the game.Rules:Pocket the object balls from the lowest number to the highest. Random object balls may be pocketed on the same shot that the lowest numbered ball is hit, but this only applies if the lowest numbered ball was hit first.Fouls:A foul will be called if:On each shot, the lowest numbered object ball is not hit first. The cue ball is pocketed (scratch). The cue ball is hit off the table.  Eight BallEight Ball is played with object balls 1-15. These balls are divided into two groups: 1-7 (Solids) and 9-15 (Stripes). The player who sinks all of their group and then the 8-ball is the winner. The first pocketed ball determines whether a player is shooting for either solids or stripes.Rules:The first pocketed ball determines whether a player is shooting for either solids or stripes. If the eight ball is pocketed on the break, it is returned to the table and the game continues.Fouls:A foul will be called if:On each shot, the lowest numbered object ball is not hit first. The cue ball is pocketed (scratch). The cue ball is hit off the table.  RotationThis game is played with object balls 1-15. Points received by a player correspond directly to the number on the ball. The first player to reach the set number of points wins. If all balls are pocketed, and no player achieves the set number of points, the game continues until someone does.Rules:On each shot, the cue ball must hit the lowest numbered object ball first. Other object balls may also be pocketed on the same shot, without penalty, provided the lowest numbered object ball was hit first.Fouls:A foul will be called if:On each shot, the lowest numbered object ball is not hit first. The cue ball is pocketed (scratch). The cue ball is hit off the table.  BasicBasic is played with object balls 1-15. The first player to sink eight balls wins the game.Rules:On each shot, the cue ball must hit the lowest numbered object ball first. Other object balls may also be pocketed on the same shot, without penalty, provided the lowest numbered object ball was hit first.Fouls:A foul will be called if:The cue ball is pocketed (scratch). The cue ball is hit off the table.  14.1 Continuous14.1 Continuous is played with object balls 1-15. The first player to reach the agreed upon number of points wins the game.Rules:Each player scores one point per ball, and may sink the balls in any order. If no player has reached the agreed upon score, with only one ball remaining on the table, that ball is left where it is and the remaining fourteen balls are setup again.Fouls:A foul will be called if:The cue ball is pocketed (scratch). The cue ball is hit off the table.  BowlliardBowlliard is played with object balls 1-10. The rules for Bowlliards are very similar to those of an actual bowling game.Rules:The break shot up until the first foul/scratch is considered the first frame. The second frame is the period immediately after the first foul/scratch up until the next foul/scratch.Fouls:A foul will be called if:The cue ball is pocketed (scratch). The cue ball is hit off the table. </description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="26">Billiards</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22869">Pool Hustler</game><game id="24770">Billiards Xciting</game><game id="13437">Championship Pool</game><game id="2042">Side Pocket</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2922/457362-528431_50967_front.jpg</image></root>