<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6250</id><name>Air Combat</name><description>Air Combat is a semi-realistic flight-sim/action game and was one of the earliest 3D flight games on consoles. It was developed by Namco and was released in 1995 for the Sony PlayStation. It was called Ace Combat in Japan, but the name was changed for overseas versions. GameplayAir Combat is considered an arcade style flight game since it has distorted physics and planes can carry up to 65 missiles. You embark on various missions to destroy bases and enemy aircraft, depending on how well you do on each mission you earn money afterwords. Money can be used to buy better and more advanced aircraft throughout the game and better weapon load outs. The game had a variety of missions, all focusing on destroying certain airborne or ground targets to advance the game. When a mission was complete the player was graded on their performance and given a grade from A to F (A being the best, F being total failure of the primary objective). The grades were calculated on time, Secondary and Primary Objectives completed and Damage Sustained, the level of the grade would affect the bounty the player would receive after the completion of a mission.   The players can choose any aircraft in Air Combat ranging from F-4 Phantoms to F-22 Stealth Fighter. Also, the player can select a wingman to accompany them during any mission. The players can "instruct" the wingman to perform one of these three actions:Cover MeCommence (Mission Objective)On Your Own (Fire At Will) As far as multiplayer, a two player split-screen "vs. mode" was offered in which 2 players could go head to head with each other in an all out dog fight.  AircraftF-4 Phantom IIF-14A TomcatF-117A NighthawkF/A-18C HornetMiG-31 FoxhoundTornado F.2F-15C EagleA-10A Thunderbolt IIMiG-29A FulcrumF-16C Fighting FalconYF-23A Black Widow IISu-27 FlankerRafale CJAS-39C GripenEF-2000 TyphoonF-22A Raptor   </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="24">Flight Simulator</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5368">Combat</game><game id="4589">Independence Day</game><game id="17739">AeroFighters Assault</game><game id="31133">Sidewinder 2</game><game id="4075">Wing Arms</game><game id="31457">Dogfighter</game><game id="7103">F29 Retaliator</game><game id="6055">Strike Commander</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2092582-box_acombat.png</image></root>