<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6262</id><name>Heroes Chronicles: Warlords of the Wastelands</name><description>OverviewWarlords of the Wastelands is the first of eight parts in a series of story driven campaigns created by New World Computing Inc. All games in this series uses the same engine as Heroes of Might and Magic III: The Restoration of Erathia but features only a story-driven campaign and was sold at a lower price. In all of the games you control the character Tarnum that upon death is denied passage to Paradise and is charged by the gods to redeem him self as a immortal Hero.In each of the games you play as a diffrent faction, in Warlords of the Wastelands you play the Stronghold faction.StoryThis game tells the story about how Tarnum ended up as the Immortal Hero. In the beginning of the game he is nothing more than a barbarian living during an oppressive rule by the Wizard-Kings of Bracaduun. One day he happens upon a bard that tells great stories of the glorious days of the barbarians. Inspired by the old stories he sets out the restore the barbarians to be the faction of the old times. This means freeing them self from the Wizard-Kings of Bracaduun. At first the wizards passes him of as nothing more then a mere rebel but he grows more dangerous and brutal they start taking him more serious.During his campaign to restore the great barbarian race he tries to rekindle the bard profession to prevent the stories of his people to become lost. But along side this he also becomes more cruel and in a blind rage his army ends up killing his long lost sister that was taken by the wizard. After a while his army starts fearing him more and some people start deserting his army, concerned that he might have a bad seed among his advisors he poisons all of them and takes responsibility for the entire army. At this point Tarnum and his army have pushed the Wizards back to Castle Steelhorn, the last frontier of Bracaduun. It is before this final battle that his father comes to see him and tells him of his concern for what he has become, but sadly his father dies before Tarnum defeats the Wizards by capturing Steelhorn.A few years after the fall of the wizards a new kingdom is born, know as Erathia, their leader is a Knight by the name of Rion Gryphonheart. Rion Gryphonheart faces the terrible barbarian leader Tarnum in battle and kills Tarnum. Upon his death his soul is suppose to enter paradise, but while in the Hall of Judgement he is deemed unworthy by the Ancestors. They send him back to the world to redeem himself as a Immortal.This is were the story of Tarnum continues in the next chapter in the Heroes Chronicles series Heroes Chronicles: Conquest of the Underworld</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/81088/2169114-heroes_chronicles_warlords_of_the_wasteland_s0.jpg</image></root>