<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6300</id><name>Hot Shots Golf Fore!</name><description>OverviewHot Shots Golf Fore! is the second Hot Shots Golf game released on the PS2. Developed by Clap Handz, the game improves on previous games in the series with more realistic physics, better graphics, more golfers and caddies. The number of courses to play on increased from six to fifteen, ten of those all new while the other five are favorites from the previous Hot Shots Golf games. Hot Shots Golf Fore! is the first game in its franchise to have online multiplayer, where up to 50 players can compete against each other.Game ModesOffline ModesSingle PlayerTournament: The player competes in an 18-hour stroke game tournament to earn the highest score against the competition. At the end of the round, the player earns points they can use at the shop to buy various items.Vs Mode: The player battles against a CPU-controller golfer in a nine-hole match rules golf match. If the player defeats the character, that character is unlocked.Mini-Game: The player plays in either a nine-hole par-three course or a nine-hole mini-golf course (putting only).Training: The player practices on any hole from a course where they are able to change the ground lie, wind speed, or retake the shot after the initial shot has been taken.Item Shop: A shop where various items can be purchased, such as special golf clubs and balls, courses, and other items.Multi-PlayerStroke: Two-to-four players can compete in a stroke round of golf.Match Play: Two golfers compete in a one-on-one match rules round of golf.Mini Games: Two-to-four players plays in either a nine-hole par-three course or a nine-hole mini-golf course (putting only).Online ModesThere are two online modes: Head-to-Head and Real Time Tournament. Only the North American and European versions of the game had online play while the Japanese did not. Head-to-head is a match between two players online playing either stroke or match rules. Real time tournament is a tournament where a number of people play a stroke round of golf. A maximum of fifty players can compete in one real time tournament at the same time.The servers for the North American online play was shut down on June 30, 2008.GameplayThree-Click SystemThe Hot Shots Golf Fore! continues the "three-click system" golf swing that has been used in previous games in the franchise. The first click initiates the system by moving the white bar leftward along the gauge. The second click marks the white bar to determine the power of the shot. The farther left the mark is on the gauge, the harder the shot. The white bar then moves back right to the right side of the gauge. The last click determines the accuracy of the shot. The closer the white bar is back to it's origin spot, the more likely the shot will go toward the player's shot destination.Special ShotsPower Shot: Increases the power (distance) of the shot.Blue Power Shot: This shot can only be used with the 1W club, where it dramatically increases the shot at the expense of the shot's accuracy.Backspin: The ball spins back once it lands on the surface.Topspin: The ball spins forward once it lands on the surface.Curve Shot: The ball's trajectory starts far left or far right, then curves the other way mid-flight.Special Clubs and BallsClubsStandardBeginnerBig AirPin ShotTurbo SpinInfinity100t HammerEverybody'sBallsStandardBeginnersBig AirPin HoleTurbo SpinInfinitySidespinStraightCharactersHot Shots Golf Fore! features a mixture of new golfers, golfers from the franchise's previous games, and includes Ratchet, Clank, Jak, and Daxter from their respective franchises.Playable GolfersEach golfer is rated E (lowest grade) to S (highest grade) in power, control, impact, and spin, as well if a golfer excels or is mediocre on a particular shot or ground lie.PhoebeMikeEmmaSamMisakiBradChaosRegisMayaFalconReneeZMelAllanTiffanyKamalaToniT-BoneLinLouiseZeusHubertRatchetJakCaddiesCaddies serve to assist the player on the course, as well as portray their unique behavior after the result of the shot.AmyBerthaKaylaGregSimonSophieMochiClankDaxterCharacter LoyaltyThe game rewards the player who frequently uses a golfer with increased power shots and additional costumes.Golf CoursesHot Shots Golf Fore! features fifteen courses to play: twelve eighteen-hole courses, a special par-three nine-hole course, and two nine-hole mini-golf courses. A few eighteen-hole courses are available to play at the start, the rest will have to be unlocked by gaining enough experience points.Eighteen-Hole CoursesMt. Sakura C.C.Aloha Beach ResortWestern Valley C.C.Bagpipe ClassicUnited Forest G.C.Northern Fox C.C.Day Dream G.C.Wild Green C.C.Silk Road ClassicBlue Lagoon C.C.Fujizakura C.C.Kawana Hotel G.C.Mini-Game CoursesSamurai Golf Club: A special golf course where all nine holes are par-threes (short length).Mini-Golf 1 (Putting only)Mini-Golf 2 (Putting only): This course is initially locked, but can be purchased at the item shop once the player reaches a particular golf rank.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="28">Golf</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20811">We Love Golf!</game><game id="7498">Outlaw Golf</game><game id="21364">Golf: Tee It Up!</game><game id="10856">Tee Off</game><game id="2573">Tiger Woods PGA Tour 2001</game><game id="2302">PGA Tour Golf: Tournament Course Disk</game><game id="5493">Tiger Woods PGA Tour 2000</game><game id="7964">Tiger Woods PGA Tour 2005</game><game id="697">PGA European Tour</game><game id="1760">PGA Tour 96</game><game id="14247">PGA Tour Golf III</game><game id="6957">Outlaw Golf 2</game><game id="9316">Kirby's Dream Course</game><game id="22203">Super Swing Golf</game><game id="33730">Fable: Coin Golf</game><game id="37624">@Field</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2222514-box_hsgf.png</image></root>