<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6315</id><name>Constructor</name><description>OverviewThis is a building game with a twist. You have a overhead view of an empty city, with only your HQ (and the HQ of your opponents, if any) and a city council. Your task is to build construction facilities in order to create wood, concrete, bricks and metal so that you can build houses for rent. These houses you can rent out to tenants, thus creating an income. These tenants come in several different "levels", which will only live in the appropriate level of housing. They will also be your main source of challenge, as they complain about a lot of things.A typical street in ConstructorIf you play with one or more opponents, you might want to build so-called Undesirables. These are buildings which house one or several persons used for making things difficult for your opponents. Like the Hippie, which can picket a resource building, halting it's production. Or the Psycho hanging out at the biker bar, which can scare away workers with his chainsaw and hockey-mask.You can also build hospitals, schools etc which helps you in the game, as well as a Mob HQ. This give you access to gangsters.But for the gangsters to be useful, you need Mob Favors. This is one of the things your tenants can produce instead of rent. Your tenants are also your source of new tenants, and workers.The game has several modes of play, with different objectives you need to achieve in order to win. It also has a Build, Build, Build mode, which is a endless game of building, where you can simply try to make the perfect town.UndesirablesOne of the funniest aspects of Constructor is the Undesirables. Coming in a variety of flavors, you can use them for just about everything. Everything bad that is. Here is a list, with some of their various uses.HippiesCan be used to picket buildings, squat in empty houses and have street-parties.ThievesDoes exactly what you would think. Can steal anything from resources to a Gangster's weapon.Mr. Fixit Can "fix" an enemies house. Plumbing, electrical work and gas leaks are his domain.ThugsWhat do you want your Thugs to do? A group of people that like to party. Usually in houses of the enemies tenants of course.PsychosChainsaw-wielding, hockey-mask wearing biker which can destroy fences, or just scare away workers.GhostsCan render people invisible, possess someone, or create a (rather harmless) army of zombies. Good for distracting the police.ClownsA pyromaniac, you can send him to houses where Mr. Fixit has fixed the gas oven, and make him play with matches. He can also distract guard-dogs, and bore away the ghost.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10733">SimCity 3000</game><game id="2081">The Settlers II</game><game id="17620">Dungeon Keeper</game><game id="12188">Theme Hospital</game><game id="21864">Overlord</game><game id="2236">RollerCoaster Tycoon</game><game id="6161">Serf City: Life is Feudal</game><game id="21384">The Political Machine 2008</game><game id="23317">Overlord II</game><game id="24458">Tropico 3</game><game id="15960">Evil Genius</game><game id="18461">Gangsters: Organized Crime</game><game id="19042">Dungeon Keeper: The Deeper Dungeons</game><game id="31818">Streetwars: Constructor Underworld</game><game id="32326">Tropico 4</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9408/725319-6727_boxshot_constructor.jpg</image></root>