<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6358</id><name>Mega Man Network Transmission</name><description>OverviewMega Man Network Transmission is a  Mega Man Battle Network spinoff. Unlike the rest of the MMBN series,  Rockman EXE WS aside, Network Transmission is a 2D platformer akin to the  Classic Mega Man games. However, it incorporates many of Battle Network's elements, including Battle Chips, Subchips, and MegaBuster Power-Ups.The game is an  interquel, taking place between the first and second Battle Network games. It features Japanese voice acting, which is left intact in the game's international releases.GameplayIn Network Transmission, players take control of  MegaMan.EXE. MegaMan, with the help of his Operator  Lan Hikari, must navigate "Cyberworld" while fending off Viruses and defeating malicious  NetNavis. Unlike the Battle Network RPGs, the player never takes direct control of Lan; in fact, the "real world" is only used to save the game, access  Higsby's store and select the stage that MegaMan will enter.Basic ActionsLike Classic Mega Man, MegaMan.EXE can run, jump, slide, fire his MegaBuster arm cannon and, after a certain powerup, charge the Buster to create a stronger shot. The amount of punishment that MegaMan can take is determined by his HP, which can be restored with health pick-ups and extended with HP Memory power-ups. MegaMan is destroyed if he has no HP, falls through the bottom of the stage, or touches a massively-damaging obstacle (like spikes or lava). MegaMan will be permanently deleted if he is destroyed with no "Backups" remaining, and the player will lose any unsaved progress.BattleChipsAlthough the MegaBuster is MegaMan's trademark weapon, it is much weaker in Network Transmission and, in its initial state, requires dozens of shots to defeat a virus. However, BattleChips are much more powerful. These card-like weapons allow MegaMan to access a variety of weapons, barriers and other miscellaneous powers. Lan can carry 20 unique chips at a time in his Folder. Extra BattleChips are randomly dropped from viruses, and can also be bought at Higsby's store.As soon as the stage starts (or whenever MegaMan is rebooted from a deletion), the Custom Screen appears. This allows the player to choose up to five BattleChips to send to MegaMan. Once MegaMan has received the chip data, the player must wait for the Custom Gauge (located at the top of the screen) to refill before he or she can reopen the Custom Screen. If the player does not load MegaMan with five chips, they will gain extra BattleChips to choose from upon reopening the Custom Menu. (For example, if three out of five chips are loaded, the number of BattleChips avaliable on the Custom Menu expands by two.)Technically, activating a BattleChip uses it up; however, unlike the original Battle Network games, spare copies of a BattleChip essentially serve as ammo. Therefore, if the player has collected 20 "Cannon" chips, Cannon can be used twenty times before it becomes unavailable. Each BattleChip has a unique duplicate limit.BattleChips are further balanced by Memory Points. The MP Gauge appears next to MegaMan's HP and essentially functions like the Classic games' Weapon Gauge. Each BattleChip has its own MB rating, which is subtracted from MegaMan's MP when used. The MP Gauge slowly regenerates over time, but heavy usage of powerful attacks will force the player to wait until MegaMan has freed up enough memory to use another chip.Power-UPPower-UPs boost the capabilities of MegaMan's Buster. There are three categories, Power, Rapid, and Charge. Power increases the damage of Buster shots, Rapid decreases the wait time between shots, and Charge first enables Charge Shots, then improves their potency and charge time.ArmorThe Armor system also returns from the first Battle Network. Fire, Aqua, Elec, and Wood Armor decrease the damage that MegaMan takes from attacks that aren't of their weakness. (Aqua douses Fire, Elec electrocutes Aqua, Wood grounds out Elec, Fire burns Wood)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1806094-box_mmnt.png</image></root>