<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6430</id><name>Adventures of Lolo 2</name><description>The GameThe Adventures of Lolo 2 is a puzzle game by HAL Corporation in 1990 for the Nintendo Entertainment System. It is the sequel to Adventures of Lolo and contains nearly all the same gameplay from that game. It has also been released on the Wii's virtual console for 1000 points. Due to the previous game not being released in Japan, this game is just titled Adventures of Lolo in that country.PlotLala, Lolo's pink blog friend, has been captured by King Egger of Eggerland AGAIN. Lolo must travel through five rooms in each of the ten levels in this castle to face off against King Egger (the Great Devil).CharactersLoloLoloThe protagonist and star. Lolo works his way through dungeons full of puzzle to rescue his princess.LalaLalaThe "Princess Peach" to Lolo. Lala is kidnapped by King Egger at the beginning of the game and it is Lolo's mission to rescue her.SnakeySnakeyThough Snakey's true intentions are unknown to the player, he is not hostile to Lolo in any way. Snakey plays an important part of many puzzles throughout the Lolo franchise. Snakey can be used to block Medusas or Gols from shooting projectiles. Snakeys can be used to stop other characters from reaching Lolo. Snakey can also be egged and ridden down rivers or be used to block character spawns.GolGolGol sits as a neutral character until all the heart framers in a level have been collected. After this, Gol becomes hostile and works very similarly to a Medusa. The only difference between Gol and Medusa at this point is that Medusa's projectiles can not be dodged, but Gol's projectiles are avoidable.LeeperLeeperAn enemy that hops around and falls asleep when he touches Lolo. Leepers are mostly harmless enemies, but their main goal is to block Lolo into an area that he'll be unable to escape. Leepers are incapable of crossing long grass areas.SkullSkullSimilarly to Gol, Skulls wake up after collecting all the heart framers in the level. Skulls do not chase after Lolo, they wander around the level and try to run into him. If they do manage to run into Lolo it's instant death.RockyRockyAn enemy that, like leeper, tries to trap Lolo; however, unlike Leeper, he will still chase after you if you somehow escape his trap. Rocky's a dick.AlmaAlmaAn enemy that chases Lolo, like Leeper or Rocky, but if he catches Lolo, Lolo dies.MedusaMedusaAn enemy that cannot move, but will instantly kill Lolo if Lolo crosses its path. He can be blocked by a rock, block, or another enemy.Don MedusaDon MedusaAn enemy that is exactly like Medusa, except he moves. It looks like he is wearing roller skates. Don Medusa either moves from side to side or up and down. His projectiles can still be blocked by rocks, blocks, or other enemies.King Egger (The Great Devil)King EggerThe main boss that captures Lala. King Egger is not actually fought in this game, and is merely around for story purposes.ObjectsHeart FramersHeart FramersHeart Framers are scattered throughout the levels and it is Lolo's job to collect them. Once all the Heart Framers on a level have been collected, the Chest opens up. Heart Framers will occasionally contain shots. Lolo uses shots to turn enemies into eggs which he can push around to block things. Alternatively he can shoot the egg again to kill the enemy.ChestsChestChests open up when all the heart framers in the level are collected. At this point many of the enemies in the level will wake up and chase Lolo. Once Lolo collects the chest in the level, all the enemies will disappear and the exit door will open for Lolo to go through.BlocksBlocksBlocks are in most levels and are pushed around by Lolo to block Medusas or other enemies .</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3758">Kickle Cubicle</game><game id="6770">Chip's Challenge</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2361121-nes_adventuresoflolo2.jpg</image></root>