<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6591</id><name>CSI: Crime Scene Investigation - 3 Dimensions of Murder</name><description>OverviewYou play as the newest member of the Las Vegas CSI team. You are put on murder investigations and must put all of your skills to the test making use of the tools and techniques available to you in order to discover the truth and uncover the murderer.CSI CrewThe following are the main CSI staff that you will work cases with. They will back you up and provide insight and help when needed. Gil Grissom Gilbert "Gil" Grissom is the graveyard shift supervisor and under his  leadership the LVPD Crime Lab has risen to national prominence rivaled  only by that of the FBI crime lab at Quantico.  Catherine Willows Catherine Willows is a CSI Level 3 and occasional Acting Shift Supervisor with the Las Vegas Police Department. Warrick Brown Warrick Brown is a CSI Level 3 for the LVPD. Nick Stokes Nick Stokes is a CSI Level 3 for the LVPD. Sara Sidle  Sara Sidle is a CSI for the LVPD. Greg Sanders Greg Sanders is the junior CSI at the LVPD.Then there are the team members who work to back up the CSI staff. Captain Jim Brass who represents the police force and Dr. Al Robbins who represents the medical staff. Captain Jim Brass Temporarily the head of the CSI Crime Lab, Captain Jim Brass is  currently a homicide detective who works closely with the CSIs to  provide them with leg work, warrants, and other things that they often  find themselves needing. Dr. Al Robbins The Chief Medical Examiner for the LVPD, he performs autopsies of  victims and provides the CSI team with medical information and analysis  relevant to the case. Game play As a CSI, you have a wealth of tools and techniques at your disposal. You will travel to various locations, examine them for evidence, collect the evidence, interview suspects, process the evidence at the crime lab, and eventually make an arrest. Tools There are various tools you will have at your disposal with which to examine the crimes scenes and collect evidence.  Latex Gloves  Latex Rubber Gloves - used to handle large evidence without contamination. Casting Plaster Casting Plaster and Frame - used to contain casting plaster when taking an impression of shoe prints, footprints, and tire tracks at a crime scene. Adhesive Lifting Tape Adhesive Lifting Tape - Adhesive vinyl lifter used to recover light, powdery, or scattered evidence such as fingerprints and footprints. Flash Drive SanDisk Crossfire Flash Drive - The SanDisk  Crossfire Flash Drive is a modified portable memory device used to help  detect computer files that are encrypted or corrupted. Fingerprint Brush Fingerprint Brush and Powder - A brush used to apply powder to a fingerprint area; usually made from fiberglass, camel's hair, or squirrel hair. Ninhydrin Ninhydrin (1,2,3 triketo-hydrindene hydrate) - Reveals latent fingerprints on porous surfaces, such as paper, by reacting with amino acids in the fingerprints. Magnetic Brush Magnetic Brush and Powder - A spring-loaded magnet used  for application of magnetic fingerprint powder to both vertical and  horizontal surfaces. Magnetic powder is used to enhance fingerprints on  certain porous objects, such as wood, polystyrene, and painted surfaces. Integri-Swab Integri-Swab - A swab fixed inside a ventilated, sterile package into which it retracts and remains protected once a sample has been taken. Luminol Luminol - A chemiluminescent that reacts with the iron  in hemoglobin, causing blood traces to illuminate with a blue-green  light in a dark environment. Effective even on surfaces that have been  wiped or washed clean of visible blood. LCV Leuko Crystal Violet (LCV) - Hexamethyl-p-rosaniline  chloride, a liquid accelerant that fluoresces when even trace amounts of  blood are present. This tool is highly specific in positively  identifying blood. Tweezers Tweezers - Very sharp and durable tweezers used for picking up dangerous or minute pieces of evidence. Mikrosil Mikrosil - Thick, rubbery putty, compounded of actuator  powder in a silicone base, usually used for making molds of tool  impressions. The putty is similar to the substance used by dentists to  make teeth molds. Flashlight High-Powered Flashlight - A powerful flashlight used to identify potential items of evidence in darkened areas. Camera Digital SLR Camera - The Digital SLR Camera captures  high-quality photographs in most light conditions. The photos are used  to document and preserve the context of a crime scene, such as  orientation and arrangement of objects. The camera is also used to  gather visual evidence that can't be collected in other ways, such as  bruising, or spatter patterns. UV Light Ultra Violet Light (UV Light) - Light-like radiation  beyond the violet end of the visible spectrum, with wavelengths shorter  than those of visible light but longer than those of X rays. This  hand held device is used to enhance potential items of evidence,  including bruising, accelerants, and various body fluids. Adhesive Mount Adhesive Specimen Mount - An adhesive pad and vial used  to lift and preserve powdery substances for chemical and microscopic  analysis in the lab. Examples of use are Gunshot residue (GSR) and trace  amounts of powder. Equipment In order to process the evidence for clues and determine concrete facts, you will have a variety of equipment at your disposal.  Assembly Table Assembly Table - A wide table with plenty of light and  room to work is the perfect spot for assembling and disassembling a  variety of items. If you find a shredded document or photo, you will  work on putting it back together here at the assembly table. If you need  to disassemble a gun in order to run ballistic tests on it, that will  also happen here. Comparison Microscope Comparison Microscope - This microscope is designed in  such as way as to allow you to make extremely magnified comparisons of  two objects side by side in order to check the smallest of details when  evaluating their similarity. For example, comparing two strands of hair  to determine if they are from the same source, or comparing a mold of a  tool indentation to the tool itself, are both done here. Also, one of  the most common uses for the comparison microscope is to compare the  markings of fired bullets to determine if they have been fired from the  same gun. Trace Analysis Computer Trace Analysis Computer - This computer is linked  into a number of national government databases for searching out  fingerprints, shoe prints, and tire tread. It is also linked into the  internet so that you can do research on various pieces of information  such as phone numbers or financial transactions. Finally it also allows  you to make digital comparisons of photographs and voice recordings.  Have a fingerprint and you want to find the identity of the owner? This  is your tool. DNA Machine DNA Machine - This large piece of equipment is used  entirely for determining and comparing DNA from various sources. It is  also hooked into the Government's national DNA database so that you can  enter in DNA from an unknown source and get back a list of possible  matches. Chemical Analyzer Chemical Analyzer - This last machine is used entirely for determining  the chemical makeup of various substances. Put in an object and it will  spit out the chemical composition. Useful for determining what a white  powder is or perhaps if two sources of lipstick are infact both from the  same single source. Mobile Crime Unit Mobile Crime Unit - A new addition to the department is the mobile crime  unit. Now if you have time sensitive evidence that needs to be  processed quickly, you can do so right at CSI's MCU. The Travel Analysis  Computer, DNA Machine, Chemical Analyzer, and Comparison Microscope  have all been packed into the trunk of this SUV for all your on the go  evidence processing needs.Cases caption Pictures At An Execution A woman has been brutally bludgeoned  to death at a local art gallery while the owner happened to be away and  the place was entirely deserted. A case of robbery gone horribly wrong  or perhaps something more sinister? Your first case as a CSI at the  LVPD, you will work closely with CSI Warrick Brown as he shows you the  ropes and evaluates your abilities. caption First Person Shooter The executive producer of LZP Games has  been gunned down at a video game convention and then posed to resemble  the ad for the very video game he was there publicizing. Was this a  publicity stunt gone horribly wrong, or did this pushy, hated boss tick  off the wrong person and pay for it with his life? You will work with  CSI Nick Stokes as you unravel the mystery behind this case. caption Daddy's Girl The daughter of a wealthy casino owner has  mysteriously vanished and all that remains of her is an extremely large  amount of blood splattered all around her apartment. Was she murdered  and if so where is her body? You must work quickly with CSI Sarah Sidle  to solve this mystery as the casino owner has a lot of pull and  influence in Vegas and is seeking answers.  caption Rough Cut A lone camper is discovered dead out in the vast  desert of Las Vegas. Was he murdered, did he commit suicide, or was he  just a little too careless and ended up dead? You'll work with the  newest CSI, Greg Sanders to discover the cause behind his death and who,  if anyone, is responsible for it. caption The Big White Lite While driving to work, Dr. Al Robbins  noticed a car suspiciously parked in an alley with its trunk open and no  one around. Stopping to investigate he found a dead body shoved into a  packing crate. Who killed this man and what was the motive? Can you  catch the killer before the trail gets cold? For this final case you'll  work with CSI Gil Grissom and CSI Catherine Willows on an investigation  that will take you back to your previous cases and show you that  something even larger is brewing.Game playIn all the CSI games, you control a no-named, no-faced rookie who has just joined the CSI team. You partner with one of the other CSI members and solve a case. Solving the cases consists of  finding clues at the scene of the crime, analyzing the clues at the lab, interrogating suspects, and finally building up enough of a case to arrest someone or get them to confess.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25685">Miami Law</game><game id="26608">Case Closed: The Mirapolis Investigation</game><game id="36434">NCIS</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2285636-box_csi3dom.png</image></root>