<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6614</id><name>Duke Nukem: Land of the Babes</name><description>OverviewDuke Nukem: Land of the Babes was the third game of the series that took place in a third-person perspective. This was easily the worst of the three and also marked the end of the cheap third person style Duke Nukem titles.In this Duke Nukem title, Duke is enjoying some RR at a local strip club back in Los Angeles. All is going well and everything is roses, and best of all, NO MORE FREAK'N ALIENS. Well, like any cheesy story line, it happens again. Portals begin to rip open in the middle of the strip club and women begin getting sucked into the dark vortexes. LARD Pig Cops also start to spawn. After a short exchange of gun fire, Duke Nukem leaps into a closing portal in hot pursuit of the alien bastards. As he awakens, Duke finds himself in the post- apocalypse ridden future of Earth. Duke quickly realizes what the aliens have done... stole our chicks! Duke Nukem meets up with the Unified Babe Resistance or U.B.R. They explain how the aliens are killing all of the men and are enslaving the women to do their bidding. This will not stand, so Duke Nukem sets out to kill the alien overlords and save the Earth. After a series of strange and humorous missions, the end of the game sees Duke Nukem repopulating the Earth with... you guessed it... him and a lot of babes. Once again the Earth is safe, and Duke Nukem takes some much needed RR.LevelsMission 1: Welcome to the futureMission 2: The future isn't so brightMission 3: Big gunsMission 4: Getting wetMission 5: TrappedMission 6: Underwater streetsMission 7: What's that smellMission 8: Silverback's strongholdMission 9: Babes in distressMission 10: Hunter killer factoryMission 11: Space portMission 12: Space bayMission 13: PromenadeMission 14: Combat</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16048">Blasto</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2114373-box_dnlotb.png</image></root>