<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6665</id><name>Super Street Fighter II</name><description>FeaturesThis remake of   Street Fighter II featured a new scoring system that kept track of combos, first attacks, and reversals. Additionally, 4 new characters join the returning twelve characters from the original. Super Street Fighter II is also the first game in the SFII series to give full move sets to the boss characters. Previously in   Street Fighter II: Champion Edition and   Street Fighter II: Turbo, whilst the four boss characters were available, they did not have different animations for some punches and kicks. Although this was expected for Balrog (being a boxer), it was unusual to see a character doing a punch when pressing a kick button, or vice-versa.Aside from the bosses' added moves, some of the main characters' moves were adjusted in some ways. For example, the differences between Ken and Ryu became more defined - Ryu focusing on deadlier fireballs, and Ken's fierce Dragon Punch being able to set opponents on fire.    Criticism For all the additions and improvements Super Street Fighter II makes over  Street Fighter II: Turbo, its biggest failing is arguably that it does not include the same degree of speed that made Street Fighter II: Turbo such a hit. It is perhaps for this very reason that, in most cases, this game is overlooked in preference to it's follow-up -   Super Street Fighter II: Turbo. Characters SSFII featured four new charactersReturning characters     Ryu     Ken Masters     E. Honda     Chun-Li     Blanka     Zangief     Guile     Dhalsim       Balrog     Sagat     Vega     M. Bison    New characters     Cammy     Dee Jay     Fei Long     T. Hawk  </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2178">Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3</game><game id="19200">Fatal Fury Special</game><game id="14669">Virtua Fighter Animation</game><game id="16793">Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors</game><game id="3744">Def Jam: Fight for NY</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="2886">WeaponLord</game><game id="21277">Ultimate Mortal Kombat</game><game id="34082">Skullgirls</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/12/121177/1748664-super_street_fighter_ii__flyer_.jpg</image></root>