<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6710</id><name>World of Illusion starring Mickey Mouse and Donald Duck</name><description>OverviewWorld of Illusion starring Mickey Mouse and Donald Duck (known in Japan as World of Illusion: Ai Rabu Mikki ando Donarudo - Fushigi na Majikku Bokkusu, translated to World of Illusion: I Love Mickey and Donald - The Mysterious Magic Box) is a 2D platformer developed and published by Sega for the Sega Genesis on December 17, 1992. Starring Disney mascots Mickey Mouse and Donald Duck, the game is considered to be a sequel to two Sega-developed games: Castle of Illusion starring Mickey Mouse and QuackShot starring Donald Duck.While preparing for a magic show, Mickey and Donald encounter a mysterious magic box and enter it, which transports them into a mysterious magical world ruled by a powerful magician. Up to two players can guide Mickey and Donald through the hostile world, as they learn new magic tricks in order to find and defeat the magician.GameplayWorld of Illusion is your standard platform game; Mickey and Donald can run, jump and attack enemies using their capes (which turns them into harmless animals or objects, such as a dove or a playing card, though it varies by enemy). A new magic spell is learned by defeating the boss of each level, allowing the pair to advance to and progress through the next level.This game features the, at the time, popular password save system, but instead of using a combination letters and numbers, you select from the 4 different suites in a deck of cards to continue.One feature that was unique at the time was how levels changed slightly depending on if you chose a single-player game with Mickey or Donald, or if you chose the two-player game. For example, in the two-player mode, Mickey and Donald would have to support each other to get through the level by jumping on each other to reach high places, then using a rope to hoist up the person who one who was used as a stepping stone, or through Mickey pulling Donald through tight crawlspaces, as he couldn't fit through them, although this would cause structural damage to the area and end up changing part of the next stage. This also affects the single-player mode, as Mickey could fit through the crawlspaces with ease, however Donald would have to find another way around.LevelsStage 1: Enchanted ForestThis first stage takes place in a giant forest where you will face enormous insects, all the while, wild weeds shoot up from the ground and leaves dance around as you progress. An emphasis on jumping on flowers and using your magic on plants will be sure to bring a few surprises. Later, a hallow log will lead you to a underground lair filled with spiders.Stage 2: Among the CloudsThis level features your character summoning a magical carpet to ride through the majority of this level, but be cognizant and dodge those vultures and whirling cyclones. You'll land high on the rocks, and you will be back to a standard platforming sequence where your character will have to dodge lightening, bouncing boulders, rushing rivers, and more which makes progression tricky. Make sure to take a dance on the piano keyboard, and watch your head!Stage 3: Underwater AdventureConjure a magical diving bubble suit and go for a swim! Dodge Snapping Tiger Fish, and don't get stuck on spiny Sea Urchins. Lure shy clams into opening the way to secret passages. Explore a sunken pirate ship, being mindful of falling tridents and watching for sharks!Stage 4: The LibraryJump out of a fish bowl and into a room with giant books and jars. This library is equipped wit all of the majors staples of a library including a springy stapler, rulers, jars of gumballs, cork boards. But be weary of enemies such as; tacks, stamps, flying pens and pencils. As you progress, you will slide down a piece of furniture to the base of an inviting cookie jar - what's inside? Hop in an take a look, you might just find a galaxy awaits your exploration.Stage 5: The Magic BoxYou've found the home of the Magic Master, a wonderland of which even Alice would approve of. This is going to be your biggest challenge yet. t will take special Magic and wise choices to make your way through the mazes that lead to the Magic Master and your final duel! Will you beat him and make it back home in time for your big magic show? Enemies in this level include animated playing cards, statues, Chandeliers, dinnerware, flying witches, jesters and many more.Magic SpellsMagic Carpet (Level 1): This allowed Mickey and Donald to fly on a magic carpet in level 2.Underwater Bubble (Level 2): This allowed Mickey and Donald to breathe underwater.Magic Box Transportation (Level 3): This allowed Mickey and Donald to transport to different places using magic boxes.Card Control (Level 4): This allowed Mickey and Donald to manipulate playing cards so they could form bridges over wide gaps.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10013">Tom and Jerry: The Magic Ring</game><game id="10299">Super Mario Bros. 3</game><game id="1994">Chip 'N Dale: Rescue Rangers</game><game id="9513">Castle of Illusion starring Mickey Mouse</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2389662-genesis_worldofillusion.jpg</image></root>