<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6732</id><name>Vengeance of Excalibur</name><description>Vengeance of Excalibur is a follow up to Spirit of Excalibur (developed by Synergistic in 1990).  It is a fantasy action role-playing game.   PlotThe game picks up where the previous game ended. The story kicks off in a newly reunited England, more specifically castle Camelot. Some strangers manage to enter the castle and to turn king Constantine into stone and then steal Excalibur, the Holy Grail and sorceress Nineve. With Camelot's mystical treasures stolen, demons and monster roam the countryside. It is up to the Knights of the Round Table to end this stiuation and restore peace to the land.   The player controls a group of knights bound for Spain, where they hope to find the culprit.   GameplayThe game is divided into seven episodes. The gameplay is a mix of RPG, Adventure and some basic strategy. The player can travel to many different towns, cities and castles. When traveling to different locations, you do so from an overhead map. When you enter a location the perspective switches to a 2D perspective with hand-drawn backgrounds.  The player controls a core-group of four knights, although different characters can temporarily join the group. The knights have different strange and weaknesses. The player is given an option to import characters from the previous game in the series, Spirit of Excalibur.   There are three different combat-styles which the player can choose for the knights. These are Reckless (offensive), normal, and cautious (defensive).   The game was originally released for MS-DOS in 1991, then later the Amiga and Atari ST.   ReceptionThe Amiga-version received mixed reviews from the press. Info gave the game credit for its non-derivative Arthurian-tale and nice looking graphics, while Amiga Power criticized the excessive disk-swapping and lack of support for the A500 Plus. </description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19688">J.R.R. Tolkien's War in Middle Earth</game><game id="16032">Spirit of Excalibur</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9408/720904-vengeance_of_excalibur.jpg</image></root>