<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6770</id><name>Chip's Challenge</name><description>OverviewChip's Challenge is a puzzle game created by Chuck Sommerville and was first released on the Atari Lynx back in 1989. The game was later ported to Windows, DOS, Amiga, Commodore, and Amstrad systems. The story of the game is about a high-school nerd named Chip McCallahan, who meets Melinda "The Mental Marvel" in a lab and will allow Chip to join her club The Bit Busters if he manages to navigate through her clubhouse.Chip's Challenge for WindowsThe gameplay of Chip's Challenge is simple and addicting. The player must navigate through 144 levels (not including bonus ones) collecting computer chips in order to proceed to the next level. The first 8 levels are lesson levels, designed to help the player understand the challenges present in the game. Chip also has to deal with hazards and puzzles such as locked doors, monsters, trap doors, etc to proceed. Blocks may also be needed to move or used to get further through the levels. Chip can be moved by the mouse button or the arrow keys, and has to collect all the chips to pass the socket and reach the exit square. Not all levels have sockets, so Chip may only need to find his way around the level to reach the exit square. Each level also had a unique password used to save the player's progress through the game, and some hardcore Chip's Challenge players may want to record their high scores and best times to try and improve them.The player community of Chip's Challenge has greatly expanded onto many different levels. Players can now make their own levels with "ChipEdit", record footage of them playing the game with "ChipCap" in video format, and download many custom created levelsets online. Official levelsets, such as the Chip's Challenge Level Pack 2, for example, is 149 new levels all created by players of the community. A sequel to Chip's Challenge, called Chip's Challenge 2 was supposed to be released, but the creator had trouble with the copyright rights and the game couldn't be released legally.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10147">Wonderland</game><game id="5026">Adventures of Lolo</game><game id="6430">Adventures of Lolo 2</game><game id="4529">Adventures of Lolo 3</game><game id="8785">Cubis 2</game><game id="5896">Paganitzu</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/10/103881/1861859-cc1.jpg</image></root>