<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6811</id><name>NCAA Football 2005</name><description>NCAA Football 2005 is the 2004 installment of EA's NCAA Football franchise. It features former Pittsburgh Panthers receiver Larry Fitzgerald on the cover.The gameplay did not change much from the 2004 installment. Two significant additions are made:Home Field AdvantageWhen playing a game at home, players have the ability to incite their crowds to cheer as loudly as possible by rapidly tapping an assigned button. The maximum amount of noise is determined by how loud the stadium is in real life. As the stadium gets louder, the volume increases, the screen starts shaking, the controller rumbles, and the offense has trouble keeping organized. If playing in a loud stadium, missed audibles and constant false start penalties are a common occurance. With this home field advantage system came a ranking of stadiums based on the noise their fans make. These rankings do not change over time.Ben Hill Griffin Stadium, FloridaNeyland Stadium, TennesseeOhio Stadium, OSUTiger Stadium, LSUAutzen Stadium, OregonHusky Stadium, WashingtonKyle Field, Texas AMCamp Randall Stadium, WisconsinMemorial Stadium, NebraskaStanford Stadium, GeorgiaKinnick Stadium, IowaMichigan Stadium, MichiganLane Stadium, Virginia TechDoak Campbell Stadium, FSUNotre Dame Stadium, Notre DameMemorial Stadium, ClemsonBeaver Stadium, Penn StateOklahoma Memorial Stadium, OklahomaJordan-Hare Stadium, AuburnCarrier Dome, SyracuseBryant-Denny Stadium, AlabamaKSU Stadium, Kansas StateMountaineer Field, West VirginiaMartin Stadium, Washington StateMiami Orange Bowl, MiamiThe second addition is the big hits system, where you can press a button before delivering a hit to make it harder, with a larger shot to miss.NCAA Football 2005, while received mainly positively, also had a major flaw with the passing game: far too many dropped balls. The amount of dropped balls was significantly higher than NCAA Football 2004, and the amount of dropped balls again went down for NCAA Football 2006.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8480">All-Pro Football 2K8</game><game id="16585">Madden NFL 07</game><game id="4222">Madden NFL 2005</game><game id="98">John Elway's Quarterback</game><game id="14001">NFL 2K2</game><game id="3333">NFL GameDay ‘98</game><game id="30003">NCAA Football 11</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2250716-box_ncaafb05.png</image></root>