<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6945</id><name>ECW Anarchy Rulz</name><description> OverviewECW Anarchy Rulz is an professional wrestling video game, released August 16th 2000 on the  Sega Dreamcast and  Sony PLaystation. Developed by  Acclaim Studios Salt Lake City and published by  Acclaim Entertainment. GameplayECW Anarchy Rulz uses the same control scheme as many other wrestling video games, and also has the same gameplay mechanics including, the grapple which allows you to do a variety of moves from a DDT to a chokeslam. The has a variety of different game modes which include, Street Fight, Table Match, Inferno Match, Dumpster Match, Lion's Den, Hate Match, and the Team Rumble.Playable Roster Bill Alfonso  Amish Roadkill  Angel  Beautiful Billy  Balls Mahoney  Big Sal E. Graziano  C.W. Anderson  Chris Chetti  Steve Corino  Justin Credible  Cyrus  Dawn Marie  DeVito  Danny Doring   Tommy Dreamer  ElektraJohn FinneganFrancineJoel GertnerLittle GuidoPaul HeymanJasonJazzJudge Jeff JonesJerry Lynn Kid KashLou E. DangerouslyJim MolineauxNew JackNova Rhino Dusty Rhodes  Rob Van Dam  Super Crazy Simon Diamond Sandman Spike DudleyLance StormJoey StylesTajiriTanakaThe ProdigyJack VictoryMikey Whipwreck</description><genres><genre id="10">Wrestling</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16435">WWF Attitude</game><game id="18801">WWF War Zone</game><game id="1204">WCW Mayhem</game><game id="17436">WWF SmackDown!</game><game id="20469">TNA iMPACT!</game><game id="8647">ECW Hardcore Revolution</game><game id="22464">Wrestling Encore</game><game id="17814">WWF SmackDown! 2: Know Your Role</game><game id="26888">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2010</game><game id="30637">Lucha Libre AAA Heroes del Ring</game><game id="13440">Backyard Wrestling: Don't Try This at Home</game><game id="18333">Backyard Wrestling 2: There Goes the Neighborhood</game><game id="31640">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2011</game><game id="28430">WWF Royal Rumble</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1550/236937-ecw_anarchy_rulz_pal.jpg</image></root>