<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6978</id><name>Enthusia Professional Racing</name><description>HistoryEnthusia, or to give it its proper title, Enthusia: Professional Racing, was a racing game produced by                   Konami, that was released in 2005. Enthusia was released first in                  Japan. Unlike many releases, the US was the final region to receive the    BMW M3 on Dragon's Pass      release of Enthusia.   OverviewEnthusia is a highly detailed game, and was arguably more realistic than its main competitors in some areas. Enthusia contains many modes that are unique to Western gamers. These modes are:  Enthusia Life Free Race Driving Revolution Time Attack Versus Racing   Enthusia Life: Enthusia Life is the real meat of the game, as this is where players unlock cars, and take part in the main races. Enthusia Life mode is most comparable to Career Mode in other racing games.    Free Race: This mode is similar to 'Free Run', as it is known in other games. Players are allowed to set up races against the                 AI and then tailor the match to their choices, rather than fixed race types like those found in Enthusia Life.    Nighttime drifting in a Mazda RX-7       Driving Revolution:  A mode in which players start on a track with a car and are challenged to pass through gates. However, these gates are made more difficult than in other games, as you must pass them at a designated speed or around that speed. By passing through a gate you earn points, and you must earn a set amount of points to progress to the next level.   Versus Racing: Versus is a split screen mode, where you may race against a friend.    Enthusia contains some extremely realistic car models, but it does not contain as many cars as                Gran Turismo 4. Where GT4 had 750 , Enthusia boasts only 200. However, these cars are relatively obscure, such as the Citroen 2CV, and some other rare vehicles.GameplayGameplay in Enthusia follows a similar pattern to some Japanese RPGs. For example, you have HP in the game, which are known as "Enthu Points", on the Western versions of the game. In the Japanese version of Enthusia, Enthu Points, as they are known, are called "Driver HP". This HP system is designed to reward clean drivers. Hitting walls depletes your overall Enthu Points, as well as hitting other drivers. The punishment for losing all your Enthu Points is simply not being     Audi S6 Quattro     able to compete in the next race. You can regenerate points by resting, and by changing to a different car.   As well as having HP, players are rewarded with a '              slot machine' after a race in Enthusia Life mode. Once a race has been completed, you receive a slot machine interface. You are able to stop the spinning. Once the spinning is stopped, you will win a car that was on the track during the race. However, this system becomes difficult after winning a lot of the cars in the game, as you can occasionally not win a car at all.  Car List Alfa Romeo 158 GTAAlfa Romeo 147 GTAAlfa Romeo GTV 3.2 V6 24VAlfa Romeo GTAlfa Romeo SZAlfa Romeo Giulia Sprint GTAAlfa Romeo Spider Quadrifoglio VerdeAlpine A110 1600 SCAudi R8 TEAM GOH 2004Audi R8 TEAM GOH 2003Audi RS6Audi A4 3.0 quattro SportAudi A8 4.2 quattroAudi TT Coupe 3.2 quattro SlineAudi TT Roadster 1.8T quattroAudi AllRoad quattroASL GaraivaAston Martin Vanquish(V12)Aston Martin DB5Austin Healey SPRITE MK1BMW McLaren F1 GTRBMW M1 procarBMW 3.0 CSL race car(Batmobile)         BMW M3 GTR road versionBMW M3 Sport EvolutionBMW Z4 3.0iBMW 2002 turboCadillac Seville STS Caterham Superlight R500Chevrolet Corvette Stingray CoupeChevrolet Corvette Z51Chevrolet Camaro Z28Chevrolet Corvette STING RAY Sport CoupeChevrolet ASTROChrysler PT CruiserCitroen Xsara Rally CarCitroen Saxo VTSCitroen DS 23 PallasCitroen C3Citroen 2CV6 CharleatonDaihatsu Sirion X4Daihatsu CopenDauer EB110De Tomaso Pantera GTS            DMC DeLoreanDodge Viper GTSFiat Abarth 1000 TCR    The Rally Raid Mitsubishi Pajero on a Rally Circuit.           Fiat Abarth 131 RallyFiat 500F           Ford Focus Rally CarFord GT2005 Ford Mustang GTFord Mustang Mach 1Ford Thunderbird1969 Ford Mustang GT             Honda NSX G'zox prospecHonda NSX-RHonda NSX Type-S ZeroHonda S2000Honda Integra Type-R(DC5)Honda Civic Type-RHonda Accord Euro-RHonda Accord EuroR (Older model)Honda Integra Type-R (DC2)Honda Civic Type-R (Older model)Honda Odyssey AbsoluteHonda Fit 1.5THonda City Turbo IIHonda MobilioHonda Civic RSHonda S800Honda insightHonda BeatHyundai CoupeJaguar S-Type RJaguar XKR100Jaguar XJR 4.0 Supercharged V8Jaguar 'E' Type 42Jaguar X-Type 2.5 V6 SportLancia Delta integrale EvoluzioneIILancia Rally 037Lancia StradoRange RoverLotus Elise 100SLotus Esprit S2Lotus Europa SpecialLotus Elan S.3Mazda 787BMazda RX-7 Spirit AMazda RX-8 TypeSMazda RX-7 Infini(Savanna)Mazda Savanna RX-7 GT-XMazda Atenza 23Z SportMazda Atenza 23E SedanMazda Roadster RS-IIMazda Eunos Roadster S-Special type IIMazda Cosmo SportMazda Savanna AP GTMazda DemioMercedes CLK-DTMMercedes SLRMercedes S600LMercedes C32 AMGMercedes CL55 AMGMercedes SL500Mercedes G500LMercedes 300SLMG MGBMini Cooper S        Mitsubishi Pajero EVOLUTIONMitsubishi Lancer Evolution VIII GSRMitsubishi Lancer Evolution VII GSRMitsubishi Lancer Evolution VI T.M. EditionMitsubishi Lancer Evolution III GSRMitsubishi Lancer Evolution VII Rally CarMitsubishi Pajero ShortMitsubishi ColtMitsubishi EK-WagonMitsubishi Galant GTO-MRMini-Cooper 1275S MKINismo R34 Skyline GT-R S-TuneNismo Xanavi GT-R    Mini Cooper S and Lotus Exige during a night race Nismo S15 Silvia R-tune       Nissan R390 GTINissan PICK UP Rally CarNissan Skyline GT-R V-spec I NurNissan Skyline GT-R V-specNissan Skyline GT-R V-specIINissan Fairlady Z Version SNissan Silvia spec-RNissan CIMA 450XVNissan Skyline Coupe 350GT PREMIUMNissan StageaNissan Skyline 350GT-8Nissan Silvia K's AeroNissan Silvia K'sNissan 180SX TypeXNissan ElgrandNissan Primera 20VNissan WingroadNissan Skyline 2000 GT-R(KPGC110)Nissan Skyline 2000 GT-R(KPGC10)Nissan Fairlady 240ZGNissan Bluebird 1600 SSS CoupeNissan MarchNissan CubeNissan MocoOpel Astra V8 Coupe 24hOpel Vita GsiPeugeot 206 Rally Car 2000Peugeot 406 CoupePeugeot 206cc S16Peugeot 106 S16Pontiac Firebird Trans AM SD-455Renault Lutecia sport 2.0 'Renault F1 Team Limited Edition'(Clio)Renault AvantimeRenault 5 Turbo2RUF Turbo RRUF CTRRUF RGTSaab 9-5 Aero 2.3TSShelby Cobra 427 S/CSmart Fortwo CabrioSubaru Impreza Rally CarSubaru Impreza WRX STiSubaru Impreza WRX Sti limitedSubaru Impreza WRX Sti Version VISubaru Impreza 22B STi VersionSubaru Legacy B4 2.0 GT spec BSubaru Legacy B4 RSKSubaru Legacy Touring Vagon GT-B E-tune IISubaru Legacy Lancaster6Subaru ForesterSubaru Young SSSuzuki CappuccinoTommykaira ZZ-S coupeToyota GT-oneToyota Supra ESSO UltrafloToyota Supra RZToyota MR2 GT-SToyota Soarer 2.5GT-TwinturboToyota Aristo V300 'Vertex Edition'Toyota Celica GT-FOUR WrcToyota Altezza RS200Toyota Celica SS-DToyota CelsiorToyota AlphardVToyota VoltzToyota Vitz RS TurboToyota MR2 'G-Limited Super Charger'Toyota MR-S V-EditionToyota Corolla 1.8 LuxelToyota Sprinter Trueno GT ApexToyota Land Cruiser 100Toyota 2000GTToyota Estima Hybrid    VW Touareg vs Merc. G-Wagen Toyota bBToyota iStToyota PriusToyota FunCargoToyota Sports800TVR Cerbera 4.5TVR Tamora      Volkswagen Golf R32Volkswagen Golf GTIVolkswagen TouaregVolkswagen New BeetleVolkswagen PoloVolkswagen Beetle Type 1Volvo S60RVolvo V70R ReceptionReception for Enthusia was generally pleasing. IGN gave the game a 7.2 out of 10, while GameSpot gave a 7.4 out of 10. PSXExtereme scored the game 7.1 out of 10. According to Metacritic's 43 critic reviews, the game has scored a 70/100. The highest score given in a review was by My Gamer, who rated it an 86, and were attributed with a quote reading: The true disaster here is the likelihood that nobody will really play Enthusia. "Gran Turismo 4's" massive popularity is destined to overshadow it even though both games rank at the top of the genre. The lowest score given in a review was by AltGaming, who rated the game a mere 40/100, and were quoted to have said: The simple fact is Enthusia is simply a simulation of life, but has little life itself.  Reasons for Obscurity Enthusia: Professional Racing is one of the least known racing games on the      Playstation 2. There are numerous reasons for this, such as the low amount of publicity before the launch. The game was mainly designed for the Japanese market and therefore was not given a major launch outside of Japan. Also, the game's release was only a few     Mitsubishi's Lancer Evo VII in Enthusia     months after that of     Gran Turismo 4, which is a much well known game series. As well as only being released after Gran Turismo 4, it was only a short time after the release of the original    Forza Motorsport on the   Xbox console.  TriviaOn the final page of the game manual, it reads "The legend is only beginning...", a quote     Sirion X4 - yeah, you want one, don't you?     that hints at a sequel being planned. However, there has been no information about a sequel, even in the past five years.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20597">Gran Turismo 5 Prologue</game><game id="21297">Gran Turismo HD</game><game id="17784">Gran Turismo 4</game><game id="17599">Forza Motorsport</game><game id="5881">Forza Motorsport 2</game><game id="19522">Live for Speed</game><game id="13895">Gran Turismo 4: Prologue</game><game id="24995">Forza Motorsport 3</game><game id="6137">Driving Emotion Type-S</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2213155-box_epr.png</image></root>