<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7010</id><name>StepMania</name><description>Stepmania is a dancemat rhythm game in the same category as the successful Dance Dance Revolution series. It expanded on the features of previous DDR-likes Dance with Intensity and Flash Flash Revolution. Stepmania serves as a way to enable fans of the DDR series to add their own music to dance to, something that was not possible on the disc based DDR games.FeaturesPlayers must avoid standing on a pad when a mine passesStepmania adds a handful of features not seen in previous dancing games, such as landmines which harm the player if stepped on (later appearing in Dance Dance Revolution X as shock notes), additional arrow scrolling options that alter the way arrows appear on screen, and the ability to change the type of life bar in use while playing.What sets Stepmania apart from other dancing games is its level of customization. While the ability to edit stepcharts (the pattern of notes used for a particular song) is retained from the Dance Dance Revolution series, the ability to import custom songs, backgrounds, themes, characters, and commentator voices has been added. Players can create their own content or download pieces of content, known as simfiles, from a number of official and unnoficial websites.Due to the ease of customization, Roxor was able to use Stepmania as the engine for their dancing game franchise In the Groove by simply applying a custom theme and licensing a soundtrack. Some of the additional gameplay modifiers were also used including mines and custom songs. Additionally players could bring a USB flash drive to arcades to play their custom songs on In the Groove arcade machines equipped with USB ports on the front.Later versions of Stepmania have continued to give theme creators the ability to further customize the gameplay experience. Online multiplayer was originally added to the game by custom themes, though it was later incorporated as a core feature.DevelopmentThe first three major versions of Stepmania had primarily striven for a visual similarity with DDR. The default theme used by the latest stable version of Stepmania (version 3.9, released in 2006) is designed to be a look-alike of DDRMAX. For several years development efforts stagnated, but the efforts of several disparate teams converged in 2011 to produce what is now available as Stepmania 5 alpha. This new version has developed its own look and feel, includes official support for online multiplayer modes, and fixes many long standing bugs. Both versions are available for free at stepmania.com and can run on PC, Mac, or Linux platforms.</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1417">DDRMAX Dance Dance Revolution</game><game id="2951">beatmania</game><game id="8743">Pump It Up : Prex 3</game><game id="5825">Frequency</game><game id="16639">Dance Dance Revolution: Mario Mix</game><game id="11694">Dance Dance Revolution SuperNOVA</game><game id="3280">Dance Dance Revolution EXTREME</game><game id="21746">Dance Dance Revolution SuperNOVA 2</game><game id="4675">Dance Dance Revolution: Disney Dancing Museum</game><game id="20631">Dance Dance Revolution HOTTEST PARTY 2</game><game id="20629">Dance Dance Revolution UNIVERSE 3</game><game id="18104">Dance Dance Revolution Disney MIX</game><game id="19822">Dance Dance Revolution 2ndMIX</game><game id="11448">Dance Dance Revolution 4thMIX</game><game id="11789">Dance Dance Revolution 5thMIX</game><game id="24918">Dance Dance Revolution ULTRAMIX 4</game><game id="31119">Dance Dance Revolution USA</game><game id="23676">Osu!</game><game id="44149">Flash Flash Revolution</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/7902/262536-solo.jpg</image></root>