<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7019</id><name>Ridge Racer V</name><description>CoursesRidge Racer V has a total of seven circuit courses, each of which are raced both forward or in reverse, during daytime, sunset, and night, and in multiple difficulties and speed classes.Park Town:Park Town is the first course you race when starting career mode. It begins/ends in a familiar part of the city from the original Ridge Racer, before taking a detour while in the tunnel, leading to all-new parts of the city never seen before Ridge Racer V.Over The City:Over The City is an extension of Park Town that is about 1.5 times in length. It adds a highway onramp section containing a series of corners that are difficult to navigate effectively.Sunny Beach:This is the classic Beginner/Intermediate course from the original Ridge Racer, just recreated for PS2 and renamed to Sunny Beach. All of the other courses in Ridge Racer V, except for the oval course, run through at least some portion of Sunny Beach.Outer Pass:The appropriately named Outer Pass is an exciting variant of Sunny Beach. While half of this course is shared with Sunny Beach, the other half leads to an alternate tunnel which opens to a wide, scenic route on a ridge, before finally merging back at the coastline.Bayside Line:Bayside Line includes most of Outer Pass, but adds a massive extension of track approaching a suspension bridge and is marked by several long, wide turns. It is the longest course in Ridge Racer V and, unlike the other courses, can only be raced during sunset or at night.Green FIeld:Green Field is a rehauled version of the Expert course from the original Ridge Racer; an extension of Sunny Beach. However, the extension is almost unrecognizable this time around, unlike the rest of Sunny Beach -- what used to be a treacherous construction route in Ridge Racer is now a high speed dash along wide highway roads.Airport Oval:Airport Oval is simply an oval course set underneath and around an airport. Despite being the only course in the Ridge Racer V not to share road with any of the other courses, its waterfront section sports a dramatic view where you can see part of Sunny Beach in the distance.Vehicles:(All vehicles and names of manufacturers in Ridge Racer V are fictional.)Standard Cars:Kamata FiaraKamata FortuneRivelta MercurioDanver ToreadorRivelta SolareHimmel E.O.Duel Cars:In addition to the standard cars, duel cars can be unlocked by winning against them in a 1-one-1 Duel race. However, a duel car will only challenge you after you enter a time trial and beat that car's respective record.These cars are exceptionally powerful and may have extraordinary handling ability. There are four cars that can unlocked through duels, and these include the ''devil'' and ''angel'' cars from Ridge Racer and Ridge Racer Revolution, now named the Rivelta Crinale and Kamata Angelus.In addition to these cars, much later in the game, you can unlock the ability to play as Pac-Man driving a miniature car, and the four ghosts from the arcade classic, Pac-Man.Official SoundtrackAn official soundtrack CD was released containing most of the music in Ridge Racer V.No.ArtistTrack NameLength1Boom Boom SatellitesFogbound5:242U (4)Hydroprism2:103KohtaEuphoria5:234Mijk Van DijkNightride6:135SanodgParis5:266U (4)LOLO 10102:297U (4)TsuiTsui5:098Mijk Van DijkPower Slider5:059KohtaJunx-Interlude0:2010KohtaRideCityFM2:0711KohtaEyeCatch0:0812U (4)Gammon3:0313SanodgRareHero20005:0614Mijk Van DijkElectroglide5:0015KohtaJunxEngine0:4116KohtaSamurai Rocket4:0917KohtaDareDevil5:0518KohtaGripMillenium3:1019KohtaJunx (Remixed by Mijk Van Dijk)5:1320KisaburoMotoPacCity55:02Race Girl/MascotRidge Racer V is the first game in the Ridge Racer franchise to not have Mascot and Race Girl Reiko Nagase represent the game in promotions and the game's pre-rendered cinematic opening. Reiko was replaced for one game with a new character Ai Fukami. Reiko returned to represent the game again with Ridge Racer 6. </description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9927">SRS: Street Racing Syndicate</game><game id="8437">TOCA 2: Touring Car Challenge</game><game id="20729">GRID</game><game id="19809">Project Gotham Racing 3</game><game id="2279">Project Gotham Racing 2</game><game id="941">Project Gotham Racing</game><game id="531">TOCA Race Driver 2</game><game id="5869">TOCA Touring Car Championship</game><game id="13734">TOCA Race Driver 3</game><game id="17872">TOCA Race Driver 3 Challenge</game><game id="6499">RalliSport Challenge 2</game><game id="20597">Gran Turismo 5 Prologue</game><game id="2416">Gran Turismo</game><game id="17784">Gran Turismo 4</game><game id="12950">Gran Turismo 3 A-Spec</game><game id="8100">Gran Turismo 2</game><game id="21297">Gran Turismo HD</game><game id="7482">Gran Turismo Concept: 2001 Tokyo</game><game id="21390">Gran Turismo Concept: 2002 Tokyo-Seoul</game><game id="7313">Gran Turismo Concept: 2002 Tokyo-Geneva</game><game id="13895">Gran Turismo 4: Prologue</game><game id="5648">Burnout Paradise</game><game id="16492">Burnout Revenge</game><game id="4970">Burnout Legends</game><game id="13514">Burnout 2: Point of Impact</game><game id="8459">Burnout Dominator</game><game id="20484">Burnout</game><game id="10149">Burnout: Championship Drag Racing</game><game id="12976">Need for Speed: Most Wanted</game><game id="18095">Need for Speed: ProStreet</game><game id="8844">Need for Speed: Carbon</game><game id="20741">Need for Speed: Undercover</game><game id="9651">Need for Speed Underground 2</game><game id="12254">Need for Speed Underground</game><game id="5977">Need for Speed III: Hot Pursuit</game><game id="8831">Need for Speed: Porsche Unleashed</game><game id="12395">Need for Speed: Hot Pursuit 2</game><game id="453">Need for Speed: High Stakes</game><game id="18021">Need for Speed: Carbon - Own the City</game><game id="367">Need for Speed II</game><game id="20927">Midnight Club: Los Angeles</game><game id="10124">Midnight Club: Street Racing</game><game id="20418">Midnight Club II</game><game id="5875">Midnight Club 3: DUB Edition</game><game id="788">The Fast and the Furious</game><game id="20919">Ford Racing: Off Road</game><game id="16276">Ford Bold Moves Street Racing</game><game id="8779">Sega GT 2002</game><game id="14428">Sega GT Online</game><game id="15965">Sega GT</game><game id="7431">Ford Racing</game><game id="24866">OutRun Online Arcade</game><game id="24513">DiRT 2</game><game id="42324">Ridge Racer Driftopia</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1839033-box_rracer5.png</image></root>