<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7023</id><name>SOCOM: U.S. Navy SEALs - Tactical Strike</name><description>SOCOM Navy Seals: Tactical Strike is a game for the PSP. Unlike other SOCOM titles, Tactical Strike is a squad based game with mechanics similar to those found in the  Brothers in Arms series.  Similar gameplay elements can be found in games like  Full Spectrum Warrior and those in the  Rainbow Six series. Players take control of a squad of four special-ops soldiers, the nationality of which is determined by the player at the start of the campaign. They progress through a series of 11 missions that take place in Panama, in an attempt to rescue their country's Prime Minister from a group of renegades.     Conceptually,  Tactical Strike actually plays like a Real Time Strategy game. The player never actually gains control of individual squadmates. Instead, you select actions and targets for your team to take out. This puts a very heavy emphasis on strategy and tactics (hence the name) since you literally never get direct control your units, much like in an RTS.  Tactical Strike  represents a huge departure from the rest of the SOCOM franchise.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14048">SOCOM 3: U.S. Navy SEALs</game><game id="6246">SOCOM: U.S. Navy SEALs</game><game id="20676">SOCOM: U.S. Navy SEALs - Confrontation</game><game id="1049">SOCOM II: U.S. Navy SEALs</game><game id="2972">SOCOM: U.S. Navy SEALs - Fireteam Bravo</game><game id="1148">Fire Emblem: The Sacred Stones</game><game id="9969">Full Spectrum Warrior</game><game id="3550">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six: Vegas</game><game id="2444">Full Spectrum Warrior: Ten Hammers</game><game id="22960">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six: Lone Wolf</game><game id="20614">Star Wars Battlefront: Renegade Squadron</game><game id="25246">Battlefield: Bad Company 2</game><game id="25894">SOCOM: U.S. Navy SEALs - Fireteam Bravo 3</game><game id="26423">Call of Duty: Black Ops</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1789979-box_socomts.png</image></root>