<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7068</id><name>Head Over Heels</name><description>Overview Head over Heels is a 3D platforming pussle game from the early 80s. It was first released for the ZX Spectrum and had an unusual isometric view.The player controls two creatures, named Head (Headus Mouthion) and Heels (Footus Underium). Head jumped high but was slow so he was not able to get far. Heals was faster but didn't jump very high. They move as two separate creatures but can join and get the benefit of having both specialities.GameplayGameplay was all about moving through rooms an corridors maximising the advantages of the two creatures. Some rooms and mazes can only be navigated with one of the two creatures and therefore forcing them to separate in two different directions to meet up later.This is an old-school game where the player get no help with navigation so pen and paper to draw maps was often used to get through the game. More than 300 rooms had to be navigated to win the game and the puzzles was quite unique for its time.Creature AbilitiesHead:Jumps twice as high as Heels.Have control while jumpingCan shoot dougnuts to stun enemiesHeelsCan climb certain staircases that Heels can not.Run twice as fast as HeadCan carry itemsStorylineThe background story puts Head and Heels as two spies from the planet Freedom. They are sent to free other planets (Blacktooth, Penitentiary, Safary, Book World and Egyptus) to free them from slavery. They had to defeat the Emperor to prevent further planets to fall into slavery. Head and Heels starts the game in a prison, separated and have to find each other to be able to escape from the prison.CreatorsThe game was made by Jon Ritman and Bernie Drummond and is was their second game following a Batman game.RemakesThe game has been remade several times and the latest, available for Windows, MacOS, Linux and BeOS was made by Retrospec and is available as freeware on their website. This remake was voted as the second best remake ever by readers of PC Zone magazine. </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14744">Get Dexter</game><game id="16856">Batman</game><game id="13220">Solstice: The Quest for the Staff of Demnos</game><game id="3935">Mystic Towers</game><game id="18183">Monster Max</game><game id="14449">Cadaver</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/5/57793/1361141-713_1.jpg</image></root>