<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7084</id><name>Stretch Panic</name><description>StoryLinda is the youngest of 13 sisters, who are all very vain. They spend their days trying on clothes, putting on makeup, and complementing each other on how pretty they are. Linda, however, is different. She is mature, good natured, and hard working.One day, while Linda is out at the shops (fetching cosmetics for her sisters), a mysterious package arrives and the sisters begin to speculate what the contents may be. As they are doing, this the package begins to speak to them. The package explains that it was attracted by their vanity and wants to offer the chance for endless beauty. The sisters, dazzled by this offer, accept.At this moment Linda returns home just as a blinding light engulfs the house the light catches her scarf and it becomes possessed by a demon, initially frightened by the large Black Hand on her scarf she soon realises that the scarf seems to like her and she can control it!The voice that was before speaking to her sisters now starts speaking to Linda offering her the same beauty that was given to her sisters and her scarf. Linda realises that her sisters have been possessed by demons of vanity and have been taken to the demon world. With only her scarf at her side she must set out to rescue them.CharactersLindaLinda and her possessed scarfLinda is the hero of this story and the character that the player controls throughout the game, at the start of the game Linda is given a demon possessed scarf which Linda can use to stretch and destroy enemies.Linda's SistersCinderLinda Fighting CinderBefore becoming possessed Cinder was obsessed with fire. She was transformed by the demon possessing her into her own image of ‘perfect beauty’ and is now a pyromaniac fire demon.SpinnerSpinner was the sportiest of the sisters before being transformed and loved running around in circles to make herself dizzy, now the demon possessing her as made her balanced like a pendulum to take advantage of her centrifugal fascination.Miss MeccaMiss Mecca was the most creative of the sisters and yearned to be an inventor, now possessed by a demon she has built a large robot to protect herself from Linda.SirenSiren used to train as an opera singer the demon now possessing her is now using this skill to captivate anyone who comes near.Fay SoffLinda Fighting FayMore than any over Sister Fay was obsessed with her facial beauty the demon possessing her as made a face gigantic and given her features a life of their own.Anne Droid V2.1Anne was the nerd of the family and her demon has transformed her into a satellite orbiting her own planet.Jelly-ChanBefore becoming possessed Jelly had a philosophy of ‘big is beautiful’ the demon possessing her now has made her bigger and hungrier than ever by transforming her into a giant gluttonous blob!DemonicaDemonica used to have an unhealthy obsession with all thing horror related, the demon possessing her has now made Demonica look sorry terror inspiring that she only has to look at you and you will drop down dead.SamanthaSamantha is the second youngest of the sisters being only a year older than Linda, Samantha used to enjoy playing with her favourite toy a plastic fish but now the demon controlling her has turned the fish into a deadly living weapon that can grapple large objects and throw them around.CyanCyan was the smallest of the sisters but now possessed the demon has transformed her into a gigantic alien waging war against tiny jet pack shock troopers that Linda must ally with to save little Cyan.MirageMirage was obsessed with Egyptian culture and has been transformed into a mummified temptress in a sarcophagus creating tornados of sand to attack Linda.SpiritLinda Fighting SpiritSpirit is the eldest of the sisters and is Linda’s ultimate adversary; the demon controlling her has changed Spirit into a ghost who can influence the world around her using two large phantom claws.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13371">Ape Escape</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2428427-box_sp.png</image></root>