<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7110</id><name>Halo 2</name><description>OverviewHalo 2 is a sci-fi first-person shooter developed by Bungie and published by Microsoft for the Xbox on November 9, 2004. The second game in the original Halo trilogy and the sequel to Halo: Combat Evolved, Halo 2 continues the story of the SPARTAN-II super-soldier Master Chief as Earth is invaded by the alien Covenant forces. During the campaign, players switch between Master Chief and the Arbiter, a disgraced Covenant Sangheili commander given a chance to redeem himself by the game's antagonists, the High Prophets. Both stories intertwine as they fight to prevent the activation of another Halo ring, Installation 05.The game adds a variety of new gameplay mechanics, such as the ability to dual wield small weapons (allowing players to wield any combination of pistols and light rifles, both Human and Covenant, and to fire them separately at the cost of not being able to throw grenades), destructible vehicles, the ability to "board" enemy vehicles (stealing some vehicles and destroying others), a new health/shield system (in which players have stronger energy shields that is faster to replenish, at the cost of a smaller hidden regenerating health buffer), and playable Elites (each with their own appearance and HUD). The game also introduces new enemies (the Brutes, large ape-like beasts) and a variety of weaponry (such as the BR55 Battle Rifle, the Particle Beam Rifle, the M7 Submachine Gun, the Covenant Carbine, and a wieldable Energy Sword).Crazy Spartan multiplayer fun, now on Xbox Live!Halo 2 is also the first in the franchise to support Xbox Live online multiplayer for up to 16 players. It is also the first game to implement the concept of matchmaking sessions (known as "optimatch"), in which player "parties" (groups of players) consolidate into individual self-hosted games based on the chosen "playlist" (predefined groups of maps and game types, such as four-on-four Slayer games and free-for-all objective games). The game also includes player ranking (which can be influenced by special ranked playlists) and in-game clan support (special player lists similar to friend lists). The online multiplayer support for the Xbox version was discontinued on April 15, 2010.The game was ported to the PC by Microsoft, released on May 31, 2007. Although it did not support Windows XP (deliberately to promote Windows Vista) at the time (without the use of an unauthorized third-party patch), it was the first game to support Games For Windows - Live features such as achievements and guide support. It was also the only game to support Microsoft's Tray and Play feature, in which players can start playing the campaign while the game is installing. This version also includes two exclusive multiplayer maps (along with most of the DLC maps) and an official map editor. Multiplayer on PC remains active but future support is unclear.GameplayMultiplayer and dual-wielding in action.Halo 2 has a lot of updates over Halo: Combat Evolved. Under the new system, once shields have been depleted, the player can only take a few hits until death, but once shields recharge, health resets. This is explained through the new Mark VI suit, which injects bio-foam directly into the wearer's wounds. Active Camo has been removed as an item. Instead, the Arbiter has a rechargeable version of Camo, instead of a flashlight like the Chief. Another new addition is dual wielding certain weapons, including the pistol, the new SMG, the needler, the plasma pistol, and the plasma rifle. When dual wielding, weapons take longer to reload and the ability to throw grenades is taken out. Another newly added mechanic is the ability to board enemy vehicles when they are near the player and travelling at low speeds.The most noticeable change in the weapons is the absence of the iconic assault rifle. It is replaced by the new battle rifle; a three shot burst weapon with a 2x scope. The Covenant equivalent of the battle rifle is the carbine; a semi-automatic weapon that also has a 2x scope (the carbine uses ammo instead of battery power). In addition to the battle rifle and carbine, there is now the SMG (a small compact fully automatic weapon), a new pistol with no scope, the brute shot (Covenant grenade launcher), a brute plasma rifle (which fires faster than the regular plasma rifle), an improved rocket launcher (which locks onto enemy vehicles), and the energy sword (which can now be used by the player).WeaponsCompared to Halo: Combat Evolved, there have been some noticeable changes in the arsenals of both Human and Covenant forces. The MA5-series Assault Rifle has been absent, replaced by both the M7 Submachine Gun and BR55 Battle Rifle. The M6D Magnum has also been replaced by the weaker M6C Magnum. The Covenant now have new tools in their disposal: the semi-automatic Covenant Carbine, the long-ranged Particle Beam Rifle, the Brute Plasma Rifle, and the explosive Brute Shot. Players can now carry the Fuel Rod Gun and Energy Sword into combat, as well as equip the mysterious Sentinel Beam.Human WeaponsMagnum - A semi-automatic handgun useful for short-to-medium ranged combat. Unlike the sidearm used in the game's predecessor, however, this handgun is highly inaccurate at long ranges and does not deal much damage (but can be dual-wielded and has a higher rate-of-fire). Each clip contains 12 rounds and players can carry up to 48 rounds per Magnum. Formally known as the "M6C Personal Defense Weapon System".Submachine Gun - A fully-automatic submachine gun useful for suppression and close-ranged combat. The replacement for the previous game's Assault Rifle, it can be dual-wielded, has a high rate-of-fire, and features a high magazine size, but deals low damage per shot, is very inaccurate, and has uncontrollable recoil. Each clip contains 60 rounds and players can carry up to 180 rounds per Submachine Gun. Formally known as the "M7/Caseless Submachine Gun".Battle Rifle - A battle rifle with a powerful three-round burst and a scope attachment (supporting 2x magnification). Very accurate and has barely any recoil. Each clip contains 36 rounds (12 bursts) and players can carry up to 108 rounds (36 bursts). Useful for medium-to-long ranged combat. Formally known as the "BR55 Battle Rifle".Shotgun - A pump-action shotgun that is deadly in close-ranged combat. Unlike the previous game's version, this version is weaker at anything but close-ranged enemies, and is significantly weaker against vehicles. Each shell must be fed to the Shotgun (which can hold 12 shells at a time) and players can carry up to 36 shells. Formally known as the "M90 Close Assault Weapon System".Sniper Rifle - A semi-automatic sniper rifle (with an electronic scope that supports both 5x and 10x magnification) that is deadly in long-ranged combat. Each clip contains 4 rounds and players can carry up to 20 rounds. Formally known as the "SRS99C-S2 AMB Sniper Rifle".Rocket Launcher - A powerful rocket launcher with a scope attachment (supporting 2x magnification). Although it has less firepower than the previous game's version, it has faster reload, faster melee, and can lock onto enemy vehicles (by zooming in and holding the crosshair over the vehicle). Each clip contains 2 rockets and players can carry up to 6 rockets. Formally known as the "M19 SSM Rocket Launcher".Frag Grenade - A standard timed fragmentation grenade with a three-second fuse. Can bounce off of surfaces. Formally known as the "M9 High-Explosive Dual-Purpose Grenade".Covenant WeaponsPlasma Pistol - A semi-automatic energy-blasting firearm that, while generally weak in short blasts, can be overcharged (by holding down the Fire button over time) into a larger superheated bolt that automatically locks onto enemy infantry (draining their shields) or enemy vehicles (causing the vehicle to become inactive for a short time). It can be dual-wielded, does not require reloading, and cannot be replenished by picking up ammo. Each Plasma Pistol's battery can carry up to 250 shots, and overcharging shots take up more of the battery over time (roughly 25 shots per fully overcharged bolt). Formally known as the "Type-25 Directed Energy Pistol".Plasma Rifle - A fully-automatic energy-blasting weapon useful for close-to-medium ranged combat. Continuously firing causes the weapon to overheat, in which the weapon must enter a cooldown phase. It can be dual-wielded, does not require reloading, and cannot be replenished by picking up ammo. Each Plasma Rifle's battery can carry up to 400 shots. Formally known as the "Type-25 Directed Energy Rifle".Brute Plasma Rifle - A special red variant of the Plasma Rifle that is usually carried by Brutes. Although each shot deals less damage than the standard Plasma Rifle, it has a higher rate-of-fire. It also overheats quicker and can also be dual-wielded. Very rarely found in Multiplayer. Formally known as the "Type-25 Directed Energy Rifle/Jiralhanae Variant".Needler - A fully-automatic projectile weapon that rapidly fires sharp purple crystalline shards. These shards lock on to enemies, impales them (dealing some damage), and detonate harmlessly after some time. However, seven or more impalements at one time causes all of them to detonate powerfully (known as a super-charge), killing that enemy. Each clip contains 30 shards, and players can carry up to 90 shards per Needler. Can be dual-wielded. Formally known as the "Type-33 Guided Munitions Launcher".Covenant Carbine - A semi-automatic marksman rifle with a scope attachment (supporting 2x magnification). Firing a powerful green blast useful for medium-to-long ranges, it becomes more inaccurate in quick blasts. Each clip contains 18 rounds, and players can carry up to 72 rounds. Formally known as the "Type-51 Carbine".Particle Beam Rifle - A semi-automatic energy-blasting equivelant of a sniper rifle with a scope attachment (supporting both 5x and 10x magnification). It does not require reloading, but can overheat if continuously fired (in which it must enter a cooldown phase). It also cannot be replenished by picking up ammo. Each Particle Beam Rifle's battery can carry up to 18 shots. Formally known as the "Type-50 Sniper Rifle System".Brute Shot - A belt-fed grenade launcher with a large blade attached to it (for more damaging melee attacks). Grenades can bounce over surfaces (like Frag Grenades), but does not deal as much damage as standard grenades. Each clip can carry up to 4 grenades, and players can carry up to 12 grenades. Formally known as the "Type-25 Grenade Launcher".Fuel Rod Gun - An energy-blasting equivelant of a rocket launcher. It does not deal as much damage as the Rocket Launcher, but each clip contains more explosive blasts. Each clip can carry up to 5 rods, and players can carry up to 25 rods. Very rarely found in Multiplayer. Formally known as the "Type-33 Light Anti-Armor Weapon".Energy Sword - A sword composed of glowing energy that is devastating for close-ranged combat. The Melee button performs a normal slash while the Fire button either performs another normal slash or, if the player's crosshair is over a close enemy, performs a lunging slash. The sword loses its energy after every successful strike for up to ten strikes (for the Campaign only, as it has infinite energy in Multiplayer). Formally known as the "Type-1 Energy Weapon/Sword".Plasma Grenade - A timed energy grenade that sticks to surfaces (including enemies and vehicles). Unlike the Frag Grenade, the three-second fuse occurs after the grenade sticks to a surface. Formally known as the "Type-1 Antipersonnel Grenade".Other WeaponsSentinel Beam - A forerunner weapon that continuously fires a long-ranged energy beam. Each weapon has a limited ammo count that cannot be replenished and is prone to overheating by continuous fire (in which it must enter a cooldown phase). Two versions of the Sentinel Beam exist: one that fires a standard orange beam, and one that fires a more powerful (but more likely to overheat) blue beam.Scarab Gun - An easter egg weapon found in secret areas of the single-player campaign. Has the appearance of a Plasma Rifle but continuously fires blasts similar to the Scarab Tank's main cannon. It never overheats and has unlimited ammo, but is easily prone to self-inflicted deaths.Skulls/Flags/Bombs - Skulls (both as single-player easter eggs and in the Oddball gametype), Flags (in the Capture the Flag gametype), and Bombs (in the Assault gametype) can be used to pummel people with melee attacks. Pressing the fire button drops the object.MultiplayerHalo 2 was the first Halo game on Xbox to feature online play through Xbox Live. The game had many advanced features including matchmaking, voice chat, and rankings. There was also some customization implemented into the game as well, which created a lot of user created content. Many games came out of these customization options, such as Tremors, Troy, Vehicle Wars and the most popular being Zombies which grew so popular Bungie saw fit to put it into Halo 3. Players really enjoyed the customization options and kept many players sticking around even after getting their fill of matchmaking. The match making games were very competitive in Halo 2 due to the intensive ranking system. The way the ranking system in Halo 2 works is when you first start playing the game you start with the level 1 and as you win matches your level increases. If you lose enough matches you can drop levels. These ranking were taken very seriously by the Halo 2 community. The color of the level a player had was very important to most Halo 2 fanatics. You can see what the levels look like in the picture below.Levels 44-50 were "secret" levels -- they were picture of various things, such as the moon or the halo ring.Halo 2 had 24 maps the people could play online and was the most played game ever on Xbox Live. Even after the Xbox 360 was released Halo 2 still remained the most popular. The first game to top the amount of online players Halo 2 had each month, was the original Gears of War.ClanHalo 2 is one of the few Xbox games ever that supported "clans", which are basically a group or team of players that play games against other "clans". This was a huge part of Halo 2 and was very successful. Clans on console games have never really worked that well and Halo 2 introduced a quick, and easy, way to make them without having the dedication PC clan members have. To check out your clan you press the Y button and bring up the friends list, you can scroll right, which will bring you to the clan page. If you are not in a clan, you can join a clan (if you were invited to a clan). You must receive a "clan invite" to be able to join a clan. If you have not been invited to a clan, you can create your own clan. If you decide to go down this route, you will be asked to create a unique name for your clan. This name can not be changed and must be appropriate, or Bungie will reject the name. After creating a name, you must invite people to join your clan. Players are only allowed to be in one clan at one time. When members join, they will first be at the level of member, but the Overlords of the clan are allowed to change their status.Clan Status LevelsOverlord- The creator of the clan is the Overlord and has complete control over the clan. The Overlord can elect other trustworthy clan members to also be an Overlord.Staff- Staff members are important respected members of a clan. Their level of power can vary by the amount of power the Overlord gives Staff members.Member- When someone joins a clan, they are a Member. This is the middle class in a clan. Most clan members are Members. Members do not hold much power.Peon- The level of Peon is the lowest level of status. Peons hold no power.Matchmaking PlaylistsRumble PitDouble TeamTeam SlayerTeam SkirmishTeam TrainingTeam SnipersTeam HardcoreBig Team BattleTeam SWATH2 ChallengeMultiplayer MapsThe Xbox version of Halo 2 included 12 multiplayer maps. One of the maps (Foundation) had to be unlocked by triggering a training event on the last level of the campaign, but was made available to all in a patch.LockoutAscensionMidshipIvory TowerBeaver Creek (remake of Battle Creek from Halo: Combat Evolved)Burial MoundsColossusZanzibarCoagulation (remake of Blood Gulch from Halo: Combat Evolved)HeadlongWaterworksFoundation (based on the Thunderdome levels from the Marathon series)Bonus Map PackThe Bonus Map Pack is one of the first two downloadable map packs for Halo 2. It was originally released for free on April 25, 2005 and contained two maps:ContainmentWarlock (remake of Wizard from Halo: Combat Evolved)Killtacular Map PackThe Killtacular Map Pack is also one of the first two downloadable map packs for Halo 2. It was originally released for $4.99 on April 25, 2005, was made free on June 28, 2005, and contained two maps:SanctuaryTurfMaptacular Map PackThe Maptacular Map Pack is the third downloadable map pack for Halo 2. It was originally released for $11.99 on July 5, 2005, was made free on August 30, 2005, and contained five maps:BackwashElongation (remake of Longest from Halo: Combat Evolved)Gemini (remake of Duality from Marathon)RelicTerminalBlastacular Map PackThe Blastacular Map Pack is the fourth and last downloadable map pack for Halo 2. It was originally released for $4.00 on April 17, 2007, was made free on July 7, 2007, and contained two map remakes from the original Halo. As of April 15, 2010, there is no way to download this map pack.Desolation (remake of Derelict from Halo: Combat Evolved)Tombstone (remake of Hang 'Em High from Halo: Combat Evolved)Vista-exclusive mapsAlong with the original maps and maps from the Bonus, Killtacular, and Maptacular map packs, the Windows Vista version of Halo 2 features two new exclusive multiplayer maps:DistrictUpliftHalo 2 Multiplayer Map PackThe retail box art for the Multiplayer Map Pack.On July 5, 2005, Microsoft Game Studios published a retail disc for $19.99 containing the Bonus, Killtacular, and Maptacular map packs, as well as game updates (up to July 5, 2005) and bonus content. The map compilation was developed primarily for Xbox owners that are not subscribed to Xbox Live. The disc also includes a bonus three-minute Halo 2 cutscene (showing what happens to the marines in the Pelican that is shot down in the intro sequence to the level Outskirts), a video documentary on the development of the maps included in the disc, the original trailer for Halo: Combat Evolved, the Halo 2 announcement trailer, and a humorous audio clip used to test your surround sound set-up. The disc is also backwards-compatible with the Xbox 360 and is the only current way to download the Bonus, Killtacular, and Maptacular map packs. (Unless you're playing the Windows Vista version)Multiplayer GlitchesSeveral weeks and months after Halo 2's release, players began to discover and take advantage of several relatively major glitches in the game. As players began to practice these glitches and become well-versed in executing them they gained a much more significant place in the meta-game, with some of the weapon-based glitches becoming essential for success against the higher ranking players. While game creator Bungie officially decreed on several occasions that a player's use of glitches for personal gain, in a Matchmaking setting, was a form of cheating, the developer had no way of tracking the use of such glitches by players. Ultimately, there were no widespread punishments or repercussions handed-down to players who utilized these glitches.Some of the most noteworthy glitches:BXRCommonly used in conjunction with the Battle Rifle (though possible to execute with any reloadable weapon) the BXR was a weapon animation glitch that allowed for a nearly instantaneous close-ranged kill. The glitch became very widespread among the highest ranks of players as the meta-game progressed.Quick Reload (YY)Another glitch commonly used among higher-caliber players, the Quick Reload glitch was a weapon animation glitch that shaved precious seconds off of a player's reload time, allowing them to fire their weapon again sooner than they normally would with the default reload. The glitch was only possible when a player was carrying a secondary weapon. The move was executed by the player pressing the Y button twice in quick succession as soon as the reload animation reached the point where the in-game character began to insert a new clip into the weapon. If done properly the player will quickly switch to their secondary weapon and then back to their primary, eliminating the rest of the reload animation while still giving the player a full clip.Double Melee (BXB)A third weapon animation glitch, the BXB was used to give players a significant advantage in close-range combat. Executed by pressing B, X, B in quick succession (under the default controller settings), the glitch allowed players to melee twice in a much shorter time span than if they were simply to press the melee button two times. Contrary to the BXR, which required a full clip of ammo to execute properly, the BXB required the player to have a partially depleted or empty ammo clip in their primary weapon. As with the other weapon glitches, the BXB saw very widespread use among the top-tier players.Double Shot (RRX)One of the most popular glitches among MLG fans and players, the Double Shot was a glitch that was used primarily with the Battle Rifle that allowed players to fire two of the weapon's 3-shot bursts in one shot, resulting in 6 bullets being fired at once. The downside to this glitch was that after successfully firing a Double Shot, there was a significant span of time (roughly two to three seconds) where the player could not fire their weapon, and could only attack if they threw a grenade, used a melee attack, or switched to a secondary weapon. For this reason players would often hold off on using a Double Shot unless they were one or several "shots down" in a BR fight, or had a secondary weapon that they could "YY" with to cancel the long delay after a successful double shot.Quad Shot (RRXYYRRX)Similar to the double shot the quad shot, if done right, can shoot 4 shots out of the BR in half the time it normally would take. To do this you need two weapons, first you start out with your double shot then you press "YY" really fast in order to cancel the reload, if you double shot correctly you will notice the reload animation isn't playing but it is still reloading in the background this is normal so don't worry, now after pressing "YY" do another double shot, and with much practice you can do this .Super Bouncing (also known as Super Jumping)A first-person view from a player who "super-bounced" to the top of the map Ascension.A glitch in the game's Havok physics engine that makes it possible for players to "bounce" to extreme heights, enabling them to reach previously inaccessible and out-of-bounds regions on a multiplayer map. The glitch was used quite frequently in a Matchmaking setting to give a player or team a significant advantage through an unreachable hiding spot or unfair vantage point.Sword Canceling (Butterflying)Sword canceling is a glitch that takes advantage of the "lunge" effect that the Energy Sword provides for the player. By aiming at an opponent with the Energy Sword at a close enough proximity for the reticule to light up red, then pressing the Right Trigger and X in quick succession, a player can achieve the normal Sword lunge without in any way damaging their opponent. The glitch is most commonly used to give players a means of reaching previously inaccessible ledges or areas of a map. The glitch earned the nickname "Butterflying" due to the strange, butterfly-like motion of the character model's arms when performing the sword cancel.Rocket Sword GlitchA glitch that would require a sword and a rocket launcher as a secondary. You would look at an enemy from a distance and rapidly alternate pressing "Y" and "B" and you would launch towards the person you were aiming at from afar.CheatingAs with most online games, Halo 2's online environment featured some players who manipulated and modified certain aspects of the game to provide themselves with an unfair advantage over their opponents. Players cheated most commonly in matchmaking playlists, so that they could more easily obtain a matchmaking rank that players would see associated with their gamertag. The highest-level matchmaking ranks, that featured symbols in place of numbers (ranks 44-50), were the most desirable and most sought after ranks to cheaters; therefore, non-cheaters often found it very difficult to play a legitimate, cheat-free match at the highest ranks. There were several different methods of cheating, each with different effects on gameplay.ModdingAchieved through the use of cheat-devices such as Action Replay, Modding was the most common, game-changing form of cheating. "Modders" manipulated map files and gametypes to create gameplay that was well-outside the normal limits placed by the game engine. Common modded elements were changes in player speed and gravity, changed weapon properties (such as Plasma Rifles that fired Wraith projectiles), and changed vehicle properties (flying Warthogs, flying turrets, faster Scorpions, etc.). Due to the dramatic, game-changing effects of modding, it was fairly easy for Bungie's automated banning tool -- notoriously dubbed the "Banhammer" by players and Bungie staff -- to detect and ban players who used modded files in matchmade games. Most "modders" had only a few hours, at most, to rise through the matchmaking ranks before being faced with a permanent ban, and a vast majority of modders were inevitably banned. The problem was that there were so many free two-month Xbox Live trials available, it was easy for a modder to quickly make another account.StandbyingThe second most game-changing form of cheating, behind Modding, was known as Standbying. Making use of the game's host-based server system, standbying was achieved by having the "host" player manipulate their internet connection to cause problems for the other players in the match. When the host managed to successfully tamper with their connection, it would cause all of the other players in the game to experience enormous amounts of lag. The host's Xbox was immune to the lag issues, and could travel around the map killing enemy players or completing game objectives without much, if any, opposition. Though the Standby glitch was originally achieved by players manually pressing the "Standby" button on their router, modem, or switch, eventually players used various computer software so that they could throttle the connections of only the opposing team, giving all of their teammates a reprieve from the negative effects of the glitch. Eventually, Bungie improved the banhammer to better detect and control "standbyers" in matchmaking.BridgingBridging was a method of controlling "host" in a matchmaking game, and, more specifically, a way of ensuring that a certain player in the game always received host. Unlike modding and standbying, though, bridging was not a very detrimental form of cheating on its own. Bridging was accomplished through the use of specific Firewall software that controlled the ports and incoming IP Addresses for a player's router or switch. By using the program with the correct settings, a player could be ensured of being host for every game they played. Also, due to the nature of the glitch, bridgers could not be matched with or against other bridgers, so the bridging player always decided who received host. While Bridging was used in conjunction with Standbying or Modding to ensure that those forms of cheating worked as efficiently as possible by giving a certain player host, it was also used as a preventative measure against cheaters. Some players used bridging to make sure that no nefarious players could obtain host, therefore ensuring a quality match experience. As of the 1.6 update for Halo 2, the most common methods of Bridging were no longer effective or possible in matchmaking.SoundtrackThe Halo 2 Original Soundtrack was released in two volumes, composed by Martin O'Donnel and Michael Salvatori. Volume One was released on November 9th, 2004 and Volume Two was released on April 25th, 2006.Halo 2 Original Soundtrack: Volume One (69:20)Volume OneHalo Theme (4:11)Blow Me Away - Breaking Benjamin (3:25)Peril (2:46)Ghosts of Reach (2:22)Follow (1st Movement of the Odyssey) - Incubus (4:15)Heretic, Hero (2:34)Flawed Legacy (1:58)Impend (2:21)Never Surrender - Nile Rodgers (3:35)Ancient Machine (1:38)2nd Movement of the Odyssey - Incubus (7:40)In Amber Clad (1:39)The Last Spartan (2:18)Orbit of Glass (1:18)3rd Movement of the Odyssey - Incubus (6:40)Heavy Price Paid (2:31)Earth City (3:06)High Charity (1:59)4th Movement of the Odyssey - Incubus (9:07)Remembrance (1:17)Connected - Hoobastank (2:39)Halo 2 Original Soundtrack: Volume Two (68:48)Volume Two1. Prologue (2:35)Rising (0:20)Cloistered Expectancy (0:25)Weight of Failure (1:50)2. Cairo Suite (9:42)Cold Blue Light (1:54)Waking Spartan (3:36)Jeweled Hull (2:03)Chill Exposure (2:09)3. Mombasa Suite (6:41)Metropole (1:29)Broken Gates (2:47)Encounter (2:25)4. Unyielding (3:04)5. Mausoleum Suite (8:10)Destroyer's Invocation (4:36)Falling Up (1:49)Infected (1:16)Shudder (0:29)6. Unforgotten (2:09)7. Delta Halo Suite (11:29)Penance (2:32)Wage (2:42)Leonidas (2:28)Dust and Bones (3:44)8. Sacred Icon Suite (7:26)Cortege (3:38)Opening Volley (0:28)Veins of Stone (3:20)9. Reclaimer (3:03)10. High Charity Suite (8:29)Rue and Woe (1:30)Respite (2:17)Antedilluvial (2:22)Pursuit of Truth (2:18)11. Finale (3:10)Great Journey (1:15)Thermopylae Soon (1:55)12. Epilogue (3:49)Beholden (1:03)Road to Voi (2:19)Subsume (0:27)System RequirementsWindows Vista/7 Operating System2.0 GHz computer processor1 GB of RAM7 GB of Hard Disk spaceATI X700 or Nvidia 6100 display adapter with 128 MB of RAM with Pixel and Vertex Shader 2 or higher.Vista Experience IndexGame Recommended Rating - 5.0Game Required Rating - 3.0</description><genres /><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2079825-box_halo2.png</image></root>