<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7139</id><name>Hokuto no Ken</name><description>OverviewHokuto no Ken is a NES game published by Toei Animation and developed by Shoei System and Toei Animation. Hokuto no Ken is the Japanese name for Fist of the North Star. This version of the game was only released in Japan, the second Japanese release was the first to be sold in America.StoryThe story take place in the Hokuto No Ken story where Kenshiro faces the bosses from Shin all the way up to Raoh.GameplayThis player controls Kenshiro where he can move either left or right and can jump across the 5 stages. He can attack using his punches and kick and both can hit either high or low to take out the enemies. Upon killing an enemy, either one of two things would happen:If the player is kicked, the enemy is flown across whilst he is still kicking (This also happens if the player dies).If the player is punched, just like the manga/anime, the enemies would shout out "Abeshi" and explode.Find Lynn to enter the correct doorInitially the enemies can be killed with just one punch but later on, they require two hits and eventually three hits to kill them. Only a maximum of 3 enemies appear on the screen and can also throw daggers and axes. There as also a mechanic to open doors in many different buildings by pressing A+B+Up. A small picture of Lynn appears on the door to show the right way to the boss. If the player keeps moving to the left, the stage will be endless until a door is opened. Once the player correctly enters the right doors, a boss appears and must be defeated to progress with Kenshiro's signature moves.Boss CharactersBossesDescriptionMr. Heart - His attacks involve charging at the player which deals for a huge amount of damage and punching. If he's constantly being kicked, he will then be killed exactly like the anime where his stomach will be permanently deformed and explode.Shin - He can perform a high jump and can throw projectiles at the player.Jagi - Can perform a high jump, can punch and can throw neeSouther - Can hurl a 3 way projectile at the player which can damage the player greatly.Raoh - He is surrounded by his aura and can push the player back to the edge of the screen. If attacked correctly, his helmet can come off.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1653">Ninja Gaiden</game><game id="20436">Streets of Rage</game><game id="20752">Double Dragon</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2453/1536924-hnk1_front.jpg</image></root>