<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7197</id><name>Dragon Quest V: Hand of the Heavenly Bride</name><description>OverviewDragon Quest V is the fifth installment in the popular RPG series, Dragon Quest and was developed by Chunsoft and published by Enix Corporation. Dragon Quest V was the first Dragon Quest game to appear on the Super Famicom (the Super Nintendo in the United States), released on September 17, 1992.A remake developed by ArtePiazza and Matrix Software and published by Square Enix was released in 2004 on the PlayStation 2. A Nintendo DS remake was released on July 17, 2008 in Japan, and February 17, 2009 in the U.S. This was once again developed by ArtePiazza and published by Square Enix and was the first time any version of Dragon Quest V was available in the U.S. and Europe.Dragon Quest V offered a new feature in the Dragon Quest series in which some monsters in random battle sequences will ask to join the player's party. This was later used in the spin-off series Dragon Quest Monsters (which is also seen as the spiritual predecessor to Pokemon). Dragon Quest V is regarded as one of the best RPGs of all-time, placing 11 on Famitsu's top 100 games of all-time.GameplayDragon Quest V generally offers the same gameplay expected from the Dragon Quest series. Your characters will level up by gaining experience points earned in battles (that take place in first person). The new feature added into this installment was the ability to tame monsters. The monster joined the player's party and leveled up in the same way that all the other characters do. However, certain monsters have a lower level cap (i.e. the Great Dragon recruit caps at level 60). The Super Famicom version had 40 different tamable monsters while both the PlayStation 2 and Nintendo DS version offered more.Dragon Quest V took a change from the previous two entries in the series (III and IV) in that it only allowed the player to have 3 players active in their party, while both III and IV allowed 4. The remakes once again allowed 4 active characters in their party.StoryThe story of Dragon Quest V spans 20 years (split into three generations) during which the player can marry and have children. There is no one big goal that the characters of Dragon Quest V are sent out to do. The game is more of just an adventure where the player will run into my obstacles along the way. However, about halfway through the game, the hero finds his mother kidnapped and transformed into a monster by Mildrath. For the rest of the game after that, finding the hero's mother is the main goal. One of the biggest story elements in Dragon Quest V are the time leaps the game takes. The game starts out with you as a child, later flashes forward to when the protagonist is a young adult where he marries, afterward, the game leaps forward to the protagonist adventuring with his children.RemakesPlayStation 2The PlayStation 2 remake was released on March 25, 2004. The game sold 722,000 copies on the first day and sold 1.5 million in its first month of release, making it the best selling Dragon Quest remake of all-time. The remake was developed by ArtePiazza, the former art directors of Dragon Quest VII. Because of this, the game features 3D graphics very similar to Dragon Quest VII. The remake also upgraded the active players limit to 4 and added more tamable monsters. Another new feature is Yuuji's Specialty Museum, where the player collects various specialties from around the world and returns them to Yuuji for various rewards.Nintendo DSThe Nintendo DS remake was released in Japan on July, 17, 2008. This version ran on the same engine as the Dragon Quest IV remake also on the Nintendo DS. The Nintendo DS version also introduced a third potential bride in Debora, Nera's older sister, who did not exist in prior versions of the game. Yuuji's Specialty Museum from the Japanese PS2 remake was localized as the Knick-Knackatory and featured the ability to trade knick-knacks through the DS's wireless capabilities. Dragon Quest V was released in the United States on February 17th 2009, and in Europe on February 20th 2009; this is the first time that Dragon Quest V has been available outside of Japan.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4793">Final Fantasy V</game><game id="5739">Lufia II: Rise of the Sinistrals</game><game id="9249">Chrono Trigger</game><game id="20829">Final Fantasy IV</game><game id="21463">Final Fantasy III</game><game id="15629">Breath of Fire</game><game id="2516">Lufia &amp; the Fortress of Doom</game><game id="23936">7th Dragon</game><game id="14350">Etrian Odyssey</game><game id="20511">Etrian Odyssey II: Heroes of Lagaard</game><game id="12462">Secret of the Stars</game><game id="21240">Black Sigil: Blade of the Exiled</game><game id="24200">Sands of Destruction</game><game id="23143">Monster Racers</game><game id="23478">Suikoden Tierkreis</game><game id="22803">A Witch's Tale</game><game id="3638">Final Fantasy Mystic Quest</game><game id="25435">Dragon Ball Z: Attack of the Saiyans</game><game id="20128">Wild Arms Alter Code: F</game><game id="4822">Wild Arms 3</game><game id="4248">Lunar 2: Eternal Blue Complete</game><game id="24865">The Dark Spire</game><game id="23987">Nostalgia</game><game id="26372">Pokémon HeartGold/SoulSilver</game><game id="26833">Golden Sun: Dark Dawn</game><game id="26932">Glory of Heracles</game><game id="27186">Final Fantasy: The 4 Heroes of Light</game><game id="3755">Persona 2: Innocent Sin</game><game id="5827">Final Fantasy Legend II</game><game id="3928">Tengai Makyou II: Manjimaru</game><game id="23450">Tengai Makyou: Ziria</game><game id="25150">Summon Night X: Tears Crown</game><game id="23904">Ni no Kuni: Shikkoku no Madoshi</game><game id="30297">Metal Max 3</game><game id="9964">Revelations: The Demon Slayer</game><game id="4338">Final Fantasy Anthology</game><game id="33729">Gdleen</game><game id="34771">PoPoLoCrois: Tsuki no Okite no Bouken</game><game id="20398">Megami Tensei Gaiden: Last Bible II</game><game id="41682">Penny Arcade's On the Rain-Slick Precipice of Darkness 4</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1875220-box_dq5hothb.png</image></root>