<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7207</id><name>Greg Hastings' Tournament Paintball</name><description>OverviewGreg Hastings' Tournament Paintball is first person paintball game developed by WXP, Inc. and published by Activision Value Publishing, Inc. exclusively for the Xbox on November 16, 2004.Game ModesGreg Hastings' Tournament Paintball has two primary modes of play, Single Player Career Mode and Multiplayer Online via Xbox Live or System Link.Single PlayerTournament PlayThere are three types of tournaments to compete in:Elimination: The player competes until one team has been eliminatedCenter Flag: Points are scored by eliminating opponents, being the first team to grab the flag located in the center of the field, and finally hanging the flag at the opposing team's start boxCapture the flag: Similar to Center Flag, however each team has a flag located at their start box. Players must retrieve the opposing team's flag and return it to back to their own start box to end the match.Tournament Scoring:First flag grab20 pointsFlag hang50 points3-on-3 match7 points for each elimination3 points for each survivor5-on-5 match4 points for each elimination2 points for each survivor7-on-7 match3 points for each elimination1 point for each survivorSingle Player TournamentsPev's PaintballNorthwest ChallengeSkirmish PaintballSplatter Park PaintballSC VillageUltimate MadnessUrban OpenCalifornia OpenIsland OpenDesert OpenFlorida OpenTampa Bay OpenRocky Mountain OpenEnglish OpenPennsylvania OpenGerman OpenHuntington Beach OpenFrench OpenJapanese OpenMultiplayer TournamentsPEV'S Large Woods FieldRooftopCharacter SkillsDuring the Single Player Career Mode the player develops a unique character, team and inventory of equipment. As the player completes tournaments they're awarded experience points that can be spent developing their character's skills. Experience points are based on the players performance and are accrued by completing Eliminations, Flag Grabs, Flag Hangs, and by winning Rounds, Matches and Tournaments. The skills to be developed are:SpeedLevel 1: Speed increase + turbo time increaseLevel 2: Speed increase + additional turbo time increaseLevel 3: Speed increase + turbo replenish increaseLevel 4: Speed increase + additional turbo replenish increaseAccuracyLevel 1: Increase your targeting accuracy by 10%Level 2: Increase your targeting accuracy by 20%Level 3: Increase your targeting accuracy by 30%Level 4: Increase your targeting accuracy by 40%Marker SkillLevel 1: Increase snap range by 15%Level 2: Increase snap range by 30%Level 3: Switch marker hands 20% fasterLevel 4: Switch marker hands 40% fasterReloadLevel 1: More efficient at reloading - 70% of podLevel 2: More efficient at reloading - 90% of podLevel 3: Faster and more efficient at reloading - 100% of podLevel 4: Moving while reloading is possibleThe GearMarkersThere are over twenty Paintgun Markers in the game from manufacturers including JT, Tippmann, Kingman, Odyssey, WGP, and Dye. Each individual marker has different weight, speed and accuracy ratings.BarrelsPlayers can customize their markers with individual barrels. Barrels will further increase the accuracy of the shots fired with Markers.HoppersThere are 5 different hoppers to choose from including gravity feed, electronic aligator and belt drive. Each hopper increases the number of paintballs loaded into the marker.Air SystemsAir systems provide Markers with the power they need to fire paintballs at high velocity. The larger the air tank, the more paintballs that can be fired. </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="24442">NPPL Championship Paintball 2009</game><game id="4530">Greg Hastings' Tournament Paintball MAX'D</game><game id="27531">Greg Hastings Paintball 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2492907-box_ghtp.png</image></root>