<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7212</id><name>Klonoa 2: Lunatea's Veil</name><description>OverviewKlonoa 2: Lunatea's Veil is the sequel to Klonoa: Door to Phantomile and it was released by Namco in March 2001. In this game, Klonoa meets a few new friends and joins them on an adventure in a magical world.StoryThough a sequel Klonoa 2 doesn't feature any of the same characters and plot elements seen in the previous game except for Klonoa himself. At the beginning of the game Klonoa finds that he has been summoned to save an unbalance dream worlds and is soon aided by the help of new characters Lolo and Popka. Throughout the game Klonoa travels to five different Kingdoms in a desperate search to save the balance.GameplayKlonoa 2: Lunatea's Veil ScreenThe game is very similar to its predecessor and contains many of the same core gameplay elements seen before, the graphics however are considerably improved due to the jump to Playstation 2. Klonoa 2 has you controlling Klonoa again through a series levels chosen from a map screen. New gameplay included Board Riding sections in which some where 3D and others were the traditional 2.5D platforming. The game also saw the inclusion of new enemies and characters including Lolo and Popka.Multi-player: Klonoa 2 features the inclusion of a semi multi-player mode in which a player on a secondary controller can take limited control of Popka and help Klonoa reach advanced areas. While this constitutes as multi-player it is rather a co op element to the single player game.Critical ReceptionGame Informer gave the review scores of 8.25 and 8.25. Matt Helgeson wrote, "Graphically, Klonoa 2 dazzles by combining Tomba 2's use of 2D platforming action set in rotating 3D environments with Jet Grind Radio's vibrant cel-shaded visuals. The gameplay, while simple, is nicely done, and makes good use of the simple concept of grabbing and throwing object and enemies...This is a solid kids-oriented title with enough to offer for those of us pass our elementary years".</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4228">Haven: Call of the King</game><game id="18473">Rayman</game><game id="609">Rayman 2: The Great Escape</game><game id="5821">Rayman 3: Hoodlum Havoc</game><game id="18309">Ratchet &amp; Clank</game><game id="4618">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Going Commando</game><game id="15212">Ratchet &amp; Clank Future: Tools of Destruction</game><game id="14623">Jak and Daxter: The Precursor Legacy</game><game id="10384">Jak II</game><game id="15353">Sly Cooper and the Thievius Raccoonus</game><game id="15573">Sly 2: Band of Thieves</game><game id="16337">Sly 3: Honor Among Thieves</game><game id="7836">Spyro the Dragon</game><game id="1563">Spyro 2: Ripto's Rage</game><game id="1753">Spyro: Year of the Dragon</game><game id="68">Crash Bandicoot: The Wrath of Cortex</game><game id="19453">Pandemonium 2</game><game id="25720">Jak and Daxter: The Lost Frontier</game><game id="2723">Tomba! 2: The Evil Swine Return</game><game id="3849">Mischief Makers</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1897540-box_klonoa2.png</image></root>