<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7215</id><name>Monty Python &amp; The Quest for the Holy Grail</name><description>Overview Monty Python  the Quest for the Holy Grail used footage and imagery from the film, as well as audio clips (some new) and featured an animated version of a scene never filmed entitled "King Brian The Wild". It's part adventure, part puzzle and part interactive movie.You play as King Arthur, followed by your faithful servant Patsy and you travel from location to location in the game. In       each location, there are a large number of clickable spots       though finding them may well be difficult. Many, many of       them will do different things at different times. In fact,       the key to playing this game is patience. You may have to       do something a number of times before you get the desired       result. This is fun however, because many of the places       give you different results each time you click there. In each location, you have to find the swallow and shoot       it, in order to gain it's coconut. You also have to find the special item (found by clicking your way       through the dialogues and finding all the clickable areas       of the scene), and eventually place a special item on the       scene. The game uses real scenes from the movie       for backdrops. The video sequences have been nicely done       frequently using the footage from the original film to fill       in what is happening. As you place the special items, video       sequences will be shown. You may then enjoy them again by       looking at the Book of the Game.  The game also included a comical multiple-choice questionnaire which featured over a hundred questions, which one needed to complete in order to pass over the Bridge of Death. Minigames  Drop Dead - This is a variation of Tetris, as the bodies fall, you need to pack the           grave as best you can. Bodies will keep falling faster,           and the occasional one isn't quite dead yet, which           makes moving it around more challenging.   Knights in Kombat - As King Arthur, you must defeat           the Black Knight by slicing off his limbs as he zips around the area, the more limbs you cut off, the faster you go. As the Black Knight, you have to kill King Arthur from a first-person perspective. You will have to win as King Arthur to move on           in the game.  Burn the Witch - You need to watch the sequence in           which the witches burn and repeat the sequence           yourself. Or fail and have one witch die when you           do.  Catch the Cow - Those naughty Frenchmen are throwing           cows at your party. You need to prevent your men from           getting squished by clicking on them to turn them to           the right.  Spank the Virgin - This is a variation of Whack-A-Mole. If you are good enough at this           game, you get a special nude bonus round. The title of           the game is pretty self-explanatory. </description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15067">Eric the Unready</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/7900/290695-monty.jpg</image></root>