<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7258</id><name>Hard Drivin'</name><description>OverviewHard Drivin' is a first-person racing game developed by Domark, Binary Design and Tengen for the arcade. The game was primarily published by Atari and released in February of 1989. Ports for the Genesis, Lynx, Super Nintendo and various PC systems were released in the following years.GameplayThe original arcade game features a full sit-down cabinet, complete with an early force feedback enabled steering wheel. Races include many A.I. opponents, which are spread around the track sparingly after the race start. Lap counts are typically two, consisting of many stunt obstacles such as loops and jumps, forcing the player to measure their speed at certain times to not overshoot a landing ramp, or lose momentum through a loop. If the player finishes in a top position, they are given an extra one-on-one race against the "Phantom Photon".PresentationThe game was a substantial improvement in polygonal gaming, as most popular arcade racers of the time utilized animated 2-D sprites rather than a 3-D wire-frame environment. The player's vehicle strongly resembles a Ferrari Testarossa, which was a very popular sports car at the time of development.Traffic, A.I. opponents, and the fast-paced arcade music endemic to the late 1980's, are featured throughout Hard Drivin'.Hard Drivin' was the first arcade driving game to feature instant replay, which repeats the last several seconds of gameplay following a crash, in an elevated third-person perspective. The instant replay has its own specific musical accompaniment.   </description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15918">Stunts</game><game id="11260">OutRun</game><game id="10087">Pole Position</game><game id="21995">Stunt Car Racer</game><game id="13008">TrackMania Sunrise</game><game id="8972">TrackMania</game><game id="19987">Big Rigs: Over the Road Racing</game><game id="26092">Rad Mobile</game><game id="5027">Club Drive</game><game id="40043">Winning Run</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1987/629294-hard_drivin___front.jpg</image></root>