<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7270</id><name>Pokémon Stadium</name><description>OverviewBattle your Pokémon...IN 3-D!!!Pokémon Stadium is quite simply the battle aspect of Pokémon in full 3D for the Nintendo 64. It applied all the rules that the Game Boy games had in the battles. The original 151 Pokémon are used in this first entry for the franchise as your goal in the game is to beat all the cups varied by level, Pokémon gyms, and Mewtwo on all the difficulties provided twice.There are also mini-games included as a distraction from all the battling. A new piece of hardware for the N64, the Transfer Pak, came bundled with the game. This uniquely shaped peripheral is plugged like the Rumble and Controller Paks gives you the ability to use your own Pokémon from the Game Boy games into battle, which sparked the beginning of console to hand-held connectivity for Nintendo.If you don't have Pokémon Red, Blue, and Yellow, you can use rental Pokémon provided in the game, but with rentals the difficulty is higher. Also with the Transfer Pak, you can play the Game Boy games on your Nintendo 64 with the ability to speed up the game to train more Pokémon that can be moved from the game to the boxes Stadium has available. Pokémon Stadium series eventually had sequels to follow up with each generation of Game Boy Pokémon games.ModesStadiumThe place where tournaments are in Pokémon Stadium are held. There are four different types types of cups in the mode. Each has their own set of distinct rules and level requirements for the Pokémon involved. The player must register a set of 6 Pokémon to enter a tournament. A total of 10 different sets are allowed at a time. Pokémon can be taken from one of the Game Boy cartridges or using the rental method mentioned above. Once a player picks a set, a tournament of eight battles starts. At the beginning of each battle, both the computer and player picks three Pokémon.Poke Cup - Pokémon at levels 50-55 are allowed to participatePetit Cup - Pokémon at levels 25-30 are allowed to participatePika Cup - Pokémon at levels 15 -20 are allowed to participatePrime Cup - Pokémon at all levels are allowed to participateFree BattleOne to four players battle with a set of rules from the one of the Cups in Stadium Mode.Gym Leader CastlePlayers battle the eight gym leaders from the first three Game Boy games in succession. Like the hand held game, before battling the leader themselves, the player must battle a few of their cronies first.Victory PalaceThe player may look at statues of the Pokémon used to win tournaments in Stadium Mode here.GB TowerLet your GB Pokémon fight on the TV!In the GB Tower, players can play the Game Boy Pokémon games using the Transfer Pak included with the game. Each of the games has an overlay on the screen during gameplay, similar to the Super Game Boy overlays on the SNES. The games that can be played with the Transfer Pak are Pokémon Red, Pokémon Blue and Pokémon Yellow.Pokemon LabWith Professor Oak's help, you can check your Pokédex, organize items and even trade Pokémon. This mode requires a Game Boy Pokémon cartridge and the Transfer Pak.Kids ClubThe mode where the mini-games in Pokémon Stadium are held. There are 9 mini-games in all. Each game is 4 players. If four players are not present the computer takes over the remaining slots.Some adorable Rattatas running.Magikarp's Splash - The goal of this game is to make your Magikarp to splash high enough to hit the counter at the top of the screen. To do this, the player must press and hold the A button. Press the A button as it lands for quick splashes. The player with the most hits at the end wins.Clefairy Says - This game very similar to a good game of Simon Says, but filled with Clefairies. Arrows come up on a chalkboard in back of the room and the player must press the D-pad in the right order of the arrows. If not, a Clefairy dressed as a teacher bops you on the head for each incorrect answer.Run, Rattata, Run - This is a racing game that puts four Rattatas against each other. Players must repeatedly tap the A button to get their Ratatata moving on their treadmill. Obstacles sometimes come up causing the player to press the D-pad to jump.Thundering Dynamo - The goal of this game is to fully charge the Electric-type Pokémon given to you. To do this, players must press the right button at the right time. When the lamp in the back is green, the B button is pressed and when the button is blue, the A button is pressed. If the player presses the wrong button, its power drains.Snore Wars - While playing this game, the player controls one of four Drowzees in a circle. A pendulum is swinging back and forth between them. The goal of the game is to press the A button, while the pendulum hits the red needle in the middle to cast Hypnosis. The last one awake wins.Dig! Dig! Dig! - The player controls a Sandshrew digging its way to victory in this game. By pressing the L and R buttons the players makes the Sandshrew dig faster. The first one to hit water wins.Sushi - Go - Round - The player controls a Lickitung trying to eat as much as it can in this game. The player moves the Lickitung with the analog stick and eats food with the A button. Each food has a certain price associated to it. Some pieces are hot and can incapacitate the Lickitung for a while. The most expensive dinner wins.Rock Harden - Watch out for the boulders! The player takes control a Bug-type Pokémon in this game. When a boulder is coming towards the Pokémon press the A button to use Harden. Each Pokémon has HP and it drains with each hit by a boulder or use of Harden.Ekans' Hoop Hurl - The goal of this game is to get as many Ekans-made hoops on the Digletts as possible. By using the D-pad the player moves the Ekans and flicking the analog stick tosses it. The harder the flick the farther the it goes. Golden Digletts are worth more points.Pokédex1. Bulbasaur2. Ivysaur3. Venusaur4. Charmander5. Charmeleon6. Charizard7. Squirtle8. Wartortle9. Blastoise10. Caterpie11. Metapod12. Butterfree13. Weedle14. Kakuna15. Beedrill16. Pidgey17. Pidgeotto18. Pidgeot19. Rattata20. Raticate21. Spearow22. Fearow23. Ekans24. Arbok25. Pikachu26. Raichu27. Sandshrew28. Sandslash29. Nidoran (Female)30. Nidorina31. Nidoqueen32. Nidoran (Male)33. Nidorino34. Nidoking35. Clefairy36. Clefable37. Vulpix38. Ninetales39. Jigglypuff40. Wigglytuff41. Zubat42. Golbat43. Oddish44. Gloom45. Vileplume46. Paras47. Parasect48. Venonat49. Venomoth50. Diglett51. Dugtrio52. Meowth53. Persian54. Psyduck55. Golduck56. Mankey57. Primeape58. Growlithe59. Arcanine60. Poliwag61. Poliwhirl62. Poliwrath63. Abra64. Kadabra65. Alakazam66. Machop67. Machoke68. Machamp69. Bellsprout70. Weepinbel71. Victreebel72. Tentacool73. Tentacruel74. Geodude75. Graveler76. Golem77. Ponyta78. Rapidash79. Slowpoke80. Slowbro81. Magnemite82. Magneton83. Farfetch’d84. Doduo85. Dodrio86. Seel87. Dewgong88. Grimer89. Muk90. Shellder91. Cloyster92. Gastly93. Haunter94. Gengar95. Onix96. Drowzee97. Hypno98. Krabby99. Kingler100. Voltorb101. Electrode102. Exeggcute103. Exeggutor104. Cubone105. Marowak106. Hitmonlee107. Hitmonchan108. Lickitung109. Koffing110. Weezing111. Rhyhorn112. Rhydon113. Chansey114. Tangela115. Kangaskhan116. Horsea117. Seadra118. Goldeen119. Seaking120. Staryu121. Starmie122. Mr. Mime123. Scyther124. Jynx125. Electabuzz126. Magmar127. Pinsir128. Tauros129. Magikarp130. Gyarados131. Lapras132. Ditto133. Eevee134. Vaporeon135. Jolteon136. Flareon137. Porygon138. Omanyte139. Omastar140. Kabuto141. Kabutops142. Aerodactyl143. Snorlax144. Articuno145. Zapdos146. Moltres147. Dratini148. Dragonair149. Dragonite150. Mewtwo151. Mew64DD RootsThe game was originally planned to be released for Nintendo's failed hardware add-on for the N64, the 64DD. After it became apparent that the 64DD would not be a commercial success, Pokémon Stadium was moved to standard cartridge format. An expansion disc was also planned for the 64DD game and got canceled in the hardware move.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21617">Rayman: Raving Rabbids</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="9639">Dragon Seeds</game><game id="27048">Fossil Fighters</game><game id="23375">Gangway Monsters</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2171291-box_pkmnst.png</image></root>