<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7284</id><name>Indiana Jones and the Infernal Machine</name><description>PlotThe game takes place in Babylon where Indy meets up with Sophia Hapgood. Meanwhile, the Russians are digging around in old Babylonian ruins. At the request of Sophia, Indy attempts to discover what they are searching for. He finds that they are looking for an "infernal machine" that can be used to converse with the ancient Babylonian god, Marduk. Of course, Indy intends to find it first. Unfortuantely though, the machine is broken up into many pieces. Fortunately however, he stumbles upon a tablet that points to the locations of the various pieces. And thus, this is where Indy's quest (and the game) begins...GameplayThe gameplay has many notable similarities to the Tomb Raider games. To begin with, Indy is constantly exploring throughout the game. He runs through canyons, fields, and valleys (among other places). During this "exploration", he is jumping across chasms, exploring hidden passages, fighting wild beasts and the like. The fighting system can also be compared to that of the Tomb Raider franchise, players "lock on" to one enemy and then circle around: dodging its attacks and returning your own with gun, whip, or fists. Furthermore, there are numerous collectibles hidden in various places which Indy must climb, swim, crawl, and swing to get to. Some items are required finds, while others are bonuses that unlock various special features.Nintendo 64 VersionFrom March 1999 to October 2000 a team of eight Factor 5 employees ported the PC version of the game onto Nintendo 64. This version contains numerous improvements such as new lighting, particle system and camera. The music system was changed to use sequenced midi music instead of the PC version's pre-recorded music files and some new compositions were composed by Chris Hülsbeck.This version of the game only saw release in North America and was only available on the LucasArts online store and at Blockbuster.TriviaIndiana ThreepwoodPressing F10 and typing 'Makemeapirate' turned Indiana Jones into Guybrush Threepwood from the Monkey Island. When using the bazooka it will shoot chickens.There is a hidden room in the game which is a replication of the Barbery Coast in 3D from The Curse of Monkey Island.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8150">Tomb Raider: The Lost Artifact</game><game id="10746">Shadow Man</game><game id="3023">Tomb Raider</game><game id="337">Tomb Raider II</game><game id="19596">Tomb Raider III: Adventures of Lara Croft</game><game id="20694">Tomb Raider: Underworld</game><game id="8554">Lara Croft Tomb Raider: Legend</game><game id="20923">The Mummy: Tomb of the Dragon Emperor</game><game id="16589">The Mummy Returns</game><game id="35780">Unearthed: Trail of Ibn Battuta</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5911/712133-infernal_poster.jpg</image></root>