<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7301</id><name>Toy Story 2: Buzz Lightyear to the Rescue!</name><description>GameplayToy Story 2: Buzz Lightyear to the Rescue is a traditional style 3D Platformer. Much of the gameplay revolves around collecting Pizza Planet tokens to advance to further levels. Levels are unlocked by collecting certain amounts of Pizza Planet tokens. On each level there are five tokens, however usually one is only needed to advance to the next level. After every three levels, you access a new zone, which progresses you through the story. To proceed to the next zone, the person has to defeat a boss, who is usually from the movie. The Core gameplay focuses on collecting parts of Mr. Potato Head to unlock accessories for other challenges, collecting missing items for one of the characters in the level, collecting fifty tokens for Hamm, solving puzzles, or beating timed challeneges.   Toy Story 2: Buzz Lightyear to the Rescue is played mainly in Third Person Perspective, however when Buzz has to make a precision shot he can go into First Person Perspective, aim his laser and fire on targets. The game features cutscenes ripped from the movie itself, tying in events from the movie to the game. Buzz can acquire many non-essential upgrades that just help him progress easier, such as a more powerful laser upgrade which has limited battery, but these kind of upgrades are usually on platforms that are hard to reach. On most levels, Buzz will come across friendly faces such as Mr. Potato Head, Rex, Hamm and other essential characters from the Toy Story universe.   LevelsAndy's HouseAndy's NeighbourhoodBombs Away! (Boss Level)Construction YardAlleys and GulliesSlime Time! (Boss Level)Al's Toy BarnAl's Space LandToy Barn Encounter! (Boss Level)Elevator HopAl's PenthouseThe Evil Emperor Zurg! (Boss Level)Airport InfiltrationTarmac TroubleProspector Showdown! (Boss Level) </description><genres><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20330">Gex 3: Deep Cover Gecko</game><game id="14604">Daxter</game><game id="4618">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Going Commando</game><game id="8837">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Size Matters</game><game id="4966">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Up Your Arsenal</game><game id="36971">World Gone Sour</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2284722-box_ts2.png</image></root>