<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7306</id><name>Starscape</name><description>OverviewStarscape is a top-down space shooter with strategic elements. The game was developed by Moonpod, who released the game as shareware on March 27, 2003. The game saw a full release on June 29, 2004.StoryA space station named The Aegis begins an experiment to test the dimension drive, their new warp system. The dimension drive malfunctions during the experiment, sending The Aegis to an alternate dimension known as the Grid, where most of its crew is killed by an evil alien race. As the last remaining fighter pilot, the player must reconnect with the missing crew members, research and implement enhancements for The Aegis, fend off alien attacks, gather minerals from asteroids, and find the missing pieces of the dimension drive to escape the Grid dimension.GameplayStarscape is a 2D space shooter that is played from the overhead perspective. The player initiates encounters by traveling to various star systems that are shown on the Aegis' map screen. The player starts each encounter by choosing which ship they will use from the ship select screen. The player exits The Aegis once they have chosen their ship. If the player dies while in combat, they will respawn at the ship select screen. The ships’ movement speed is dependent on momentum, meaning that they slowly pick up speed and cannot stop on a dime.While in an encounter, the player’s main focus is protecting The Aegis from enemies. The Aegis is outfitted with upgradable turrets that automatically shoot any enemies within range, so it can protect itself, but it is fragile, and if it is destroyed the game is over. The player’s other main focus is to collect resources that are housed inside asteroids. The asteroids function very similarly to the ones in Asteroids: when the player destroys an asteroid, it splits into two smaller ones; that process repeats until the asteroid is completely destroyed. When the player destroys an asteroid, it is quite likely that one of three resource types will come out of the debris. To collect those resources, the player uses their tractor beam to suck them into their ship. The player’s storage capacity is limited, so they must deposit the resources into The Aegis to collect more. To deposit resources, the player must renter The Aegis, which will completely empty their storage (The Aegis may also be reentered to change the player’s ship or exit the area). These resources are used to repair The Aegis and fighter ships, research upgrades, and construct objects (ships, turrets, weapons, etc.).System RequirementsSupported OS: WindowsProcessor: Pentium II 300 MHz or higherMemory: 128Mb or more free system memoryHard disk space: 100MbDirectX version: DirectX 8 or higherVideo: Any Hardware 3D graphics accelerator with 32Mb or more of onboard memorySound: Any DirectSound compatible soundcardController: Any Direct compatible pad</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23214">Sinistar</game><game id="7030">Star Control II</game><game id="35942">Space Pirates and Zombies</game><game id="36681">Fusion: Genesis</game><game id="29777">Abaddon</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/7667/1552656-ssss_4.jpg</image></root>