<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7364</id><name>Blake Stone: Planet Strike</name><description>OverviewBlake Stone: Planet Strike (also known as just Planet Strike) is a sci-fi first-person shooter developed by JAM and published by Apogee for the PC on October 28, 1994. It is a sequel to Blake Stone: Aliens of Gold and, in similar vein to Spear of Destiny, consists of a single 20-level episode with new levels, monsters, weapons, and gameplay mechanics (such as a new level goal, new weapon graphics, destructible ammunition packs, and a flexible mini-map).Set in the year 2149, nine years after the events of the game's predecessor, players are put back into the boots of British secret agent Blake Stone. Years after a failed five-year manhunt for elusive mad scientist Dr. Pyrus Goldfire, intelligence uncovers suspicious activity in the abandoned STAR Institute Training Complex on the planet Selon. Blake is brought back for Operation: Planet Strike, in which he must infiltrate the complex, fight a brand new army of mutants, and attempt to stop Dr. Goldfire once and for all.The game never received a demo or shareware episode, and was later re-released (running under DOSBox) via GOG.com and Steam (via the Apogee Throwback Pack bundle, which also includes the predecessor and Rise of the Triad: Dark War).PC System RequirementsOperating System: Windows XP or Windows Vista.CPU: 1.8 GHz Processor.RAM: 512MB RAM (1 GB recommended).GPU: 3D graphics card compatible with DirectX 7 (compatible with DirectX 9 recommended).HDD: 2GB.Peripherals: Mouse and/or Keyboard.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7694">Wolfenstein 3D</game><game id="18539">Corridor 7: Alien Invasion</game><game id="9972">Operation Body Count</game><game id="12813">Spear of Destiny</game><game id="5403">Rise of the Triad: Dark War</game><game id="14462">Ken's Labyrinth</game><game id="4302">Pathways into Darkness</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/4/48222/1085509-565008_29835_front.jpg</image></root>