<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7382</id><name>Loaded</name><description>Loaded was released for the PlayStation near launch, and was met with decent sales and moderately good reviews. Loaded features very simple over head gameplay similar much to that of games like Gauntlet or Project Overkill. The gameplay is simple two dimensional, in which you seek out color marked keys to unlock the color corresponding door. There are different enemy types throughout the games 15 stages all of which die rather easily. You pick from one of 6 characters, all with their own unique look, weapon and abilities. Movement in the game is done through the use of the D-Pad, and players may only move in one of 8 basic directions. Players used their one weapon attack and had one special attack, that was usually a bomb style weapon. There was no jumping or anything else along those lines, but it was simple clean fun. Much like a bloody version of Gauntlet, players could co-op with one other friend. The game's sales were satisfactory enough to produce a sequel, Reloaded. The Soundtrack was original but was considered to be one of the finest parts of the overall package. The game's CDROM could be used as an audio CD and contained the games 25 songs. They were written by several real world DJs, including Pop Will Eat Itself. CharactersMamma Weapon: Plasma GunBomb: Ripple GrenadeFwankWeapon: CannonBomb: Explosive Teddy BearBounca Weapon: Missile LauncherBomb: Frag MissileVoxWeapon: Hail FlailBomb: Sonic BlastButchWeapon: FlamethrowerBomb:Explosive RingCap n' handsWeapon: Flintlock Pistols Bomb: Vortex Bomb Enemies Inmates Guards Crazies  Dogs Rats Scorpions Zombies Mutants Armored Assaulter Guard Robot FUB - Boss of the Game Stages Prison - Holding CellsPrison - Administration Upper Service ConduitLower Service ConduitMain GateDesertBadlandsSpace Port Level 1 Space Port Level 2Docking BayScrap YardProcessing PlantRecycling CenterSecurity LevelControl Center</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8442">ONE</game><game id="2893">Re-Loaded</game><game id="13246">Project Overkill</game><game id="948">The Chaos Engine</game><game id="3472">Cannon Spike</game><game id="3246">O.D.T. - Escape... Or Die Trying</game><game id="16449">Gauntlet: Seven Sorrows</game><game id="5888">God Hand</game><game id="16194">Smash TV</game><game id="24253">Burn Zombie Burn!</game><game id="31028">Steel Harbinger</game><game id="14991">Crack Down</game><game id="38399">Serious Sam: The Greek Encounter</game><game id="15736">Take No Prisoners</game><game id="39452">Hotline Miami</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1614/811605-loaded_ps_us.jpg</image></root>