<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7391</id><name>Mega Man 7</name><description>OverviewMega Man 7 title screen.Mega Man 7 (known as Rockman 7 Shukumei no Taiketsu in                 Japan, which is literally Rockman 7: A Destined Confrontation) was released on March 23, 1995 in North America, March 24, 1995 in Japan, and March 24, 1995 in Europe for the                Super Nintendo Entertainment System. The game is also playable in the                                Mega Man Anniversary Collection for the               PlayStation 2,              Nintendo             GameCube, and            Xbox. Mega Man 7 was developed and published by                                Capcom. The game is part of the original                                Mega Man series, consisting of the games                                Mega Man through      Mega Man 10. Mega Man 7 is more well-known for the introduction of characters                                Bass and                                Treble (Forte and Gospel in Japan).  In 2008, an 8-bit fan-made version of Mega Man 7 was released to coincide with Mega Man 9's revival of the classic series. The free-to-play rom can be found here.GameplayBeatMega Man 7 is very similar to the previous six titles in the                                Mega Man franchise, except for several refinements to gameplay. Mega Man 7 was the third Mega Man game to have a store with wares such as items and           powerups available for a set amount of "bolts," the currency of the game which can be collected during levels. To access the store, the player must press the select button on the stage select screen. Later games, such as                                Mega Man IV (         Game Boy version),                                Mega Man V (Game Boy version),                                Mega Man 8,                                Mega Man  Bass, and Mega Man 9 also featured the store.In         Slash Man's stage, the character         Beat is unlockable upon being rescued. Beat's job, unlike in                                Mega Man 5 and                                Mega Man 6 where he attacks enemies, is to rescue                                Mega Man when he falls into a pit. The player can hold up to four of Beat's whistles, summoning Beat. Beat can also carry Mega Man for a short period of time, but when it runs out, Beat drops him. If Beat drops Mega Man in a pit by accident, or if the player runs out of whistles, then Mega Man loses a life.BassCapcom, being the creators of the                                Street Fighter franchise, slipped in an extra two player versus mode. It is two rounds long and can be accessed by typing a password while holding L and R. When the password is inputted without L and R, it takes the player (fully powered Mega Man) to the very last                                Wily Level.  The weapons that Mega Man earns from the eight bosses of the game play more of a role in Mega Man 7. For example, the weapons can be use to alter the environment to discover hidden areas for secret  items. In Slash Man's stage, the scorch wheel weapon can be use to burn some of the trees that are in the level.Mega Man 7 also introduces the game with a level, making it the first game in the series to have an introductory level. This level serves as the introduction of the story, and shows new characters Bass and Treble, who serve as Mega Man and                                Rush's rivals.PlotThe destroyed city.Mega Man 7 opens with a retrospective of Mega Man and his friends defeating the threat of Dr. Wily by battling him through the course of several years. In 20XX, Dr. Wily was finally sent to jail, and the world sighed in relief when the door shut. Of course, Dr. Wily was a genius, so he planned for such an event.He knew that one day Mega Man may bring him to justice, so he anticipated his capture. His hidden lab contained four Robot Masters who were backup in case this happened. If, for six months, they didn't receive any communication from Dr. Wily, then they would automatically activate and go search for Dr. Wily. Since Dr. Wily is in jail, the robots activate after six months of peace. They go on a rampage and cause chaos through the city.Mega Man, upon hearing of the destruction, jumps into action. Mega Man goes to the city with his sister, Roll, and robot friend Auto to investigate this problem. After they find that the road is unstable, Mega Man continues alone, where he finds Dr. Light and Rush. Dr. Light points out the prison where Dr. WIly is being held, and four objects are streaking towards it (the four Robot Masters). They destroy the prison and free Dr. Wily.Wily's CastleNaturally, Mega Man chases after Dr. Wily. Bass, a robot with very similar abilities as Mega Man, and Treble, whose abilities are akin to Rush, are dispatched to deal with Mega Man, but it is revealed after a brief battle that the two are also fighting Dr. Wily. But before they can explain why, they disappear.After defeating all four Robot Masters (not to mention four more that Dr. WIly builds), Mega Man returns to Dr. Light's  lab. It is destroyed, and Dr. Light blames it on Bass and Treble, who are apparently creations of Dr. Wily. Bass wanted to steal blueprints for an upgrade: the Super Adapter, a combination of Rush Jet Suit and Rush Power Suit from Mega Man 6.Mega Man sets out for Dr. WIly's laboratory, and after re-fighting all eight Robot Masters, as well as various other robots, Mega Man makes it to Bass (who has been upgraded using the blueprints). Mega Man defeats him and moves on to Dr. Wily. Mega Man defeats Dr. Wily's many robotic forms, but as Dr. Wily is begging for mercy, Mega Man heartlessly walks over to Dr. Wily and aims his Mega Buster at his head.He begins charging his Mega Buster, and says that he should, "do what I should have done years ago," but Dr. Wily reminds him that as he is a robot, he cannot harm humans. Mega Man stops as the fortress starts to fall. A bar falls from the ceiling, pinning Dr. Wily, but before Mega Man can do anything else, Treble teleports in and saves Dr. Wily. Mega Man walks away from the exploding castle, victorious.   Levels            Slash Man's Stage   Heavily based off the film Jurassic Park, Slash Man's stage contains robotic dinosaurs--some can shoot razor sharp propellers, and others can help Mega Man get across spiked plains. Mega Man will also go though waterfall sequence with logs coming down the waterfall's stream--the logs are used as platforms for Mega Man to get through. Eventually Mega Man will encounter a large dinosaur as a mid-boss fight.           Shade Man's Stage    This stage has areas of robotic zombies that will regenerate. They come out of a coffin that rise up out of the ground. Robotic crows will appear to give Mega Man a hard time - the stand in the way and shoot out a pellet. Enemies will sneak up on Mega Man from the background. Mega Man will also encounter a mid boss fight in this stage as well--a giant pumpkin that bounces around as one of its attack, then the top and bottom sides will open up and shoot out pellets at Mega Man. This level also houses a secret battle with Proto Man. In order to meet him here, you must have met him twice before.          Junk Man's Stage    A factory that has robotic bugs coming out of hives that's made out of junk. Other section contain gaps that's filled with molten lava that Mega Man has to cross. One touch of the lava and Mega Man is done for. Another area is an elevator section with enemies coming down while the elevator is taking Mega Man to the next part of the level.           Freeze Man's Stage    Freeze Man's stage is a snowy level that has robotic polar bears that can breath out spiked balls and throw them at Mega Man, bob sliders that will throw three bombs once destroyed, and enemies that hang on the ceiling and shoot glaciers that can be use as platforms to get through gaps filled with spikes. Sections of the stage have platforms that are covered with slippery ice - if not careful, Mega Man could accidentally fall off.           Burst Man's Stage   This stage has platforms that are ticking time bombs. A large portion of the stage is done underwater - the water can increase the height that Mega Man can jump, but it can be dangerous for Mega Man because some areas in the stage have spikes hanging on the ceiling. In other sections, the water level will rise up and down, Mega Man will float on top when the water level is up - which will help Mega Man get through sections with gaps that are filled with spikes.       Turbo Man's Stage   Most of this stage is made out of tires. Right at the beginning, Mega Man will be attacked by a robot on a bulldozer with spikes on the front. Other sections have tires that are attached to chains. They can get in the way of Mega Man jumping across spiked gaps. Another has Mega Man going dropping down avoiding fiery beams that will destroy Mega Man with one hit (This section is reminiscent of    Quick Man's level from   Mega Man 2).        Spring Man's Stage    This stage contains springs attached on walls, floors, and ceilings- they can launch Mega Man up in the air. Two of the enemies are robotic springs; one jumps around the stage and attacks Mega Man, and the other is similar to a Slinky. Sections in the level have jack-in-the-boxes suspended in mid air; they launch out a metal boxing glove. Mega Man can jump on them and change the direction where the metal boxing will aim.       Cloud Man's Stage   Very reminiscence of  Air Man's stage from Mega Man 2, Cloud Man's stage takes place up in the air.  Some sections have robots that can change the weather depending which weapon is used on it. For example, If Freeze Man's weapon is use, the entire level will be covered in snow.  Robot MastersFreeze ManEnemy Alignment: IceEnemy Weakness: Junk ShieldWeapon Gained: Freeze CrackerJunk Man Enemy Alignment: TrashEnemy Weakness: Thunder Bolt Weapon Gained: Junk ShieldBurst Man Enemy Alignment: Water Enemy Weakness: Scorch Wheel Weapon Gained: Danger WrapCloud Man Enemy Alignment: Air Enemy Weakness: Danger Wrap Weapon Gained: Thunder BoltSpring Man Enemy Alignment: Coils Enemy Weakness: Slash Claw Weapon Gained: Wild CoilSlash Man Enemy Alignment: Claws Enemy Weakness: Freeze Cracker Weapon Gained: Slash ClawShade Man Enemy Alignment: Sound  Enemy Weakness: Wild Coil  Weapon Gained: Noise CrushTurbo Man Enemy Alignment: Fire  Enemy Weakness: Noise Crush  Weapon Gained: Scorch Wheel</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21761">Metroid</game><game id="5708">Metroid II: Return of Samus</game><game id="8292">Super Metroid</game><game id="10323">Metroid Fusion</game><game id="17356">Metroid: Zero Mission</game><game id="4725">Metroid Prime 3: Corruption</game><game id="6215">Metroid Prime: Hunters</game><game id="2866">Super Mario World 2: Yoshi's Island</game><game id="16188">Clash at Demonhead</game><game id="8583">Metal Slug Advance</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2363970-snes_megaman7.jpg</image></root>