<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7437</id><name>NBA Live 07</name><description> 1000 People OnlineMultiplayer Achievements: The Eternal Struggle. NBA Live 07 has an achievement for being online with 1000 other players which was an extreme rarity and is now impossible. EA announced that the servers for NBA Live 07 would be shut down permanently on February 2nd 2010. In a desperate fight for all achievement whores out there, many players organised one final push to get 1000 players online on 31st January 2010 before the servers went down. SoundtrackARTIST - SONGArmy Of The Pharaoh - GorillasBossman ** - Hand ClapBraza ** - Son Do BrazaCitty ** - Them BallersDamizza feat Butch Cassidy ** - In 2'sFeezy 350 feat. Shauna K** - Mr. DJGhislain Poirier - Mic DiplomatGnarls Barkley - CrazyJurassic 5 featuring Dave Matthews ** - Work It OutLady Sovereign - A Little Bit of Shh (Adrock Remix)Lupe Fiasco - Kick PushDead Prez Presents M-1 - Til We Get ThereMark Ronson feat Alex Greenwald - JustMurs  9th Wonder - L.A.Pigeon John - HigherRaptile ** - Neva EvaRedrama - I Don't Know What To Tell YouRhymefest - Some Of These DaysRobert Randolph  The Family Band ** - Thrill Of ItSergio Mendes  The Black Eyed Peas - Mas Que NadaTalib Kweli - ListenTen Days Till ** - Get Them Hands HiThe Coup - My Favorite Mutiny** Indicates song will debut in NBA LIVE 07 before being released to retail. </description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="22">Basketball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21470">NBA 2K8</game><game id="21363">NBA 2K6</game><game id="20917">NBA 2K9</game><game id="9829">NBA 2K7</game><game id="21762">NBA ShootOut 2000</game><game id="1395">ESPN NBA 2K5</game><game id="61">NBA Street V3</game><game id="7982">NBA Street</game><game id="3557">NBA 07</game><game id="16937">ESPN NBA Basketball 2004</game><game id="6199">NCAA College Basketball 2K3</game><game id="20242">NBA Showdown</game><game id="23188">ESPN NBA 2Night</game><game id="23864">NBA '08</game><game id="27885">NBA 2K10: Draft Combine</game><game id="4632">NBA Showtime: NBA on NBC</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2243869-box_nbalive07.png</image></root>