<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7450</id><name>Super Ghouls 'N Ghosts</name><description>OverviewSuper Ghouls 'N Ghosts takes place 4 years after the previous game in which Arthur saved the Princess Prin Prin from Loki. In this game Arthur and Prin Prin are engaged and set to be married, but, of course, Prin Prin is kidnapped by a demon, and it is up to Arthur to rescue his bride.Super Ghouls 'N Ghosts was developed for the SNES, while the non super title, Ghouls 'N Ghosts, was a launch title for the Sega Genesis which came out much earlier. Asutaroto/Astaroth replaces Loki as the main antagonist in Super Ghouls 'N Ghosts and like the original title, Ghosts 'N Goblins, you have to go through the game twice and use a special weapon to properly reach the game's conclusion.GameplayThe game plays mostly like a run and gun shooter (like Contra) mixed with a traditional side-scrolling platformer. Arthur starts with the lance, which is reliable but slow. Other weapons that can be picked up through the game include axes, fireballs, scythe and the popular daggers. Whilst the weapons are usually just thrown, if Arthur is lucky enough to pick up Super/Magic Armor, he can charge up for a super attack that can affect a larger section of the game screen.The control system is slightly different in this G'n'G game compared to its prequels. Super Ghouls 'N Ghosts uses a 'double jump' system which was quite novel at the time for a platformer. Rather than a Super Mario Bros. style mechanic where the player can steer their character a little in mid-jump, in this game Arthur can only move through the trajectory set when he first jumps, until he makes a laws-of-physics-breaking second jump. This allows for additional control over Arthur, even letting him completely change the direction he's going in, in mid-air. It also adds a touch of difficulty, in timing that second jump to maximizes the height of Arthur's jump. </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10717">Maximo: Ghosts to Glory</game><game id="8040">Maximo vs Army of Zin</game><game id="13688">Gargoyle's Quest</game><game id="7274">ActRaiser</game><game id="12176">Ironsword: Wizards &amp; Warriors II</game><game id="11443">Super Castlevania IV</game><game id="22857">Battletoads</game><game id="19067">Walt Disney's The Jungle Book</game><game id="18097">Rastan Saga 2</game><game id="14216">Castlevania: Symphony of the Night</game><game id="14800">Trojan</game><game id="39003">Musya</game><game id="4795">Whirlo</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2364818-snes_superghoulsnghosts.jpg</image></root>