<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7458</id><name>Racing Destruction Set</name><description>OverviewRacing Destruction Set from                   Electronic Arts is a      car  and motocross racing game developed for the                   Commodore 64, and later  released on the                   Atari 8-bit.  The game was known for its at the time innovative             track editor. It received much critical praise, and saw numerous remakes and  copycats in the years following its release.  Gameplay The gameplay is that  of the typical racing game: just beat your opponent in a lapped race.  The game is played from an isometric perspective and splits the screen  in two, with each part showing a different player, allowing one to easily track  their opponents progress. This is also how the game handles   multiplayer.  Up to two players can compete against each other  in Racing Destruction Set. Player 1 is put in control of the red car on  the upper half of the screen, and player 2 controls the yellow car on  lower part of the screen. Track  Editor For its time, Racing Destruction Set was a highly  innovative racing game for many reasons. The most notable one being its  track editor. With it, players could create their very own tracks using  one of several templates to choose from, and from there, add things like             ramps and elevation changes, as well as different terrain like           sand,           ice, and, of course, standard tarmac.  Each terrain type  produces different effects.     Ice, for example, causes cars to slip all  over the place, and    sand slows the car when driving on it. These  obstacles can hinder your opponents progress or your own, which can make  for some very challenging tracks if done correctly. Car Customization In  addition to the robust track editor, Racing Destruction Set also  allowed players to customize certain aspects of their cars, such as  tires and engines. They could also load it with traps like         land mines,  and        oil that players can spill behind their vehicles.  The types  of tires you use effect how well the car will handle on various  surfaces. Some are better for ice, while others are better for dirt.  This makes being conscious of what your car is specked out with  important to know, as failure to properly spec your vehicle could result  in losing the race  Other Customizable Elements Gravity levelsDifficulty level, and  skill level of your opponentNumber of lapsGraphic  style List of Available Vehicles Can-Am sports carJeepLunar  RoverDirt bikeBaja bugPickupSting  rayStock carIndy/Gran prix Modes The  game features two modes that up to two players can compete in: a  standard lapped race, or destruction mode. The former is standard race  to the finish line, and the latter tasks players with taking down their  opponent using oil slicks and land mines that can be ejected from the  vehicles. Remakes A remake of Racing Destruction  Set was released on the                   Super Nintendo Entertainment System  in 1991, under the name                   Radical Pyscho  Machine Racing.                   Rock N' Roll  Racing, which followed the release of RPM Racing, was also released  on the SNES in 1993.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17410">Pinball Construction Set</game><game id="4494">Adventure Construction Set</game><game id="28137">Radical Pyscho Machine Racing</game><game id="18026">Rock 'n Roll Racing</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15693/625415-racing_20destruction_20set_1_.jpg</image></root>