<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7508</id><name>Mario Party 7</name><description>Overview Mario Party 7 is the ninth game in the   Mario Party franchise (including   Mario Party-e and   Mario Party Advance). Mario Party 7 was released for the   Nintendo GameCube on November 7, 2005 in North America, on November 10, 2005 in Japan, on February 10, 2006 in Europe, and on June 8, 2006 in Australia. The game was developed by   Hudson Soft and published by Nintendo. Mario Party 7 has 88 new minigames, as well as various other new features. Mario Party 7 also is packaged with a microphone, like   Mario Party 6. The story of the game involves   Toadsworth hosting a cruise and inviting everyone except for   Bowser. Bowser decides to ruin their vacation.GameplayOne of the many minigames. Mario Party 7 is the same as almost all other Mario Party games. Mario Party 7 takes place across a variety of boards. Each of these games has the goal of collecting the most stars, but each board has a different way of getting these stars. The multiplayer game now can have up to eight people at once. Players have are split into four teams of two, and each team must share one controller. The first player uses the control stick and L button, while the second player uses the C-stick and R button.The single-player game is very different from previous Mario Party games. The player plays against either computer or human controlled opponents while attempting to complete several objectives. These objectives vary, such as collecting an amount of stars, or collecting coins.The game has all of the playable characters of Mario Party 6 (save for Koopa Kid), as well as two new characters.   Mario,   Luigi,   Princess Peach,   Princess Daisy,   Yoshi,   Birdo,   Toad,   Toadette,   Wario,   Waluigi,   Boo, and   Dry Bones are the playable characters. Boo and Dry Bones must be purchased in the shop.The minigames in Mario Party 7 are split up into nine different types: four player, one versus three, two versus two, Battle, Duel, eight player,   Donkey Kong, Bowser, and Rare minigames. In addition to this, there are nine minigames that can be played with the microphone. As in other Mario Party games, Mario Party 7 contains no minigames from previous iterations.Game BoardsGrand CanalPagoda PeakPyramid ParkNeon HeightsWindmillville Bowser's Enchanted Inferno! Bowser's Enchanted Inferno     MinigamesFour player minigamesCatchy TunesBubble BrawlTrack  YieldFun RunCointagiousSnow RidePicture ThisGhost in the HallBig DripperTarget TagPokey PummelTake Me OhmKart WheeledBalloon BustersClock WatchersDart AttackOil CrisisMathemortician One versus three minigamesLa BombaSpray AnythingBalloonaticSpinner CellEasy PickingsThink TankFlashfrightCoin-op BopPogo-a-Go-GoWheel of WoeBoxing DayBe My Chum!StratosFEAR!Number Crunchers Two versus two minigamesBuzztormerTile and ErrorBattery RamCardinal RuleBumper CropHop-O-Matic 4000Sphere FactorWingin' ItHerbicidal ManiacPyramid SchemeWorld PieceSpider Stomp Battle minigamesHelipopperMonty's Revenge Deck Hands Deck HandsAir FarceThe Final Countdown Duel minigamesWarp Pipe DreamsWeight for ItMad PropsGimme a SignBridge WorkSpin DoctorHip Hop DropRoyal RumpusLight Speed Apes of Wrath Apes of WrathFish  CheepsCamp Ukiki Eight player minigamesReal SmoothieSpin OffGrin and Bar ItHammer SpammerGimme a BrakeBumper to BumperSynch-row-nicityRope a DopeDuct  CoverBob-Onic PlagueUnhappy TrailsShock Absorbers Other minigamesIce MovesBowser's Lovely Lift! Stick and Spin  Stick and Spin Bowser Minigames Funstacle Course!Funderwall!Magmagical Journey! Slot-O-Whirl!Treasure Dome!Treasure Dome!Tunnel of Lava!  DK Minigames  Peel OutBananas FasterStump ChargeJump, Man          Vine CountryVine CountryA Bridge Too Short </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21617">Rayman: Raving Rabbids</game><game id="8753">Bomberman Land Touch!</game><game id="12162">Mario Party 2</game><game id="8380">Mario Party 6</game><game id="8362">Mario Party 8</game><game id="6424">Mario Party</game><game id="15952">Crash Bash</game><game id="2819">Sonic Shuffle</game><game id="23732">Bomberman Land Touch! 2</game><game id="404">Disney's Party</game><game id="7669">Cartoon Network Block Party</game><game id="17156">My Street</game><game id="24844">Every Party</game><game id="31210">Wii Party</game><game id="33914">Doraemon Wii: Himitsu Douguou Ketteisen!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2129491-box_mparty7.png</image></root>