<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>758</id><name>Heart of Darkness</name><description>Development    Eric Chahi, the creator of the classic adventure game  Out of This World  was the creative force behind Heart of Darkness. The game had been in development at            Amazing Studio for more than five years and suffered numerous delays before it was finally released in 1998. The development time was mostly spent in creating the game's music and                  FMV's. One of the most unique aspects of this game at the time is that it was first game to have a musical score recorded by an orchestra. The game has no relation in story or themes to the Joseph Conrad novel of the same name.  Story The protagonist is a young boy with a vivid imagination called Andy. While Andy was watching a solar eclipse with his dog Whiskey, the evil ruler of another world called the Darklands used this period of darkness to pay Earth a visit. The intrusion of The Master of Darkness caused a hurricane which transferred Whiskey into the Darklands by mistake. Andy, who has many inventions in his tree house, grabs a plasma gun and jumps into his spacecraft to follow the Master of Darkness and rescue Whiskey from the monsters of shadow. At the Darklands, he encounters a strange race called the Amigos. He learns that the Master of Darkness is transforming the Amigos into monsters, so he teams up with them to fight the the Master of Darkness and free his dog.  Gameplay  This is a 2D side scrolling platform game similar to the original                Prince of Persia,   Out of This World, and  Oddworld: Abe's Odyssey. Andy has the ability to walk, jump, crawl, climb and swim. He can also use magic to grow trees and attack enemies. Later in the game he can use his plasma gun against shadow creatures. The player must solve puzzles which involve timing the character's movement and using his various abilities to progress through the game. If Andy falls off cliffs or is eaten by a shadow creatures the game is over.</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17483">Out of This World</game><game id="5269">Oddworld: Abe's Oddysee</game><game id="19281">Oddworld: Abe's Exoddus</game><game id="1066">Flashback: The Quest for Identity</game><game id="2561">Prince of Persia</game><game id="30380">Limbo</game><game id="36447">Rocketbirds: Hardboiled Chicken</game><game id="35489">The War of the Worlds</game><game id="37262">Deadlight</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2284341-darkness.png</image></root>