<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7676</id><name>X-Men: Legends II - Rise of Apocalypse</name><description>StoryThe story of X-men Legends 2 has the brutal villain Apocalypse going to war with Man and Mutant-kind in an attempt to enforce his mantra of "Survival of the fittest. The X-Men must team up with their bitter enemies, the Dark brotherhood in order to defeat Apocalypse and his four horsemen.The story features many characters and sub-plots from the X-Men comics. It is also the first of the Legends series that allows the player to have members of the Brotherhood of Evil on their team.GameplayThe game plays similar to a standard RPG, except you have superpowers instead of spells.You go through dungeons, towns and bosses with your team of mutants(You are able to choose from either X-men or The brotherhood).Your team gains experience and items that can increase their stats and the power of their mutant abilities.Your team can also be customized in the way of different skins, players can select skins for each of their characters.Playable CharactersWolverineRogueCyclopsStormToadScarlet WitchMagnetoColossusIcemanJuggernautGambitBishopJean GreySunfireNightcrawlerUnlockable CharactersProfessor XavierDeadpoolIron ManPlatform Exclusive CharactersPCSabretoothPyroPSPCableCannonballDark PhoenixX-ManN-GageBeastPC System RequirementsMinimum System Requirements:Windows 98/ME/XPPentium III or AMD Athlon 1.2GHz Processor256MB RAM2.5GB Hard Disk SpaceDirectX compatible Sound Card64MB nVidia GeForce2 or ATi Radeon 7500 Class Video CardDirectX 9.0c16X CD-ROM Drive</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7527">Marvel Ultimate Alliance</game><game id="16327">Justice League Heroes</game><game id="13087">X-Men: Legends</game><game id="1727">Dungeon Siege II</game><game id="12835">Fantastic 4</game><game id="12903">Marvel Super Heroes</game><game id="10574">X-Men: Children of the Atom</game><game id="8899">Marvel Super Heroes in War of the Gems</game><game id="3228">Spider-Man</game><game id="26649">Marvel Super Hero Squad</game><game id="2361">Crisis Core: Final Fantasy VII</game><game id="21559">Marvel Ultimate Alliance 2</game><game id="20319">Nicktoons Unite!</game><game id="30399">Spider-Man: Shattered Dimensions</game><game id="12107">Baldur's Gate: Dark Alliance II</game><game id="13091">Baldur's Gate: Dark Alliance</game><game id="13217">Champions of Norrath</game><game id="3156">Champions: Return to Arms</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14912/946764-xmenleg2_final_rgb4.jpg</image></root>