<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7701</id><name>The Lord of the Rings: The Battle for Middle-earth</name><description>The Lord of the Rings Battle for Middle earth was published by EA for PC: it's original U.S. releases date was December 6th 2004. It is a Real-Time Strategy game set in Middle-Earth. The objective of the game is for one player to build a bigger standing army than the other player and economically cripple him. The game is set in the fictional world of Middle-Earth created in the hit books by J. R. R. Tolkien, however the game is based more on the blockbuster movies more than the fictional novels. The Battle for Middle Earth is really the first Lord of the Rings games to bring Middle-Earth to your computer. The player will be hypnotized by its great character models, map textures, and environments. This game uses the same engine as Command and Conquer Generals. This game offers a nice single-player storyline. Once the player has completed the storyline he can choose if they want to go online. The online portion of this game is a lot different than the single-player portion.GameplayThis game is similar to your average RTS but has changes that add to the gameplay. The objective is for the player to create a base, build an army which can be managed, and gather all the resources on the map. Doing so the player will be able to cripple its enemy before they cripple them. This game is fast paced and games will roughly last 10-30 minutes. Unlike other RTS games, in BFME you cannot build your structures anywhere on the map. Each player will start off with a base that has a set number of buildings you can build on it. If one wants to build more buildings they must explore the map and find more small bases to build on. Players can also overtake enemy bases and build their own structures on the the previous base's foundation.To gather resources, the players must build farms and level them up as quick as possible. The player can choose if they want to build the farms in their base or outside. Each map will have set locations for farms to be built outside. The two players must compete on controlling all these farms if they are to economically win the game.The campaign in BFME offers both a good and evil campaign. In the good campaign the player will work on defeating the evil forces of Mordor and Isengard. In the evil campaign the forces of evil will fight the forces of good. The campaign focuses a lot on heroes like Gandalf, Frodo, and Aragorn. The levels in each campaign are separated by cut-scenes from the movies which help tell the games story. The good campaign roughly follows the main events of the movies - you fight familiar battles in the Mines of Moria, Helm's Deep, Isengard and Minas Tirith and follow separate characters stories throughout the campaign. The final battle in the good campaign is set outside the gates of Mordor. In the Evil campaign however you command the forces of Isengard and Mordor and lead them to victory over the men of Rohan and Gondor as well as conquering the Shire.Multiplayer:The game features online multi-player with anywhere from 2 to 8 players. In the multi-player you choose your faction and start off in a base on the map and your objective is to destroy the other players armies and bases before they destroy yours. The games are not necessarily "free-for-all", players can make teams before the game (4v4, 2v2v2v2, 3v3 etc). The multi-player mode is essentially a Skirmish game but with players controlling the opposing teams instead of A.I..Minimum System Requirements:OS: Windows 2000/XP/VistaCPU: Intel Pentium 4; 1.3GHzMemory: 256 MB RAMMinimum Hard Drive Space: 3.5GBDVD-ROM Speed: 8-SpeedVideo Card: 32MB Direct30Sound Card: DirectX 9.0bDirectX: Version 9.0b</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8421">Outlive</game><game id="14073">Warcraft III: The Frozen Throne</game><game id="13076">Age of Mythology</game><game id="1370">Age of Mythology: The Titans</game><game id="18623">Black &amp; White</game><game id="12474">Black &amp; White 2</game><game id="6594">Robin Hood: The Legend of Sherwood</game><game id="4867">The Lord of the Rings: The Battle for Middle-earth II</game><game id="6447">The Lord of the Rings: The Battle for Middle-earth II - The Rise of the Witch-King</game><game id="12054">Battle Realms</game><game id="20103">Warcraft II: Tides of Darkness</game><game id="18607">Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Dragonshard</game><game id="8546">Age of Empires III</game><game id="10485">Age of Empires</game><game id="2846">Age of Empires II: The Age of Kings</game><game id="12483">Age of Empires III: The WarChiefs</game><game id="14590">Age of Empires II: The Conquerors</game><game id="4391">Age of Empires: The Rise of Rome</game><game id="11786">Age of Empires III: The Asian Dynasties</game><game id="19857">Empire Earth</game><game id="1565">Empire Earth II</game><game id="13037">Empire Earth III</game><game id="20509">Empire: Total War</game><game id="17677">The Lord of the Rings: War of the Ring</game><game id="20215">Star Wars: Galactic Battlegrounds - Clone Campaigns</game><game id="738">Black &amp; White 2: Battle of the Gods</game><game id="19932">Emperor: Battle for Dune</game><game id="24079">StarCraft II: Legacy of the Void</game><game id="26539">The Lord of the Rings: Aragorn's Quest</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/11423/1105102-middleearth.jpg</image></root>