<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7718</id><name>SingStar Popworld</name><description>International TracklistsAshlee Simpson - Pieces Of Me Avril Lavigne - Sk8er Boi Beyonce - Crazy In Love Black Eyed Peas - Shut Up Blink-182 - What's My Age Again? The Clash - Should I Stay Or Should I Go? Dandy Warhols - Bohemian Like You Erik B. and Rakim - Paid In Full Fountains Of Wayne - Stacy's Mom Good Chalotte - I Just Wanna Live Hoobastank - The Reason Jamelia - Stop Kylie Minogue - In Your Eyes Manfred Man - Do Wah Diddy Natasha Bedingfield - These Words OutKast - Roses Robbie Williams - Let Me Entertain You Robbie Williams and Kylie Minogue - Kids Ronan Keating and Yusuf Islam - Father And Son Sister Sledge - We Are Family Steppenwolf - Born To Be Wild Tom Jones - It's Not Unusual  United Kingdom Only Songs Annie - Heartbeat Girls Aloud - Love Machine The Hives - Main Offender Jay Sean - Eyes On You Joss Stone - Super Duper Love (Are You Digging On Me?) Keane - Somewhere Only We Know Marylin Manson - Personal Jesus McFly - Obviously   Australia Only Songs Bic Runga - Sway Delta Goodrem - Born To Try Evermore - It's Too Late INXS - New Sensation Missy Higgins - Scar Savage Garden - To The Moon And Back Shannon Noll - What About Me Spazzys - My Boyfriend's Back      American Tracklist As the first SingStar released in America, the tracklist used in this version varies greatly to those used in other releases. Whilst recycling some content from the original SingStar and SingStar Party, some songs have been changed to compensate for differing tastes in the region, as well as the later release date. 3 Doors Down - Kryptonite A-Ha - Take On Me Alicia Keys - Fallin' All-American Rejects - Move Along Ashlee Simpson - Invisible Avril Lavigne - Sk8er Boi Blue October - Hate Me Britney Spears - (Hit Me) Baby, One More Time  Cartel - Honestly The Clash - Should I Stay Or Should I Go?  Cyndi Lauper - Girls Just Wanna Have Fun Daniel Powter - Bad Day  Destiny's Child - Survivor Franz Ferdinand - Take Me Out The Fray - Cable Car (Over My Head) Gorillaz - Feel Good, Inc. Hinder - Lips Of An Angel Hoobastank - The Reason James Blunt - You're Beautiful Jesse McCartney - Beautiful Soul Lifehouse - Hanging By A Moment My Chemical Romance - Helena Natasha Bedingfield - These Words Panic! At The Disco - I Write Sins, Not Tragedies The Raconteurs - Steady As She Goes Rhianna - S.O.S. Ryan Cabrera - On The Way Down Snow Patrol - Chasing Cars U2 - Vertigo Whitney Houston - I Wanna Dance With Somebody  </description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15661">Karaoke Revolution</game><game id="9860">Rock Band</game><game id="20673">Guitar Hero World Tour</game><game id="33148">Disney Sing It: Party Hits</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/495/643418-51kazyxsvzl.jpg</image></root>