<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7753</id><name>Gothic 3</name><description>StoryFighting a GolemGothic 3 opens with the            Nameless Hero and his friends sailing to a new continent overrun with orcs, arriving in the           Myrtana, the central region of the continent. Presumably this is the source of the Orc invasion that was launched on          Khorinis during the second chapter. These lands have no physical connection to Khorinis or the ruins of the penal colony. In these mountainous forests the orcs have enslaved the human kingdom with only a few free humans living in the nearly uninhabitable icy Northlands of Nordmar and the southern desert of Varant. The hero must decide whether to join the rebellion and stay true to the deposed human king, serve the Orcish usurpers in their quest to topple the last remaining human stronghold, or choose a path that serves his own ends. Throughout the story, he is accompanied by a number of NPCs, some of whom are old friends. While this chapter brings forward friends from the previous title (        Xardas,        Diego,       Milten,      Gorn,     Lester, and Vatras) it also introduces two new major characters;    King Rhobar the Second (Who ultimately was responsible for sending the Nameless Hero to the penal colony in the first game) and Zuben. While the king has a strong past as a bold leader, he now faces a near defeat; his fame on the decline. Zuben leads the Hashishin that inhabit the southern region of Varant.GameplayThe player must complete quests and slay wild animals and monsters to earn experience and improve skills. The game is  reputation centric allowing the player to side with the Orcs or Humans or a little of both within the quest and faction systems, or just battle it out. The player is able to take advantage of missons to allow either side to take over towns. Dialog changes according to in-game actions and behavior. The game places a special focus on the interactivity of the environment. The game claimed to employ an unusual combat system which emphasizes carefully timed combinations of strikes, requiring the player to read the body language of attacking opponents. However, in practice, many players found the combat system lacking such unique features and have been known to describe it as a "button mashing clickfest." This was due to the fact that the most successful strategy during combat seems to be to just click the left mouse button as quickly as you can, if you time it right at the beginning you are able to defeat any enemy with relative ease. The controls have been altered slightly with a stronger focus on action. Navigation and combat are more mouse-centric, with each mouse button having a different combat action. The Nameless Hero can also now wield dual weapons or use a shield. ReceptionGothic 3 was met with a poor reception in the US.  This was mostly due to the often crippling and debilitating bugs that the game shipped with; but the terrible voice acting and hording of system resources also caused alarm.The game has gone through many patches but continued support has ended  due to the split between JoWooD and Piranha Games.   In the western and eastern Europe however, especially in Germany (programmers' homeland), Poland and Russia, it had very favorable reviews, ranging from 7 to even 9 in 10-point scale. The game was far better treated there because of much greater attention paid to the voicework, faster patch releases and overally greater publisher and community support (not to mention better franchise recognition - first two Gothics, even with favourable reviews, were never big in the US). The game is now supported through community patches. Current, so called "Enhanced" version of Gothic 3 killed off most of the bugs, balanced the combat and trading system, and made the game more system's memory and graphic card's memory friendly. The latest community patch is 1.74 which is a whopping 917Mb download but more than worth the wait.SoundtrackDisc 1Soundtrack of the game cover01 - Title Theme02 - Opening Sequence03 - Xardas Tower04 - Vista Point05 - Ruinfields06 - Dark Presence07 - Orc Camp08 - From Silden to Trelis09 - Ominous Woods10 - Showdown11 - The Dig12 - Slaves13 - Divine Powers14 - Vengard Theme15 - Exploring Myrtana16 - Revolution17 - Northmar (Upper Level)18 - The Creation of the Barrier19 - Vista Point (Reprise)20 - Desert Sun21 - Welcome to Varant22 - Northmar (Lower Level)23 - Sad Strings24 - The End25 - End Titles (Bonus Track)26 - In My Dreams27 - Is Nomine Vacans28 - Welcome to the Bronx29 - Bring Back the Magic    System requirementsWindows SP4,  Windows XP SP1,  Windows Server 2003 or  Windows XP 64MinimumIntel Pentium 4 2GHz or AMD Athlon 64 3200  Processor512MB RAM4.6GB Hard Disk Space128MB 3D Accelerated Video Card4X DVD-ROM DriveDirectX compatible Sound CardDirectX 9.0cKeyboardMouseRecommendedIntel Pentium D 3GHz or AMD Athlon 64 4000  Processor1GB RAM256MB 3D Hardware Accelerated Video Card    </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17367">The Elder Scrolls III: Morrowind</game><game id="20238">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion</game><game id="21473">Blade of Darkness</game><game id="7870">Dark Earth</game><game id="14759">Two Worlds</game><game id="10473">The Witcher</game><game id="14565">Dungeon Lords</game><game id="23081">Risen</game><game id="23139">Divinity II: Ego Draconis</game><game id="9061">Neverwinter Nights 2</game><game id="20504">Fallout 3</game><game id="22488">Mortal Online</game><game id="9641">Age of Conan: Hyborian Adventures</game><game id="27218">Two Worlds II</game><game id="28178">The Witcher 2: Assassins of Kings</game><game id="33149">Risen 2: Dark Waters</game><game id="11583">SpellForce 2: Shadow Wars</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15693/618107-920920_54699_front_1_.jpg</image></root>