<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7964</id><name>Tiger Woods PGA Tour 2005</name><description>New to 2005 The 2005 edition of Tiger Woods PGA Tour added many new features, most importantly overhauling the character creator.  Players were able to take their newly created golfer on a brand new "Legend Tour" in which they faced a number of highly regarded golfers such as Jack Nicklaus and Arnold Palmer on classic courses.  There were also "Legend Scenarios" in which players would have to re-enact difficult shots or incredible comebacks made by classic golfers in the game.  Players could also play tournaments against current professional golfers such as Tiger Woods and Vijay Singh, or against EA created golfers such as "The Hustler" who bears a likeness to Justin Timberlake.  All of these events reward the player with money that they save up to "Tiger Proof" a course before a final faceoff against Woods himself.  Tiger Proofing includes reducing the size of the fairways, increasing the frequency of water hazards and bunkers, and changing the surface of the green so that putts roll faster or slower.  Tiger Woods PGA Tour 2005 was also the first title in the series to support Xbox Live play.PGA/Legend Golfer Roster (incomplete)        Tiger Woods       Ben Hogan      Gary Player     Seve Ballesteros    Arnold Palmer   Jack NicklausJesper Parnevyk  Vijay Singh Ty Tryon Fictional Golfer Roster Bev "Boomer" BouchierBilly "Bear" HightowerAdriana "Sugar" DolceAlastair "Captain" McFaddenAphrodite PapadapolusBunjiro "Bud" TanakaCeasar "The Emperor" RosadoDion "Double D" DouglasHunter "Steelhead" ElmoreJeb "Shooter" McGrawJustin "The Hustler" TimberlakeKendra "Spike" LovetteRaquel "Rocky" RockersReginald "Reg" WithersTiffany "Tiff Williams</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="28">Golf</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2302">PGA Tour Golf: Tournament Course Disk</game><game id="697">PGA European Tour</game><game id="1325">PGA Championship Golf 2000: Titanium Edition</game><game id="1760">PGA Tour 96</game><game id="6799">PGA Tour Golf</game><game id="21309">Golf Magazine Presents 36 Great Holes Starring Fred Couples</game><game id="21379">ProStroke Golf : World Tour 2007</game><game id="17375">Jack Nicklaus 6: Golden Bear Challenge</game><game id="10089">Jack Nicklaus 5</game><game id="19715">Jack Nicklaus 4</game><game id="2617">Jack Nicklaus' Unlimited Golf &amp; Course Design</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2269429-box_twpgat05.png</image></root>