<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>798</id><name>Math Rescue</name><description>The evil Gruzzles are back! After they were beaten in Word Rescue, they return. This time, they have taken - wait for it - the world's numbers. The player takes control of a girl or boy, like in Word Rescue, and again teams up with Benny, now a butterfly. Math problems must be solved in each level to rescue the lost numbers and defeat the Gruzzles again.Math Rescue was programmed and designed by Karen Crowther, art by Dale Homburg and Jimmie Homburg, and writing by Maya Watson.Like its predecessor, Math Rescue has three difficulty levels: easy, medium, and hard. In each level, enough numbers must be collected, revealing a key. To collect a number, a math problem must be solved. Once they are collected, the key is fully revealed, and the door to the next level is accessible. Points are given for collecting numbers, as well as items in the levels, like crayons and ice cream cones. If the numbers from zero to nine are collected in order, a bonus is awarded. Bonuses can also be earned by finding garbage trucks matching random math problems displayed at the bottom of the screen. Points are also given for defeating enemies by calling Benny with the space bar, which enables him to dump slime on them. Slime is limited, but can be refilled by collecting numbers. An addition to Math Rescue is the use of garbage can lids, which act as a life system. Instead of having to restart the level after being damaged, a lid "protects" the player from the attack. A lid is used when a Gruzzle attacks or after touching an incorrect truck.A bonus stage activates between levels. In it, a series of rapid fire math problems award points, lids, and slime, but with an added time limit.</description><genres><genre id="8">Educational</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14275">Yogi Bear's Math Adventures</game><game id="12022">Superfrog</game><game id="1796">Word Rescue</game><game id="13046">Commander Keen 5: The Armageddon Machine</game><game id="25658">Math Blazer</game><game id="31833">Mathe Pfiffikus</game><game id="1949">Pickle Wars</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1169/276015-mrtitle.jpg</image></root>