<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8045</id><name>Karnov's Revenge</name><description>OverviewKarnov's Revenge (known in Japan as Fighter's History Dynamite) is a 2D fighting game developed and released by Data East for arcades (running Neo Geo hardware) in 1994. It is the sequel to the 1993 arcade game Fighter's History (infamous for bringing Data East into court for being identical to Capcom's Street Fighter II), revamping the original's gameplay (adding new mechanics, characters, and secret special moves while making the overall game speed faster).The game was later released on April 28, 1994 for the home Neo Geo consoles and the Neo Geo CD. It was ported to the Sega Saturn (in Japan only) on July 4, 1997, adding new control options and the option for an arranged soundtrack. The original game was later released for the Wii (via the Wii Virtual Console) on June 8, 2010 (for Japan) and December 27, 2010 (for North America) and for the Zeebo on April 23, 2010.Much of the game's assets were reused for the Japanese-exclusive Super Famicom spin-off, Fighter's History: Mizoguchi Kiki Ippatsu!!.CharactersAll of the characters from the original Fighter's History make a return, all with new special moves (including secret, powerful moves). While the character graphics were slightly modified for the new Neo Geo hardware, Karnov was the only character to receive entirely-new graphics. The bosses of the previous game (Clown and Karnov) are now playable, and the game includes two new playable characters (Liu Yungmie and Zazi Muhaba) and one new secret opponent (Ox, a reference to Karate Champ).Ray McDougal - Brawling detective from the U.S.Liu Feilin - Actress (of classical Chinese opera) from China.Ryoko Kano - High-school Judo master from Japan.Matlok Jade - Punk rocker from England.Samchay Tomyamgun - Muay Thai fighter from Thailand.Lee Diendou - Martial arts master from China. Makoto Mizoguchi - High-school delinquent (in his 20's) from Japan.Jean Pierre - Professional gymnast from France.Marstorius - Professional wrestler from Italy.Liu Yungmie - Young Taekwondo master from South Korea. Zazie Muhaba - Nature-loving fighter from Kenya.Clown - Travelling clown from France. Serves as the game's penultimate boss. Karnov - The "undefeated servant of God" from Russia. Serves as the game's boss. Ox - A large bull. A secret, unplayable opponent that can only be fought against by winning the game without losing a round.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="243">Street Fighter II: The World Warrior</game><game id="2396">Fatal Fury</game><game id="13327">Art of Fighting 2</game><game id="18554">World Heroes</game><game id="25801">Global Champion</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1408690-karnovr_box.jpg</image></root>