<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>807</id><name>Space Battle</name><description>History  Originally based on the popular  Battlestar Galactica  TV series, this space combat simulator was produced by    APh Technological Consulting for                    Mattel Electronics, programmed by                      Hal Finney and tested by    Dale Lynn.  Two versions of the game were released in a blue box and a red box. The  red box was the initial release and was eventually deemed too easy by   Lynn,  and eventually the general public. So a more difficult version, the  more commonly known blue box, was released as part of the "Intellivision  Space Action Network" series of games which included a super advanced speed mode that the original version did not.   The name was changed because,  although one of Mattel's subsidiaries, Concepts 2000, had the rights to produce the official line of  Battlestar Galactica toys , Mattel could not secure the license for their videogame. At the point that this was  discovered, development had been underway for a while. The name was  changed to the painfully generic "Space Battle", but the graphics remained the same. This is why the enemy ships  look like             Cylon raiders.     Red Box Version Blue Box version           Object  Defend the Mothership from the invading squadrons of enemies using your  own squadrons. There are two screens a player will have to deal with  when playing. One is the radar view that shows the location of the  Mothership in the center, the player's squadrons of ships, and the enemy  squadrons. The other view is the cockpit view where the player will  move a            reticule around the screen to fire upon enemy ships.    Radar View     From the radar screen the player is able to direct his squadrons. The  player is given three squadrons with which to dispatch the enemies. A  blue, gold, and white squadron have the ability to be dispatched,  returned to base, or battle. When dispatching an alien must be selected  then the dispatch key for the appropriate color must be hit. This will  cause the squadron to proceed to the selected enemy. Once intercepted  your ship will start blinking. This means you can battle. This will  cause you to enter the cockpit mode.                In the battle view the player is presented with a view of the stars. The player is also given a          reticule with which to target enemy     Cockpit View     ships. Enemy ships will appear from off screen and  continue moving around on the screen. It is the player's job to move  the         reticule near the enemy ships so the explosion will hit  them and cause them to blow up. In the bottom left and right of the  screen are the number of ships left in the enemy's squadron and the  player's squadron respectively. One either of those numbers reach zero  the battle is over and the player will be returned to the radar view.          It is possible to blow up multiple enemy ships with one shot if time  right. When destroyed an enemy will let off three other explosions from  around the original explosion. If these explosions hit another enemy  ship it will be destroyed as well. This is why it becomes important to  lead some of your targets.  When in cockpit view the enemies will also fire at the player. The player must avoid these shots by keeping his        reticule away from the shot. These shots appear as two squares side by side separated by a little space that become red as they get closer (depth wise) to the player.  The player wins when all five enemy squadrons have been eliminated of the radar. A player loses when the Mothership has sustain too much damage. This happens when the siren has been going off for a set time. It is the management of the player's squadrons and his ability to switch quickly between the screens that will allow a player to master this game.  "Two player co-op" is also available but only in the cockpit view. In this case one player will control the      reticule while the other fires.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7214">Space Hawk</game><game id="1163">Star Strike</game><game id="30759">Space Battle</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2366985-intv_spacebattle_none.jpg</image></root>