<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8382</id><name>Sid Meier's Civilization IV: Warlords</name><description>OverviewSid Meier's Civilization IV: Warlords is an expansion pack (for the 2005 turn-based 4X strategy game Sid Meier's Civilization IV) developed by Firaxis and published by 2K for the PC on July 26, 2006. The first expansion pack for Sid Meier's Civilization IV, Warlords adds six new civilizations (each with their own leader), four new leaders (for existing civilizations), three new leader traits, new units (including a new type of "Great Person": the Great General), new buildings (including new Wonders and new buildings unique to each civilization), new leader traits, and the concept of Vassal States (in which players can take up other civilizations as "vassals", protecting them from other civilizations while demanding tribute).The second expansion pack, Sid Meier's Civilization IV: Beyond the Sword, released a year later, retained all additions from this expansion with the exception of the eight new scenarios.Gameplay AdditionsGreat GeneralsAs the name suggests, Great Generals are the military version of Great People. As a civilization fights and their units earn experience, the game keeps an internal total of all the experience. Once a sufficient amount has been accumulated a Great General emerges in one of the civilization's cities. Like other Great People, there are a number of new abilities a Great General can perform. However, Great Generals cannot be used to start a Golden Age for a civilization.The first ability of the Great General is to construct a Military Academy in a city, granting it a 25% bonus in military unit production. The second ability is letting the Great General join a city as a Great Military Instructor. This gives all units built in that city an extra 2 experience points. The last option is to turn your Great General into a Warlord by binding him to another unit. All three options uses up the Great General unit.A Warlord unit is essentially an enhanced version of the unit the Warlord is bound to. During the creation of the Warlord unit, 20 experience points is distributed evenly between all units in the Great General's tile. The Warlord unit will then be more powerful than normal due to the Warlord's abilities, gaining free upgrades for the remainder of the game, and access to five Warlord only promotions:Combat VI: 25% strengthLeadership: 50% experience from combatMedic III: Heals units in same and adjacent tiles extra 15% damage per turnMorale: +1 movementTactics: 30% withdrawal chanceVassal StatesVassal States allow one civilization to server as master to another, weaker, civilization. Once the Feudalism technology is research a civilization can become a Vassal in one of two ways. The first method is completely voluntary. A civilization simply says they wish to become the Vassal of another through the Diplomacy screen and it takes affect. The Vassal state then has the option to renew the agreement every 10 turns.The second method is through Capitulation. If two civilization are at war one nation can Capitulate, becoming the other's Vassal. The difference here is that civilizations which have Capitulated cannot end their Vassal Agreement unless the Vassal either grows to half the land and population size of the master or loses more than half of their territory while a Vassal.Vassal Agreements are not always beneficial to both nations so they must be considered carefully.The master's benefits are:Complete freedom to move within the Vassal's territory including the use of any Vassal fortifications.The ability to heal normally within the Vassal's territory.The ability to be invisible to enemy civilizations within Vassal cities.The master can demand any resource from the Vassal at any point. However, if the Vassal refuses the agreement ends and the two civilizations are immediately at war.The master's cities enjoy increased happiness.The Vassal immediately adopts the war and peace relationships of it's master.Half the Vassal's territory and population count towards the master's score.The benefits for the Vassal are:The master is now responsible for your safety.The downsides are:The Vassal's cities suffer decreased happiness.The Master's cities suffer increased maintenance costs.Other civilizations may not like the Vasal Agreement.New Units and BuildingsUnique BuildingsUnique Buildings were added to the game in Warlords. Unlike traits, which are different for each leader of a civilization, Unique Buildings are specific to the civilization as a whole. Unique Buildings add on top of the the abilities of the building they're replacing, where applicable.CivilizationUnique BuildingReplacesAttributesAmericaMallSupermarket+10% wealth+1 happiness from Hit Musicals, Hit Singles, Hit MoviesArabiaMadrassaLibraryCan turn two citizens into Priests+2 cultureAztecsSacrificial AlterCourthouse-50% anger duration from sacrificing populationCosts 30 hammers less than CourthouseChinaPavilionTheatre+25% cultureCarthageCothonHarbor+1 trade routeCosts 20 more hammers than HarborCeltsDunWallFree Guerilla I promotion for units built in the cityEgyptObeliskMonumentCan turn two citizens into PriestsEnglandStock ExchangeBank+15% wealthFranceSalonObservatory+1 free ArtistGermanyAssembly PlantFactoryCan turn 2 more citizens into Engineers than Factory+50% production with coalGreeceOdeonColosseum+3 culture+1 happiness, +1 happiness from Hit SinglesCan turn 2 citizens into ArtistsIncaTerraceGranary+2 cultureIndiaMausoleumJail+2 happinessJapanShale PlantCoal Plant+10% productionKoreaSeowonUniversity+10% researchMaliMintForge+10% wealthMongoliaGerStableNew mounted units receive +2 experience pointsOttomansHammamAqueduct+2 happinessPersiaApothecaryGrocer+2 healthRomeForumMarket+25% Great People birth rateRussiaResearch InstituteLaboratory+2 free ScientistsSpainCitadelCastleNew siege weapons get +2 experience points-50% damage to city defenses from non-gunpowder bombardmentVikingsTrading PostLighthouseFree Navigation I promotion for naval units built in the cityZuluIkhandaBarracks-20% city maintenance costCosts 10 more hammers to build than BarracksNew WondersThe game adds three new Great Wonders to the main game:Great Wall - 250 Production cost (double speed with Stone). Requires the Masonry tech. Can only be built prior to the Medieval Era. Adds +2 rate to Culture and +2 rate to Great People Points. Prevents barbarians from entering the player's cultural borders on the continent. Adds +100% chance for a Great General to emerge from combat taking place within the cultural borders. Increases the ability for the city hosting the Wonder to generate Great Engineers.Temple of Artemis - 400 Production cost (double speed with Marble). Requires the Polytheism tech. Can only be built prior to the Medieval Era. Expires with the Chemistry tech. Adds +8 rate to Culture and +2 rate to Great People Points. Adds +100% income from trade routs. Adds a free priest specialist to the city hosting the Wonder. Increases the ability for the city to generate Great Merchants.University of Sankore - 550 Production cost (double speed with Stone). Requires the Paper tech. Can only be built prior to the Industrial Era. Expires with the Computers tech. Adds +8 rate to Culture and +2 rate to Great People Points. Adds +2 rate to Research per all buildings associated with the civilization's stage religion. Increases the ability for the city to generate Great Scientists.New Civilizations and LeadersNew Leader TraitsSid Meier's Civilization IV: Warlords added 3 new leader traits, for a total of 11 traits overall.Charismatic - +1 happiness per city. -25% XP needed for unit promotions. +1 happiness from Monument and Broadcast Tower.Imperialistic - +100% Great General emergence. +50% faster production speed of Settlers.Protective - Archery and Gunpowder units receive Drill I and City Garrison I automatically. +100% faster production speed of Walls and Castle.As the result of the new traits, many existing leaders had their existing traits changed:Washington (America) - Charismatic, Expansive.Saladin (Arabs) - Protective, Spiritual.Mao Zedong (China) - Expansive, Protective.Qin Shi Huang (China) - Industrious, Protective.Victoria (England) - Financial, Imperialistic.Napoleon (France) - Charismatic, Organized.Frederick (Germany) - Organized, Philosophical.Huayna Capac (Inca) - Financial, Industrious.Muhatma Gandhi (India) - Philosophical, Spiritual.Tokugawa (Japan) - Aggressive, Protective.Genghis Khan (Mongolia) - Aggressive, Imperialistic.Cyrus (Persia) - Charismatic, Imperialistic.Julius Caesar (Rome) - Imperialistic, Organized.Catherine (Russia) - Creative, Imperialistic.New CivilizationsThe game added six new civilizations to the main game:Carthage - Starts with the Fishing and Mining techs. Their unique unit is the Numidian Cavalry (replacement for the Horse Archer, adding Flanking I from the start, +1 to Strength, +50% attack power against Trebuchets and melee units, and the chance ability to withdraw from combat, at the cost of -10% attack power against units in cities).Celts - Starts with the Hunting and Mysticism techs. Their unique unit is the Gallic Warrior (replacement for the Swordsman, adding Guerilla I from the start)Korea - Starts with the Mysticism and Mining techs. Their unique unit is the Hwacha (replacement for the Catapult, adding +20% faster production speed, no general damage reduction, +50% attack power against melee units, +7% city defense bombardment, and the chance ability to withdraw from combat, at the cost of immunity to collateral damage from other Seige Weapons).Ottoman - Starts with The Wheel and Agriculture techs. Their unique unit is the Janissary (replacement for the Musketman, adding +25% attack power against archery, melee, and mounted units)Viking - Starts with the Hunting and Fishing techs. Their unique unit is the Berserker (replacement for the Maceman, adding Amphibious from the start and +10% attack power against units in cities)Zulu - Starts with the Agriculture and Hunting techs. Their unique unit is the Impi (replacement the Spearman, adding Mobility from the start and +1 to Movement).Along with a new leader for each of the six civilizations, the game also adds a new leader to four of the existing civilizations:Augustus Caesar (Rome) - Creative, Organized.Brennus (Celts) - Spiritual, Charismatic.Winston Churchill (England) - Charismatic, Protective.Hannibal (Carthage) - Financial, Charismatic.Mehmed II (Ottoman) - Expansive, Organized.Ragnar (Viking) - Aggressive, Financial.Ramesses II (Egypt) - Industrius, Spiritual.Shaka (Zulu) - Aggressive, Expansive.Josef Stalin (Russia) - Aggressive, Industrious.Wang Kon (Korea) - Financial, Protective.ScenariosSid Meier's Civilization IV: Warlords includes eight scenarios (modifications) unique to the expansion (as they cannot be played when Sid Meier's Civilization IV: Beyond the Sword is enabled), seven of which are based on central points in history:Peloponnesian Wars (430 B.C.) - Players control either Athens or Sparta as they struggle for dominance of Greece and its surrounding territories.Chinese Unification (350 B.C.) - Players control of one of Ancient China's kingdoms in an attempt to unify the country (by either the pen or the sword).Alexander's Conquests (330 B.C.) - Players control the leadership of Alexander the Great as he attempts to conquer the world to the south and east of Greece (taking on the Persians, Egyptians, and Indians).Rise of Rome (300 B.C.) - Players control either Rome, Carthage, Greece, Gaul, or Egypt, as they battle for control of the Mediterranean.Vikings (800 A.D.) - Players take on the role as the ruler of the Vikings, sending their men out on numerous raids against Europe (and collecting loot).Genghis Khan (1206 A.D.) - Players control the leadership of Genghis Khan, who must capture (or destroy) all of Asia.Omens (1753 A.D.) - Players command either Great Britain or France at the start of the Seven Years' War.An eighth scenario, Barbarians!, is a unique scenario in which the world is generated with competing civilizations, and the player enters as the leader of the barbarian horde (set out to destroy everything in their path).System RequirementsPC MinimumPC RecommendedOS: Windows 2000/XP/Vista/Windows 7Processor: 1.2GHz Intel Pentium 4 or AMD Athlon processor or equivalentMemory: 256MB RAMVideo: 64 MB Video Card w/ Hardware TL (GeForce 2/Radeon 7500 or better)Sound: DirectX7 compatible sound cardHDD: 1.7GB of free hard drive spaceSoftware: DirectX9.0cOS: Windows 2000/XP/Vista/Windows 7Processor: 1.8GHz Intel Pentium 4 or AMD Athlon processor or equivalent/betterMemory: 512 MB RAMVideo: 128 MB Video Card w/ DirectX 8 support (pixel and vertex shaders)Sound: DirectX7 compatible sound cardHDD: 1.7GB of free hard drive spaceSoftware: DirectX9.0cMac MinimumMac RecommendedOS: Mac OS X 10.5.8 or higherProcessor: Intel chipsetCPU Speed: 1.8 GHzMemory: 512 MB RAMHard Disk Space: 3.5 GB free disk spaceVideo Card: (ATI): Radeon 9600 Video Card (NVidia): GeForce FX 5200Video Memory: (VRam): 64 MB or higherMultiplayer: Internet (TCP/IP) and LAN (TCP/IP) play supported. Internet play requires broadband connection.Media Required: DVD Drive Supported Video cards: NVIDIA GeForce 5200, 6600, 6800, 7800 ATI Radeon 9600, 9650, 9700, 9800, X600, X800, X850, X1600OS: Mac OS X 10.5.8 or higherProcessor: Intel chipsetCPU Speed: 2.0 GHzMemory: 512 MB RAMHard Disk Space: 3.5 GB free disk spaceVideo Card: (ATI): Radeon 9600 Video Card (NVidia): GeForce FX 5200Video Memory: (VRam): 128 MB RAMMultiplayer: Internet (TCP/IP) and LAN (TCP/IP) play supported. Internet play requires broadband connection.Media Required: DVD Drive Supported Video cards: NVIDIA GeForce 5200, 6600, 6800, 7800 ATI Radeon 9600, 9650, 9700, 9800, X600, X800, X850, X1600NOTICE: This game is not supported on volumes formatted as Mac OS Extended (Case Sensitive).</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="8">Educational</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14391">Heroes of Might and Magic: A Strategic Quest</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/30036/2240309-6534635.jpg</image></root>