<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8384</id><name>The Adventures of Willy Beamish</name><description>OverviewWilly Beamish is a point and click adventure game with several odd (especially at the time) game mechanics. It features the passage of time: certain events only take place at certain times of day, and Willy only has a certain amount of time to complete each "block" of time. It's a similar mechanic to that of Majora's Mask albeit in a totally different genre. Secondly the game features a "trouble meter" which indicates just how close Willy Beamish is to being sent to military school. If it fills up, the game is over.The game's universe is an odd mix of fantasy and reality - exemplified by one scene where Willy's babysitter turns out to be a practitioner of witchcraft. An adventure-puzzle based boss battle ensues when she attempts to kill Willy and his sister.The game's cartoony look was accomplished by using hand painted backgrounds and hand-animated sprites, like many adventure games of the era.An argument can perhaps be put forth that Willy Beamish pioneered the inclusion of every-day tasks in video games. Willy has to eat dinner and make conversation with his family, and at one point you have to disinfect and bandage your own finger after cutting it. It implements these tasks into the puzzle solving and even make them integral to the plot at times.Willy Beamish's frog is named "Horny".  Metagame Along with every-day, mundane tasks, Willy can also head to his bedroom at most times to play the game-within-a-game: Monster Squad Super Space K'noidtrix for the Nintari game console. An interesting mix of Arkanoid and Tetris, puzzle-like pieces are thrown onto the playfield which must be avoided and destroyed before they stack up to the top of the screen. Several powerups can be shot and collected in the same manner as Arkanoid and can even be leveled up as rounds grow faster and harder. Combined with the peculiar soundtrack it makes for a decidedly Japanese feel in the middle of this Western-made game. System RequirementsThe original PC system requirements are:MS-DOS 5.0 or greater286 or better512 KB RAM8.5 MB Hard drive spaceVGA Thunderboard Pro Aud Spectrum, AdLib, Roland MT-32/LAPC-1/CM-32L or SoundBlasterMouse</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11852">Sam &amp; Max Hit the Road</game><game id="22906">Tiny Toon Adventures: Toonenstein Dare to Scare</game><game id="21174">Full Throttle</game><game id="4372">Maniac Mansion: Day of the Tentacle</game><game id="13230">Grim Fandango</game><game id="11508">Space Quest: The Sarien Encounter</game><game id="2448">Rise of the Dragon</game><game id="6715">The Dark Crystal</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9408/721520-6997_boxshot_the_adventures_of_willy_beamish.jpg</image></root>