<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8407</id><name>Shogun: Total War</name><description>OverviewShogun: Total War is the first game in Creative Assembly's Total War series. Shogun blends Risk-like turn-based strategy with real-time tactical management. The Sengoku period (during which the game is set) and Sun Tzu's The Art of War are central concepts; the Sengoku period was a hundred-year swath of internecine, territorial warring and Tzu's work provides loading screen quotations and the basis for the game's battlefield AI. A sequel was released on March 15, 2011 named Total War: Shogun 2.GameplayShogun: Total War is divided into turns: at the beginning of each turn each faction will decide what units and buildings to construct in which regions and then move their armies. When the end turn button is pressed each faction's orders are executed simultaneously; if two opposing armies occupy the same territory the outcome of the battle can either be determined automatically or the player can switch to a real-time tactical battle. Turns cycle through the four seasons with weather and wind conditions affected which, in turn, affect battles.Terrain also plays a huge role in the tactical battles. Ranged units on higher ground gain large rage bonuses, melee units are more effective, and units attempting to climb up the incline will suffer a huge speed penalty. Calvary units lose maneuverability and effectiveness in forests and lose speed in snowy winter situations. Ranged units can be hindered by rain, with bows becoming less effective and guns failing to work altogether, and forests vastly decrease accuracy as missiles are blocked by trees. These elements also mean that the deployment phase is extremely important as factions holding the high ground can easily defeat a force nearly twice their size.All units have an honor rating: honor is the experience level of the unit, with higher honor making units far more effective in battle and less likely to rout when they take heavy loses. Generals also earn a honor rating that increases upon their success in battle; this in turn bestows bonuses on the armies they command. This encourages the player to preserve their elite units, as throwing them into enemy lines will both lose you the elite unit and also increase the honor of your enemy's unit. Units can earn honor in multiple ways; training in certain provinces or in higher level buildings can increase their honor but the most common way is to earn honor is to defeat enemy units in battle.Another element to the strategic half of the game is the agent units. These units are trained exactly like regular units but they each have different functions. Emissaries are used to negotiate treaties with opposing factories and spies can be used to see the strengths of units in enemy regions, but by far the most useful is the ninja (or the geisha, a unit with similar abilities). The ninja can kill specific characters such as spies or generals. A general with a very high honor might be next to impossible to kill on the battlefield, but using the ninja to kill him while he sleeps can confuse and disorientate his army and leave them leaderless and vulnerable in battle. Uniquely, each assassination mission undertaken is accompanied by a video of the ninja attempting to eliminate his target. These videos show either the ninja killing his target or the target catching and killing the ninja.Playable FactionsThere are seven playable factions in Shogun: Total War: Shimazu (green), Mori (red), Oda (orange), Imagawa (light blue), Takeda (black), Hojo (purple) and Uesugi (blue).ShimazuThe Shimazu are based in a secure location in the south-east of the map. They maintain control of the province of Satsuma, which is famous for its No-Dachi Samurai.Starting Units:3 Yari Samurai3 Samurai Archers2 Yari AshigaruStrategic Advantage:Train and maintain No-Dachi Samurai for a lower cost.MoriThe Mori has a great respect for tradition and religion and inspire fanaticism among their Warrior Monks. They are in the north of the map slightly to the west. They start with the province of Iga which has rich silver deposits which can be exploited by building mines.Starting Units:5 Yari Samurai5 Samurai Archers2 Yari AshigaruStragic Advantage:Train and maintain Warrior Monks for a lower cost.OdaThe Oda operate on a broad battle plan: leave no one alive, they are know for their ferocity and are willing fight rival clan or monk alike in their persuit of power. They begin with the province of Iga and Kii, the former is famous for its Ninjas and the latter is famous for its strong yet rebellious Warrior Monks. The are based just west of the centre of the map.Staring Units:10 Yari Ashigaru6 Samurai ArchersStrategic Advantage:Train and maintain Yari Ashigaru for a lower cost.ImagawaThe Imagawa occupy the centre of the map which although it offers them stratigic advantages it also means that they are surrounded which means they must use other methods, such as diplomacy, to succeed, the also have provinces in the top left of the map. The begin with the province of Totomi which is famous for the skills of its archers.Starting Units:6 Samurai Archers6 Yari Samurai2 NinjaStrategic Advantage:Train ninja and shinobi for a lower cost.TakedaThe Takeda are ruthless masters of the traditional arts of war, using any means necessary. They are famous for the ferociousness of their cavalry. Their territories are divided, one section is just left of the centre of the map and the other is just to the right. The province of Kai which they possess has rich veins of gold, which can be utilized, and Aki has rich veins of silver. They also possess Sagami which is one of the richest provincies in japan.Starting Units:4 Yari Samurai1 Samurai Archers3 Cavalry Archers3 Yari CavalryStrategic Advantage:Train and maintain Cavalry for a lower cost.HojoHistorically, the Late Hojo clan: unrelated to the Mongol-repelling regents of centuries before, they appropriated the name for its illustrious legacy. They prefer to rely on wealth, fighting prowess and mighty fortresses, rather than other methods such as diplomacy. They possess the territories Musashi, Kozuke and Hitachi which are some of the most fertile lands in Japan. They also control the Shimotsuke which has copper deposites which can be exploited. They are based in the top right of the map. The provinces of Dewa, Mutsu and Echigo are rich and productive.Starting Units:2 Yari Samurai4 Samurai Archers2 Yari AshigaruStrategic Advantage:Build castles for a lower cost.UesugiThe Uesugi are experianced tough warriors with wise generals. They are based in the top right of the map. They possess the provinces of Dewa, Mutsu and Echigo are rich and productive. In addition to this Dewa is rich in gold and Echigois rich in silver. Also they have Shinano which is famous for its cavalry.Starting units:3 Yari Samurai4 Samurai Archers2 Yari AshigaruStrategic Advantage:Train and maintain Archers for a lower cost.Unplayable FactionsRebelsThese are made up of smaller neutral clans which fight for their independence, ronin (masterless samurai), rebellious peasants, and even fanatical warrior monks. They cannot be controlled as they are not grouped together under one leader.Battlefield UnitsThese are the units that are availiable for you to use on the battlefield.Yari AshigaruThese are common conscripted foot soldiers, which carry spears. They aren't very strong or durable, but they are quite cheap. They require a Spear Dojo to train them.Attack factor: -1Defense factor: -1Armor: 2Morale bonus: -4Walk speed: 7Run speed: 12Yari SamuraiThese are spear carrying, heavily armored samurai, which can be quite effective against cavalry. They require a Spear Dojo to train them.Attack factor: 0Defense factor: 2Armor: 3Morale bonus: 2Walk speed: 6Run speed: 10Samurai ArchersSamurai Archers are the main long range unit through out the game. An Archery Dojo is required to train them.Attack factor: 0Defense factor:0Armor: 1Morale bonus: 0Walk speed: 6Run speed: 10No-Dachi SamuraiThey are foot soldiers’ which carry large swords, but they are lighlty armored and are vulnerable to ranged attacks. A Sword Dojo is required to train them.Attack factor: 5Defense factor: -2Armor: 1Morale bonus: 8Walk speed: 7Run speed: 12Warrior MonksThese are one of the most powerful infantry units in the game. They carry a shrine as a standard which makes other units (apart from Christian units) reluctant to attack them. A Buddhist temple is required to obtain them.Attack factor: 5Defense factor: 2Armor: 1Morale bonus: 8Walk speed: 7Run speed: 12NaginataThe Naginata is the most heavily defended infantry unit in the game, yet they are very slow. An Armory and a Famous Spear Dojo is required to train them.Attack factor: 0Defense factor: 6Armor: 5Morale bonus: 4Walk speed: 4Run speed: 8Yari CavalryYari Cavalry are basic cavalry which carry spears, they are vulnerable to tightly packed formations of infantry spearmen. A Spear Dojo and a Horse Dojo are required to train Yari Cavalry.Attack factor: 2Defense factor: 2Armor: 3Morale bonus: 2Walk speed: 10Run speed: 24Cavalry ArchersArchers on the back of horses, but they are not as accurate as Samurai Archers. The Archery Dojo and a Horse Dojo is required to be able to train Cavalry Archers.Attack factor: 1Defense factor: 2Armor: 3Morale bonus: 0Walk speed: 8Run speed: 20Heavy CavarlyThey are powerful mounted units which carry swords. Usually the faction leader (Daimyo) and the Taisho (generals can be the daimyos heirs) appear in groups of 11 heavy cavalry. A Famous Horse Dojo is required to train them as well as an Armory.Attack factor: 2Defense factor: 6Armor: 5Morale bonus: 4Walk speed: 8Run speed: 20ArquebusiersThese troops use early primitive guns acquired from Dutch and Portuguese traders, they do not work in wet weather due to the powder getting damp and the matches (firing mechanism) getting put out. They require a treaty with the Dutch or the Portuguese plus a Dutch Trading Post or a Portuguese Trading Post plus depending on who you treat with.Attack factor: -6Defense factor: -3Armor: 2Morale bonus: -4Walk speed: 7Run speed: 12MusketeersThese are similar to Arquebusiers except the have a higher rate of fire. As well as the requirements for Arquebusiers a gun factory is also requiredAttack factor: -6Defense factor: -3Armor: 2Morale bonus: -4Walk speed: 7Run speed: 12Non-Battlefield UnitsThese units are political tools as well military tools, they can give you a significant military advantage.EmissaryEmissaries can offer treaties, alliances, or ceasefires to other Daimyos on behalf of your Daimyos. They require a Tranquil Garden to be trained.NinjaA ninja is an assassin/spy who operates covertly in an enemy's province. He can assassinate generals and heads of armies yet if he is inexperienced, he will fall easily. A Ninja House is required to train them.ShinobiA Shinobi is a spy/counter spy: he may detect undercover agents in the player's own territories. He can also gain information such as troop numbers as well as dissolving loyalty towards the Daimyo of the enemy province he is in. A Tea House is required to train a Shinboi.GeishaThese play a similar role to the Ninja except they have more chance of successfully killing higher officials. A Legendary Tea House, a Tranquil Garden, and an Infamous Ninja House are required to train one.Useful linksOfficial website</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8876">Sid Meier's Colonization</game><game id="29207">Europa Universalis: For the Glory</game><game id="8349">Hearts of Iron</game><game id="29283">King Arthur: The Role-Playing Wargame</game><game id="29182">Takeda 3</game><game id="2846">Age of Empires II: The Age of Kings</game><game id="31531">Total War: Shogun 2</game><game id="9792">Jeff Wayne's The War of the Worlds</game><game id="186">Stronghold</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2130/642396-shogun.jpg</image></root>