<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8440</id><name>Red Dead Revolver</name><description>OverviewRed Harlow, the game's main protagonist.Red Dead Revolver is a third-person shooter developed by Rockstar San Diego and published by Rockstar (and Capcom for Japan). Set in the American Wild West during the 1880s, players take the role of quiet-mouthed bounty hunter Red Harlow as he sets off to dispense his own brand of justice while seeking revenge for the murder of his parents at a young age.The game was originally in production by Capcom, which had a more arcade experience (borrowing elements from their 1985 arcade game Gun.Smoke). However, after Capcom dropped production in 2002, Rockstar bought the game and produced it with their San Diego team, giving it a theme similar to Spaghetti Western films while refining the gameplay to a refined third-person shooter.Red Dead Revolver is considered to be the spiritual predecessor to Rockstar San Diego's 2010 game, Red Dead Redemption. Though Red Dead Redemption softens both the arcade-style action and over-the-top theme, both games share many similarities (including the Dead-Eye targeting mode). Eight characters from Red Dead Revolver, including Red himself, are playable characters in Red Dead Redemption via paid downloadable content.GameplayThe game takes a level structure, comprising of around 24 levels. For the most part, the player takes control of Red Harlow, out to get revenge for his parents' murder, only the player also takes control of Annie Stoakes, Jack Swift, Shadow Wolf, a Buffalo Soldier and General Diego for certain levels.Whilst most of the game takes place on foot, there are instances where Red is on horseback. The player controls these segments in much the same way as when Red is on foot.In addition to the single player campaign, which lasts roughly 8 or 9 hours, there are a few multiplayer modes;"Bounty Hunter" which takes the form of a standard death match, with card game influenced titles"Sundown" which the same as "Bounty Hunter" only with a time limit rather than a death limit."High Noon"This last game mode is unique to Red Dead Revolver. It is the archetypal gun "duel" in which 1-4 players must quickly draw and kill all the remaining characters before they are killed themselves. Duels consist of pulling the character's hand down to the holster using the Right Stick and then bringing it back up once the gun has been drawn. If the player draws the hand back too early, they will not have grasped the revolver and therefore cannot shoot.There is a large amount of characters to play as who can be unlocked by competing challenges in the story mode. Each character has unique abilities which are particularly evident in High Noon. It features two players in a slow-motion quick-draw where a targeting reticule runs across their body and goes from green to yellow and red. Yellow means a powerful shot, red is near-fatal, and green is a miss. While drawing and shooting first gives a distinct advantage, patience and accuracy are key to winning.WeaponsThroughout the game you can buy or acquire many different weapons, all dating back to the old west. Here are all of the weapons in the game.Side ArmsOld PistolSix ShooterTwin RevolversRevolverInquisitorWidowmakerScorpion RevolverNot pictured:PacificadorLong ArmsHalcon RifleOwl RifleRepeater RifleHigh Caliber RifleBayonet RifleThe Oppressor12 Gauge ShotgunSawn-Off ShotgunEscopeta (Spanish for shotgun)Zwei Fasser (German for two barrels)The LionBreech LoaderThrownKnifeFire BottleDynamiteNot pictured:Bow and ArrowSnake Oil</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/13158/1039634-gb.png</image></root>