<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8521</id><name>SVC Chaos: SNK vs. Capcom</name><description>OverviewSNK vs. Capcom: SVC Chaos is the final Capcom and SNK crossover fighting game that followed the release of Capcom vs. SNK 2: Mark of the Millennium 2001. Developed by SNK, SVC Chaos is strictly a 1-on-1 fighting game that is missing some of the gameplay mechanics found in Capcom vs. SNK 2 but is instead focused on faster gameplay.CharactersViolent KenThere are a total of 36 playable characters. The mid-bosses and final bosses fought depend on the player's progress through the game. The more skilled the player, the more likely they are to face the more challenging opponents. The game also features a pair of original characters in special boss forms of Mr. Karate and Violent Ken, a version of Ken Masters similar in nature to Evil Ryu or Orochi Iori seen in other games. To date, SVC Chaos marks the only appearance of Violent Ken.SNK CharactersNormal Terry Bogard (Fatal Fury) Mai Shiranui (Fatal Fury 2) Kim Kaphwan (Fatal Fury 2) Ryo Sakazaki (Art of Fighting) Mr. Karate (Art of Fighting) Kasumi Todoh (Art of Fighting 3) Kyo Kusanagi (King of Fighters '94) Choi Bounge (King of Fighters '94) Iori Yagami (King of Fighters '95) Earthquake (Samurai Shodown) Genjuro Kibagami (Samurai Shodown II) Shiki (Samurai Shodown 64)Midboss Geese Howard (Fatal Fury) Leopald Goenitz (King of Fighters '96) Orochi Iori (King of Fighters '97) Mars People (Metal Slug 2)Final BossMr. Karate (Original) Athena (Athena)Capcom CharactersNormal Ryu (Street Fighter) Ken Masters (Street Fighter) Sagat (Street Fighter) Chun-Li (Street Fighter II) Guile (Street Fighter II) Dhalsim (Street Fighter II) Balrog (Street Fighter II) Vega (Street Fighter II) M. Bison (Street Fighter II) Akuma (Super Street Fighter II Turbo) Hugo (Street Fighter III 2nd Impact) Tessa (Red Earth)Midboss Violent Ken (Original) Dan Hibiki (Street Fighter Alpha) Demitri Maximoff (Darkstalkers) Zero (Mega Man Zero)Final Boss Shin Akuma (Super Street Fighter 2 Turbo) Red Arremer (Ghosts 'n Goblins)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1615">Street Fighter III: 3rd Strike</game><game id="7751">Art of Fighting Anthology</game><game id="16793">Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="9726">Super Street Fighter II: Turbo Revival</game><game id="617">NeoGeo Battle Coliseum</game><game id="20728">Tatsunoko vs. Capcom: Ultimate All Stars</game><game id="32161">Street Fighter X Tekken</game><game id="32162">Tekken X Street Fighter</game><game id="30558">Sunday vs. Magazine: Shuuketsu! Choujou Daikessen</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2151661-box_svcc.png</image></root>