<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8542</id><name>Super Noah's Ark 3D</name><description>OriginsDisappointed with the number and severity of edits that Nintendo forced them to make to the Super Nintendo version of Wolfenstein 3-D, id Software moved to get their revenge in a roundabout way by taking the SNES engine for the game and licencing it for free to Wisdom Tree, a developer known for making unlicenced, low quality religious video games for Nintendo consoles.OverviewArmed with the Wolfenstein 3-D engine, Super Noah’s Ark 3-D was created by Wisdom Tree and released in 1994. The Nazi enemies from the original game have been replaced with sheep, goats, camels, and other animals, and the guns were replaced with a few different types of slingshots. You play as Noah, and it’s your job to feed all the rogue animals until they fall asleep by shooting grain and other foods at them with your slingshot. Super Noah’s Ark 3-D was the only unlicenced Super Nintendo game ever released, and the cartridge was black and oddly shaped. In order to even play the game, you had to insert a "real" SNES game into the slot built into the top of the Noah’s Ark cartridge, to allow it to bypass a SRAM check that would determine if the cartridge was official, illegally exploiting the system and getting around Nintendo's built-in safeguards against unlicenced games.StoryAs Noah, your journey inside the Ark has been a long one, but you're just days away from the time when the waters will recede and it’ll all be over. However, the animals have all become restless and have escaped their pens. Now it’s up to you to restore order and get the animals back in their places before the trip is over. You must not kill them, as they are the last animals on Earth, so you must use your slingshot to shoot food into their mouths, calming them and putting them to sleep. Subduing all the animals and returning them to their pens will thus bring your journey to an end.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7694">Wolfenstein 3D</game><game id="29367">Little Red Hood</game><game id="1505">Blake Stone: Aliens of Gold</game><game id="15567">I.M. Meen</game><game id="4512">H.U.R.L.</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14684/383837-noah3.jpg</image></root>