<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8573</id><name>Clubhouse Games</name><description>GamesThe games in Clubhouse Games are organized into various categories:   Card Games Basic Card GamesIntermediate Card GamesAdvanced Card GamesOld MaidBlackjackFive Card DrawSpitHeartsTexas Hold 'EmI Doubt ItPresidentNapSevensRummySpadesMemorySeven BridgeContract BridgePigLast Card  Last Card Plus Board Games Basic Board GamesAdvanced Board GamesChinese CheckersBackgammonCheckersChessDots and BoxesShogiHasami ShogiField TacticsTurncoatLudoConnect Five Grid Attack    Parlor Games  Variety GamesAction GamesSingle-Player GamesSoda ShakeBowlingSolitaireDominoesDartsEscapeKoi-KoiBilliardsMahjong SolitaireWord BalloonBalance  Takeover   Gameplay ChatThe chat feature is very similar to Pictochat in that it allows the use of drawing or writing with the stylus to message whoever is in the room with them. However, it offers more diverse tools than Pictochat through the use of 13 different colors, a paint tool, and a stamp tool. It is accessible at most times and allows a conversation to carry with local players during any game or in the menus between games. Single PlayerFree playFree play allows the player to select and play any of the 42 various games.As the player completes a game a certain amount of times, they are rewarded with different designs that act like skins for said game. This includes anything from changing the color or texture of card decks, backgrounds, or, in the case of the action games, it can cause entire graphical overhauls, allowing the player to choose from the normal design to a stone, paper, or digital aesthetic. The game also keeps tracks of the records of each game played, tracking the players' attempt and completion rate. A handful of games even allow the player to switch between a type of rule set that typically includes how many rounds a game is played for or other game-specific restrictions. Other than the Single-Player games, which include Solitaire, Escape, and Mahjong Solitaire, the player is able to pick between one to three computer controlled opponents, per the games necessity.StampStamp mode is another mode in which the player is tasked with completing each game in a strict progression one after another. Each game requires 3 stamps to progress to the next game. Depending on how well a player completes one round of the game, they will be awarded with a certain amount of stamps that contributes to their overall progress. If a player acquires an abundance of stamps on one game, they will carry over to the next game. Once the player reaches the end, normal and hard difficulties unlock, and completion of those modes give the players added functionality in the chat.MissionMission mode is a series of thirty missions that span most of the games included in the free play mode. They typically involve either reaching a set goal of points or involve completing a game with a unique request you must accomplish before that game ends. Each successful completion of a mission unlocks a specific icon that player can use in conjunction with their name for when in chat mode or to identify them in a multiplayer game. After completing each of the thirty missions, a pop version of the background music unlocks.MuiltiplayerLocal WirelessThis menu allows players to play locally with other players in all multiplayer games provided they own a copy of the game as well. If not, the player with a copy of the game may gift a demo of any of the 42 games to the recipient, albeit with no multiplayer features.Nintendo WFCHere, players can compete in a Wi-Fi Battle or edit their friend and Wi-Fi settings.  In Wi-Fi Battle, players can compete against friends or challenge other players worldwide in any multiplayer game except for Old Maid, Spit, I Doubt It, and Pig.RanksIn this menu option, players can check Nintendo WFC and local wireless records as well as checking their friends ranks and worldwide ranks.   DSiWare Releases    Beginning on April 27th, 2009, Nintendo began releasing truncated versions of the full release in America for a smaller price on the DSiWare shop, which is exclusive to the Nintendo DSi system. The first release was Clubhouse Games Express: Card Classics, released on April 27, 2009. It included the Blackjack, Five Card Draw, Last Card, Last Card Plus, and President games and was sold for 500 Nintendo points ($5.00). The second to be released in America was Clubhouse Games Express: Family Favorites on September 7, 2009. This release included the Hearts, Contract Bridge, Dominoes, Ludo, and Dots and Boxes games and was sold again for 500 Nintendo points ($5.00). A third entry, which has already been released in Japan, is to be called Clubhouse Games Express: Strategy Games and is expected to go for the same price point of 500 Nintendo points.</description><genres><genre id="13">Card Game</genre><genre id="14">Trivia/Board Game</genre><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22346">Ultimate Board Game Collection</game><game id="12083">Uno</game><game id="29062">100 All-Time Favorites</game><game id="13621">Mario's Game Gallery</game><game id="28221">50 Classic Games</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/26/961996-clubhousegameslogo.png</image></root>