<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8584</id><name>Terminator 3: The Redemption</name><description>This Terminator game was set to come out with the theatrical release of Terminator 3:Rise of the Machines.  However the game's production started 8 short months before the movie was due to hit theaters.  The game that was planned was far to large to complete in that amount of time and a reasonable quality level. So Atari, brought on Black Ops to create a First person shooter Terminator based game that would come out when the movie hit theaters.   Unfortunately 8 months proved too short for that game as well and ended up scoring very poorly in the media and tainting the Terminator franchise with the help of Terminator 3: War of the Machines.Terminator 3: Redemption was originally titled Terminator 3: Chase because the game play revolved around vehicular combat and the levels were designed in a race track approach.  However after seeing the poor press reception of other Terminator 3 based games, it was retitled with the "Redemption" Tag in the hopes of redeeming the Franchise.The Storyline follows the events of the movie, Rise of the Machines, while filling in story gaps as well as creates it's own fiction.  About halfway through the game The Terminator T-850(The Player Character) is sent to an alternate future where John Conner was killed by the T-X(Terminatrix) and mankind has been completely wiped out.  The Player must fightt here was to Skynet headquarters and use the Time Chamber and get back to present day and stop that Alternate future from occuring.  The alternate future is dominated by skynet's machines which are larger and more destructive because there was no John Conner led resistance to stop them.  The environment looked distinctly different as well and was painted with a red skyline and very sparse buildings.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14843">Spy Hunter</game><game id="14871">The Terminator: Dawn of Fate</game><game id="3575">Battalion Wars</game><game id="9051">Psi-Ops: The Mindgate Conspiracy</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2285716-box_t3tr.png</image></root>