<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8632</id><name>Soldier of Fortune: Payback</name><description>OverviewThe game's signature dismemberment and gore effects in action.Soldier of Fortune Payback is the third game in the Soldier of Fortune series. It was developed by Cauldron, and released by Activision Value. The game was generally received poorly by critics and fans alike, who claimed that it's only redeeming quality is the series' signature bloody dismemberment. Shooting an enemy's limb could result in it being blown off, exposing the bone, and blood spewing from the wound onto the surroundings. The game also features 12 player multiplayer, but is scarcely populated in this post Call of Duty 4 world. Luckily, the gore is maintained in multiplayer.ControversyThe Soldier of Fortune series has always been in hot water for it's excessive violence, and the trend continues with Payback. The game was effectively banned in Australia on October 16, 2007, being denied a rating as well as sale in the country. The game was, however, eventually planned for release in New Zealand with a rating of R18. Soldier of Fortune: Payback came out on schedule in North America.Xbox 360 Game InstallationSoldier of Fortune: Payback requires 3.4GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD.</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20655">Battlefield: Bad Company</game><game id="20479">Army of Two</game><game id="2106">Conflict: Denied Ops</game><game id="18162">Team Fortress 2</game><game id="23907">Secret Service</game><game id="9491">Cold Winter</game><game id="12311">Delta Force: Black Hawk Down - Team Sabre</game><game id="4878">Combat: Task Force 121</game><game id="22858">Rogue Warrior</game><game id="29336">Medal of Honor</game><game id="5722">Counter-Strike: Condition Zero</game><game id="3550">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six: Vegas</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2314078-box_sofp.png</image></root>