<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8763</id><name>Neverwinter Nights 2: Mask of the Betrayer</name><description>Mask of the Betrayer is the first expansion pack for Neverwinter Nights 2, following up directly on the story of that game and taking place in Rashemen.  Players are allowed to import already created characters into the expansion or create a character from one of several new classes, with the Red Wizards of Thay being the most crucial to the plot of the game.    DevouringOne of the key gameplay changes between Neverwinter Nights 2, and Mask of the Betrayer is that a hunger resides inside of the player character that requires him/her to devour souls for sustenance. Depending on their moral alignment, they can choose to suppress the hunger which can only be done once per day, or they can choose to devour souls that they come across which can be done multiple times per day, but results in an addiction that will require the character to devour more and more souls.  As time passes without a soul being consumed or the hunger being suppressed, a hunger meter will begin to fill up. As the meter begins to hit certain waypoints, the player will become weaker and weaker until eventually they die.   Recruitable Characters  Safiya - she is a practical, honest and knowledgeable character, with a bald head which decorated with a tatto which marks her as a Red Wizard of Thay. Safiya specializes in transmutation and is very fond of her familiar Kaji, one of her earlier creations . She is the first companion to join the player's party and is a romance option for male charecters.  Gannayev of Dreams (Gann) - Is an optional follower for the player, and recruited to the party if the player chooses to release him from his prison. Gann is unusually charismatic and witty, but his constant emphasis of his physical appeal makes him seem self-centered and superficial. He is a romance option for female charecters.  Okku - Is a bear god and an optional party member if the player chooses to spare his life.  One of Many -  is an evil being that devours souls and can join the player's party if the player choose not to spare Okku and then bring its pelt to play host to the evil entity.   Kaelyn the Dove - Is a half-celestial who's only concern is to rally troops and bringing about the third crusade. She is a zealous character, loyal and pure but sometimes can be quite naive.   New Features   2 new base classes:  Spirit shaman    Favored soul   5 new  prestige classes:  Stormlord  Sacred fist Invisible Blade Red Wizard of Thay  Arcane Scholar of Candlekeep     6 new sub-races:  Wild elf Half-drow Air genasi Water genasi Fire genasi Earth genasi     Epic Levels - the level cap was increased from 20 to 30.  60 new epic feats. More than 50 new spells. New DD monsters. Enhancements to the mod-making tools. New tilesets  terrains.   System Requirements Minimum:  Windows XP/Vista Intel Pentium 4 2.0 GHz or AMD Athlon XP 2000 or equivalent  512 MB RAM  5.5 GB free hard disk space   ATI Radeon 8500 or NVIDIA GeForce 3 or 4 MX Series Video Card w/ 32MB of VRAM Windows XP-compatible sound card   Recommended:  Windows XP/Vista Intel Pentium® 4 3.0 GHz or AMD Athlon™ XP 64  1 GB RAM 5.5 GB free hard disk space    ATI Radeon 9000 or NVIDIA GeForce 4 Ti Series Video Card w/ 64MB of VRAM Windows XP-compatible sound card   </description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10637">Baldur's Gate II: Shadows of Amn</game><game id="17949">The Elder Scrolls III: Tribunal</game><game id="2235">Planescape: Torment</game><game id="10473">The Witcher</game><game id="30995">Dragon Age II</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/30036/1291451-box_l.jpg</image></root>