<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8810</id><name>Suikoden</name><description>OverviewSuikoden was developed by Konami KCE-Tokyo and directed by Yoshitaka Murayama. Originally planned as a single game, it has gone on to spawn five sequels and multiple spin-offs. The game was first released in Japan in December 1995, United States in December 1996, and Europe in 1996 for the Sony Playstation. In 1998, the game was released for both the Sega Saturn (Japan) and the PC (Japan, China, and Korea). In its lifetime, Suikoden has sold roughly 216,542 copies.In 2008, it was released as a PSone Classic on the PlayStation Network. A Japanese-only mobile version was released the same year.StoryThe game is set in a fantasy world resembling feudal China. It begins in Solar Year 455 and ends in 457. The game follows the adventures of Tir McDohl, a young staff fighter. He learns early on that he is destined to be the "Tenkai Star", a prophesied hero that will unite the 108 Stars of Destiny and bring forth a new age of prosperity. Throughout the game, Tir learns of the 27 True Runes, which hold great power. These same runes, if in the wrong hands can be used to destroy or enslave the world. Early in the game, Tir inherits the Rune of Life and Death, also known as "Soul Eater", which grants him great power, but that power comes at a price.Tir and his entourage encounter many enemies throughout the game. Their main foe is the Scarlet Moon Empire. Tir's father, Teo McDohl is one of the Six Great Generals of the Scarlet Moon Army. Tir briefly joins the army, but soon becomes entangled with a rebel force known as the Liberation army. Tir and his friends join the rebel army after learning of its' goals and the tyrannous ways of the empire. They then begin the long journey to stop to the empire's evil ways, and restore it to its former glory.GameplaySuikoden was one of the first (traditional) RPGs for the Playstation. There are three types of combat in Suikoden: standard turn-based, large army battles, and one on one duels. The turn-based battles are much the same as any traditional Japanese RPG, giving the player time to choose their actions and fight at their own pace. The large scale army battles work on a glorified rock, paper, scissors type system, with players choosing from 3 different units and going against the enemy's unit until one side defeats the other. The one on one battles work largely the same as the army battles with the player choosing one of 3 different attack types each turn. A wrong choice in any battle could result in the permanent death of one of the 108 stars. Losing one of the main characters effects the outcome of the game.The major goal in the game is to recruit all 108 stars while progressing through the story. All of the 108 are usable at any time after they have recruited. Some of the characters you recruit are Active, meaning that you will be able to add them to your six person entourage. Others are Passive, meaning that they are not available for your entourage. Passive characters will stay at your headquarters and setup five different kinds of stores. Those stores are a blacksmith, an appraiser, an armorsmith, a runemaster, and general goods. Other passive characters will be available for mini-games such as a dice game, a memory game or a coin-and-cup game. Others serve as an outlet to customize your menu window theme, sound theme, and bathhouse decorations. There are many characters who serve as both Active and Passive.A major perk of the game was the ability to transfer your data from Suikoden I to its sequel, Suikoden II.SoundtrackThe OST Cover ArtThe Suikoden soundtrack was released as 2 discs and with 48 tracks on April 5, 1996. Published by King Records and was composed and arranged by Miki Higashino, Tappy Iwase, Taniguchi Hirofumi, Mayuko Kageshita and Hiroshi Tamawari. The Suikoden Soundtrack was only released in Japan.Tracklist:Disc One01 - Into a World of Illusions02 - Beginning Theme03 - Royal Palace Consultation04 - Eternal Empire05 - Beautiful Golden City06 - Main Theme Arranged~Guitar Version07 - Fly, Black!08 - Black Forest09 - Touching Theme10 - Tiny Characters in a Huge World11 - Distant Mountain12 - Penpe13 - Confrontation with Monsters14 - Victory Theme15 - Rock Rockland16 - Theme of Tension~Ensemble Version17 - Theme of Sadness~Ensemble Version18 - Eternal Flow19 - Joy Joy Time20 - Intrusion21 - Mysterious Forest22 - People of Great Pride23 - Theme of Despair24 - Peaceful People25 - Rising Tide26 - Theme of Perversion27 - This Sweetie is the Town Treasure28 - Narcy's Theme29 - Gorgeous Scarleticia30 - Dancing GirlDisc Two01 - Collision!02 - Victory March03 - Tense Crisis04 - Theme of Sadness~Guitar Version05 - Inside the Silence06 - Gathering of Warriors07 - Theme of Tension~Impact Version08 - This is Just a Rumor09 - Forgotten Days10 - Passacaglia11 - Main Theme Arranged~Ensemble Version12 - Island Fortress13 - Glorious Island Fortress14 - Blue Oceans, Blue Skies15 - An Old Irish Song16 - Gate17 - Theme of a Moonlit Night18 - Theme of the Advancing Army19 - Echoes of the Changed Past20 - Ultimate Enemy21 - Theme of Tension~Tama-dator22 - Requiem23 - Avertuneiro Antes Lance Mao (After the Battle)24 - Tropical Bath FURO-mix25 - Cursed Bath~Long Steam Baths Are Taboo26 - Theme of Thoughtlessness27 - Gakkuri28 - FanfareThe 108 Stars of DestinyThe following is a complete account of all the characters that will join your quest.1. Tir Mcdohl (Main Character)2. Lepant3. Mathiu Silverberg4. Luc5. Humphrey Mintz6. Kasim Hazil7. Kwanda Rosman8. Pesmerga9. Gremio10. Warren11. Kun To12. Cleo13. Viktor14. Valeria15. Griffith16. Clive17. Flik18. Camille19. Kreutz20. Stallion21. Kage22. Fu Su Lu23. Kirkis24. Milich Oppenheimer25. Pahn26.Sonya Shulen27. Anji28. Tai Ho29. Kanak30. Yam Koo31. Leonardo32. Hix33. Tengaar34. Varkas35. Sydonia36. Eileen37. Leon Silverberg38. Georges39. Ivanov40. Jeane41. Eikei42. Maximillian43. Sancho44. Grenseal45. Alen46. Tesla47. Jabba48. Lorelai49. Blackman50. Joshua Levenheit51. Morgan52. Mose53. Esmeralda54. Melodye55. Chapman56. Liukan57. Fukien58. Futch59. Kasumi60. Maas61. Crowley62. Fuma63. Moose64. Meese65. Sergei66. Kimberly67. Sheena68. Kessler69. Marco70. Gen71. Hugo72. Hellion73. Mina74. Milia75. Kamandol76. Juppo77. Kasios78. Viki79. Rubi80. Vincent De Boule81. Meg82. Taggart83. Giovanni84. Quincy85. Apple86. Kai87. Lotte88. Mace89. Onil90. Kuromimi91. Gon92. Antonio93. Lester94. Kirke95. Rock96. Ledon97. Sylvina98. Ronnie Bell99. Gaspar100. Window101. Marie102. Zen103. Sarah104. Sansuke105. Qlon106. Templeton107. Krin108. Chandler</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6336">Final Fantasy VI</game><game id="17659">Grandia</game><game id="10401">Radiata Stories</game><game id="7940">Rogue Galaxy</game><game id="3762">Thousand Arms</game><game id="12099">Star Ocean: Till the End of Time</game><game id="20829">Final Fantasy IV</game><game id="17767">Lunar: Silver Star Story Complete</game><game id="10392">Paladin's Quest</game><game id="13180">The Legend of Dragoon</game><game id="7197">Dragon Quest V: Hand of the Heavenly Bride</game><game id="7447">Blue Dragon</game><game id="9177">Breath of Fire IV</game><game id="6557">Revelations: Persona</game><game id="27501">Hexyz Force</game><game id="9896">Beyond the Beyond</game><game id="38725">Americana Dawn</game><game id="9249">Chrono Trigger</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2099992-box_suikoden.png</image></root>