<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8873</id><name>GUN</name><description>OverviewDeveloped by Neversoft, then famous for the Tony Hawk Pro Skater series, GUN was an approach to a genre that didn't have much ground in the industry - the Western. The storyline, often considered the redeeming aspect of the game, was written by Randall Jahnson (Mask of Zorro, The Doors) and follows the life of Colton White after he finds out his father isn't really who he says he is.The game plays from the third person perspective, controlling Colton White, in a free-roaming environment. The sandbox styled world allows the player access to several side-missions and activities including poker games, cattle herding, law enforcement, and hunting. Side missions reward money to the player for purchasable upgrades such as additional health slots and speed loaders. Throughout the game the player can gain access to a wide variety of authentic weaponry including six shooters, rifles, shotguns, bows, and thrown explosives. When attacking enemies a "Quickdraw" meter fills up and, when activated, switches to a first person perspective as well as entering a Bullet Time like state. This game is very similar to a less popular western game released by Rockstar titled Red Dead Revolver.PlotColton WhiteColton White wakes up to his father Ned's call. They hunt game together supplying food and furs to steamboats traveling the Missouri river. They board a boat called the Morning Star where Ned meets with a girl named Sadie. She shows him something stored in the ship's safe. A suspicious looking man introduces himself to Colton as Reverend Josiah Reed. Colton follows him the the front of the ship where he hassles Sadie, telling her to tell him where "it" is. When she runs, he kills her with a throwing tomahawk then signals for a group of ambushers to come aboard. Ned and Colton hold them off until the boilers begin to blow. Ned gives Colton a coin for The Alhambra telling him to ask for Jenny. Colton refuses to leave his father behind so Ned grabs him, tells him he's not his real father, and throws him overboard just as the boat explodes - setting Colton on his journey.LevelsThe HuntSteamboat MassacreHonest TomThe Red Hand GangQuick KillerWhore CoachLaw and OrderEscape the JailAmbush the TrainDefend the HideoutTake Down HoodooSave SoapyHollister's FortAttack the FortBattle at the SteamboatAcross the BadlandsEscape the AmbushMagruder's MineSide MissionsBountiesPony ExpressDeputyFederal MarshallRanchIndian HunterPoker TournamentMultiplayerA port to the Playstation Portable was released on October 10th 2006 titled Gun Showdown. While as well as sporting several other additions to the console/pc versions, Showdown added an "up to six players" multiplayer feature. Of this there were three multiplayer modes including Texas Hold 'Em, Deathmatch, and Golden Cross. Maps and characters seen throughout the storyline are selectable in the multiplayer games.Xbox 360 Game InstallGUN requires 2.1GB of hard drive space for installation.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21191">Call of Juarez</game><game id="21431">Oddworld: Stranger's Wrath</game><game id="25249">Red Dead Redemption</game><game id="4114">Desperados 2: Cooper's Revenge</game><game id="1673">Outlaws</game><game id="25066">Call of Juarez: Bound in Blood</game><game id="27769">Lead and Gold: Gangs of the Wild West</game><game id="1803">Dead Man's Hand</game><game id="39682">Call of Juarez: Gunslinger</game><game id="37494">Assassin's Creed III</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2213160-box_gun.png</image></root>