<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8898</id><name>Genji: Dawn of the Samurai</name><description>Storyline/GameplayLoosely based on The Tale of the Heike, Genji follows the exploits of a young man named Minamoto Yoshitsune who becomes embroiled in a war between the Tamayori and Taira clans after the latter attack him in an attempt to aquire his Amahagane - a mysterious orb that grants its wielder incredible powers. After discovering that his late father was a revered general that was slain by Taira Kiyomori in the Heishi Rebellion, Yoshitune allies himself with the Tamayori and the powerful warrior monk Musashibo Benkei to seek revenge and thwart the Taira clan's attempts to gain all the Amahagane to rule over Japan with an unrivaled power. Genji is a third-person action game with RPG elements including character, weapon and armor upgrades, and the game allows you to alternate between either Yoshitune or Benkei on your quest with each having their own individual uses and skills. Similar to the Onimusha series, the game places a heavy emphasis on striking critical hits against the enemy and has an entire system in place to accommodate the concept called "Kamui", where pressing the L1 button will slow down time enough for you to time your counter attacks effectively.  Instead of being a complete retelling of The Tale of the Heike, Genji is set roughly in the third section of the book which corresponds with the Genpei War, which took place between 1180-1185 AD. The game spawned a PlayStation 3 exclusive sequel titled Genji: Days of the Blade which continues the story three years after Dawn of the Samurai ends. </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11334">Blood Will Tell: Tezuka Osamu's Dororo</game><game id="26431">Kengo: Legend of the 9</game><game id="10990">Genma Onimusha</game><game id="6959">God of War</game><game id="7649">Mortal Kombat: Shaolin Monks</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2117037-box_genjidots.png</image></root>