<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8911</id><name>Battle Raper II: The Game</name><description>Battle Raper 2 is a Japanese video game that is the second  game in the Battle Raper Series. The game is a 3D fighter where you are  able to knock the female opponent's clothing off through combat.  The  story line has no relations to the original Battle Raper.  In Battle  Raper 2 there is no raping in the whole game even though the title may  imply that there is.  In this Battle Raper you also have the option of  editing the clothing and weapons of characters.  In combat every  character has unlimited guard, a move that can not be blocked, and a  super move. PlotThe year is 20XX A.D. Yuuki goes to an island in search of the symbol  element of the power of god. The Eisen Kreuz guild, Arcana clan, and  Osei clan are also in search of this element. A shiki attacks Yuuki when  he gets on the island. And then he meet the guild and the clan. After  meeting them he travels with one of the three clans. He fights the rival  female characters against him. Yayoi gets attacked by Mukuro Gyoubu and  Yuuki defends her. At the end he finds out that she had the element of  the power of god.  CharactersThe main character that you play as is Yuuki Kukami. He is  armed with a sword and a gauntlet called the Soul Eater. He is followed  by a succubus named Eliza who turns into the sword. His element is Dark  Flame. Yayoi Mibu Yayoi Mibu is a dark-haired young woman who is a member of the  Eisen Kreuz guild. She is armed with a Holy dragon blade. She is a very  hot-tempered, prone to letting her sword do the talking. Despite her  personality, she is fond of cute things (like Eliza [or Moka, trans.  from the game], Yuuki's succubus familiar). Her element is wind. Elferris Kyougoku Elferris is a blond girl who is armed with a weapon called  'Zubra' which is similar to a rapier. Like, Yayoi, she is also a member  of the Eisen Kreuz guild, and is her superior. Elferris, in contrast to  Yayoi, is regal and dignified, and would resort to using her sword only  as a last resort. Her element is thunder. Yura Kamishiro Yura is a girl with orange hair in the Arcana clan which finds  artifacts. She uses two Eagle Claws and holds an artifact which allows  her to use the element of fire. Yura is more rambunctious and outgoing  than her bespectacled older sister. Sara Kamishiro Sara is Yura's older sister. She is a member of the Arcana clan  who specializes in computers. She is armed with a Dread Scythe. Her  element is vorpal. Sara is sent in with her sister, Yura, to search for  the Divine Element. Setsuna Yagami Setsuna is a ninja of the Osei clan. She is armed with the sun  and moon daggers. She uses the elements of Light and Darkness. In the  story-mode, from the conversations, it is clear that Yuuki knows  Setsuna, and that she has not forgotten him   Monsters Shiki Shiki The Shiki Shiki roam the island in hopes of preserving it. They spit acid and use hand to hand combat. Mukuro Gyoubu Mukuro Gyoubu uses a large claw in combat. He seeks the power of god and was corrupted by it.  GameplayStory mode In story mode you get to fight the monsters and other female characters.  You have one of the female characters accompany you while you travel  the island. In the end you get to have sex with the female character who  accompanies you Free mode Vs CPU is where you get to fight against a computer character.  Finish 10 rounds of battle with the same female character to unlock new  clothing items. Vs 2 player allows you to battle a friend. Extras Touch mode allows you to heal injured characters. Heal them in  the order of left to right to get items on the bar below to unlock  clothing items. Replay mode allows you to have sex with any female characters you  finished the storyline with. To change their positons you wait for the  characters to move themselves.   Extras Sexy Raper is an add-on to Battle Raper 2 which allows you to take  pictures of all the female characters in poses with different outfits  and backgrounds. You can also change their Facial expressions and eye  position.  CapRaper is similar to Sexy Raper, but adds on three characters from Biko  3 and Des Blood 4. The CapRaper addon can be downloaded from Illusion  Softs Battle Raper 2 website. The characters from CapRaper can be used  in the main Battle Raper game by starting the game with the executable,  that comes with the "Battle Raper 2 Plugin", and holding the CTRL key  while selecting the first, second or the fifth character. The first  character will then be Esk, the second Mayu and the fifth Bael. The  "Battle Reaper 2 Plugin" can also be downloaded from Illusion Softs  Battle Raper 2 website. </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="35450">Sexy Beach Zero</game><game id="34148">Touki Denshou Angel Eyes</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9778/2179429-br2_17850_500m.jpg</image></root>