<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>898</id><name>Democracy 2</name><description>OverviewDemocracy 2 is the sequel to Democracy released by Positech Games in 2007. In the game the player takes control of the government of a fictitious country with the aim to stay in office and win future elections.Gameplay:An Example of the Issues/Policy PanelEvery turn you, the leader of the highest government office in your country, earn and use political capital to change policies in your nation. These policies effect the welfare of your country, how your economy is doing, how many police are on the streets, pollution given off my your residents, tax rates, and more. Changes in these policies will effect different pockets of voters in negative and positive ways as well as effect the budget and debt of your country.Different sets of policies fit into seven different categories each with their own set of issues and policies. Each policy change can effect current problems in the nation and will effect a variety of issues in other sections.In Game Issues:Law and Order:Alcohol regulationsTobacco regulationsGun regulationsPolice fundingPolice arms/weaponsPrison fundingDeath PenaltyDrug regulationsGambling RegulationsRight to jury trialsHealth Services:Scientific grantsSchool Lunch SubsidiariesCollege LoansCreationism vs. EvolutionState Health ServicesFaith School SubsidiesState SchoolsTechnology CollegesMonetary:Corporate TaxTobacco TaxAlcohol TaxGasoline TaxSales TaxIncome TaxCar TaxEconomic:Technology GrantsTax SheltersLabor LawsMaternity LeaveCar Emissions LimitsAgricultural SubsidiesRecyclingPlastic Bag TaxPollution ControlsMilitary/Foreign Issues:Armed Forces FundingBorder ControlForeign AidCitizenship TestsNational Military ServiceImport TariffsTransit:Subsidizes School Buses FundingRoad Building FundingBus Lane FundingToll RoadsTrain SubsidiesFree Bus PassesWelfare:State HousingState Employee PensionsUnemployment BenefitChild BenefitChildcare ProvisionDisability BenefitsWelfare FraudWinter Fuel SubsidiesSystem RequirementsPCOS: Windows XPProcessor: Pentium 2.0Memory: 1 GB RAMGraphics: 64MB VRAMDirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 100 MB HD spaceSound: AnyAdditional: Internet connection required for installation and authenticationMacOS: Mac OS 10.4 or laterProcessor: Intel Core Duo 2.0 GHzMemory: 1 GB RAMGraphics: NVIDIA GeForce 9400MHard Drive: 100 MB HD spaceAdditional: Internet connection required for installation and authentication</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="8">Educational</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1553">President Forever</game><game id="39117">Planets Under Attack</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9872/270182-949.jpg</image></root>