<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8986</id><name>Larn</name><description>OverviewLarn is a Roguelike ASCII based RPG originally created by Noah Morgan for the UNIX operating system. During the course of it's development it was ported to other systems including PC, Amiga and Atari ST.  StoryYour daughter is ill and the doctor says she has Dianthoritis.  Only problem is the potion required is in a volcano filled with monsters and your the one who's got to go and get it.GameplayLarn is a typical RPG based heavily on dungeon crawling, randomly generated dungeons, randomly generated loot and stats.  As you progress down through the levels the monsters get harder and greater in number.  Weapons, armours, spells all become more powerful as well.Like most early roguelike ASCII based games it has no fancy graphics or sound, everything is in ASCII characters.  The character you control is an "@", the monsters are all characters such as "q" or "L" and items in the world are all letters or symbols such as * for gold.Throughout the game you'll find lots of weapons, armours, rings, gold coins, gems, spell books that can be use, sold or read.  Spell books are of great interest as there are many spells that can help you defeat the monsters.SpellsThere are many spells in LARN ranging from healing to invulnerability and walk through walls.  All spells in the game of LARN are picked up or brought in spell books, once you read the book you know the spell and the book disappears.  You can only cast spells you know and you can only cast a limited amount of spells.  The number of spells you can cast depends on how many books the player has read, what character level they are and if the player has been granted any bonuses from water fountains.PLY - PolymorphFLO - FloodCLD - ColdCRE - Create monsterSSP - Sonic spearPHA - IllusionENL - EnlightenmentLIT - Lightning boltSTP - Time stopCKL - Charm monsterCHM - Charm monsterCAN - Cancel monster special abilitiesPER - Makes a character spell permanent (awesome spell to get)SUM - Summon demon to helpGLO - InvulnerabilityMFI - Magic fire surrounds characterINV - InvisibilityDRL - Drain lifePRO - Protection field ( 2 to protection)STR - Strength ( 2 for limited period)DEX - Dexterity ( 2 for limited period)SLE - Send monster to sleepWEB - Entangle enemyMLE - Magic missileCBL - Cure BlindnessBAL - FireballSCA - Scare monsterHLD - Hold monsterFGR - Finger of GodTEL - Teleport awayWTW - Walk through wallsALT - Alters realityDRY - Dries up water in immediate vicinitySPH - Sphere of annihilation (another awesome spell)This isn't a complete list.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22309">Rogue</game><game id="18358">Hack</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1987/1094302-larn_800k_floppy_009.gif</image></root>