<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>922</id><name>Final Fight: Streetwise</name><description>OverviewFinal Fight: Streetwise is a 3D open-world beat 'em up developed by Capcom Studio 8 and published by Capcom for the Xbox and PlayStation 2 on February 28, 2006. It is a grittier spinoff of the Final Fight franchise.Set several years after the original Final Fight, players take the role of Kyle Travers, an underground "pit fighter" and the younger brother of Cody Travers (one of the protagonists from the first game). After discovering that Cody has been mutated while using a powerful strength-enhancing drug (called "glow"), Kyle must search out Metro City for the distributor of the drug (a man known as Father Bella) while fighting various punks along the way. Guy and Mike Haggar (the other two protagonists from the first game) make an appearance to help the player. Hugo Andore (also from the first game) and Cammy White (from the Street Fighter series) also make an appearance as "pit fight" opponents.Along with the single-player campaign, the game includes a traditional "arcade mode", in which up to two players fight through four linear series of battles (known as missions) in similar vein to the original Final Fight. The gameplay mechanics are simpler in this mode, including an arcade-style scoring and lives system, and a basic movelist. Kyle and Cody are the two characters unlocked from the start, with Guy and Haggar as unlockable characters. Three of the four missions also must be unlocked. An emulation of the arcade version of the original Final Fight is also featured as an unlockable extra.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15143">Knights of the Round</game><game id="21847">Watchmen: The End is Nigh</game><game id="5888">God Hand</game><game id="6722">Final Fight</game><game id="11814">The Bouncer</game><game id="26913">Watchmen: The End is Nigh Part 2</game><game id="11898">Beat Down: Fists of Vengeance</game><game id="35737">Altered Beast</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2080534-box_ffsw.png</image></root>