<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9228</id><name>Parasite Eve</name><description>OverviewThe worst foe lies within the selfParasite Eve is an action RPG title billed as the first "cinematic RPG" by its developer and publisher, Square. The game is a sequel to a novel by Hideaki Sena. With the success of Final Fantasy VII, Square had cemented itself as one of the leaders in videogame cinematics. Square was attempting to bring it's own mix of high quality CGI, quirky Japanese gameplay and heavy plot to a game akin to the Resident Evil series. The music was also notable, and was of the same high quality of other Square games of the era. The tagline was, "The worst foe lies within the self."Though a bit dated now, the cutscenes were gorgeous for the time.Many overtones present in survival-horror titles are present here, mainly consisting of similar control schemes, limited survival-based item management, and the dispatching of menacing, horrifying enemies. The included battle system is more akin to other Square franchises, such as fifth generation Final Fantasy games. However, Parasite Eve departed from this system by allowing the player to still move, but employed an ATB gauge to have the action remain turn-based.The game garnered significant praise and acclaim upon release, garnering support for a Western-developed sequel that was released in North America in 2000. An indirect sequel is planned for the DoCoMo mobile phone platform as well as the PSP titled " The 3rd Birthday".StoryPearce and Brea sense something familiarParasite Eve is the story of the destruction of New York by a mitochondrial menace known as Eve, and the military's struggle to defeat it.Set in New York just prior to and just after Christmas 1997, the story follows NYPD officer and protagonist Aya Brea. She finds herself mysteriously drawn to an opera house, and to the lead actress Melissa Pearce. As Pearce is performing, their eyes meet in a deadlock - and suddenly everyone in the opera house begins to burst into flames. Brea, who is unaffected, finds herself the lone agent able to investigate the scene.Brea tunnels through the opera house, fighting rats who were horribly mutated by the phenomenon. Searching through the actor's quarters, she finds that Pearce was taking massive amounts of an unknown drug to cement her role as lead actress. Other actresses vying for Pearce's part were mysteriously killed in a fire.Aya confronts Eve at the Oprah HouseIn a showdown between the two, Brea confronts Pearce in the opera house as she is playing the piano. Pearce's body mutates horribly, as her skin changes in pallor and her hands lengthen into talons. Floating above the ground, Pearce proclaims herself "Eve." Brea is able to defeat her with the powers she has mysteriously developed. Before escaping, Eve laughs and warns Aya that her mitochondria have not yet become fully awake.The plot continues to center around the mystery of "Eve" and how everything relates to Aya and her supposed underdeveloped mitochondria. Aya and her NYPD partner Daniel Dollis, an African American and twenty-year veteran of the force investigate the mystery by visiting Dr. Klamp, the leading name behind mitochondrial research.Eve destroys a fighter jet after the evacuation of New YorkSoon, the incident with Eve in the opera house turns into an onslaught against New York. In a murderous incident in Central Park, Eve slaughters thousands of people - absorbing them into a blob of mitochondrial biomass. The remaining inhabitants of New York are evacuated, leaving the city strangely barren, and the military is called in to fight the creature.What is the connection between Brea and Pearce? What does it have to do with Aya's sister who was hospitalized with an illness when they were children? Why does Aya have these powers, and why is she immune the mitochondrial insurgence she sees all around her?GameplayA central mechanic is dodging enemy attacksThe game allows the player to traverse freely through designated areas throughout Manhattan. Once a player encounters a battle, enemies appear inside a set perimeter that restricts movement to that portion of the screen. A departure from previous Square RPG titles, the game has no transition to the battle mode and requires players to dispose of (or flee from) enemies in natural spaces.The Active Time Bar (ATB) serves as the basis for the battle system--something of a replacement for the turn-based systems of previous RPG titles. This bar allows the player to move around freely in the designated area (the screen prior to the battle engagement) while they await the bar to be filled and attacks to be made.A wire-frame polygon indicates the range of your weaponAttacks are the result of either direct fire of firearms or by the use of Parasite Enegy (PE), which utilizes Aya's special mitochondrial sensitivity and allows her to control the output of her focused attacks. The Parasite Energy has defensive measures as well, allowing the player to use standard RPG conventions in unfamiliar ways.Parasite Energy allows players to use their learned skills and traits for powerful attacks. In conjuction with customized weapons, foes are easily dispatched of when in the right hands. Also, weapons and armor can be customized with tools, as well as super tools, in order to alter the attributes of each. To upgrade, players are required to sacrifice attributes on other weapons and armors to be transferred to the desired item. This adds a depth of unpredictability to the progression of your inventory, making replayability a rewarding experience all its own.Pearce after her mutation into EveParasite Eve was released in a time period just after the North American release of the Dual Shock controller, and was one of the first games to support it. Without the Dual Shock, Parasite Eve utilized the heavily-critizized "tank" control scheme of Resident Evil. Brea's movements were irritatingly slow unless players held down the circle button. Many players were pleased that it offered analog support, making the control of Brea much easier, though it frustratingly rendered the D-pad inoperative.SoundtrackThe parasite eve original soundtrackDisc 1 (52:34)1. "Primal Eyes" - 2:212. "Waiting for Something Awakens" - 1:123. "Overture [from opera "La mia verita"]" - 2:164. "Se il mio amore sta vincino [Vocalize]" - 2:065. "Memory I" - 0:356. "Gloom and Doom" - 2:417. "Theme of Mitochondria" - 1:398. "Sotto Voice" - 2:079. "Arise within You" - 2:0510. "Main Theme [Piano Solo Version]" - 2:0711. "The Surface of the Water" - 2:0212. "Memorize of "Aya and Eve" - 1:3713. "Out of Phase" - 4:0214. "Urban Noise" - 1:5215. "Mystery Notes" - 1:0116. "Influence of Deep" - 3:0317. "Phrase of Aya" - 1:1418. "Phrase of Mitochondria" - 0:4219. "Theme of Aya" - 1:3420. "Under the Progress" - 3:0721. "Plosive Attack" - 2:1922. "Missing Perspective" - 3:4023. "Memory II" - 1:0924. "Force Trail" - 1:4225. "Phrase of Eve" - 3:0726. "Memory III" - 1:14Disc 2 (54:40)1. "Matrix" - 2:442. "The Omission of the World" - 2:323. "Wheel of Fortune" - 3:314. "Kyrie" - 2:435. "Across the View" - 1:516. "Femmes Fatales" - 4:427. "A Piece of Remain" - 1:208. "Musica Mundana" - 2:139. "U.B." - 4:5210. "Escape from U.B." - 0:5411. "Main Theme" - 1:4912. "Theme of Aya [Reprise]" - 1:1413. "I Hear a Voice Asking Me to Awaken" - 1:5414. "Somnia Memorias" - 5:5815. "Consensus" - 1:5616. "Someone calls me... Someone looks for me..." - 1:4617. "Main Theme [Orchestral Version]" - 7:5318. "Influence of Deep -CM Version-" - 2:4319. "Se il mio amore sta vincino -CM Version-" - 2:05Parasite Eve RemixesDisc - (63:25)"A.Y.A. (Theme of AYA Primary Mix)" - 5:10"Arise within You (remixedbyTomo)" - 7:12"Plosive Attack (CULTIVATE MIX)" - 8:34"Missing Perspective (Dan K's Late Night Session)" - 6:42"Influence of Deep (DJ Hiraguri's Operattack)" - 8:12"Under the Progress (SOMETHING WONDERFUL remix)" - 6:35"Primal Eyes (WE ARE ALL PARASITES/CHARLIE HORSE MIX)" - 4:41"Across the Memories (DB Remix)" - 4:56"Urban Noise (112-80MIX)" - 5:37"Somnia Memorias (Platinum Edition)" - 5:56EX GameOnce you have beaten the game for the first time a mode called "EX game" unlocks. In this mode you have access to items located in storage, the weapon and armor you had engraved at the end of the first game as well as your bonus points, however your level does not carry over and enemies will also be tougher. The biggest difference in this mode is the Chrysler Building a new and more difficult dungeon. In it is 77 floors with each one (except boss floors and floors 70-77) being completely random. Every 10th floor contains a boss fight and you can only save after you have defeated a boss. The most powerful weapons and armor are located in this dungeon as well as trading cards which allow you to customize weapons and get you tool kits and super tool kits. Once you reach the final floor you will be able to fight the true final boss of the game and unlock the true ending.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11497">Final Fantasy XII</game><game id="10896">Vagrant Story</game><game id="5495">Persona 2: Eternal Punishment</game><game id="20439">Shin Megami Tensei: Devil Summoner - Raidou Kuzunoha vs. the Soulless Army</game><game id="17000">Fear Effect 2: Retro Helix</game><game id="23138">Planet Laika</game><game id="718">Galerians: Ash</game><game id="11126">Galerians</game><game id="5223">Koudelka</game><game id="25787">Resonance of Fate</game><game id="7360">Fear Effect</game><game id="8813">OverBlood 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2193298-box_peve.png</image></root>