<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9243</id><name>Dave Mirra Freestyle BMX</name><description>OverviewDave Mirra Freestyle BMX is a "spin-off" the Tony Hawk Pro-Skater Series. Released in 2000, this game takes place on bikes instead of skateboards, and various different locations around the world with huge ramps and dirt tracks. The game was released for the Playstation, Dreamcast, Game Boy Color, and PC. The story mode took players through various levels where completing objective style tricks and stunts to unlock gear for their biker. Gear was different for each bike to build replayability.GameplayThe game play consisted of a biker riding around various areas pulling off different tricks. The trick system involved pulling off one base trick, and then adapting other modifier tricks into that one base trick. It was easy to do double backflip tailwhips, creating a sense of arcade while losing a lot of its realism. Also involved in the game is the rag doll physics. When a biker wrecks, he is thrown about furiosuly adding a funny factor into the wreck sequence. Four modes were involved in the first game and they are Proquest, Free Ride, Session, and 2-player. Each mode had different events and certain tasks.Unlockable CharactersThe Slim Jim GuySoundtrack59 Times the Pain - Got It All in SightCypress Hill - DustDeftones - Be Quiet and Drive (Far Away)Dropkick Murphys - Never AlonePennywise - GreedPrimer 55 - LooseRancid - Maxwell MurderSocial Distortion - Don't Drag Me DownSublime - What I GotSwingin' Utters - Stupid LullabiesVision - Don't Sound the Alarm</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3238">Dave Mirra Freestyle BMX 3</game><game id="5474">BMX XXX</game><game id="21793">Downhill Domination</game><game id="25743">Sunny Garcia Surfing</game><game id="26415">Gravity Games Bike: Street Vert Dirt</game><game id="27632">MTV Sports: T.J. Lavin's Ultimate BMX</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2133344-box_dmfsbmx.png</image></root>