<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9279</id><name>Kelly Slater's Pro Surfer</name><description>OverviewDeveloped by Treyarch and published by Activision as part of their O2 range of extreme sports games, Kelly Slater's Pro Surfer is a spinRiding the wavesoff the Tony Hawk franchise that features the likenesses of popular pro surf boarders such as Kalani Robb, Rob Machado, Bruce Irons, Donovan Frankenreiter and many more.The game puts the player in the shoes of a group of 8 surfers in search of "the perfect wave". On your journey you'll stop at over 15 locations around the globe from the slow, lazy waves of Sebastion, to the fast, aggressive surfing of Pipeline.GameplayThe gameplay of Kelly Slater's Pro Surfing sticks relatively close to that of the Tony Hawk series. You arrive at one of the over 15 locations and are given a handful of goals you must complete under a time limit in order to progress. These goals can range from jumping over a pier and spraying windsurfers to collecting objects placed around a level.The game also features dozens of moves and special moves such as hang 10s, cross steps and cutbacks. These moves can be used in a sequence to create "combos" similar to that of the Tony Hawk games.Surf BoardersThe game features 8 professional surf boarders that the player can choose from. Each Character has their own unique stats comparable to their real life talents. All surf boarders are unlocked from the start of the game, however the characters "personality costume" is unlockable as you play further on in the game.Professional Surf Boarders:Kalani RobbRob MachadoKelly SlaterBruce IronsDonovan FrankenreiterNathan FletcherTom CurrenTom CarrolLisa AndersonSoundtrackBen Harper - FadedJack Johnson - Middle manPearl Jam - WMAPerry Farrell - Nua NuaChristopher Goze - SiroccoFunky Lowlives - NotabossaGreyboy - Master the ArtJeremy Kay - Back to YouMo' Horizons - Fota VidaQuantum Dub Force - Quantum ZoneRae and Christian - Ready to RollSatan's Pilgrims - Step it upShur i Kan - AdvanceSi Se - Stepping outSmith an Mighty - No JusticeSoul Hooligan - Pyschedelic SoulSpace Cossacks - Solaris StompSun Child - Vagabond ParadeThird World - 1865Thunderball - Heat of the HustlerThunderball - Vai VaiTruby Trio - Alergre</description><genres><genre id="47">Surfing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16364">Surfing H3O</game><game id="12077">Tony Hawk's Project 8</game><game id="5688">Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3</game><game id="12691">Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 2x</game><game id="17149">SSX 3</game><game id="18782">SSX Tricky</game><game id="12685">Tony Hawk's American Sk8land</game><game id="12418">SSX on Tour</game><game id="7222">Tony Hawk's American Wasteland</game><game id="1932">SSX</game><game id="17969">SSX Blur</game><game id="3631">Tony Hawk's Downhill Jam</game><game id="1492">Tony Hawk's Underground 2</game><game id="22469">Dave Mirra BMX Challenge</game><game id="2751">TransWorld SURF</game><game id="25647">Transworld Surf: Next Wave</game><game id="25743">Sunny Garcia Surfing</game><game id="20661">Skate 2</game><game id="14896">Tony  Hawk's Underground</game><game id="2570">Aggressive Inline</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3498/611822-kelly_slater_27s_pro_surfer_coverart.png</image></root>