<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>934</id><name>MechWarrior 4: Mercenaries</name><description>OverviewDeveloped by Cyberlore Studios and published by Microsoft, Mechwarrior 4: Mercenaries is a standalone expansion to Mechwarrior 4: Vengeance. The game mirrors Mechwarrior 2: Mercenaries with the ability to manage a mercenary company.CampaignIn MechWarrior 4: Mercenaries, you lead lances of 'Mechs into combat for private and House contracts for C-bills. Players assume the role of "Spectre" a fledgling mercenary 'Mech pilot, as he attempts to start up his own mercenary company and achieve riches and fame. The player must choose one of four established mercenary units as a sponsor.Wolf Dragoons: One of the most famous mercenary companies, companies sponsored by the Dragoons start with Clan technology and have greater purchasing power of Clan tech. However they start with the least amount of money and Clan tech is very expensive.Kell Hounds: Another famous mercenary company and a potential employer and ally in future missions, companies sponsored by the Kell Hounds have early access to Clan tech but do not start with it like the Dragoons do.Northwind Highlanders: A mercenary group with a Scottish ancestry, companies sponsored by the Highlanders start with more money and earn 20% more C-bills each mission.Gray Death Legion: A mercenary unit in the process of rebuilding, companies sponsored by the Legion gain early access to Lostech weapons and have greater purchasing power of these weaponsThe gameplay is based on using the money you earn by completing contracts to purchase new 'Mechs and weapons for you and your lancemates. Your weekly costs to repair 'Mechs and drop into missions will increase based on the weight and number of your 'Mechs, but more advanced missions require heavier equipment, so striking a balance is very important in the campaign. The Free Market is introduced, allowing players to buy or sell unwanted 'Mechs and weapons. Players can now command a secondary lance, allowing up to eight 'Mechs to participate in a mission. Furthermore there is Solaris VII, a 'Mech fighting sport planet that the player can participate in to earn more C-Bills and gain points towards Steiner or Davion factions.There is a point system in this game's story similar to moral choice systems in other games. When you take a mission you will earn points toward either Steiner or Davion loyalty in the FedCom civil war. After a certain point it will be impossible to keep taking missions from both sides of the war and your unit will be forced to choose an allegiance to one side or the other.The ending of the game's campaign varies depending on which side of the civil war you have decided to support, as your help will ultimately sway the outcome of this conflict. Players who chose to side with Steiner have access to two endings, making a total three possible endings. Regardless of which ending the player takes, the story ends with an ominous warning about the Word of Blake invasion. To date, there has been no continuation of this story in the form of another MechWarrior game, though various novels in the BattleTech universe have explored story elements of the years after the events in the game.Free ReleaseOn the 25th Anniversary of BattleTech, Mechwarrior 4: Mercenaries became free to play via the MekTek website. MekTek also provides the servers for multiplayer and also released the MekTek MechPak 3.1, a large mod adding an additional Mechs, Power Armors, weapons and more. MechPak 3.1 is required to play on MekTek servers.New 'MechsMercenaries contains all the 'Mechs from Vengeance and Black Knight as well as 10 new 'Mechs for a combined total of 36 'Mechs. Mercenaries also contains data from the Clan and Inner Sphere 'Mech Paks although the 'Mechs are unplayable if the Mech Paks are not installed. Furthermore, the 'Mechs from the Clan and Inner Sphere 'Mech Paks cannot be salvaged or bought in the campaign and can only be played in Instant Action and Multiplayer. Including the 'Mechs from the 'Mech Paks, Mercenaries contains a total of 44 playable 'Mechs.LightNameInformationFireflyManufacturer:	Coventry/Earthwerks CombineIntroduced: 2790Model: FFL-4BClass:	LightCost: 2,342,600 C-billsMass:	30 tonsChassis:	Earthwerks FireflyArmor:	StarSlab/1Engine:	GM 150Communications System: Datacom 18Speed:	86.4 km/hJump Jets:	Lexington LiftersArmament: 3xMedium Lasers, 1xLRM-5, 1xAnti-Missile SystemOwensManufacturer:	Luthien Armor Works, Irian BattleMechs UnlimitedModel: OW-1Class:	LightCost: 7,882,875 C-billsMass:	35 tonsChassis:	Alshain Class 48 OmniArmor:	StarshieldEngine:	VOX 280 XLSpeed:	129.6 km/hJump Jets:	NoneArmament: 1 x TAG, 1 x C3 Slave Unit, 1 x Active Probe, 1 x Medium Laser, 2 x Small Lasers, 2 x LRM-5sPumaManufacturer:	Sheridan LM-TA 8-10, W-7 Facilities, Wolf Clan Site 3Introduced: 3010Model: PrimeClass:	LightCost: 7,021,688 C-bills[2]Mass:	35 tonsChassis:	Hooded Endo-Lite Endo SteelArmor:	Star Lite Ferro-FibrousEngine:	Great Father 210 XLSpeed:	97.2 km/hJump Jets:	NoneArmament: 1xFlamer, 2xER PPCsMediumNameInformationHellhoundManufacturer:	Irece Alpha, othersIntroduced: 2826Model: HellhoundClass:	MediumCost: 5,320,500 C-billsMass:	50 tonsChassis:	Puma Type Medium Endo SteelArmor:	Alpha Plate Special Ferro-FibrousEngine:	300 StandardSpeed:	96 km/hJump Jets:	BMP Mk. XXIArmament: 1x Large Pulse Laser, 2x ER Medium Lasers, 2x Streak SRM-2sAssaultNameInformationVictorManufacturer:	HildCo Interplanetary, Independence Weaponry, Tao 'Mechworks, General MotorsIntroduced: 2510Model: VTR-9BClass:	AssaultCost: 8,044,320 C-billsMass:	80 tonsChassis:	HildCo Type VArmor:	Durallex HeavyEngine:	Pitban 320Speed:	64.8 km/hJump Jets:	HildCo Model 12Armament: 1xAutocannon/20, 2xMedium Lasers, 1xSRM-4LongbowManufacturer:	StarCorps IndustriesModel: LGB-7QClass:	AssaultCost: 7,408,325 C-billsMass:	85 tonsChassis:	StarCorp 100Armor:	StarSlab/9.5 Mk IIEngine:	Strand 255Speed:	54.0 km/hJump Jets:	NoneArmament: 2xLRM-20s, 2xLRM-5s, 2xMedium LasersTemplarManufacturer:	Kallon IndustriesModel: TLR1-OClass:	AssaultCost: 25,338,448 C-billsMass:	85 tonsChassis:	Kallon Type XIX Endo SteelArmor:	Starshield A with CASEEngine:	KalTek 340 XLSpeed:	64.8 km/hJump Jets:	NoneArmament: 1xGauss Rifle, 1xLarge Pulse Laser, 1xMedium Pulse Laser, 1xStreak SRM-4, 2xER Medium LasersHauptmannManufacturer:	Coventry Metal WorksIntroduced: 3060Model: HA1-OClass:	AssaultCost: 12,938,860 C-billsMass:	95 tonsChassis:	StandardArmor:	StandardEngine:	285 FusionSpeed:	54.0 km/hJump Jets:	NoneArmament: 2 x ER Large Lasers, 2 x Medium Pulse Lasers, 1 x ER Small Laser, 1 x LB-X Autocannon/20, 2 x Streak SRM-2sGladiatorManufacturer:	Alshain BattleWorxIntroduced: 3001Model: PrimeClass:	AssaultCost: 35,713,073 C-billsMass:	95 tonsChassis:	Clan Series Assault SXEArmor:	Arcadia Compound Delta VII Ferro-FibrousEngine:	Heavy Force 380 XLCommunications System: Dash-2 OptimaSpeed: 64.8 km/h (86.4 km/h with MASC)Jump Jets:	Pryzhok WM10Armament: 1xGauss Rifle, 2xER Large Lasers, 2xMachine GunsFafnirManufacturer:	Defiance Industries of Hesperus IIIntroduced: 3063Model: FNR-5Class:	AssaultCost: 11,470,000 C-billsMass:	100 tonsChassis:	Foundation Type 220 Endo SteelArmor:	Durallex Speical Heavy V2 with CASEEngine:	Vlar 300Communications System: Angst Discom /w Guardian ECMSpeed:	54 km/hJump Jets:	NoneArmament: 1xMedium Pulse Laser, 2xER Medium Lasers, 2xHeavy Gauss Rifles</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12849">Heavy Gear</game><game id="19719">Chromehounds</game><game id="13461">Ultrabots</game><game id="9122">Front Mission Online</game><game id="13569">Heavy Gear II</game><game id="25296">Lore: Aftermath</game><game id="25684">Murakumo: Renegade Mech Pursuit</game><game id="26008">Front Mission Evolved</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/28314/1530023-mechwarriormercenariescover.jpg</image></root>