<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9358</id><name>Feet of Fury</name><description>OverviewFeet of Fury is a rhythm game, heavily inspired by Dance Dance Revolution. The game features 22 songs from 3 artists, with 13 unlocked from the start. The game features the ability for players to import songs from their PCs via swapping CDs. Feet of Fury takes advantage of the security holes of the system to bypass the licensing required to officially publish a game for the system. It was developed using the KallistiOS Project development tools. The game is compatible with dance pads for the Dreamcast and PlayStation (through a converter), and can also be played using the regular game pad or the Dreamcast keyboard peripheral.Game ModesThe game offers several different modes of play, all available for play for either one or two players.Feet of Fury - The game contains a progression in the form of an anime-inspired story. This mode is where players can unlock additional songs and characters to play as.Typing of Fury - This mode allows players to use the keyboard peripheral for the Dreamcast to type in time with the music.Item Battle - This mode uses the regular dancing game as a base, and adds in items which change up the gameplay. This mode is focused on multiplayer, with most items being used to harm opponents in various ways, such as adding random arrows to their screen, or making their arrows move wildly about the screen.Practice - This mode allows players to play through songs without any penalties.Swap CDsFeet of Fury allows players to import songs from the PC based DDR clone Dancing with Intensity. The process for creating CDs compatible with the game is relatively difficult, which limits the usefulness of the feature, but tutorials exist on the game's forum. Creating images for the game to recognize requires specific instructions, and differences in the programming of Feet of Fury and Dancing with Intensity make it difficult for imported song timing to match that of the original.ISO files of player-created CDs exist as well, easing the process considerably for those simply interested in playing more music. The game's creators stress that only legally reproducible music be used in swap CDs.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/16238/506398-fof_songs.jpg</image></root>