<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9369</id><name>Namco x Capcom</name><description>OverviewNamco x Capcom is a strategy RPG featuring dozens of characters from games created by Namco and Capcom. The game was developed by Monolith Soft and publish by Namco for the PlayStation 2 on May 26, 2005.GameplayNamco × Capcom (pronounced "Namco Cross Capcom") plays like a typical turn-based strategy game allowing you to move units and issuing attacks when it's your turn. However when you issue the attack instead of choosing the move to use and watching the battle take place, you issue the attack by inputting commands. The commands are inputted by following the button patterns at the lower part of the screen. If you know what these moves do, then you are able to pull of combos. Generally, longer combos will net you bonuses such as the ability to use more moves or stronger attacks in battle. When the super gauge is full, you are able to pull of super attacks. Getting this bar up requires attacking or defending against the enemy, much like in 2D fighting games. Certain characters can pull of special tag team attacks depending on who that character was partnered with, and special attacks once the special gauge is filled up. For example, Ryu and Ken will use a double attack because they from the same series. Also Dino Crisis, Resident Evil, and Darkstalkers characters will use a special attack together due to being in Capcom franchises. These attacks, however, can only be done once in a great while, so players should be using them appropriately.When defending against enemy, attack, you must input commands onscreen to avoid further damage from the enemy, much like Paper Mario does in its battle systems.Featured SeriesA list showing the characters which feature in the game from the different franchises made by Namco and Capcom. Three characters have been created for the sake of this game. They would be Xiaomu, Reiji and Saya.Dino Crisis seriesRegina (Dino Crisis)Velociraptors (NPC)Wonder MomoMomoTekken seriesJin Kazama (Tekken 4 ver.)Heihachi Mishima (Tekken)King (Tekken 4 ver.)Armour King (Tekken)Devil Kazuya (NPC)Mokujin (NPC)Jack (NPC)P-Jack (NPC)Ghosts 'n Goblin seriesArthurAstaroth (NPC)Red Aremer (NPC)BravomanBravomanResident Evil seriesBruce (Resident Evil Dead Aim)Street Fighter seriesRyu (Street Fighter)Ken Masters (Street Fighter)Chun Li (Street Fighter II)Karin and Sakura (Street Fighter Alpha 3)Cammy (Street Fighter Alpha 3)Rose (Street Fighter Alpha 3)Juni and Juli (NPC)M. Bison (NPC)Akuma (NPC)Captain CommandoCaptain CommandoGinzu the NinjaBaby HeadMack the KnifeGenpei Toma DenSoul Edge/Soulcalibur seriesMitsurugi HeishiroTakiCharade (NPC)Darkstalkers seriesMorrigan AenslandDimitriLei-LeiLilithFeliciaLord Raptor (NPC)Q-Bee (NPC)The Tower of DruagaGilDruaga (NPC)Street Fighter Alpha seriesStrider seriesStrider HiryuStrider HienKlonoa seriesKlonoa and GantzFinal Fight seriesMike HaggarGuyRival Schools seriesBurning ForceHiromi TengenjiTales seriesStanRuteeMega Man Legends seriesMega Man VolnutRollTron BonneMega Man Juno (NPC)Xenosaga seriesM.O.M.O. and ShionKOS-MOSThe Legend of ValkyrieYokai DouchuukiDig DugTaizo HoriForgotten WorldsBaraduke</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="22820">Red Earth</game><game id="12125">Capcom Fighting Evolution</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="9542">Night Warriors: Darkstalkers' Revenge</game><game id="23621">Super Robot Taisen OG Saga: Endless Frontier</game><game id="2259">Segagaga</game><game id="20728">Tatsunoko vs. Capcom: Ultimate All Stars</game><game id="28913">Mugen no Frontier EXCEED: Super Robot Wars OG Saga</game><game id="29271">Negima!?: Chou Mahora Taisen Kattoiin, Keiyaku Shikkou Dechai masuu</game><game id="32161">Street Fighter X Tekken</game><game id="32162">Tekken X Street Fighter</game><game id="37959">Project X Zone</game><game id="35910">Dramatic Dungeon: Sakura Taisen - Kimi Arugatame</game><game id="41346">Shin Megami Tensei X Fire Emblem</game><game id="42463">Namco Super Wars</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2179490-box_nxc.png</image></root>