<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>941</id><name>Project Gotham Racing</name><description>OverviewProject Gotham Racing is the first installment in the incredibly successful arcade racing franchise for the Xbox.  Developed by     Bizarre Creations and published by Microsoft Game Studios, this Xbox launch title became one of the best selling games for the console selling over 2 million units worldwide and one of the most recognizable franchise for Microsoft.  This game is the spiritual successor to the Dreamcast's Metropolis Street Racer. The game's most distinct feature is the Kudos system, whereby players earn points for driving with style and precision. Kudos are awarded for performing feats such as powersliding, 360s, navigating areas without damage, etc. The game also features a    Tony Hawk-esque combo system whereby performing a series of stunts in quick succession allows the player to multiply the number of kudos earned. This encourages both speed and accuracy in that driving quickly allows the player to string together large combo points, but crashing causes the player to lose a significant number of points in his current combo.    The game sits between pure arcade and simulation style driving in terms of handling and physics. The game was notable in its time in that although it featured around thirty cars, fewer than in many other racing game, it was able to secure the coveted Ferrari and Porche licenses. The game also featured a damage model for its licensed vehicles, which didn't affect handling but could affect the cars aesthetically during a race.    The game features over 200 tracks set in four cities: San Francisco, New York City, London, and Tokyo.  The game also include nighttime racing and a weather system, which can affect both visibility and handling.  Game ModesThe game features a variety of both single player and multiplayer modes.  Quick Race is most similar to other racing games in that finishing in the top three positions allows the player to advance to the next level.  Arcade Race involves the player driving through an obstacle course of cones in meet a quota of Kudos.  Time Attack allows the player to race in any unlocked track to achieve better and better times.  An unlockable Medal Pursuit mode enables the player to unlock additional vehicle colors by completing certain challenges.   Kudos Challenge is the heart of the game.  This mode features thirteen levels of increasing difficulty, each level featuring a number of challenges.  Challenges include one-on-one racing events, time trials, lap challenges, and more.  Each challenge featured adjustable objectives; for example, in a street race, a player could attempt a minimum of third place, but could choose to go for first in order to increase the number of Kudos earned after the race.  These Kudos are combined with the points earned over the course of the race to determine the player's overall score and advancement.  At later difficulty levels the player must both complete more difficult objectives and simultaneously earn style points during a challenge in order to meet the quota for advancement.  The game also features a split-screen multiplayer mode for up to four players.  Players can compete either for the best position or greatest number of Kudos during a race.  Multiplayer options include track setting, time of day, and ambient weather.   Car List MINI Cooper S Toyota MR2 Spyder Mercedes-Benz SLK 320 Volkswagen New Beetle RSi Audi TT Roadster Audi TT Coupe BMW Z3 Roadster 3.0i Mazda RX-8 Chevrolet Camaro SS Porsche Boxster S Opel Speedster Ford Focus Cosworth Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution VII Subaru Impreza WRX Panoz Esperante Nissan Skyline GTR Lotus Exige Ferrari F355 Spider Ferrari 355 F1 Aston Martin V12 Vanquish Chevrolet Corvette Z06 Delfino Feroce Ferrari 360 Spider Ferrari 360 Modena TVR Tuscan Dodge Viper RT-10 Porsche 911 GT2 Porsche Carrera GT Ferrari F50  Cities  DistrictsLondonSt James' Park  Trafalgar  Westminster New York City  Times Square  Central Park  Wall Street San Francisco  Financial District  Fisherman's Wharf  Pacific Heights Tokyo  Asakusa  Shibuya  Shinjuku</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11055">NASCAR 08</game><game id="20038">NASCAR: Dirt to Daytona</game><game id="2416">Gran Turismo</game><game id="8100">Gran Turismo 2</game><game id="453">Need for Speed: High Stakes</game><game id="18021">Need for Speed: Carbon - Own the City</game><game id="367">Need for Speed II</game><game id="5977">Need for Speed III: Hot Pursuit</game><game id="12976">Need for Speed: Most Wanted</game><game id="18095">Need for Speed: ProStreet</game><game id="8844">Need for Speed: Carbon</game><game id="12254">Need for Speed Underground</game><game id="9651">Need for Speed Underground 2</game><game id="8831">Need for Speed: Porsche Unleashed</game><game id="1591">Need for Speed Underground: Rivals</game><game id="12395">Need for Speed: Hot Pursuit 2</game><game id="12950">Gran Turismo 3 A-Spec</game><game id="17784">Gran Turismo 4</game><game id="20597">Gran Turismo 5 Prologue</game><game id="21297">Gran Turismo HD</game><game id="13895">Gran Turismo 4: Prologue</game><game id="7313">Gran Turismo Concept: 2002 Tokyo-Geneva</game><game id="21390">Gran Turismo Concept: 2002 Tokyo-Seoul</game><game id="7482">Gran Turismo Concept: 2001 Tokyo</game><game id="17599">Forza Motorsport</game><game id="5881">Forza Motorsport 2</game><game id="17872">TOCA Race Driver 3 Challenge</game><game id="13734">TOCA Race Driver 3</game><game id="5869">TOCA Touring Car Championship</game><game id="531">TOCA Race Driver 2</game><game id="8437">TOCA 2: Touring Car Challenge</game><game id="6499">RalliSport Challenge 2</game><game id="3027">Metropolis Street Racer</game><game id="589">R:Racing Evolution</game><game id="20729">GRID</game><game id="7019">Ridge Racer V</game><game id="16276">Ford Bold Moves Street Racing</game><game id="20919">Ford Racing: Off Road</game><game id="7431">Ford Racing</game><game id="7777">Juiced</game><game id="10124">Midnight Club: Street Racing</game><game id="284">NASCAR 2005: Chase for the Cup</game><game id="22693">RACE Pro</game><game id="1712">Apex</game><game id="16882">Running Wild</game><game id="24866">OutRun Online Arcade</game><game id="24513">DiRT 2</game><game id="2453">R4 Ridge Racer Type 4</game><game id="25961">Blur</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2213165-box_pgr.png</image></root>