<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9413</id><name>Cossacks: European Wars</name><description>OverviewCossacks: European Wars is an Isometric RTS game developed by GCS Game World. The games is centered on tried and true RTS concepts such as base building, resource gathering and the creation of often massive armies. The game is notable for it's ability to allow the player to generate thousands of units, having a population cap that is only a measure of the amount of resources the player can gather. The game takes place roughly between the seventeenth and eighteenth century. There are seventeen playable factions. The object of the game is to defeat the other nations, or complete certain objectives. There are 3 game types:Campaign, in which the player plays through several missions with one nation.Single mission, in which the player must complete an objective.Random map, in which the player can choose a random or defined map and battle other nations.The game features several recourses which include:Gold,Iron,Coal,Food,Wood and Stone. The recourses are used to build various buildings,create armies and upgrade them.NationsThere are seventeen nations a player can choose from, these include:RussiaAustriaAlgeriaDenmarkEnglandFranceNetherlandsPiedmontPolandPortugalPrussiaSaxonySpainSwedenTurkeyUkraineVeniceEach nation has unique units and advantages as well as disadvantages.For example Russians have the most effective spearmen and powerful cavalry, where as Piedmont has the best healers, Turkey and Algeria can not advance to the 18th century but make up for it with their cheap and fast to produce infantry.UnitsEach nation has unique units (except Portugal, though they have a shipyard that acts similarly to a defensive tower) the units vary in effectiveness against other units and buildings as well as speed,hitpoints and power.For example cavalry is used to raid and harass enemies, by capturing unguarded mines and artillery, they are also very effective against infantry.Spearmen can easily destroy enemy cavalry and ranged units are powerful though very weak at close combat, some ranged infantry in fact can't even engage enemies at close combat.By creating any 30-36 infantry units its possible to create a squad using a drummer and an officer, a squad has 3 formations and improved performance.UnitsSupport UnitsPeasantPriestMontgolfierInfantryPikemanSpearmanOttoman Pikeman RoundshierMercenaryLight infantryMercenaryMusiciansOfficerArcherMercenary MusketeerStreletsPandurHighlanderChasseurJanissary SerdiukGrenadier MercenaryCavalryMamelukeSpakhLight RiderHussar Don CossackUkrainian CossackMercenary Heavy RiderWinged HussarCuirassierVityazCavalry GuardsTatarsDragoonsMercenaryKing's MusketeerArtilleryCannonHowitzerMortarMulti-barrelled cannonFleetBoatFerryGalleyYachtFrigateBattleshipXebecSystem RequirementsOperating system:Windows® XP / Vista™ / Windows® 7Processor: 1.4 GHz CPUMemory: 512 MBHard disk space: 3.5GBVideo:Video Card with 64MB dedicated memory and DirectX 9 CompatibleSound:Sound card with DirectX 9.0 supportDirectX®:9.0 or higher</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3892">American Conquest</game><game id="23206">American Conquest: Divided Nation</game><game id="27879">Napoleon: Total War</game><game id="4686">Waterloo: Napoleon's Last Battle</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/34413/1419353-r11208_cossacks_european_wars_b00005a9w0_l.jpg</image></root>