<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9445</id><name>MotoGP '07</name><description>Career Mode Racing SeedsPlayers start at Seed 100 and eventually achieve Seed 1. To improve the seed players must win races in both Grand Prix and Extreme Career modes. Seeds rise and fall depending on where players finish in a race, and the seed of the opponents players race against. Beating high seeded opponents’ nets more improvement then beating low seeded opponents. And losing to higher seeded opponents has less of a negative effect than lower seeds. Improving seeds will also improve the player’s attributes for Handling, Braking, Speed, and Acceleration. To continue improving seeds the player has to increase the difficulty of each season.   Rookie-Seeds 100-71  Pro-70-51  Champion-50-31  Legend-30-1   Grand Prix CareerIn Racing Career players must select Grand Prix first. Completing it unlocks Extreme mode. Grand Prix allows players to choose championship bikes that have been unlocked during previous seasons. Before each race of a season the player can choose to adjust bike settings, practice, qualify, and race. Practice will allow as much time and as many laps as the player desires to master the track. Qualifying will give the player ten minutes to achieve the fastest lap on the track. The race option begins the race, starting the player in the qualified position. Each race can be set to the desired number of laps in the options menu. Manufacturers include:   DucatiHondaKR212VSuzukiYamaha   Extreme Career In Extreme the structure of the season remains the same. But rather than simply choosing a bike players are given a set amount of money to spend on a new bike. Tracks in the Extreme season are wider, faster, and more forgiving then Grand Prix. Bikes handle accordingly, with more accessible controls. Each race will reward the player with a certain amount of money depending on the position they finished in. Money is used to upgrade the bikes with new parts, or purchase new bikes. Rider and Bike Customization Players can customize a rider’s appearance including helmet designs, and rider leathers. Logos are created with separate layers, shapes and colors. Finally, a team name, number, and nationality are selected. In Extreme mode players earn money to purchase various bikes and upgrades. Bikes are separated into four different fictional manufacturers. Manufacturers offer 4 kinds of bikes, each increasingly more powerful and expensive. Players can improve those stats by replacing different parts of the bike. Changes can have a positive and negative impact on how the bike will ultimately handle. Some parts will only change the aesthetic. Parts that can be swapped out include:   WheelsBrakesSwingarmsExhaustsTiresBodyworkSuspensionEngine   Bikes can be further customized by making adjustments to the compounds of both the front and rear tires. The trade-off is more speed versus better handling in the corners. Gear ratios can be changed to increase acceleration or top speed. Suspensions can be adjusted to improve grip and speed. Stability can be an issue depending on the hardness of the suspension. Finally the wheelbase can be changed to increase stability or responsiveness, respectively.  Challenge ModeEach Grand Prix track includes a set of three goals in Challenge Mode. Players can acquire Gold, Silver, and Bronze medals depending on their performance. Completed challenges will offer rider attributes depending on the medal.    Challenges include a timed run around a part of the course. There is a start and finish mapped into each track, and a target time to beat.  Speed runs, in which you must attain a set speed on the track as you reach the finish.  And Follow the Leader, where the goal is to race a lap against an AI opponent, finishing no worse than 5 seconds behind. Rider Attribute point values are:   Gold-3 pointsSilver-2 pointsBronze-1 point   Xbox Live Online play is both ranked and unranked, and includes Championship Mode, Pink Slip Racing, and Online Tournaments. Championship Mode-Players can choose to use either a Moto GP 07 racer, or a player created model, to race on any of the Grand Prix courses. Pink Slip Racing-Players can adjust the match to allow only racers of their skill level to compete. Each player must wager one extreme bike. If a player wins the race, they earn the other players bike.  Online Tournaments-There are five tournaments to choose from. Each tournament has its own set of unique restrictions to follow, including types of bikes.   Circuits The game features all the real world tracks of the season, which are:   Losail-Qatar Grand Prix  Jerez-Spanish Grand Prix  Istanbul-Turkish Grand Prix  Shanghai-Chinese Grand Prix  Le Mans-French Grand Prix  Mugello-Italian Grand Prix  Catalunya-Catalan Grand Prix  Donington-British Grand Prix  Assen-Dutch TT  Sachsenring-German Grand Prix  Laguna Seca-United States Grand Prix  Brno-Czech Republic Grand Prix  Misano-San Marino Grand Prix  Estoril-Portuguese Grand Prix  Motegi-Japanese Grand Prix  Phillip Island-Australian Grand Prix  Sepang-Malaysian Grand Prix  Valencia-Valencian Grand Prix   Extreme Tracks:  The extreme tracks in the game are all fictional, but are based on real world locations.   Gulf  Andulcia  Whale Coast  Copa Cabana  Riveria  Tuscany  Barcelona  Shires  Low Country  Autobahn  Monterey  Prague  Algarve  Tokyo  Outback  Malay  Sevilla   Trivia Casey Stoner won the 2007 Grand Prix season.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5881">Forza Motorsport 2</game><game id="20935">SBK: Superbike World Championship</game><game id="23187">Ducati World Racing Challenge</game><game id="669">Big Air FreeStyle</game><game id="28043">SBK: Superbike World Championship 09</game><game id="28327">MotoGP 09/10</game><game id="34405">MotoGP 10/11</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2421667-box_motogp07.png</image></root>