<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>945</id><name>Castlevania: Bloodlines</name><description>Overview The main protagonists: John Morris (right) and Eric Lecarde (left)Castlevania: Bloodlines (known in Japan as Vampire Killer and in Europe as Castlevania: The New Generation) is an action platformer developed and published by                                 Konami for the                                Sega Genesis in March 17, 1994. Although the game features the                               Vampire Killer whip, Castlevania: Bloodlines is the first                             Castlevania game to not include a primary descendent of the Belmont clan of vampire hunters as the main protagonist. This is also the first Castlevania game to refer to the Vampire Killer whip by it's name. The game is also known for its attempt to connect the   Castlevania franchise to Bram Stoker's novel,                            Dracula (even by referring to the father of the game's protagonist as Quincy Morris, the name of a key character in the novel). Taking place in 1914, the story follows two indirect blood descendants of the Belmont clan (                     John Morris, an American who wields the Vampire Killer whip, and                     Eric Lecarde, a Spaniard whose love interest was lost to vampirism), as they set out throughout Europe to prevent the resurrection of                       Count Dracula by his neice, the revived vampire Elizabeth Bartley.  Castlevania: Bloodlines is also known for being the precursor to                   Castlevania: Portrait of Ruin, in which the player plays as John's son,                  Jonathan Morris. Eric Lecarde also plays a prominent role in the game as both the father of                 Stella and                Loretta Lecarde and the spirit "Wind", who guides the main protagonists in their adventure. It is also revealed that John was unable to fully utilize the Vampire Killer whip without draining his life, perishing some time before Castlevania: Portrait of Ruin. Gameplay          Castlevania: Bloodlines plays like a traditional Castlevania platformer. Players guide either John or Eric through six stages spread throughout Europe, increasing their score by defeating enemies and collecting bags of  money (dropped by enemies or destroying scenery). Players will also find               jewels (which serve as ammunition for sub-weapons and super "Item Crash" attacks), the "           Mirrors of Truth" (which clears the screen of all enemies), black orbs (which grant the player        temporary invulnerability),   Coat of Arms (which upgrades the player's primary weapon),         mutton chops (which restroes some of the player's health), and          1-Up items (which grant the player an extra life). Each stage is linear (with the exception of certain parts that must be completed with a specific character). Along with one boss to close the level, each stage also features one or more mini-bosses.    Character Differences Castlevania: Bloodlines allows the player to pick one of two playable characters, each with their own unique primary weapon and special attributes.  John Morris utilizes the legendary Vampire Killer whip, which can be charged by holding down the attack button. Like    Simon Belmont from   Super Castlevania IV, John can use his whip to swing from special blocks, allowing him to easily pass certain chasms. Although he can only attack horizontally on the ground, he can whip diagonally and under him while in the air.    Eric Lecarde wields the Alcarde Spear, a long spear that allows him to stab at enemies in multiple directions. When jumping out of a crouch, Eric uses his spear to propel himself into the air, allowing him to reach new heights while attacking airborne enemies. Sub-Weapons/Item Crushes  Along  the way, John and Eric can pick up sub-weapons that consume jewels for a  special attack (which, unlike most early Castlevania games, is given  its own attack button).    Boomerang Battle Axe Sacred Water </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16098">Black Tiger</game><game id="28250">Rusty</game><game id="6339">Rocket Knight Adventures</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1773381-box_cvb.png</image></root>