<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9450</id><name>Croc: Legend of the Gobbos</name><description>OverviewCroc is a third-person, 3D platform game in which you play as a crocodile named Croc who seeks to save the Gobbos from the evil Baron Dante. The game takes the player to several islands, with his job to find and save all the Gobbos, little furry creatures with big eyes, as possible and defeat the level bosses which occur every half level. However, this is no easy task because Baron Dante has set his henchmen around every island you visit. They can betaken out, but only for a short while, with a blow from your tail.GameplayThere are four islands and one secret island in croc. Each of the four main contain six normal levels, in which Croc has to collect six Gobbos and five Coloured Crystals. The Coloured Crystals open the Crystal Door at the end of each normal level which contain the sixth gobbo required. This is usually the hardest part of the level.Each also contains two Boss Levels, in which Croc does not collect any Gobbos, but collects crystals and defeats a boss at the end of the level. If all six Gobbos are collected in each set of three levels and the boss is defeated, there are two secret levels in which Croc has to find a jigsaw piece. He has to collect all eight jigsaw pieces in each secret level to gain access to the secret island.PlotCroc holding a gobboThe Gobbo King Rufus was watching the sunset when he noticed a small basket in the lake, containing a small, screaming baby crocodile. The Gobbos begin to raise him and train him to become one of their own. Croc mostly ate buckets of peas when raised by the Gobbos. Croc eventually grew to twice the size of a normal Gobbo. All was peaceful until one day suddenly, the evil Baron Dante arrives and invades with the help of his demon minions, Dantinis. He imprisons many of the Gobbos, most notably their King, who he keeps in a steel cage within his castle island. Before the Gobbo King is taken, he hits a magical gong that summons a yellow bird called Beany. Beany, in turn, causes Croc to shrink and he whisks Croc away to safety. Croc then goes on a quest to free all the Gobbos and defeat the evil Baron Dante himself.</description><genres><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7380">Crash Bandicoot</game><game id="2931">Super Mario 64</game><game id="10533">Conker's Bad Fur Day</game><game id="7836">Spyro the Dragon</game><game id="10920">Banjo-Kazooie</game><game id="19873">Conker's Pocket Tales</game><game id="4434">Earthworm Jim 3D</game><game id="15000">Donkey Kong 64</game><game id="24704">Frogger</game><game id="609">Rayman 2: The Great Escape</game><game id="11371">Gex: Enter the Gecko</game><game id="5642">Jersey Devil</game><game id="27562">Disney Epic Mickey</game><game id="8698">Tail Concerto</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2689/240682-croc_legend_of_the_gobbos.jpg</image></root>