<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9458</id><name>Peter Jackson's King Kong: The Official Game of the Movie</name><description>OverviewKing Kong is the video-game adaptation of Peter Jackson's King Kong. It is part first-person shooter with you taking the role of the character Jack, and part third-person beat-em up as Kong.GameplayThe game doesn't include a heads-up-display.Although games in which the player takes control of multiple characters are not exactly rare, King Kong takes this to extremes by changing the style of gameplay dramatically. Whilst most of the game is played through the first person perspective of Jack Driscoll, occasionally, players will get the opportunity to take a more diverse route as King Kong exploring the jungle in platforming style segments as you leap from trees and walls, and also taking the approach of a beat-em-up, usually in colossal, almost boss-like battles against a Tyrannosaurus Rex or at times even a pack of Tyrannosaurs.Whilst playing as Jack, however, the game still manages to divert from the first person archetype most games follow by making ammunition for automatic weapons such as guns sparse and scattered far away, meaning the character has to learn to use bones, torches and sharpened sticks to fend off dinosaurs, giant bugs and other ghastly creatures.The notable lack of a HUD also increases the difficulty factor putting players in a position where they need to judge how far and where to throw their projectiles. Due to the lack of a HUD, the game introduces tactics to keep the player in the know regarding their ammo count, such as having Jack shout out how much ammunition he has left whenever he reloads his clip and allowing players to manually check their ammo with a button press. When injured too much, the screen will go red and blurry and Jack's heartbeat will sound off louder than usual. All this serves to create atmosphere within the game which, although used frequently today, might have been considered somewhat unnerving and effective when the game was initially released.Scoring SystemOnce 100% game completion is obtained, an extra scoring system is unlock inwhich you can replay each chapter and try to earn the highest score.   Each copy of the game included a unique internet code that you can enter your high score into the ubisoft's king kong website (www.kingkonggame.com) .  [Ubisoft redesigned their website and made this feature obsolete].   Your overall score is kept and depending on the score it will unlock additional extrasThe max high score for each chapter/level is 20,000, You recieve a level bonus after completing each level again.  the system adds to your score as well as take points away based on your actions.  Below is a general guideline for the points+5,000 points - Big Predators Killed+1,000 points - Big Predators Killed+500 points - Big Predators Killed-100 points - Bullets Used-20 points - Spears Used-5,000 points - Deaths-1,000 points - Injuries-1,000 points - Friends Injured-25 points - Attack Attempted -10 points - Time per second ExtrasBased on percentage of game completion and your overall score certain things will unlock. 05% Completion - Weta Artworks:  Environments Part 115% Completion - "Old Movie" Filter25% Completion - Weta Artworks: Environments Part 250% Completion - Weta Artworks: Creatures75% Completion - Weta Artworks:  Kong Part 1100% Completion - "High Contrast"  Filter, Horizontal Flip20,000 Points - Weta Artworks:  Kong Part 250,000 Points - Weta Artworks:  Environments Part 375,000 Points - Peter Jackson Interview100,000 Points - Weta Artworks: Kong Part 3150,000 Points - Weta Artworks:  Kong Part 4200,000 Points - Philippa Boyens Interview250,000 Points - Alternate Ending ProductionAs the director of the 2005 remake of the movie King Kong, Peter Jackson worked very hard to make sure the video-game tie-in would be a more pleasurable experience for gamers than most other movie-game tie-ins which are on the whole considered sub-par by the video game community. Jackson's own background as a video-gamer is known to have prompted this.The game was made alongside the film and was seen as a collaborative effort between the cast and crew of the film and the developers of the game, two groups of people attempting to tell the same story through different mediums, and trying to evoke different experiences, whilst maintaining a positive response.Almost all of the cast from the 2005 motion picture lent their voices to the game including Jack Black, Adrien Brody and Naomi Watts. As well as that, Andy Serkis, the critically acclaimed motion capture performer praised for his acting as Gollum in The Lord of the Rings trilogy of movies, and playing King Kong in the movie provided his services for the video game as well.ChaptersThe VentureSkull IslandNecropolisScorpionsThe WallSacrificeOn Kong's TracksHayesV-RexAnnKongThe CanyonMillipedesBrontosaurusJimmyOn the RaftRapidsFightSwampsChased by V-RexThe LogThe Skull IslandersTo Save AnnThe CaveVenatosaurusIn the MudCall KongKong to the RescueTo the PlaneTo the LairKong's LairFight in the LairFreeChased by KongHeading BackBack to the VillageKong's CaptureKong Struck DownIn the Streets of New YorkThe Empire State BuildingKong's DeathSoundtrackThe soundtrack was composed by Chance Thomas and was released free on the official website. It contains mysterious and powerful elements, similar to motion picture score, composed by James Newton Howard.Track ListingAnn Leaves The IslandAnn's ThemeBetween Two Worlds/Vision of AnnFury and HeroicsThe Island TombsKing Kong, the Tragic HeroKong Dispatches the TyrantLost in the JungleNest of RaptorsPanicRaptor Attack/Death of a FriendRelentlessSting of the Giant ScorpionThe T-Rex ComethValley of the BrontosaurusVampires of the SkyXbox 360 Game InstallationPeter Jackson's King Kong: The Official Game of the Movie requires 6.2GB of space to be installed on an Xbox 360 HDD.System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows® 98SE/ME/2000/XPProcessor: 1.0 GHz AMD Athlon™ or Intel® Pentium® IIIRAM: 256 MBVideo Card: 64 MB DirectX® 8.1 compliantSound Card: DirectX 8.1 compliantDirectX: DirectX 8.1CD-ROM: 8x or fasterHard Drive Space: 1.5 GB minimumRecommendedOS: Windows® 98SE/ME/2000/XPProcessor: 2.5 GHz Pentium IV or AMD Athlon™RAM: 512 MBVideo Card:128 MBSound Card: DirectX 8.1 compliantDirectX: DirectX 9.0cCD-ROM: 32x or fasterHard Drive Space: 1.5 GB minimum</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20532">Legendary</game><game id="22968">Splatterhouse</game><game id="457">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Double Agent</game><game id="8201">Lara Croft Tomb Raider: Anniversary</game><game id="28916">Jurassic: The Hunted</game><game id="14782">Far Cry</game><game id="1109">Trespasser: Jurassic Park</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2285669-box_kingkong.png</image></root>