<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9463</id><name>Mega Man X</name><description>OverviewNot to be confused with  Mega Man 10 ,  Mega Man X introduced players to new mechanics such as dashing, wall-jumping, and finding hidden upgrades throughout the levels, something which would carry on and become an essential part of each  X game to follow. It was originally released in 1993 by  Capcom, later ported to the  PC in 1995, as well as being remade in 2005 for the  PSP under the name  Mega Man: Maverick Hunter X. The remake featured enhanced 3D character models and backgrounds, remixed music, re-tuned level designs, and the ability to play as series villain  Vile. This game was also included in the  Mega Man X Collection for the  Nintendo Gamecube and  PlayStation 2. The lead designers were both  Tokuro Fujiwara (Producer) and  Keiji Inafune (Characters) and the head composer was  Setsuo Yamamoto.GameplayThe opening highway stageUnlike the core  Mega Man series, the X games are much faster and more detailed. From the moment you press start, the game has you  wall jumping for your life up onto destroyed highways crawling with angry Mavericks, only for you to end up fighting a  meched up Vile, who, for the first time in the franchise, is a boss that you cannot defeat. While a lot is different, the structure of the game is similar to its namesake: fight eight bosses in any order, exploiting their weaknesses to defeat them more easily; make your way through Sigma's lair; and finally fight the final boss,  Sigma. Of course, keeping with the precedent set by the previous evil mastermind  Dr. Wily, Sigma narrowly escapes death, to return again in the next installment. The levels consist of  Mega Man X running, dashing, jumping, and wall-kicking frantically to avoid many difficult obstacles and to find hidden  Upgrade Capsules. There are four capsules hidden throughout the game's eight stages, with each one containing one of four body parts: arm, leg, torso, and head. Once X collects all four of them, he is basically an unstoppable badass (assuming the player has the skill). Once X reaches the end of a level, he will be confronted by a boss robot that he must fight with everything he has to defeat, and take his weapon. It is worth noting that the bosses in this game are much more intelligent than those found in the classic Mega Man series, changing up their attack patterns as they take more damage.UpgradesThroughout the game, if X is lucky, he may stumble upon one of the aforementioned large blue capsules that when approached will show him a hologram of  Dr. Light, his long-dead creator. Depending on which capsule X finds, Light will brief him on what the upgrade does and then give him the pleasure of stepping into the capsule. Here is a list of all the upgrades and the area that they are in.Speed BootsThese will give X the ability to dash.Location - Chill Penguin's lairUpgrade CapsuleNote: Unlike the other upgrades, this is in the direct path of the level, and X is unable to proceed without it.Body ArmorDecreases the damage X takes by half.Location - Sting Chameleon's lairHelmetAllows X to destroy certain blocks by headbutting them.Location - Storm Eagle's lairChargeAllows X to charge one stage higher to shoot a super-charged blast that can go through enemies. This also lets X charge up weapons he has received from the bosses, giving him a bunch of new attacks.Location - Flame Mammoth's lair. If this is missed, it is received automatically in the first Sigma stage.Special/SecretX hitting Sigma with a HadoukenIf you have played  Street Fighter then you will recognize this one. It is the  Hadouken move. You fire large blue blasts out of your hands, which kills bosses in one hit. It is performed by simply performing the famed quarter-circle motion that you would do in any Street Fighter game. The move can only be used while X is at full health.Location - Armored Armadillo's lair at the end of the level before you enter the boss hallway.Kill yourself three times, and then climb up onto the ledge above where the boss door is. A  Gi-clad Dr. Light will congratulate you and you will get the upgrade.Bosses (Maverick Reploids) Chill PenguinChill PenguinHeight: 5.34 ftWeight: 237 lbsAttacks: Shotgun Ice, SlidingWeakness: Fire Wave Storm EagleStorm EagleHeight: 8.20 ftWeight: 275 lbsAttacks: Storm Tornado, DivingWeakness: Chameleon Sting Flame MammothFlame MammothHeight: 10.5 ftWeight: 719 lbsAttacks: Fire Wave, Oiling, Jump PressWeakness: Storm Tornado (Boomerang Cutter can cut of his trunk, preventing him from using certain attacks) Spark MandrillHeight: 10.0 ftWeight: 646 lbsAttacks: Electric Spark, Dash PunchWeakness: Shotgun Ice Armored ArmadilloArmored ArmadilloHeight: 6.36 ftWeight: 510 lbsAttacks: Rolling Shield, GuardingWeakness: Electric Spark Launch OctopusLaunch OctopusHeight: 7.80 ftWeight: 348 lbsAttacks: Homing Torpedo, Energy DrainWeakness: Rolling Shield (Boomerang Cutter can also cut off his tentacles, preventing him from using certain attacks) Boomer KuwangerBoomer KuwangerHeight: 7.93 ftWeight: 206 lbsAttacks: Boomerang Cutter, Dead LiftWeakness: Homing Torpedo Sting ChameleonSting ChameleonHeight: 5.80 ftWeight: 169 lbsAttacks: Chameleon Sting, Iron TongueWeakness: Boomerang CutterPC Version DifferencesMusic has much lower fidelity than the  SNES version.Many enemies appear to have more healthMega Man: Maverick Hunter X (PSP)Mega Man: Maverick Hunter XMain Article:  Maverick Hunter XFully remade  2.5D graphicsAnime  FMV sequencesVoice actingRemade scriptFeatures a 20 minute OVA: "The Day of Sigma."New playable character:  VileNew  difficulty settingsNew musicSlightly restructured levelsAbility to save; no passwordsEnergy tank, heart, and power-up stations rearrangedSoundtrackCover ArtIn 2005 Capcom released a 5-disc box set called Capcom Music Generation Rockman X1~6. It contains the original music of Mega Man X through Mega Man X6 as well as some unused tracks. Mega Man X tracks cover half of the first disc and the tracks are listed as followed:Track #TitleLength1.CAPCOM LOGO0:072.TITLE0:273.PASS WORD1:264.OPENING STAGE1:405. VAVA 10:276.VAVA 21:097. ZERO0:498.DEMO1:169.STAGE SELECT 11:0810.STAGE START0:0911. LAUNCHER OCTOPULD STAGE1:5312. ICY PENGUIGO STAGE1:3713. BURNIN' NOUMANDER STAGE2:0914. BOOMER KUWANGER STAGE2:3015. STING CHAMELEAO STAGE1:2216. SPARK MANDRILLER STAGE1:5517. STORM EAGLEED STAGE1:2418. ARMOR ARMARGE STAGE2:0619.BOSS 10:2520.BOSS 21:1221.STAGE CLEAR0:0922.GET A WEAPON0:2423.STAGE SELECT 20:4924. SIGMA STAGE 12:0525.SIGMA STAGE 22:1926.SIGMA STAGE 31:5427.SIGMA STAGE 40:5528.SIGMA 1st0:5029.SIGMA REBIRTH0:1030.SIGMA 2nd2:0231. DR.RIGHT0:4532.ENDING1:4833.CAST ROLL1:4734.STAFF ROLL1:5835.SE5:23</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18309">Ratchet &amp; Clank</game><game id="21115">Ratchet &amp; Clank Future: Quest for Booty</game><game id="15212">Ratchet &amp; Clank Future: Tools of Destruction</game><game id="10384">Jak II</game><game id="9669">Jak 3</game><game id="3479">Keith Courage in Alpha Zones</game><game id="8292">Super Metroid</game><game id="20124">Cave Story</game><game id="18041">Turrican II: The Final Fight</game><game id="8583">Metal Slug Advance</game><game id="4350">Contra</game><game id="1257">Blaster Master</game><game id="4237">Contra 4</game><game id="791">Demon's Crest</game><game id="14450">Super Star Wars</game><game id="33981">A.R.E.S.: Extinction Agenda</game><game id="6141">Mega Man Anniversary Collection</game><game id="39276">Freedom Planet</game><game id="2114">Kaizou Choujin Shubibinman</game><game id="40902">Rockman ×over</game><game id="6763">Skyblazer</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2363964-snes_megamanx.jpg</image></root>