<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9539</id><name>Extreme Assault</name><description>Developed by Blue Byte Studio GmbH, released in 1997. Players assume control of a futuristic Sioux AH-23 Attack helicopter and a T1 assault tank to battle space aliens, who have secretly set up operation on Earth. There are over 50 missions to play through as well as multi-player levels that allow up to 4 players to play together. There are about twenty different types of enemies and six operation zones with various terrain in single-player mode. WeaponsSioux AH-23: Helicopter. Fast, maneuverable and armed.  T1: A heavily armed battle tank. Has the ability to move sideways. Runs on glides over an anti-gravity field. Same weapons and weapon system as the AH-23.   Razor gun: Fires rounds that are similar to mini-missiles. They follow the target just about anywhere. Ammunition never runs out, but requires additional ammo to use all three barrels.   Laser Cannon: Useful against slow-moving or stationary targets. Never runs out of ammunition, but extra ammo is required to use the maximum fire power available.   Fire Flash: Supposedly a deadly weapon that can destroy an entire house. It has not been invented yet in the beginning of the game.  Guided Missile: Effective against fast and heavily armed opponents. Players must select a target to use the guidance feature. When there is less than six missiles left, players can pick up refills.  Smart Bomb: Most advanced and most intelligent bomb in existence. It will disseminate numerous rockets simultaneously.   Thunderbolt: Functions like a guided missile, covers an entire zone with grenades.  References http://www.mobygames.com/game/extreme-assault http://www.bluebyte.net/eng/products/extreme-assault/index.htm </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2529">Black Dawn</game><game id="2422">Soviet Strike</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/12482/776852-extreme_assault__pc.jpg</image></root>