<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9594</id><name>Metal Gear Solid: The Twin Snakes</name><description>OverviewMetal Gear Solid: The Twin Snakes is the 2004 remake of Metal Gear Solid developed by Silicon Knights of Eternal Darkness fame as part of a special partnership between Nintendo, Konami, and Silicon Knights. The game uses the levels and story of Metal Gear Solid and reworks the gameplay to include elements that were introduced in Metal Gear Solid 2: Sons of Liberty. Portions of the script were retranslated, as well, and all of the game's voicework was re-recorded. According to various sources, David Hayter (the voice of Solid Snake) used half of his paycheck to bring the original actors back to reprise their respective roles. The Ninja however, was voiced by Rob Paulsen instead of Greg Eagles. The Twin Snakes was the last game developed by Silicon Knights as a Nintendo studio.StoryThe game stars Solid Snake investigating the nuclear disposal facility which had been taken over by FOXHOUND, a special ops unit led by Snake's brother Liquid Snake. He enters from an underwater entrance and then sneaks past the guards and onto the ground level of the facility on Shadow Moses Island. He proceeds throughout the game by sneaking past enemies and, when necessary, by engaging them in gun fights. He then talks to the DARPA Chief who has been imprisoned and finds out about a nuclear bipedal tank called Metal Gear REX. Early on he encounters the niece of his CO, Col. Campbell, Meryl Silverburgh. Shortly after he encounters the first boss battle with gunslinger Revolver Ocelot. Then a Cyborg Ninja comes in and cuts off Ocelot's right arm."This is no longer 32-bit, Snake. Welcome to the 128-bit world!"He runs away to recover after the ninja leaves in a crazed state. He then talks to the head of the fictional weapons company called ARMS Tech. He learns that there are keys needed to stop the Metal Gear from launching its nukes. He then calls Meryl via the codec found on the back of the game box and he heads outside where he fights a tank driven by FOXHOUND's Vulcan Raven. Snake fights the Cyborg Ninja who reveals himself to be Gray Fox and then befriends Hal Emmerich aka Otacon. Soon after they both meet up and head towards Metal Gear's location. They encounter Psycho Mantis of FOXHOUND in one of gaming's greatest boss battles. Afterward, Meryl in incapacitated by FOXHOUND's sniper, Sniper Wolf which leads to a duel between her and Snake. Snake is then incapacitated and brought to the torture chamber where the player has to resist electric shocks administered by Revolver Ocelot. In order to do that the player to resist they must mash on the action button. This is where the ending of the game is determined. If you resist then you'll get the Meryl ending. If you surrender to the torture then you get the Otacon ending. Snake then goes to fight Sniper Wolf, but this time she dies. After that Snake fights off Liquid who is in control of a Hind D helicopter. After that Snake sets off toward the underground base were Metal Gear Rex is contained. On the way Snake fights Vulcan Raven again, without the tank.After Snake defeats him he makes it to Metal Gear Rex and learns the that instead of having three seperate key cards, the card was sensitive to heat and would change shape when exposed to heat and cold. Snake uses the key card in each terminal. To his surprise this activiated REX and Liquid exposes that Snake was being used to activate REX. Snake then fights REX by shooting it's radar with stinger missiles. Gray Fox then appears to aid Snake in destroying the radar. This makes Liquid exposes his cockpit allowing Snake to fire at him with missiles. After Snake destroys REX the explosion throws Snake into the wall with enough force to cause him to pass out. When Snake comes to it eventually climaxes into a fist fight between the two brothers resulting in Solid Snake's victory. Liquid dies after a vehicle chase from the FOXDIE virus which was responsible for the deaths of both Decoy Octopus, who was disguised as the DARPA chief and the ARMS Tech president.After the credits a phone conversation is heard between Revolver Ocelot, the only survivor of FOXHOUND, and a mysterious person. The person is later to be revealed as George Sears, the President of the United States, and the third clone of Big Boss whose nickname is Solidus Snake.Cast of CharactersProtagonistImageNameVoice ActorDescriptionSolid SnakeDavid HayterThe legendary soldier send back from retirementto stop a group of terrorists fromlaunching a nuclear weapon to the worldSupporting CharactersImageNameVoice ActorDescriptionMeryl SilverburghDebi Mae WestCampbell's niece who is captured by FOXHOUNDand is being held captive on Shadow Moses Island.Meryl may lack field experience but her courageis what makes her a great ally for SnakeColonel Roy CampbellPaul EidingFOXHOUND's former Commanding Officer andSnake's former mentor. He serves as Snake'sprimary radio contact in the game andgives information about his missionobjective and general gameplay tips.Dr. Naomi HunterJennifer HaleNaomi is FOXHOUND's chief of medical staffand is part of Snake's radio supportMei LingKim Mai GuestFOXHOUND's communications expertwho designed the codec radio and soliton radar.Mei Ling also handles the saving dataDr. Hal "Otacon" EmmerichChristopher RandolphAn ArmsTech employee who designed Metal Gear REX.Nicknamed Otacon for his love of AnimeMaster MacDonnell MillerCam ClarkeFOXHOUND's former drill instructor and have sinceretired in Alaska. Master serves as Snake's radiosupport.Nastasha RomanenkoRenee RaudmanNastasha was born in the USSR and is aweapons expert. She can be contacted for anyenquiries about weaponries that are foundon Shadow Moses IslandVillains (FOXHOUND)ImageNameVoice ActorDescriptionLiquid SnakeCam ClarkeMain antagonist and leader of theterrorist groupRevolver OcelotPatric ZimmermanSecond-in-command and aninterrogation expertVulcan RavenPeter LurieAn Inuit member of FOXHOUND who wields agiant Vulcan cannon and has shamanicpowers of intuitionPsycho MantisDoug StoneA psychic expert for the FOXHOUND unit.Has the ability to read people's mind andmanipulate his victim's body movementSniper WolfTasia ValenzaA beautiful and deadly Iraqi-Kurdsharpshooter of the FOXHOUND unit,who uses a Heckler  Koch PSG1.Though snipers usually work in pairs,Sniper Wolf works alone.Decoy OctopusN/AA master of disguise. As a perfectionist,Decoy Octopus goes to great lengths inimpersonating someone by injecting the bloodof those he impersonates into his ownbody for a more "perfect" disguise.OthersImageNameVoice ActorDescriptionCyborg NinjaRob PaulsenA mysterious cyborg ninja who wieldsa katana blade. Apparently, he is onneither side and his main agenda is unknownDonald AndersonGreg EaglesThe DARPA chief who is taken hostage by FOXHOUNDKenneth BakerAllan LuriePresident of ArmsTech who is also being heldcaptive against his willJim HousemanWilliam H. BassettThe United States Secretary of Defense whoobserves the situation on Shadow Moses Islandaboard an AWACS command planeJohnny SasakiDean ScofieldAn enemy guard whose uniform is stolen by Meryl.Has a long history of suffering from cold and diarrheaChangesThe Twin Snakes boasted many changes from the original game, including:Graphics and AudioThe graphics were subject to a major overhaul, bringing them more in-line with the second game.The cut scenes were completely re-choreographed and directed by acclaimed action director Ryuhei Kitamura.The audio was completely re-recorded in a higher fidelity. Additionally, the script was revised, and characters that previously had thick accents have their accents either lessened or removed completely. Mei Ling no longer speaks with a Chinese accent, Naomi no longer speaks with a British accent, and Nastasha's thick Russian accent is now only a slight inflection.Gameplay EnhancementsThe new first-person viewThe ability to aim in first-person view, first introduced in Sons of Liberty, was added to the game.The ability to hang over ledges, also taken from Sons of Liberty, was added as well.The Mk-22 tranquilizer gun is available for use. This weapon was introduced in Sons of Liberty.As in the original game, there is a lengthy sequence in which Snake must use the temperature-sensitive PAL key. To progress, Snake must use the key after it has been heated and cooled one time each. In the original version, this requires the player to backtrack to earlier areas with extreme temperature environments and then race back to the control room before the card's state resets. Twin Snakes features a streamlined option to solving this puzzle by including hot and cold pipes in the Rex hanger that can be shot. The steam from these pipes is capable of cooling or heating the PAL key, preventing the need to backtrack, though the option to backtrack is still present.Easter EggsDog tags were added for Twin Snakes as collectable items. If Snake successfully performs a hold-up, he can raise his gun to the face or crotch of a soldier and scare him into shaking loose a dog tag. These tags feature the names of programmers on them and can be viewed from the main menu.Mario and Yoshi make a cameo appearance as mini statues in Otacon's office.When Psycho Mantis reads the player's memory card, he names Nintendo titles such as Super Smash Bros. Melee and Eternal Darkness.ReceptionFor the most part, The Twin Snakes was openly accepted by fans. Many believe that it captured the story and atmosphere of the original, but also introduced necessary improvements which made the game more accessible. However, the new gameplay elements have been deemed as unnecessary by some. The level design of The Twin Snakes is practically unchanged from the original Metal Gear Solid which makes the new control scheme seem almost out of place. It has also been stated this new introduction makes them game too straightforward, and practically ruins many of the once challenging battles.The Twin Snakes also received some negative feedback regarding changes to the script and cutscenes. Seemingly unnecessary small changes to the script and voice acting were jarring to fans and the new over-the-top cut scenes were felt to detract from the experience for some. The cutscenes were also criticized for its heavy use of the bullet-time effect, which many people felt to be too excessive and felt like it was trying to be the next Matrix movie. For this reason, many fans of the original still prefer to play the PlayStation version.</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7539">Tenchu: Wrath of Heaven</game><game id="16004">Tenchu: Stealth Assassins</game><game id="7750">Tenchu: Return from Darkness</game><game id="5961">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell</game><game id="12354">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Chaos Theory</game><game id="34">Batman Begins</game><game id="23695">Shadow Harvest: Phantom Ops</game><game id="23924">Spy Fiction</game><game id="21965">Cipher Complex</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1789944-box_mgstts.png</image></root>