<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9669</id><name>Jak 3</name><description>OverviewGood. Bad. Jak's the guy with the gun.Jak 3 is an action-adventure/platforming game and the third installment in the Jak and Daxter franchise, as well as the final chapter in the original trilogy. Taking place a short period after the events of Jak II, Jak and his smart-mouthed ottsel companion, Daxter, find themselves outcasted by Haven City, and its new leader, Count Veger, as the city continues to fight a seemingly endless, and increasingly hopeless, war against the Metal Heads and a new enemy called the Dethbots.The game follows the duo's fight for survival and acceptance out in the Wasteland, their fight back into the city, their revenge against Count Vegar, and the final battles against the Metal Heads and Deathbots.Jak 3 was developed by Naughty Dog, Inc. and published by SCEA. The game was released on the PlayStation 2 on November 9, 2004 in North America and on November 26, 2004 in Europe.GameplayInsert jokes regarding Chocobos here.The gameplay, which continues off of the combat-heavy, open world gameplay introduced in its predecessor, returns with new abilities and weapons while staying true to the platforming elements introduced in the The Precursor Legacy. While Jak's Dark Eco form returns, which allows him to use stronger attacks for a short time, the game introduces a "Light Eco Form", which gives him non-combative, but still useful, abilities. Additionally, Daxter is given more playable scenarios: including a Dodge 'Em -style minigame and his own platforming levels in areas inaccessible by Jak.The Morph Gun, which was introduced in the previous game, returns in this installment. This time, however, there are a total of 12 "weapon mods" that Jak may use on his enemies. There are four different color-coded mods (Red, Yellow, Blue, "Dark") and each with 3 different variants. As in the last game, weapon mods are unlocked by playing through the game and appear in a linear order.Vehicles also return in this installment, and have also been given more focus gameplay-wise. In most of the Wasteland chapters, Jak can drive unlockable cars and engage in open-world vehicular combat and treasure collecting, the latter being similar to the gameplay of the Smuggler's Run franchise. Jak can still commandeer vehicles, ala' Grand Theft Auto, which also controls the same way in Jak II, but with less traffic. In the Wasteland, Jak can ride on bird-like creatures, called Leapers, to traverse the desert and streets of Spargus City. Finally, the hoverboard also returns but since, in the story, the Arena district has been destroyed, players do not compete in the Tony Hawk-esque minigame from the predecessor.SettingJak and Daxter gliding over the vast Wasteland.Jak 3 takes place in a fictional universe set around 500 years after the events of the first game, and a couple of months after the second. Unlike Jak 2, the locations have been expanded to include Haven City, Spargus City, and the Wastelands.Haven City has become a war-torn city due to the war between the Metalheads, the Deathbots, and the Crimson Guard. Unlike in Jak 2, there are very few safe locations in the city and Jak will need to fight either Metal Heads or Deathbots in order to survive and open once-accessible areas.Spargus City was a city built by Damus in order to help protect those who were stranded in the desert. Even though Spargus is a city for refugees, citizens must earn their place by fighting in the city's arena. That means that unlike the denizens of Haven, Spargus' people are all heavily armed and happy to fire off a few shots if Jak bumps into them. Spargus City's technology is far behind Haven City. Even though you can travel via hovercraft in Haven City, Jak can only travel by foot or by Leaper in Spargus.The Wasteland is a dangerous location filled with giant Metal Heads and vicious Marauders. Both will force the player to defend themselves with their weapon-equipped buggies as they traverse the land. Some of the landmarks in the Wasteland include: a Metal Head nest, the Marauders' camp, the monks' tower, and the abandoned city.Weapon ModsJak's main weapon in the game is his Morph Gun, which he acquires early on in the game. This gun doesn't function as a single-purpose firearm. Instead, it uses different weapon mods, collected throughout the game, to deal different amounts of damage for almost every combat situation. There are four different styles of mods, each having three different versions of their variant.Red Mod: Shotgun variations for close-quarter combat.Yellow Mod: Rifle variations for long-range.Blue Mod: Machine Gun variations for taking out waves of enemies.Dark Mod: Power weapons that have small amounts of ammo but deal devastating damage.Red ModPictureNameAmmoRangeDescriptionScatter Gun50ShortA basic shotgun that you acquire early in the game. While it packs a decent punch, the gun fires very slowly.Wave Concussor75MediumA chargeable weapon that unleashes a powerful blast that is effective against surrounding enemies. Its ammo usage can range between 1-5 ammo depending on how long the blast is charged for.Plasmite RPG100MediumLaunches a powerful bomb that also has a very large blast radius. While it is powerful, one RPG uses 10 ammo.Yellow ModPictureNameAmmoRangeDescriptionBlaster100LongA rifle useful for its long range and decent damage. It has a good firing rate and is useful in almost every situation.The Blaster is the first weapon you gain in Jak 3.Beam Reflexor150LongActs the same way as the Blaster but the bullets will reflect off of walls and enemies. The added bonus comes at the cost of one extra ammo.Gyro Burster200MediumShoots out a floating pod that rapidly fires at every enemy near it. It's a great weapon for clearing out large groups on enemies. However, it will only use a maximum of 50 ammo.Blue ModPictureNameAmmoAmmoDescriptionVulcan Fury100Medium-LongThe game's heavy duty machine gun. The bullets are weak but it can fire so fast that the weakness won't be a problem.Arc Wielder150MediumOutputs a stream of electricity that you can use to badly damage any enemies near you. However, it uses ammo faster than the Vulcan Fury.Needle Lazer200LongRapidly shoots out small blue lasers that will track down any enemies. Uses more ammo than the Arc Wielder.Dark ModPictureNameAmmoRangeDescriptionPeacemaker5LongShoots a single ball of lightning that will severely damage, if not instantly kill, any enemy hit by it. The blast will also arc to any nearby enemies and damage them as well.Mass Inverter10MediumDoesn't damage any enemies but it does give them anti-gravity properties that will make it vulnerable to an attack.Supernova10LongLaunches a small missile that depletes all of your Dark ammo, but will destroy every nearby enemy on and off screen.BossesDark Maker Satellite (Desert Oasis)Precursor RobotPrecursor Robot (Eco Mines)Cyber Errol (KG War Factory)Dark Maker Terraformer (Wasteland)Cyber Errol [Dark Maker Terraformer] (Wasteland, on Terraformer)Soundtrack#Song TitleTimeArtist1Spargus Arena2:33Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins2Spargus City2:22Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins3Calm Wasteland3:24Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins4Harsh Wasteland4:48Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins5Artifact Race4:48Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins6Leaper Race4:56Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins7Metalhead Hunt5:20Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins8Wasteland Run2:50Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins9Metalhead Nest5:59Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins10Monk Temple2:58Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins11Monk Glider2:40Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins12Volcano5:22Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins13Precursor Sub-rails6:02Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins14Eco Mine3:00Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins15Haven City3:37Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins16Sewers5:14Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins17Incoming Blast Bots3:04Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins18Gun Course2:38Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins19Metalhead City Area6:01Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins20Haven City Battle4:42Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins21Haven City Chase4:46Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins22Metal-peads2:37Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins23War Factory3:58Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins24Monk Temple Under Attack3:58Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins25Dark Maker Ship6:00Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins26Tower Bombs5:03Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins27Stadium Ruins4:35Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins28Palace Ruins4:37Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins29Dark Maker Finale6:30Mark Mothersbaugh, Josh Mancell, Larry Hopkins</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18745">Ratchet: Deadlocked</game><game id="18309">Ratchet &amp; Clank</game><game id="7380">Crash Bandicoot</game><game id="7836">Spyro the Dragon</game><game id="15835">Beyond Good &amp; Evil</game><game id="68">Crash Bandicoot: The Wrath of Cortex</game><game id="15212">Ratchet &amp; Clank Future: Tools of Destruction</game><game id="13992">Uncharted: Drake's Fortune</game><game id="3438">MediEvil II</game><game id="4228">Haven: Call of the King</game><game id="11407">Vexx</game><game id="16337">Sly 3: Honor Among Thieves</game><game id="15353">Sly Cooper and the Thievius Raccoonus</game><game id="15573">Sly 2: Band of Thieves</game><game id="1563">Spyro 2: Ripto's Rage</game><game id="6134">The Legend of Spyro: The Eternal Night</game><game id="3457">MediEvil</game><game id="7804">Rocket: Robot on Wheels</game><game id="20330">Gex 3: Deep Cover Gecko</game><game id="15991">Chameleon Twist 2</game><game id="4618">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Going Commando</game><game id="4966">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Up Your Arsenal</game><game id="18376">Looney Tunes Back in Action</game><game id="1850">Ninja Gaiden III: The Ancient Ship of Doom</game><game id="12909">Crash Bandicoot: Warped</game><game id="14790">Crash Twinsanity</game><game id="9523">Sonic Heroes</game><game id="581">SpongeBob SquarePants: The Movie</game><game id="21115">Ratchet &amp; Clank Future: Quest for Booty</game><game id="14582">Legend of Kay</game><game id="609">Rayman 2: The Great Escape</game><game id="25673">Ratchet &amp; Clank Future: A Crack in Time</game><game id="26496">Agent Hugo: Lemoon Twist</game><game id="2906">Psychonauts</game><game id="30746">Ruff Trigger: The Vanocore Conspiracy</game><game id="32361">Ratchet &amp; Clank: All 4 One</game><game id="20406">Smuggler's Run</game><game id="35559">Sly Cooper: Thieves in Time</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1897527-box_jak3.png</image></root>