<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9730</id><name>The Simpsons: Bart vs. the Juggernauts</name><description>Bart vs. The Juggernauts is a 1992                 Game Boy game developed by  Imageneering and published by                  Acclaim. The game is a                parody of the television show               American Gladiators. The game consists of seven different events which showcase a variety of locations from the show and include several other characters from the show.EventsDr. Marvin Monroe's Hop, Skip and FryThe first event is a makeshift game of              basketball where          Bart must score baskets against the Juggernauts while avoiding electrified panels on the floor.Captain Murdock's Skateboard Bash and CrashHere, Bart starts at the top of a             giant ramp and skateboards down it, attempting to gain enough speed while avoiding obstacles to clear the gap and knock the Juggernaut on the other side off his post.Nuclear Power Plant Bop `Till You DropThis event takes place in the            nuclear plant where           Homer works and places both Bart and a Juggernaut on separate platforms over a pit of nuclear waste.  The goal of this event is to knock off the Juggernaut using padded batons. Moe's Tavern Shove FestBart is found at Moe's         bar and must engage a female juggernaut and Barny Gumbel in a good old fashioned shove match.  The last man (or woman) on the mat is the winner.Herman’s Military Minefield MayhemNext Bart is forced to       parachute past a flurry of flying knives and navigate a    mine field covered in  bared wire in an obstacle course from   hell.The Krustyland Hammer SlammerIn this event, Bart must attempt to knock the Juggernauts from their platforms by taking a running start and hitting the tower hard enough to sound the bell at the top and send the Juggernauts to the ground.The Kwik-E-Mart Doggie DodgeBart finds himself in the Kwik-E-Mart and must run around the level gathering food items while avoid rabid dogs that are chasing him.  After collecting enough food, Bart must make a dash to the      cash register to complete the challenge.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="3">Sports</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="346">American Gladiators</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/6/60173/1477594-26b73478c791649df260682dc23687b4_the_simpsons__bart_vs_the_juggernauts.jpg</image></root>