<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9883</id><name>Deus Ex: Invisible War</name><description>PlotDeus Ex: Invisible War starts twenty years after the original Deus Ex. You are placed in a world that is recovering from a catastrophic event called the Collapse. The story starts just after a terrorist attack that destroys the city of Chicago. You take the role of Alex D., who is a trainee at the Tarsus Academy. As you progress through the story Alex learns that there are conspiratorial groups who seek to change the world dramatically. Also, as you play, certain events can be influenced by your actions.GameplayLike the prequel, Invisible War is a first-person game. The game combines elements from a range of genres including stealth and shooter. Deus Ex: Invisible War emphasizes player choice, depending on your gender some of the quests and dialogues are varied, the developers designed the game in this way so the player has a choice in a situation. An example of this is when you have to somehow commandeer an airship, you have three choices: you can bribe the guard with money, attack him, or try to sneak past him. Alex D. can be equipped with microscopic implants called bio-mods, which grant special abilities such as invisibility or increased strength. Alex D. has 5 slots where you can hold the bio-mods. Every bio-mod can be upgraded twice, enhancing their effects.The gameplay dynamics have suffered vastly compared to the original. In addition to pooled ammo (all guns use the same ammunition), there are more fetch quests and diplomatic options than the previous game. While you never form an actual alliance with any organization, you can choose which groups you want to assist.The game cannot decide whether it wants to keep the dystopian feel of the original Deus Ex with levels consisting of bright, colourful scenery contrasted with hints in the story of a suffering world at the brink of social and economic collapse.Organizations and FactionsThe WTO - The most prominent of new establishments in the game. Primarily focused on the achievement of political and economic recovery in North America, Europe, and Asia. The WTO works with local established governments to help establish urban growth, stability, as well as a global information network.The Order - The order is a religious group, they are dedicated to personal fulfillment through non material means, and are very protective of the natural state of humankind and the environment. In addition to being naturalists, the Order is a culmination of every major religion on Earth.Tarsus - Tarsus Academies is a very exclusive global chain of schools that along with advanced academics also has physical, technological, psychological, and weapons focused educations. Each student is matched with an anonymous corporate sponsor, revealed only to them upon graduation.The Templars - The Templars are a group dedicated to the eradication of human biotechnology. They believe themselves to be a modern incarnation of the "Knights of the Templar" made famous from the Crusades. They advocate 'genetic purity' and oppose and form human tampering through bio-modification. They are an evolution of the Purity First movement from the superior prequel, Deus Ex: Human Revolution.The Omar - The Omar are a worldwide cult of cyborgs, whose primary interest is transcending human limitations through the use of technology. In addition to being avid merchants, the Omar are always seeking ways to improve upon the modification and adaptation methods.Mission LocationsSeattleCairoTrierAntarcticaLiberty IslandWeaponsCombat KnifeCrowbarEnergy BladeRiot Control BatonStun ProdBallistic PistolBoltcasterMag RailShotgunSMGSniper RifleFlamethrowerRocket LauncherGrenades (Concussion, EMP, Phosphorous, Noisemaker, Gas, Flash, Scrambler, Spiderbomb)Mines (Concussion, EMP, Scrambler)Assassin PistolDragon Tooth SwordHellfire BoltcasterRed Greasel HunterToxin BladeWidowmaker SMGAugmentations/BiomodsLocationStandard BiomodBlack Market BiomodEyeRegenerationVision EnhancementSpy DroneCranialCloakHazard DroneNeural InterfaceSkeletalAggressive Defense DroneThermal MaskingElectrostatic DischargeArmsBiotoxin Attack DroneStrength EnhancementBot DominationLegsMove SilentSpeed EnhancementHealth Leech DroneSoundtrackThe soundtrack was composed by Alexander Brandon and Todd Simmons"Invisible War Title Theme" – 01:51"Seattle – Tarsus Apartments" – 02:32"Seattle – City Hub and Emerald Suites" – 02:55"Seattle – Mako Ballistics Interior" – 02:21"Seattle – Lower Seattle and Heron's Loft" – 02:34"Cairo – Mosque" – 02:24"Cairo – ApostleCorp Lab" – 02:21"Trier – Streets and Black Gate" – 02:59"Trier – Templar Compound" – 02:48"Antarctica – VersaLife Base Exterior" – 02:19"Antarctica – JC Denton's Lair" – 02:20"Return to Cairo – Shantytown and Arcology" – 03:05"Liberty Island – Statue Exterior" – 03:30"Credits" – 01:34System RequirementsMinimum:IBM PC or 100% compatibleMicrosoft Windows 2000/XPPentium IV, 1.3GHz (Or AMD Athlon XP equivalent) processor100% DirectX 9 32MB 3D Accelerated video card with Pixel Shader v1.1 Capability256 MB System RAM100% DirectX 9 Compatible Sound Card2GB free uncompressed hard drive space (additional space may be necessary for saved games)100% Windows 2000/XP compatible Mouse and KeyboardRecommended:Pentium IV, 1.5 Ghz (or AMD Athlon XPequivalent) or greater processor512 MB System RAM100% DirectX 9 128MB 3D Graphics Card2GB of Hard Drive SpaceSupported Video Chipsets: NVidia GeForce 3Ti/4Ti/FX - Note: GeForce MX series is NOT SUPPORTED. ATI Radeon 8500/9xxx or higher.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8870">System Shock 2</game><game id="9258">Neocron 2: Beyond Dome of York</game><game id="11085">The Chronicles of Riddick: Escape from Butcher Bay</game><game id="16426">Vampire: The Masquerade - Bloodlines</game><game id="2335">Thief: Deadly Shadows</game><game id="4523">Thief: The Dark Project</game><game id="7787">Thief II: The Metal Age</game><game id="11725">S.T.A.L.K.E.R.: Shadow of Chernobyl</game><game id="10565">Strife</game><game id="13948">System Shock</game><game id="21256">Perfect Dark</game><game id="21912">Planetside: Core Combat</game><game id="21302">S.T.A.L.K.E.R.: Clear Sky</game><game id="20504">Fallout 3</game><game id="3857">Project: Snowblind</game><game id="21549">White Gold: War in Paradise</game><game id="12203">Red Faction II</game><game id="20987">The Chronicles of Riddick: Assault on Dark Athena</game><game id="4301">Area-51</game><game id="8580">Jade Empire</game><game id="23471">Prey 2</game><game id="29717">E.Y.E: Divine Cybermancy</game><game id="38456">Cyberpunk 2077</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15693/622641-528588_50970_front_1_.jpg</image></root>