<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9913</id><name>Casino FunPak</name><description>Overview Casino FunPak is a casino game that features five different casino games. The player starts out Casino FunPak with a stock of $10,000. If the player busts out and loses all the money, the game will be taken back to the main menu.GameplayCasino Games: Craps Table  Craps  In Craps the A button is used to set the bet at the beginning of the game. There is no limit to the size of the bet, and the bet goes up one dollar at a time. Once the bet amount has been set, the B button is then used to put the chips on whatever is being bet on. The start button will go back to setting the bet amount. CrapsVideo Slot Machines  Video Slot Machines  In video slots the A button is used to set the amount of the bet at the beginning of the game. The maximum bet size is the amount of money currently on hand and the bet is set five dollars at a time. After the bet amount has been set the hand icon must be moved over to the coin slot and the A button pressed. After the coins have been put into the slot the handle can also be pulled using the A button.Video SlotsVideo Poker Machines  Video Poker  In video Poker the A button is used to set the bet amount. The maximum bet amount is the amount of money the player has on hand and the bet goes up by five dollars at a time. After the bet amount has been set the hand icon must be placed over the coin slot and the A button pushed. Once the money has been inserted into the machine the "deal" button on the screen can be pressed. Once the cards have been dealt the cards selected will be the cards held. Video PokerRoulette Table  Roulette  In Roulette the A button is used to set the bet amount. There is no maximum bet and the bet goes up by one dollar at a time. The A button is then used to put the bet amount down on the betting space the player wishes to bet on. Once all the bets have been set the spin button is pushed to spin the Roulette wheel.RouletteBlack Jack  Black Jack  In Black Jack the bet amount is set using the A button. There is no limit to the bet amount and the bets go up by one dollar each. Black Jack</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22987">Fable II Pub Games</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/10/103881/1745923-cf1.jpg</image></root>