<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>993</id><name>Okage: Shadow King</name><description>PlotOkage Shadow King begins with an over shadowed boy named Ari (Default name of the character in the beginning of the game, you can customize his name in the beginning). One night on the day of the circus your sister goes on a date with her boyfriend.  A ghost attacks her and she becomes cursed making her speak pig latin. Ari and his family are then forced to save her from this terrible disaster by opening up a lantern/pot to bring out Stan the evil king to cure the girl's problem. He does but Ari has to help the evil king on a quest to conquer the "Fake evil Kings" and gain their power to rule the world. On the adventure Ari meets new people along the way adding up to the party such as Rosalyn a knight who was made fun of because of her pink shadow this is no coincidence however as stan did it just like Ari's sister.Characters Ari Ari:This boy named Ari is the person you will be playing as through out the game. His name by default is Ari. He is a 16 year old boy that will encounter many bosses and friends as you play the game.               StanStan:Your shadow has been cursed to save your little sister's life, and now you have to deal with this shadow. As you keep on playing the game you will notice that Stan-does not-like to agree with people unless they are the exact thoughts of what he thinks or wants.                 Rosalyn:This woman was cursed by stan the evil king, now she is laughed at cause she has a pink shadow and was stripped of her high rank in society. She has a stubborn attitude sometimes but can give a good idea on the situation. She saved you from ghosts several times and is said to double the amount of ghosts near by when she is in your party. She always fights with stan over who is better and can blabber on non stop 24/7 with stan about how being a hero is better than a villain. Though hardheaded she is a good addition to your party.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23905">Ushiro</game><game id="16836">Shin Megami Tensei: Nocturne</game><game id="4473">Shin Megami Tensei: Persona 3</game><game id="21373">Shin Megami Tensei: Persona 4</game><game id="3755">Persona 2: Innocent Sin</game><game id="5495">Persona 2: Eternal Punishment</game><game id="27861">Shin Megami Tensei: Persona 3 Portable</game><game id="34918">Sagashi ni Ikouyo</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2428413-box_okagesk.png</image></root>