<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9951</id><name>UEFA Champions League 2006-2007</name><description>Game FeaturesPS2/PC/PSPThe Treble - You play as a manager of a club for one season with one goal, to get the treble. You play through your club domestic league and domestic cup aswell as the UEFA Champions League.Ultimate Challenge (PS2 and PC only) - You recreate some of the most famous matches in the champions league history. UEFA Champions league tournament - Play through your own champions league with any club from the group stages to the final.Online Head-to-Head - Using ad-hoc or Infrastructure (PSP) or going online (PS2 or PC), you can play against other players.The Quiz - the Quiz tests your football knowledge as you progress through the ever more challenging stages of the UEFA Champions League.Xbox 360Ultimate Team Mode - Build your Ultimate Team by collecting player, staff and gameplay cards. You can trade any cards in your collection with other players using Xbox Live.Take on the World's Best - Using any team or your ultimate team, you manager them to make it to the top.UEFA Champions League Challenge - You recreate some of the most famous matches in the champions league history.UEFA Champions league tournament - Play through your own champions league with any club from the group stages to the final.SoundtrackAndy Caldwell feat. Gina Rene - Runaway - Universal Truth Baïkonour - Jain Rock - Topo Gigio vs. Baïkonour Bonobo feat. Bajka - Nightlite - Days To Come Brazilian Girls - Le Territoire - Talk To La Bomb Cal Tjader - Mambo Mindoro (Hex Hector Remix) - Explorations Champion - Two Hoboes - Chill' em all Osunlade - Two Phish - Aquarian Moon Ray Barretto - Work Song (Thievery Corporation Remix) - Explorations Thunderball feat. Miss Johnna M. - Chicachiquita - Cinescope</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="40">Soccer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13165">Pro Evolution Soccer 2008</game><game id="1787">FIFA World Cup: Germany 2006</game><game id="2100">Pro Evolution Soccer 5</game><game id="37">FIFA Soccer 07</game><game id="9171">FIFA Soccer 06</game><game id="18564">FIFA Soccer 2005</game><game id="20798">UEFA Euro 2008</game><game id="21030">FIFA Soccer 09</game><game id="26702">FIFA 10</game><game id="25791">Pro Evolution Soccer 2010</game><game id="27038">FIFA 06: Road To FIFA World Cup</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/18185/683633-champions_league.jpg</image></root>