<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9981</id><name>MX vs. ATV Unleashed</name><description>Gameplay This game has a variety of indoor and outdoor tracks filled with different sets of jumps and turns to push you to the highest level.  This game tries to make you find what the fastest and smoothest way around each track is and to master the clutch to get you around the track in the best way.  This game has third person view while you are racing with many other angles as well. It also has first person view which attempts to make you feel like you are really on the dirt bike or four wheeler because the camera for first person is in the helmet so the handlebars and wheels are right where they should be.  There are freestyle tracks that are open and ready to be torn up to do all the crazy tricks you want.  There are many different game types such as supercross, motocross, short tracks, hill climb, waypoint, and open class which means all types of vehicles can be racing each other at the same time. Multiplayer The multiplayer allows you to get online and play with people from across the world or just a system link or split screen match with a couple of friends.   Soundtrack    Ozomatli - Saturday Night   Skindred - Nobody   Phunk Junkeez - Magnetic Mic Control   Pillar - Bring Me Down   Strung Out - Analog   Powerman 5000 - Heroes And Villains   Trust Company - Stronger   Unwritten Law - Celebration Song   Bullets And Octane - Pirates   Rise Against - Give It All   Earshot - Wait   Black Eyed Peas - Anxiety   Riddlin Kids - Stop The World   Crossfade - Cold   Shinedown - Fly From The Inside   Kottonmuth Kings - Let's Ride   Mudmen - Animal   Authority Zero - Revolution   Nickelback - Because Of You   Papa Roach - Getting Away With Murder       Vehicles  Dirt bike ATV Trophy trucks Plane Helicopter Monster trucks Dune buggy Golf cart  Characters MX Riders   Jeremy McGrath James Stewart Jr. Chad Reed Dave Teodosio Kevin Windham Mike LaRocco Michael Byrne Sebastien Tortelli Josh Grant Ivan Tedesco Broc Hepler Josh Hansen Bobby Hochrun Nathan Ramsey  ATV Riders    Dave Teodosio   Tim Farr   Keith Little   Jason Dunkelberger   Jason Luburgh   Tavis Cain   Dana Creech   Jeremiah Jones   Doug Gust   Shane Hitt   John Natalie Jr.   Kory Ellis   Joe Byrd    </description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6787">Supercross Circuit</game><game id="22272">Super Off Road: The Baja</game><game id="20933">Baja: Edge of Control</game><game id="20957">Pure</game><game id="22065">ATV Offroad Fury 4</game><game id="19180">Motocross Madness 2</game><game id="24793">MotorStorm</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2210193-box_mxvsatvunl.png</image></root>