<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10037</id><name>Bullet Witch</name><description>OverviewBullet Witch is third-person action/shooter for the Xbox 360 developed by cavia, inc. It was first released in Japan on the 27th July, 2006 by publisher AQ Interactive and then on February 27th, 2007 in North America. A number of downloadable missions and costumes were later made available via Xbox Live, though in Japan the game was later re-released under the "Xbox 360 Platinum Collection" label with all downloadable content included on the disc.GameplayThe game centres on a young witch named Alicia as she attempts to rid the world of a demon army known as the Geist. The world's population has been slaughtered at the hands of demon army and mankind is on the brink of destruction. Wielding a magic weapon known as the gunrod, and a variety of spells, Alicia endeavours to save the world from the Geist.Weapons listAlicia has access to four different weapons through her gunrod that she can switch between at will during play. Each of the four weapons has different stats and after each level the player can upgrade them using skill points to a maximum level of three. As the weapon's level is raised, the amount of damage it does is increased, as well as the amount of points needed to upgrade it further.MachinegunShotgunCannon (Sniper Rifle)Gatling (Minigun)Magic ListIn a similar fashion to the gunrod, most of the magic spells can also be upgraded, with each having a maximum level of three. The upgrades can dramatically increase a spell's damage, duration, or range. It should be noted that the greater spells (Lightning, Tornado and Meteor) cannot be upgraded and must be unlocked by progressing through the game.Elemental ShotAncient WallRose SpearWillpowerSacrificeRavens PanicLightningTornadoMeteorStory MissionsClad in Streaming BlackThe City of Screams10,000 Feet of FlameDawn in the ValleyThe Bound SoulThe End of ChaosSoundtrackDusk (3:10)System Menu (2:42)Geist (4:26)Despair (3:58)Result (1:50)Gigas (3:21)Dauntless (3:31)Insane (1:42)Crisis Intro (0:23)Crisis (2:03)Disaster (1:09)Past Days (1:53)Eerie (2:22)Alicia (1:53)Demon Intro (0:40)Demon (3:11)Defeat (0:59)Dawn (2:41)The Vanishing Sky (2:38)Bullet Witch (4:28)Voices from Hell (0:57) (Bonus Track)Xbox 360 Game InstallationBullet Witch requires 5.2GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD.</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20710">Bayonetta</game><game id="1636">BloodRayne 2</game><game id="16437">BloodRayne</game><game id="22999">Onechanbara: Bikini Samurai Squad</game><game id="9037">Gungrave</game><game id="36285">Onechanbara Z: Kagura</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2133339-box_bwitch.png</image></root>