<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10084</id><name>Mario Kart 64</name><description>OverviewThe game's title screen.Mario Kart 64 is a Mario themed go-kart racing game developed by Nintendo for the Nintendo 64, released in 1996. It is the sequel to Super Mario Kart for the SNES and features characters and track locations from the Mario universe. Mario Kart 64 made the leap from Mode 7 to full 3D computer graphics, which allowed for complex track designs. The characters, however, remain 2-dimensional sprites. The game was a huge success, selling millions of copies and eventually became a Player's Choice title.GameplayBowser in Mario Kart 64Mario Kart 64 can be a simple racer in order to appeal to a casual player, but offers more advanced techniques to keep a more experienced player interested. At its most bare-bones, Mario Kart 64 only requires the player to press the accelerate button to drive and use the analog control stick to control the kart's direction. More experienced players will be able to use drifting and Mario themed weapons and items such as Turtle Shells and Mushroom Boosts to get the advantage over their opponents. Items are scattered in rainbow colored boxes across each track and as the items in each box are random and potentially very powerful, they add a certain level of uncertainty to each race. The drifting mechanic is performed by hopping and turning in mid air which allows a player to take sharp turns without losing speed, and if done correctly one can obtain a speed boost.The game is separated into four play types, Grand Prix, Versus, Battle, and Time Trial. In each of these modes you choose from 16 race tracks and 8 playable racers, each of which have different attributes such as speed, acceleration, and weight. These attributes affect how each character handles. The Grand Prix mode has four difficulties, 50cc, 100cc, 150cc, and Extra, each progressively faster with more difficult opponents, or in the case of Extra, mirrored versions of all of the tracks. The 16 tracks are divided into 4 cups, and you are tasked with racing these cups to win trophies. If you achieve all gold trophies in all the cups in each difficulty, you are rewarded with a new title screen. Versus and Battle mode allow players to compete with up to four of their friends via split screen. Versus allows friends to race together on any of the single player tracks, and battle allow players to fight in large arenas using items. Time Trial has a player racing against the clock. This mode will display a " ghost" of your best time, which is a translucent recording of your previous best lap.CharactersThe playable characters are:LightweightPlayer select screenToadPrincess PeachYoshiMiddleweightMarioLuigiHeavyweightDonkey KongWarioBowserLightweight racers have quick acceleration and excellent handling, but have slow top speeds and are easily knocked around. Middleweight racers are good all around racers with middle of the road attributes. Heavyweight racers have high top speeds and are very difficult to bully, but have slow acceleration and can be difficult to handle.An early version of the game featured the character Magikoopa instead of Donkey Kong.TracksThe 16 tracks in Mario Kart 64 are:Mushroom CupSherbet LandLuigi Raceway - A simple course that slightly resembles a Nascar track.Moo Moo Farm - A bumpy dirt course that circles a farm pasture. Watch out for jumping Monty Moles.Koopa Troopa Beach - A sandy beach island course. A rocky interior is to one side and the ocean to the other.Kalimari Desert - This course is a desert course that weaves across train tracks. Make sure to stop for trains.Flower CupToad's Turnpike - A simple freeway made difficult by oncoming traffic. Avoid getting hit at all cost.Frappe Snowland - A snowscape littered with explosive snowmen and thick snow dunes.Choco Mountain - Race along chocolate cliff overhangs and dodge falling boulders.Mario Raceway - A twisty thin track with piranha plants and a huge green pipe tunnel.Star CupRainbow Road from Mario Kart 64Wario Stadium - Resembles a dirt bike race course. Many great jumps and full of shortcuts.Sherbet Land - An ice course around a freezing lake. Avoid the sledding penguins big and small.Royal Raceway - Windy and thin asphalt course. Watch for the hidden Mario 64 castle.Bowsers Castle - Filled with menacing traps and hazards.Special CupDK's Jungle Parkway - A Jungle course with a large jump across a river. Watch out for the ferry.Yoshi Valley - A thin twisting multi-path course. It has many bottomless pits.Banshee Boardwalk - A rickety wooden course with ghosts and a haunted house full of bats.Rainbow Road - A long course in space made of rainbows. SoundtracksMario Kart 64 Race TracksThe soundtracks to Mario Kart 64 were composed by Kenta Nagata.Mario Kart 64 Greatest Hits SoundtrackReleased: March 1st, 1997Total length: 31:44Mario Kart 64 ThemeCircuit SelectMoo Moo FarmKoopa Troopa BeachFrappe SnowlandKoopa CastleKalimari DesertRainbow RoadDK's Jungle ParkwayToad's TurnpikeBattle 1Results ThemeTrophy PresentationVictory LapMario Kart 64 TracksMario Kart 64 Theme3 Raceways/Wario StadiumMoo Moo Farm/Yoshi ValleyKoopa Troopa BeachKalimari DesertToad's TurnpikeFrappe Snowland/Sherbet LandChoco Mountain/Battle ArenasKoopa CastleDK's Jungle ParkBanshee BoardwalkRainbow RoadStar PowerSetup and Kart SelectBattle ArenasWinning ResultsLosing ResultsTime Trial ResultsTrophy PresentationsNo Trophy for You!Victory LapBonus TracksStart Your EnginesFinish TrialFinal LapFinish FirstFinish OKFinish OutFinish LastVoice CollectionReceptionMario Kart 64 initially received relatively positive reviews. Some reviewers found fault with the gameplay depth and single-player experience, but rated it fairly well overall. Commercially Mario Kart 64 is one of the most successful Mario Kart games in the series. It sold 5.5 million copies in the US and 2.24 million in Japan. </description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15990">Diddy Kong Racing</game><game id="2278">Crash Nitro Kart</game><game id="11174">LEGO Racers</game><game id="4902">Mad Dash Racing</game><game id="20906">Cocoto Kart Racer</game><game id="24733">NASCAR Kart Racing</game><game id="25026">MySims Racing</game><game id="18808">F-Zero X</game><game id="25772">Cro Mag Rally</game><game id="689">Jak X: Combat Racing</game><game id="20135">POD SpeedZone</game><game id="13772">Ostrich Runner</game><game id="28027">Krazy Kart Racing</game><game id="14384">Woody Woodpecker Racing</game><game id="29220">Zero Gear</game><game id="26792">Kinect Joy Ride</game><game id="12544">Wacky Wheels</game><game id="1316">R.C. Pro-Am II</game><game id="25961">Blur</game><game id="32225">Crash Bandicoot Nitro Kart 2</game><game id="2260">Sonic R</game><game id="4515">RC Revenge</game><game id="32330">TNT Racers</game><game id="7440">Power Drift</game><game id="1145">Pokémon Dash</game><game id="14277">Banjo-Pilot</game><game id="34493">Mayhem</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2261111-box_mk64.png</image></root>