<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10122</id><name>Pokémon Ruby/Sapphire</name><description>PlotPokémon Ruby title screenPokémon Ruby and Sapphire are the twin titles of the 3rd generation in classic Pokémon fare. They follow the established formula with a young boy or girl starting their own quest to become the Pokémon Champion by battling their way through the region's gyms and finally facing the Elite Four.Along the way they must also thwart the evil Team Magma (in Ruby version) or Team Aqua (in Sapphire version), who seek to awaken one of the legendary Pokemon to expand either the earth or the sea, and allows you the player to come in contact with one of the ancient legendary pokémon, Kyogre or Groudon.GameplayTreecko, one of the new Pokémon added to the Hoenn Region.The game follows a simple turn-based RPG system, that is unique in that you can acquire your party members from battling and capturing them. You travel the world escorted by a team of up to six creatures that you swap out and train for new attacks and tactics. The battles themselves are a turn based affair with the trainer able to use items to bolster the team or catch new Pokémon.Additions from previous generations include new Pokémon to catch, battling with 2 creatures at a time in special 2-on-2 battles with other trainers, and there is a new gadget called the Pokénav, replacing the PokéGear from the previous generation.New featuresBattle mechanics2-on-2 Pokemon BattleIn certain situations, trainers may now participate in double-battles, using 2 of their Pokémon versus 2 of an opponents. This was a first in the series. Pokémon may choose which enemy to use a move on, and certain moves may affect both combatants.Abilities and NaturesPokemon Contest ConditionAbilities are now present in all Pokémon, and have effects both inside and outside of battle. Examples include lowering the foes attack (Intimidate) or increasing the power of Grass moves (Overgrow).Natures were also introduced in this game. They affect a pokémon's stats. An example would be the Hasty nature.This nature is beneficial to a Pokémon's speed in the long run, while hindering its defense stat. Natures also affect which Pokéblock a Pokémon will love and hateike or dislike.Pokemon ContestsPokemon ContestsThese are contests in the game that allow Trainers to display their best breed of Pokemon.Ribbons from a victorious ContestantAll the moves in the game are used, but are categorized within 5 types; Cool, Beauty, Smart, Cute, and Tough. All corresponding types are designated to specific contest judging.The objective is to impress the judge the most in 2 forms; sheen, and move appeal. Sheen is determined by what Pokéblocks are eaten, which can raise the required quality of sheen in that stat area. The second way is through Appeals, which are taken in turns, to earn hearts from appealing. the one collecting the most stars wins.Secret BasesFortree City's surroundings is teeming with basesSecret bases are what they say; a secret base away from home that you can decorate with many different items. It also draws on a concept first seen in Gold and Silver,Secret Base display of goodswhereby upon completing the main story, you can battle your friends' teams for experience points, money, and you can get Pokedex sight entries at their secret bases.Linking with a friend and mixing records gives you a copy of their secret base for you to access. also, Secret bases can be made using the move Secret Power (TM 10) in holes in walls, piles of grass, or certain trees.LegendariesThe Legendary Pokémon available without special events are:GroudonRayquaza, a Dragon/Flying type at level 70.Regice, Ice type at level 40.Regirock, Rock type at level 40.Registeel, Steel type at level 40.Ruby version only:Latios, Dragon/Psychic at level 40.Groudon, Ground type at level 45.Sapphire version only:Latias, a Dragon/Psychic at level 40Kyogre, Water type at level 45.Special Event Legendary PokémonJirachiLatios/ Latias - You can catch the opposite Lati@s to that roaming in the game if you have an Eon Ticket.Jirachi - Found in Pokemon Colosseum Bonus Disc at Level 5, or at Nintendo Event.Deoxys - Found in Nintendo Event.PokedexThe Pokédex of Pokémon Ruby/Sapphire/Emerald includes all the Pokémon from the previous two games (once the national dex is unlocked).Hoenn PokedexThe first 151 Pokémon are listed in the Pokémon Red/Blue Pokédex section. Pokémon 152 to 251 are listed in Pokémon Gold/Silver's Pokédex section.All Pokémon new to Ruby/Sapphire are listed below, with the National Dex Number on the left, and Hoenn Dex on the right. Entries from previous generations have their national dex set as blank.252/001 Treecko253/002 Grovyle254/003 Sceptile255/004 Torchic256/005 Combusken257/006 Blaziken258/007 Mudkip259/008 Marshtomp260/009 Swampert261/010 Poochyena262/011 Mightyena263/012 Zigzagoon264/013 Linoone265/014 Wurmple266/015 Silcoon267/016 Beautifly268/017 Cascoon269/018 Dustox270/019 Lotad (Sapphire only)271/020 Lombre (Sapphire only)Ralts, a rare psychic type native to both versions.272/021 Ludicolo (Sapphire Only)273/022 Seedot (Ruby only)274/023 Nuzleaf (Ruby only)275/024 Shiftry (Ruby Only)276/025 Taillow277/026 Swellow278/027 Wingull279/028 Pelipper280/029 Ralts281/030 Kirlia282/031 Gardevoir283/032 Surskit284/033 Masquerain285/034 Shroomish286/035 Breloom287/036 Slakoth288/037 Vigoroth289/038 Slaking---/039 Abra---/040 Kadabra---/041 Alakazam290/042 Nincada291/043 NinjaskShedinja, a peculiar Pokemon that originated from Nincada.292/044 Shedinja293/045 Whismur294/046 Loudred295/047 Exploud296/048 Makuhita297/049 Hariyama---/050 Goldeen---/051 Seaking---/052 Magikarp---/053 Gyarados298/054 Azurill---/055 Marill---/056 Azumarill---/057 Geodude---/058 Graveler---/059 Golem299/060 Nosepass300/061 Skitty301/062 Delcatty---/063 ZubatSableye, a Ghost/Dark Pokemon exclusive to Sapphire Version.---/064 Golbat---/065 Crobat---/066 Tentacool---/067 Tentacruel302/068 Sableye (Sapphire only)303/069 Mawile (Ruby only)304/070 Aron305/071 Lairon306/072 Aggron---/073 Machop---/074 Machoke---075 Machamp307/076 Meditite308/077 Medicham309/078 ElectrikeManectric, the Thunder Lion.310/079 Manectric311/080 Plusle312/081 Minun---/082 Magnemite---/083 Magneton---/084 Voltorb---/085 Electrode313/086 Volbeat314/087 Illumise---/088 Oddish---/089 Gloom---/090 Vileplume---/091 Bellossom---/092 Doduo---/093 Dodrio315/094 Roselia316/095 Gulpin317/096 Swalot318/097 Carvanha319/098 Sharpedo320/099 Wailmer321/100 Wailord322/101 Numel323/102 CameruptSlugma, one of the Pokemon first seen in Johto.---/103 Slugma---/104 Magcargo324/105 Torkoal---/106 Grimer---/107 Muk---/108 Koffing---/109 Weezing325/110 Spoink326/111 Grumpig---/112 Sandshrew---/113 Sandslash327/114 Spinda---/115 Skarmoury328/116 Trapinch329/117 Vibrava330/118 Flygon331/119 Cacnea332/120 Cacturne333/121 Swablu334/122 AltariaZangoose, one of the Pokemon exclusive to Ruby Version.335/123 Zangoose (Ruby only)336/124 Seviper (Sapphire only)337/125 Lunatone (Sapphire only)338/126 Solrock (Ruby only)339/127 Barboach340/128 Whiscash341/129 Corphish342/130 Crawdaunt343/131 Baltoy344/132 Claydol345/133 Lileep346/134 Cradily347/135 Anorith348/136 Armaldo---/137 Igglybuff---/138 Jigglypuff---/139 Wigglytuff349/140 Feebas350/141 MiloticCastform, a Pokemon that changes with the weather.351/142 Castform---/143 Staryu---/144 Starmie352/145 Kecleon353/146 Shuppet354/147 Banette355/148 Duskull356/149 Dusclops357/150 Tropius358/151 Chimecho359/152 Absol---/153 Vulpix---/154 Ninetales---/155 PichuPikachu, one of the original generation of Pokemon available in the game.---/156 Pikachu---/157 Raichu---/158 Psyduck---/159 Golduck360/160 Wynaut---/161 Wobbuffet---/162 Natu---/163 Xatu---/164 Girafarig---/165 Phanpy---/166 Donphan---/167 Pinsir---/168 Heracross---/169 Rhyhorn---/170 Rhydon361/171 Snorunt362/172 Glalie363/173 Spheal364/174 Sealeo365/175 Walrein366/176 Clamperl367/177 Huntail368/178 Gorebyss369/179 Relicanth---/180 Corsola---/181 Chinchou---/182 LanturnRelicanth, an ancient Pokemon found at the bottom of the sea.370/183 Luvdisc---/184 Horsea---/185 Seadra---/186 Kingdra371/187 Bagon372/188 Shelgon373/189 Salamence374/190 Beldum375/191 Metang376/192 Metagross377/193 Regirock378/194 RegiceThe Legendary Regice of the Regi Trio379/195 Registeel380/196 Latias (Sapphire only)381/197 Latios (Ruby Only)382/198 Kyogre (Sapphire Only)383/199 Groudon (Ruby only)384/200 Rayquaza385/201 Jirachi (event only)386/202 Deoxys (event only)</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18602">Spectrobes</game><game id="10950">Dokapon</game><game id="23117">Robopon 2: Cross/Ring Version</game><game id="23128">Robopon: Sun Version</game><game id="8307">EarthBound</game><game id="2731">Mega Man Zero</game><game id="26576">Shaman King: Legacy of the Spirits, Sprinting Wolf</game><game id="26575">Shaman King: Legacy of the Spirits, Soaring Hawk</game><game id="6557">Revelations: Persona</game><game id="24009">Dragon Quest Monsters 1 &amp; 2</game><game id="13470">Dragon Warrior Monsters</game><game id="8048">Dragon Warrior Monsters 2</game><game id="6632">Dragon Quest Monsters: Joker</game><game id="24011">Dragon Quest Monsters: Caravan Heart</game><game id="27048">Fossil Fighters</game><game id="21079">Dinosaur King</game><game id="23375">Gangway Monsters</game><game id="33000">Shin Megami Tensei: Persona 2 - Innocent Sin</game><game id="3879">Digimon World 3</game><game id="40424">Keitai Denjuu Telefang 2</game><game id="39473">Dragon Fantasy: Book II</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/17172/1255532-pkmnrubysapphire.png</image></root>