<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10186</id><name>Resident Evil: Director's Cut</name><description>OverviewResident Evil: Director's Cut is the re-release of the original   PlayStation classic title,                         Resident Evil. This version released 18 months after the original and featured some new elements. The major feature added was the additional game mode, arrange game, in which the main quest items and weapons and such had been moved around. This made for an all new experience, and challenged series veterans all over again. The characters in the new mode (    Chris Redfield and                       Jill Valentine) also wore different costumes, and had come equip with a custom Beretta M9 handgun. This mode was much harder and spared less ammo. The Director's Cut edition had two discs, with one being a full demo of the upcoming sequel,                   Resident Evil 2, that    Capcom had to delay at the time. The main purpose of the Director's Cut edition was in fact to tide fans over due to the rather large delay. This version of the game hit America in September of 1997, and had a slightly different cover shot. In 1998 the "Greatest Hits" version of Resident Evil: Director's Cut released at a discounted price and featured completely brand new cover art, with a bloody faced zombie looking over his shoulder.    Greatest Hits Version The rest of the game remains largely the same game as the one released in 1996. Players choose between two protagonists and approach a similar single player experience with minor changes in dialogue, items, weapons and visited areas. This game was said to be the first survival horror (with the exception of the                      Alone in the Dark games), and forced gamers to conserve ammo and explore dangerous areas full of infected humans and animals. Resident Evil mainly takes place in                  Raccoon City, on the outskirts of the town in the mountain region just outside of the uptown district. Here, the founder of Umbrella Corporation, had an estate where he lived before the Umbrella corp. took off. In this game world, this company is massive to the point it has it's own economy and even a small military. They major in medical and science/research. Their experiments with a substance known as the 'T-Virus' had somehow been unleashed and had infected some of the mountain community. Without guidance, the virus turns it's host into a mindless being searching for flesh. It can infect any mammal and can mutate them to where they grow or take a lot of damage before death can occur. When Umbrella kidnapped people, and took them to their labs hidden under the Spencer Estate, The subjects that were controlled, turned into bio-weapons in the labs, including "The Hunter", "The               Tyrant T-002" and even a big shark codenamed "Neptune". The player discovers the evils of the company and it's research as they investigate the mansion and its secret lab.When you start Resident Evil Director's Cut, you must pick between two characters, Chris Redfield and Jill Valentine. The same story then played out in which you, being part of alpha team, is sent in to find bravo team. Bravo teams mission was the investigation of the cannibalistic actions occurring in the mountains outside of Raccoon City. As you arrive, you discover the crashed chopper of the bravo team, and are soon attacked by an infected pack of dogs. You escape to the Spencer estate where the evil story is slowly unraveled. You will slowly find the members of Bravo team dead, or dying. They warn you of the dangers ahead and you continue to discover the evil that is resident. At one point, the squad leader of                 S.T.A.R.S. (Special Tactics and Rescue Service),                    Albert Wesker, is revealed to be double agent working for umbrella who only joined the Police Force to bribe the mayor into covering up the events and experiments of umbrella. The T-Virus was actually co-developed by Albert Wesker, along side William Berkin (who is later seen in Resident Evil 2).                Barry Burton, one of the members of Alpha team is blackmailed by Wesker to kill all of his S.T.A.R.S. teammates, so that Wesker can finally rid the city and umbrella of the S.T.A.R.S. unit. Barry kills                     Enrico Marini, the leader of Bravo team, but at the end of the game, when Barry and Jill or Chris meet Wesker in the labs, Barry decides to risk his family's life and turn back against Albert Wesker and his research. At the end, Wesker is killed by his prized creation, The Tyrant, but Jill, Chris and Barry are tasked with the chore of fighting the beast, twice. The Team make's it to the helipad of the mansion region as the lab prepares for self destruction, there, the finals showdown of you and the Tyrant takes place, and with the single blast of a rocket launcher, the tyrant is toast. You escape via helicopter with the three surviving members of S.T.A.R.S. and return to the city where they must reveal the truth of umbrella. Sadly, as found out in Resident Evil 2, nobody believed them. Jill Valentine leaves the force, and Chris goes to Europe to expose the truth with Barry. It wouldn't be too long until they did not need to prove anything, as the outbreak of the 'T-Virus' began to spread into the city...Weapons           BerettaBeretta Custom (arranged game only)          Shotgun         Magnum         Bazooka       Flamethrower      Knife     Rocket LauncherBossesYawn (Giant Snake)Neptune (Infected Shark)Plant 42 (Plant that had mutated due to the virus)Black Tiger (Giant Spider queen)            Tyrant (Bio Weapon)PlayStation NetworkThe game is available on the American PlayStation Network, launching at $9.99.</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4312">Silent Hill</game><game id="2842">Haunting Ground</game><game id="17962">Clock Tower 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1790017-box_redc.png</image></root>