<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10227</id><name>The Yukon Trail</name><description>OverviewThe Yukon Trail is a PC game developed in 1994 by MECC, the creators of esteemed "The Oregon Trail".  The game is based on the Klondike Gold rush, with players finding partners, buying provisions, setting out on an expedition to one of two prospects, and finally, mining gold.Start of the GameIn the beginning of the game, players start out in Seattle in the late 1800's.  The player then has to choose from one of four partners, each with a different bonus:The Banker-Increased money The Carpenter-Builds a boat the most effectively. The Journalist-N/A  The Yukon Native-Carries the most supplies  If he chooses to, the player can then buy supplies.  Finally, the player purchases a ticket for a ferry which will take them to the mining town of their choice.  There are 3 ferries available per destination, each with varying safety.Start of the Game In Seattle, the player can buy supplies/provisions for the expedition, including:Outfits Dogsleds Whipsaws Caviar Eggs Kittens Canvas boat "Gold-sniffing Gophers" Trail Bicycle  All of the items can either be used to some advantage on the trail, or sold for a profit later.  There are also several items that are not worth the purchase.The Trail and RiverThe player than proceeds to travel across the Trail, making decisions such as how much of a load to carry, and how much food to consume.  Eventually, the player will arrive at Lake Bennett, where they will have to build a boat to move downstream.  Finally, the player will get to choose a claim, and mine for gold there.  At the end of winter, the player's costs are calculated, and they are told how much gold they have mined.Random EventsSeveral random events can happen in the game, including:A character being injured Bandits stealing goods or supplies Harsh weather Items being lost, including a trail bike being thrown off of a boat  ActivitiesThroughout the game, the player also has access to several activities, whether as entertainment, or an extra way to make money.  These include:Gambling Watching/betting on dograces Mini-games including steering the boat  Educational InfoAs an educational game, The Yukon Trail teaches plenty of info about the Gold Rush, including facts about places, items such as totem poles, the ability to have conversations with famous people, and more.Famous LocationsSeattle Skagway Dyea Yukon Territory Bennett Lake Dawson City Dead Horse Trail Miles Canyon White Horse Rapids Five Finger Rapids  Famous PeopleSam Steele Jack London Nellie Cashman </description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="8">Educational</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8916">The Amazon Trail</game><game id="17852">The Oregon Trail</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5457/540256-713px_yukoncover1.jpg</image></root>