<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10261</id><name>Bad Dudes</name><description>Are you a bad enough dude?Released in 1988 (when Ronald Reagan was still actually president of the United States), Bad Dudes vs. Dragon Ninja is a 2-D side scrolling beat 'em up in the same vein as Final Fight, Kung Fu or Double Dragon.However, by the time of the NES/Famicom release Reagan was no longer President, and has been replaced accordingly with George Bush. In the game's attract mode, players see the statement: "The President has been kidnapped by ninjas. Are you a bad enough dude to rescue the president?"Players, as protagonists Blade and Stryker (who were named unironically), can use knives and nunchaku to fight their way through levels, collecting power-ups along the way in the form of soda to refill lost life or clocks to add time.At the end of each level is a boss character.Stage NameDescriptionStage 1: The streets of a cityThe boss is Karnov.Stage 2: On top of a speeding "Dudes" truckThe boss is a clawed ninja named "Nenail".Stage 3: The sewersAt this point in the Famicom version of the game, the bosses begin to threaten the player before the beginning of the stage. The boss is a ninja named "Hanzo", a master of creating illusion copies of himself.Stage 4: A forestThe boss is a gigantic man named "Animal", who is decidedly un-ninja-like.Stage 5: A trainKarnov appears again in this stage, recoloured blue in the NES/Famicom version. Amusingly, he also turns blue in the Karnov game when he has been hit once.The boss is a warrior named "Killer Joe" who wields a claw on the end of a chain.Stage 6: CavesThe boss is Kon Bousai.Stage 7: The Dragon Ninja's HQAll of the earlier bosses are fought a second time, with the finale being against the leader of the Dragon Ninja, coincidentally called "Dragon Ninja" himself, on a helicopter. Endurance RunDuring the Quick Look of DataEast Arcade Classics, Jeff and Vinny played through the entire Bad Dudes campaign.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13297">Two Crude Dudes</game><game id="20752">Double Dragon</game><game id="6608">River City Ransom</game><game id="2536">Altered Beast</game><game id="1618">The Ninja Warriors</game><game id="13315">Bad Street Brawler</game><game id="11438">Hagane: The Final Conflict</game><game id="3482">Shinobi</game><game id="563">Wrath of the Black Manta</game><game id="15504">Top Hunter: Roddy &amp; Cathy</game><game id="5546">Sengoku 2</game><game id="13074">Sengoku 3</game><game id="2057">Karnov</game><game id="19366">Battletoads &amp; Double Dragon: The Ultimate Team</game><game id="27119">Angry Barry</game><game id="29491">Scott Pilgrim vs. The World: The Game</game><game id="11220">Altered Beast: Guardian of the Realms</game><game id="5423">Double Dragon II</game><game id="31941">Lucha Fury</game><game id="37090">Trio The Punch – Never Forget Me...</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2361145-nes_baddudes_gb.jpg</image></root>