<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10307</id><name>Sid Meier's Alien Crossfire</name><description>OverviewSid Meier's Alien Crossfire is an expansion pack to the critically acclaimed 4X turn-based strategy game, Sid Meier's Alpha Centauri. The expansion pack adds seven new factions, two of which are alien races, new technology to research and modified gameplay mechanics.New FactionsCult of Planet"Mankind has been blind for thousands of years-for all of its history. We have come to a place whose wonders are a hundred-fold more amazing than anything on Earth. Around us is clear evidence of the will of a higher power. I bring the Vision to the blind eyes of men. I bring the Word to the deaf ears of men. I will make them see it. I will make them hear it." -- Prophet Cha Dawn, "Planet Rising"These are worshipers of Planet, led by Prophet Cha Dawn. The Cult arrives with Social Psych and Centauri Ecology as well as a Mind Worm boil. The Cult causes less eco damage, and have a higher ability to capture Mind Worms, as compared to other factions. The cost of production for units and structures, however, is increased by 10% as a result of their will to not pollute the environment.The Cult tends to be at odds with Morgan Industries, the Free Drones, and both the Usurpers and the Caretakers.+2 PLANET: (Devoted to promoting native growth)-1 INDUSTRY: (Reluctant to pollute environment)-1 ECON: (Disinterested in wealth and its trappings)Free BROOD PIT with discovery of Centauri GeneticsMind Worms do double police duty: (Fear and reverence for native life)May not make Wealth choice in Social EngineeringAggression AggressivePriorities Green (social)Starting Tech Social Psych and Centauri GeneticsAgenda Return Planet to its pristine stateAversion Wealth (values)Cybernetic Consciousness"Those who join us need give up only half of their humanity--the illogical, ill-tempered, and disordered half, commonly thought of as 'right-brain' functioning. In exchange, the 'left-brain' capacities are increased to undreamed potential. The tendency of Biologicals to cling instead to their individual personalities can only be attributed to archaic evolutionary tendencies." --Prime Function Aki Zeta-5, "Convergence"A race of cyborgs led by Aki-Zeta 5. They arrive on the planet with Information Networks and Applied Physics. Due to their nature, the research capacity of this faction is increased, causing a 20% increased rate of research. The growth rate, however, is reduced by 10%, because of the same reason.+2 RESEARCH: {Human research abilities enhanced by algorithmic control}+2 EFFICIENCY: {Cybernetic biologicals extremely efficient}-1 GROWTH: {Humans 'possessed by an algorithm' find reproduction awkward}Impunity to CYBERNETIC penalty: {Cybernetic social choice is 'rational' and not dissented by citizens}Can steal technology when capturing a baseMay not make Fundamentalist choice in social engineeringAggression PacifistPriorities Cybernetic (social)Starting Tech Information Networks, Applied PhysicsAgenda Rational ObjectivityAversion Fundamentalist (social)Data Angels"What's more important, the data or the jazz? Sure, sure, 'Information should be free' and all that--but anyone can set information free. The jazz is in how you do it, what you do it to, and in almost getting caught without getting caught. The data is 1's and 0's. Life is the jazz." -- Datatech Sinder Roze, "Infobop"This faction is comprised of experts at espionage, and is lead by Datajack Sinder Roze. They arrive with technologies Information Networks and Planetary Networks as well as a Probe Team. Data Angels' Probe Teams have a morale upgrade, and enemy Probe Team actions are at double-costs against the Angels. The Angels have a 25% reduced cost in Probe Team actions.Usually, the Angels are in conflict with The Believers, and The Hive.+2 PROBE: (Highly motivated computer specialists)-1 POLICE: (Decentralized, difficult to control)Gain any tech known to 3 other factions with whom Angels have infiltration: (Wide-ranging covert activities)-25% cost to PROBE TEAM actions: (Skilled at network access and control}Free COVERT OPS CENTER with discovery of Pre-Sentient AlgorithmsMay not make Power choice in social engineering.Free vehicle- probe teamAggression ErraticPriorities Democracy (Social)Starting Tech Information Networks, Planetary NetworksAgenda Free Flow of InformationAversion Power (Social)Free DronesThe socialist faction is led by Foreman Domai, and arrive with Industrial Base. Because of their socialist nature, they complete projects at 20% less mineral cost, but the research rate is reduced by 20% because all citizens are of lower / working classes.The Drones are immediately at odds with the Consciousness, and are also usually enemies with the Gaians and the Cult. Supposedly due to class issues, they are also unfriendly with Morgan Industries. However, the Drones have a good relationship with both alien factions, as compared with other human factions.+2 INDUSTRY: {Excellent craftsmen and skilled workers}-2 RESEARCH: {Emphasis on productivity instead of 'blue-sky' research}Revolting bases tend to join drones: {Offer a workingman's paradise}-1 DRONES in every base: {Working for common good reduces discontent}May not use Green economics.Aggression ErraticPriorities EudaimonicStarting Tech Industrial BaseAgenda Emancipation of the working classAversion Green (economics)Nautilus Pirates"The sea ... vast, mysterious ... and full of wealth! And the nations of Planet send their trade across it without a thought. Well, the sea doesn't care about them, so it lets them pass. But we can give the sea a little hand in teaching the landlubbers a lesson in humility." -- Captain Ulrik Svensgaard, "The Ripple and the Wave"A sea-based faction led by Captain Ulrik Svensgaard. They arrive on the planet with Doctrine: Mobility and Doctrine: Flexibility, as well as a unity gunship and a sea colony pod. Colonies of the Pirates grow 10% slower than normal due to their inefficient lifestyle.The Pirates are very similar in thought and ideology to the Spartan Federation, and are usually found at odds with the University.NOTE: Loading the pirates on a custom map without any water can cause the game to crash.-1 EFFICIENCY (Individualistic mentality opposed to central organization)-1 GROWTH (Culture does not place high emphasis on family)Free NAVAL YARD with discovery of Doctrine: Initiative: (Skilled shipwrights)Enhancements may be built in ocean and trench squares with the discovery of Advanced Ecological Engineering: (Trained for life at sea)Sea colony pod  sea former prototypes FREE: (Advanced oceanic technology)Bonus mineral from ocean shelf squares: (Culture and technology adapted for the ocean)Marine Detachment ability FREE to all naval combat units upon discovery of Adaptive DoctrineAggression ErraticPriorities Power (Values)Starting Tech Doctrine:Mobility, Doctrine:FlexibilityAgenda Pillage and burnAversion noneManifold CaretakersLular H'minee"Tau Ceti Flowering: Horrors visited upon neighboring systems must never be repeated. Therefore: if it means the end of our evolution as a species, so be it." -- Caretaker Lular H'minee, "Sacrifice : Life"The first Alien race wishes to protect the planet, and prevent the process of transcendence as desired by the Usurpers. Led by Guardian Lular H'minee, they start with technologies Progenitor Psych, Centauri Ecology, Field Modulation, Information Networks, and Biogenetics. They also start with an extra colony pod and Battle Ogre Mk. I. The Caretakers are able to capture Mind Worms. They also gain a 25% defensive bonus for their units.The Caretakers are usually seen against the Gaians, the Cult, and Morgan Industries. They also have a permanent Vendetta status against the Usurpers.NOTE: The Caretakers cannot make treaties with the Usurpers, or their allies.+25% Defensive combat: {Can sense and manipulate "Resonance" fields}+1 PLANET: {Understand workings of Planet, the Sixth Manifold}Free RECYCLING TANKS at every base"Energy Grid" at each base: {Increased infrastructure generates additional energy}Make Planetfall with a Mk I Battle Ogre and extra Colony PodAll prototyped combat units have 2-square sighting radius ("Resonance" sensitivity)Can direct research efforts (rediscovering technology  infrastructure)Possess a physical scan of Planet's surfaceAggression AggressivePriorities Planned (Economics)Starting Tech Progenitor Psych, Centauri Ecology, Field Modulation, Information Networks, BiogeneticsAgenda Prevent TranscendenceAversion noneManifold Usurpers"Risks of Flowering: considerable. But rewards of godhood: who can measure?" -- Usurper Judaa Marr, "Courage : To Question"The second Alien race that seeks to use the power of the planet by forcing a process known as "transcendence". The Usurpers are led by Conqueror Judaa Maar, and arrive with the technologies Progenitor Psych, Centauri Ecology, Field Modulation, Applied Physics, and Biogenetics. They also start with an extra colony pod and Battle Ogre Mk. I. Their colonies grow 10% faster and also have units gain a 25% offensive bonus.Usurpers also have a permanent Vendetta status against the Caretakers.NOTE: The Usurpers cannot make treaties with the Caretakers, or their allies.+1 GROWTH: (Abuse Planet's resources for their own gain)+1 MORALE: (Warlike culture)-1 PLANET: (Planet senses Usurper's dark intent)+25% Offensive combat: (Can sense  manipulate "Resonance" fields)Free RECYCLING TANKS at every base"Energy Grid" at each base: (Increased infrastructure generates additional energy)Begin game with a Mk I Battle Ogre and extra Colony PodAll prototyped combat units have 2-square sighting radius ("Resonance" sensitivity)Can direct research efforts (rediscovering technology  infrastructure)Possess a physical scan of Planet's surfaceAggression AggressivePriorities Planned (economics)Starting Tech Progenitor Psych, Centauri Ecology, Field Modulation, Applied Physics, BiogeneticsAgenda Subvert Planet for galactic dominationAversion Democracy (social)FiraxiansThis is the hidden eighth faction. To access the Firaxians, the player needs to go to "Load Faction" and either type in "sid" or "brian" as faction to load. The former has Sid Meier as faction leader, and the latter has Brian Reynolds. Once loaded and saved once, the Firaxians can be added to a game. This faction begins the game with Singularity Mechanics.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10525">Imperium Galactica</game><game id="217">Sid Meier's Civilization II</game><game id="5822">Star Wars: Rebellion</game><game id="18795">Deadlock II: Shrine Wars</game><game id="9398">Galactic Civilizations</game><game id="9115">Sins of a Solar Empire</game><game id="21592">Galactic Civilizations II: Twilight of the Arnor</game><game id="7419">Master of Orion 3</game><game id="6868">Deadlock: Planetary Conquest</game><game id="24092">Sins of a Solar Empire: Entrenchment</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2970/459011-aliencrossfirecover.jpg</image></root>