<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10338</id><name>WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2006</name><description>OverviewWWE Smackdown vs. Raw 2006 is the first game in the series to differentiate itself by using a year in its title. It's also the second game in the series to use the "Smackdown vs. Raw" name.  Smackdown vs Raw 2006 added newer superstars and legends to the roster. The Playstation 2 version added online support for up to 4 players. The PSP version only had ad-hoc play for up to 4 players.  New Features Several new gameplay features are introduced, including pre-match and in-match  mini-games. The pre-match mini games are randomly chosen before every singles match:  Test of strength - a certain button shows up on the screen and the first player to press the button overpowers the other one. Best two out of three wins.  Stare down - the wrestlers talk trash to each other before the match and after a while, an "X" button picture appears. The first wrestler to press the button after that hits the other wrestler. Pressing the button too early will cause the wrestler to lose the stare down.  Shoving match - a wrestler initiates the match by pressing the X button when prompted, causing the wrestler to gently shove his opponent. A semi-circular meter appears and the player must stop the arrow at certain points of the meter to shove again with full power. If the player doesn't time the first shove correctly, the other player gets a turn to shove. Best of three shoves wins.    Roster  Raw Superstars  The Big Show  Carlito  Chavo Guerrero  Chris Jericho  Chris Masters  Danny Basham  Edge  EugeneSnitsky The Hurricane  John Cena  Kane  Kurt Angle  Lita  Rene Dupree  Ric Flair  Rob Van Dam  Rob Conway  Shawn Michaels  Shelton Benjamin  Tajiri  Torrie Wilson  Triple H    SmackDown! Superstars  Batista  Booker T  Charlie Haas  Chris Benoit  Christian  Christy Hemme  Doug Basham  Eddie Guerrero  Heidenreich  JBL  Joy Giovanni  Daivari  Mark Jindrak  Michelle McCool  Muhammad Hassan  Orlando Jordan  Paul London  Randy Orton  Rey Mysterio  Scotty 2 Hotty  Spike Dudley  Stacy Keibler  Steven Richards  Sylvain Grenier  The Undertaker  William Regal   Legends  Andre the Giant  Bret Hart  British Bulldog  Hulk Hogan  Hogan 80s  Hollywood Hogan  Jimmy Hart  Junkyard Dog  Mankind  The Rock  Stone Cold  Ted DiBiase  Jake "The Snake" Roberts (Can only be unlocked on PSP; accessible on PS2 via PSP-to-PS2 link)   Soundtrack   Billy Ray -  "Scream At Me"Bumpy Knuckles - "Bang Bang"Bumpy Knuckles - "You Don't Want War"Dark New Day - "Pieces"The Dillinger Escape Plan - "Unretrofied"Fireball Ministry - "The Broken"Megadeth - "Symphony of Destruction"Not Forgotten - "Waiting"Ron J - "I Ain't Going Nowhere"Static-X -   "Start a War"Vada - "King of the Mat"Poet - "Crush Kill Destroy"</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="10">Wrestling</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22464">Wrestling Encore</game><game id="20723">WWE Legends of WrestleMania</game><game id="30637">Lucha Libre AAA Heroes del Ring</game><game id="18333">Backyard Wrestling 2: There Goes the Neighborhood</game><game id="28430">WWF Royal Rumble</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2139898-box_wwesdraw06.png</image></root>