<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10343</id><name>Predator 2</name><description>The first Predator 2 came out in 1990 in                    North America. Being a "                                          on rails shooter" of sorts, it came out on                                          PC in 1990 and on                                         Amiga,                                        Amstrad CPC,                                       Atari ST,                                      Commodore 64 and                                     ZX Spectrum in 1991. The game was also published by                                    Konami.  The second game came out in 1991 for the                                   Sega Master System in                                  Europe and in 1992 for                                 Game Gear and Genesis/Mega Drive in Europe and             North America. The game is a shooter and published by                               Arena Entertainment.  Overview- (Genesis/Megadrive version) The                              Predator is in town with a few days to kill!!! It comes from a distant world... invisible, it's armed with powerful weapons unlike anything we know. It mercilessly stalks humans.. for sport. As Lt. Harrigan, it's up to you to rescue the innocent people from the clutches of the evil drug gangs-- before they become trophies of the Predator. Search the                             streets,                            rooftops, and                           subways until you confront IT. The Predator is on the hunt... find him before he finds you! ~Passage from the back of the case  Weapons-   (Genesis/Megadrive version)              Rifle - Provides greater firepower than the standard issue     firearm.             Scatter Gun - Sprays streams of bullets across a wide field of fire.             Sawed-Off Shotgun - The most powerful firearm supplied by              L.A.P.D. ballistics.            Grenade - Highly effective    explosive for concentrated pockets of gang members or vehicles. Aid-   (Genesis/Megadrive version)        Flak Jacket - Increases your life meter to 100%.         First Aid Kit - Rewards you with an           extra life.  The game also provides a password-save system for the seven levels within the game. </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19571">T2: The Arcade Game</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4859/507651-1209_1.jpg</image></root>