<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10387</id><name>Tekken 2</name><description>OverviewLogoTekken 2 is the second game in the Tekken series and features 25 playable characters as well as several updates to the original game. The game was praised for it's greatly updated graphics and fluidity of animation and went on to sell more than 3,000,000 copies worldwide on the Playstation.StoryTekken 2's charactersFrom the 8 warriors who competed in the first King of Iron Fist Tournament one emerged above all others to challenge Heihachi Mishima, the head of the massive Mishima Zaibatsu corporation and tournament organiser, in the final battle. That fighter was Kazuya Mishima, son of Heihachi, bearing the scar he received from his father when he was thrown off a cliff as a child.After a grueling fight that lasted for hours Kazuya bested his father using the skills that had been handed down through the Mishima family. Kazuya lifted Heihachi's lifeless body from the ground and walked to the same cliff he had been cast from when he was 6. He stared out onto the barren landscape before he dropped his father from the edge and smiled to himself as he realized he had finally gotten his revenge.The Mishima Zaibatsu flourishes under Kazuya's control and expands its business to all corners of the world. Kazuya however, becomes more and more isolated from the outside world and rumours spread of an evil inside him trying to escape. Exactly a year after Kazuya defeated his father, an announcement is made that the Zaibatsu is organising the second King of Iron Fist Tournament. Skilled fighters from around the world take notice and they rush to compete in the most elite martial arts tournament in existance.CharactersSelectable CharactersHeihachi MishimaJun Kazama (new character)Paul PheonixLei Wulong (new character)Marshall LawKingJack-2(upgrade of Jack)Nina WilliamsYoshimitsuMichelle ChangUnlockable CharactersLee ChoalanWang JinreiKumaBruce Irvin (new character)Beak Doo San (new character)Armour KingPrototype JackAnna WilliamsKunimitsuGanryuRoger (new character)Alex (new character)Kazuya MishimaAngel (new character)Devil (new character)StagesMorning Fields - Jun Kazama's stageSerene Forest - Yoshimitsu's stageAthens, Greece - Nina Williams stageGreat Wall - Marshall Law's stagePagoda Temple - Heihachi Mishima's stageNew York - Paul Phoenix's stageFactory Plant in Akibahara - Jack-2's stageChurch Sanctuary - King's stageArizona Desert - Michelle Chang's stageHong Kong Rooftops - Lei Wulong's stageSzechwan Fields - Wang Jinrei's stageCambodian Wetlands - Kunimitsu's stageTaj Mahal - Anna Williams' stageKorean Temple - Beak Doo San's stageChicago Launch Pad - Lee Chaolan's stageAcropolis - Kuma's stageLondon Ruins - Prototype Jack's stageNowhere Desert - Armour King's stageKyoto at Sunset - Ganryu's stageGrand Canyon - Bruce Irvin's stageEternal Darkness - Kazuya Mishima's stageMirror Darkness - Devil/Angel stageBeach - Roger's stageAcropolis - Alex's stagePlaystation NetworkThe game is available on the American Playstation Network for $5.99 (PS3/PSP).</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="41">Virtua Fighter 2</game><game id="5662">Fighting Vipers</game><game id="3839">Dead or Alive</game><game id="7792">Dead or Alive 4</game><game id="2895">Battle Arena Toshinden 3</game><game id="10651">Mortal Kombat: Unchained</game><game id="20678">Soulcalibur IV</game><game id="3760">Street Fighter: The Movie</game><game id="9603">Star Wars: Masters of Teräs Käsi</game><game id="19043">Fighters Megamix</game><game id="2045">Dead or Alive 2</game><game id="15584">Virtua Fighter</game><game id="6153">Soul Blade</game><game id="11065">Shaman King: Power of Spirit</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="12014">Evil Zone</game><game id="16842">Street Fighter: Anniversary Collection</game><game id="13753">Dead or Alive Ultimate</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="23220">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja</game><game id="22519">Naruto: Uzumaki Chronicles 2</game><game id="23007">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja Heroes</game><game id="21582">Naruto Shippuuden: Gekitou Ninja Taisen! EX 2</game><game id="10126">X-Men: Next Dimension</game><game id="3965">X-Men: Mutant Academy 2</game><game id="383">Mortal Kombat: Deception</game><game id="9855">Soulcalibur III</game><game id="13875">Plasma Sword: Nightmare of Bilstein</game><game id="21277">Ultimate Mortal Kombat</game><game id="22305">Street Fighter III: 2nd Impact</game><game id="26413">D-Xhird</game><game id="31109">Kinnikuman Muscle Grand Prix MAX</game><game id="6409">Kensei: Sacred Fist</game><game id="3323">Battle Arena Toshinden 2</game><game id="19738">Bloody Roar</game><game id="36412">Dead or Alive 5</game><game id="707">Virtua Fighter 5</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1791097-box_t2.png</image></root>