<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1045</id><name>Big Bumpin'</name><description>OverviewBig Bumpin' is a promotional game that was released by Burger King alongside two other games,Sneak KingandPocketbike Racer, on Nov. 19th 2006 up until December 24. All three of these games were $4.00 with the purchase of any combo. Note that all of the BK games only had achievements worth 200 points. Cross-Compatibility The three promotional games were notable for being the first three games to have cross-compatibility between the originalXboxand theXbox 360. The same disc could be used on either system. This forced some of the graphics to be toned down, otherwise the original Xbox wouldn't be able to handle the graphics. This included low-resolution textures, and lower polygon count. Despite this, they still did as much as they could, and made some moderately decent graphics, especially for budget titles.Gameplay The Game has five different game modes, all of which are playable online:Last Man Standing This game mode is an arena-style type of battle mode. It's you vs. three other bumper cars, with trap doors, saw blades, and all other sorts of goodies set up around the arena. This game type doesn't usually last long.Own The Puck In this game mode, there's a puck that you need to touch. As soon as you touch it, the puck will change to your bumper car's color and you'll start accumulating points. In order to keep getting points, you have to defend the puck from the other players who are trying to touch it and turn it to their color. This game mode can get quite hectic at times.Shockball This game mode plays a lot like Hot Potato. Someone will start off carrying the "Shockball", in order to get rid of it, he needs to bump into another player. When the timer reaches zero, the shockball will explode, causing massive damage. The game continues until there's one player left standing.Power SurgeIn this game mode, you must run over a power source to collect some power, and then bring it back to your base. The catch is, whenever the other players hit you, they'll drain some of your power. This mode plays kind of like a modified version of Capture the Flag.HockeyThis game plays a lot like air hockey, except you're using a bumper car. There's two teams of two, and you must hit the puck into the other team's net. There's also some power ups on the field, including a shield, a speed boost, and a power drainer.Xbox 360 Game Installation This game is not permitted to be installed to aXbox 360 HDD.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="39">Hockey</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4622">Pocketbike Racer</game><game id="20670">Sneak King</game><game id="24825">Dash of Destruction</game><game id="12655">Cap'n Crunch's Crunchling Adventure</game><game id="26848">ModNation Racers</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1803945-box_bbumpin.png</image></root>