<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10469</id><name>Heretic</name><description>OverviewHeretic is a fantasy first-person shooter developed by Raven and published by id on December 23, 1994 for the PC. The first in the Serpent Riders trilogy (followed by Hexen), the game sets the story of the Serpent Riders, a demonic triumvirate who have used to their dark magic to conquer the seven kings of the realm of Parthoris. As the Sidhe elves are immune, they are branded heretics and went into hiding. One Sidhe elf, Corvus, sets out through the City of the Damned in search of D'Sparil, the weakest of the three dark brothers and the only one remaining in the realm, to destroy him.The game uses a modified version of the id Tech 1 engine, adding new features such as inventory manipulation, ambient sounds, particle effects, and the ability to look up and down. The source code to the game's engine was first released in 1999 (under a license that granted rights to non-commercial use), and then re-released under the GNU General Public License on September 4, 2008 (having it comply with other GPL source ports, such as Chocolate Doom and Odamex).GameplayThe gameplay is very similar to Doom in the sense, that you'll have to find three colored keys to progress. Also, the weapons in the game are also very similar. The staff in the beginning is very much like the pistol etc. Items include from simple health potions to power-ups to the "morph ovum," an item that transforms enemies into chickens. Looking up and down come in handy, since some of the enemies have wings or float.MultiplayerLike Doom before it, Heretic supported four-player co-op and four-player deathmatch games. Matches could be played over modem or LAN, and were also supported by DWANGO.WeaponsWeaponDescriptionThe StaffThe StaffThe most basic melee weapon of the game. Sometimes useful early in the game, but when stronger monsters appear, you should run away and look for ammo.Gauntlets of the NecromancerGauntlets of the NecromancerIf you have these puppies, you don't need the staff. These gauntlets deliver a strong electrical attack.Elven WandElven WandThe basic ranged weapon. It fires single yellow crystals. Quite deadly, if you're on lower levels. On higher, you should do the mentioned tactic used for the staff.Ethereal CrossbowEthereal CrossbowIt fires three arrows at once, good for multiple enemies or concentrating your fire on one.DragonclawDragon ClawThe Dragon's Claw is the perfect weapon for those, who are into machine guns. This destroys everything in your path, leaving you a nice cleared hallway.HellstaffHellstaffPowered by Hell itself, this staff is so fast you just see the enemies dying. Another winner for the clear-the-hallway-quickly type.Phoenix RodPhoenix RodThe Phoenix Rod fires an explosive charge and when it hits, dead bodies follow quickly. mmm... Incendiarism...FiremaceFiremaceThis man-made machine fires small "grenade" type objects that bounce around and explode. Oh joy!Items and ArtifactsItem/ArtifactDescriptionCrystal VialCrystal VialThe most invaluable friend of them all. This little guy restores your health a little bit.Bag of HoldingBag of HoldingAn extra bag is always handy. It increases your ammo capacity.Map ScrollMap ScrollHandy little helper, this gives you the map of the entire level. Don't forget to press TAB...Silver ShieldSilver ShieldIf you can't find anyone, who will take someone else's punches, this will really help. Gives 100 armor.Enchanted ShieldEnchanted ShieldThe enchanted version of the one, who will take the punches. This one gives 200 armor.Quartz FlaskQuartz FlaskIf you've got one and expected to go through an entire boss fight with no vial in sight, you're toast. If you have ten, you're in heaven. This increases your health.TorchTorchInvaluable. Never go through a dark spot without it!ShadowsphereShadowsphereThis turns the game into a covert ops mission. Turns you partially invisible. Stealthy kills, here I come!Mystic UrnMystic UrnMaybe this contains some guys ashes... don't care! This gives you full health!Darchala's Chaos DeviceDarchala's Chaos DeviceHandy, when you're overwhelmed. Teleports you back to the start of the level.Torpol's Morph OvumTorpol's Morph OvumA delight. Some humor in this eerie place. This turns the enemies into chickens! Do they lay eggs? No... Wish I could throw this into D'Sparil's face and laugh... Bring on the omelet!Valador's Ring of InvincibilityValador's Ring of InvincibilityGod-Mode... for a duration of time...Delmintalintar's Timebomb of the AncientsDelmintalintar's Timebomb of the AncientsGot a second? That's the time you have to get out of this thing's way before it explodes! Be careful!Tyketto's Tome of PowerTyketto's Tome of PowerThis powers up your weapon, making it all-around useful. Even now the staff seems good... Why... oh why can't you power up the Morph Ovum?Inhilicon's Wings of WrathInhilicon's Wings of WrathWings. Simple as that.Fly me to the moon, let me sing among those stars...Heretic: Shadow of the Serpent RidersSimilar to Doom, Heretic was only available through mail order as a three-episode game, with the first episode released as shareware. On March 31, 1996, a retail version was released, distributed by GT Interactive, titled Heretic: Shadow of the Serpent Riders. Along with the three main episodes, this version featurs two additional episodes:The Ossuary - Takes the player to the remains of a world conquered by the Serpent Riders many centuries ago.The Stagnant Demesne - Takes the player to the birthplace of D'Sparil.After its release, Raven discontinued production of the original version of Heretic, while releasing a patch from their website to update the original game to match the retail version.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7326">Doom</game><game id="10157">Clive Barker's Undying</game><game id="12714">ShadowCaster</game><game id="6413">Ultima Underworld: The Stygian Abyss</game><game id="8147">Ultima Underworld II: Labyrinth of Worlds</game><game id="7747">John Romero's Daikatana</game><game id="21912">Planetside: Core Combat</game><game id="8456">An Elder Scrolls Legend: Battlespire</game><game id="24657">HacX</game><game id="16788">Doom 64</game><game id="6130">Cryptic Passage for Blood</game><game id="20232">Marathon</game><game id="2134">Witchaven</game><game id="20041">Witchaven II: Blood Vengeance</game><game id="23289">Robotica</game><game id="19869">Necrodome</game><game id="5843">Descent to Undermountain</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/13692/1237788-heretic_cover.jpg</image></root>