<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10461</id><name>Clive Barker's Jericho</name><description>OverviewJericho is an FPS published by Codemasters. It is the third game to feature the involvement of horror writer Clive Barker (including EA's Undying and the canceled Demonik). In it the player takes charge of the seven-man Jericho squad as they investigate the Middle Eastern city of Al Khali. They fight through several historical eras, such as World War I and the Crusades, encountering enemies from each period. At the center of the city is the Firstborn, which God created before Mankind.The squad uses a combination of conventional firearms and supernatural powers (including pyrokinesis and telekinesis). Players can posses any member of the squad to use these powers, revive injured members, and issue squad commands.Clive Barker in one of his recent interviews stated that he is currently working on the a sequel and gave fans the hint on where it will begin, in a ship with hundreds of children at the middle of the sea. Clive Barker also asserted that this game will be a trilogy. An exact release date is yet to be confirmed by Codemasters.CharactersThe game features 7 members of a Jericho squad:Devin RossWeapon: PatrioteerPrimary Fire: Automatic Assault RifleSecondary Fire: Underslung Automatic ShotgunSpecial ability: ResurrectionXavier JonesWeapon: PatrioteerPrimary Fire: Automatic Assault RifleSecondary Fire: Underslung Automatic ShotgunSpecial abilities: Astral Projection and PossessionSimone ColeWeapon: Assault RiflePrimary Fire: Automatic FireSecondary Fire: GrenadesSpecial abilities: Infinite Loop (Slows down time for all but Simone) and Firestorm (Increases damage dealt by squads gunfirePaul RawlingsWeapons: Faith  Destiny, Twin Desert EaglesPrimary Fire: Fire Left GunSecondary Fire: Fire Right GunSpecial abilities: Ghost Heal (Acts like Devin's Resurrection) and Vlad's Curse (Drains enemy health and heals your squad)Abigail BlackWeapon: Flash ThoughtPrimary Fire: Sniper RoundSecondary Fire: Grenade LauncherSpecial abilities: Ghost Bullet (Guide bullet from one enemy to the other) and Telekinesis (Can deflect certain attacks)Frank DelgadoWeapons: Hells Keeper / PainPrimary Fire: Continuous fire Mini-GunSecondary Fire: Semi-Automatic PistolSpecial abilities: Ababinili Attack (Spirit homes in on enemies)and Ababinili Flame Barrier (Protective)Billie ChurchWeapons: Nodachi / KenjuuPrimary Fire: Nodachi (Sword strikes/combo)Secondary Fire: Kenjuu (Sub-machine gun pistol)Special abilities: Blood Ward (Paralyzes enemies)and Fire Ward (Damages enemies)LevelsMission 1: Al-Khali (Current Time)The StormThe TombOperation VigilAl KhaliGreenMan down!Mission 2: World War II (1942)Still with youThe Path of SoulsBlackwaterAmbushFlames of angerExorcismBrandenburg GateMission 3: The Crusaders (1213)Rivers of bloodMotley CrewSewersOut of the Frying PanTortured soulsBlack RoseMission 4: Roman Provinces (38 AD)ImperiumThe low roadDecadenceTemple of painGardens of HellMorituri te salutantGutsMission 5: Sumeria (3000 BC)The GodSealSpiritual guideSkinFleshBloodSacrificePyxis PrimaSpecial EditionsIn North America, a special edition of the game was released in limited quantities through GameStop. This version of the game came packaged in a steelbook case and included an "Image Vault" Art Book and a "Making of" DVD, as well as the game's soundtrack.SountrackAlbum CoverThe original score for Clive Barker's Jericho was composed by Cris Velasco.Track No.Song TitleRunning Time01Legend of the Firstborn01.5702The Coloseum02.5503Lichthammer01.5004Path of the Righteous02.1805Corpse Behemoth02.0106Maleficarum01.5307Unholy Rapture02.0708Lost Souls of the Rub'al Khali03.2309The Child Crusaders02.0910The Penitent Man / Vicus Spills His Guts02.4011Let Us Prey01.5612Final Confrontation03.3613Firstborn Theme01.13PC System RequirementsMinimum RequirementsOS: Windows XP / VistaCPU: Pentium 2.4 GHz or Athlon XP 2400RAM: 1 GBGraphics Card: GeForce 6600 / Radeon X1600Sound Card: DirectX 9 CompatibleHard Drive Space: 6 GB2x DVD-ROM DriveRecommended RequirementsOS: Windows XP / VistaCPU: Intel Core 2 Duo or Athlon 64 X2RAM: 1 GBGraphics Card: GeForce 8800 or Radeon X1950 XTXSound Card: Creative Sound Blaster X-FiHard Drive Space: 6 GB2x DVD-ROM DriveXbox 360 Game InstallationClive Barker's Jericho requires 5.6GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10157">Clive Barker's Undying</game><game id="4800">F.E.A.R.: First Encounter Assault Recon</game><game id="20663">F.E.A.R. 2: Project Origin</game><game id="9201">The Darkness</game><game id="11787">F.E.A.R.: Extraction Point</game><game id="20532">Legendary</game><game id="13683">Quake 4</game><game id="13600">Painkiller: Overdose</game><game id="7754">Doom 3: Resurrection of Evil</game><game id="15048">Killzone</game><game id="20601">Killzone 2</game><game id="6730">Painkiller</game><game id="6042">Realms of the Haunting</game><game id="23254">Shellshock 2: Blood Trails</game><game id="22425">The Darkness II</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2243843-box_cbj.png</image></root>