<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10485</id><name>Age of Empires</name><description>OverviewAge of empires is a classical style real time strategy (RTS) game developed by Ensemble Studios and released in 1997. This is the first game in the popular Age of empires series and is one of the first historically based RTS games and has a heavy focus on resource gathering and Base creation.Historical BackgroundSheets of ice up to three miles high covered much of the earth’s northern hemisphere during the last Ice age. Our human ancestors persevered in the harsh Ice Age environment by developing new technologies and survival strategies at unprecedented rates. When climate changes melted and removed the ice around 12,000 years ago, humans were uniquely suited to take advantage of the new worlds that were beckoning.During the next 5,000 years humans expanded to become the dominant species on earth. Human populations exploded because of new technologies for hunting and food gathering put all other species at a disadvantage. Within 3,000 more years, humans had established the first great civilizations on earth.GameplayA Roman city in the Bronze Age.In Age of Empires your goal is to build your tribe into a mighty civilization that can fight for world dominance. You begin the game in the Stone Age with a small tribe of villagers. You most locate and extract resources such as food, wood, stone and gold. These resources let you construct building and train units to either further your economy of to protect your civilization from attack. As you advance through the Ages your building will improve and more skilled and elite units and structures will become available to you. There are four stages to development. The Stone Age, the Tool Age, the Bronze Age and finally the Iron Age. At each Age structures will change in appearance to reflect the historical period.Building a wonder can win you the game if you keep it standing for 2000 years.As well as campaign modes, the game includes two other game types. Random map and the so called “death match” in which all players start at Iron age and have very high resources. There are multiple ways to win these game types. Such as military conquest (killing all other civilizations on the map), Building a wonder ( a unique building for each civilization that costs large amounts of resources) or by achieving the highest score.CivilizationsThere are 12 different playable civilizations in Age of Empires each with their own benefits and specialities.AssyrianArcher, Chariot Archer and Cavalry Archer fire rate 40%Villagers 30% fasterBabylonianDouble Wall and Tower HP.30% Priest rejuvenation rate.30% Stone mining.Choson80 long swordsman and Legion HP.2 tower range.-30% Priest cost.Egyptian20% Gold mining.33% Chariot and Chariot Archer HP.3 Priest Range.GreekKeeping all four artifacts in your control will bring you victory in 2000 short years!Hoplite, Phalanx and Centurion 30% faster.War Ships 30% faster.HittiteDouble Stone Thrower, Catapult, Heavy Catapult HP.1 Archery Range unit attack 4 War Ship Range.4 warship range.Minoan-30% ship cost.2 Composite Bowman range.25% farm production.Persian30% hunting.-30% farm production.War Elephant and Elephant Archer 50% faster.50% Trireme fire rate.Phoenician-25% War Elephant and Elephant Archer cost.65% Catapult Trireme and Juggernaught fire rate.2 woodcutting.Shang-30% villager cost.double Wall HP.Sumerian15 villager HP.50% stone thrower, catapult, heavy catapult fire rate.Double farm production.Yamato-25% Horse Archer, Scout, Cavalry, Heavy Cavalry, Cataphract cos.Villagers 30% faster30% ship HPSoundtrackAge of empire has a unique sounding soundtrack created by David  Stephen Rippy who wished to create a sound that reflected the time period of the game.Title ScreenWinLoseTango Alpha BravoPolyester JammyHyman's WrathMix of the Great BooksMeanMedieval MelodyRocky RoadsKitty's SongFretless SalsaBigelow's BungalowCreditsSystem Requirements (PC)Pentium 90 or higher processor16 MB RAMMicrosoft Windows 95 operating system or Windows NT Workstation 4.0 with Service Pack 3Local SVGA bus video display (with 1 MB VRAM)80 MB of available hard disk space50 MB free disk space for swap fileQuad speed CD-ROM drive - for cinematicsDouble speed CD-ROM drive - for gameplayMicrosoft Mouse or compatible pointing deviceSound board plus speakers or headphones to hear audio28.8 Kbps modem for head-to-head play</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14073">Warcraft III: The Frozen Throne</game><game id="11993">Rise of Nations</game><game id="19857">Empire Earth</game><game id="1565">Empire Earth II</game><game id="10244">Rise of Nations: Rise of Legends</game><game id="11610">Empires: Dawn of the Modern World</game><game id="18901">Star Wars: Galactic Battlegrounds</game><game id="20215">Star Wars: Galactic Battlegrounds - Clone Campaigns</game><game id="11816">Warcraft II: Beyond the Dark Portal</game><game id="9719">Warcraft: Orcs &amp; Humans</game><game id="1370">Age of Mythology: The Titans</game><game id="8546">Age of Empires III</game><game id="21982">Small Soldiers: Squad Commander</game><game id="20103">Warcraft II: Tides of Darkness</game><game id="18072">Command &amp; Conquer: Red Alert 2</game><game id="1702">The Horde</game><game id="5550">Command &amp; Conquer: Yuri's Revenge</game><game id="18915">Populous: The Beginning: Undiscovered Worlds</game><game id="14291">Stronghold Crusader</game><game id="22846">Stronghold Crusader Extreme</game><game id="17778">Impossible Creatures</game><game id="17982">Command &amp; Conquer: Generals - Zero Hour</game><game id="8421">Outlive</game><game id="7701">The Lord of the Rings: The Battle for Middle-earth</game><game id="24496">Mosby's Confederacy</game><game id="24890">Warfare Incorporated</game><game id="25404">Barca B.C.</game><game id="25670">Ikariam</game><game id="27075">BC Kings</game><game id="1765">Ancient Wars: Sparta</game><game id="10111">Tzar: The Burden of the Crown</game><game id="19932">Emperor: Battle for Dune</game><game id="29066">Dune: The Battle for Arrakis</game><game id="31033">GodFinger</game><game id="13326">ParaWorld</game><game id="19887">Rome: Total War</game><game id="24078">StarCraft II: Heart of the Swarm</game><game id="38672">Command &amp; Conquer: The First Decade</game><game id="43986">Three Kingdoms: Fate of the Dragon</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/17557/1131792-age_of_empires_user.jpg</image></root>