<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10525</id><name>Imperium Galactica</name><description>  Story The third millennium of Earth came with an age of technological and social revolution after thousands of years of warfare before humanity finally found peace. In this climate of progress, Metropolises emerged from the various cities before eventually linking together, transforming the Earth into a vast hive of human activity as nature was driven out. This golden age of progress however was marred by overpopulation, and so millions of scientists desperately sought a solution to this problem. The scientists eventually discovered that the star system Proxima Centauri contained a habitable planet but was unreachable due to mankind having no form of FTL. In a flash of insight, one "Dr. Emily Nagome" found out how to break the constraining three dimensions of our world by accessing a fourth dimension in which movement can cross great distances whilst taking place outside the flow of normal time. This was all mankind needed before realising their manifest destiny, going forth into the great unknown whilst colonizing worlds in their wake. Mankind also made their first contacts with various aliens, some friends whilst others enemies. As man forged a great empire, its vast wealth would eventually lead to the foundation of "Centronom" which would later become the new capital world of humanity. Earth however would be stripped of its cities as painstaking natural and ecological reclamation projects aimed to restore Earth as a symbol of man's ancestral homeworld. Earth became a paradise, pilgrimage planet that also served as a research hub on expanding the farthest bounds of technology. Faced with the challenges this galaxy presented, humanity created countless innovations from nanites that sustained development on harsh worlds to the first true androids that could look and act like humans. Acting as protectors of man they were first deployed on Centronom, however a freak accident in their coding caused them to go insane, the most notable incident being one android pilot crashing his ship into the space station holding the 5th Congress of the Imperial Senate, killing everyone aboard. This and other related deaths led to the outlawing of all android research and production.  In 3226, mankind's galaxy spanning empire buckled under social strain. Unable to cope with such rapid expansion, the empire fractured as warring factions ended this peaceful age as they began to divide up and fight over vast regions of space. Sensing weakness, expansionist aliens started probing humanity's borders whilst the desperate admiralty of the old empire decides to use its "secret weapon" to alter its downward spiral. OverviewDante, a young, loyal and eager Lieutenant is called by his commanding  Colonel who proceeds to instruct him that the planet Achilles has been  under subsequent anarchy and war for some time now. The Colonel subsequently gives him the task that he has to restore  order to the sector. Upon doing so, Dante is ordered  to expand control over the cluster of worlds under his command by dealing with pirate  fleets. Eventually Dante is instructed to rendezvous with an Admiral  Mark Tullen, whose flagship Thorin is under attack from Garthog forces and must withdraw. After Dante successfully intervenes, he is promoted to Captain.   Dante is then introduced to the neighboring Garthog empire, whose forces make  periodic attacks upon Galactic Empire worlds and so Dante must fend them off. At the same time of repulsing Garthog incursions he also has to deal with a particular virulent virus that requires  quarantine of the planet New Caroline. Upon defeating the infection and  reporting viral developments to the Colonel, he suspects biological  warfare and sends up for some specialized equipment to detect virus  carriers whilst Dante is recalled to escort the Admiral's fleet to New  Caroline. Soon the Garthogs ambush the fleet, and shortly after the Garthogs are repulsed another viral outbreak occurs. The sensor equipment confirms that it is  the Garthogs who are engaging in viral warfare, and swiftly dealing with  the infection and the viral transport ships, they are dissuaded from  making the same attack again. Dante begins to have recurring flashbacks whilst he develops suspicions  that Catherine Reinhardt, the ship's doctor, may be an enemy spy.  After  rigging up a camera feed in his quarters, his suspicions are correct in  that the doctor is secretly accessing his room and his computer for  unspecified reasons. Dante reports this to the Colonel who states that he will take a  look into this matter. Later, Dante is assigned to protect a money  transport from Garthog pirates and then to retrieve a prototype  destroyer stolen by the Garthogs which upon its recovery, Dante is promoted  to Commander.   The Colonel then orders Dante to deal with the renegade governor of the  planet Zeuson by blockading it. After the governor is dealt with, Dante must escort a cargo vessel as well as taking the fight  to the Garthogs. After the Garthog empire has been fully conquered,  Dante is promoted to Admiral and given the command of the Thorin. Suffering from more intense flashbacks he  goes to the new ship's doctor with inquiries into robotics, who tells  him about a " Professor Reinhardt"'s "infernal android project". After  sending his suspicions to Earth, Dante tracks down Professor Reinhardt who reveals that Dante is in fact, the "secret weapon" of the empire. Dante is an  android whose entire life, family and friends were fabricated to make  him identify with the image of a young, ambitious officer. He was  created after long range probes detected the coming of an expansionary  alien race invading the galaxy. It was the hope that Dante would be able  to command the failing old empire to stand against this threat, and to  restore it beset by hostile aliens and within the myriad of its own problems. He was  designed to be the "perfect leader", one who had to manage the Galactic  Empire on an exceptional level of technical, military and governing abilities.  Catherine Reinhardt was the Professor's daughter, sent to keep an eye on  Dante as the military desired more tests to assess Dante's mental  stability. Professor Reinhardt then states that the future of mankind  rests within Dante's hands.   Dante is promoted to Grand Admiral after encountering the alien race  mentioned by Professor Reinhardt as it encroaches Galactic Empire fleets and  worlds. These aliens are identified as the Dargslans, a warlike,  conquering alien race bent on subjugation of all who stand in their way.  When first encountered they are an extreme, growing militarist power  utilising superior technology and as such Dante is drawn into a long war  in the attempt to gain a technological and manufacturing equality with  these aliens. After the Dargslans are defeated, various warring factions  throughout the galaxy rally to the Galactic Empire after seeing this sign of strength, thus preventing a possible interstellar war. Historians  disagree on what saved humanity, many believe that a higher power  preserved what was gained in the last millennium whilst others argue  that only a machine unswayed by doubts and fears saved mankind from annihilation. Only the admiralty knows the truth however, and the  only declaration was that a secret weapon led to their triumph, what  this may be however still is shrouded in mystery, secrecy and classified  government files. Gameplay   The starmap is an overhead view of the in-game world, giving info on owned planets, events and fleet movements.       Imperium Galactica is set sometime during the fourth millennium with the  player given the task of rebuilding the Galactic Empire. The player is  placed into the role of a Lieutenant called Dante who is  given a series of missions to complete. You then advance to the next  rank upon completion of these missions which gives more strategic options and available ships to command. Being promoted also unlocks a greater section of your area of the galaxy to police,  conquer and colonize. This continues until you reach the rank of Grand  Admiral, where the game is now fully unlocked to the player. At this point, the whole map of the galaxy is available to be viewed and the event missions effectively cease.    One of many colonies the player must manage throughout the game.  When you are in command of a region, you must ensure that its economy  and colonies are contributing to you in some way. You collect taxes,      produce colonies, move your fleets, research and manufacture as game  time passes which can be paused, sped up or slowed down. Events    also  happen based on specific in-game times. You must also ensure that the  people are well-fed, happy and reproducing, whilst if the tax level is too high it causes a constant migration of citizens and eventual planetary revolts. Research into weapons technologies and such  offers more competent ships whilst colony technologies offer more ground  defense and morale boosting structures. 75 new scientific discoveries  can be made over the course of the game, each requiring prerequisites of  empire wide "development centres". Only one  development centre can be sustained per planet, and the more advanced  technologies may require a combination of five specific types of development centre throughout your empire. In addition, successful  invasions can result in the chance of procuring colony technology from  other races.  Races  Your enemies are several alien races. They each have their own styles of  architecture, ships, and unique land-based units. However, some are more  inspired than others, and at the Grand Admiral stage diplomacy options  ensure that all-out war is not the only way to victory. The list below details all of the races in the game:   Galactic Empire, (a.k.a. Human Empire, "Old Empire"):  The player's faction, which appears on the starmap as orange to the far  middle left of the galaxy. The player does not initially have any  access to special land units unlike the AI alien races however late in  the tech tree the Behemoth tank used by other human races as a unique  special can be unlocked. Alliance of Free Traders (AFT): "Once part of the Old  Empire, the  traders left to create a new empire for themselves. They  are a peaceful  race of traders and enjoy good relations with Ychoms." The AFT is a human offshoot race that utilises Behemoth tanks as their unique vehicles in battle.  Dargslan Kingdom: "Very little is known about the  Dargslans.  Intelligence reports show that they have extremely powerful  ground  attack forces, as well as a competent space fleet."  The  Dargslans expand primarily by invasion rather than colonization. The Dargslan  unique land units are "Auto-repair tanks". A distinct Dargslan  ground  advantage is one where they are able to make all of their ground forces  appear in front of you at the start of a battle. Defeat of the Dargslans  by having them surrender to you or by conquering every last one of  their colonies ends the game and it is also possible to band other alien  races against them. Dribs: "The Dribs are a proud race, with  advanced knowledge of  mechanics and architecture. They have known of  the Dargslan race for a  long time, since the Dargslans occupied some  Drib territory." The Dribs use a special "Paralysis tank" in battle.  Ecaleps : "With the rapid expansion of their  empire, tax revenue  has increased to a very high level. This partially  explains their  obsession with money.."  The Ecaleps arm themselves with unique "Anti-missile tanks", which have an immunity to the player's Rocket Sled missiles.   Free Nations Society (FNS): "Once part of the  Old Empire, they  declared themselves independent a long time ago. The  Free Nations  Society has developed rapidly, occupying territories with  ease. The  Society is well known for their arrogant attitude and  contempt for the  Empire."  Another human offshoot, they also use Behemoth tanks.    Garthogs: "The Garthogs are a contemptible and  un-trustworthy  race, who implant their young with bio-mechanical  devices. They have a  special interest in mechanics and are renowned for  stealing the  technology of other races. It is rumored that they  destroyed an entire  race, known as the Nubs, to obtain their secrets.  The Garthog Empire is  close to the Human Empire and there has been  conflict for 10 years." The Garthogs bring their  "Radar Jammer" vehicles into battle, which disables your battle radar on colony fights.   Morgarths: "The Morgarths are an insular and hostile race.."   The Morgarths have unique  "Kamikaze tanks" for ground combat.    Sulleps: "The Sulleps are a warlike race with a very  strict  social structure. From a very young age, Sulleps are subjected  to  military training. Such is their code of combat, it is more  honourable  for them to die in battle than surrender. "  The Sulleps have unique "Mobile Artillery" units for ground combat.   Ychoms : "A peaceful trader race that enjoys good relations with Alliance of Free Traders.." The Ychoms have their unique unit as  a saucer shaped "Mine Layer".   Combat     Imperium Galactica combat, 2D lasers pew pew!   Space combat is done on a 2D grid where ships are pitted against other  ships with a certain amount of hitpoints in real time which can also be paused or slowed down. The player must take note on  how to equip all of his ships through various technologies then upgrade  them, as well as knowing the limitations of his ships. Ships can also  fire missiles in combat by individually ordering and clicking on enemy  ships, although ECM systems help in making the missile not hit at all. Shields give their equipped ships  another hitpoint layer which must be downed first  before damage to the hull can occur. Ground colonies can build several  planetary defences and starbases which can fight on their own or  automatically aid defending space fleets.    Ground combat occurs when an enemy fleet or one of your own which is carrying tanks attacks a colony and manages to destroy the planetary defences (if any). Your tanks are then controlled in a real-time  tactical map after you place them on the battlefield depending if you are attacking or defending. The AI then places its units after you have placed yours. If you are attacking, to seize an an enemy colony you must  destroy all enemy tanks and defense buildings. Buildings are affected by  power, so by destroying enough power plants on the colony  fortifications can be powered down allowing more strategical  flexibility. If a player does not have enough ground strength to take  the planet, scorched earth tactics are still viable to cripple the colony  meaning the AI may need to rebuild those structures. Regional Differences  There are plot-driven FMV and 3D modeled cutscenes to the  game along with an opening intro movie. These cutscenes appear whenever you  advance in rank and also at certain other points in the game. In the  Hungarian version of the game, the intro and cutscenes involve a  combination of 3D rendered models and FMV actors, however the English  version of the game instead uses extended cutscenes with the rendered 3D  models overdubbed with English voice actors. The FMV actors from the  Hungarian version however still make an appearance in the English version, but  only in the small video messages that are sent to the player from time to time  with an English voice acted dub. </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11342">Master of Orion</game><game id="9115">Sins of a Solar Empire</game><game id="11765">Star Trek: The Next Generation - Birth of the Federation</game><game id="13152">Sword of the Stars</game><game id="1894">Emperor of the Fading Suns</game><game id="12379">Sid Meier's Alpha Centauri</game><game id="10307">Sid Meier's Alien Crossfire</game><game id="24092">Sins of a Solar Empire: Entrenchment</game><game id="30683">Distant Worlds</game><game id="32496">Shores of Hazeron</game><game id="18545">Pax Imperia: Eminent Domain</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/864/624268-imperium_galactica.jpg</image></root>