<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10528</id><name>Monkey Island 2:  LeChuck's Revenge</name><description>OverviewDeveloped by            LucasArts and released in 1991,  Monkey Island 2: LeChuck's Revenge is a sequel to          The Secret of Monkey Island. The project was lead by Monkey Island creator            Ron Gilbert who was, again, assisted by            Dave Grossman and            Tim Schafer. The sixth game to use the SCUMM engine and the first to use the iMuse sound system, Monkey Island 2 is considered by many to be the high point of the series and adventure games in general. PlotHanging  precariouslySet several months after the events of The Secret of Monkey Island the game begins mid-story with            Guybrush hanging onto a rope with a chest telling            Elaine the sequence of events that led to the situation, starting the flashback to Scabb Island.Guybrush is seen telling two pirates about the time he defeated            LeChuck and his ongoing search for the reclusive treasure of Big Whoop, saying he is in need of a ship to take him there. The pirates tell Guybrush that Largo LeGrande, one of LeChuck's ex-henchmen, has placed an embargo on the insland and Guybrush goes on to defeat him with a voodoo-doll provided by the Voodoo Lady. While Guybrush attempts to convince Largo that he was the one who killed LeChuck he brandishes his beard which Largo promptly steals and uses it to resurrect his former master. The Voodoo Lady informs Guybrush that the only way to stop LeChuck now lies only in the secret of Big Whoop.After a lengthy series of events including library research and a spitting contest, Guybrush is able to reconstruct the long-hidden map of Dinky Island that pinpoints the location of Big Whoop. He loses the map to LeChuck but manages to land on Dinky anyway where he discovers Herman Toothrot once more. He is typically unhelpful again but his parrot remember the conversation between the sailors who originally found Big Whoop and guides Guybrush to the burial site in exchange for crackers. Guybrush begins digging and lowers himself down on a rope.Underground  TunnelsAt this point we return to current events with Elaine and Guybrush talking. Unfortunately Guybrush's rope snaps and he falls into a series of artificial tunnels. LeChuck confronts Guybrush, claiming to be his own brother, and stalks him through the tunnels tormenting him with a voodoo doll. While running from LeChuck, Guybrush makes several surprising discoveries including the skeletal remains of his parents, an elevator to Melee Island and the beginnings of an amusement park.By scavenging his surroundings, Guybrush is able to make a voodoo doll of Lechuck and maims the zombie pirate. LeChuck begs Guybrush to take his mask off. Guybrush agrees, revealing the face of his brother, "Chuckie". The reunion of the brothers is interrupted by a man in brown coveralls telling them that kids are not allowed "down here". The two brothers, both appearing as children, exit the tunnels together and meet their parents aboveground in the "Big Whoop" amusement park. As the family leaves to ride the Madly Rotating Buccaneer, Chuckie turns towards the screen and grins, voodoo magic playing over his eyes. The last in-game screen shows Elaine standing outside Big Whoop excavation site, wondering, "What could be keeping Guybrush? I hope LeChuck hasn't put some sort of SPELL over him .... " ReleaseThe game was originally released on floppy disks for the PC, Mac, and Amiga. In 1994 the game was released on FM Towns, the last LucasArts game to be released on the platform. The game was later repackaged and released on CD in the The Monkey Island Bounty Pack along with Monkey Island and Curse of Monkey Island.Monkey Island 2 Special Edition: LeChuck's RevengeAt GDC 2010 on March 10th, 2010, Monkey Island 2 Special Edition: LeChuck's Revenge was announced. This remake has updated graphics, a hint system, a re-mastered soundtrack,   achievements and full voice-over. It was released for PlayStation 3, PC, Mac, Xbox 360, iPhone, and iPod Touch during July 2010.  The Special Edition also features a developer commentary featuring       Ron Gilbert,      Dave Grossman and     Tim Schafer.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4372">Maniac Mansion: Day of the Tentacle</game><game id="11852">Sam &amp; Max Hit the Road</game><game id="13230">Grim Fandango</game><game id="4084">Broken Sword II: The Smoking Mirror</game><game id="11734">Leisure Suit Larry: Love for Sail!</game><game id="17544">Broken Sword: The Shadow of the Templars</game><game id="9527">Flight of the Amazon Queen</game><game id="21914">A Vampyre Story</game><game id="7947">Lure of the Temptress</game><game id="600">Future Wars</game><game id="2228">Space Quest III: The Pirates of Pestulon</game><game id="14441">Pajama Sam 2: Thunder and Lightning Aren't so Frightening</game><game id="8430">Pajama Sam: No Need to Hide When It’s Dark Outside</game><game id="14732">The Legend of Kyrandia: Hand of Fate</game><game id="23532">Nikopol: Secrets of the Immortals</game><game id="21667">Gray Matter</game><game id="6113">Cirque de Zale</game><game id="11221">Runaway 2: The Dream of the Turtle</game><game id="22496">Runaway: A Twist of Fate</game><game id="13476">Igor: Objective Uikokahonia</game><game id="31657">Jolly Rover</game><game id="4889">Rent-a-Hero</game><game id="32871">Junkland Jam</game><game id="9015">Sam &amp; Max Episode 202: Moai Better Blues</game><game id="4885">Sam &amp; Max Episode 203: Night of the Raving Dead</game><game id="4399">Sam &amp; Max Episode 204: Chariots of the Dogs</game><game id="21643">Sam &amp; Max Episode 205: What's New, Beelzebub?</game><game id="30372">Sam &amp; Max Episode 303: They Stole Max's Brain</game><game id="30373">Sam &amp; Max Episode 304: Beyond the Alley of the Dolls</game><game id="30374">Sam &amp; Max Episode 305: The City That Dares Not Sleep</game><game id="7344">Sam &amp; Max Episode 5: Reality 2.0</game><game id="34211">Hector: Badge of Carnage</game><game id="31451">The Book of Unwritten Tales</game><game id="39355">Primordia</game><game id="25513">Ceville</game><game id="25680">Ghost Pirates of Vooju Island</game><game id="38390">The Cave</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/24/379393-1216513843243.jpg</image></root>