<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10621</id><name>The King of Fighters '98: The Slugfest</name><description>Overview The King of Fighters '98: The Slugfest (known in Japan as The King of Fighters '98: Dream Match Never Ends) is a 2D 3-on-3 fighting game developed and published by         SNK for the        Neo Geo. It is the fifth installment in the       King of Fighters series and contains no canon story (and is non-canon to the franchise). It features most of the characters that appeared in the first four installments (with the exception of      Eiji Kisaragi,     Kasumi Todoh,    Geese Howard,   Wolfgang Krauser, and  Mr. Big)GameplayClark Still Vs Ralf Jones.The King of Fighters '98 uses four buttons - light punch, strong punch, light kick, strong kick - and other techniques can be use by performing combination of those four buttons. It also features two fighting systems known as "Advance mode" and "Extra mode." And a service known as "Continue service" that is a mini-game of roulette that is played when the player loses a match in the arcade mode.A variety of techniques is uses in the game such as a technique that is called "Bop attack," it's a technique that is done by pressing strong punch and strong kick simultaneously. The bop attack is a knockdown attack that dose some heavy. The game also has several ways to use the super meter, obviously one way is you can perform a super deadly move when the meter is fulled up. Other ways is the ability to go into "Armor mode" that is done by pressing light punch, light kick, and strong punch together.  Armor mode increases the attack power for a short amount of time; if the player has one meter fulled up and is in armor mode, then the player can perform a more powerful version of the super deadly move. Or if the player can perform the ultra powered version of the super deadly move if the player has all three gauges fulled up. The player can use a counter attack when the player blocks an attack and pressing strong punch and strong kick at the same time and used up one power stock from the super meter (Those technique can only be used in Advance mode). In Extra mode, the player has the ability to charge up the meter by pressing light punch, light kick, and strong punch together.Command ModesKing of Fighters '98 features two command modes - Advance mode and Extra mode. Advance Mode Running: Move as you run forward.Emergency Evasion: Move forward or backwards while rolling.Advance Gauge: Can increase the gauge by performing attacks and the stock of gauges increase by one  when a character gets defeated.Extra Mode Step: Lets you smoothly move (Step in) toward opponents.Attack Evasion: Steps out of the way from attacks and counters with any attack.Extra Gauge: Increases gauge by taking damage or by doing a "Power Built" (Press Light Punch, Light Kick, and Strong Kick). The gauge can only hold up one stock.Continue Service   When the player loses in one of the single player mode, the player goes through the "Continue Service," this service is were the player has the option of four condition.Decrease the level of difficulty.The computer's health starts at 1/3.The player's power gauge will start at Max.No Service.Characters  Japan TeamKyo Kusanagi '98  Kyo Kusanagi (also has an EX version)                                                                                                                                                                            Benimaru Nikaido                                                                                                                                                                           Goro Daimon     Fatal Fury Team Terry Bogard (also has an EX version) Andy Bogard (also has an EX version) Joe  Higashi (also has an EX version)     Art of Fighting Team Ryo  Sakazaki (also has an EX version) Robert Garcia (also has an EX version) Yuri Sakazaki (also has an EX version)     Ikari Warriors Team                                                                                                                   Leona                                                                                                                                                               Ralf Jones                                                                                                                                                             Clark SteelPsycho Soldier Team                                                                                                                                                                    Athena  Asamiya                                                                                                                                                                  Sie  Kensou                                                                                                                                                                 Chin  Gentsai Women Fighters Team                             Chizuru Kagura Mai Shiranui (also has an EX version)                                                                                                             King     Korea Team                                                                                                                                                          Kim Kaphwan                                                                                                                                                         Chang Koehan                                                                                                                                                        Choi Bounge Orochi Team                            Yashiro Nanakase (also has an EX version)                            Shermie (also has an EX version)                            Chris (also has an EX version) '97 Special Team                                                        Ryuji Yamazaki Blue Mary (also has an EX version)                                                      Billy Kane Yagami Team                       Iori Yagami                     Mature                    Vice Masters Team                    Heidern                  Takuma Sakazaki                 Saisyu KusanagiOther  Rugal Bernstein (with Omega Rugal as an unplayable boss)                                                    Shingo Yabuki Other Versions of King of Fighters '98Dreamcast VersionKing of Fighters '98 was re-released on the Dreamcast in 1999 under the title, King of Fighters '99: Dream Match Never Ends. That version feature 3D backgrounds and a color edit mode.Ultimate MatchIn 2008, SNK re-released the game to celebrate the 10th anniversary of the games' released. Ultimate Match is based on the Dreamcast version of King of Fighters '98 - the game features 3D backgrounds and the color edit is also feature. Ultimate Match also feature more characters and re-balance gameplay.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11156">X-Men vs. Street Fighter</game><game id="7751">Art of Fighting Anthology</game><game id="18484">Killer Instinct</game><game id="21952">Killer Instinct 2</game><game id="10614">Killer Instinct Gold</game><game id="20456">Street Fighter IV</game><game id="28446">Street Fighter III: Double Impact</game><game id="39531">Xuan Dou Zhi Wang</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/6735/538763-kof98f.jpg</image></root>