<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10644</id><name>Entomorph: Plague of the Darkfall</name><description>SettingEntomorph takes place in the same universe as Thunderscape - World of Aden, based on somewhat generic series of books and pen-and-paper RPG system.Entomoprh is not a direct sequel to Thunderscape and even the setting is not exactly the same - while the first World of Aden game had a bit of steampunk feeling in it, the second game world seems a lot more savage and primitive, with only simple technology in use (common stone and wooden weapons, elevators powered by animals etc.).PlotThe game starts with it's main hero, Warrick, dreaming a surreal vision of giant spider talking to him in a puzzling manner. He wakes up on a small island, with amnesia and the fact that his sister disapeared is the only thing he still remembers.He starts a long journey through the world filled with giant and intelligent bugs fighting with the inhabitants of the nearby islands. During his journey he has to make some hard choices and change his life completely and quite literally, as he slowly transforms into an insect himself.GameplayEntomorph mixes a couple of genres - action is shown form a bird's eye perspective and Warrick is a pretty capable fighter, even using his bare fists. He can also become a skilled mage and use healing and offensive spells. But killing some gross insects is not the main course of the game. Most times the player faces classic point-and-click adventure problems, ie. how to start an elevator, how to obtain a very important object and so forth. Dialogue is simple and serves mainly as exposition.Structure of the game is very linear and only one solution is offered to every riddle, and there are not many hints nor clues what to do next. This, and a bit clunky and unintuitive interface makes the game pretty hard to finish without any guide or FAQ.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/7900/285307-entomorph.jpg</image></root>