<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10652</id><name>Arc the Lad II</name><description>You take the role of Elc, a young hunter from a tribe which has the ability to manipulate fire. He has a sarcastic personality and hates Arc. He believe that Arc is behind the death of his tribe, as Arc now possesses the Silver Noah, something that was burned into his mind as he watched his entire tribe murdered infront of him.The game is widely to considered to be vastly superior to the first game. The first game takes around 10-12 hours to complete whereas there is about 70 hours of gameplay in Arc the Lad II. The player is rewarded for having a clear save of the original Arc the Lad. The player's save in Arc the Lad II can also be imported into a secondary game called Arc Arena in which you pit your party against monsters for in-game rewards. You can then export the save game back to Arc the Lad II with stronger and richer characters. Arc Arena was included with the Arc the Lad Collection on PS1.CharactersElc is the last of the Pyrenians, an ancient tribe that had the ability to summon and manipulate flame. While Arc was still a child in Touvil, a small child named Elc watched as the Silver Noah launched a vicious assault that destroyed his entire village. During the raid, Elc was captured and sent to a place code named White House for further studies. A Hunter known as Shu rescued Elc in the forest near White House, and took him in. While under Shu's care, Elc was taught many battle and survival techniques. Even now, Elc is still haunted by nightmares of his time at White House. As this chapter begins, he is about to take an assignment that will force him to confront all he has struggled to forget.Abilities:Fire StormFire ShieldChargeRetaliationMight MindExpand RangeExplosionInvincibleProtectionStrike PowerMind BusterDivideExtractSwingLieza was born into a tribe of Beasttalkers that can communicate with monsters, Lieza has spent most of her life on an isolated plateau, away from other humans, and raised by her grandfather, Joseph. Her grandfather was painfully aware of the gift that his granddaughter possessed, and of the scorn it might bring if exposed to the outside world. Instilling his own fears into her, he's taught Lieza that people kill what they fear and don't understand. Unfortunately, in the case of Romalia, that's true, but only after they've harnessed her power for the mysterious Chimera program.Abilities:SearchPower LossCureGround ShieldRavishWeaknessEarthquakeSpinsterCounter HangTrans EnemyDistract RangeHold EnemyDispelMud stormPaundit is the wolf monster of the girl Lieza, through her natural born ability she is able to communicate with him and other monsters. He acts as her protector, being friendly to anyone who is her friend and fierce to her enemies. The two have been together for many years. When casting a spell the wolf urinates whether this is required or to make the spell stronger is anyone's guess.Abilities:Ice ShieldCold BreathStrike PowerChargeDestructionCounter HangMind busterDiamond DustThunder BreathBlizzardShu is clad in the traditional black bodysuit of the ninja, Shu keeps his true identity a mystery, but that hasn't stopped people from constantly guessing as to his origins. One popular rumor tells of his birth in the city of Seirya and his apprenticeship in the secret corps of assassins, but Shu himself has never confirmed or denied this tale. Shu's stern personality keeps most potential allies at a distance, but his taciturn manner conceals a warm heart.Abilities:StealPlasma ShockScapegoatSpeed UpWind ShieldTime BombRandom AttackWind SlashJump HighPower LossChargeThunder StormTornadoExtractShante was abandoned as a child, Shante essentially raised herself and her brother. They spent many years wandering the country of Aldia before settling down in the city of Indigos. Shante frequently performs in the bars and pubs of Aldia, but prefers to stay near Indigos. She works hard to provide her brother with the life she feels will never be hers to live. After a lifetime of overcoming hardships, Shante has developed a fighting spirit that will serve her well.Abilities:CureSilentResurrectionRefreshIce ShieldDispelDivideDiamond DustDestructionRetaliationDivine JudgementSleep WindBlizzardRob MindGruga was 23 years old when he assumed leadership of Brakia, a colony of Niedel. Brakia declared a war of independence against Niedel, and as the battle raged on for years, Gruga became increasingly depressed at the mounting casualties on both sides of the conflict. The depression eventually drove Gruga to abandon his position. He now lives with his adopted daughter Elena, whose parents were killed in the war.Abilities:Gruga ChargeGruga TackleConfusionRolling SabotDistract RangeExtractGruga SpecialSuper NOvaPower LossExpand RangeCounter HangPrrotectionStrike PowerInvincibleGogen over 3,000 years ago fought as one of the original seven heroes in an attempt to save the world. The confrontation climaxed at the Ancient Monolith near the small town of Touvil. As the battle dragged on, it became apparent to Gogen that the only way for good to emerge victorious was to seal himself and the enemy in the Illusion World. Due to the length of time he has spent away from humanity, Gogen's brain is a little foggy, but he remains a powerful wizard nonetheless. Abilities:ExplosionDream KnockDiamond DustWind SlashRob MindThunder stormTeleportEarthquakeMight MindDestructionMagic ShieldMud StormBlizzardSuper NOvaPoco is part of the Palencia Military Corps - the marching band part. He is very cowardly. He is a returning character from the first game who supports Arc in his quest to save the world from evil. Abilities:Battle DrumLion DrumCheer TrumpetAtrophy HornHealing HarpMind BusterSpeed OrcarinaOrchestra HitJump HIghJump lowIce ShieldDiamond DustMight MindBlizzardTosh was a member of the Elite Guard in the town of Palencia, but travels with Arc after being freed from a prison cell below Palencia Castle. He's wise but still temperamental and prone to recklessness at times. Abilities:Ouka-raibaku-zenJubakukenShinku-zenKoei-zenToha-zenKishinohoRyugakenMonji SlashSpeed upSpeed downExpand RangeFire StormExplosionSwingKukuru is part of the clan sworn to protect the sacred Flame Cion due to her selfishness it caused the Dark One to escape; in order to stop him she had to become the seal that keeps him imprisoned. Because of this sacrafice she is not able to leave the Sabactico Shrine located in Touvil. Abilities:CureMagic ShieldSilentRefreshDivine JudgementResurrectionDivideProtectionSania is the daughter of the King and queen of Millmana, when they met their untimely end at the hands of monsters they hid her so that she may escape to the neighboring country of Greyshinne. Scarred by the memory of that attack, she has vowed to avenge the death of her parents. Abilities:Shuffle ShotX-CryteRandom DiceDark ShieldTrans EnemyTransferPoison WindSleep WindParalyze WindPetro WindDivdeDeathArc is the main character of the first Arc the Lad. Having the blessing of the Spirits, Arc fought against evil in the first ATL game, and in the second is still painted as a criminal by Andel, the evil minister of Seirya. Having a strong crew and the airship Silver Noah at his disposal, he's sure to turn up wherever foes are taking advantage of the weak. Abilities:Burn GroundTotal HealingGale FlashSlow EnemyMeteor ShowerTornadoMagic ShieldWeak EnemyRetaliationMight MindExpand RangeFire StormExplosionInvincibleIga was a monk at Amaidar Temple in Greyshinne during the events in the first Arc the Lad game, and now travels at Arc's side in the Silver Noah, unafraid to deliver justice on those who would harm the innocent. Abilities:Shingan-hoTaima-kodanSenpu-gekishuRyusei-bakuKijinryu-eihaMessho-reppaAmaidar FirstPower LossGround ShieldStrike PowerMud StormEarthquakeExtractChoko is a rambunctious little girl with the powers whom Chongara could use in battle in the first Arc the lad game. She is a cheery, funny and cute little girl who helps the heroes fight evil while trying to "grow up". Abilities:Pasha-PashaMeki-MekiHyururuMera-MeraEarthquakeBlizzardExplosionTornadoSuper NovaDeathDiebeck is a robot that was created to protect the world from evil. After having his power restored by Elc he joins them in the fight. Abilities: Unlike the other characters in the game his abilities change based on which power unit he has in place which include, fire,water,wind,earth and raw power.StoryElc a young hunter, a person who takes jobs from anything from hunting down criminals or providing protection for his clients finds himself waking up after a recurring nightmare that he has been having from his trouble past. As a young boy his village was attacked by a military group searching for the power of the flame. After his father was killed by the soldiers Elc summoned the power of the flame to kill his enemies overwhelmed by the power he passes out. Instead of killing the boy they take him as a prisoner so that they may use his power for their own gain.Not able to remember his dreams clearly or the events that has transpired Elc does recall a ship by the name of the Silver Noah who he has come to learn is flown by the criminal Arc. Elc takes a job that involves a terrorist attacking the local airport and runs to the rescue. Upon arriving at the scene he battles the terrorist after defeating the enemy he begins a chase to apprehend the suspect. While searching he finds a young girl hiding with her wolf companion inside one of the cargo bays of an airship. After defeating the terrorist Elc tries to obtain answers from him when he is mysteriously sniped and killed. Elc meets back up with the girl to find out why she is hiding when men in suits show up to take her away. Having been in the same situation as a kid Elc decides to protect her from the men when she is shot and he makes a daring escape with her down a zip line.Elc travels to the town of Indigos to meet with his friend Shu to hide out and find a doctor for the young girl Lieza. When the young girl is recovered from her injuries Shu, Elc and Lieza meet up with the local singer and dancer Shante to try and obtain information on the pursuers. In exchange for the information Shante asks if she can travel with the party so that she can find information on her missing brother who she believes is kidnapped by the same people.Traveling together taking jobs on the side to make money the team begins to find more information that children and adults are being held captive and turned into monsters. Determined to stop this the group begins their attack on the different labs through out the world. The group is separated and branch off on their own trying to stop the evil and find each other.Shu and Shante travel to a military airport in an attempt to hitch a ride to find their friends when Shante is thrown off the flying ship into the ocean below. Shu finds Elcs airship stored on the airship and travels to a city where he hears about a rebel group that is trying to stop the army from erecting a statue that will control the population and turn them into monsters. Shu tries to join the cause but is shot down by Tosh who is a companion of Arc.Determined to go back and save a child hood friend from the same center that Elc escaped from as a child he and Lieza break into the facility to not only destroy it but to free anyone else who is imprisoned.After awaking on the beach to find that she is still alive Shante meets the barbarian Grunga who is partaking in a local fighting tournament to win money to pay the doctors to restore his adopted daughters sight. After winning the tournament he joins Shante in her quest to stop the evil organization while leaving his daughter in the care of the inn keeper. Once her sight is restored she will know that he is not her true father and the best way to protect her is to leave.The heroes come back together at the main Chimera lab. While battling monsters and saving the people kidnapped people they run into Arc who with his ship the Silver Noah is attempting to stop the evil that is being done as well. Elc is injured in the fight and brought back to the temple to be healed by Kukuru the seal who is holding back the most vile evil of the world. She explains to his friends that she may be able to save his body but his mind is a battle in which he has to recover on his own. Once Elc awakens he is quick to notice that Arc is among the group and wants to take revenge on him for killing his family.Poco who has been with Arc after leaving the military takes Elc to the a destroyed castle to show him that Arc is not the evil that he has made out to be and that he is in fact a hero. After learning the truth Elc decides to join Arc and his crew to stop the evil that is in the world. Traveling from country to country the companions begin to over throw evil empires and stop monsters from hurting the people of Touvil.SoundtrackOST cover01 - Theme of Arc the Lad02 - Opening03 - The Four Generals04 - West Ardia05 - The Airport06 - Battle 107 - Meeting with Liza08 - Battle 209 - Theme of Elc10 - Theme of Shu11 - Battle 312 - Music Man13 - Prodius14 - Statue of a Goddess15 - Battle 416 - Memories17 - Yagos Island18 - Cave19 - Beach20 - Area Map21 - Galuerno's Mansion22 - Battle 523 - Sadness24 - Silver Noah Tactics Room25 - Suspicious Place26 - Battle 627 - Touville's Shrine28 - Theme of Liza29 - Theme of Gruger30 - Scrap Iron City31 - Battle with the Four Generals32 - Romalia33 - Time Battle34 - Anger35 - Father36 - Last Battle37 - Ending38 - And Tomorrow39 - Save  Load40 - Fanfare41 - Milmahna42 - Gleycine43 - Sumeria44 - Aliversha45 - Alarats46 - Niedel47 - SpiritUnlockablesHemo-Ji is unlocked by competing in the survival mode located at the monks temple once you complete 25 kills.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19864">Final Fantasy Tactics</game><game id="19905">Vandal Hearts</game><game id="8352">Vandal Hearts II</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9261/294012-arcthelad2alterntscj1qt8.jpg</image></root>