<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10688</id><name>Albatross18</name><description>OverviewAlbatross18 is the American version of the online golf title, Pangya. Developed by Korean developer, Ntreev Soft  and published in North America by Game Factory Inc [as known as OGPlanet]. While the title is free to download and play, certain items require real money to purchase. The rest of the items require Pang, the in-game currency. Pang is earned through various feats accomplished while playing A18. New characters have pang and real cash purchase options while decorations, clothes, clubs, caddies, etc. don't offer such options. Upgrading your characters and their clubs is only possible with pang. Ntreev Soft has been careful to balance out the benefits of cash and pang items, making everything fair game.GameplayAlbatross18 uses the tried-and-true "Three-Click System" used in most golf titles in the past. The first click starts the power gauge on the bottom of the screen, the second sets the power level of the shot, and the third click determines the accuracy. You do this by either pressing the 'Space Bar' or using the Left Mouse button. Hitting a perfect shot results in 'PANGYA' . Hitting PANGYA results in a straight full powered shot. Missing it will result in a slice, hook, shank or a miss and loss of overall power. Before each shot you can set the spin on your shot, use an item to assist you with your shot, use a power shot and set up for a special shot. When adding spin, you can curve a shot left or right. You can also add a backspin which gives your shot extra loft, increase your flying distance and lessen the roll with your landing. Or put a top spin on the ball to give the ball a lower trajectory at a faster velocity and increase the length of the roll after landing, although your total flying distance will be shortened. You can also combine a little bit of both worlds by adding a bit of spin and a bit of a curve to your shot if needed.Power Shots do as they sound - add distance to your shot. A normal Power Shot adds ten yards to your shot and can be activated by tapping ALT, while Double Power Shots add 20 yards and are triggered by quickly double-tapping ALT. Power Shots are unstable shots that lower your character's overall Control and Accuracy stats, making it more difficult to control the power gauge. Power Shots are required to perform any of the three Special Shots in the game: the Tomahawk, the Cobra, and the Spike Shot. All three Special Shots offer unique characteristics that allow a player to move the ball in ways not possible with a normal shot.</description><genres><genre id="28">Golf</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="24256">Super Swing Golf Season 2</game><game id="24570">Easy Golf</game><game id="35579">Hot Shots Golf: World Invitational</game><game id="25607">Pangya: Fantasy Golf</game><game id="22203">Super Swing Golf</game><game id="20598">Hot Shots Golf: Out of Bounds</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/7670/228362-pangya_art.jpg</image></root>