<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10775</id><name>WWF Royal Rumble</name><description>OverviewWWF Royal Rumble is LJN's "Sequel" to WWF Super Wrestlemania. WWF Royal Rumble features twelve wrestlers in each version, some wrestlers exclusive to each port of the game. There was an updated port featuring a bigger roster and other features added in called WWF Rage in the Cage released on the Sega CD. Both the SNES and Genesis versions of Royal Rumble support up to 2 players. Royal Rumble on the Genesis had a VRC (Video Game Rating Council) rating of GA for General Audience.Match TypesOne on One (One wrestler against one other wrestler)One Fall - First player to score a pinfall is the winner.Brawl - First player to deplete the other players energy bar is the winner.Tournament - Player must face all the opponents in order to get to the title.Tag-Team (Teams of two wrestlers. The "legal" wrestler must make a tag in order to switch.)One Fall - First team to score the pinfall is the winner.Brawl - First team to deplete the other teams energy bar is the winner.Tournament - Face all other superstars in tag teams to get to the titles.Triple Tag-Team (Teams of three wrestlers each. The "legal" wrestler must make a tag in order to switch.)One Fall - First Team to score the pinfall is the winner.Brawl - First team to deplete the other teams energy bar wins the match.Royal Rumble (Free for all 12 wrestler over the top rope battle royal.)EndingsSNES VersionOnce you have won the Royal Rumble whichever character you chose will raise their hands above their heads and the screen will fade to black. When the screen comes back it will list the times of all the entrants in the Royal Rumble match, then cycle through the order they were thrown out and by whom they were thrown out.Genesis VersionOnce you have beaten all the other characters, you will face the final wrestler. The final wrestler is Razor Ramon. After you defeat Razor an issue of WWF Magazine will fly at the screen featuring the wrestler chosen and the headline "New World's Champion."RosterFor a list of all characters in the game, see the guide.Critical ReceptionElectronic Gaming Monthly gave the review scores of 7,6,7,7 and 6. Mike Weigand, who gave the game a six, wrote, "Played the SNES version? This one is basically the same thing on a different platform. The colors are diminished somewhat, but wrestling fans will love it! Be sure to use the 6-button controller with this one!".</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="10">Wrestling</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16435">WWF Attitude</game><game id="13393">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW</game><game id="13445">WWE Raw 2</game><game id="17436">WWF SmackDown!</game><game id="16684">Saturday Night Slam Masters</game><game id="14721">Super Fire Pro Wrestling  X Premium</game><game id="4155">WWF Raw</game><game id="22273">WCW Superbrawl Wrestling</game><game id="30637">Lucha Libre AAA Heroes del Ring</game><game id="22268">WWF Rage in the Cage</game><game id="28430">WWF Royal Rumble</game><game id="43984">Super Fire Pro Wrestling</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/10/103881/1773102-rrgen.jpg</image></root>