<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10784</id><name>Arx Fatalis</name><description>OverviewArx Fatalis, developed by Arkane Studios, is a solitary first-person role-playing game that was originally envisioned as the third game in Looking Glass Studios' Ultima Underworld series, following in the footsteps of Ultima Underworld: The Stygian Abyss and Ultima Underworld II: Labyrinth of Worlds. Though the developers had the blessings of Looking Glass founder Paul Neurath, acquiring the rights to use the Ultima name from Electronic Arts, who had obtained them by purchasing their original publisher, Origin Systems, proved to be too difficult, and the idea of making it an official Ultima Underworld title was eventually abandoned. Despite not bearing its name, many elements of the final product, from its level-based underground structure to its runic magic system, will be immediately familiar to anyone who has played an Ultima Underworld game.PlotThe City of ArxThe events of Arx Fatalis take place in and around the city of Arx. Long before the events of the game, Arx was a prosperous city led by the noble King Poxsellis. This would soon change, however, as in the year 216 a meteor fell to earth, and soon thereafter the sky began to darken. Lunshire, the son and successor of King Poxsellis, seeing the gravity of this event, ordered the city to be moved into a nearby dwarven mine. The next five years would be an unprecedented time of cooperation among the races, as humans, dwarves, goblins, and trolls laid aside their enmities to ensure their collective survival. In return for their efforts, each race was given its own level of the mine. As work came to an end and all began to adjust to their new home, the sun over Arx went completely dark, and the surface world became a frozen inhospitable wasteland. Other fortresses such as Arx exist, though they can only be reached through dangerous treks across the planet's surface. Finding themselves in close proximity with their neighbors, the old animosities between races soon flared once more, and life in the underground world of Arx is every bit as contentious as it was on the surface.It is in this setting that the game begins, with the protagonist Am Shaegar awakening in a goblin prison. With no memory of his identity or purpose (Am Shaegar literally means "The Nameless One"), he immediately sets out to free himself. Not long after this is accomplished, he comes across the remains of a human outpost that was recently beset by Ylsides, a group of fearsome warriors. From there, Am Shaegar slowly discovers the plans of a shadowy cult intent on calling forth Akbaa, the God of Destruction, and allowing him to take form in the world of Arx. Discovering his purpose, he sets out to stop the cult of Akbaa or, barring that, to banish Akbaa back to the Noden, the realm of the gods, where he belongs.GameplayConvincing this goblin to open the portcullis is just one of many allusions to Ultima Underworld.Being that it was conceived as an Ultima Underworld title, gameplay in Arx Fatalis is heavily reminiscent of Looking Glass' signature RPG in many respects. Much like the aforementioned game, Arx Fatalis drops the player into a fairly large underground kingdom complete with various factions and hostile forces. Interacting with the world from a first-person perspective, players are free to approach the game at their own pace, with numerous side activities such as cooking and fishing available. While exploration is a key part of Arx Fatalis, it is not quite an open-world game, as the main quest line is very linear, and many parts of the world will be inaccessible until one has reached a certain point in the story. Nevertheless players are encouraged to go off the beaten path, often being rewarded with secret areas or new side quests for their efforts.Exploring the environment yields other benefits as well, as many types of items, such as potions, weapons, and food, can be created by the player provided they have the proper components. The latter is of particular importance, as In addition to raising one's overall statistics as in any RPG, players in Arx Fatalis are also tasked with maintaining the health of their avatar, with Am Shaegar needing to eat in order to stay in good condition (though he does not have to sleep as was required in Ultima Underworld).Main Races of ArxWith the cataclysmic climate change forcing their journey into the depths of the earth, the disparate clans of the surface world suddenly find themselves in very close proximity. Though an initial treaty ensures the cooperation of all races as they voyage underground, it is not long before old tensions resurface and the tight quarters of their new subterranean abode leads to disagreements. What follows is a list of the major factions that exist in the underworld of Arx.An Ice Dragon in her lairDragonsAmong the oldest and most powerful of the races of Arx, dragons are said to inhabit locations that reflect their abilities. They are intensely reclusive, so much so that many do not believe they exist. Due to the infrequency of their interaction with other races, very little is known about the origin and nature of their kind. Though they are usually not actively hostile toward outsiders they encounter, the problems of the rest of Arx do not seem to concern them, and they are usually reluctant to aid others when they do not personally benefit. For reasons unknown, all dragons possess no more and no less than 4,815 scales.The remains of a dwarven settlementDwarvesA race known for its industriousness and ingenuity, dwarves are typically craftsmen, tinkers, or smiths by trade. While other races live underground out of necessity, dwarves do so by choice, and can often be found much deeper below the surface than the people of other civilized nations. Having honed their talents in mining over decades, the exodus from the surface world put a premium on their skills, and many dwarves were influential in the creation of the various subterranean chambers the other races would come to inhabit. The location of what became the city of Arx was once in fact among the largest mines in the dwarven kingdom.The gluttonous Alotar, King of the GoblinsGoblinsThe most populous race of Arx due in no small part to their high birth rate, goblins are also among the surliest and most mistrustful of all underground inhabitants, being particularly suspicious of Humans. Due perhaps to a lack of strong leadership, goblins have never been able to translate their advantage in numbers into any real position of power, though they have cornered the gemstone market in no small part due to their exploitation of the slow-witted trolls. Aside from trolls, they have trouble outsmarting other races, though they are not above other forms of skulduggery when it will get them what they desire.King Lunshire, son of the late King PoxsellisHumansHumans are possibly the least well-suited to life under the surface, and as a result are not often found far from it. Nonetheless it was they who instigated the massive migration that saw the displacement and relocation of all the people of Arx, as well as the treaties that led to the creation of their new underground homes. These treaties did not hold long past the initial exodus, though humans still see themselves as leaders among the various underground populations despite their status as newcomers.Two Rat-Men attackingRat-MenLike dwarves, the rat-men were accustomed to life underground long before the migration. Often living in the sewers of human kingdoms, they are scavengers much like the common rat. They communicate non-verbally for the most part, which has not led to solid relationships with other races; these poor relations only worsened with the exodus to the underground, as the rat-men moved deeper into the earth, becoming even more elusive. Worsening the matter, they often attack outsiders on sight. They are lithe and nimble creatures, making them natural assassins.Mother Superior ZalnashhSisters of EdurneumSecond only to dragons in their mysteriousness, the members of the Order of Edurneum are a secretive and poorly understood group that is skilled in the arts of magic. Several basic facts about the sisters are unknown, such as their origin and manner of reproduction. In the absence of knowledge, many rumors have sprouted, such as notions that they are responsible for the creation of all magic in Arx. Though their overall goals are unclear, these serpentine women seem to have a particular interest in humans, having helped them at several crucial stages in their history.King Pog standing beside his throneTrollsWhile most similar in appearance to goblins, trolls could not be more different. Though not smart, trolls are generally easygoing and good-natured creatures, a fact that goblins are apt to exploit. They are not quick to anger, but when they feel they have been wronged their minds are not easily changed. Trolls are beings of simple pleasures and small ambition, and while they seem vaguely aware that the goblins are taking advantage of them, they are not particularly motivated to do anything about it.Character ProgressionAm Shaegar striking a suggestive pose on the Character SheetPlayers in Arx Fatalis do not choose from preset character classes as is common in many RPGs, but rather decide their specialization entirely through the selection of attributes and skills. A player's attributes are a selection of four statistics (Strength, Intelligence, Dexterity, and Constitution) that govern their overall strengths as well as determining what skills they have an affinity for. Skills are specific talents that represent a character's proficiency in a certain talent, such as melee or spellcasting. With each level gained a player may assign one point to an attribute and fifteen points toward skills.AttributesStrength - Determines damage inflicted by physical attacks and ability to use heavy equipment.Associated Skills: Close Combat, Projectile Weapons, Object KnowledgeIntelligence - Determines overall mana points and magic resistance.Associated Skills: Magic, Ethereal Link, Technical Skill, Object Knowledge.Dexterity - Determines critical chance and accuracy in combat.Associated Skills: Close Combat, Projectile Weapons, Stealth, Technical Skill, Object KnowledgeConstitiution - Determines overall hit points, physical resistance, and ability to use heavy equipment.Associated Skills: NoneCombatAn unfortunate rat on the receiving end of a Meteor SaberCombat in Arx Fatalis will be instantly recognizable to fans of Ultima Underworld. Melee and ranged combat alike are initiate first by readying one's weapon, which initiates combat mode. In this mode, a small gem appears at the bottom of the screen, which is the charge indicator. This indicator will slowly illuminate the longer the attack button is held, with a full charge being much more powerful than a normal strike. Furthermore, holding any direction when pressing attack will result in a different strike depending on the direction, from an overhead blow to a powerful thrust.Supplementing the combat system is an optional stealth mechanic which allows players who are skillful enough to avoid detection altogether. As is typical in such games, attacking from behind while undetected yields a significant damage bonus, and players with high enough stealth rating can pickpocket as well. Whenever a player is in conditions conducive to stealth, such as dim environments, an icon of a crouching man will appear in the lower left of the screen to indicate that the player's presence is hard to perceive.MagicA full Spell Book with all 20 runesLike much of the rest of the game, the magic system in Arx Fatalis is heavily inspired by Ultima Underworld. As in that game, spells are cast through special runic symbols whose associated runes must be found and memorized before use. These runes do not represent spells in and of themselves, but rather components of spells, with each rune possessing a fixed property that, when combined with other runes, can create various effects. To prevent the player from having to rely on trial and error in order to discover spells, the Spell Book is automatically updated with new possible rune combinations when a new rune word is memorized, though there are some spell that can only be discovered through experimentation.Once the necessary runes are contained in the Book of Magic, a spell is cast by tracing the corresponding symbols in the air. In order to prevent frantic spell casting in the midst of battle, and also to allow easy access to frequently used spells, up to three spells can be pre-cast and stored. Any pre-cast spell can be unleashed with a single button press at a later time.Rune (Property)All Affiliated Spell Phrases  EffectsAam (Creation)Chaos (Aam Mega Morte) - Unleashes a wave of explosions in a wide radius from the casting point.Feed (Aam Vitaé Cosum) - Creates a field around the player that magically satisfies hunger.Fireball (Aam Yok Taar) - Calls forth an explosive ball of flame that can be hurled in a straight line.Fire Field (Aam Yok Spacium) - Erects a wall of flame directly in front of the caster.Force Field (Aam Kaom Spacium) - A magical shield envelops the caster.Ignite (Aam Yok) - Sets fire to any flammable material near the caster, such as torches or kindling.Incinerate (Aam Mega Yok) - Causes the ground on which it is cast to burn intensely for a short time.Ice Patch (Aam Fridd Spacium) - Creates a stationary patch of ice that damages anyone that touches it.Ice Wave (Aam Fridd Taar) - A wave of ice issues forth from the spell's point of origin, traveling slowly forward.Lightning Projection (Aam Folgora Taar) - Creates a bolt of lightning that arcs directly in front of the player.Magic Missile (Aam Taar) - Fires a single bolt of non-elemental magical energy toward its target.Mass Incinerate (Mega Aam Mega Yok) - Invokes a much larger and more deadly ground fire than Incinerate.Mass Lightning Projection (Aam Folgora Spacium) - Similar to Lightning Projection, though with multiple bolts.Poison Cloud (Aam Cetrius Taar) - Creates a toxic cloud of gas directly in front of the casting position.Trap (Aam Morte Cosum) - Allows the placement of a magical trap at a specified location.Raise Dead (Aam Morte Vitaé) - Summons an undead minion to fight for the summoner.Summon (Aam Vitaé Tera) - Calls a random creature to the caster's side.Cetrius (Poision)Cure Poison (Nhi Cetrius) - Reverses the effects of the poison status ailment.Poison Cloud (Aam Cetrius Taar) - Creates a toxic cloud of gas directly in front of the casting position.Communicatum (Communication)Control Demon (Movis Communicatum) - This spell allows a conjured creature to be controlled by the spellcaster.Telekinesis (Spacium Communicatum) - Allows the player to manipulate objects outside their physical reach.Cosum (Object)Detect Trap (Morte Cosum Vista) - All nearby traps are marked with a distinctive color to reveal their presence.Disable Trap (Nhi Morte Cosum) - Disables all traps within a certain range of the spellcaster.Enchant Object (Mega Stregum Cosum) - Permanently imbues an object with an augmentative item.Feed (Aam Vitaé Cosum) - Creates a field around the player that magically satisfies hunger.Negate Magic (Nhi Stregum Cosum) - Prevents outside forces from magically harming the caster.Trap (Aam Morte Cosum) - Allows the placement of a magical trap at a specified location.Folgora (Storm)Lightning Projection (Aam Folgora Taar) - Creates a bolt of lightning that arcs directly in front of the player.Mass Lightning Projection (Aam Folgora Spacium) - Similar to Lightning Projection, though with multiple bolts.Fridd (Ice)Cold Protection (Fridd Kaom) - Shields the target from ice-based damage for a time.Ice Patch (Aam Fridd Spacium) - Creates a stationary patch of ice that damages anyone that touches it.Ice Wave (Aam Fridd Taar) - A wave of ice issues forth from the spell's point of origin, traveling slowly forward.Kaom (Protection)Armor (Mega Kaom) - Significantly increases the defense rating of a single target.Cold Protection (Fridd Kaom) - Shields the target from ice-based damage for a time.Fire Protection (Yok Kaom) - Increases fire resistance for the duration of the spell.Force Field (Aam Kaom Spacium) - A magical shield envelops the caster.Lower Armor (Rhaa Kaom) - The defensive rating of a single target is diminished briefly.Repel Undead (Morte Kaom) - Any undead within a certain radius will move away from the player.Mega (Augmentation)Activate Portal (Mega Spacium) - Activates a nearby portal, allowing easy access to other levels.Armor (Mega Kaom) - Significantly increases the defense rating of a single target.Bless (Mega Stregum Vitaé) - Boosts the main statistics (Strength, Dexterity, etc.) of its target for a short period.Chaos (Aam Mega Morte) - Unleashes a wave of explosions in a wide radius from the casting point.Enchant Object (Mega Stregum Cosum) - Permanently imbues an object with an augmentative item.Heal (Mega Vitaé) - Temporarily surrounds the caster in an energy field that heal vitality.Incinerate (Aam Mega Yok) - Causes the ground on which it is cast to burn intensely for a short time.Levitate (Mega Spacium Movis) - Allows the caster to hover at a set elevation above the ground.Mass Incinerate (Mega Aam Mega Yok) - Invokes a much larger and more deadly ground fire than Incinerate.Mass Paralyze (Mega Nhi Movis) - Paralyzes any targets caught within range of the spell.Nightvision (Mega Vista) - Allows better sight and increased awareness of hidden objects in the environment.Speed (Mega Movis) - Momentarily augments the speed of a target.Morte (Death)Chaos (Aam Mega Morte) - Unleashes a wave of explosions in a wide radius from the casting point.Detect Trap (Morte Cosum Vista) - All nearby traps are marked with a distinctive color to reveal their presence.Disable Trap (Nhi Morte Cosum) - Disables all traps within a certain range of the spellcaster.Raise Dead (Aam Morte Vitaé) - Summons an undead minion to fight for the summoner.Repel Undead (Morte Kaom) - Any undead within a certain radius will move away from the player.Trap (Aam Morte Cosum) - Allows the placement of a magical trap at a specified location.Movis (Movement)Control Demon (Movis Communicatum) - This spell allows a conjured creature to be controlled by the spellcaster.Drain Life (Vitaé Movis) - Creates a field around the player that leeches life from enemies.Flying Eye (Vista Movis) - Creates a player-controlled eye that scouts unknown areas without alerting enemies.Levitate (Mega Spacium Movis) - Allows the caster to hover above the ground, though without alteration of height.Mana Drain (Stregum Movis) - Drains mana points from any mana-using target.Mass Paralyze (Mega Nhi Movis) - Paralyzes any targets caught within range of the spell.Paralysis (Nhi Movis) - Targets affected by Paralysis are completely immobile, though for only a short period.Slow (Rhaa Movis) - Dramatically decreases a single target's speed.Speed (Mega Movis) - Momentarily augments the speed of a target.Nhi (Negation)Cure Poison (Nhi Cetrius) - Reverses the effects of the poison status ailment.Disable Trap (Nhi Morte Cosum) - Disables all traps within a certain range of the spellcaster.Dispel Field (Nhi Spacium) - Negates force fields, mainly used for clearing blocked passages.Douse (Nhi Yok) - Puts out any lights in the immediate vicinity, as well as negating certain fire spells.Invisibility (Nhi VIsta) - Renders the caster invisible. Any interaction with the environment will break the effect.Mass Paralyze (Mega Nhi Movis) - Paralyzes any targets caught within range of the spell.Negate Magic (Nhi Stregum Cosum) - Prevents outside forces from magically harming the caster.Paralysis (Nhi Movis) - Targets affected by Paralysis are completely immobile, though for only a short period.Reveal (Nhi Stregum Vista) - Dispels illusions and allows its caster to see otherwise hidden objects.Rhaa (Weakness)Confusion (Rhaa Vista) - Confuses an opponent, causing it to behave erratically.Curse (Rhaa Stregum Vitaé) - The opposite of Bless, this spell lowers the target's main statistics.Harm (Rhaa Vitae) - Does direct non-elemental damage to targets in a radius.Lower Armor (Rhaa Kaom) - The defensive rating of a single target is diminished briefly.Slow (Rhaa Movis) - Dramatically decreases a single target's speed.Slow Time (Rhaa Tempus) - The caster moves at normal speed while all enemies have their speed reduced.Spacium (Space)Activate Portal (Mega Spacium) - Activates a nearby portal, allowing easy access to other levels.Dispel Field (Nhi Spacium) - Negates force fields, mainly used for clearing blocked passages.Ice Patch (Aam Fridd Spacium) - Creates a stationary patch of ice that damages anyone that touches it.Fire Field (Aam Yok Spacium) - Erects a wall of flame directly in front of the caster.Force Field (Aam Kaom Spacium) - A magical shield envelops the caster.Levitate (Mega Spacium Movis) - Allows the caster to hover above the ground, though without alteration of height.Mass Lightning Projection (Aam Folgora Spacium) - Similar to Lightning Projection, though with multiple bolts.Telekinesis (Spacium Communicatum) - Allows the player to manipulate objects outside their physical reach.Stregum (Magic)Bless (Mega Stregum Vitaé) - Boosts the main statistics (Strength, Dexterity, etc.) of its target for a short period.Curse (Rhaa Stregum Vitaé) - The opposite of Bless, this spell lowers the target's main statistics.Enchant Object (Mega Stregum Cosum) - Permanently imbues an object with an augmentative item.Mana Drain (Stregum Movis) - Drains mana points from any mana-using target.Negate Magic (Nhi Stregum Cosum) - Prevents outside forces from magically harming the caster.Reveal (Nhi Stregum Vista) - Dispels illusions and allows its caster to see otherwise hidden objects.Taar (Projectile)Fireball (Aam Yok Taar) - Calls forth an explosive ball of flame that can be hurled in a straight line.Ice Wave (Aam Fridd Taar) - A wave of ice issues forth from the spell's point of origin, traveling slowly forward.Lightning Projection (Aam Folgora Taar) - Creates a bolt of lightning that arcs directly in front of the player.Magic Missile (Aam Taar) - Fires a single bolt of non-elemental magical energy toward its target.Poison Cloud (Aam Cetrius Taar) - Creates a toxic cloud of gas directly in front of the casting position.Tempus (Time)Slow Time (Rhaa Tempus) - The caster moves at normal speed while all enemies have their speed reduced.Tera (Earth)Summon (Aam Vitaé Tera) - Calls a random creature to the caster's side.Vista (Sight)Confusion (Rhaa Vista) - Confuses an opponent, causing it to behave erratically.Detect Trap (Morte Cosum Vista) - All nearby traps are marked with a distinctive color to reveal their presence.Flying Eye (Vista Movis) - Creates a player-controlled eye that scouts unknown areas without alerting enemies.Invisibility (Nhi VIsta) - Renders the caster invisible. Any interaction with the environment will break the effect.Nightvision (Mega Vista) - Allows better sight and increased awareness of hidden objects in the environment.Reveal (Nhi Stregum Vista) - Dispels illusions and allows its caster to see otherwise hidden objects.Vitaé (Life)Bless (Mega Stregum Vitaé) - Boosts the main statistics (Strength, Dexterity, etc.) of its target for a short period.Curse (Rhaa Stregum Vitaé) - The opposite of Bless, this spell lowers the target's main statistics.Drain Life (Vitaé Movis) - Creates a field around the player that leeches life from enemies.Feed (Aam Vitaé Cosum) - Creates a field around the player that magically satisfies hunger.Harm (Rhaa Vitae) - Does direct non-elemental damage to targets in a radius.Heal (Mega Vitaé) - Temporarily surrounds the caster in an energy field that heal vitality.Raise Dead (Aam Morte Vitaé) - Summons an undead minion to fight for the summoner.Summon (Aam Vitaé Tera) - Calls a random creature to the caster's side.Yok (Fire)Douse (Nhi Yok) - Puts out any lights in the immediate vicinity, as well as negating certain fire spells.Fireball (Aam Yok Taar) - Calls forth an explosive ball of flame that can be hurled in a straight line.Fire Field (Aam Yok Spacium) - Erects a wall of flame directly in front of the caster.Fire Protection (Yok Kaom) - Increases fire resistance for the duration of the spell.Ignite (Aam Yok) - Sets fire to any flammable material near the caster, such as torches or kindling.Incinerate (Aam Mega Yok) - Causes the ground on which it is cast to burn intensely for a short time.Mass Incinerate (Mega Aam Mega Yok) - Invokes a much larger and more deadly ground fire than Incinerate.Food PreparationAm Shaegar searing a couple racks of rat ribsThough it is a fairly rudimentary one, Arx Fatalis contains its own in-game food preparation system that allows for various types of consumables to be combined, cooked, or both. Most of these recipes consist of simple, one-step procedures, such as heating raw meat in order to create cooked meat, though a few of them are slightly more involved. Baking an apple pie is perhaps the most complicated recipe, as it requires the player to create dough, roll it, add apples, and then cook it. What follows are some of the more common food combinations.RecipesWater  Flour = DoughDough  Fire = BreadDough  Rolling Pin = Uncooked PieDough  Apple = Uncooked Apple PieAny Uncooked Pie  Fire = Cooked PieAny Uncooked Meat  Fire = Cooked MeatPotion MixingA still and several potion-making componentsThough slightly more involved than cooking, potion creation follows the same basic idea of item collection and combination. There are three steps involved in creating a potion. The first step is to convert the component ingredient into a powder through use of a mortar and pestle. Next, the newly created powder must be funneled into an empty bottle. Finally, the ingredient must be heated with a distillation apparatus to create the final product. All potions are created from plant matter, with each plant producing a set type of potion.FormulaeFern - PoisonMedicinal Herb - AntidoteMorning Glory - Mana PotionSnowdrop Flower - Invisibility PotionWater Lily - Life PotionLater Support and Source Code ReleaseIn an unusual move, Arkane Studios, nearly a decade after the game's initial launch, patched Arx Fatalis to version 1.21, primarily to increasing performance and compatibility on more modern systems. The game's source code was released at the same time, and while it is uncommon for a single-player game to be patched so long after its release, some speculate that it might be a means of increasing awareness of the relatively unknown developer before the announcement of their newest project.System RequirementsMinimumOperating System: Windows 98/ME/2000/XPProcessor: Intel Pentium II 500 MHzRAM Memory: 64MBHard Drive Space: 750MBVideo Card: 16MB DirectX 8.0-compatibleDirectX: 8.0Sound Card: DirectX 8.0-compatibleRecommendedProcessor: Intel Pentium III 900 MHzRAM Memory: 256MBVideo Card: 32MB DirectX 8.0-compatible</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6413">Ultima Underworld: The Stygian Abyss</game><game id="17367">The Elder Scrolls III: Morrowind</game><game id="20238">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion</game><game id="8147">Ultima Underworld II: Labyrinth of Worlds</game><game id="15065">Dark Messiah of Might &amp; Magic</game><game id="16927">Gothic II: Night of the Raven</game><game id="1982">Gothic</game><game id="1804">Gothic II</game><game id="15660">Hexen II</game><game id="20198">Mordor: The Depths of Dejenol</game><game id="9802">Demise: Rise of the Ku'tan</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/11/118253/1713096-arxfatalispcboxart.png</image></root>