<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10796</id><name>EverQuest</name><description>OverviewEverQuestEverQuest was and is a pioneer of the MMORPG genre by attracting mass appeal to the game format and setting the standard of the subscription model for persistent worlds. Released in the Spring of 1999, when online gaming was still in its early years, Sony originally did not believe EverQuest would be nearly the success that it became. It was published under the 989 Studios brand, developed by Verant Interactive. Not long after the game's release, Sony absorbed Verant and continued to develop new content for EverQuest under a new studio name; Sony Online Entertainment. Since 1999, the world of EverQuest has grown thanks to seventeen full expansions and countless content updates. The roaring success of the game has not only led to new entries in the EverQuest franchise, but also laid the foundation for all future massively multiplayer online games.EverQuest ClassicInformation on this page is based on the original game, before any expansions. Additions to the classes, races, and geography will be found on the respective expansion's page. There are a few exceptions to this, as several zones were added to the "old world" regions of the game that were not part of any particular expansion. These zones will be listed here for lack of a better place to document their existence.ClassesEverQuest originally offered fourteen playable classes each with their own unique strengths and weaknesses. Among the class types are three fighters (monk, rogue, warrior), three priests (cleric, druid, shaman), four casters (enchanter, magician, necromancer, wizard), and four hybrids (bard, paladin, ranger, shadow knight). Most players often decide what class to play before selecting one of the available races to that class.BardBardBards are the "do it all" class. They can sneak and pick locks like a rogue, track and forage like druids and rangers, dual wield and wear plate like warriors, and use songs to mimic the effects all types of casters. The catch is that they are not as skilled in any of these abilities as the class associated with the skill. One thing bards have over everyone though is speed. A bard with good percussion skill can run faster than anyone. Skilled bards can even twist multiple songs together for combined effects on themselves or their group.ClericClericClerics are the masters of healing and resurrection. Clerics also wield some of the best health and armor buffs in all of Norrath. They have the ability to not only cure poison and disease effects, but even protect their friends from these status effects with a line of resist buffs. Clerics do have the ability to wear plate armor, but do not usually have the ability to solo well. Although, they do excel in combat against undead. The resurrection line of spells cast by clerics allows them to not only bring back fallen friends, but also restore the experience lost in the death. Clerics can also get themselves out of certain death with the most powerful shield buff int he game, Divine Aura, which renders them invincible for a short time, but without the ability to cast or attack.DruidDruidDruids are guardians of nature. As such, they can use nature in a myriad of ways. They can heal and buff allies similar to clerics, but can also wield fire and stinging swarms of insects to attack their enemies. One of the most important skills of a druid though is their ability to teleport to various locations around the world. With this skill, druids can mobilize a group of adventurers with great haste, and also make a decent amount of coin serving as Norrath's taxi for high level players. Druids are limited to wearing cloth or leather armor, but can use their root and snare spells to keep enemies at a distance. They, along with rangers and shaman, wield arguably the most sought after buff in all of Norrath, Spirit of Wolf. Although, SoW and many of a druid's spells cannot be cast indoors.EnchanterEnchanterEnchanters are casters that focus on the manipulation of the mind and deception. They have the ability to mesmerize enemies in order to easily fight a mob one at a time, or even charm an enemy to use it against its cohorts. Enchanters also have the ability to cast illusion spells on themselves to change their appearance to any race. And since most enchanters are agnostic, they can get into most any city in Norrath without catching a glaring eye. Aside from their crowd control abilities, groups of adventurers will often search for an enchanter to join them for their ability to cast haste upon their melee classes. A good enchanter often is the most valuable asset a group can have, but a weak enchanter will often result in a party's demise. Enchanters, like other casters, are limited to cloth armor.MagicianMagicianMagicians are the masters of elemental magic ( earth, fire, air, water) as well as the arts of summoning. A mage alone can be powerful, but when he/she brings an army of pets, that mage becomes deadly. Magicians can summon a pet of any of the four elements, each with its pros and cons to fit any scenario. They can also protect themselves with the phantom armor line of spells and the best damage shield in the land. In the realm of casters, magicians are second only to wizards when it comes to direct damage, but a magician's pet can often make up the difference. Mages can also debuff enemies by lowering their resistance to elemental magic. Aside from their ability to summon pets and weapons, they can also summon food and drink. Many magicians can excel at soloing, and their pet can often be a sacrificial lamb as the magician runs for the hills if a fight gets too heated. Magicians, like other casters, are limited to cloth armor.MonkMonkMonks are some of the most fearsome fighters in all of Norrath. While living a life of poverty and limited to cloth or leather armor, they are masters of hand-to-hand combat. While they do have the ability to wield blunt weapons, most monks rely only upon their fists and feet. A monk in a solid group of adventurers fully buffed can be unstoppable, but even a solo monk can excel in Norrath thanks to their ability to mend wounds and feign death. When a situation appears to be too overwhelming, monks can feign death, wait for the enemies to leave, then make an escape. This ability also makes monks sought after by groups of adventurers as monks can use this ability to "pull" enemies one at a time to the group instead of several at once. Monks are limited with how much equipment they can carry. If a monk is carrying more than 15 stone, they begin to lose armor class.NecromancerNecromancerNecromancers are seekers of darkness and evil. They are the masters of all things dead. Though physically weak, necromancers can summon undead soldiers to do their bidding and wield spells that inflict poison and disease upon their foes. Most factions within Norrath find necromancers repulsive, which is meaningless to most necromancers because they are arguably the best soloing class in the world. Like monks, they have the ability to feign death, but with their Harmshield spell, they have two ways to escape death (three if you include Gate). A skilled necromancer does not die very often. They are also the masters of damage over time spells, which whittle away at their enemy's health while their undead minion bludgeons them. Necromancers, like other casters, are limited to cloth armor.PaladinPaladinPaladins are the knights of all that is good and just. They are given the duty of defending against darkness and evil at all costs. Paladins are essentially a hybrid of the warrior and cleric classes. While nowhere near the healing ability of a cleric, paladins do carry the powerful ability to Lay on Hands, which instantly fully heals its target, but can only be used once per day. Much like clerics, paladins excel against undead. They do not have the ability to dual wield, but can deal heavy damage with an assortment of two-handed weapons or protect themselves with a weapon and shield combination. Paladins can wear any of the four armor types, but most often choose plate.RangerRangerRangers are a hybrid of warriors and druids. They possess the ability to not only dual wield, but are second to none in the field of ranged weapons. They are also masters of tracking, which allows them to locate specific targets from great distances, or avoid danger in some circumstances. Rangers are limited to chainmail, which hinders their ability to tank when compared to paladins or warriors, but with the use of their druid spells and archery, they can solo from a distance. In groups, rangers off a myriad of skills that can benefit their friends whether its tracking, pulling, foraging food/water, or of course Spirit of Wolf.RogueRogueRogues are the masters of stealth and weaponry. They truly shine when in a group of adventurers where the enemy is focused on others, which allows the rogue to prove himself/herself as the best damage dealing melee class thanks to their backstab ability. Rogues can also work as scouts for their allies using the sneak/hide ability that allows them to traverse unseen by most enemies. This also allows rogues to retrieve fallen friends' bodies from the clutches of enemy camps. In many dungeons, there are locked doors that can be picked by having an adept rogue in your group. Rogues are relegated to leather or chain armor and cannot solo very well considering most of their damage is dealt from behind an enemy. Rogues also have the unique skill of poisoncrafting, which allows them to increase the already lethal damage of their blades with the application of status affecting poisons. They can also pick the pockets of most enemies, taking money and valuable gems before the rest of the group knows what loot the enemy carried.Shadow KnightShadow KnightShadow Knights are a hybrid of warriors and necromancers, and are renowned as the most evil and feared fighters in all of Norrath. Even in their own home towns they are often shunned and kept out of sight. They are essentially the polar opposite of paladins. Rather than having the ability to Lay on Hands, shadow knights have the ability to Harm Touch once a day, dealing massive amounts of damage to a single target. Shadow Knights, like paladins, can either wield a shield, or go all offense with a two-handed weapon. Their limited skills in necromancy allow them to cast damage over time spells, snare their enemies, and also summon undead minions. They focus their hatred for all things pure into a fearsome offensive assault from all angles. These hybrids can wear any of the four types of armor, but almost always choose to wear plate as soon as they can afford it.ShamanShamanShaman are one of the most versatile classes in the game, but their strength comes in the form of their many buffs and debuffs that they offer a group of adventurers. They melee better than either of the other two priest classes ( cleric and druid), and along with their healing and health buffs, they offer haste. One of their most powerful spells comes in their ability to slow enemies, keeping damage to the party's tank to a minimum. While their healing skills do not match that of a cleric, a shaman lighten the load on a cleric with his/her regeneration line of spells. Shaman have the unique trade skill to craft potions, which can be sold to others adventurers giving them the ability of invisibility, Spirit of Wolf, teleportation, illusion and many other things. Shaman can wear chainmail, which enhances their ability to mitigate damage while working their magics.WarriorWarriorWarriors are the tanks of Norrath. They don't deal the most damage, but they are second to none in mitigating damage. Warriors come equipped with various melee skills including bash, dual wield, double attack, parry, riposte, dodge, taunt, and disarm. Although they wield all of these abilities, they have absolutely no magic ability, which means they cannot solo very well. Even a great warrior is dependent upon a great partner or team to keep him/her standing toe-to-toe with the enemy. Their main task is keeping the enemy at hand focused on him/her so that the rest of his/her team can do what they do best uninterrupted. So, while warriors need others to excel, everyone needs a good warrior. They can wear any of the four types of armor, but would be unwise not to wear plate as soon as it becomes available to them.WizardWizardWizards are undoubtedly the masters of damage. No one, caster or melee, can kill something faster than an uninterrupted, adept wizard. Just like any other caster, they will not survive long against direct melee from an enemy, but they can often go it alone and use their skills to kite enemies from a distance. In a group, an experienced wizard can quickly drain the health of an enemy without drawing attention to himself/herself. Wizards also have the ability of teleportation, which can be used to travel great distances quickly, alone or with their friends. This skill also allows the wizard to get his/her friends out of immediate danger. Unlike druids though, wizards are the only class with the ability to take adventurers to the Planes of Hate and Sky. Wizards, like other casters, are limited to cloth armor.RacesEverQuest originally offered twelve playable races that could start in one of thirteen starting cities. Each race is limited to a certain number of classes based on their own abilities and religious beliefs. Choosing what race to play is second in importance to deciding on which class.BarbarianBarbarianBarbarians hail from the frozen city of Halas and are most often followers of The Tribunal. Halas sends forth many fierce warriors, adept shaman, and surprisingly sneaky rogues. Many barbarians, known also as the Wolves of the North, are isolationists, which makes sense given their home town is nestled far away from anyone else in the icy Everfrost Peaks. Barbarians make great warriors due to their size, innate strength, and stamina. They are welcomed in most 'good' cities, although their size can hinder their ability to do business in buildings found in Kelethin or Ak'anon. Like their human cousins, barbarians have no enhanced vision, making traveling at night dangerous. They also start with an extra +10 cold resistance, and unlike any other race, can wear both medium and large armor.ClassStrengthStaminaAgilityDexterityWisdomIntelligenceCharismaBonus PointsRogue103959280706055+30Shaman1031008270806060+30Warrior1131058770706055+23Dark ElfDark ElfDark Elves are Innoruuk's corrupted version of Norrath's elven population. They refer to themselves as the Teir`Dal, devoting their lives to the Prince of Hate, and embark on a journey to spread hate and cruelty. Unlike the ogres and trolls though, dark elves are highly intelligent. They reside in the underground city of Neriak where they are trained to exterminate all other races. Neriak produces casters of all types (wizards, magicians, enchanters), but necromancers are held in the highest regard. Other dark elves train to become warriors, shadow knights, clerics, and rogues. They do not tolerate ogres and trolls for their devotion to hate and fear, but simply use these often dimwitted mastodons as tools for achieving their own goals. Dark elves realize that their ways are not accepted by most other races throughout Norrath and will often perform tasks in order to raise their faction enough to at least be tolerated in larger cities such as Freeport. All dark elves are born with ultravision, which allows them to see as clearly in the dark as they do during the day. They all have the ability to hide, and they can wear small or medium armor.ClassStrengthStaminaAgilityDexterityWisdomIntelligenceCharismaBonus PointsCleric65709075939960+30Enchanter606590758310970+30Magician607590758310960+30Necromancer606590858310960+30Rogue606510085839960+30Shadow Knight707090758310965+20Warrior70759575839960+25Wizard607590758310960+30DwarfDwarfDwarves were created by The Duke of Below, Brell Serilis, in the depths of Butcherblock Mountains, which is where they still reside. The city of Kaladim produces some of the fiercest warriors and paladins, but also some of the most skilled clerics and most dexterous rogues. As residents of Faydwer, the dwarves are friendly with both the elves and gnomes, and also any other good-natured cities. They do not tolerate the likes of dark elves or trolls, and have a long history of war with the ogres. Living daily life in the caves of Kaladim, dwarves are born with infravision, enhancing their sight in the dark. They also have an innate sense of direction and begin with plus +5 resistance to both poison and magic. Dwarves can only wear small armor.ClassStrengthStaminaAgilityDexterityWisdomIntelligenceCharismaBonus PointsCleric95957090936045+30Paladin100957090886050+20Rogue909080100836045+30Warrior1001007590836045+25EruditeEruditeErudites believe they are the next step in the evolutionary chart after humans, just as the humans evolved from the barbarians. They are the most intelligent race found on Norrath and, therefore, excel as enchanters, magicians, and wizards. Led by a man named Erud, they left the city of Qeynos and founded the city of Erudin on the small continent of Odus. Before long, a rebel faction led by a man named Miragul, broke away from Erudin and founded the city of Paineel where he and his followers could freely practice necromancy. Miragul and his people are referred to as Heretics by those true to Erudin. There are a few Erudites that devote their lives to Prexus or Quellious as a cleric. And depending upon which city they're born, Erudites can also become paladins or shadow knights. Like other humans, Erudites have no enhanced vision, making the darkness of night difficult to deal with. All Erudites have an innate plus +5 to magic resistance, -5 to disease resistance, and wear medium armor.ClassStrengthStaminaAgilityDexterityWisdomIntelligenceCharismaBonus PointsCleric657670709310770+30Enchanter607070708311780+30Magician608070708311770+30Necromancer607070808311770+30Paladin707570708810780+20Shadow Knight707570708311775+20Wizard608070708311770+30GnomeGnomeGnomes are the smallest race and were also created by Brell Serilis. Although small, gnomes are highly intelligent, which is why many decide to become casters. A few gnomes choose to devote their lives to Brell as a cleric, but their low wisdom makes it a struggle. Their size also grants them great agility and dexterity, which makes for excellent rogues and an occasional warrior. Gnomes make their home in the ancient city of Ak'anon in the Steamfont Mountains. While most gnomes are good-natured, there are those that dwell below the city practicing the arts of necromancy, worshiping other gods, and training to become conniving thieves. All gnomes have an affinity for mechanics, and as such, they have the unique skill of tinkering. Gnomes also have infravision, enhancing their vision in the caves of Ak'anon and any other darkness. And, obviously, they wear only small armor.ClassStrengthStaminaAgilityDexterityWisdomIntelligenceCharismaBonus PointsCleric65708585779860+30Enchanter607085856710870+30Magician608085856710860+30Necromancer607085956710860+30Paladin70758585729870+20Rogue60709595679860+30Shadow Knight707585856710865+20Warrior70809085679860+25Wizard608085856710860+30Half ElfHalf ElfHalf Elves, as their name would suggest, are half human and half elf. The elven half is almost always from a wood elf, for the high elves do not see the humans as equals. While half elves are generally good-natured, they are often nomads as they are not fully accepted in either the human or elven cities. Because of this, many half elves become rangers or druids wandering the wilderness. Some become bards, traveling the world to their own tune. Others struggle with their lack of acceptance and become rogues. And occasionally, a half elf will choose to try to gain acceptance by becoming a warrior or paladin for their chosen home town, whether it is in Qeynos, Freeport, Kelethin, or rarely in Felwithe. Half elves do get infravision from their elven parent, and are able to wear medium armor like their human parent.ClassStrengthStaminaAgilityDexterityWisdomIntelligenceCharismaBonus PointsBard75709095607585+25Druid70809085657575+30Paladin80759085657585+25Ranger758010085657575+20Rogue707010095607575+30Warrior80809585607575+25HalflingHalflingHalflings are a humble, laid back race of people that live in the town of Rivervale, which is located in central Antonica. They are known across Norrath for their skills in both baking and brewing, most notably with jumjum. Most halflings are content with becoming farmers, merchants, fishermen, or crafters. But some halflings decide to journey outside of the thicket becoming some the best druids and rogues the world has seen. Some join the defense of the great wall and become warriors, and there are a few who join the Church of Mischief as devout clerics of Bristlebane. Halflings have great agility and dexterity, with surprising strength for their size. They are also wiser than their laid back demeanor would lead most to believe. Although not very attractive, halflings are some of the kindest people you'll find. All halflings can see fairly well in the dark thanks to infravision, and they have +5 resistance to both poison and disease. Even the warriors, clerics, and druids have the ability to sneak and hide, and all halflings wear small armor.ClassStrengthStaminaAgilityDexterityWisdomIntelligenceCharismaBonus PointsCleric75809590906750+30Druid70859590906750+30Paladin80809590856760+20Ranger758510590856750+20Rogue7075105100806750+30Warrior808510090806750+25High ElfHigh ElfHigh Elves are the original race created by Tunare, the Mother of All. They refer to themselves as the Koada`Dal. Their nobles were abducted by Innoruuk long ago in his creation of the dark elves. The high elves were then driven from their homes in Tunaria by Solusek Ro, the Burning Prince, when he scorched the forests into deserts. The elves who survived made new homes on the continent of Faydwer in Castle Felwithe. Even now, they are constantly attacked by Innoruuk's abominations as he has now twisted his own race of orcs into attack the elves. High elves are more intelligent than their nature loving cousins, the wood elves. Many high elves become excellent enchanters, magicians, and wizards. While intelligent, they are also quite wise, which lends to their adeptness as clerics and paladins. All high elves are good-natured, but are often found to be rude or prude by other races. Those other races won't kill high elves on sight as they would dark elves, but merchants may charge a higher price or simply not to talk high elves at all. High elves can see decently in the dark thanks to infravision, and they can wear either small or medium armor.ClassStrengthStaminaAgilityDexterityWisdomIntelligenceCharismaBonus PointsCleric607085701059280+30Enchanter556585709510290+30Magician557585709510280+30Paladin657085701009290+20Wizard557585709510280+30HumanHumanHumans of Norrath can choose almost any profession and can either come from the west coast city of Qeynos or the east coast city of Freeport. They have the most balanced distribution of base statistics and can align themselves with almost any god, good or evil. The only class unavailable to humans is shaman, but they do have the unique option of being monks. Humans have no enhanced vision in the dark and only wear medium armor.ClassStrengthStaminaAgilityDexterityWisdomIntelligenceCharismaBonus PointsBard80757585757585+25Cleric80807575857575+30Druid75857575857575+30Enchanter75757575758585+30Magician75857575758575+30Monk80808585757575+20Necromancer75757585758575+30Paladin85807575807585+20Rogue75758585757575+30Shadow Knight85807575758580+20Warrior85858075757575+25Wizard75857575758575+30OgreOgreOgres were created by The Warlord, Rallos Zek, as the greatest race of soldiers ever created. The ogres of ancient times were also highly intelligent and wielded powerful magics along with their brute strength, but their vanity became their downfall as they attempted an assault, along with Zek's other creations (giants and goblins) upon the gods themselves. In defeat, Zek's children were cursed by the other gods. The giants are almost completely extinct; the goblins' history was eradicated; and ogres lost almost all of their intelligence. The ogres of today are forced to rely primarily on their size and unmatched strength to crush their foes. Some ogres have retained enough wisdom to become shaman, and some struggle to learn the ways of necromancy by becoming shadow knights. But, most commonly, ogres leave Oggok on a warpath of destruction as the most fearsome warriors in all of Norrath. Ogres are friendly with the neighboring trolls and are tolerated by the dark elves, while some ogres have gone out of their way to prove themselves to the humans and are allowed in Freeport. All ogres have the ability to slam opponents, infravision to see in the swamp's darkness, and wear only large armor. They are also weak to fire.ClassStrengthStaminaAgilityDexterityWisdomIntelligenceCharismaBonus PointsShadow Knight1401277070677042+20Shaman1301277070776042+30Warrior1401327570676037+25TrollTrollTrolls are much like their neighboring ogres. Large, strong, and dim-witted. Trolls, though, don't have a curse to blame; that's just how they are. The biggest perk about trolls though is their innate regenerative ability. They regenerate health faster than any other race. That combined with their strength and stamina make them some of the best warriors in the land. Also like ogres, some trolls attempt to learn the arts of alchemy and necromancy by becoming shaman and shadow knights in their devotion to hate and fear. Trolls are often found trading with merchants in Oggok when items cannot be found in their own home of Grobb. They are hated and feared by most other races, which is how they like it. Trolls wear only large armor.ClassStrengthStaminaAgilityDexterityWisdomIntelligenceCharismaBonus PointsShadow Knight1171148375606245+20Shaman1081148375705242+30Warrior1181198875605240+25Wood ElfWood ElfWood Elves, along with the high elves, were driven from Tunaria (now Antonica) by Solusek Ro. While the high elves built the glorious Castle Felwithe, the wood elves built a magnificent treetop city known as Kelethin. Wood elves are not nearly as arrogant as their high elf cousins, which explains the existence of half elves. As one would imagine, wood elves are devout followers of Tunare and all of her creations. They lack strength but make up for it with their agility and dexterity. Wood elves make for excellent druids and rangers. Some spread the word of Tunare as bards. Kelethin also produces rogues they call scouts sent forth to collect intelligence on their enemies. And a few wood elves discard their empathy for nature and take on a life of defending the city as a warrior. All of them have infravision, helping them see through the darkness of the forest. They also have the ability to forage food and water. Like other elves, they can wear small or medium armor. Wood elves refer to themselves as the Feir`Dal when using the Elvish tongue.ClassStrengthStaminaAgilityDexterityWisdomIntelligenceCharismaBonus PointsBard70659590807585+25Druid65759580907575+30Ranger707510580857575+20Rogue656510590807575+30Warrior757510080807575+25Race/Class Combination Chart.BRDCLRDRUENCMAGMNKNECPALRNGROGSHDSHMWARWIZBarbarianXXXDark ElfXXXXXXXXDwarfXXXXEruditeXXXXXXXGnomeXXXXXXXXXHalf ElfXXXXXXHalflingXXXXXXHigh ElfXXXXXXHumanXXXXXXXXXXXXXOgreXXXTrollXXXWood ElfXXXXXDeitiesAlong with an adventurer's race and class, religion is also the basis for much of their faction standing, and, for some races, from which city they begin. Norrathians cannot convert to another religion at any point in life, and must deal with both the benefits and repercussions of their beliefs. Some choose to be Agnostic, but here are the gods that are most worshipped by Norrath's people.Bertoxxulous - The PlaguebringerBertoxxulousBertoxxulous' plague-ridden followers believe in one simple rule: Everything Dies. While disgusting and horrific to most, they see the decomposition of flesh as a sacred thing. Bruises, blisters, pus, oozing sores, infected cuts, and contagious rashes are just a few things that followers of Bertoxxulous treasure. Unsurprisingly, necromancers are some of his most common devotees. While they surround themselves in death and unlife, do not mistake them as ones who seek death themselves. It is their mission to serve Bertoxxulous to spread disease around the world for as long as possible.RacesClassesGnomeCleric, Enchanter, Magician, Necromancer, Rogue, Shadow Knight, Warrior, WizardHalf ElfRogue, WarriorHumanCleric, Enchanter, Magician, Rogue, Shadow Knight, Warrior, WizardBrell Serilis - The Duke of BelowBrell SerilisBrell Serilis' followers believe the surface of the world to be an utter waste of time and space. True happiness for them is found beneath the crust of the world, in the darkness of the caves and tunnels. Sadly, this is about the only thing that Brell's followers can agree. Brell probably has one of the most diverse populations of devotees. The Dwarves of Kaladim believe without question that they are the true children of Serilis. But the ferocious Gnolls of the world vehemently disagree. Kobolds and Gnolls were his first creations, but Brell later turned his attention to his more intelligent children, the Dwarves and Gnomes of Faydwer. The gnolls still worship him, as they have built a temple in Jaggedpine Forest to prove it, but the kobolds have turned their back on him as they believe he did the same to them. The goblin clan of Runny Eye believe Brell to be their father, despite it being well known that Rallos Zek is he one who created the goblin race.RacesClassesDwarfCleric, Paladin, Rogue, WarriorGnomeCleric, Enchanter, Magician, Paladin, Rogue, Warrior, WizardHalf ElfBardHalflingDruid, Ranger, RogueCazic-Thule - The FacelessCazic-ThuleCazic-Thule's followers are deathly afraid of him, but believe that spreading this intense fear into the hearts and minds of others will earn the Faceless' favor. Hope is the eternal enemy of any true Cazicite. Terror, fright, and dread, and living sacrifice are the tools of a devotee of Cazic-Thule. Most lizardman tribes are devout followers of Cazic-Thule, but his population of more intelligent races grows every day. It is their beliefe that soon all of Norrath will be enveloped in a fog of nightmares. A massive temple to The Faceless was built centuries ago by the Ogres in the jungles of The Feerrott. The Erudites of Paineel also worship the Lord of Fear.RacesClassesEruditeNecromancer, Shadow KnightOgreShadow Knight, WarriorTrollShadow Knight, Shaman, WarriorErollisi Marr - The Queen of LoveErollisi MarrErollisi Marr teaches her followers that love conquers all. She, along with her twin brother Mithaniel, created the Barbarians during the Age of Monuments. It is believed that the evolution of Barbarians to Humans was sparked by the divine touch of Erollisi. While love is a beautiful thing, Erollisi's devotees are not so obtuse to believe a Norrath without war is possible. They are willing to enter battle themselves if it means defending the principles, people, and places they love. Followers of Erollisi believe the most honorable death would be earned defending someone or something they love deeply. A great number of paladins entrust their hearts to the ideals of Erollisi Marr. An order of priests and paladins devoted to Erollisi and Mithaniel once held political power in Freeport, but were driven out by the corrupt militia captain, Sir Lucan D'Lere. A few members of the Elven population also worship the Queen of Love.RacesClassesHalf ElfBard, Paladin, Rogue, WarriorHigh ElfEnchanter, Magician, WizardHumanBard, Cleric, Enchanter, Magician, Paladin, Rogue, Warrior, WizardWood ElfBardFizzlethorpe Bristlebane - The King of ThievesBristlebaneThose who claim Bristlebane as their god are all about having fun above all other things. Bards and rogues the most common devotees, but there are a great many gyspies that worship him as well. Mischief is encouraged heavily among the King of Thieves' followers. While other religions focus on honor, fear, or peace, these clever and witty tricksters have rituals consisting of practical jokes. Followers of other gods may sometimes find these mischief makers annoying, but very few of them have evil intentions. During the Age of Turmoil, the most devout followers of Bristlebane are the Halflings of Rivervale, where a chapel has been erected in honor of the King of Thieves.RacesClassesBarbarianRogueDark ElfRogueDwarfRogueGnomeCleric, RogueHalf ElfBard, RogueHalflingCleric, Paladin, RogueHumanBard, RogueWood ElfBard, RogueInnoruuk - The Prince of HateInnoruukAlmost the entire Dark Elven race sees The Prince of Hate as their true father. They trust in him that hate is the driving force in the universe. Their devotion to hate has led them to believe love is simply a means for the weak-minded fools of the world who are too scared to take what they want. Spite is the only true way to overpower your enemies. Innoruuk's children believe in their dark hearts that if they could combine their hate collectively, they could destroy Norrath. Understandably, the most devout followers of Innoruuk are found in Neriak, where the dark elves have erected a large church, among other shrines, in his honor.RacesClassesDark ElfCleric, Enchanter, Magician, Necromancer, Rogue, Shadow Knight, Warrior, WizardHalf ElfWarriorHumanCleric, Enchanter, Magician, Necromancer, Rogue, Shadow Knight, Warrior, WizardTrollShadow Knight, Shaman, WarriorKarana - The RainkeeperKaranaKarana's followers invest all of their faith in the life-giving and destructive force of storms of all types. Typical followers of Karana are farmers, druids, and rangers. While they respect the power of the Storm Lord, they often provide shelter to travelers, for they are mostly good-natured people who value honesty. Much like the followers of Quellious, a great deal of Karana's devotees live a life of a nomad. The plains of western Antonica are named after Karana due to the frequent rain in the region that provides excellent farming for Qeynos.RacesClassesHalf ElfBard, Druid, Paladin, Ranger, Rogue, WarriorHalflingDruid, RangerHigh ElfEnchanter, Magician, WizardHumanBard, Cleric, Druid, Enchanter, Magician, Paladin, Ranger, Rogue, Warrior, WizardWood ElfBard, Rogue, WarriorMithaniel Marr - The LightbringerMithaniel MarrMithaniel Marr's followers believe they are distinguished from the beats of the world by their valor and honor. He, along with his twin sister, created the Barbarians of Norrath and are believed to have sparked the evolution of the Humans from those Barbarians. The twins are also responsible for the Frogloks of the world. Followers of Marr live a life of a high moral standard and devote much of their lives to spreading the word of truth and selflessly giving to charity. Throughout Norrath, they are known as the most noble warriors in the world. These warriors and paladins fight for the sake of all that is good in the world and will do so without fear of death. Many would say that Marr's followers take their cause a bit too seriously, having short patience for humor or mischief.RacesClassesHalf ElfBard, Paladin, WarriorHigh ElfEnchanter, Magician, WizardHumanBard, Cleric, Enchanter, Magician, Paladin, Warrior, WizardWood ElfBardPrexus - The OceanlordPrexusPrexus' followers believe in the raw power of the world's oceans. They do not worship the element of water specifically, but it is their belief that life originated in the sea and it will consume those who do not respect it. The Oceanlord's devotees almost always live in cities or towns on the coasts of the world. Prexus is not a commonly worshiped god, but he has many faithful sailors and fishermen. The Erudites have erected a church in Erudin to worship Prexus, and many to train young clerics and paladins.RacesClassesEruditeCleric, Enchanter, Magician, Paladin, WizardHalf ElfBard, WarriorHumanBardWood ElfBardQuellious - The TranquilQuelliousPeace is the primary focus for any followers of Quellious. Do not take them lightly though, for they will fiercely defend themselves and those they love. Quellious' followers seek the inner peace that will teach them the true meaning of their lives and the world itself. They believe that through the sharing of the knowledge gained through this enlightenment, peace throughout the world is obtainable. The most common followers of Quellious are nomads, such as monks.RacesClassesEruditeCleric, Enchanter, Magician, Paladin, WizardHalf ElfBardHumanBard, MonkWood ElfBardRallos Zek - The WarlordRallos ZekRallos Zek's followers believe in the idea of only the strong shall survive. War is the only venue to earn the favor of the gods and achieve enlightenment. They believe the universe was created in the midst of battle and so too shall it end. Those who fall in battle are quickly forgotten by Zek's faithful, for the dead were too weak to pass the test. Most warriors are devout followers of Zek.RacesClassesBarbarianWarriorDark ElfWarriorGnomeWarriorHalf ElfBard, WarriorHalflingWarriorHumanBard, WarriorOgreShadow Knight, Shaman, WarriorTrollWarriorWood ElfBard, WarriorRodcet Nife - The Prime HealerRodcet NifeRodcet Nife's faithful all accept an oath to battle disease and death until succumbing to either. They are very kind to others and live a life of simplicity. One should not mistake them for being pacifists though, for they do not only seek to cure disease and illness, but explore the world searching intensely to for the root of these plagues. Human and Half Elven priests and mystics from western Antonica are the largest contingent of Rodcet's faithful. It is their belief that the evils of the universe shall one day be expunged and the looming darkness of death never be seen again.RacesClassesHalf ElfBard, Paladin, Rogue, WarriorHumanBard, Cleric, Enchanter, Magician, Paladin, Rogue, Warrior, WizardWood ElfBardSolusek Ro - The Burning PrinceSolusek RoFollowers of the Burning Prince put their faith in the power of fire. They believe aggression is the only way to obtain the things they desire in the world and they fear very little. Ro's faithful are typically blunt and direct in their manner of speaking, which is viewed as unkind or rude to most others, but they care not. They are not out to make friends, only to earn respect. Since fire is the focus of most wizards, they are Solusek Ro's most devout followers.RacesClassesDark ElfWizardEruditeWizardGnomeWizardHalf ElfBardHigh ElfWizardHumanBard, WizardWood ElfBardThe Tribunal - The Six HammersTribunalFor true followers of the Six Hammers, only one thing matters; Justice. Many of the world's police, guards, and governors worship The Tribunal, the most devout recognize only one law or court in the universe; that of the Tribunal themselves. Through methodical patience, it is their sacred duty to deal out punishment, vengeance, and retribution to those who rightfully deserve it. Patience may be the most important quality in any follower of the Tribunal, for if they punish an innocent, they will answer to the Six Hammers personally. Barbarians are the most common followers of the Tribunal.RacesClassesBarbarianRogue, Shaman, WarriorHalf ElfBard, WarriorHumanBardWood ElfWarriorTunare - The Mother of AllTunareTunare's followers believe, despite what any one else thinks, that Tunare is the mother of all living things. They understand that not everyone accepts this ideology, but is their goal to protect and preserve the living, breathing world they inhabit. Many druids, rangers, and most Elves in general follow the ways of Tunare.RacesClassesHalf ElfBard, Druid, Paladin, Ranger, Rogue, WarriorHigh ElfCleric, Enchanter, Magician, Paladin, WizardHumanBard, Druid, RangerWood ElfBard, Druid, Ranger, Rogue, WarriorVeeshan - The Wurm QueenVeeshanVeeshan was the first of the gods of influence to discover the world of Norrath. It is said that she soars throughout the universe claiming planets that she deems worthy of her brood. She does not have many non-dragon followers, but there are Half Elves who live through life with such a sense of rejection that they choose to worship dragonkin.RacesClassesHalf ElfBardHumanBardWood ElfBardThe World of NorrathNorrathThe known world of Norrath consists of three continents. In the center is the largest of the three, Antonica. It features nearly every type of environment from icy mountains to scorching deserts, and from humid jungles to rolling plains. Antonica is home to Norrath's population of humans (Qeynos, Freeport, Surefall Glade), halflings (Rivervale), dark elves (Neriak), trolls (Grobb), and ogres (Oggok). Across the Ocean of Tears to the east is the continent of Faydwer. It is a land full of mystical creatures such as faeries and unicorns. Faydwer is also home to Norrath's population of dwarves (Kaladim), wood elves (Kelethin), high elves (Felwithe), and gnomes (Ak'Anon). From Antonica, across the water of Erud's Crossing, to the west lies the small continent of Odus. It is a dark, forested continent with rocky beaches. Odus is home Norrath's population of erudites (Erudin, Paineel). Within the world of Norrath, there are also several astral planes that have been discovered including Fear, Hate, and Sky.AntonicaMap of AntonicaAntonica, formerly known as Tunaria, is the largest of the three continents in the known world. The northern reaches of this land are mountainous with icy peaks of Everfrost in the west to the volcanoes of Lavastorm in the east. Across the center of Antonica, divided by the Serpent's Spine, are the rolling plains of Karana and a region simply known as the Commonlands. In the southeast, what was once the richest forest in all of Norrath, is now the scorching, barren Desert of Ro. And in the south, guarded by the Rathe Mountains are the humid and dangerous jungle known as The Feerrott and the Innothule Swamp.The ArenaThe ArenaThe Arena can be found on the western edge of Lake Rathetear. The Power of Discord holds sway over the Arena and allows any adventurer who chooses to enter to harm other adventurers, regardless of the normal influences of Order. Many duels have been held within its walls. Occasionally, tournaments known as the Best of the Best are held to determine the elite of each class or team. The origins of the Arena are unknown, though many believe that the gods themselves once battled within its confines. The ogres believe it to have been built by Rallos Zek himself. No creatures can be found to hunt here. The Arena does serve as a great place for adventurers of southern Antonica to bind their soul.BefallenBefallenBefallen can be found on the southern edge of the west Commonlands where the grasslands begin to merge with the desert. The dungeon was once a proud temple maintained by The Ashen Order of monks. Now it has been overrun with dark elves and others practicing the arts of necromancy. The dark elves claim the dungeon is the last remnant of the ancient city of Takish Hiz, the great elven city. Many of the passages in Befallen require keys that must be obtained from various notable enemies within the dungeon. A skilled rogue can pick these locks and speed up his or her party's progress significantly.BlackburrowBlackburrowBlackburrow is an outdoor dungeon nestled between Qeynos Hills and Everfrost Peaks. It is the stronghold of the Sabertooth gnolls. These gnolls once roamed the hills outside Qeynos, but were driven back as the human settlement grew. The risk of the caverns' numerous traps and tricky terrain is often worth the reward though, as the gnolls are known to carry coin and other items of value for young adventurers.CommonlandsEast CommonlandsEast Commonlands is located directly outside the western gate of Freeport and is the first step into making the trek across Antonica to Qeynos. Nektulos Forest lies to the north, and a long tunnel to the south leads to the Desert of Ro. Many young humans will test their new skills against the bears, snakes, spiders, undead and camps of Deathfist orcs found throughout the hills. Inns and merchants can be found scattered throughout the region, giving rest and replenishment to travelers. The East Commons tunnel was once an excellent flea market where adventurers gathered to buy, sell, and trade all kinds of items. The corrupt Freeport guards, most notably Sergeant Slate, would often wreak havoc on the ogres and trolls attempting to sell their wares in the tunnel.West CommonlandsWest Commonlands is a bit more dangerous than the eastern half. The deadly Kithicor Forest lies to the west, while Befallen lies buried in the sand to the south. Along with the Deathfist orcs, several camps of Dervish Cutthroats threaten the passers by. Occasionally, a hill giant may be found roaming the hills killing adventurers without prejudice, and a roaming Dragoon from Neriak will crush most good-natured travelers. The main road leading to and from Freeport is blocked by a tollbooth set up by the corrupt Freeport Militia. Western Commonlands is a teleport destination for both druids and wizards. Many young adventurers often seek refuge at the druid ring. Though there are no guards to protect them, the more experienced druids and their companions will often help someone unfortunate enough to have angered a legion of orcs and/or cutthroats.Desert of RoNorthern Desert of RoThe Northern Desert of Ro lies directly outside the gates of East Freeport and spans south to the Oasis of Marr. The Ocean of Tears washes up on the beach to the east. Near an active wizard teleportation spire, a tunnel to East Commonlands can be found. A few inns can be visited closer to the city walls, but the grass quickly becomes a barren desert scattered with giant spiders, snakes, wandering madmen, and undead. The desert was once the great Elddar Forest, home to the elves of Norrath. Legend states it was the most beautiful forest ever seen, and was scorched by the Burning Prince, Solusek Ro. The drought drove the elves to flee across the ocean to Faydwer and all that remains are miles of sand and occasional remnants of the city of Takish Hiz peaking through the dunes.The Southern Desert of Ro is where the scorched ancient forest slowly merges into the swamps of southern Antonica. Sand giants can often be found roaming the steep slopes of sand, and some lucky adventurers will catch sight of an ancient cyclops. Somewhat hidden in the northwestern reaches of this region is a mysterious Erudite man and his hulking orc bodyguard. In the center of the region is a dark elf gypsy camp offering rare tailoring supplies. The southern region of the desert is also another area that has teleport locations built for both druids and wizards, which allows for veteran adventurers to quickly get to the depths of Lower Guk. Several camps of orcs offer a challenge to trolls who have graduated from the tests found in Innothule Swamp to the south.Everfrost PeaksEverfrost PeaksEverfrost Peaks can be found in the northern reaches of the continent. Upon entering the mountain range from Blackburrow, adventurers are met with towering slopes of ice and snow. Halas, the city of the barbarians, can be found at the northern most point of the range. To the east, the terrain levels out to reveal a frozen river and scattered remains of the Combine Empire from the Elder Age. These lands were once the fertile grounds the giants of Norrath called home, but were frozen during The Rathe's curse upon all of Rallos Zek's creations. The goblins, orcs, and giants still remain in the region, yet lesser in the mind than they were centuries ago. Dedicated adventurers will find that beneath the frozen river lies an entrance to the caves once inhabited by Miragul, the leader of the Heretics of Paineel. Far to the east of the frozen tundra lies Permafrost Keep. Many veteran warriors and adept spell casters have entered the keep never to be seen again.The FeerrottThe FeerrottThe Feerrott is a marshland in southern Antonica that is patrolled by many young ogres. The swampy jungle is also where one will find some of the most dangerous areas to explore. The Temple of Cazic-Thule lies to the south, while the realm of god of fear himself can be found beyond a portal hidden in the southwestern corner of the region. A winding road traces a route through the marsh from the Innothule Swamp to the east all the way to the Rathe Mountains to the west. Far to the north, one will find the ogre city of Oggok. While most of the creatures in The Feerrott are fodder for young ogres, those same young ogres are protected by patrolling guards known as Bouncers from Oggok that will smash any good-natured visitors to the jungle on sight. A druid ring, to which druids can teleport, near the center of the region allows for quick mobilization of raids headed for the Plane of Fear.FreeportEast FreeportEast Freeport is not necessarily the nicest part of town. Most of this portion of the human city is a slum, but it does have one very important feature; the docks. Two boats make stops at the Freeport docks taking adventurers across the Ocean of Tears to the continent of Faydwer. The city gates lead to the Desert of Ro to the south. Beneath the surface of the slums lies a Temple of Innoruuk where human necromancers, shadow knights, and other worshipers of hate begin their journey. The entrance to this hidden society lies beneath the docks, allowing evil visitors to Freeport to jump off the boat before being spotted by the guards on the docks. Like the western portion of Freeport, the guards patrolling the slums and docks are part of the corrupt Freeport Militia led by Sir Lucan D'Lere. The Seafarer's Roost at the docks is an inn for tired sailors, but is also the secret hideout for rogues passing through town.North FreeportNorth Freeport is the last remnant of the Freeport of old. This region of the massive city is the last to not be controlled by Sir Lucan's militia. The Knights of Truth, followers of Mithaniel Marr, patrol the streets and protect its residents as best they can from the corruption found in the rest of the city. The clerics and paladins found in the Temple of Marr worship both Mithaniel and his sister, Erollisi. Lucan's forces grow every day, but the Knights of Truth still control the city's only bank, which is known simply as The Vault. North Freeport is also home to the eastern branch of the League of Antonican Bards. The shops are much nicer in this part of the city, and the prices reflect that. Those who aspire to be grandmaster jewelers will certainly want to stop by this area of town to stock up on supplies.West FreeportWest Freeport is the heart of Lucan's forces in the large human city. The militia's barracks lie just within the city gates after arriving from the Commonlands. Along the city's outer walls, those not welcome in Freeport can find an underground tunnel leading the seedy underground sewers. In the southern area of this part of town, a large arena awaits young warriors to begin their training. And across the way, a calm cabin next to a stream houses The Ashen Order, where young monks learn the power of tranquility. Near the Ashen Order, a theater built by bards can be found. The most notable feature of this part of the city though is the Academy of Arcane Sciences, which can be found floating above a pond in the center of town. The Academy serves as the guild house for magicians, enchanters, and wizards, and sells some of the greatest spells found this side of Erudin. The guild leader, Lome Tredore, remains neutral in the war that is tearing the city apart. West Freeport is obviously the most diverse part of the city, and is also home to many different merchants that cater to all types of trade skills.The Gorge of King XorbbThe Gorge of King XorbbThe Gorge of King Xorbb is also known as Beholder's Maze. It is a labyrinth of rock and mud to the north of the eastern plains of Karana leading to the underground lair of the Pickclaw goblin clan known as the Runnyeye Citadel. King Xorbb is the lord of the evil eyes, whom held the goblins as slaves. These beguilers use minotaurs as soldiers to patrol the region. King Xorbb himself is rarely ever seen, but the legend of his xenophobic acts remains in the minds of the people of central Antonica to this day.GrobbGrobbGrobb is the city the trolls call home. This swamp town is a sight that only a troll could love. Rotting wooden planks span the many streams running through the city from the Innothule Swamp. Homes and stores are not much more than mud and rock holding together enough to qualify as shelter. Signs painted with the blood of 'lesser' creatures such as lizardmen, frogloks, and dwarves advertise the city's landmarks. Violence is the norm in this society, as the trolls obviously do not have a diplomatic society. The troll shadow knights known as the Nightkeep police the city, but the mob truly rules here. For those disagreements between trolls not decided in the streets will often be settled in the warriors guild hall known as Da Bashin Place.GukUpper GukUpper Guk is not nearly as dangerous as the lower levels of the ancient city, but it's twisting and turning caverns will leave many who enter lost within minutes. The city was once inhabited by the trolls, but was overthrown by the invading bands of frogloks. The frogloks witnessed the horrific practices of the trolls first hand, and in the honor of Marr, were determined to rid Norrath of these abominations. They were successful in taking the city, but the trolls still remain nearby in the town of Grobb. The frogloks are generally friendly to most races, especially if they have spent a good deal of time slaying the undead below. These good-natured frogloks also have cultivated a farm of fungus men in the slippery depths of the city.Lower GukLower Guk is one of the most dangerous dungeons in all of Antonica. The risk is worth the reward in many cases though, as the sprawling caverns hold many of the continent's most prized treasures. The entire place is crawling with frogloks, a noble race of frog people who worship Mithaniel Marr. Half of the dungeon is ruled by the froglok king, but the other half is ruled by the ghoul lord and his army of undead frogloks. The undead are a result of a curse laid upon the ancient city by a powerful troll shaman who called upon the power of Innoruuk himself in a suicidal attempt at revenge. Because of this, Lower Guk is often referred to as the Ruins of Old Guk. Battling one faction of the frogloks will earn favor with the other, and many experienced adventurers spend countless hours slaying these frogloks in search of riches such as the Shining Metallic Robes, Short Sword of Ykesha, and the legendary Flowing Black Silk Sash.HalasHalasHalas is the home to Norrath's barbarians. Hidden in the northern reaches of Everfrost Peaks, Halas does not get many outside visitors, but the barbarians are tolerant of any good-natured people. Any barbarians who are not agnostic will most likely worship The Tribunal, while a few Halasian warriors pay homage to Rallos Zek. The rogues of the White Rose guild are not exactly celebrated in the community, but are respected for their mastery of weapons of all styles. Unknown to even most barbarians, Cappi McTarnigal, the proprietor of the city's bank, is also the guildmaster of the White Rose. Shops are scattered throughout the icy town providing basic needs. And there seems to be a tavern around every corner. The shaman of Halas are highly revered, and are the only shaman found worldwide that do not worship the dark gods of fear and hate. Halas is an excellent rest stop for experienced adventurers attempting to hunt ice giants or those that dare to enter Permafrost Keep.High KeepHigh KeepHigh Keep is quite a unique locale. On the ground and upper levels, it is a fort signifying the midpoint on the trade route between Qeynos and Freeport. It offers rest for the weary, as well as merchants and a bank for traders, adventurers, and travelers alike to restock their wares. At the highest levels of the keep, marble hallways lead to casinos that offer entertainment for those that can afford it. But down below, a battle rages as the Pickclaw goblins of nearby Runnyeye Citadel have been literally coming out of the walls as they attempt to expand their citadel. The High Keep guards employ many adventurers in keeping the goblins at bay. The close proximity of merchants and a bank make it an excellent location to earn experience for future battles. The duke of the keep, Carson McCabe, is not exactly loved by its inhabitants. His taxes and fees keep most citizens struggling to get by, but McCabe claims these fees keep the settlements safe, which increases income from the many travelers passing through. McCabe knows that he rules the only passage between Freeport and Qeynos for those not willing to risk passing through the mountains, swamps, and desert to the south.Highpass HoldHighpass HoldHighpass Hold is an outdoor village of inhabitants at the peak of the mountains in the center of Antonica. To the west lie the plains of Karana and to the east is the deadly Kithicor Forest. Anyone travelling between Qeynos and Freeport must pass through here unless they wish to risk the likes of trolls and ogres. McCabe's militia patrols the area in attempt to keep the growing threat of Deathfist orcs and invading gnolls at bay. Many merchants can be found amid the threat of orc ambushes. Also hidden in the pass is a society of smugglers known as the Circle of the Unseen Hand who are led by the legendary rogue, Stanos Herkanor. Many believe that McCabe not only knows about the smugglers, but is in league with them and the rogue guilds of both Qeynos and Freeport. It would certainly help explain the lavish nature of the keep and the embattlements that protect the pass.Innothule SwampInnothule SwampInnothule Swamp is what connects the Desert of Ro up north to the jungles of The Feerrott to the west. It is inhabited by trolls, frogloks, kobolds, and many other creatures slithering through the marsh. Most of the creatures found here are even matches for the fledgling trolls coming from the city of Grobb to the south, but travelers should keep a sharp eye for the patrolling city guards known as Bashers. The trolls of the region believe that the gods of hate and fear, Innoruuk and Cazic-Thule, conspired in their creation of the humid, dank swampland and gave it the name of Innothule. The ancient city of Guk lies to the east, which is the epicenter of a never ending war between the trolls of Grobb and the frogloks that took Guk many years ago.Jaggedpine ForestJaggedpine ForestJaggedpine Forest was not open to the public for for an extensive period of time. Its secrets have been guarded by the druids and rangers of Karana. The region was first settled long ago by a nomadic tribe of humans who had just broken away from their barbarian forefathers. When many other humans founded Qeynos, Karana's followers befriended them. Antonius Bayle III decided to seal the entrance to the forest to protect it from the impeding war and corruption that came to Antonica during his reign. The gnolls of nearby Blackburrow inadvertently tunneled their way into the forest and have since built a temple to Brell Serilis there. Antonius Bayle IV decided to reopen the entrance within Surefall Glade to help defend the region from the gnoll menace. The forest is full of wildlife, which has brought greedy poachers to the region. The Jaggedpine Treefolk offer rewards for those who can show proof of slain poachers. The Hatchling River divides Jaggedpine from the Unkempt Woods to the east, which still remain unreachable by Bayle's decree. The potameides of the river have inexplicably become hateful to any and all visitors of the forest. Many believe that the unkempt have a hand in this.Karana PlainsEastern Plains of KaranaThe Eastern Plains of Karana is the quarter of the great plains east of the Serpent River that rolls down from the frozen tundra up north. To the east, the plains become rocky and begin to rise into the peaks where Highpass Hold is located. Westward, over a massive wooden bridge, lies the rest of the Karana plains. Threats to adventurers and travelers come both high and low here as there are ferocious griffons patrolling the skies and many large spiders crawling through the grasslands. Many have told stories of a clan of cyclops near the river. Closer to Highpass, several merchants and an inn can be found for traders to rest before scaling the gorge. Far to the south, along the river, is a village of barbarian fishermen. Two Qeynosian paladins, Sir Morgan and Squire Wimbley, patrol the road from the bridge to Highpass and, for a small fee, will escort ill-equipped travelers through the fields of danger.Northern Plains of KaranaThe Northern Plains of Karana is home to many types of creatures including hill giants, bears, lions, and some of the fiercest griffons seen anywhere in Norrath. Stores of the horrifying speed of Stormfeather keeps most travellers with one eye on the horizon at all times. A community of druids keep watch over an ancient stone ring where many druids arrive through teleportation. Qeynos guards are present in the region with a guard tower in the northwest and also guarding the white stone bridge leading to the southern plains. Those with malicious intent would be smart to swim the river rather than take the bridge. Just north of the stone bridge are the largest set of wizard spires found on the continent. The Combine Empire built one of these structures on each continent centuries ago, and wizards of Norrath have the ability to teleport to them at will. Near the center of the region, a band of gypsies have set up camp to trade their wares to travelers between the two great cities.Southern Plains of KaranaThe Southern Plains of Karana is the region of the flatlands inhabited by the most diverse types of creatures. In the northeast, near the river, is a village of centaurs whom are indifferent to all other races and offer to buy, sell, and trade with all. The Splitpaw gnolls have a large underground lair near the center of the plains. The ancient treants roam the eastern borders. And a massive, towering structure in the south is home to the bird people known as aviaks. The aviaks are generally friendly to all except ogres, but many adventurers choose to hunt them instead. Overall, the plains offer much practice for mid-seasoned adventurers. In the southeast, a lone house surrounded by a wall houses a lonely man simply known as "the hermit" to all that have passed by his establishment. At the southern most reaches of the plains, a small passage through the granite can be found that leads to Lake Rathetear.Western Plains of KaranaThe Western Plains of Karana is the largest sector of the Rainkeeper's plains. Much of these "plains" are actually intruded upon by the mountains from the north. As travelers approach Qeynos Hills to the west, several inns and merchants can be found in the large fields of green. Several farms can also be seen from the winding trail, which supply the many citizens of Qeynos with all types of food. There was a time when Bertoxxulous brought a plague upon these great plains, which devastated the crop supply for Qeynos. The citizens were saved by a priest of Rodcet Nife's Temple of Life as he cured the Plaguebringer's curse upon the land. A few guard towers can be spotted along the route, and should of course be avoided by any who have earned distrust from the Qeynosian guard. Along the river is another barbarian fisherman village. Nestled in the rising mountains to the north is a shrine to Rallos Zek, which is watched eternally by a small band of ogre shaman. Hidden among the mountains are camps of bandits that often pilfer the heavy traffic of traders through the region. A small stone pyramid found near the river signifies a target for wizard teleportation, being the closest wizard could get to Qeynos without walking.Kithicor ForestKithicor WoodsKithicor Forest can be a hunting ground for young halflings from the neighboring town of Rivervale, or it can be the scariest place on Antonica. While the sun peeks through the towering trees, relatively harmless beetles, bats, and an occasional bear roam the forest. But when night falls, an army of undead rise from the earth terrorizing even the most experienced adventurers. The forest is named for a legendary human ranger who once single-handedly defended the woods from an army of dark elves who were attempting to take over Highpass. Several settlements of rangers can be found throughout the area and are one of the only places for rangers to train their skills in all of Antonica. The undead are forgotten souls from a great war that took place in these woods when the dark elves waged war against a coalition of humans, dwarves, and elves. The dark elves were led by Laarthik K'Shin, a highly decorated warrior from Neriak, and his pupil, Lanys T'Vyl, the daughter of Innoruuk himself. The forces of good were led by Firiona Vie, the celebrated champion of Tunare. When it was apparent the dark elves would lose, Innoruuk entered the battle himself. When the powers of hate and nature collided, it left both armies devastated. Firiona survived by the grace of Tunare, while Lanys was pulled to the safety of the Plane of Hate by her father. As a result of the Prince of Hate's interference, a passage was left open for mortals to enter his plane. Laarthik and his undead armies now roam the forest in the darkness, preying on travelers large and small.Lake RathetearLake RathetearLake Rathetear is the largest body of water on Antonica and borders the southern Plains of Karana to the north and the Mountains of Rathe to the east. Legend states that the lake was formed from the tears of The Rathe, the council governing the element of earth, as they mourned the death of a councilman at the hands of Murdunk, a great ogre warrior of the Elder Age. In the center of the lake, upon a small island, stands a massive tower lit by an eternal flame. Aviaks keep watch from this tower, keeping a keen eye on all that pass through the lake. The Arena can be found along the western wall of the mountains. Along the rest of the shores of the lake, many different tiny villages can be found. Beneath the waters, those with the ability to breathe underwater will find a city of aqua goblins. On one small island, an erudite is hard at work studying in silence. What appears to be a calm and beautiful region of Antonica holds many secrets and a great deal of history.Lavastorm MountainsLavastorm MountainsLavastorm Mountains is a treacherous terrain to say the least. Found to the north of Nektulos Forest, this volcanic region of jagged rocks is home to many creatures that are apparently impervious to the scorching heat. Fire beetles, imps, fire goblins, elementals, and shadow men roam throughout the area. Many of these creatures are believed to be unnatural and emanating from the infamous dark elf summoner Najena's dungeon to the east. Gypsies have set up camp along the western edges of the wasteland including one that operates a shop within the ancient druid ring, which is quite convenient for the experienced adventurers teleporting into the region. Those willing to journey to the northern most reaches of the volcanic ash will find a massive pool of lava. Around this pool are three caves. Within these caves are Solusek's Eye, a stronghold of fire goblins and laboratory for ambitious gnomes; The Temple of Solusek Ro, a church offering lucrative quests for all professions; and Nagafen's Lair, a twisted labyrinth of humidity with an army of kobolds, royal fire giants, and the red dragon himself, Lord Nagafen.Misty ThicketMisty ThicketMisty Thicket is renowned as one of the best training grounds for all young adventurers. The dense forest lies between the halfling town of Rivervale and the Pickclaw goblin's Runnyeye Citadel, which makes for a constant struggle between the halfling deputies and the invading goblins. A large stone wall has been erected by the halflings to help protect Rivervale from them. Even though most halflings worship either Karana or Bristlebane, the wall is devoted to Brell Serilis, the Duke of Below. A group of deputies stand guard at the one passage through the wall protecting young halflings from danger, sometimes a little too well. Many halfling civilians live just outside the city in earthen huts selling various goods, which is convenient for those testing their skills against the goblins, fire beetles, and bixies. Many druids make use of the ancient stone ring as it is the closest teleport location to a city bank. On the "bad side" of the wall, as halfling civilians refer to it, there are several camps of goblins and orcs constantly testing the skills of fledgling halflings. The combination of gradually increasing difficulty of opponents, protection of guards, and closeness of the town of Rivervale makes Misty Thicket a destination for new adventurers of all races, not just the native halflings.Nagafen's LairNagafen's LairNagafen's Lair is the home to one of two dragons exiled to Antonica. From the depths of the dungeon, Lord Nagafen commands an army of fire giants, kobolds, and other lethal critters. The smoldering heat within the dungeon is almost unbearable, but many of Norrath's veteran fighters, priests, and casters survive the environmental hazards in attempt gain riches and glory. While the fire giants and kobolds ultimately serve the ancient dragon, they each have their own hierarchy of nobles that govern the everyday life of each race. Also to be found here are a race of efreeti, whose master holds the much sought after Golden Efreeti Boots. Lord Nagafen was exiled from the Ring of Scale for, as the stories say, attempting to mate with a white dragon. Despite being exiled, Nagafen's power reached far and wide. For many years, he commanded the city of Qeynos to sacrifice a young woman to him once a year. When a maiden by the name of Erolette was selected, she spent her final moments of life praying to the goddess of love, Erollisi Marr. Erollisi heard these paryers and used a golden thread to sew Nagafen's heart to his stomach, causing the dragon to confuse his hunger for love. Nagafen could not bear to eat Erolette, and as he grew hungrier, his heart grew, causing Nagafen himself to grow until he was so large that he could no longer leave his own lair. Upon realizing the dragon was helpless, Erolette escaped. And as legend has it, Nagafen let loose a roar so mighty that lava spewed from the mountains above. The fiery dragon remains trapped here, only able to fill his hunger when foolhardy adventurers attempt to slay him.NajenaNajenaNajena is actually a supremely powerful dark elf magician who has taken over an ancient temple carved into the largest peak of the Lavastorm Mountains. No one seems to know what the temple was originally for, but she has converted the temple into a dungeon full of traps, locked doors, and an army of elementals that do her bidding. It is rumored that Najena is the niece of Queen Cristanos Thex of Neriak. Brave adventurers will certainly be shocked by the creatures found around every corner of her dominion. Tentacle terrors siphon the life from would be looters, while an undead froglok known as Bonecracker will catch most dungeon crawlers by surprise with his powerful necromancy. Najena herself is in fact a resident here, but finding her is quite a test. She continues to conduct gruesome experiment with her summoning power and vast knowledge of the dark arts.Nektulos ForestNektulos ForestNektulos Forest is where young dark elves first begin to hone their skills before venturing out into the world. The path stretching from the Commonlands to the south to Lavastorm Mountains to the north is often patrolled by the Neriak guards known as Dragoons. Neriak itself is buried beneath the rocky hills in the northeast region of the forest. The Dragoons of the Indigo Brotherhood guard the only bridge that crosses the river running west to east through the forest. Those not in league with the Teir'Dal must brave the piranha filled waters to avoid these deadly warriors. A wizard spire can be found along the eastern border allowing many experience dark elf wizards to return home quickly. To the west, a brave band of halflings known as the Leatherfoot Raiders stand guard to protect RIvervale from any dark elves attempting to invade by way of the river. Occasionally, they will use their guile to enter the city of Neriak itself, but are seldom heard from again.NeriakNeriak Foreign QuarterNeriak Foreign Quarter is the first area reached upon entering the extensive underground city of the dark elves. Ogres, trolls, and anyone else who has won the favor of the Teir'Dal are allowed to enter, shop, and sell their wares. Much of the architecture here resembles that of Freeport as more than a few human Innoruuk followers have set up shop here. The ogres and trolls have their own specific area near the back of the Foreign Quarter, which is obvious to any visitor not just because of the smell, but due to the poorly written signs advertising their shops and guild halls. Not far from the makeshift ogre and troll village is an arena that has been erected to settle disputes, as the larger citizens often don't settle squabbles with a debate or trial. Compared to the rest of the city, the Foreign Quarter is a bit of a slum. But it is also the busiest part of the city since visitors aren't often allowed into the Commons, and all the dark elves coming and going to and from the city must pass through here.Neriak CommonsNeriak Commons is the second gate of the Teir'Dal city. As it is deeper underground, absolutely no natural light penetrates this part of the city, but that doesn't bother a dark elf. The majority of the shops and taverns of the city are located in the Common quarter. The most famous tavern is easily The Maiden's Fancy, as it features entertainment downstairs that attracts many male citizens. Unlike the Foreign Quarter, the architecture here is more of a Teir'Dal original design featuring several sculptures and fountains. To the rear of the quarter, a house of marble serves as the stronghold of the Indigo Brotherhood as they train Neriak's young warriors in a blood-soaked arena. Next door is the guild hall of The Spurned, the city's population of wizard, enchanter, and magician trainers. This region of the city is also where the bank is located.Neriak Third GateNeriak Third Gate can be a deadly place even for a dark elf, but certainly for anyone who is not of their lineage. The Third Gate is considered sacred for several reasons. The first building found in this part of the city is the temple known as the Spires of Innoruuk, where many come to worship the Prince of Hate and also where some of the greatest clerics on Norrath are trained. A massive building on the north side of town known as the Lodge of the Dead holds the deepest secrets of the dark arts, where necromancers and shadow knights learn new skills and spells. The dark arts are considered above the schools of enchanting, wizardry, and summoning by the elite of Neriak. The necromancers and shadow knights are highly respected, but equally feared. The third guild hall in the Third Gate is the rogue guild. The rogues of Neriak are not respected at all, and are kept in the lowest reaches of the city simply so the highly respected guilds can keep an eye on them. Also found nearby is a library holding the history and secrets of Innoruuk's children.Oasis of MarrOasis of MarrThe Oasis of Marr lies between the two halves of the Desert of Ro and is one of the most popular regions for those who have just left the safer confines of their home towns. The scenery alone is much more desirable than the rest of Ro's Desert. The saltwater crocodiles found on the shores and the endless waves of undead wandering the desert offer a great test to younger adventurers. A camp of gypsies in the center of the region allow for quick access to selling off loot found in the desert. The real danger comes from the occasional sand giant stomping through the desert crushing anyone and everyone regardless of their race, class, or deity. In the center of the oasis is a small island with an intriguing tower. Those foolish enough to inspect this tower will likely never return. Those that do escape often end up causing the death of many other adventurers due to bringing the evil specters of the tower to the beaches on their attempts to escape the region. Further to the south, there are camps of orcs and giant dune tarantulas that will frighten even the trolls who venture north of the swamps.OggokOggokOggok is home to Norrath's ogre population. Located in the northern reaches of the jungle known as The Feerrott, Oggok was founded before the curse laid upon Zek's children by the gods, but the founders' children were the first to show signs of the curse's effects. A few remnants of the ogres of old remains in the design of the city, but today's ogres have ruined most of it with rudimentary stone slabs. The city does offer many shops, taverns, and craftsmen. The dark elves, who have a trade agreement with the ogres, take advantage of the dimwitted behemoths quite often.Permafrost KeepPermafrost KeepPermafrost Keep is easily one of the most dangerous places to visit across Antonica. Legend states that this castle of ice was built long ago by giants who have since left Everfrost in an attempt to escape the curse upon Zek's creations. The vacant keep then became inhabited by a legion of goblins who have mined small passages through the castle. They do not rule this dungeon though. Centuries ago, Lady Vox, an ice dragon formerly of the Ring of Scale, resides in the deepest depths of the ice. The stories heard in the taverns of Halas state that she was exiled by her kin for attempting to mate with a dragon of a different color. Armies comprised of both good and evil adventurers have banded together on countless occasions in attempts to slay the mighty ice dragon, but few have returned. Those few who survive her lair return with some of Norrath's richest treasures, but also with horror stories of friends encased in ice for eternity or slaughtered by massive bears after falling to Vox's traps.QeynosNorth QeynosNorth Qeynos is a sight for sore eyes of those travelers that have made the long trek from Freeport. Virtually anything you could need in terms of weapons, armor, tradeskill supplies, or ale can be found within the walls of Qeynos. The northern part of the city is where one can find the guild houses for the clerics, paladins, and monks of western Antonica. Many of the buildings here appear very old, and that's because they are. North Qeynos is where the city was founded in 5130, then after a war which saw part of the city walls toppled, the king decided to simply expand the city. On the eastern side of town lies the Temple of Life, which includes a small pond surrounded by marble walkways. A platform will teleport clerics and paladins to a strange flying saucer that eternally hovers over the pond. Inside, the most skilled followers of Rodcet Nife offer training and supplies. On the opposite side of town, the disciples of Quellious the Tranquil, known as the Silent Fist, train in hand to hand combat. A relentless, and some would say psychotic, gnoll named Fippy Darkpaw can often be found attempting to raid the city all by himself. Seldom does he get past the front gate's guards, but he often threatens young humans in the yard while they attempt to learn the basics against fire beetles.South QeynosSouth Qeynos is the relatively new side of town. Qeynos is the pinnacle of human achievement and Antonius Bayle IV rules over much of the western half of Antonica. Antonius is loved by most of the city's citizens, but corruption by way of the Circle of the Unseen Hand seems to be slowing creeping into the city. Qeynos is by no means as taken by corruption as Freeport, but Antonius' younger brother Kane is believed by many to be planning to usurp the king. Rumor has it that a guild hall for rogues of the Unseen Hand lies somewhere inside the Crow's Nest tavern. The docks of South Qeynos bring peaceful adventurers back and forth from Odus, but the steep cliffs of the shore make the city impenetrable by sea. Dozens of tents scatter the open plaza where merchants from around the world offer all kinds of wares. Near the center of town, human warriors can be found training to join Bayle's army on the blood soaked Grounds of Fate. Protected by thick walls in the northeast side of teh city is the bank, which is neighbored by several colorful guild houses featuring the human's greatest minds who teach the skills of enchanting, wizardry, and summoning to young humans. Near the gates of North Qeynos is a large blue building where music pours out of the large doors around the clock as bards sing tales about "The Great Unifier," the first Antonius Bayle.Qeynos CatacombsQeynos Catacombs may appear to simply be the means of supplying the great human city with fresh water, but many dangers lie beneath the streets. A temple has been built down here for worshipers of Bertoxxulous the Plaguebringer. A cult of human necromancers and shadow knights practice the dark arts here accompanied with an evil legion of clerics, warriors, casters. Their plans are secret, but do bode well for the city. The aqueducts can be reached either from an underwater entrance near the Qeynos docks, a secret passage outside the gates of North Qeynos, or though one of the various drains about the city. Graffiti on the walls warn trespassers of the evils that lie within. Aside from Plaguebringers cult, many creatures inhabit the murky waters including sharks that have moved in from the nearby ocean.Qeynos HillsQeynos HillsQeynos Hills are the training grounds for humans from the western shores of Antonica. The hills are full of wildlife to test fledgling skills while under the protection of the Qeynos guards nearby. But young adventurers should be careful not to slay any wolves or bears within sight of the rangers of Surefall Glade, as they value the lives of the animals more than that of a poacher. The Glade is beyond the stone cliffs to the north and is where the human and half elf rangers and druids of Karana learn their craft. Blackburrow lies to the northeast, which keeps the guards attention for any incoming gnoll invasion. Out of the east are the Plains of Karana and the long road to Freeport. A small lake can be found on the western borders of the hills. A seemingly innocent barbarian man named Hadden often fishes here when not being attacked by those attempting to steal his earring.Rathe MountainsRathe MountainsRathe Mountains is probably the most dangerous outdoor region of Antonica. Claustrophobic valleys wind through the towering mountains leaving many adventurers blind to threats hiding around every corner. Wildlife such as kodiaks and grizzlies can pounce at any moment. Bandits will pillage travelling traders without thinking twice. Lizardmen from the neighboring Feerrott make sure no one tries to escape the mountains in favor of the jungle. And the Mountains of Rathe are home to the largest population of giants anywhere on Antonica. As dangerous as the region may be, many adventurers reap major rewards. Giants are known for carrying quite a bit of gold. And the gypsy camps near Lake Rathetear to the west make for quick exchange of loot for gold. Another point of interest here are Ankhefenmut and Zazamoukh, a pair of sphinxes that drive adventurers mad with their riddles. Several mysterious towers are scattered about the region, giving a glimpse into the regions past. Historians say that the ogres believe that each of the twelve peaks in this range of mountains each sprung from the ground as Murdunk, the great ogre hero, and the Rallosian Empire of the Elder Age assaulted the twelve remaining members of The Rathe Council. Massive stone arms can be seen atop a plateau, which many believe to be the earth itself reaching to the heavens in anguish as Murdunk slaughtered a member of The Rathe.RivervaleRivervaleRivervale is where Norrath's halflings call home. While halflings are generally laid back, they will often surprise those not welcome in the town with their ferocity. The city is safe for those friendly with Bristlebane's children, except for maybe when Mangler, the crazy guard dog, gets loose. Overall, the city is protected quite well, not just by the sheriff's deputies, but by the granite mountains descending from Highpass and the Wall of Serilis built outside in Misty Thicket. Although Mayor Gubbin is the richest halfling that ever lived and runs the city's day to day affairs, many would tell you that Beak Guinders, the High Priest of Mischief, is the city's true leader. Guinders and his clerics maintain the Chapel of Mischief and he is the one who represents the halflings in foreign affairs. Unlike most societies, the rogues of Rivervale are highly regarded. The Fool's Gold tavern sits in the center of town and serves as the guild house for these rogues, which is run by Lendel Deeppockets. A farm on the east part of town is maintained by the halfling druids of Karana. Many travelers come to Rivervale for a taste of these druids' famous jumjum, whether it be in the form of smoke, juice, pastries, or whatever the special of the week is. The northern part of the village features a lake which is fed by a stream rolling off the mountains of High Pass. Many residents can be found fishing these waters on any given afternoon.Runnyeye CitadelRunnyeye CitadelRunnyeye Citadel is a mind numbing series of twisting caverns that wind deep into the Antonican earth. For those few that have made it to the lowest levels, they return with stories of what appeared to be a legit city of goblins, not simply aimless tunnels of mud. Even fewer have actually befriended the goblins by way of their adventurers in the Gorge of King Xorbb just outside. Enough slaying of muddites, minotaurs, and evil eyes will earn the respect of the clan. Until recently, Xorbb controlled the caverns with the goblins as his slaves. Lord Pickclaw himself is quite indifferent to visitors, unless of course they have slain a few hundred of his kin on the way to his throne room. While it may be much more difficult to get to than the one nearby in Rivervale, how many can say they bank their goods in the Runnyeye vault?Solusek's EyeSolusek's EyeSolusek's Eye is one three caverns found within the massive lava pool in the northern reaches of the Lavastorm Mountains. Most of the dungeon is infested with a clan of fire goblins that do not welcome any visitors regardless of their allegiance. Mid-seasoned adventurers that can withstand the suffocating heat can often emerge with great riches. Gnomes seem to deal with the heat surprisingly well. The Solusek Mining Company has set up shop deep within the region to search for treasure that will make Ak'anon proud. They also have marvelous tinkered servants that are often mistaken for actual gnomes by dimwitted trolls and ogres. These clockwork minions aren't nearly as tasty. Several tunnels will lead unwary adventurers directly into Nagafen's Lair, where more powerful enemies, such as ferocious kobolds, make certain that they will never see the light of day again.Splitpaw LairSplitpawSplitpaw Lair is buried beneath the southern Plains of Karana and can easily be spotted thanks to three dark spires that surround the entrance. Gnolls believe this is one of the few places that Brell Serilis himself set foot on Norrath. The Splitpaw gnolls lived here for generations, serving as only a minor annoyance to the humans of Qeynos. Several years ago though, a tribe of gnolls calling themselves the Verishe Mal invaded the region and vanquished most of the Splitpaw clan. The Verishe Mal are much more advanced in terms of intelligence. They have members trained in almost all arts of melee and magic based combat. No one truly knows where they came from. Some believe their white pelts signify their origin being from some frozen underfoot in Everfrost, while others tell tales of an ancient lost continent. Their leader, known as the Ishva Mal, is a mighty necromancer. Some say he has the skill to summon fallen friends to his feet from great distances in order to be resurrected. Many necromancers wishing to learn this skill have sought the Ishva, but he does not offer his secrets without a fight.Surefall GladeSurefall GladeSurefall Glade is nestled between the rolling Qeynos Hills and the Jaggedpine Forest. Within the dense forest, some of Antonica's best druids and rangers hone their skills before venturing into the wild. Humans and half elves that choose to follow Karana will often leave the walls of Qeynos as soon as possible to begin learning nature's secrets in the Glade. While on friendly terms with the great human city, Surefall is one of the few areas of western Antonica not under Antonius Bayle IV's rule. The druids and rangers are self governed. A glittering pond can be found not far from the cabins. A small waterfall feeds this pond, while bear caves lie hidden behind the falls. Occasionally, a poacher from the nearby Jaggedpine Forest will enter these caves in hopes of snagging a bear pelt. These poachers are not tolerated, and are often incinerated by a nearby druid or pierced by a well placed arrow from a local ranger. The druid guild itself is inside a massive redwood tree, which also serves as a teleport location for skilled hierophants. As such, it is the convenient teleport location for much of the western half of Antonica.Temple of Cazic-ThuleThe Temple of Cazic-ThuleThe Temple of Cazic-Thule has always been a dangerous place to visit, but as time passes, it becomes more deadly. The temple is hidden in the dank marshes of The Feerrott. Its massive stone walls are covered in moss centuries old. The god known as The Faceless, Cazic-Thule, takes great pride in the temple built for him. Over time he has sent more and more of his own minions from the Plane of Fear to inhabit the temple. Great pyramids have been built in the temple. These pyramids are constructed with a unique marble that is not found anywhere else on the continent, which puzzles and frightens many historians. Beneath the pyramids are a series of dark caverns and sewers that trickle into one massive chamber that houses an enormous green sphere. Some of Norrath's elder adventurers tell tales of once battle the Avatar of Fear in this place. Those brave enough to venture into the temple will be tested, but often escape to the jungle with some of the rarest treasures in the world.Temple of Solusek RoThe Temple of Solusek Ro is found in one of the three caves visible from the lava pit in Lavastorm Mountains. Inside, adventurers of all persuasions will find countless quests. Solusek's followers include members of every race, and they teach that one should pay homage to the Burning Prince by simply devoting their lives to improving the skills of their chosen profession. Casters of all four houses of magic will certainly find quests of great interest here. Clerics also will be dedicated to capturing the suit of golden plate armor offered through these quests. Combat is not tolerated within this sacred temple, and those breaking this rule will be dealt with swiftly, for this is a place of learning, not violence. While the quests are offered by men and women of all races and classes, none are hostile to anyone, except the Efreeti Lord Tazgar. Tazgar is believed to be from the astral plane ruled by Solusek Ro himself, sent to keep watch over the temple. Mortals foolish enough to attempt to converse with him will quickly learn how powerful the Burning Prince's wrath can be.FaydwerMap of FaydwerFaydwer is an enchanted land that is covered mostly with thick forests that are guarded to the west and east by the mountains of Butcherblock and Steamfont respectively. The forests here, known as the Faydark, are full of mystical creatures that are not found anywhere else in the world. The children of Brell Serilis, dwarves and gnomes, are native to this land, while the elves came here after their original home lands were scorched by Solusek Ro.Ak'AnonAk'AnonAk'Anon is the reclusive home of Norrath's gnome population. The ancient city is buried beneath the Steamfont Mountains of eastern Faydwer where hundreds of Brell's smallest creation tinker some the world's wildest inventions. The gnomes of Ak'anon are accustomed to being on their own and view other races with a certain level of tension, although they don't often mean any harm. The city features no less than nine guild halls where young gnomes learn their craft before venturing into the outside world. The gnomes clockwork creations have spread across the globe. From fireworks to telescopes, many of their creations are now sold in cities across Norrath. The city guards are actually clockwork creations themselves and are programmed to guide citizens and visitors to locations within the city upon request. Ak'anon is also the only city known to have a zoo. Young gnomes of an evil persuasion have often been found testing their newly learned skills on these defenseless creatures. The two factions seem to have an unspoken truce to not cause harm to one another. The city is ruled by King Ak'anon, the greatest invention of the gnomes. King Ak'anon himself is a clockwork creation. The gnomes have created an immortal king who has ruled over the city for over five centuries without a single year of hardship.Butcherblock MountainsButcherblock MountainsButcherblock Mountains of western Faydwer are where visitors from Antonica first land after crossing the Ocean of Tears. The docks were built by the elves after they were forced from their homes by the raging inferno set forth by Solusek Ro. A series of buildings at the docks represent each of the races to be found on the continent. A trail leads away from the docks, passing by the dwarven city of Kaladim all the way to the Greater Faydark. Dwarven warriors known as the Stormguard patrol this road from their dozens of guard houses posted along the way, making the region tricky to navigate for anyone who has earned the hatred of the dwarves (or were just born with it). The creatures of this region are relatively docile unless provoked. Many dwarves learn their first skills in these mountains by battling scarabs, basilisks, and an occasional drake. A druid ring to the southwest allows for many to skip the long boat ride by simply teleporting to the continent. To the east, a giant chessboard can be found. Its origins are unknown. To the south lies a passage to Dagnor's Cauldron.Castle MistmooreCastle MistmooreCastle Mistmoore is easily the most feared region of Faydwer. All of the continent's citizens have been warned to stay far away from the castle. Mayong Mistmoore's vampiric minions do not take kindly to visitors of any race, even dark elves such as themselves. The castle has been here since before the elves arrived from Tunaria (now Antonica) and before the dwarves first emerged from beneath the mountains. Legend has it that Mayong Mistmoore is a vampire lord over 10,000 years old, and some say he rivals even the gods in terms of power. None lucky enough to have returned from the castle have ever seen the lord himself. Portraits of a Teir'Dal nobleman are hung on the walls in the depths of the castle, leading many to believe Mayong himself was once a mortal dark elf. Despite the ruthless vampires, deadly gargoyle minions, and countless undead, many adventurers discard the warnings of their teachers and enter the castle in search of treasure. Those who return will often speak of luxurious black silks and powerful wreaths of nightshade.CrushboneCrushboneCrushbone is the stronghold of the orcs of Faydwer. The blue-skinned orcs worship Bertoxxulous but have formed a treaty with Innoruuk's children, the dark elves. Located in the cliffs north of the Greater Faydark, the Crushbone orcs raid Kelethin quite often. They send many troops in attempt to chop down the massive trees that support the city. Emperor Crush also sends forth bands of orcs to capture elves and dwarves to work as slaves in the mines that supply the clan with weapons and armor. The elves of Faydwer will look amiably upon any who slay these orcs, especially those that return with proof of the death of the high priest, emperor, or Ambassador D'Vinn. D'Vinn is a dark elf that resides within the citadel. He was sent by Queen Cristanos Thex of Neriak to negotiate with the orcs. The dimwitted orcs get funding and better weapons, while the dark elves get an army of minions attempting to exterminate the high elves and wood elves without ever having to leave Nektulos Forest themselves.Dagnor's CauldronDagnor's CauldronDagnor's Cauldron is easily the most treacherous terrain on the continent. The region is named for the great dwarven hero, Dagnor Butcherblock, for this is where he fell in battle with the ogres many decades ago. The sharp granite peaks are covered in slippery moss and drop abruptly to the salt water lake below. The Ocean of Tears can be heard crashing against the other side of the rocks, but the Cauldron is completely walled in from the ocean itself. Many dwarves tell horror stories of a great monster that lies beneath the lake. Those that have dared to enter the waters tell tales of magnificent pillars marking the entrance to an underwater city known to historians as Kedge Keep. At the southern edge of the Cauldron is the entrance to the Estate of Unrest, which was once a beautiful mansion, but is now overrun with the most vile creatures imaginable. A clan of water goblins roam the region attacking any adventurers on sight. A lone island can be seen in the center of the lake. Rogues speak of a reclusive dwarf on this island that sells powerful poisons and teaches the skills to create them.Estate of UnrestThe Estate of UnrestThe Estate of Unrest was originally a mansion built by a high priest of Quellious. This human cleric brought his family from Qeynos to Faydwer in an attempt to spread the word of The Tranquil to a new continent of people. A dwarf by the name of Garanel Rucksif had, for unknown reasons, gone insane and murdered his family in Kaladim. During his escape from the city, he found the estate and murdered the human cleric and his family. The act so angered Quellious that she actually lost her temper and struck Garanel with a wicked curse causing him to spend eternity within the confines of the estate. An erudite priest from Paineel caught wind of this story and set out to investigate the matter. This priest of The Faceless confronted the dwarf ghost and convinced him of a vile plan. The erudite exhumed the bodies of the dead and dissected them into hundreds of pieces. He then cast a might spell that called upon Cazic-Thule himself. Cazic answered the call, seeing the devotion his priest offered, for the erudite had presented an opportunity for The Faceless to take adventage of Quellious' unexpected rash of anger. The spell was so powerful that it killed the erudite, but with the touch of Cazic-Thule, the pieces of decayed flesh and bone mutated into full bodies of the most wretched undead creatures. The priest's sacrifice essentially left an army of ghouls, festering hags, and other terrifying creations for Garanel's ghost to command.FaydarkGreater FaydarkGreater Faydark is a dense forest that was formerly home to pixies, drakes, brownies, and other mystical creatures. A few of these creatures remain, but much of the forest has been claimed by the immigrant elves. The high elves have built an extravagant castle to the southeast while the wood elves have built the wonderous city of Kelethin within the treetops of the forest. A winding trail from the Butcherblock Mountains to the west leads visitors to the region past Castle Felwithe and to the lifts that take citizens to the city of Kelethin. Along the path are a set of massive spires marking the central teleport location for wizards coming to Faydwer. Small camps of bandits have been seen in the forest, but the true threat comes from the Crushbone orcs to the north. The orc pawns and other forest critters offer excellent training for the pupils of both elvish cities. Many of these young adventurers have complained to the higher ups of Kelethin though, as the guards often ignore cries for help. To the south lies a passage to the Lesser Faydark, which is where the majority of the fay moved when the elves arrived.Lesser FaydarkLesser Faydark is the last portion of the forest that is not under elvish control. A decent amount of traffic comes through thanks to the Steamfont Mountains and Ak'Anon to the east. Most stay as far away from the southwest areas of the forest due to the closeness of Castle Mistmoore. Many young paladins and clerics come to Lesser Faydark to test their skills against the undead that often roam the region. The mystical creatures that roam the woods have been here for over 1000 years, long before the dwarves or gnomes emerged from the Underfoot. While the fay tolerate their mortal neighbors for the most part, there is a village of brownies near the northwest borders of the forest that will attack anyone taller than them on sight. Those few who have befriended these brownies, or beguiled them, tell tales of an assortment of unique items sold by their vendors. A handful of adventurers have spoke of a white unicorn prancing through the Faydark.FelwitheNorth FelwitheFelwithe is the home of Norrath's Koada'Dal, the high elves. The castle in North Felwithe is a beauty to behold with its checkered marble floors, lush trees, silk tapestries, and sparkling water that flows through the heart of the city. The paladins and clerics are the pride of the hamlet due to their devotion to Tunare, the Mother of All. The city is named for Alissa Felwithe who led the elves from the devastation they suffered at the hands of Solusek Ro. The dwarves of Kaladim immediately formed an alliance with their new neighbors, helping construct the beautiful castle with their decades of masonry. Many shops are scattered throughout the city, many of which are run by heroes of old. Taverns are just as popular as in other cities, except here adventurers will find mostly wine instead of beer and ale. The city is governed by King Tearis Thex.South FelwitheSouth Felwithe is where the casters of the Koada'Dal learn their craft. Upon entering this part of the city, there is a shop selling robes, staves, and other equipment for the city's spell casting population. Then there is a small marble building magically rests above a pond here in the southern half of the city. This building is the gateway to the Keepers of the Art, the magical academy. A stairway leads to the building where, inside, three glowing platforms can be found. Each platform represents a house of magic and by stepping upon the selected platform, an adventurer will be teleported to the respective guild house on the otherwise unreachable opposite side of the pond. Inside each guild hall are countless tomes chronicling the elves history. The greatness of the city of Takish'Hiz will not be forgotten by the elves of Faydwer.KaladimKaladimSouth Kaladim is the largest part of the underground stronghold of the dwarves. They are a proud people and welcome any good-natured visitors to buy, sell, and trade their wares, for the dwarves offer some of the best blacksmithing on Norrath. The dwarves will not tolerate any visitors of the dark allegiances without extensive work to prove their worth. Upon passing through the elaborate gates of the city from Butcherblock Mountains, paths extend to the west and east. To the west are many homes, shops, and an arena in front of the city's warrior guild. To the east is Stormhammer Hold, the home of King Kazon Stormhammer. The Hold is one of the most magnificent displays of architecture one will ever see. King Stormhammer struggles every day with the problems facing his people, now especially with the alliance between the nearby orcs and the despised dark elves.North KaladimNorth Kaladim is the largest part of the underground stronghold of the dwarves. They are a proud people and welcome any good-natured visitors to buy, sell, and trade their wares, for the dwarves offer some of the best blacksmithing on Norrath. The dwarves will not tolerate any visitors of the dark allegiances without extensive work to prove their worth. Upon passing through the elaborate gates of the city from Butcherblock Mountains, paths extend to the west and east. To the west are many homes, shops, and an arena in front of the city's warrior guild. To the east is Stormhammer Hold, the home of King Kazon Stormhammer. The Hold is one of the most magnificent displays of architecture one will ever see. King Stormhammer struggles every day with the problems facing his people, now especially with the alliance between the nearby orcs and the despised dark elves.Kedge KeepKedge KeepKedge Keep is the most unique dungeon across the three continents of Norrath. The entire ancient city is under water. Adventuring here requires either a magical item that grants the ability to breathe underwater, or the aid of a friendly druid. The Kedge were a highly intelligent fish-like race of people who studied science and magic, but only one has survived. His name is Phinigel Autropos, and he is considered by many to be the most powerful wizard in the world, rivaled only by Al'Kabor. The city is now overrun with sharks and other aquatic creatures that threaten even the most experienced adventurers. A society of beautiful mermaids also live here, formerly on their own accord, but now under the enchantment of Phinigel. Within the ruins, a temple to Prexus the Ocean Lord can be found, which tends to make historians believe the Kedge honored Prexus rather than the Triumvirate of Water. Phinigel Autropos sought to become the greatest wizard the world had ever seen. He thirsted for knowledge and even created a spell that would allow him to leave the water for short periods of time in order to learn from other cultures. After years of study, Phinigel attempted to cast a spell in the Temple of Prexus; on that would show his people his true magnificence. The maelstrom of arcane power that Phinigel unleashed killed everyone in the city. Historians believe that the power summoned by Phinigel was that of Prexus himself, and the power was unbearable for mortal souls. Phinigel, somehow surviving the blast, retreated to the depths of the city. Over the decades, his guilt turned to rage. Adventurers of many types now search for him, as he holds many powerful artifacts.KelethinKelethinKelethin is the treetop city built by the wood elves. It is easily the most wondrous city in all of Norrath as it is constructed of dozens of massive wooden platforms hundreds of feet off the ground connected by suspension bridges. Three lifts are set up in different parts of the city to take citizens and visitors up and down to and from the Greater Faydark. The city is completely safe from raiding orcs, but the orcs have begun to chop at the trees that support the city. Young adventurers can reap great rewards from the various guild halls of the city by thwarting the orcs attempts. The wood elves are a quiet and reserved race of people, but welcome any good-natured people to their city. The various platforms, ramps, and bridges can become confusing for young wood elves, and especially visitors, and it's not unheard of to have some fall to their deaths. But once familiar with the city's routes, any amenities needed or wanted can be acquired here. Tradeskill tools are scattered throughout the platforms. Several taverns selling wines and ales to resting adventurers are available. And of course the city has its own guilds that train young citizens. The pride of the city is Faydark's Champions, where some of Norrath's greatest rangers begin their journey. The Emerald Warriors equip the only full blooded, untainted elven warriors in the world. The Scouts of Tunare teach the forest's sneakiest rogues the tricks of the trade. Wood elves also make for some of the best bards in the world thanks to Songweavers' guild hall. And finally, there is the Soldiers of Tunare druid guild, for the large chunk of Kelethin's population that choose to serve Tunare in the purest way possible.Steamfont MountainsSteamfont MountainsSteamfont Mountains are named for the natural geysers and springs that pepper the region. These mountains are very old and it is known that dragons once resided here, as their bones are left behind to prove it. Small drakes fly throughout the region, being the only living proof of the mountains' ancient history. Not much else is known about the dragons' history here, for they were long gone before the gnomes emerged from the Underfoot. In present times, the region serves as a training ground for a myriad of gnome adventurers. The city of Ak'anon lies to the south. Some young elves from the nearby Faydark also join the gnomes in their hunting here. An ancient druid ring still stands in the southwest corner of the range, being one of just two teleport locations for druids on Faydwer. Massive windmills near the center of the region show travelers the wonder of gnomish tinkering. In the far north, minotaurs rule a series of caves speak of an evil gnome known as Meldrath who plots against his own kin.OdusOdusOdus is the smallest continent on the face of Norrath. It features thick forests, a snow-capped mountain range, and a tropical, yet rocky coast line. The creatures native to Odus have been forced to make room for the Erudites who migrated to this land from across the sea in Qeynos. The Erudites have since split into two warring factions, which has left many of the indigenous creatures caught in the crossfire. A race of peaceful, tribal cat people, known as Kerrans, are the most notable of the innocent bystanders. Much of their population was lost during the war between the Erudites. Most of Odus is not dangerous to a mid-seasoned adventurer, but many secrets lie beneath the surface in what has become known as The Hole.ErudinErudinErudin is home to the High Men known most commonly as Erudites. From the moment one enters the city, either by sea or from the Toxxulia Forest, it is obvious that Erudin is an extravagant city. The Erudites are highly intelligent and often considered snobbish by other races, but they are a good people that detest those with evil intentions. Erudites take pride in their vast knowledge, thus the city features the most robust library found anywhere among the three continents. Erudin rests high on the cliffs overlooking the Vasty Deep. Its streets are made with the finest marble and the lush gardens are impeccable. The steep cliffs make the city quite defensible. A port is located just north of the city where boats travel to and from Qeynos, but it is not directly attached to the city itself. All entrances to Erudin involve a teleport platform, which can easily be deactivated if the Erudites ever needed to defend their great city. The great library is located in the center of the town square surrounded by various shops, a guild hall for clerics and paladins of Prexus, and an inn. All of these buildings are built of the most beautiful stones available. Just north of the courtyard lies a grand stairway to Erudin Palace, the interior part of the city, which is also accessed via teleportation. Near the teleporter is yet another teleporter that takes citizens to the docks. Nestled quietly behind the staircase is a church for more clerics and paladins. This church worships Quellious the Tranquil.Erudin PalaceErudin Palace is a sight to behold. The entire palace is constructed with marble accented with the most precious stones and metals in the world. Silk banners are draped upon the walls while crystal clear water flows through the palace's series of fountains. Upon entering the palace, stairs will take visitors down to a large open room which features the city's bank, city hall, and a jewelry store. The jewelcrafters also offer training for those wishing to learn the trade. Beneath city hall is the city prison. Upstairs, surrounding an enchanting fountain are the three colleges of the arcane arts. Erudin produces some of the world's most powerful wizards, magicians, and enchanters. Much like the outdoor parts of the city, the Palace is a quiet and calm place built for learning and reflection.The HoleThe HoleThe Hole is also referred to as the Ruins of Old Paineel and can only be entered from inside Paineel itself. Not too long ago, a faction of Erudites decided to start their own city, where they would be free to practice the dark arts of necromancy and worship The Faceless, Cazic-Thule. Erudites true to Prexus and Quellious refer to these defectors as Heretics, but they refer to themselves as Cazicites. After the split, a battle for supremacy was held between the two factions of High Men. At the climax of the battle, the combined powers of the two armies of spell casters resulted in a cataclysmic eruption of the ground they stood upon. Massive craters were left in the earth, the largest of which is now referred to as simply The Hole. Shocked at the effect of their power, both sides retired from the field of battle. The Heretics retreated into the depths created by the blast and built a secret city they called Paineel and continued their studies of the forbidden magic of the dead. The Heretics also explored the mysterious caverns revealed by the crater, and eventually discovered what is known as the Vault of Living Stone. It is believed that the gates beyond the vault lead to the Plane of Underfoot, the realm of Brell Serilis. Many say that this is the way in which Brell came to Norrath to "plant" his creations (dwarves, gnomes, gnolls, etc.) deep within the earth. The vault was built to protect mortals by keeping the more vicious denizens of Brell's plane, led by Master Yael, from entering Norrath. Foolishly, the Heretics must have opened the gate, because the Ruins of Old Paineel are now overrun with earth elementals and powerful minions infused with the strength of Brell. Ghosts of Old Paineel's citizens wander aimlessly through the halls. These dangers make The Hole a worthy test for even the most battle tested adventurers.Kerra IsleKerra IsleKerra Isle is a tropical beach surround by the sharp rocks that make up the northern part of Odus. The isle is populated by a cat-like race of people known as Kerrans. They are mostly friendly to visitors unless of course they are provoked. Adventurers should be careful, because the Kerrans are an intelligent bunch who will fight in packs with a mix of warriors and shaman that can outlast many younger groups of heroes. The Kerrans hold nightly bonfires in honor of their fallen hero, Kejaan, who is credited with bringing the many tribes of Kerrans together for the common good of their people. Many of the villages warriors will call upon Kejaan to help them in battle. Those friendly with the Kerrans will find that they offer various quests, including the much sought after Paw of Opolla. Priestess Mitty currently governs the village, but her views are a bit different than previous leaders. Under her rule, the village has become a society dominated by the females of the tribe. Many of the Kerran people were lost as collateral damage in the great war between the Erudites. The large lake around the village is said to have been due to a large crater caused by the maelstrom of magic. The villagers say the earth ripped apart and a large portion of their isle was launched into the skies above.PaineelPaineelPaineel is now a thriving city above ground where Erudites who have chosen to follow the teachings of the god of fear, Cazic-Thule, practice dark magic. The Cazicites of Paineel say that the earth itself is infused with powerful magic in this region of Norrath, giving them even more skill. Visitors of any kind are not often welcome here. Most would not even recognize the entrance to the city, as it is a lift hidden within the stone cliffs surrounding The Hole. A field of rollings hills known simply as The Yard lies outside the city walls where young pupils can test their fledgling skills against bats, rats, and other critters without fear of the self-righteous Erudites attacking them in Toxxulia Forest. The citizens of Paineel walk amongst the undead they have summoned to protect the city. The city itself is divided via portals much like Erudin. The first section of town includes the shadow knight guild known as The Fell Blade and an arena for practice between trainees. The second section of town is the busiest as it features many shops selling all kinds of goods, the city's bank, and The Abbatoir, which is the guild hall for the necromancers of Paineel. The final portion of the city is where Darkglow Palace can be found. Just outside the palace are a few more shops and also the Tabernacle of Terror, where a fearsome guild of clerics study the ways of fear. The residents have also built an observation deck on the opposite side of The Hole only reachable via teleportation from within the city, which allows them to keep watch over all those coming in from Toxxulia.Stonebrunt MountainsStonebrunt MountainsStonebrunt Mountains is a truly unique region. The northern part of the area is coated with thick snow year-round, but as the mountains roll south, they are met with a dense jungle, and then sharp cliffs that drop to a beach that faces the gulf to the south. A waterfall at the northeastern most reaches of the mountains flows all the way to the Gulf of Uzun. Wizards and druids have recently learned the ability to teleport to this remote land, otherwise, the only way to reach the mountains would be by passing through the underground lair of kobolds known as The Warrens. Many camps of kobolds can be found in the southern half of the mountain range, which will test groups of adventurers' skills in managing packs of enemies. The largest of the snowy peaks to the north is known as Mount Klaw. Upon this peak is a small village of Kerrans known as the Kejeka tribe. The Kejeka are a spiritual people and seek to protect the secrets of their encampment from all others. They are generally friendly to visitors, yet hesitant to reveal much of their ways of life. They long for a day whenthey can coexist with the Erudites, but are content with their anonymity for now. While the Kerrans of Kerra Isle are a matriarchal society, it is obvious that the Kejekans are a patriarchal one. The shaman of the village are the authority, while a house of monks teach the younglings the ways of combat by use of claws and teeth. The females of the village are generally the workers and gatherers.Toxxulia ForestToxxulia ForestToxxulia Forest is where many Erudites begin to learn the ways of combat, but they'd be better served by getting on the boat to Qeynos and venturing into Qeynos Hills to learn their craft. Toxxulia Forest is a dense, dark forest and Erudites have no enhanced vision, which makes the forest a struggle to even navigate. Most of the creatures in this forest are docile unless provoked, making the area relatively safe. But there are some ferocious kobolds that can quickly swarm young pupils from Erudin. Several azure huts are located near the city, which allow for adventurers to easily sell their loot before venturing back into the forest. At the southeast border of the forest, a set of massive wizard spires can be found signifying the presence of the Combine Empire here long ago. The spires offer an easy way to Erudin's wizards to return home with ease. Just north of the spires is an ancient druid ring, which allows druids to explore the continent they may otherwise never see. Across the river to the west lies Kerra Isle, and the dark city of Paineel rests to the south.The WarrensThe WarrensThe Warrens was discovered not all that long ago by curious citizens of Paineel. The underground lair is home to Odus' kobold population. Any kobold seen on the continent came from here originally. These dog-like creatures attack in packs and are deadly to lone adventurers. Those wishing to make it all the way to Stonebrunt Mountains will do themselves a favor by bringing a few friends along. The skills learned here will prepare many young adventurers for the battles they will face later in life. The dirty caves eventually lead to a more civilized looking, stone floored courtyard. The Erudites who have studies the region tell tales of the kobolds of old building an empire within the Stonebrunt Mountains with the aid of their creator, Brell Serilis. The kobolds were apparently, at one time, Brell's chosen ones long before the dwarves and gnomes emerged from the depths of Faydwer. When Brell turned his attention to the eastern continent, the kobolds felt abandoned, so they rejected the teachings of their creators. The kobolds of The Warrens now worship Rolfron Zek, the Lord of Despair, as they attempt to rebuild their former glory under the rule of King Gragnar.OceansThe map of the known world has many large bodies of water. The Ocean of Tears, between Antonica and Faydwer, and Erud's Crossing, between Odus and Antonica, are the only two that are relatively safe. The elves have recently sent expeditions south into the Timorous Deep from Faydwer, but no hard facts have been revealed to the public. The waters west of Odus have become known as the Abysmal Sea, for none have returned after sailing into the darkness.Erud's CrossingErud's CrossingErud's Crossing lies between the continents of Odus and Antonica. This region is named in reference to when Erud led his people from Qeynos to build their own city on the western continent. Two boats make trips back and forth between the cities every day. When taking the trip from Qeynos to Erudin, the boat will make a short stop on Talysra's Paw. This small island is home to a tribe of Kerran people, known as the Laahr, who are friendly to most adventurers. They have named the island in honor of their new god. Their belief in Talysra was what caused them to leave Kerra Isle in Odus to start their own society. The island does offer experience for small groups as the inverted, dormant volcano has many will-o-wisps, bats, and other creatures crawling about it. Off the western shores of the island is a sunken ship of unknown origins, which is guarded by a group of zombie sailors. Scattered around the island are large, mysterious stone blocks featuring faces on each side. No one knows where they came from, but obviously ten to make many believe an ancient civilization once inhabited the island. If visiting the island, it is smartest to wait for a boat in order to leave, for it is a long swim to either continent and the waters are infested with sharks.The Ocean of TearsOcean of TearsThe Ocean of Tears gets its name from the elves who crossed these waters after their homeland was burnt to the ground by Solusek Ro. The elves left Antonica (then known as Tunaria) and traveled to Faydwer in search of a new home. The ocean is quite large and features many small islands along the trade routes that two boats travel back and forth from Freeport to Butcherblock Mountains. Upon entering the ocean from Freeport, the ship will almost immediately stop at an island inhabited by the Sisters of Erollisi, who are a group of elves and half elves that left the city of Kelethin in order to freely worship the goddess of love. They are friendly to all good-natured travelers and offer to trade many goods. Directly across from the Sisters isle to the north is an isle inhabited by a legion of ferocious goblins. Strangely, there is also a high elf on this isle known as the Oracle of K'Arnon, who is protected by his trusted bodyguard. To the east of the Sisters Isle is where lucky adventurers tell tales of spotting the ancient cyclops. Many adventurers have waited on these beaches for days or even weeks in hopes of spotting him to no avail.Ocean of TearsTo the east of this isle is the largest land mass in the region, which is primarily inhabited by the Seafury clan of cyclopses. A small band of friendly pirates somehow coexist on the island with these behemoths. To the north of the Seafury isle is an isle populated with spectres who worship a mysterious dark tower. No visitors are welcome here. Along the southern edge of the ocean is another large island inhabited by more goblins. At the peak of this island is a temple where some say a monstrous lizard sometimes worships Cazic-Thule. As the boat approaches Faydwer, it passes between to rocky spires which are inhabited by sirens who lure foolhardy adventurers to leap off the boat. North of these spires is an isle inhabited by a colorful race of aviaks. Before docking in Butcherblock, ships will pass through a second set of rocky cliffs as aqua goblins glare at the passing adventurers. When traveling from Butcherblock, the boat will quickly stop at an elven outpost who offer to buy and sell goods, but not much else of interest can be found here. The boat will then swiftly travel along the northern borders of the ocean to East Freeport.PlanesThe planes are the realms of the gods. While it is said that mortals are unable to fully comprehend these astral planes, a means of travelling to several of these realms has been discovered by the races of Norrath.The Plane of FearThe Plane of FearThe Plane of Fear is home to Cazic-Thule the Faceless and his army of fear mongers. It is the first plane to have been discovered by adventurers of the Age of Turmoil. A portal to the plane rests hidden within the rocky cliffs that border The Feerrott. Those who are brave enough to step through the portal and lucky enough to return are often changed forever by the sights they see within the realm of the god of fear. Even worshipers of Cazic-Thule are not welcome in this plane. To escape the plane alive, the most experienced adventurers often charge into the plane in groups of forty or more. The realm itself appears to mortals as a dense jungle with numerous graveyards and decrepit buildings housing some of the most vile creatures ever imaginable. A massive pyramid to the north is surrounded by a moat of fire, while several smaller pyramids dot the jungle where Cazic-Thule's golems guard the plane. Fright, Terror, and Dread are their names, and they have the ability to instantly kill any intruder they choose. The sky here is an uneasy crimson and will often open up to rain blood upon all who inhabit the plane. The denizens of fear do offer some of the best armor available for many classes. Those skillful and lucky enough to escape the plane often return to their city's clad in new silks, mail, and armor never seen before. Those brave or foolish enough to attack the Lord of Fear himself will have done themselves a favor to slaughter the rest of the denizens of the plane first. By doing so , they will be better equipped to face The Faceless, but also because Cazic-Thule will summon any of the remaining minions to his aid. Cazic appears to mortal eyes as a hulking mass of what appears to be dirt and clay with four arms and razor sharp spikes running down his back. It is quickly obvious as to why his followers refer to him as The Faceless.The Plane of HateThe Plane of HateThe Plane of Hate is home to the creator of trolls and dark elves, the Prince of Hate, Innoruuk. There is not an entrance to his plane from anywhere upon Norrath. A skilled wizard must cast a spell with the aid of a special stone only available from the church in Neriak in order to take a group of adventurers to the realm of hate. Most of those brave enough to assault the plane will coordinate the efforts of several wizards in order to bring a small army into the realm. Dark elves often speak of wanting to enter the plane to pay homage to their father, but no visitors are welcome here, regardless of their race, class, or deity of choice. Innoruuk's minions only offer spite and malevolence to those not invited to the realm. The inhabitants of Hate include a legion of dark elf warriors and clerics hand picked by the Prince of Hate himself. Also calling this plane home are an assortment of ghouls, vampires, gargoyles, and even undead dragons. Much like the Plane of Fear, slaying the denizens of Hate will gain many members of the assault new class-based armor that is unmatched in the material realm of Norrath. These rare and powerful items are what draw mortal men and women of all races to Innoruuk's plane despite its dangers. The plane itself is like a massive city of unorganized streets and buildings set in such a way to confuse invaders. In a large structure to the northeast resides the Maestro of Rancor, a villain of such great power that he is only rivaled by Innoruuk himself. Innoruuk rules the plane from the upper levels of the metropolis. The Prince of Hate appears to mortals as a towering, withered, troll-like man with indigo colored hands and feet.The Plane of SkyPlane of SkyThe Plane of Sky is the realm of Veeshan the Wurm Queen. Her plane is unlike the two known to the people of Norrath, for there is a society of Veeshan worshipers here who offer quests in the form of tests of skill to adventurers of any class. The plane itself, as viewed by mortals, is comprised of a series of massive floating islands held together by gigantic chains. Veeshan herself is not present here, for they say her divinity and power is too great for any mortal to comprehend. Even in her absence, all of the creatures found here serve her faithfully. Legend states that when the universe was young, Veeshan traveled through the cosmos marking planets she claimed as her own. The other gods then followed, taking interest in any worlds deemed worthy by Veeshan. The Plane of Sky is all about progression, because each island is only accessible after meeting certain requirements on the previous one. Unlike anywhere else, adventurers must work together to solve the riddles of the realm and earn enough keys to continue. Similar to the Plane of Hate, there is no entrance to Veeshan's astral plane from the material realm of Norrath. A wizard must teleport his companions to the plane using a stone discovered by the erudites. While visiting the plane, everyone will learn one simple lesson; don't mess with Sirran the Lunatic.</description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12149">Dark Age of Camelot</game><game id="9705">Lineage II: The Chaotic Chronicle</game><game id="4791">Vanguard: Saga of Heroes</game><game id="11142">Final Fantasy XI Online</game><game id="545">Asheron's Call</game><game id="8474">Guild Wars: Factions</game><game id="5767">Ultima Online</game><game id="9437">Star Wars: Galaxies - An Empire Divided</game><game id="21545">Tibia</game><game id="21308">Aion: Ascension</game><game id="13682">Asheron's Call 2: Fallen Kings</game><game id="24416">Free Realms</game><game id="8999">The Realm</game><game id="27767">Soul of the Ultimate Nation</game><game id="13869">Istaria: Chronicles of the Gifted</game><game id="22395">Copernicus</game><game id="26770">Rift</game><game id="12376">The Lord of the Rings Online: Shadows of Angmar</game><game id="38774">Final Fantasy XI: Seekers of Adoulin</game><game id="38488">Rift: Storm Legion</game><game id="38206">The Elder Scrolls Online</game><game id="19138">Meridian 59</game><game id="21223">Guild Wars 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15693/625406-everquest_box_art_1_.jpg</image></root>