<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10927</id><name>Loom</name><description>In Loom, you take control of young     Bobbin Threadbare. Following cataclysmic events early in the game, Bobbin goes on a quest of fate and prophecy.  Throughout the story you interact with an enchanted swan with whom you are mysteriously connected. The interface in Loom is unlike any of the other     SCUMM games; Bobbin interacts with his surroundings by using musical enchantments, which replace the standard adventure game commands. This interface created a uniquely immersive gameplay environment. However, the game was not as successful as Lucasfilms had hoped, and the sequel it was obviously poised for never arrived. Loom is referenced in a few other     LucasArts games, most notably     The Secret of Monkey Island.  Examples include a minor Loom character appearing as the pirate in the     SCUMM bar who shamelessly advertises Loom, as well as     Guybrush's reaction to     Meathook.  A dialogue selection from that event reads  "I'm Bobbin, are you my mother?"  Meathook replies, "Your mother was a duck." in reference to the swan from Loom. A Seagull from Loom can also be found by the water outside the SCUMM Bar kitchen.  The original release of Loom came with an audio cassette containing a 30 minute dramatized prologue for the game.  All the music in Loom is from the 1877 ballet "Swan Lake" by Tchaikovsky.   Loom was re-released on Steam on July 8th, 2009 along with a few other LucasArts classic adventure games.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3019">The Secret of Monkey Island</game><game id="600">Future Wars</game><game id="6728">Zak McKracken and the Alien Mindbenders</game><game id="14748">Indiana Jones and The Last Crusade: The Graphic Adventure</game><game id="3633">Indiana Jones and the Fate of Atlantis</game><game id="10915">Beneath a Steel Sky</game><game id="14075">Gabriel Knight: Sins of the Fathers</game><game id="21914">A Vampyre Story</game><game id="7947">Lure of the Temptress</game><game id="9527">Flight of the Amazon Queen</game><game id="21667">Gray Matter</game><game id="14097">The Neverhood</game><game id="2614">The Dig</game><game id="3880">Monty Python's The Meaning of Life</game><game id="31657">Jolly Rover</game><game id="6630">Aquaria</game><game id="33158">Kaptain Brawe: A Brawe New World</game><game id="39355">Primordia</game><game id="42300">Spellirium</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4938/609394-loom_box_front_6552x8262.jpg</image></root>