<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10990</id><name>Genma Onimusha</name><description>OverviewGenma Onimusha is an updated version of Onimusha: Warlords but released for the Xbox. The game has various changes from the original. Such as more enemies which are also tougher. Green soul energy which can be absorbed for temporary invulnerability however if the Genma monsters absorb this they become faster and stronger. There is also a new area as well as new costumes and this time around enemies limbs can be cut off. A few new cut scenes were also added and a super attack. The game also received minor graphical updates.PlotThe story begins with a powerful warlord of Saruga, Yoshimoto Imagawa, has intentions to unify Japan; just so he can become the sole king of the country. Yoshimoto then leads an army to take over the capitals of Japan. On a march in Owari, the entire army halt and decide to rest in for the night.While resting, an army of 2,000 Soldiers that's being lead by the warlord of Owari, Nobunaga Oda, ambushes Yoshimoto and his army. While the invasion was going on, a man far up on a hill, Samaosuke Akechi, watches on. One of Nobunaga's soldiers runs up to Nobunaga and gives him the news that Yoshimoto was slayed and his army was defeated. Nobunaga stands up and starts laughing manically about the victory over Yoshimoto; then a arrow from one of Yoshimoto's men pierces Nobunaga's throat. He falls to the ground with blood pouring out rapidly out of his throat, his life slowly begins to fade.One year after the events of Nobunaga's death, strange occurrences was starting to emerge at the Inabayama Castle; disappearances of Soliders and workers without a trace. Cause of the unusuals events, the princess of the castle, Princess Yuki, sent a SOS to her cousin, Samanosuke. Samanosuke arrives but he was too late, Yuki was kidnapped.Right after that, an attack was being made on the castle. By a army of inhumane creators, demons, that was led by the Nobunaga Oda (Whom was presumed dead). Samanosuke and a female ninja named Kaede decide to go and rescue Princess Yuki and defeat Nobunaga and his army of demon warriors.GameplaySamanosuke, engages in battle.Onimusha's gameplay is pretty much a cross between Resident Evil and Devil May Cry. The action is on par with Devil May Cry, while the progression, camera preservative, and controls was on the vein of the earlier Resident Evil games. The game also has several puzzle solving sequences.The game also has a leveling up system, the way it works, is Samanosuke uses a gauntlet to collect red "souls" from defeated enemies. The souls are use for enhances weapons, magic, and healing items. There are also other versions of the souls that is use for other purpose.Souls TypeRed Souls: Use for enhancing weapons and items.Blue Souls: Use for restoring magic that is lost.Yellow Souls: Use for recovering health.Green Souls: Use for temporary invulnerability. Though, if the demon were to gather them first, it will make them stronger and faster.WeaponsNormal SwordJust a plain old samurai sword that is use for the beginning of the game.RaizanA more powerful version of the Normal Sword and its style of fighting is in the same way.EnryuuA broad sword that's a bit slow, but can perform powerful strikes.ShippuuA weapon with blades on both ends. It's also extremely fast.Bishamon SwordThe most powerful in the game. This sword has no magic mainly due to its tremendous power.MagicShidenA lighting fast combo attack with the final blow being a vertical strike with a bolt of lighting striking down from above.KoudenA vertical strike with the blade bursting into a viscous flame.ArashA vortex that can take down any enemies that's near it.CharactersSammnosuke AkechiSamanosuke."A master swordman who travels across Japan seeking his rival. Often preceived as a passionless solider because of his quiet ways, Samanosuke is actually a hot-blooded warrior with a noble sense of justice."KaedeKaede."An expert kunoichi (female ninja), Kaede was originally send by the Iga ninjas to assassinate Samanosuke. Instead, she develops absolute trust in him and joins him as his confident."YukiPrincess Yuki."Yuki is the sister of Yoshitatsu, the master of Inabayama Castle and Samanosuke's cousin. She becomes aware of strange events in the castle and sends an SOS to Samanosuke. But before he arrives, she is mysteriously kidnapped."YumamaruYumemaru."An enigmatic orphan discovered by Samanosuke while looking for Yuki in the castle."Toukichiro KinoshitaToukichiro Kinoshita."One of Nobunaga's high-ranking generals, Kinoshita has the warlord's complete trust. Though he has sworn absolute loyalty to Nobunaga, the only thing Kinoshita truly cares about is his own advancement in the ranks of power."Nobunaga OdaNobunaga Oda."An exceptional warlord who aspires to unify Japan. With the victory against Imagawa in Okehazama, he rides a tidal wave of success. Though he was once thought dead, Nobunaga's acts have now become extremely heartless and cruel."EnemiesKatana AshigaruKatana Ashigaru.A slow-moving skeleton that uses a sword or a bow.Three-EyesAn agile blue-suited ninja with three glowing green eyes. The can leap from a distance.Dark SpiderAn enhanced version of the Three-Eyes. They can perform illusions of them self and throw projectiles.Long ArmA tall samurai that can grab Samanosuke from a distances.Dark ArmorThree-Eyes.A enhance version of the Long Arm, and also holds a shield.BazooBoar-like demons that carry machetes, and have a rolling attack.Bala BazooThese bull-like demons have giant axe. They're very powerful, but slow.SharukaAnt-like demons that uses their legs as a weapon.GalarnA blue skull demon that floats around sucking up demon souls.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26431">Kengo: Legend of the 9</game><game id="8898">Genji: Dawn of the Samurai</game><game id="11334">Blood Will Tell: Tezuka Osamu's Dororo</game><game id="13072">Devil May Cry</game><game id="16741">Devil May Cry 2</game><game id="32687">Ninja Gaiden 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2115772-box_onimushax.png</image></root>