<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>10993</id><name>Stunt Island</name><description>Overview Stunt Island is a flight simulator and movie making sim released for the PC in 1992 by Disney Interactive. While basically a flight simulator at heart, the game allows for the creation of short films using the in-game Set Design creator- including placement of cameras, props, vehicles, and more- and the Editing Room, where multi-camera films can be edited, scored, and finally viewed and exported for viewing by others, making it one of the earliest forms of Machinima creation software.   Story  The Stunt Coordinator. Smug, behind a desk. While lacking a traditional narrative, the player can choose to either create their own stunts and films or to follow the direction provided by the Stunt Coordinator. The Stunt Coordinator takes the player through 32 stunts of increasing difficulty, including flying through a barn, navigating a canyon, and eventually even landing on a moving train. The player can  also participate in the Stunt Pilot of the Year competition, with improved performance in these stunts resulting in a higher ranking.     From the opening screen, the player, arriving at Stunt Island, can choose to visit five different destinations:   Welcome to Stunt Island!Cabin 273. This is where the player “lives” during their stay at Stunt Island. This includes checking the ledger (showing the player the money received so far for stunts completed), listening to answering machine messages from various NPCs, and looking at daily score standings for the Stunt Competition.    Airfield. Visiting the Airfield allows the player to pick any airplane in the game and fly it freely around the map. The Airfield is also home to the Hall of Fame, a listing of high scores for each stunt.    Production Building. The Production Building is where all stunts are assigned by the Stunt Coordinator or created by the player.    Post-Production Building. All viewing and editing of films happen here in the Theater and Editing Room, respectively.    Ferry Harbor. To leave the game, the player had to visit the Ferry Harbor and choose to leave on the ferry. Quitting the program without leaving by ferry will not save the game’s progress.    To win the Stunt Pilot of the Year contest, 26 of the 32 stunts had to be completed, without going over the limit for takes on each stunt. The player’s reward for winning the contest was to have the airfield named after them.    If a player is not part of the Stunt Pilot of the Year contest, all stunts are open to choose from immediately. However, being a part of the contest limits the number available, and new, more difficult stunts are unlocked upon completion of easier stunts. At any point, though, the player can choose the “Risk” option, which gives the player a difficult stunt that they must complete.    Extra takes or crashes cost the player points and money in the competition standings. Crashes, when not a scripted part of the stunt, will land the player in the hospital, though the hospital visit could be turned off in the game’s preferences. The player can also be fired from a stunt if they’re doing poorly enough.    Gameplay  Inside the cockpit.  Stunt Island houses a relatively deep flight simulator. Each cockpit includes an engine power indicator, horizon gauge, speed indicator, vertical climb indicator, altimeter, clock, and compass, and each plane has its own unique flight envelope. An autopilot feature is  included, but only maintains altitude and heading, rather than completing stunts for the player. A player can also eject and open a parachute, which they can then also control in its decent (crucial for some stunts).  Some aircraft have weapons, including guns, missiles, and bombs.    At any point in free flight, the player can press “R” to record their current gameplay, making it easy to shoot footage without having to set up stunts and cameras ahead of time.   Players can choose not to edit their own films, in which case the game would auto-edit any stunts completed.     Movie Editing, Viewing, and Sharing They love it!  Stunt Island gives the player an unprecedented (at the time) amount of control over the filmmaking process, from set design and multi-camera placement to editing and sound design, introducing many to the idea of Machinima long before it became popular, common, or even technically possible in many other games. Finished films could be viewed in the Movie Theater, full screen.     Stunt Island was released with the MAKEONE tool which allowed the game to generate a self-contained file of any given movie that could be viewed by anyone with the game or even without the game (using the PLAYONE utility). Many films were created and shared this way over Compuserve and between friends.    There is still an active Stunt Island group on Yahoo!     Aircraft     Aircraft   Manufacturer   Take-off speed   Stall speed   Maximum speed   Maximum altitude   Flaps   Retractable landing gear     A-10 Thunderbolt   Grumman Corporation   138 mph   115 mph   439 mph   45,000 feet   Yes   Yes     A-E Intruder   Grumman Corporation   136 mph   113 mph   644 mph   42,000 feet   Yes   Yes     B-2 Stealth Bomber   Northrop   143 mph   117 mph   627 mph   50,290 feet   Yes   Yes     Beechcraft Bonanza V-35   Beech Aircraft Corp.   90 mph   72 mph   209 mph   17,858 feet   Yes   Yes     Boeing 727   Boeing Commercial Airplane Group   150 mph   125 mph   599 mph   45,000 feet   Yes   Yes     Boeing 737   Boeing Commercial Airplane Group   145 mph   125 mph   532 mph   45,000 feet   Yes   Yes     Boeing 747   Boeing Commercial Airplane Group   160 mph   145 mph   602 mph   50,000 feet   Yes   Yes     Bristol Bulldog (MK 11A)   Bristol Aeroplane Co.   65 mph   55 mph   135 mph   25,000 feet   No   No     Cessna Model 172 (Skyhawk)   Cessna Aircraft Co.   55 mph   45 mph   138 mph   12,000 feet   Yes   No     Curtiss JN “Jenny”   Curtiss Aeroplane and Motors Corp.   54 mph   30 mph   75 mph   14,000 feet   No   No     Curtiss June Bug   Curtiss Aeroplane and Motors Corp.   48 mph   25 mph   65 mph   14,000 feet   No   No     Douglas DC-10   Douglas Aircraft Co.   155 mph   130 mph   564 mph   50,000 feet   Yes   Yes     Duck   N/A   Low   Low   Low   Low   No   Yes     E3 AWACS   Boeing Aerospace and Electronics   168 mph   140 mph   530 mph   30,000 feet   Yes   Yes     F-4E Phantom   McDonnell Douglas Corp.   168 mph   140 mph   1,484 mph   62,250 feet   Yes   Yes     F-I 5C Eagle   McDonnell Douglas Corp.   168 mph   130 mph   1,868 mph   60,000 feet   Yes   Yes     F-I 6C Falcon   General Dynamos Corp.   168 mph   130 mph   1,5000 mph   60,000 feet   Yes   Yes     F/A-18A Hornet   McDonnell Douglas Corp.   168 mph   130 mph   1,345 mph   50,000 feet   Yes   Yes     F-88 Sabre   North American Aviation, Inc.   122 mph   110 mph   617 mph   50,800 feet   Yes   Yes     F-I 17A Stealth (Fighter)   Lockheed Corp.   190 mph   158 mph   673 mph   60,000 feet   Yes   Yes     Fokker Dr. 1 (Triplane)   Fokker Fugzeugwerke   60 mph   50 mph   103 mph   20,000 feet   No   No     Hang Glider   N/A   Low   Low   Medium   Low   No   No     Hawk   British Aerospace Ltd. Military Aircraft Division   145 mph   122 mph   621 mph   50,000 feet   Yes   Yes     Junkers Ju 76D Stuka   Junkers Flugzeug Und Motorenwerke   90 mph   75 mph   255 mph   24,000 feet   Yes   Yes     Junkers Ju 88A   Junkers Flugzeug Und Motorenwerke   114 mph   95 mph   295 mph   25,000   Yes   No     Learjet 60    Learjet, Inc.   146 mph   122 mph   548 mph   51,000 feet   Yes   Yes     Lockheed TR-1   Lockheed Corp.   168 mph   140 mph   428 mph   80,000 feet   Yes   Yes     Lockheed U-2 Spy Plane   Lockheed Corp.   168 mph   140 mph   428 mph   80,000 feet   Yes   Yes     Messerschmitt BF 109 G   Messerschmitt Flugzegbau G.M.B.H.   96 mph   80 mph   428 mph   35,000 feet   Yes   Yes     Messerschmitt BF 110   Messerschmitt Flugzegbau G.M.B.H.   105 mph   88 mph   340 mph   35,000 feet   Yes   Yes     MiG-15(UT) Midget   Mikoyan Guryevitch   123 mph   112 mph   668 mph   51,000 feet   Yes   Yes     MiG-25 Foxbat   Mikoyan Guryevitch   162 mph   135 mph   668 mph   75,450 feet   Yes   Yes     MiG-29 Fulcrum   Mikoyan Guryevitch   168 mph   140 mph   1,530 mph   60,700 feet   Yes   Yes     Mirage 2000   Dassault Aviation   138 mph   114 mph   1,645 mph   59,000 feet   Yes   Yes     Mitsubishi A6M Zero-Sen   Mitsubishi Jukogyuo Kabushiki Kaisha   90 mph   75 mph   340 mph   24,000 feet   Yes   Yes     P-51 D Mustang   North American Aviation, Inc.   90 mph   75 mph   445 mph   40,000 feet   Yes   Yes     P-38 Lightning   Lockheed Corp.   90 mph   75 mph   350 mph   40,000 feet   Yes   Yes     Paraglider   N/A   Low   Low   Low   Medium   No   No     Piper Cherokee   Piper Aircraft Corp.   60 mph   47 mph   144 mph   12,000 feet   Yes   Yes     Pitts Special   Christen Industries   65 mph   55 mph   160 mph   14,000 feet   Yes   Yes     Pterodactyl   N/A   Low   Low   Low, but more than the duck   Low   No   No     SR-71A Blackbird   Lockheed Corp.   190 mph   160 mph   2,000 mph   85,000 feet   Yes   Yes     Sopwith Camel   Sopwith Aviation Company   60 mph   50 mph   115 mph   19,000 feet   No   No     Sopwith Triplane   Sopwith Aviation Company   60 mph   50 mph   113 mph   20,500 feet   No   No     Spitfire   Supermarine Viokers-Armstrongs, Ltd.   96 mph   80 mph   416 mph   44,000 feet   No   No     Space Shuttle   *See below   *See below   *See below   *See below   *See below   Yes   Yes     Tupolev Tu-142 Bear   Tupolev Design Bureau   150 mph   125 mph   575 mph   45,900 feet   Yes   Yes       *According to the manual, “Because the Space Shuttle has been specifically tailored for stunt flying, the speed and altitude capabilities have been modified from those of an authentic space shuttle. The Stunt Island space shuttle flight specifications are comparable to those of a very fast aircraft.  Stunts    Stunt Assignment   Description   First take bonus   Crash penalty   Take Penalty   Maximum takes allowed     Scene 1.     Take off and shoot a Zero.   This is the final scene in the World War II epic. Taking off from the   runway in your P-38 Lightning, you need to pull up before you hit the burning   Zero on the runway. Then, without going over 200 feet, you need to shoot down   another Zero that’s bombing the Allies’ hangars. You have a shot limit of 40.   220   180   90   10     Scene 2.     Land on the Golden Gate.   This stunt’s for a drama that takes place in the “City by the Bay.” In a   tense moment, you’re forced to land your Cessna 172 on the Golden Gate Bridge   without hitting any cars. You should be heading north when you perform this   stunt.   150   270   150   4     Scene 3. Barnstorm.   This is a classic barnstormer. You have to guide your Fokker Triplane   through the open doors of a barn. The added challenge is dodging the three   combines passing in front of the barn as you make your entrance. Touching the   ground is out, so don’t think about landing and then driving through.   600   390   240   8     Scene 4.     Pick up a convict on Alcatraz.   This assignment takes you to The Rock. You need to pluck a convict who’s   trying to escape off a tower. The convict is holding a hook that will latch onto the wheels of your Sopwith Camel. Fly   too high and you’ll miss him; fly too low and he’ll be forced to duck, Your   “package” is about 180 feet off the ground. You must execute the pickup at a   minimum of 110 m.p.h.   150   360   210   6     Scene 5.     Catch a balloon.   There’s political trouble afloat in the hot air balloon festival. The red and white balloon is carrying an explosive cargo that is slated to be dropped when it drifts over the governor’s mansion. A   group of hot air balloons loosely dot the sky. Your job is to snag the red   and white balloon with your P-38 Lightning while avoiding all other balloons.   Have any part of your aircraft touch the hot air balloon by the basket only;   if you hit the balloon, it will cause an explosion and end the stunt.   150   210   150   6     Scene 6.     Castlestorm.   In this medieval farce, you’ll start the scene positioned at the backside   of a castle in your hang glider. You need to glide around to the front of the   castle and go in through the castle’s entrance. Once inside, land with your   feet on the catapult. You’re catapulted back out so be sure to hang on tight.   150   300   90   6     Scene 7.     Park at the hamburger stand.   In an incredible lapse of vegetarianism, the lead character gets a   pathological desire for a grilled cheeseburger. As the vexed pilot, you’re   going to land your Piper Cherokee on a quiet country road, taxiing it on the   road until you hit a roadblock of two police cars. Just before you hit the   roadblock, you’re going to make a hard left turn down another road, where   you’ll soon see a parking lot to your left. Pull into the first series of   parking spaces and put the nose of your aircraft in the second row, stall 3   (it doesn’t matter how the aircraft is positioned as long as the nose is in   the right stall). When you park, be sure to put on your brakes or cut your   engine so you’re stopped. Bon appetit.   150   420   270   6     Scene 8.     Shoot planes in formation.   This director loves a tense chase scene. Your allies are being pursued by   the enemy. You need to hit the five enemy planes without striking your two   allies who are in the lead. You’ll be positioned behind all the planes in   your P-51D Mustang when the action starts. There’s a time limit of 3 minutes   or a shot limit of 100, whichever occurs first.   600   390   180   7     Scene 9.    Crash into a 747’s engine.   In this mid-air collision footage, your troubled F4U Corsair is making an   emergency landing at the airport. As you’re coming in, a Boeing 747 is just   taking off. You need to strike the right outermost engine of the 747,   avoiding the rest of the 747. The right wing and engine are specially   reinforced for this stunt, so it’s imperative you hit the 747 in that spot.   450   480   150   9     Scene 10.    Crash into a hotel.   Here’s your first science fiction assignment. You’re going to crash this   specially-made meteor into the hotel that sits at the confluence (or “Y”) of   the river. Because these meteors were expensive and time-consuming to make,   only a few were created. The director and stunt coordinator are counting on   first-take success. If you don’t succeed, you might consider finding a real   meteor to crawl under.   600   1,260   600   3     Scene 11.     Blast a jeep.   This is the scene where the lead character finally tracks down -and   finishes off - his nemesis. In this one-pass stunt, you’ll chase down and   shoot the escaping jeep in your Zero.   600   330   240   6     Scene 12.     Bomber duck.   In this documentary based on the shocking 1992 research revealing the   criminal proclivity of birds, you reenact the events of the famous “Egg   Blotter” incident. As a duck, you’ll fly over the town in search of the   police car containing the officers who supposedly chased off your flock from   the town square’s water fountain. You’ll bomb the police car with your Grade   A Jumbos. The eggs must hit right in front of or directly on the police car   for success.   300   270   330   6     Scene 13.     Land on the blue building.   You’ll wish you had a helicopter for this one. Land your Pitt Special on   the roof of the blue building. You must come to a complete stop without any   part of the plane hanging over the edge of the building.   300   390   180   8     Scene 14.     Save the U.N.   The international establishment known for its attempts to make world peace   is about to have its own shattered unless you succeed in your role. From your   F4U Corsair, you must shoot at and hit the two leading Humvees in the convoy   headed toward the United Nations building. After you’ve struck your targets,   you need to shake off the Zeros by cutting a hard right around the United   Nations building.   450   300   210   10     Scene 15.     Hit the renegade caterer.   The catering truck, having just stripped the gas station of all its   lottery tickets, is racing to get out of town. The hero, who looks forward to   his weekly stab at being a millionaire, grows incensed when he picks up the   crime on his shortwave radio. He heads for the catering truck in his Sopwith   Camel and intends to clip the fleeing truck with his plane (you must hit the   right side of the catering truck). You’ve got to pull off this stunt before   the catering truck passes the Stop ‘N’ Rob and goes out of view.   300   390   180   6     Scene 16.     Fly over a train tunnel.   Here’s one that’ll test your nerves. You need to fly your Sopwith Camel   through a tunnel as a train passes through in the opposite direction. You’ve   got a very narrow flight corridor, but you wouldn’t be assigned this stunt if   it couldn’t be done. Don’t drop below 4 feet, and watch your speed or you may   find yourself exiting the tunnel before the train even gets there - that’s a   “no go”!   410   360   180   6     Scene 17.     Land before the armored truck.   This stunt opens the upcoming film on the autobiography of Tex S. Cooper,   the World War II veteran pilot and volunteer sheriff who would chase down   criminals in his plane. In this re-creation, you’re going to stop the   hijacked armored truck by landing your Pitts Special in front of it without   hitting any other vehicles. You must intercept the armored truck between the   two freeway overpasses.   270   360   270   10     Scene 18.     Fly down an aqueduct.   An aqueduct that runs between the ocean and a dam is flanked   intermittently by towers. The towers will be to the left, to the right, or on   both sides of the aqueduct near overcrossings. Your goal is to fly your Pitts   Special beneath any overcrossings that are flanked by a tower. Here’s the   catch: The crossroads that traverse the aqueduct are each held up by two supports,   dividing the flight space beneath the overcrossing into three parts. You must   fly through the section that the tower is next to. If two towers flank an   overcrossing, you must fly between both supports (basically, through the   center of the aqueduct).   750   450   270   6     Scene 19.     Crash through a billboard.   Zig zag your way through six big rigs and then crash through a billboard   that’s beyond the line of big rigs. You must keep your Piper Cherokee within   20 feet of each truck and fly no higher than 50 feet. Start the stunt by   flying to the right of the trailing truck in the convoy.   370   240   90   7     Scene 20.     Fly inverted past a Jenny.   This movie involves two old fighter pilots with something to prove. In   this particular scene, two Jennys will fly inverted to one another. You’ll   approach the other Jenny from the opposite direction and as you pass each   other, you must be inverted and above the other Jenny at no greater than the   distance of 10 feet.   750   480   360   7     Scene 21.     Land on the goalpost.   The San Jose Silverbacks have just won the Superbowl and in the most   flamboyant exhibition of football fanaticism, the lead character - a diehard   fan with a flair for the outrageous - lands his paraglider right on the   goalpost. Your job is to land right in the center of the goalpost nearest to   you at less than 8 miles per hour. Don’t hit those uprights!   750   180   120   8     Scene 22.     Hit the bullseye with your wing.   In this small town scene, you’re going to approach a tower with a bullseye   at the top. Fly your Jenny inverted and then hit the bullseye with your   reinforced right wing. Your target is about 350 feet off the ground.   750   420   300   5     Scene 23.     Land on a moving train.   The spy, casually dipping into caviar and enjoying the company of a lovely   frauline, thinks he’s safely on his way out of the country. You’re the only   thing that stands between him and even more caviar. In your last chance to   capture him, you must land the Sopwith Triplane on the moving train -   particularly, on the train car that immediately precedes the caboose. The   train will be traveling at 64 m.p.h. and you can’t be traveling at more than   70 m.p.h. when you land on the train car.   900   450   270   8     Scene 24.     Escape from the U.N.   In this role, you’re a terrorist positioned on the roof of the United Nations   building. You need to make a bold escape in a parachute. Jump from the top of   the building and drift down to a boat that awaits you on the river. Don’t   land around the edge of the boat - nail it dead center - and don’t hit it at   more than 16 m.p.h. unless you have a lot of free time to rehabilitate two   broken legs.   750   150   270   6     Scene 25.     Bomb the SAM site.   In this war scene, you’re going to fly over a large “X” on the ground   which will signal the ground-to-air missiles to be launched. You need to   dodge these missiles and head for the SAM radar station. When you’re in   position, you must drop a bomb and take out the radar station. This is a   one-pass stunt.   750   210   70   10     Scene 26.     Land on top of a balloon.   A wedding is taking place in a hot air balloon that the bride’s father is   paying your character to stop. You must land a paraglider on the top of a hot   air balloon, touching down at a maximum of 13 m.p.h. If you touch the hot air   balloon at any point other than at the top, it will cost   you a take.   600   150   300   6     Scene 27.     Recover from a stall.   The pilot starts out the day eating drug-laced pancakes made by a vengeful   roommate. After breakfast, the pilot is out enjoying a leisurely flight when   suddenly the drug takes effect and the pilot becomes severely disoriented. In   this particular scene, the Spitfire will be flying straight up - you’ll have   to recover from the inevitable stall. Hitting the ground is obviously out,   but so is any type of contact with the trees in the forest.   1,050   450   300   4     Scene 28.     Slalom through the towers.   Here’s a chance to show your touch in a Bristol Bulldog. You’re going to   slalom between six towers, staying as close as possible to each. Enter the   slalom to the right of the first tower.   900   1,050   1,200   10     Scene 29.     Fly under two bridges.   No twists or turns to this one. Fly your F16-C Falcon beneath the two   bridges at a speed of no less than 1,000 miles per hour. Hint: Don’t blink.   1,500   2,400   1,500   4     Scene30.     Bomb the three radar sites.   This assignment takes place in the recreation of a busy Middle Eastern   city. Your job is to bomb three rotating enemy radars without hitting any   surrounding civilian structures. You get one pass in your A-6E Intruder.   900   1,050   1,200   6     Scene 31.     Pull out of a dive.   You start this stunt in a Pitts Special that’s pointed straight towards   the earth. You must begin to pull out of the dive at no greater than 400   feet, yet you cannot rise above the altitude of 50 feet once you begin to   pull out. When you’ve pulled out of the dive, head straight and then make a   hard right bank around the United Nations building. Remember, stay below that   50-foot ceiling at all times.   1,130   450   360   8     Scene 32.     Fly between sky scrapers.   This one-plane Russian parade is about to take downtown Duluth by   surprise. Race the MiG-29 Fulcrum down the street that splits the highrises   at a minimum of 1,000 miles per hour. The trick is that you’ll be starting   perpendicular to the “urban canyon” so you’ll have to cut hard to get into   position.   1,500   2,400   1,500   8 Technical Specs  Stunt Island ran on MS-DOS, came on six floppy disks, and required installation. The game was also playable in Windows 3.x and Windows 95. The game's graphics ran at 320x200 resolution with 256 colors.    The game's engine, developed by Disney and The Assembly Line, was very advanced for the time, rendering sometimes hundreds of 3D objects on only a few megabyes of RAM and a 486 processor.  </description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="24">Flight Simulator</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7996">Danger Freak</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/4/43870/1325864-250px_stuntisland_cover.jpg</image></root>