<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11004</id><name>Hitman: Blood Money</name><description>PlotThe majority of the game takes place as flashback sequences that occur through the meeting between a journalist and a former FBI Director, “Jack” Alexander Leland Cayne. The two discuss a number of contract kills over the past two years (2004-2005) and Agent 47's involvement in them. The reporter, Rick Henderson, arranged to interview Cayne in regards to a recent attack on the White House. It quickly becomes clear that Cayne's real intent is to discuss his views on human cloning and his obsession with capturing the genetically engineered super assassin. Cayne lies about many of the details that he gives Rick Henderson such as stating that 47 stole cloning data from Ort-Meyer to sell to the highest bidder.The story of 47 is gradually revealed as the player completes the various contracts they receive. The main story really begins when Diana informs 47 that they are the only two left in the agency. It is implied that the others have been systematically wiped out by Mark Purayah II and Mark Parchezzi III - two of The Franchise's best assassins.Diana finally decides to close down the agency but not before she gives 47 one final contract. This is the mission "A Dance with the Devil", where 47 must infiltrate a party at the CIA headquarters and take out the assassins who are trying to kill him. Once this is complete he and Diana split the funds and go their separate ways.After what seems to be 47's final contract he is approached by an old CIA acquaintance named Smith (who 47 has previously rescued from a rehabilitation clinic in the mission "Flatline"). He requests that 47 take on a mission to kill the men who are trying to assassinate the President of the United States. These men are Vice President Daniel Morris and Mark Parchezzi III, who are both working for Alpha Xerox. This is a political organization which owns "The Franchise" and wish to monopolize the cloning facility that created 47. They want the President taken out before the elections so that he is definitely not elected and so he cannot forward his pro-cloning policy. This would prevent Alpha Xerox from attaining the monopoly on cloning.During this mission 47 successfully kills Morris and also finally takes down Parchezzi in a shootout on the roof of the White House. After this mission a newspaper article is shown which states that the authorities believe Parchezzi to be Morris' assassin. As he is now being hunted by both enemy operatives and the police 47 retreats to his hideout. Here he is approached by Diana without warning which instantly arouses his suspicion as they rarely meet face to face. She proposes a plan which should secure both of them safety from "The Franchise". As 47 is considering the idea and reading the briefing he expresses his doubts about its success. However, before he can say any more Diana injects him with what seems to be a poison. 47's body is quickly surrounded by SWAT members, and Diana, announcing that bringing down 47 was "surprisingly pleasant" is inducted into "The Franchise" by Cayne, it's founder.After this event the plot suddenly returns to present day, with Cayne and Rick Henderson, where 47's body is about to be cremated so that rival cloning companies cannot take a sample of his bone marrow and no more non-defective clones can ever be made. Diana approaches 47's body and places his signature Silverballer pistols on his chest during his funeral and kisses him after applying lipstick. It then becomes clear that the "poison" that Diana used on 47 was actually a fake death serum which is used earlier in the game and that her lipstick contained the antidote. This shows that this was Diana's true plan to save them both and she did not betray 47. The game can then end in one of two ways. As the player watches 47 lying on a pedestal before he is cremated a faint heartbeat can be heard. If the player does not react in any way then 47 will be lowered into the crematorium and will perish. However, if the player keeps spinning both of the analog sticks then 47 will come back to life and the player will have to control him as he takes out all of the witnesses to his revival. Many of the witnesses try to escape but it becomes apparent that Diana has locked the gates of the exit and no one survives except 47 (and Diana, who had left earlier).The game ends with a cut-scene in which Diana states that she has made the Agency operational again using the funds of "The Franchise". She is on the phone with someone who she refers to as "Your Majesty". Diana then says to this mysterious person that the Agency has lost track of 47. The game finally ends with 47 in a brothel having a conversation with a traditionally dressed Chinese man on what can only be assumed is another job.MissionsThe missions during the game are listed below, along with a brief overview of how they are tasked, and the intel that can be purchased in the pre-mission briefing. Typically, the missions occur in order of difficulty though for the inexperienced or violent player, A Vintage Year can pose more problems than some other missions due to the small corridors of the house and the guards who are armed with shotguns and the SAF SMG.The Death of a ShowmanThe Death of a Showman is the tutorial level for Hitman: Blood Money, and is intended to introduce the player to the mechanics of the game, such as poisoning food or water. The mission involves assassinating Joseph Clarence, better known as 'Mr. Swing King', after an accident at his amusement park caused the deaths of several children. One vengeful parent decides that Mr. Swing King should be punished severely. Enemies during the level are gang members, as the amusement park is being used by a 'Mr. Scoop' in order to produce drugs under a supposed agreement that will allow Clarence to restart his amusement park. The Death of a Showman is considered by players as a poor tutorial, as it encourages killing enemies who do not otherwise need to be killed to complete an objective. For example, one of the instructions is to kill two gang members in a room with a shotgun, before hiding the bodies. It would theoretically be possible to continue without having to kill them. The Death of a Showman has no intel, and does not need to be completed for Xbox 360 achievements related to completing the game on different difficulty settings. It is not possible to receive a rating on this level.A Vintage YearA Vintage Year is the first 'true' mission of the game, and places Agent 47 in Chile, during a wine convention held by one Fernando Delgado. His son, Manuel, is using the vineyard as a front for distributing cocaine. Only Fernando was requested for execution by a client, though it is viewed as safer to eliminate Manuel as well, in order to make it appear as a drug-related killing. The mission introduces a camera, used by a Chilean television crew who are present at the event. As usual, Agent 47 should be avoiding the cameras to complete the hits set out. To escape, players depart using a seaplane which has docked at the vineyard.Due to the nature of this mission, it is one of the hardest missions to play aggressively. Guards are armed with the pump-action shotguns, while VIP Guards wield the SAF SMG. Unusually the VIP Guards are less well armed than the standard guards due to the relatively tight confines of the villa, where the shotgun can do the most damage. VIP Guards have access to the villa and drug lab though standard guards do not. A Vintage Year is the first mission where a player can earn the Silent Assassin rating, and also introduces intel you may buy to make your mission easier to complete. The intel is copied directly from the game below.IntelThe guided tour of the wine cellar might prove useful, especially when looking for potential death traps.We've heard that Manuel likes to entertain friends and enjoy the merchandise in the wine cellar.The entrance to the secret lab is hidden somewhere in the wine cellar.The insides are guarded by highly trained guards.Cost is $3,500 eachCost for all Intel = $14,000Grand Total = $14,000Curtains DownTenor Alvaro 'Alvade can be seen in position alongside the executionerCurtains Down opens in the Paris Opera House. Agent 47 has been tasked to assassinate two men: Richard Delahunt, and Alvaro D'Alvade. Richard Delahunt is an American ambassador with a fascination for D'Alvade, who is performing as the tenor in Tosca, which is being performed. Agent 47's chance to strike comes when the tenor faces a firing squad, and strike he does. The two men supposedly run a child trafficking ring in Eastern Europe, and a client has requested their death. Agent 47 is dispatched to make this a reality.It is during Curtains Down that we first see specialized bodyguards protecting Delahunt. It is possible to dress as the executioner and shoot Alvaro yourself, though it is much easier to simply replace the prop Mauser pistol he uses with a real pistol that can be attained through talking with the secretary. It is also possible to take 47's talents onto the stage by dressing as one of the supporting actors, and taking a prop rifle. You may then stand and watch Alvaro's death at the hands of his unwitting killer.It is possible to complete this mission in less than a minute, though with a very low rating. If a player is on a low difficulty, they can shoot their way in to the box where Delahunt watches from, and then shoot Alvaro D'Alvade as he acts his role on the stage. This method ceases to work on higher difficulties, where Agent 47 will be killed before being able to line up a shot with Alvaro on the stage below, or before he can reach the exit again. It is entirely possible to finish the mission in this manner on both Easy and Normal difficulties though is not recommended for Expert or Professional levels for obvious reasons.Completing Curtains Down with a Silent Assassin rating is difficult due to the vigilant guards and long time spent waiting in order to ensure all enemies are in position for you to make your moves. The approach involves replacing the executioner's pistol with a real World War I-era handgun so that he will shoot D'Alvade dead. When Delahunt runs towards the scene he will trip on the carpet, so the chandelier above can be rigged with an RU-AP Mine to eliminate him as an 'accident'.IntelThe content of toolboxes will not be searched when you are frisked.There is a lift shaft from the backstage area to the stage. It is closely observed and only actors are permitted.Lead Actors go to their private rooms to rehearse during breaks.The large chandelier is attached with bolts to the floor of the attic.Only actors are allowed on stage.Light Technicians have key card to Light Control Room.There is a light rack above the stage that might prove useful.The prop gun used for the execution in the opera is an exact replica of a real World War 1 pistol.FlatlineFlatline loading screenAgent Smith has been taken in to solitary confinement in one of the strictest rehab clinics in the world, after attempting to spy on members of a crime family who are present in the facility. Agent 47 has been tasked with helping Smith out of the facility, despite its reputation for not letting patients out unless they are 'sober or dead'.The members of the crime families reside in New York, and become targets due to a shift in the balance of the crime families working in the city. To smuggle Smith out, you will need an experimental serum that will give him the appearance of being dead, without actually killing him. This is because the facility Smith has been checked into is renowned as being the toughest rehab clinic in the United States. Diana Burnwood states that the only way someone will get out is if they are "clean or dead".IntelAdmission papers are required to check-in. Future patients often wait in the park outside.Troublesome patients are often confined to the medical wing.The brochure lists some interesting facilities such as a library, a gymnasium, and a large spa area.Therapists occasionally get contacted for private sessions.Some guests hide stashes of alcohol in quiet places. Let's hope they don't get alcohol poisoning.Weight Lifting can be fatal.Some guests cheat on the spa's strict diet by smuggling camping stoves into their rooms. Sounds dangerous!Deceased patients are taken straight from the medical wing to the morgue.Cost is $3,500 eachCost for all 8 = $28,000Grand Total = $70,000A New LifeVinnie Sinistra is an ex-criminal turned federal snitch. Given a new identity and home by the government, his ex-compatriots want him dead before he gives a court hearing against them. Agent 47 is the go-to guy to making snitches disappear, so Sinistra is no different. He is holding a birthday celebration for his daughter, and this provides an ample time to eliminate him. However, his wife possesses a piece of information that would still be of value regardless of Vinnie's position in the world: on it, or buried in it. It is a piece of microfilm, hidden in her necklace. It is vital that this microfilm is removed from the crime scene, lest the evidence contained be used to convict Sinistra's ex-allies.Despite the birthday party being clearly intended for a young girl (there is a clown as an entertainer), there is no child present in the level due to the media controversy it would cause.IntelGarbage trucks can dispose of all kinds of waste.The surveillance team has an unhealthy appetite for donuts.Vinnie has complained about the neighbor's son taking pot shots into the garden with an airgun.Vinnie lives close to a veterinary surgeon. Sometimes a vet needs to tranquilize wild animals!Rumor has it that Vinnie's wife flirts with hired staff, but Vinnie trusts her company.Some field agents are too nosy in teenage girls' rooms.A barbecue is being prepared for the party. Be careful with flammable liquids!Vinnie just bought a very expensive and unusual necklace for his wife.Cost is $3,500 eachCost for all 8 = $28,000Grand Total = $98,000The Murder of CrowsA US senator is providing a speech during Mardi Gras in the city of New Orleans, Louisiana. Members of the shadowy 'Alpha Xerox' group intend to put a permanent stop to his election campaign, lest he poses a threat to them later in their plans. 47 has been contracted to eliminate all those who intend to cancel the election speech.The key members of the attack, and the guards, are dressed as birds. The 'crows', as the hit-squad are known, communicate via walkie-talkie. Mark II is the mastermind behind the assassination, while Raymond Kulinsky acts as the shooter. Angelina Mason does not provide a major role, unless she discovers Kulinsky's death, in which case she will stab the senator to death, sacrificing herself to complete their mission. It is utterly vital that the politician, and his float, are protected during the celebrations.As a bonus, a case of blood diamonds are changing hands during the festivities, and Agent 47 will be paid extra should he manage to bring them as well. The diamonds are carried by a red bird seen in the hotel at the beginning of the mission, and he will take them across to Mark II by the bookshop. It is possible to intercept him on the way there or walk out, killing Mark II and taking the diamonds as well. Entering the area without the diamonds as the red bird will cause the AI to begin demanding the diamonds on a constant loop, meaning the mission will be virtually impossible to finish.IntelWalkie Talkies transmit everything - even background sound and music, which could reveal someone's location.Clubs usually have a back entrance for the staff.Bookstore walls are like paper - you can overhear what's going on next door.Clubs in this area are known for having hat-dress codes and music themes.Some private apartments have a useful view.Pianos can kill - especially when they are dropped from the sky.A guy dressed as a yellow bird checked into a hotel room a couple of hours ago.Cost is $3,500 eachCost for all 7 = $24,500Grand Total = $122,500You Better Watch Out..Lorne de Havilland is a porn tycoon, who is holding a Christmas party at his reclusive mansion. VIPs have been invited to the proceedings to enjoy a little Christmas gift, and one of the attendees must be eliminated. Lorne de Havilland has footage of Chad Bingham Jr., son of a US senator, getting a little 'rough' with one of Lorne's girls. The girl didn't survive the events that followed, and Lorne intends to use this videotape to bribe the senator. Eliminate Chad to prevent such occurrences in the future, and Lorne to prevent him from going public with the story. The videotape must also disappear.IntelDon't expect any presents this year - Santa drinks too much.The bartender knows how to help improve performance in the grottos!Waiters often shower in the staff changing room.Even small, annoying dogs eat sausages.The glass-bottomed outdoor jacuzzi looks down on the pier, 70 feet below.Among high society, spiked drinks are all the rage.Heavy light rigs are installed in the Photo Studio.Lorne recently hired a former US Air force helicopter Pilot.Cost is $3,500 eachCost for all 8 = $28,000Grand Total = $150,500Death on the MississippiSkip Muldoon operates a paddle ship on the Mississippi river, and he uses it to allow a local gang to move drugs across the river. This gang call themselves the 'Gator Boys', and in return for Skip turning a blind eye to their doings, he receives their protection as guards. There are six key members of the gang, and Skip Muldoon himself. With all of these keys removed, the Gator Boys have no hope of survival. Agent 47 is contracted to collapse the Gator Boys in a single days' work. Skip also possesses some compromising pictures, which must be removed from the crime scene.IntelThe engine room is off limits to passengers - the furnace is a dangerous workplace.Man overboard - the wild waters of the river will cause certain death.The captain's cake is being prepared in the galley in the rear of the 4th deck.Only 1st Class Parsers are allowed in the Gators Private area.The lower class kitchen prepares food for both the tourists on board as well as the Gators on the top deck. Extra flavor could be added.The boss has received some heavy gear from a business alliance. The present is kept secure at the staff quarters.Cost is $3,500 eachCost for all 6 = $21,000Grand Total = $171,500Till Death Do Us PartIt's time to crash a wedding... and what better way to do so than ensure the Groom turns up dead? Agent 47 has been contracted for another mission in Mississippi, this time to eliminate a groom at a wedding, and the bride's father. The bride is strictly off-limits and must not be injured during proceedings. The Groom has something of a sweet-tooth, and frequently samples some of the icing from his wedding cake. This could provide a window of opportunity for a swift elimination.IntelGuns and shooting in outdoor areas don't make rednecks panicThe water is home to alligators.The priest rings the Wedding Bell to announce the ceremony.The Father's recently deceased brother is buried at the family graveyard.The Groom can't keep himself away from the whipped cream on the wedding cake.Cost is $3,500 eachCost for all 5 = $17,500Grand Total = $189,000A House of CardsLas Vegas. Sin City. Agent 47 is on his way to the most morally deprived location in the United States to deal with an Arab Sheikh, and put an end to a deal. The Sheikh is meeting with a white supremacist from South Africa to exchange conflict diamonds for human DNA. An optional objective, that includes additional payment, is to steal the conflict diamonds. It's not like the targets are going to need them.Completing this mission with a Silent Assassin rating can be done by following some online strategies, though it is well known that the AI for the Sheik can bug, leading him to repeat the "This is a very large casino" line of dialogue for an extended period of time.IntelIt would be wise to check in at the hotel reception.Staff have keycards that only provide access to the floors they're guarding.There's an Agency pickup at room #701.Fire alarms are located at the top floors.Room balconies may provide good vantage points.Only waiters are allowed into the VIP room the Sheik has requested.No cell phones allowed in the casino. If someone has to make a call, he must step outside.The items used in the trade are transported in normal-looking briefcases.Cost for each: $3,500Cost for all: $28,000A Dance with the DevilThere are more targets than may initially appear during this mission. To begin with, you are asked to eliminate an FBI agent and his girlfriend, who are attending different parties at the same office block in Las Vegas. Vaana can be found in the Hell party, and Anthony in the Heaven party. Upon assassinating one of the two, other targets will become apparent. A female assassin called Eve, and a male assassin called Maynard John become targets as well. Eve likens herself to a spider, and Maynard John has a passion for the theatrical, referring to Agent 47 as 'less than human'. John challenges Agent 47 to a duel, in the Hell Party. It is a duel Agent 47 cannot afford to lose.IntelTrailers arrived earlier with decorations for the parties.Information about who is trying to kill you might be found on a laptop on the top floor.Don't go for a swim in the shark tanks at the Hell party.Be careful playing with pyrotechnics - they could kill someone.Bartenders are usually well informed.Look out for the singer at the heaven party. Looks can be deceiving.The devil is never to be trusted.There is a food elevator which might be used to transport more than just food.Cost is $3,500 eachCost for all 8 = $28,000-Grand Total = $245,000Amendment XXVAmendment XXV is the closure of the story, with Agent 47 being tasked by Agent Smith with preventing the assassination of the US President. The assassin is 'Mark III': the upgraded, enhanced version of Mark Purayah II. Parchezzi is utterly relentless, but he is only one of the conspirators. The other conspirator is... the Vice President, Daniel Morris. Neither of these men must survive their failed execution attempt.IntelThe guards here will open fire if weapons are detected by the metal detector.Any confiscated weapons at the museum entrance will be stored away by security.The White House is surrounded by an iron gate - which varies in height.Guards will respond if the laser alarm system in the museum is triggered.The 1st lady has a dog, which is regularly taken out for a walk in the backyard.The Oval Office has been the setting for many historical meetings.Carpenters working in the main building have put up scaffolds for renovation purposes.Cost is $3,500 eachCost for all 7 = $24,500Grand Total = $269,500RequiemRequiem is a hidden mission, accessed through pressing buttons during the end credits. Agent 47 will awake from his induced coma, and you are tasked with eliminating all of the witnesses: including Jack Cayne. Requiem is considered as a canon mission, and among those eliminated is Rick Henderson. Diana Burnwood is not present, as it appears she ensured 47 could accomplish this feat, using the serum that was seen during 'Flatline'.GameplayThe gameplay in Blood Money follows the same path as the previous Hitman games in many regards. The basic concept remains the same, you must take out your mark(s) any way you see fit. The way you go about this is entirely up to you and the game this time around gives you even more options then the previous Hitman games to leave your personal touch.One new game mechanic is the ability to use 'environmental' kills, i.e. rigging a bomb to a beam and then waiting for the right moment to remotely detonate it and take out your mark. Another new feature is the ability to customize your weaponry and gadgets. This can consist of larger magazines, red dot and laser sights, better silencers, armour piercing rounds which can go through doors and Kevlar vests, and many more tweaks. Other new abilities 47 has is the ability to take hostages, throw weapons and bombs, and the much welcomed close combat attacks. Nothing feels better than head butting someone and then punching them in the face, or the ability to grab a threats weapon while elbowing them in the face in the process (however you always take the chance that they may pull the trigger, resulting in alerting nearby guards).Go ahead, make my day...Another new addition to gameplay is the concept of witnesses, which are any AI character(s) who witness you do something violent during a mission and survive to talk about it. Witnesses can negatively impact your overall rating at the end of a mission, so in many cases you must be even more careful in Blood Money then in previous Hitman games. However a witness is no longer a threat if they are dead…Which brings us to another new concept in Blood Money, your notoriety level. Your notoriety is dictated by the number of witnesses that are alive at the end of any given mission. Your notoriety will carry through to the next mission you attempt, the higher your notoriety the more likely someone will be able to see through your disguise and identify you as a fugitive. However, one can always opt to decrease their notoriety at the end of each mission, for a price.The newspaper is another new game feature which the player gets to see at the end of each mission, which describes the murder(s) they committed. The newspaper can also offer a deeper back story of the mark(s) you just took out and the articles surrounding the main article are usually an entertaining read as well as hinting at what will happen in later missions.WeaponsBlood Money contains an assortment of upgradeable weapons, which players may choose to bring along when on a contract. To upgrade a weapon, the player needs money, which is attained from successfully completing missions. Each weapon has 5 levels to upgrade, with each level increasingly more expensive.Level 1Level 2Level 3Level 4Level 5$50,000$75,000$100,000$150,000$200,000There are 5 unique upgradeable weapons. To fully upgrade all weapons it would cost $7,075,000. However, you can steal enemy weapons and use those. No collected weapons can be modified though, and the majority of the weapons are not suppressed, making poor choices for use during an assassination, unless compromised.AMT HardballerThe AMT Hardballer is an American-made M1911 clone. The weapon is well known among Hitman fans, as it is Agent 47'sNow imagine this with some of the upgrades below.signature pistol. In most artwork for the games he is brandishing at least one Hardballer, but he is capable of firing two at once. In Blood Money, the Hardballer can be modified and upgraded with different optics and parts, which can be very helpful.In-game the Hardballer is referred to as the Silverballer, and is the signature weapon of Agent 47 in the Hitman franchise. Upgrades make it one of the most versatile weapons in the entire game, and potentially the best all-rounder as well. It can even be used to make shorter range sniper shots, as well as acting as a close range machine pistol depending on how it is configured.LevelUpgradeDescription1Low Velocity AmmoLow Velocity ammo is one of the two initial upgrades available for the AMT Hardballer, and is almost completely essential. Recoil is vastly decreased, and the ammunition can work similarly to a suppressor. When using one, there is no real need for the other, at least until the second suppressor becomes available.Silencer Type 1The silencer is a signature of the professional, and decreases the noise of the weapon when it is being fired. In Hitman: Blood Money the silencer does not seem to impact the power of the weapon, meaning that it is a good choice on all contracts, should a gun be essential to bring.2Extra Ammo'Extra Ammo' is a permanent benefit, and cannot be removed. It does not make a visual change to the weapon, and allows you to carry two additional magazines. The actual quantity of extra ammunition carried changes depending on whether or not Extended Magazines is also used. If not, you will carry 18 additional rounds - two magazines. If it is equipped, you will have 36 rounds, which is still two (larger) magazines.Laser SightThe laser sight is mounted below the barrel of the gun, and allows for more precision when firing. The crosshair is replaced with a red dot emitted from the laser. This can allow for more precise firing, but is more useful when using the first-person camera. It can still be used with third-person, but it does not provide the same benefit.Rail MountThe Rail Mount is required for the Red Dot Sight and Scope, much like the modified handguard for the M4 assault rifle. If you do not purchase this before the optics you wish to own, then you will be prompted to purchase both at the same time.3Magnum AmmoMuch noisier, and with a higher recoil than standard or low velocity ammunition, the Magnum Ammo sounds like a poor choice. However, these two cons are balanced by massive firepower and extreme damage. A single shot to the chest of a victim normally guarantees a kill when using Magnum Ammo.Long SlideLonger slide for the Hardballer. This selection decreases recoil, and increases the accuracy of the shooter. When used with Low Velocity ammunition it is worth considering, at least until the second Silencer is unlocked, whereupon it is normally a better choice.Dual WieldDouble the firepower, double the fun. The second Hardballer gives you more of everything. It is normally a good choice, though when carrying a briefcase or two-handed weapon, you will only draw the one, as opposed to the two weapons.4Red Dot SightA Red Dot Sight is mounted on the slide of the gun, providing a more accurate sight than the Laser Sight which was made available earlier in the game. The RDS is viewed as a scope of sorts, and as such, it has some sway and Agent 47 will hold his breath. It is relatively accurate, but experienced shooters may find it a drawback if they can line up a headshot easily with previous attachments.Large ClipDoubles the size of the magazines used in the weapon, from 9 rounds to 18. Trigger-happy players will love this, but it also serves a useful benefit if compromised. Combined with the second pistol, available as a 'Tier 3' unlock, this makes the ultimate combination for the inaccurate player.5Silencer Type 2Bigger, better, and quieter. The Type 2 Silencer is much quieter than the Type 1, and is a fairly useful piece of equipment in all scenarios. It beats the Type 1 Silencer in all ways, and if a silenced weapon is one of your preferences, then this will improve on the base weapon in many different ways.Full Auto FireFull-Auto modifies the internals of the Silverballer to make it capable of firing fully automatic, as opposed to semi-automatic. Recoil builds more quickly with this customisation, and ammo is drained much faster, but it is potentially extremely useful in areas with a large number of guards present.ScopeA Scope, which will be mounted on the Rail Mount along the slide of the gun. It cannot be used with the Red Dot Sight, but provides more zoom and extreme precision. It does not give the same range as 47's Walther 2000 sniper rifle, but it can still be used for longer-range engagements.SPAS-12A real-world example of a SPAS-12 with pistol gripLike any shotgun, the SPAS-12 (or SP-12, as it is identified in-game) decreases in usefulness across longer ranges. It cannot be concealed either, and is therefore useless in stealthy engagements. It can be suppressed and all other kinds of benefits, but ultimately the usefulness comes down to whether or not players are prepared to find a method of bringing the shotgun in and out.Should the SPAS-12 be brought on a mission it can be advantageous to attempt to find a way of not alerting guards that you have it initially, since sneaking towards the target with it could lead to being able to drop the weapon and escape incognito. If necessary it could also be used to shoot your way back out towards safety.LevelUpgradeDescription1Flechette AmmoFlechette Ammo allows for more accuracy, and less spread. However, the damage is decreased with this. It may still be worthwhile if the shotgun's spread is a problem.Butt StockThe Butt Stock decreases the recoil of the SP-12, and is worthwhile for this reason alone. The SP-12 recoil is managable without it though, so for players who are trying to conserve their cash there is no real need.2Extra AmmoProvides additional ammo.Reload BoostMounts more ammunition on the side of the weapon, ready for when you need it. It divides the reload time by precisely half, making it quite useful in some situations.12 Gauge SlugsThe ultimate slug for causing damage to a target, but with absolutely no precision at all. Think Rambo... and then a little less accurate. Still, if you want to guarantee it's dead, accept nothing else.3Rail MountThe Rail Mount is a necessity for the Red Dot Sight to be mountable on the gun. It is not worth buying unless you intend to mount the Red Dot Sight on the SP-12, as otherwise it has no benefit.Short BarrelThe shortened barrel makes a brutal increase in damage a reality, but as you'd expect, it comes at the cost of accuracy. Experienced shotgun users likely will not have a problem with this, but ultimately the appeal of the shortened barrel is limited.4Laser SightProvides a laser pointer for additional accuracy, and increased likelihood of hitting the target. Due to the fact that the shotgun is a close range weapon, a laser sight is not entirely necessary, but it might be worthwhile nonetheless.MagazineImproves the SP-12's rate of fire considerably, making it into a semi-automatic shotgun as compared to a pump-action. Plus, it increases the reload speed vastly. If you use the shotgun frequently, this is a very useful purchase to get the most from it.5Red Dot SightImproves accuracy when being used, but it is ultimately not a massive help on a shotgun. Some players may prefer using the shotgun with this attachment, but it does not give a drastic improvement in accuracy unless you use the first-person view when shooting.Silencer Type 1The only silencer available for the SP-12, it has the exact same properties as the silencers for other weapons: it decreases the noise of the weapon as it is fired. This is an essential to anyone who intends to replay missions with a shotgun, due to the fact that the weapon makes a very easily-identified blast.SMG TacticalThe SMG Tactical appears to be based on Heckler  Koch's MP5 and MP5k designs, and is heavily customisable. Initially it is a small weapon, let down by its similarly small magazine size. However, upgrades can make the SMG Tactical a viable weapon choice, particularly due to the fact that it is concealable and can be smuggled into different locations rifles and shotguns could not.LevelUpgradeDescription1Butt Stock 1 or 2Less recoil, more precision. The differences are cosmetic: The first one is a fixed, synthetic, MP5A2-style buttstock, while the other one is a metal MP5A3-style buttstock of the retractable kind.Low Velocity AmmoActs in the same manner as the Low Velocity ammunition for the AMT Hardballer. It is quite useful with the SMG Tactical as well, due to the fact that it decreases recoil, and due to the weapon's unlock tree, a silencer does not become available for quite some time.2Extra AmmoProvides an extra two magazines of ammunition to bring to the party. It does not make a cosmetic change and cannot be disabled, but it is definitely worthwhile.Rail MountThe Rail Mount is needed to place the Red Dot Sight on the SMG Tactical. Without the Rail Mount the RDS cannot be purchased and mounted on the weapon, so it is definitely a worthwhile purchase for this reason. It doesn't need to be purchased unless you intend to use the Red Dot Sight though, as it provides no other benefits.Magnum AmmoMagnum Ammo is louder and has more recoil than standard or low velocity ammunition, but it shreds a target apart with ease. It also rips through doors, so if you're not concerned with stealth, why not leave a 'lasting impression' upon your target? With massive power, a shot or two in the chest area will almost always yield results.3Rapid FireA massively increased rate of fire, which is very useful with the smaller frame and shorter barrel. It is less accurate, and recoil will build more quickly, but this is really only an attachment for closer range engagements.Short BarrelA shortened barrel for the SMG Tactical, which helps to look a lot like the MP5k. It decreases the weapon's accuracy though, but ultimately it does work well with equipment such as the increased rate of fire.Silencer Type 1Like all suppressors for weapons, the silencer for the SMG Tactical allows you to fire without immediately alerting everyone to your presence. It has limited usefulness when combined with the Low Velocity Ammunition, however.4Laser SightThe Laser Sight fits a laser pointer onto the SMG Tactical, and allows for increased accuracy. The crosshair is replaced with the pinpoint red dot emitted from the laser sight, but it does not have a major benefit unless you are using the first-person viewpoint for shooting accurately.Double ClipHaving a second magazine nearby will always speed up reloading, and this attachment is always valuable for frequent reloaders. Having a second magazine attached to the first one means that you can simply move from one magazine to the other, and save vital seconds. It is particularly useful when involved in firefights, as reloading is normally the moment when you will be destroyed by enemy fire.5Silencer Type 2Decreases firing noise even further than Silencer Type 1.Red Dot SightA small amount of zoom and improved accuracy; provides you with a red dot.M4The M4 is an American-made killing machine, and appears to be the only assault rifle employed by the Agency. It is quite possibly one of the best weapons in the game, but is let down by the fact it is not concealable. When fully upgraded, the M4 is comparable to a light machine gun, and has the firepower to put down many, many targets.LevelUpgradeDescription1R.I.S. HandguardLike the Rail Mount, this is a prerequisite for a later upgrade.Low Velocity AmmoDecreases firing noise and lessens recoil.Butt StockLess recoil, more precise.2Extra AmmoTwo additional magazines.Laser SightProvides you with laser to show where your bullet will go.Rail MountAs for other weapons, this is a prerequisite for scopes, doing nothing on its own.Armor Piercing AmmoIt does more damage and can penetrate doors.3Silencer Type 1Greatly decreases firing noise.Pistol GripReduces recoil and increases precision slightly.4Double ClipTwo magazines clipped together, making reloading considerably faster.Red Dot SightA small amount of zoom and improved accuracy; provides you with a red dot.5Silencer Type 2Decreases firing noise even further than Silencer Type 1.Drum Magazine100 rounds per drum, increases recoil.Scope Type 1Scope that can zoom more than the Red Dot Sight and considerably better aiming accuracy.Walther 2000The only sniper rifle that can be customised in the game, the WA2000 (or W2000, as it is identified as in-game), is Agent 47's preferred long-range rifle. It can be customised to a huge degree, and many of the customisations are worthwhile for different engagements. Due to the fact it is a sniper rifle it makes a typically loud noise when fired, so players who will be sniping their targets frequently are advised to invest in a silencer for their rifle.LevelUpgradeDescription1Low Velocity AmmoDecreases firing noise and lessens recoil.Double Capacity ClipDoubles the amount of bullets in each clip.2Extra AmmoAn extra magazine.Scope Type 1Scope that can zoom more than the stock scope and considerably better aiming accuracy.Lightweight FrameImproves overall handling, it makes the rifle more precise and stable.3Silencer Type 1Greatly decreases firing noise.Armor Piercing AmmoIt does more damage and can penetrate doors.4Extra AmmoTwo extra magazines.Carbon-Fiber BarrelLess recoil, more precision.Bolt ActionIncreases precision significantly..5Silencer Type 2Decreases firing noise even further than Silencer Type 1.Scope Type 2Maximum zoom.Melee WeaponsMelee Weapons can be found in different missions, or as part of Agent 47's standard equipment. They cannot be taken out of the level, and cannot be collected. They are useful in some situations, but generally out of them all, those which do not spill blood are superior. Knives are also useful due to the fact they are lethal when thrown, but have the downside of spilling a target's blood, which could help security find the bodies.WeaponDescriptionLocationBaseball BatMedium damage. Cannot be concealed.Garage in “A New Life”. Wall in “Death of a Showman”.Cane SwordMedium damage. Cannot be concealed.On Vaana Ketlyn's corpse in “A Dance with the Devil”.Fibre WireEffective, can be concealed, not detected by metal detectors. Can only be used from behind.Already possessed.Fire ExtinguisherCannot be concealed.Outside office in “Death of a Showman”. In drug lab in “A Vintage Year”.HammerMedium damage. Can be concealed.In Joseph Clarence’s office in “Death of a Showman”. Various locations in “A Vintage Year”. On builders in “Curtains Down”. In a crypt in “Requiem”.Hedge CuttersLarge Damage. Cannot be concealed.On the gardener in “A New Life”. In a crypt in “Requiem”.Kitchen KnifeEffective weapon. Can be thrown.In kitchens and on chefs. In a crypt in “Requiem”. Can also be found in the door of a wardrobe during 'Death of a Showman'.Meat CleaverOperates similarly to the Kitchen Knife, and can be thrown as well. It has a different execution animation when used from behind an unaware target.Top floor kitchen in “A Dance with the Devil”.ScrewdriverEffective, concealable.On the light technician in “Curtains Down”. In a crypt in “Requiem”.ShovelEffective, with decent power. It cannot be concealed, limiting its usefulness.In the engine room in “Death on the Mississippi”. In the family graves in “Till Death Do Us Part”. In a crypt in “Requiem”.StilettoA small knife with a thin blade. It is commonly used as a throwing knife, and is employed in the exact same manner as the Meat Cleaver and Kitchen Knife.On Eve in “A Dance with the Devil”. On a guard in “Requiem”.Stun GunKnocks enemies unconscious.On the orderly’s in “Flat Line”Controversy50Hz DisplaysWhen the game was released on the Xbox 360, Eidos released it in a manner where it could not be played on 50Hz televisions. As the game is an earlier 360 title, many players did not realise this, and had not upgraded their sets to either HDTVs or televisions which could support the game. When attempting to play Blood Money on a 50Hz television, it will simply show a black screen.Advertising ControversyHitman: Blood Money had been described in the past as being 'the most violent game in the series, but ironically the game itself was not the source of complaints and controversy. The advertising for the game was much more controversial, and some of those who witnessed the adverts complained to advertising standards agencies. There were at least four ads for the game, and these ads featured slightly different taglines. The most controversial advert read 'Beautifully Executed', and featured a woman lying on a bed, apparently asleep. However, there was a bullet hole in her forehead, suggesting that it might be a very long sleep.HD Re-ReleaseHitman: Bloody Money was re-released with high definition visuals as part of Hitman: HD Trilogy on January 29, 2013. It was also made available as a standalone 4.54 GB download on the PlayStation Network for $16.99.Xbox 360 Game InstallationHitman: Blood Money (the original, non-HD version) requires 5.8GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD.System RequirementsMinimumMicrosoft Windows® 2000/XP/7 (Windows 95/98/ME/NT Not Supported)Pentium 4 1.5Ghz or Athlon XP Equivalent512MB RAM100% DirectX 9.0c compatible video card which supports Hardware TnL and Pixel Shader 2.0 (GeForce FX / Radeon 9500 or higher)100% DirectX 9.0c Compatible Sound Card5.0GB free disk space100% Windows 2000/XP compatible Mouse and Keyboard (Gamepads and controller are not supported)RecommendedPentium 4 2.4Ghz or Athlon XP/64-bit equivalent1024MB RAMATI X800 series, Nvidia GeForce 6800 series or higher video card100% DirectX 9.0c Compatible Sound Card, Sound Blaster X-Fi series5.0GB free disk space</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21331">Tenchu Z</game><game id="2335">Thief: Deadly Shadows</game><game id="4523">Thief: The Dark Project</game><game id="19998">Tenchu: Dark Secret</game><game id="7787">Thief II: The Metal Age</game><game id="20669">Metal Gear Solid 4: Guns of the Patriots</game><game id="15549">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Pandora Tomorrow</game><game id="15282">Tenchu: Fatal Shadows</game><game id="12354">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Chaos Theory</game><game id="457">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Double Agent</game><game id="21654">Metal Gear Solid 2: Substance</game><game id="22928">Assassin's Creed II</game><game id="5961">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell</game><game id="7539">Tenchu: Wrath of Heaven</game><game id="16004">Tenchu: Stealth Assassins</game><game id="24617">Tenchu: Shadow Assassins</game><game id="15737">Tenchu 2: Birth of the Stealth Assassins</game><game id="2077">The Mark of Kri</game><game id="21258">Manhunt 2</game><game id="16093">Death to Spies</game><game id="20464">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Conviction</game><game id="5704">Shadow of Rome</game><game id="35850">Dishonored</game><game id="37494">Assassin's Creed III</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1891348-box_hitmanbm.png</image></root>