<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1102</id><name>Civilization II: Test of Time</name><description>  Overview Civilization II: Test of Time is a turn based strategy game, released in 1999,  in which you must advance your civilization to conquer the world. There are four ways in which this can be achieved, through a high level of culture or religion, through technological advance or through wiping out the other players.  GameplayIn the custom game you may choose the size of map, land mass, land form (Archipelago, Varied, Continents), climate (Arid, normal, wet), temperature (cool, temperate, warm) and the age of the world (3billion, 4billion, 5billion). There are then six difficulty settings; Chieftain (easiest), Warlord, Prince, King, Emperor, Deity (toughest) to choose. You can pick the number of opponents, from 3 to 7 and the level of barbarian activity (Villages, Roaming Bands, Restless Tribes, Raging Hoards). You may then choose your gender and race. You may then select the style of your cities and, if you opted to, the race of your opponents.  RacesRomans - Irrigation, Mining  Roads.Babylonians Germans Egyptions Americans GreeksIndians - Irrigation, Mining, Bronze Working, Ceremonial Burial  Roads.Russians Zulus French Aztecs Chinese English Mongals Celts Japanese Vikings Spanish Persions Carthaginions Sioux  Game typesOriginal Science Fictiuon Fantasy Multiplayer ModeThere are a number of ways to host the multiplayer mode; a hotseat,  via dial-up networking (two-player) or an internet or network game.  Hotseat Mode In this mode up to 7 human players take it in turns at a PC to advance their civ's. You can choose the type of game, the amount of time for each players turn and customize the world and your race.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14391">Heroes of Might and Magic: A Strategic Quest</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/15/155745/2167541-civilization2_test_of_time.jpg</image></root>