<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11021</id><name>Cloning Clyde</name><description>OverviewThe game was released on the Xbox Live Marketplace on July 19, 2006 for 800 Microsoft Points and released on Steam on March 15, 2011. On May 24, 2010, the game was designated an Arcade Hit and its price dropped to 400 Microsoft Points.PlotClyde is offered 20 dollars to enter a cloning experiment as the test subject. The experiment goes wrong, and Clyde and his Killer Kenn action figures are cloned multiple times. In the lab are portals Clyde can use to enter in order to save his clones, gather his Killer Kenn action figures and hopefully collect his 20 dollars.GameplayOne of many levels found in the gameThe player controls Clyde as he ventures through 35 side-scrolling levels. Clyde can jump, attack and mutate into other shapes using objects in the environment with cloning machines. Only one Clyde can exit a level, but clones can be evacuated using vents. The player can switch control between clones, and thus take on puzzles requiring more than one clone. Levers, drains and moving platforms need to be used in order to finish a level. Clones can be found scattered across a level, but can also be found by opening cages or cloning Clyde using cloning machines. Camera robots are the main enemies of the game, with Clyde having to destroy each one in order to exit the level, but flesh-eating plants and mines are also present in the game. Clyde re-spawns nearby upon death.There are over 240 cloned Clydes and 156 Killer Kenns to save or collect.Cheats can be used to give Clyde different skins or proportions.MultiplayerThere are online leaderboards and also there is a Versus Mode that is available over Split-Screen or Xbox Live. Two teams go against each other and try to destroy the other team's camera robots first.Clyde MutationsAn important aspect of the game is mutation. Animals and objects can be placed with Clyde on a special cloning machine that combines the DNA of both, giving Clyde special abilities.Ape-ClydeBy combining his DNA with an ape, Clyde can climb the ceiling using the pipes that extend out of it.Chicken-ClydeClyde can combine his DNA with a chicken, granting him the ability to fly.Frog-ClydeCombining Clyde with a frog lets him jump higher and breathe under water.Dynamite-ClydeAn explosive barrel can be combined with Clyde, giving him the ability to explode without harm to himself.Rock-ClydeRock-Clyde is the result of Clyde combining himself with a rock, thus giving him the ability to slam the ground and withstand suction from drains.Sheep-ClydeAlthough sheep can be ridden, combining Clyde with a sheep grants Clyde faster speeds and higher jumping.Mutant-ClydeClyde's ultimate form, Mutant-Clyde, is available from the Cheat screen after completing the game and gives Clyde abilities from every other mutated form except for Rock-Clyde.Clyde OutfitsThere are also a number of outfits that Clyde can switch into at any time in the game, these however unlike the mutations do not add any gameplay advantages and are unlocked as you progress through the game.Outfit ClydeBig HeadLab RatFrankenMiniRobotGiantGiantPrincessDevilCowboySantaMartianPC System RequirementsOS: Windows 98 or higherProcessor: 2.0Ghz or higherMemory: 512 MBGraphics: Shader version 2.0 or higher (does not support Intel integrated graphics card)DirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 133MB</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5429">The Lost Vikings</game><game id="12321">Krusty's Fun House</game><game id="1446">Lemmings</game><game id="25714">Explodemon!</game><game id="26041">Alfred Chicken</game><game id="14216">Castlevania: Symphony of the Night</game><game id="29103">Ancients of Ooga</game><game id="35148">Tommy Tronic</game><game id="26355">'Splosion Man</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1841433-box_cclyde.png</image></root>