<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11069</id><name>Jurassic Park: Operation Genesis</name><description>Welcome to Jurassic ParkAs John Hammond welcomed his guests to Jurassic Park to see amazing living, breathing dinosaurs, Blue Tongue Entertainment invites gamers a in the same way to Jurassic Park: Operation Genesis to build their own parks with their own living, breathing dinosaurs. This is a Park Building simulation game where your goal is to create dinosaurs for all to see and to prevent disasters from occurring to the parks inhabitants, both human and dinosaurs alike, and to prove to INGEN (The company responsible for funding the park) and the World that Jurassic Park can be a success.The player takes control of all operations: building the park, looking after the environment, cloning the dinosaurs and most important of all, entertaining and protecting the visitors. Your not alone in building and running the park as you have the help of various staff who will guide you and help you with decisions.Operation GenesisThe ultimate goal of the game is to make a five-star theme park which will have visitors streaming in to see the amazing dinosaurs and to leave feeling that their curiosity about dinosaurs is satisfied. There are many different types of visitors who require safety, thrills, food and even the bathroom. Your job is to manage the park wisely and maintain guest satisfaction. You start the game off by developing the type of island you want, with options to customize the rivers, mountains and trees to your satisfaction. After this quick selection of a personalized island, you then build the park with paths, fences, attractions, amenities and, ultimately, dinosaurs.DinosaursWould you hop into that jeep?You're able to clone various Dino's of various levels from docile to dangerous. Carnivores can be dangerous, so be careful when putting multiple dinosaurs in the same pen. They are the primary attraction and central to the park being a success or flop. You also must look after their welfare making sure they don't contract diseases, die from starvation or escape their confines. Using your ranger helicopter, you can shoot the dino's with tranquilizers or lethal shots if they get out of hand. Using the helecopter you can also rescue any unfortunate humans who may fall into a compound and carry dinosaurs to other parts of the island is necessary.Since the Dinosaurs are clones they have much shorter lifespans and are more susceptible to disease than other creatures. Researching immunizations, maxing out the genetic sequence of each dinosaur and making sure they are treated when sick will ensure your dinosaurs live for a longer period of time.Dinosaur SpeciesSpinosaurus and Tyrannosaurus fighting.DryosaurusGallimimusHomalocephaleKentrosaurusPachycephalosaurusStyracosaurusAnkylosaurusBrachiosaurusCamarasaurusCorythosaurusEdmontosaurusOuranosaurusParasaurolophusStegosaurusTorosaurusTriceratopsAlbertosaurusCeratosaurusDilophosaurusVelociraptorAcrocanthosaurusAllosaurusCarcharodontosaurusSpinosaurusTyrannosaurusAll of the dinosaurs are rated on a scale from 1 to 5 stars in popularity. A boring Dryosaurus rates only 1 star, while Brachiosaurus and Spinosaurus rate 5 stars. Parasaurolophus, Albertosaurus, and the like rate in between the two. In addition, certain activities dinosaurs partake in, whether it be fighting, drinking, defecating, etc., attract or appall certain visitors. The visitor types are the following: Mainstream, Dino Nerd, Fun Lover, Thrill Seeker. Each type have specific interests and demands.Both the Original Xbox and PS2 versions of Jurassic Park: Operation Genesis do not feature any multiplayer, online gameplay or downloadable content. The original Xbox game requires a download to be playable on the Xbox 360.PC System Requirements:Playing Jurassic Park Operation Genesis on PC requires a Minimum of:Pentium 2 -400MHz.128mb RAM.659mb Hard Drive Space.16mb 3D Accelerator Graphics.Windows XP, ME, 98, 95.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="8">Educational</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18743">Dinopark Tycoon</game><game id="7434">Universal Studios Theme Park Adventure</game><game id="9677">Zoo Tycoon</game><game id="23431">Zoo Tycoon 2: Extinct Animals</game><game id="4680">Zoo Tycoon 2</game><game id="16654">Zoo Tycoon 2: African Adventure</game><game id="14988">Zoo Tycoon 2: Zookeeper Collection</game><game id="18121">Zoo Tycoon 2: Marine Mania</game><game id="9578">Zoo Tycoon 2: Endangered Species</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2285666-box_jpog.png</image></root>