<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11082</id><name>Guild Wars: Nightfall</name><description>LocationGuild Wars: Nightfall takes place on the continent of Elona, adding a descent into the Realm of Torments towards the end of the plot. Information on core Guild Wars gameplay and character classes can be found here.PvP Game Types:Hero Battles (HB):The only form of 1v1 PvP combat available in Guild Wars, Hero Battles allow players to face off with their choice of 3 NPC heroes. The goal is simply to reach 20 points before your opponent does. Points are awarded either for killing your opponents or for capturing and holding the Shrines spread around the map. Winning matches rewards players with points towards their Commander title.(NOTE: As of the October 2009 updates, HB was retired along with Team Arenas (TA) and replaced with Codex Arena.Character ClassesIn addition to the six core classes, Nightfall players also have access to two entirely new ones.ParagonThe Paragon classThe Paragon is a natural born leader who uses chants to aid his allies and defeat opponents and throwing spears to attack the enemy. Paragons can attack at half the range of Rangers and casters, allowing it to both attack the enemy and support its team with its shouts and chants while avoiding melee damage at the same time. Despite having a low energy recovery, Paragons can use a large quantity of shouts and chants due to its primary attribute. The Paragon works equally well as a support character or attacker, and has an armor bonus rivaling that of the Warrior's. Also similar to a Warrior, many of its attack skills in Spear Mastery use adrenaline, which charges as damage is done or received. All of these factors come together to make a solid class that can play a variety of roles on any team.AttributesLeadership (Primary) - increases energy gained whenever a shout or chant endsSpear Mastery - increases damage with spears and chance of critical hitsCommand - increases effectiveness of Command skills (mainly shouts and chants that buff the party)Motivation - increases effectiveness of Motivation skills (mainly shouts and chants that heal the party or remove conditions)Energy: 30Energy Recovery: 2Armor: 80Armor Bonus: 10 EnergyDervishThe Dervish classThe Dervish is a scythe wielding class that can use earth and wind prayers in addition to its scythe to damage opponents. The Dervish also has the unique ability to take on God forms which give very effective bonuses such as not being affected by conditions or losing a hex every time it uses a skill, and it also uses its primary attribute Mysticism to cast and maintain a large amount of enchantments on itself. The Dervish's scythe has the best single hit damage in the game, often being able to hit for a quarter or even a third of the enemy's health in one hit, which lethally pairs with its ability to inflict deep wound, removing an additional 20% of their enemy's total health. The scythe can also hit all the targets in its sweep radius, making the Dervish a solid PvE class as well. Dervishes also have access to fairly formidable healing spells, so its dual role as a powerful melee attacker and a healer makes Dervishes effective and versatile units to have on your team.AttributesMysticism (Primary) - increases health and energy gain whenever an enchantment endsScythe Mastery - increases damage with scythe and chance of critical hitsEarth Prayers - increases effectiveness of Earth Prayers skills (mainly defensive enchantments)Wind Prayers - increases effectiveness of Wind Prayers skills (mainly offensive enchantments)Energy: 25Energy Recovery: 4Armor: 70Armor Bonus: 25 Health, 5 EnergySkillsIn addition a new storyline and 2 new classes, Nightfall offers around 250 new skills. That is:75 skills for each of the new professions, The Dervish and The Paragon25 skills for the other professions, including the 6 original professions and the Assassin and Ritualist from the Factions campaignSome Temporary Mission Based skills, and Title Based skillsArmor  WeaponsWith the Nightfall campaign, Many armor types are unlocked. There are Several for each Profession, but they all have the same basic styles:AncientIstaniSunspearElite SunspearPrimevalVabbianMany weapons are also unlocked, mostly dropped from "Bosses" and offered referred to as Green weapons due their Unique status.Title TracksNightfall also introduced two sets of title tracks and the reward of skills as you progressed through them. The tracks are Sunspear and Lightbringer, and point are awarded for them by completing themed quests or defeating enemies in certain areas after acquiring the bounty for them.Bounty is earned after talking to the keepers at each respawn shrine and grant rewards for killing certain enemy types - for example, a Sunspear bounty might be for killing skale, or corsairs, or bugs. Lightbringer bounties are reserved for servants of the dark, like djinn, margonites and creatures of torment.Advancing in the ranks of either title track will unlock certain abilities and skills. The Sunspear track is limited to a handful of skills, but Lightbringer bonuses are constant, and grant you increased damage and damage-resistance to torment creatures - the Lightbringer skills are also focused in that area and cause holy damage or increased protection from margonites and Torment creatures.The concept of skills for title tracks was carried several steps further in Guild Wars: Eye of the North, with the Deldrimor, Asuri, Human, and Norn title tracks and their corresponding class-specific rewards.SoundtrackThe music from Guild Wars Nightfall was composed by Jeremy Soule.The Guild Wars: Nightfall Soundtrack1. Land of the Golden Sun 2:132. Guardian Sunspears 3:173. Lost Dynasties 3:534. The Grand Cataract 1:025. Gathering Storm (Extended) 3:096. Festival of Lyss 3:207. Desert Dwellers 1:028. March of the Margonites 1:189. Fortress of Jahai 2:0010. Pride of the Centaurs 1:0011. Haunted Ruins 2:2012. Turai's Legacy 3:1013. Dining in the Great Hall (Bonus) 0:4714. Elona's New Hope (Bonus) 0:5015. Path to War 1:1816. Tortured Souls 3:1417. Sunspear Assault 1:2018. Garden of Seborhin 4:1719. On Harpie's Wings 1:0320. The Forgotten God 2:2021. Corsair Armada 1:0422. Black Sails at Dawn 2:1623. Theme for Varesh (Bonus) 1:5824. Sulfurous Wastes 2:1625. The Garrison 1:0926. Web of Terror 3:5327. Invasion of Vabbi 1:1028. Resplendent Makuun 3:0929. Kormir's Theme 2:1930. Kournan Caravan 2:1631. Into the Breach 1:1732. Distant Battle 1:0733. The Makers' Song 2:1234. Desperate Flight 1:0435. Unseen Intruders 0:5436. Abaddon's Gift 1:1037. The Barricades 1:1538. The Five True Gods 1:0839. Trailer - Cries of Elona (Bonus) 2:1740. Trailer - Sunspears Attack! (Bonus) 2:1841. Alternate Theme (Bonus) 1:29System RequirementsMinimumMicrosoft Windows XP/2000/ME/98Intel Pentium III 1 GHz or equivalent512 MB RAMCD-ROM Drive3 GB Available HDD SpaceATI Radeon 8500 or NVIDIA GeForce 3 Series video card with 64 MB of VRAM16-bit Sound CardInternet ConnectionKeyboard and mouseDirectX 8RecommendedMicrosoft Windows XP/2000Intel Pentium 4 2.0 GHz or equivalent1 GB RAMCD-ROM Drive4 GB Available HDD SpaceATI Radeon 9600 or NVIDIA GeForce FX 5700 series video card or above16-bit Sound CardInternet ConnectionKeyboard and mouseDirectX 9</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21223">Guild Wars 2</game><game id="9641">Age of Conan: Hyborian Adventures</game><game id="18603">World of Warcraft: The Burning Crusade</game><game id="5767">Ultima Online</game><game id="9989">Hellgate: London</game><game id="22063">Perfect World</game><game id="22997">The Lord of the Rings Online: Mines of Moria</game><game id="23411">Runescape Classic</game><game id="9705">Lineage II: The Chaotic Chronicle</game><game id="23193">Perfect World International</game><game id="6204">EverQuest: The Shadows of Luclin</game><game id="545">Asheron's Call</game><game id="29355">Tera</game><game id="26847">Final Fantasy XIV Online: A Realm Reborn</game><game id="27896">World of Warcraft: Cataclysm</game><game id="34791">Avatar Adventurers Online</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2531062-box_gwnf.png</image></root>