<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11103</id><name>Mega Man ZX</name><description>ZX takes place at about 200 years after the end of the  Zero series. This game contains elements from the  Mega man X series and the Mega Man Zero series. Players take contol of either  Vent or  Aile, and can select a mission at a computer out of a list . The player has free exploration of the game world during and between missions, and they must find the specified area themselves. The player may also find computer chips to complete the game database, and Life Ups, which can be compared to the Heart Tanks from the Mega Man X series. Players also collect "Biometals" from the game's bosses that allows the player character to transform and gain various armors that have different abilities.  The Biometals are designed to resemble characters from Mega Man Zero.  Bosses all have their own individual weak points where the Biometal they're using is stored; hitting it deals more damage than normal, but it also decreases your ranking level at the end of the battle (ranging from one being the worst and four being the best). This also determines the level of the Biometal which they receive afterwards. But even if the level is low, the Biometals can be upgraded with Energy Crystals later. Bosses will eventually be resurrected and can be fought again, to increase the level of the Biometal. Biometals Model X Model Z Model ZX Model H Model F Model L   Model S Model O (hidden)ExtrasIf you start the game with a  Mega Man Zero 3 or  Mega Man Zero 4   cartridge inserted in the GBA slot, boss enemies from the Mega Man Zero series will appear at a certain point in the game....</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10347">Yoshi's Island DS</game><game id="20627">Castlevania: Order of Ecclesia</game><game id="13197">Castlevania: Circle of the Moon</game><game id="11321">Castlevania: Dawn of Sorrow</game><game id="12036">Castlevania: Aria of Sorrow</game><game id="23282">Henry Hatsworth in the Puzzling Adventure</game><game id="9882">Super Princess Peach</game><game id="36680">Cave Story 3D</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1806116-box_mmzx.png</image></root>