<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11124</id><name>Carmageddon TDR 2000</name><description>OverviewCarmageddon TDR 2000 is the sequel to the controversial vehicular combat game Carmageddon 2, developed by Torus Games and released in 2000. Much of the controversy surrounding this game and the series as a whole is derived from one of the three objectives the player is able to complete in order to progress through the game. That objective is to kill all of the pedestrians on the map.GameplayThe basic gameplay in Carmageddon TDR 2000 consists of three major objectives. Each objective will result in completing the map.List of Carmageddon TDR 2000 Objectives:Waste all opposing vehicles.Kill all of the pedestrians on the map.Complete the race.Carmageddon 2 is known to have one the first (if not the first) realistic damage physics on its vehicle models and Carmageddon TDR 2000 continues this tradition. As a result , a vehicle that is being destroyed will have damage on its model. The vehicular destruction in this game is vast and therefore you may see your car being split in half one time and at another time being crushed.Most of the maps in Carmageddon TDR 2000 feature well over 200 pedestrians and every impact is fills the screen with blood and gore.Whenever a pedestrian is killed you gain a certain amount of credits. The amount of credits gained depends on the brutality of the kill. In addition to killing pedestrians the player can also gain credits by destroying the opposing vehicles and or reaching checkpoints/completing laps. These credits can be used to purchase new vehicles and or upgrades such as Power, Defense, and Offense.After the player completes two or three races in the area they must complete a mission based map where the objectives range from collecting various items to destroying specific structures. Each mission has different objectives which are specific to the area therefore the mission based maps never contain the exact same objectives as the others. After these missions are accomplished the player unlocks a new area with new race tracks and cars to destroy.CarsOriginalNamePhotoDriverInformationThe Beast"The Beast is a Torture Machine!"Gimi CarnageTop speed 273 MPHKerb weight 1.7 tons0-60 MPH 3.8 secondsCost $320,000Big Wig"Size does matter"Kenn WorstTop speed 152 MPHKerb weight 14.0 tons0-60 MPH 6.9 secondsCost $1,420,000The Boss"If its on the road, Eat it"Mustang SmellyTop speed 250 MPHKerb weight 1.7 tons0-60 MPH 2.1 secondsCost $665,000Bumble Bee"Come see what I got under my bonnet"Ma DonnaTop speed 160 MPHKerb weight 2.2 tons0-60 MPH 4.5 secondsCost $325,000The Chef"A fat man needs two fat ladies to spread his love"Eddie GourmetTop speed 230 MPHKerb weight 1.3 tons0-60 MPH 2.4 secondsCost $1,650,000Copcar"Go ahead, make my day"CopsTop speed 170 MPHKerb weight 1.8 tons0-60 MPH 4.2 secondsCost $765,000The Cutter"We will rule the Wasteland"HumungassassTop speed 180 MPHKerb weight 3.4 tons0-60 MPH 6.9 secondsCost $500,000Da Panzer"Tanked up and ready to blow"Rommel WarTop speed 161 MPHKerb weight 26.0 tons0-60 MPH 8.6 secondsCost $1,880,000Drag-Ghoul"R.I.P. Rithe in pain"Bel LaGhostlyTop speed 253 MPHKerb weight 1.3 tons0-60 MPH 3.2 secondsCost $150,000Eagle MK4"The Eagle's back and it rocks"Max DamageOpponent number 8Short name MaxTop speed 186 mphKerb weight 1.5 tons0 - 60 mph in 3.4 secondsCost N/AElectric Blue"It’s not the volts! It’s the Amps"Crank ZapperTop speed 250 MPHKerb weight 1.1 tons0-60 MPH 2.5 secondsCost $1,200,000Enforcer"I bring law to the lawless"Officer GooseTop speed 230 MPHKerb weight 1.8 tons0-60 MPH 4.2 secondsCost $200,000Femme Fatal"I’ll show you, Boys Toys"Veronica VixenTop speed 220 MPHKerb weight 1.6 tons0-60 MPH 4.4 secondsCost $670,000The Fortress"She's FORT KNOX on wheels"Alotta SlaughterTop speed 200 MPHKerb weight 5.2 tons0-60 MPH 8.4 secondsCost $930,000Gorvette"Where there’s a kill, there’s a way"Gore UsomeTop speed 283 MPHKerb weight 1.6 tons0-60 MPH 1.8 secondsCost $1,250,000The Green Hammer"I am the hammer, you are the anvil"Thor IronhammerTop speed 230 MPHKerb weight 1.6 tons0-60 MPH 4.8 secondsCost $420,000HFB Terra"This baby plays classic hits"Wayne KerrTop speed 187 MPHKerb weight 1.8 tons0-60 MPH 6.2 secondsCost $335,000Husky"Ask for flaring, ya get flares"Abe LTop speed 294 MPHKerb weight 2.2 tons0-60 MPH 5.2 secondsCost $930,000Jadead"Behold my Wonders"Jay DeadTop speed 203 MPHKerb weight 1.3 tons0-60 MPH 3.0 secondsCost $1,360,000Killa Kart"When I yell 4, better get off the road!"Iron TigerTop speed 245 MPHKerb weight 1.0 tons0-60 MPH 4.1 secondsCost $87,000King Merc"Havoc in the name of the Fatherland"Hans Kristoff HavocsteinTop speed 128 MPHKerb weight 2.9 tons0-60 MPH 7.6 secondsCost ?Knave"Thou dost quiver at my sight"Sir David HavahockTop speed 206 MPHKerb weight 0.9 tons0-60 MPH 4.8 secondsCost $450,000Limey"Heads or Tails baby!!"Uther HurtOpponent number 45Short name U. HurtTop speed 210 mphKerb weight 1.5 tons0 - 60 mph in 2.8 secondsCost 650,000The Machine"I am Man and Machine"TetsuoTop speed 170 MPHKerb weight 2.1 tons0-60 MPH 4.4 secondsCost $390,000Master Mine"I'm haulin' ass!"Doug AholTop speed 77 MPHKerb weight 47.0 tons0-60 MPH 15.6 secondsCost ?McKilem"My Mac is eeeeeevil"WiseguyTop speed 235 MPHKerb weight 1.2 tons0-60 MPH 2.3 secondsCost $1,850,000The Mecha"Domo origato! Watashi wa...DANGEROUS"Bonsai LunTop speed 173 MPHKerb weight 0.8 tons0-60 MPH 12.8 secondsCost $80,000Rubber Ducky"Who dropped the soap?!"Ernie DuckTop speed 216 MPHKerb weight 1.0 tons0-60 MPH 3.7 secondsCost $95,000Shark"Eat you!"Jaws VerneTop speed 360 MPHKerb weight 0.6 tons0-60 MPH 1.5 secondsCost $828,000Soul Harvester"I’m gonna give ya a Kainin"Samson KaineTop speed 85 MPHKerb weight 3.9 tons0-60 MPH 13.4 secondsCost $110,000Sparrow"Let the Deathbird fly"Maya De'AthTop speed 229 MPHKerb weight 1.6 tons0-60 MPH 4.4 secondsCost $265,000The Spectre"Pace GHOOOOST"Pacey GowstTop speed 216 MPHKerb weight 1.2 tons0-60 MPH 3.6 secondsCost $78,000Stormbringer"I am the hammer of the gods"Lightning LarryTop speed 360 MPHKerb weight 1.3 tons0-60 MPH 1.2 secondsCost $665,000SuperCharger"I'll kick box those poofs, mate"Guido KiksassTop speed 208 MPHKerb weight 1.8 tons0-60 MPH 4.3 secondsCost $315,000Suppressor"Resistance is useless"CopsTop speed 229 MPHKerb weight 4.7 tons0-60 MPH 4.8 secondsCost $1,250,000SXE Black Hatch"Nitrous fumes burning my brain!"Maxx RazorTop speed 252 MPHKerb weight 1.8 tons0-60 MPH 4.2 secondsCost $600,000Throb Rod"I ride her hard"Philippe A. ShioTop speed 235 MPHKerb weight 1.2 tons0-60 MPH3.1 secondsCost $675,000Thummper"Ya, das is goot auto"Major PayneTop speed 156 MPHKerb weight 2.5 tons0-60 MPH 5.4 secondsCost ?TNT"Light the fuse  Booooom!"Han GrenadeTop speed 247 MPHKerb weight 1.7 tons0-60 MPH 5.0 secondsCost $350,000Tomahawk"My beast run on fire water"PsychohontasTop speed 230 MPHKerb weight 1.3 tons0-60 MPH 4.8 secondsCost $142,000Tow MeisterHugh JorgenTop speed 127 MPHKerb weight 2.9 tons0-60 MPH 7.5 secondsCost ? CreditsTres Hombres"She got legs... and she gonna lose them..."Billy, Bob, Billy-BobTop speed 186 MPHKerb weight 2.3 tons0-60 MPH 5.5 secondsCost $250,000Viper"Let me show you 'my' SNAKE"Jake ViperTop speed 253 MPHKerb weight 1.8 tons0-60 MPH 4.8 secondsCost $305,000Vlad"Nitro-Maniac"VladTop speed 360 MPHKerb weight 1.4 tons0-60 MPH 1.0 secondsCost $1,495,000The Vulture"I'm never more dangerous than when you're dead"Cameron CarrionTop speed 201 MPHKerb weight 1.6 tons0-60 MPH 3.4 secondsCost $829,000White Trash"When there's garbage on the road, I clean up"Syn BinTop speed 163 MPHKerb weight 6.8 tons0-60 MPH 10.3 secondsCost $780,000Witch Doctor"Do not doubt the power of Voodoo, Mun!"Doctor MamboTop speed 175 MPHKerb weight 2.5 tons0-60 MPH 5.8 secondsCost $385,000The Wheel"It's man's first invention! Why complicate things"Mono MassacreTop speed VariesKerb weight 0.5 tons0-60 MPH 12.8 secondsCost $150,000Wraith"Silent but deadly"Orlando GassimTop speed UnknownKerb weight Unknown0-60 MPH UnknownThe Nosebleed PackColumn HeadColumn HeadColumn HeadBigdaddyTop speed 200 MPHKerb weight 1.3 tons0-60 MPH 5.5 secondsBlood  BonesTop speed 250 MPHKerb weight 1.3 tons0-60 MPH 3.4 secondsBuggyTop speed 200 MPHKerb weight 1.3 tons0-60 MPH 5.5 secondsJawsTop speed 250 MPHKerb weight 3.5 tons0-60 MPH 3.4 secondsLuciferTop speed 250 MPHKerb weight 1.5 tons0-60 MPH 3.4 secondsPed BasherTop speed 200 MPHKerb weight 1.3 tons0-60 MPH 5.5 secondsThe Pigs!Top speed 120 MPHKerb weight 2 tons0-60 MPH 10.5 secondsPogoTop speed 180 MPHKerb weight 1.0 tons0-60 MPH 4.8 secondsSports SedanTop speed 290 MPHKerb weight 1.3 tons0-60 MPH 3.4 secondsSteam MachineTop speed 250 MPHKerb weight 4.0 tons0-60 MPH 6.2 secondsMusicCarmageddon TDR 2000 contains music from the "Utah Saints" and "Plague". These bands are nowhere near as well known as the band Iron Maiden featured in Carmageddon 2. The lack of well known bands may have been a result of lower production values.Track List:1. Data Track2. Plague - Carma (3.38)3. Plague - Eat It Up (3.57)4. Plague - Dedicated to Hate (3.26)5. Utah Saints - Techknowledgy (5.26)6. Utah Saints - Sick (5.18)7. Utah Saints - Hands Up (4.02)Carmageddon ComicWhile Carmageddon TDR 2000 was being developed an online comic was created based on the series.Part of the Carmageddon comic.PC RequirementsWindows 95/98/Me/XP (Home Edition);Pentium 266 (Min.), Pentium 300 (Rec.);8x CD-ROM drive;32 MB RAM (Min.), 64 MB (Rec.);8 MB DirectX 7 compatible graphics card;DirectX 7 compatible sound card;410 MB hard drive space (Min.).</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6426">Twisted Metal: Black</game><game id="16436">Twisted Metal 2</game><game id="13200">Vigilante 8</game><game id="7468">Vigilante 8: 2nd Offense</game><game id="9017">Mad Max</game><game id="23527">Hardware 2</game><game id="16728">Powerslide</game><game id="25512">Clutch</game><game id="31863">Carmageddon 64</game><game id="4543">Quarantine II: Road Warrior</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2593/1022350-tdrbox.jpg</image></root>