<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11126</id><name>Galerians</name><description>OverviewGalerians was released on the PlayStation by Polygon Magic, in Japan in 1999 and in the West in 2000. Galerians is considered a survival horror game with a psychic dark setting. You play Rion a boy who discovers he has pyschic powers but suffers from constant amnesia. Through the game he tries to remember who he is and by doing so finds out he is the last hope for Galerians.StoryRion SteinerYou play as a Protagonist called Rion who finds himself in hospital with no memory, with psychic powers. Using these powers he tries to escape from hospital but hears a young girls voice calling him. So he decides to find this girl and find out what his real identity is. Through the hospital he finds rooms where experiments are done to him and other people as well. After escaping from the hospital he tries to make his way home. by using his powers he learns that his parents were killed by other people with psychic powers and learns one of the doctors created an A.I. computer called Dorothy. Dorothy who can control itself without any help decides to do things differently against the orders of the doctors and declares in creating a super human race called the galerians. In order to save humanity Rion and the young girl must go and face Dorothy to save all of human life.GameplayBeing a survival horror game it has the Resident Evil style control and feeling in the game. Using items such as drugs and finding clues using your psychic power you work your way through the game meeting enemies and new characters. In the hud there are 3 bars which represent HP (Health), AP ( Stress meter, if this meter becomes full by being attacked Rion will lose control of his abilities and start killing non enemies. If this is not treated with a drug he will begin to short and eventually be killed) and drug meter ( which shows which drug you are using and how much of it is left).CharactersRion Steiner - A 14 year old boy who finds himself in a hospital, with no memory of how he got there and who he is.Lilia Pascalle - Her and Rion are childhood friends and she is the daughter of Dr Pascalle. She gained her telepathic powers after both Rions father and her own injected a virus program into her brain.Dr Lem - In charge of the hospital and the man who experimented on Rion.Birdman - Another galerian who has the powers of teleportation. He is looking for Lilia under the command of the super computer Dorothy.Rainheart - A galerian with a split personalty. This 15 year old who acts like a child is the most destructive galerian as his split personalty is both of a simple child and a killer.Rita - Another member of the galerians, she has the powers of psychokinesis.Cain - The last galerian and who looks like Rion.</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="718">Galerians: Ash</game><game id="9228">Parasite Eve</game><game id="7360">Fear Effect</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2193293-box_galerians.png</image></root>