<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1113</id><name>Gumshoe</name><description>Overview Gumshoe was created by Nintendo artist and game designer Yoshio  Sakamoto and was only released in the US. In an interview he did with  Wired.com he spoke about how he was asked by Gunpei Yokoi to make a game that would utilize the zapper peripheral as the sole controller for a game. His prototype of the game was a rolling ball that you shot to make it bounce. After realizing the lack of entertainment with such a basic mechanic the idea of obstacles and targets came into play. Sakamoto also admits that the main character, Mr Stevenson, was drawn to resemble Mr Yokoi.  StoryA mafia boss named King Dom kidnapped Mr. Stevenson's daughter. Mr. Stevenson must collect five black panther diamonds to save his daughter.  Mr Stevenson is an ex-FBI agent turned detective. Gameplay Gumshoe is an Auto-Scrolling, platformer game that is entirely controlled by the NES Zapper. You control Mr Stevenson by shooting him with the zapper making him jump to avoid enemies and obstacles such as pits and platforms. You can also use the zapper to shoot enemies, though you have limited ammo. There are several red ballons floating around in levels that if you shoot them they replenish some of your ammo. No ammo is actually lost when controlling Stevenson.</description><genres><genre id="35">Light-Gun Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17486">Mad Dog McCree</game><game id="15365">Time Crisis 2</game><game id="6490">Hogan's Alley</game><game id="19246">Vampire Night</game><game id="14088">Operation Thunderbolt</game><game id="14869">Operation Wolf</game><game id="16218">Battle Clash</game><game id="16148">To the Earth</game><game id="12102">Baby Boomer</game><game id="8177">Barker Bill's Trick Shooting</game><game id="4116">Wild Gunman</game><game id="2758">Duck Hunt</game><game id="5967">Chiller</game><game id="3484">Metal Combat: Falcon's Revenge</game><game id="17980">Gotcha! The Sport!</game><game id="29088">Shooting Range</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2361788-nes_gumshoe.jpg</image></root>