<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11300</id><name>RollerCoaster Tycoon: Corkscrew Follies</name><description>OverviewOn top of all of the other content from the original RollerCoaster Tycoon, the Corkscrew Follies (known as Added Attractions in Europe) expansion pack adds a plethora of new attractions and scenery, as well as 30 new scenarios. GameplayScenariosMuch like its predecessor, players unlock a new scenario upon completing another.ScenarioObjectiveDescriptionWhispering Cliffs$17,000 park value by October 31, Year 3Develop the seaside cliffs into a thriving amusement park.Three Monkeys Park1,400 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3Central to this large developing theme park is a giant triple-track racing/dueling steel coaster.Canary Mines1,300 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3This abandoned mine already has mrakings of a tourist attraction with its miniature railway and a pair of vertical drop coasters.Barony Bridge1,200 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3An old redundant bridge is yours to develop into an amusement park.Funtopia1,400 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3Covering land both sides of a highway, this park has several rides already operating.Haunted Harbour1,200 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3The local authority has agreed to sell nearby land cheaply to this small seaside park, on the condition that certain rides are preserved.Fun Fortress1,300 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3This castle is all yours to turn into a theme park.Future World1,500 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3This futuristic park has plenty of space for new rides on its alien landscape.Gentle Glen1,200 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3The local population prefer gentle and relaxing rides, so it is your job to expand this park to suit their tastes.Jolly Jungle1,600 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 4Deep in the jungle lies a large area of land ready to be turned into a theme park.Hydro Hills$20,000 park value by October 31, Year 3A series of stepped lakes form the basis for this new park.Sprightly Park1,500 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3This elderly park has many historical rides but is badly in debt.Magic Quarters$30,000 park value by October 31, Year 4A large area of land has been cleared and partially themed ready for you to develop into a landscape theme park.Fruit Farm1,100 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 2A thriving fruit farm built a railroad to boost its income, your job is to develop it into a full-blown amusement park.Butterfly Dam1,400 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3The area around a dam is available for you to develop into an amusement park.Coaster Canyon1,200 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3A vast canyon is yours to turn into a theme park.Thunderstorm Park1,400 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3The weater is so wet here that a giant pyramid has been built to allow some rides to be built under cover.Harmonic Hills1,200 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3The local authority won't allow you to built above tree height in this park.Roman Village1,500 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3Develop this Roman-themed park by adding rides and roller coasters.Swamp Cove1,600 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3Built partly on a series of small islands, this park already has a pair of large roller coasters as its centerpiece.Adrenaline Heights1,600 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3Build a park to appeal to the high-intensity thrill-seeking local people.Utopia Park1,400 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3An oasis in the middle of the desert provides an unusual opportunity to build an amusement park.Rotting Heights1,200 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3Overgrown and dilapidated, can you ressurect this once-great amusement park?Fiasco Forest900 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 1Full of badly designed and dangerous rides, you have a very limited budget and time to fix the problems and turn the park around.Pickle Park1,400 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3The local authority will not allow any kind of advertising or promotion, so this park must succeed by reputation only.Giggle Downs1,250 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 2A four lane steeplechase ride is the centerpiece of this expanding park.Mineral Park$10,000 park value by October 31, Year 2Turn this abandoned stone quarry into a place to attract thrill-seeking tourists.Coaster CrazyBuild 10 different roller coasters with an excitement rating of 6.00You have limited funds but unlimited time to turnt his mountside area into a vast roller coaster park.Urban Park1,000 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3A tiny park has done a deal with the nearby town to allow expansion through the town itself.Geoffrey Gardens2,000 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 4A large garden needs turning into a thriving theme park. Downloadable ScenariosFollowing the release of Corkscrew Follies, two extra scenarios were made available for download from the Atari website. Alton Towers was also later released with RollerCoaster Tycoon's second expansion, Loopy Landscapes.ScenarioObjectiveDescriptionAlton Towers2,500 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3Based on the real park in Alton, Staffordshire, England, it is your job to expand its ride selection and attract more guests.Fort Anachronism1,250 guests, 600 park rating by October 31, Year 3The park has a landmark - a fort in the center. Build the park into a thriving theme park. Other AdditionsNew challenges await in Corkscrew FolliesThe core gameplay remains largely the same in this expansion, although a few minor changes were implemented, such as the ability to change the color of the balloons and umbrellas sold at individual stalls, the addition of gradual turns on track rides (which allow rides to run diagonally on the isometric grid), and the addition of pathway banner signs, which can be used as decoration or as "No Entry" notices to prevent guests from entering certain parts of the park. Attraction ListsCorkscrew Follies adds the following attractions on top of what the original RollerCoaster Tycoon offers. Gentle RidesRideDescriptionCircus ShowShow takes place inside a circus-style big top tent.Crooked HouseWooden building with crooked rooms designed to disorient people walking through it.Cycle MonorailThe powered cars run on steel track, and are controlled by the pedaling of the riders.Cycle RailwayTrack consists of steel rails for supporting and guiding the bicycles.Ghost TrainTrack has a central guide rail, and can be constructed above ground or underground to create an enclosed ride. Cars are powered, and follow the guide rail along the track.Flying SaucersAir is kept under pressure beneath the floor, entering the flying saucer cars through valves in the floor. The cars then float on the cushion of air this creates.Miniature GolfA gentle game of miniature golf. Roller CoastersRideDescriptionFlying Roller CoasterTrack has a tubular steel spine, connected to the outside edges of tubular steel running rails. Supports are large tubular steel posts. Trains are held on the track by wheels below and inside the running rails.Heartline Twister Roller CoasterTrack consists of tubular steel running rails running through circular steel hoops. Cars run centrally between the rails, allowing heartline twists.Steel Twister Roller CoasterTrack has a tubular steel spine, connected to the inside edges of tubular steel running rails. Supports are large tubular steel posts. Trains are held on the track by wheels above, below, and outside the running rails.Steel Wild Mouse Roller CoasterTrack consists of tubular steel rails. Supports are large tubular steel posts. Cars are held on the track by wheels above, below, and outside the running rails.Virginia ReelTrack is flat-bottomed wooden trough. The cars are guided along the track by the sides of the trough, spinning as they touch the sides.Wooden Reverser Roller CoasterTrack is laminated wood topped with a flat steel running rail, constructed on a wooden support structure. Cars run on bogies guided along the track by side-friction wheels running inside wooden guide rails. Special sections of track are used to turn the car around, allowing it to run backwards.Wooden Side-Friction Roller CoasterTrack is laminated wood, topped with a flat steel running rail, constructed on a wooden support structure. Trains are guided along the track by side-friction wheels running inside wooden guide rails.Wooden Twister Roller CoasterTrack is laminated wood, topped with a flat steel running rail, constructed on a wooden support structure. Trains are held on the track by up-stop wheels, which run under the inside edge of the rails. Thrill RidesRideDescriptionRoto-DropThe ring of seats is pulled up to the top of the tower while gently rotating, then allowed to free-fall down, stopping gently at the bottom using magnetic brakes. Transport RidesRideDescriptionSuspended MonorailTrack is a box-section steel rail suspended by steel support legs. Trains are powered and hang underneath the rail. Water RidesRideDescriptionRiver RideWater channel is supported by steel lattice supports. The large-capacity flat-bottomed boats are propelled up slopes on a conveyor belt, and are guided along the water channel by guide wheels under the hull. Note: Known as Splash Boats in the European versions. Shops/StallsShop/StallDescriptionCandy Apple StallSells candy apples.Exotic Seafood StallSells fried tentacles.Hat StallSells hats that guests will wear in the park. Player can designate the color of hat sold at each individual stall.Hot Dog StallSells hot dogs. Scenery ListCorkscrew Follies also adds the following scenery on top of what the original RollerCoaster Tycoon offers.Category/ThemeDescriptionGardensA garden clock is added to this original RollerCoaster Tycoon category.Abstract ThemingAbstract-themed decor.Jungle ThemingJungle-themed decor.Jurassic ThemingDinosaur-themed decor.Spooky ThemingHorror-themed decor. System RequirementsMinimumPentium 90 MHzWindows 95/9816 MB RAM50 MB hard drive space4x CD-ROM1 MB SVGA video cardWindows 95/98 compatible sound cardDirectX 5.0 (included)MouseRecommendedPentium 200Windows 9532 MB RAM180 MB hard drive space8x CD-ROM4 MB SVGA video cardWindows 95/98 compatible sound cardDirectX 5.0 (included)MouseKeyboard</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="33263">Hyper Rails</game><game id="1153">NoLimits Roller Coaster Simulation</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/46/1212494-corkscrewfollies.jpg</image></root>