<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11334</id><name>Blood Will Tell: Tezuka Osamu's Dororo</name><description>OverviewBlood Will Tell focuses on the adventures of one Hyakkimaru and his sidekick Dororo. After Hyakkimaru's father makes a bad deal with the Fiends, these devils come up to his son after he is born and steal 48 of his body parts. The father is crippled by fear upon learning this truth, and sends Hyakkimaru off into the wild on his own by laying him in a basket and letting the current of a nearby river take him.Hyakkimaru is saved by a talented doctor, who replaces his lost organs, arms, legs and so on with synthetic counterparts that did not only enable him to survive, but also made him a bit of a supersoldier as he grew up. After Hyakkimaru becomes of age, he takes these toys, such as a knee-mounted bazooka, to the fiends in order to regain that which they have taken of him. He is quickly joined by the self-proclaimed "greatest thief of all time", a youngster named Dororo. Together, they face many a foe and rescue feudal Japan from the Fiends' oppression.List of FiendsNote: interpretation help: "Name of the fiend - Body part gained from killing the fiend (Effect of reacquisition of body part) - Level of the fiend at hand"Note 2: the phrase "Make(s) Hyakkimaru stronger" indicates that he will receive a stat boost. For instance, he will get HP 1.Prologue FiendsGreat Horn - Vocal cord (Allows Hyakkimaru to use his natural voice, as opposed to the robotic voice he had before) - Level 1Homunculus - Left eye (Allows Hyakkimaru to see the world in colour) - Level 2Chapter 1 FiendsDream Eater - Hyppocampal synapse (Enables the "Enemies Killed" stat to become operational) - Level 4Scourge - No body part obtained - Level 3Inquisitor - Trapezius muscles (Make Hyakkimaru stronger) - Level 6Hell Crusher - Esophagus (No bonus) - Level 4Ogress - Left leg (Gives you the ability to dash by pushing down L3) - Level 6Grave Golem - Platelets (Make Hyakkimaru stronger) - Level 5Mai Mai Onba - Vissudha (Makes Hyakkimaru stronger) - Level 44Chapter 2 FiendsMasterless Samurai - No body part obtained - Level 6Possessed Dororo - No body part obtained - Level 8Giant Fire Wheel - Kidneys (Make Hyakkimaru stronger) - Level 10Dragon Brood - Spine (Makes Hyakkimaru stronger) - Level 10Impaler - Manipura (Makes Hyakkimaru stronger) - Level 9Night Terror - Cerebellum (Makes Hyakkimaru stronger) - Level 12Fiend Misaki - Right leg (Enables use of a bazooka with 10 shots that can blast rocks that impede your progress through bonus areas) - Level 35Draconus - Liver (Makes Hyakkimaru stronger) - Level 41Chapter 3 FiendsGoliath - Adrenal glands (Make Hyakkimaru stronger) - Level 12Twin Blade - Ears (Allow you to recover from a fall in mid-air and land on your feet) - Level 11Fire Golem - Stomach (Makes Hyakkimaru stronger) - Level 12Gapping Maw - Small Intestines (Make Hyakkimaru stronger) - Level 23Mountainous - Sense of pain (The controller will vibrate when you take damage) - Level 14Wind Fiend - Abdominal muscles (Make Hyakkimaru stronger) - Level 19Chapter 4 FiendsThree Tailed Fox - Lymph nodes (No bonus) - Level 15Beast Fiend - Cerebral neocortex (Makes Hyakkimaru stronger) - Level 17Six Tailed Fox - Pancreas (Makes Hyakkimaru stronger) - Level 16Snake-eyes Saboruta - No body parts obtained - Level 18Tahoumaru - No body parts obtained - Level 18Nice Tailed Fox - The heart (Makes Hyakkimaru stronger) - Level 24Death - Thyroid glands (Make Hyakkimaru stronger) - Level 21Hell Cat - Muladhara (Makes Hyakkimaru stronger) - Level 20Blood Ape - Ribs (Make Hyakkimaru stronger) - Level 27Chapter 5 FiendsGiant Inferno Wheel - Bone marrow (Makes Hyakkimaru stronger) - Level 29Misaki - No body part obtained - Level 1Redcap - Left arm (Allows you to dual-wield swords) - Level 27Thunder Fiend - Lateral muscles (Make Hyakkimaru stronger) - Level 25Minotaur - Pelvis (Makes Hyakkimaru stronger) - Level 46Legion - Nose (Makes the controller vibrate when enemies are nearby, as Hyakkimaru can smell them now) - Level 26Soul Stealer - Large intestines (Make Hyakkimaru stronger) - Level 31Chapter 6 FiendsPossessed Misaki - No body part obtained - Level 28Cursed Monk - Ajna (Makes Hyakkimaru stronger) - Level 45Midoro - Right eye (Makes Hyakkimaru stronger) - Level 33Boar Fiend - Pectoralis muscles (Make Hyakkimaru stronger) - Level 33Other InformationBlood Will Tell features two-player co-op that sees one player taking control of Hyakkimaru and the other of his partner, Dororo. The action takes place on a single screen, and players can only stray a certain distance from one another. It is viewed by most as clumsy.Although Dororo is referred to as male, hints in the unfinished Dororo manga make it fairly clear that the character is actually a girl disguised as a male. This is nodded to in the Blood Will Tell game, where Dororo is visibly a little girl, and voiced by a female voice actor making little effort to sound male.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3757">Dynasty Warriors 5</game><game id="8898">Genji: Dawn of the Samurai</game><game id="19861">Onimusha 2: Samurai's Destiny</game><game id="9088">Onimusha: Warlords</game><game id="5704">Shadow of Rome</game><game id="10990">Genma Onimusha</game><game id="2838">Bujingai: The Forsaken City</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2375780-box_bwt.png</image></root>