<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11350</id><name>Zone of the Enders</name><description>PlotIn the remote reaches of the solar system in the 22nd century, there is a colony on Jupiter called "Antilia". In a sudden outbreak of war a shy youth named Leo Stenbuck loses his friends right before his eyes. Thoughts of "if they just weren't around I wouldn't be picked on anymore" had crossed through his mind just moments before his friends were killed. Blaming himself for not being able to save them, he panicked and ran away from the scene of the attack inadvertently stumbling onto the cause of the war, orbital frame " Jehuty," a colossal war machine with a human form that holds the key to civilization's existence.Move ListDash AttackWhen the enemy is in close range the dash attack is a high powered sword attack, however when your enemy is in long range you fire a barrage of lasers.Burst AttackThe Burst attack gathers a massive ball of energy that us used to attack hardened targets and larger enemies.Grab and ThrowThe grab and throw is exactly what it sounds like you grab an enemy or object in the environment and throw it.EscapeIf a battle becomes to overwhelming it is possible to escape and then reengage when you are more prepared for battle.Metal Gear Solid 2 DemoThe likely reason many sought out Zone of the Enders was not for its action-packed gameplay and interesting story, but for its packed in Metal Gear Solid 2: Sons of Liberty demo which included much of the first level in the game (the Tanker Mission.)Zone of the Enders Original SoundtrackThere are 29 tracks on the CD. The music featured on the CD is of the Electronica and Japanese Pop genre. The CD released on April 25, 2001, and it is produced by Konami Music Entertainment.Track ListingZone of the Enders Soundtrack Cover1. Title (The Origin)2. Introduction3. Leo Stenbuck (Break Out)4. Factory (Vivid Transparency)5. VR (The Fourth Dimension)6. Flowing Destiny (Piano Arrange)7. Global 1 (Forever and Ever)8. Are You Alright, Celvice?9. Boss (Neves)10. Celvice! This Way, Quickly!11. Residential Block (S02)12. A Light with a Name of HOPE (Piano Arrange)13. Radar (Pandemonium)14. Global 2 (Virus)15. City (The Earth Light)16. Mountain (Who Can Read the Future?)17. Rock Thunderheart (Function)18. A Light with a Name of HOPE (Protect Me)19. You Need This Done to You20. Flowing Destiny (Resolution)21. Ada (Promise)22. Flowing Destiny (Memories)23. Neith (Risky)24. Viola (Silent Death)25. Anubis (Impossible)26. Jehuty Will Self-Destruct?27. Flowing Destiny - Ending Theme28. Kiss Me Sunlights - Opening Theme29. A Light with a Name of HOPE - Ending Theme 2/Celvice's Theme</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17059">MechAssault: Phantom War</game><game id="17438">MechAssault</game><game id="17861">MechAssault 2: LoneWolf</game><game id="4819">Cyber Troopers Virtual-On: Oratorio Tangram</game><game id="17675">Armored Core 4</game><game id="2506">Armored Fist 2</game><game id="15116">Armored Core 3</game><game id="13759">Cyber Troopers Virtual-On Marz</game><game id="13931">MechWarrior</game><game id="1497">WarTech: Senko no Ronde</game><game id="26008">Front Mission Evolved</game><game id="29753">Armored Core V</game><game id="30598">Another Century's Episode R</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2428436-box_zote.png</image></root>