<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11523</id><name>Discord Times</name><description>OverviewDiscord Times is an    Aterdux Entertainment developed strategy/Role Playing game released for the PC. GameplayDiscord Times features a top down view and turn based combat.  Movement Movement in Discord Times is accomplished by pointing the mouse at the  location desired to move to. There will be a trail of arrows leading  to the spot if that location can be traveled to. The left mouse button  can be clicked or a key on the keyboard pressed during movement to  cancel the current move.   Walking Path       Information WindowCharacters and objects will often times have more information about them. By right clicking on an object or character an information window will be displayed with any relevant information.     Information Window for a ghost  In-game ClockDiscord Times features an in-game calendar and clock. Every turn adds time to the clock. The game keeps track of the year, month, day, and hour. There are some quests and actions in the game that require a set amount of time to pass. The player can choose to wait for 1 hour or wait for 4 hours.    In-Game Clock  InventoryThe player can hold up to 25 items in their inventory. There can also be 4 items equipped to the character for use in combat.    Inventory Screen  BarracksIn various buildings around the world there are barracks. In the barracks the player can hire more people to help in battles. There are mercenaries who will help heal, help fight with melee, or help fight with ranged attacks.    Barracks Screen  BattlesBattles in Discord Times are turn based. The team with the highest initiative character gets the first turn. The players team member who is highlighted in green is the active team member and can attack. The enemies players highlighted in red can be attacked by the current player. The player can move the active team member to an empty space that is highlighted in blue.     Battle Screen ClassesIn Discord Times there are three playable classes to choose from.ClassDescription     Knight  KnightThe Knight is the standard melee class. The Knight class takes 20% less damage from all non-magic attacks.Knight Base StatsHealth - 80Melee Attack - 45Melee Defense - 15Long Range Defense - 10Magic Immunity - 15%Initiative - 9Number of Actions - 1    Archmage  ArchmageThe Archmage is the standard magician class. The Archmage class will cast spells in half the time of the other classes. The Archmage class can also cast spells for half of the mana of the other classes. Archmage Base Stats  Health - 50 Magic Attack - 25 Magic Immunity - 35% Initiative - 26 Number of Actions - 2    Ranger  RangerThe Ranger is the agile ranged class. The Ranger Class can move across the map 20% quicker than the other classes. Any members of the Rangers army will heal 20% every day. Ranger Base Stats  Health - 65 Melee Defense - 5Long Range Attack - 30 Long Range Defense - 5 Regeneration - 5% Initiative - 19 Number of Actions - 2System RequirementsOperating System - Windows 2000/XP/Vista/7Processor - 600mhz or fasterRam - 128 MB or more</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/10/103881/1758388-dt.jpg</image></root>