<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11544</id><name>Armies of Exigo</name><description>OverviewArmies of Exigo is a PC Real Time Strategy game developed by Black Hole Entertainment and published by EA. A fairly generic RTS with strong similarities to Warcraft III and StarCraft. The game's major twist on the genre is the 'dual-layered map system', which allows you to delve deep underground and explore caves and caverns, then tunnel to the surface to ambush your enemies.UnitsArmies of Exigo feature's three different armies: The empire, the fallen, the beasts.The empireThe empire represents the human side. "comprised of valiant knights, hardworking peasants, mystical elves and others". The empire is lead by the mage Alric do Rei.Alric do ReiAlric recently took over as head of the Council of Mages when his mentor suddenly and mysteriously died. though still young, Alric's knowledge of ancient spells and unmatched spell-casting mastery make him indispensable in the fight for supremacyDunehelm BellangereA brave and battle-tested knight dedicated to protecting the empire from the growing threats from the beasts and from the more tenuous new threat posed by the fallen, Dunehelm is instrumental in the fight against encroaching evil.Lady TiernaLady Tierna and her giant eagle, Silver Wing, lead the elite Valkyrie warriors. the daughter of the King of the Northern Elves, Lady Tierna remembers and honors the old alliance with humans to defend the realm against invaders, be they beasts or Orcs. Her exquisite mastery of archery is unparalleled.PC System RequirementsWindows 98SE/ME/2000/XP1.5GHz Processor384MB RAM8X CD-ROM Drive1.5GB Hard Disk Space64MB nVidia GeForce 3 or ATi Radeon 8500 Class Video CardDirectX compatible Sound CardDirectX 9.0c</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14073">Warcraft III: The Frozen Throne</game><game id="13062">StarCraft</game><game id="5415">StarCraft: Brood War</game><game id="24078">StarCraft II: Heart of the Swarm</game><game id="24079">StarCraft II: Legacy of the Void</game><game id="18623">Black &amp; White</game><game id="12474">Black &amp; White 2</game><game id="8546">Age of Empires III</game><game id="2846">Age of Empires II: The Age of Kings</game><game id="24380">Age of Empires: Mythologies</game><game id="13076">Age of Mythology</game><game id="20287">KnightShift</game><game id="14458">Warlords: Battlecry III</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/7/71614/1228435-armies_of_exigo.jpg</image></root>