<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11620</id><name>Dungeon Siege: Throne of Agony</name><description>OverviewThrone of Agony is an action RPG for the PSP similar to the Untold Legends, Baldur's Gate Dark Alliance, Champions of Norrath series of games. It is part of the Dungeon Siege franchise, however it was not developed by Gas Powered Games, although they did provide assistance on the project. GameplayLike the aforementioned franchises, the gameplay mostly consists of hack and slash action. However, unlike  Dungeon Siege on the PC which is party based and mouse point controlled, Throne of Agony contains console familiar controls. Press a button to attack, move the character with the analog nub. Unfortunately, Throne of Agony lacks one of its PC cousins' most lauded aspects, seamless loading.   The experience is quest driven, with many main quests and side quests along with secret areas to explore and frequent loot drops. The game features ad hoc local multiplayer to go along with the single player mode.The story will likely last most players around 15 hours, but you can replay it with a friend or just to grind it out alone to max out your levels. ClassesWhen you start the game given the choice between 3 different characters;  mage,  fighter, and ranger.  Each class plays differently and has a distinct look. New classes are unlocked at levels 30 and 50. The classes are Hero and Legendary, respectively.  This is similar to Baldur's Gate: Dark Alliance 2, since the new classes are essentially extra abilities.  It differs from Baldur's Gate: Dark Alliance 2 in that  you must  chose the class, and therefore the set of abilities to advance with. For instance the Mage can become a DeathKnight or a BattleMage, but can not use abilities from both.One of the unique aspects of this game is that after choosing your character you get to pick a pet to help you throughout the game.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2603">Untold Legends: The Warrior's Code</game><game id="13217">Champions of Norrath</game><game id="5985">Diablo</game><game id="7584">Etrom: The Astral Essence</game><game id="3247">Untold Legends: Brotherhood of the Blade</game><game id="13091">Baldur's Gate: Dark Alliance</game><game id="12107">Baldur's Gate: Dark Alliance II</game><game id="3156">Champions: Return to Arms</game><game id="7048">Kingdom of Paradise</game><game id="24801">Angels Online</game><game id="2361">Crisis Core: Final Fantasy VII</game><game id="21636">Dungeon Explorer: Warriors of Ancient Art</game><game id="11806">Silverfall</game><game id="32416">DeathSpank: Thongs of Virtue</game><game id="35560">Warrior's Lair</game><game id="31832">Konung III: Ties of the Dynasty</game><game id="12">Blade &amp; Sword</game><game id="20803">Diablo III</game><game id="8590">Dawn of Magic</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1992/1154415-dstoa.jpg</image></root>