<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11656</id><name>Rockman Battle &amp; Chase</name><description>OverviewThe title screen.MegaMan: Battle  Chase is a cart racing game in the vain of Nintendo's Mario Kart series. It was released only in Japan for the Playstation in 1997, and then re-released for the PS2  GameCube as part of the MegaMan X Collection in 2006.  GameplayThe gameplay of MegaMan Battle  Chase is similar to the Mario Kart games. The game features custom option for the vehicles that the character rides such as, body, engine, wing, and tire, it also adds a bit of strategy to the gameplay. Each vehicle has its own two unique abilities and a special meter, one regular attack and a special attack when the player's meter is charged up. For example, Gustman can throw giant rocks as his regular attack and can cause earthquakes when his special meter is charged; while MegaMan can shoot projectile to slow down enemies and shoot big projectiles to fully stop enemies when his meter is charged up.ProtoMan, catching up to Roll.The single player is played by earning parts - from the other racer's cart - when the player defeats his or her opponet. The parts can be used to help the player win other races but they do have their strength  weaknesses, it also adds a bit of strategy to the gameplay. For example, some race tracks have a extensive amount of dirt plains, going through them can slow down the player's vehicle; that's where Gutsman's "Press Tires" comes in. Characteristic of vehicle partsBody: Weapon.Engine: Performance.Wing: Acceleration.Tire: Control.Characters/Vehicles Characters MegaMan Roll ProtoMan IceMan Bass QuickMan NapalmMan ShadowMan GutsMan SpringMan Duo Dr. WillyBlack Troops Members.Black Troops MembersBlack Troops members are secret racers that sometimes appears at the beginning of a race.Black JoeBlack 4 Roader Black Yellow DevilVehicles/PartsRush Roadstar.Rush RoadstarPartsBody: Rush Body.Engine: Twin Engine.Wing: Starter WingTire: All-Round TirePop'N Beat.Pop'N BeatPartsBody: Beat Body.Engine: Follow Engine.Wing: Feather Wing.Tire: Non-Drift Tire.Red Striker.Red StrikerPartsBody: Shield Body.Engine: L-Blow Engine.Wing: Hi-Speed Wing.Tire: Sharp Tire.Treble DarkStar.Treble DarkStarPartsBody: Treble Body.Engine: Double Engine.Wing: Accel. Wing.Tire: Almighty Tire.Wilds Arms.Wild ArmsPartsBody: Twin Arm Body.Engine: Slope Engine.Wing: Power Wing.Tire: Press Tire.Sonic Formula.Sonic FormulaPartsBody: Turbo Body.Engine: Dash Engine.Wing: Rocket Wing.Tire: On-Road Tire.Cool Mobile.Cool MobilePartsBody: Polar Body.Engine: Aurora Engine.Wing: Blizzard Wing.Tire: Non-Slip Tire.Shinobi Master.Shinobi MasterPartsBody: Ninja Body.Engine: Idaton Engine.Wing: Hayate Wing.Tire: Fuuma Tire.Patriot Bomber.Patriot BomberPartsBody: Full Metal Body.Engine: Device Engine.Wing: Counter Wing.Tire: E-Guard Tire.Surprise Boxer.Surprise BoxerPartsBody: Turn Punch Body.Engine: Happy Engine.Wing: Lucky Wing.Tire: Hopper Tire.Hand GrandeurHand GrandeurPartsBody: Giga Fist Body.Engine: Final Engine.Wing: Maximum Wing.Tire: Supreme Tire.Skull Machine.Skull MachinePartsBody: Bone Head Body.Engine: Nova EngineWing: BarrierTire: Ultimate Tire.LevelsCourse select screen.Sky Circuit 1Sky Circuit 2 Sky Circuit 3City CourseSunset CourseRocky Mountain CourseSouth Pole CourseRidge CourseCrystal CourseArms Factory CourseToy Factory CourseBase CourseSpace CourseWily Fortress CourseRe-ReleaseThe game finally made its way outside of Japan in the form of MageMan X Collection. A collection of MegaMan X games (X1 to X6), and as a added bonus to the game, Battle  Chase was a part of the compilation.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6196">Crash Team Racing</game><game id="2260">Sonic R</game><game id="20645">Mario Kart Wii</game><game id="18757">Mario Kart: Double Dash!!</game><game id="6539">Mario Kart DS</game><game id="19071">Super Mario Kart</game><game id="22373">Mario Kart Arcade GP</game><game id="25285">Mario Kart Arcade GP 2</game><game id="16769">Mario Kart: Super Circuit</game><game id="14134">Pac-Man World Rally</game><game id="20644">Donkey Kong: Barrel Blast</game><game id="26657">Sonic &amp; Sega All-Stars Racing</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3161/329504-rockmanbattlechasentscjslps007.jpg</image></root>