<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1165</id><name>Beavis and Butt-head in Virtual Stupidity</name><description>OverviewBeavis and Butt-head in Virtual Stupidity is a point and click adventure game developed by Viacom New Media and published by B-Factory for the PC and PlayStation platforms.Beavis and Butt-head in Virtual Stupidity is based on the MTV animated series titled "Beavis and Butt-head".PlotBeavis and Butt-head in Virtual Stupidity starts out with the two titular main characters, Beavis and Butt-head working their job at the BurgerWorld. They are approached by Todd who proceeds to threaten them. After being threatened by Todd, Beavis and Butt-head decide that they want to try and become part of the gang that Todd is the leader of.Throughout the rest of the game, Beavis and Butt-head work on various tasks which will hopefully get them closer to the members of Todd's gang in hopes of joining them.GameplayBeavis and Butt-head in Virtual Stupidity is a point and click adventure game in which the player tries to solve puzzles by collecting items and using them in different situations.Mini GamesIn addition to the main gameplay mechanic, there are also four different mini-games that are played:Hock-A-LoogieCourt ChaosBug JusticeAir GuitarMusic VideosThroughout the course of the game, there are TV sets which can be used to watch three full music videos, complete with commentary by Beavis and Butt-head, similar to the TV show. The music videos contained in the game are:"Saddam a Go-Go" by GWAR"DMV" by Primus"Riddles are Abound Tonight" by SausagePortsWhile the PC platform was the first release, a port for the Philips CD-i platform was planned, but due to poor sales of the CD-i console the port was cancelled. The game was instead ported to the Sony PlayStation platform, but was only released in Japan.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18248">Beavis and Butt-head</game><game id="19729">The Ren &amp; Stimpy Show: Stimpy's Invention</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2579/1673241-beavis_and_butt_head_in_virtual_stupidity_box_front.jpg</image></root>