<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11704</id><name>Fallout</name><description>PlotThe Overseer of Vault 13Taking place in the year 2161, the story of Fallout begins 84 years after a short but disastrous world war devastates the Earth and human society. Atomic war was occasioned by "Resource Wars" for petroleum and uranium. The game puts the player in the shoes of the Vault Dweller, an inhabitant of one of a series of government fallout shelters referred to as Vaults. This particular Vault, #13, is located in Southern California, and was intended to remain shut for 200 years. Unfortunately the water purification system of Vault 13 failed, and the Overseer sent out the Vault Dweller to find a new water chip. The vault has enough water in reserve to last them a 150 days, which means that the Vault Dweller must find and return a water chip in that time frame.Eventually the Vault Dweller finds the water chip in the ghoul city of Necropolis, but also learns of the existence of Super Mutants. When he returns to the Overseer, the Vault Dweller gives him the new, working water chip, and also makes a report on Super Mutants. The Overseer views their presence as a threat, and asks the Vault Dweller, to once again go into the wastes, and find and destroy the source of the mutant army. (prior to version 1.1 there was a time limit of 500 days for eliminating the mutant threat, if the player failed to do so, the mutants would find Vault 13 and destroy it)The one, the only, the Master himselfThe Vault Dweller finds that the Mutant leader, The Master is located in Boneyard (Los Angeles) in the Cathedral, the headquarters of a secretive cult that unbeknownst to most, works to further the cause of Unity and therefor, The Master. When speaking with the master it is revealed that he seeks to unify humanity by creating a new race of mutants. He believes that in order for humanity to prosper and for peace to be obtained, everyone must be forced to undergo an evolution, this is core of his plan, Unity.The way new mutants are created, is the same way the man known as Richard Moreau was turned into the master. Richard Moreau was a scientist and doctor in The Hub and was hired by a caravan master named Harold to uncover the source of the mutants that were attacking Harold's caravan. Their travels eventually led them to the Mariposa Military Base, where a pre-war virus, created by West-Tek at the orders of the U.S. Army was located. Somehow both of them were exposed to this pre-war virus, known as the FEV (Forced Evolutionary Virus). Harold was rescued by his Caravan, but Richard was never found. Moreau was pushed into a vats filled with FEV, he remained in it for a month. After, as he gained consciousness he realized that he was transformed into a blob-like creature. He discovered that he could absorb biological creatures, as well as computers. As he absorbed his intelligence increased greatly and he formulated a plan for unification of the wasteland. The Master began dipping other humans into the vats, but they came out horribly wrong, as mutants that were barely able to speak. The Master absorbed them, rather than letting them live. In the early years of the 22nd century, the master perfected the creation of Super Mutants. He created a super mutant army with a single goal in mind. The forcing of every human to evolve into a super mutant and the unification of the wasteland.The Vault Dweller defeated the Master and ruined his plan, after which he traveled to Mariposa Military Base to destroy the mutant army, by destroying the vats and therefor the creation system of super mutants. After all of these events, the Vault Dweller returns to Vault 13 and the Overseer. His reward for securing the water chip, destroying the Master and his mutants and saving the vault, was exile. The overseer argued that if the Vault Dweller was to return to the vault, everyone would want to leave, and follow in his footsteps. It would be better for the vault, and everyone in it if the Vault Dweller simply left. He did, and wandered the wastes for a while before founding Arroyo.GameplayCharacter CreationFallout is a turn-based role playing game, featuring a customizable character with basic attributes that can be improved over time using a system designed specifically for the game called SPECIAL (Strength, Perception, Endurance, Charisma, Intelligence, Agility and Luck). The player can also learn from 18 individual skills (which are partly derived from the SPECIAL configuration of the character), governing aspects of social interaction, healing, weapon use, and so on. Additionally, the game also tracks the moral/ethical qualities of the player through karma, and the game will react to the player differently depending on how the player has acted throughout the course of the game. For example, if the player has killed two or more children, a group of tough bounty hunters will be set loose to find and kill the player.S.P.E.C.I.A.L. (Primary Statistics)The S.P.E.C.I.A.L. system is basically the attributes system of Fallout (the attributes are referred to as primary statistics). It stands for Strength, Perception, Endurance, Charisma, Intelligence, Agility and Luck - S.P.E.C.I.A.L.Fallout was originally supposed to use Steve Jackson Games's system called GURPS (Generic Universal RolePlaying System). The early working title for Fallout was "Vault 13: A GURPS Post-Nuclear Adventure" and later "Fallout: A GURPS Post-Nuclear Adventure". Due to licencing problems the developer was forced to create the Special system. There are some similarities with GURPS, but it's largely an original creation.No primary statistic can be raised beyond 10, or below 1 (if the Gifted trait is taken, primary stats can't be below 2). Many of the perks in the game require a certain level of each statistic and/or skill. Apart from that, each statistic modifies and effects the player character in some way. Strength, for example, determines the weight one can carry and the damage someone can do with melee attacks. Agility modifies action points, which are used in combat. Each action requires a certain amount of action points, and so on.There are also ways to increase primary stats in-game permanently or temporary. The "Gain" perks increase an attribute by +1 permanently, for example Gain Strength increases strength by +1. Power Armor also increases strength, but by +3. Mentants increase Charisma by +1, Intelligence and Perception by +2, etc.For more information on primary statistics see below.Name and ImageDescription and UseStrength (ST)Raw physical Strength. A high Strength is good for physical characters.Modifies: Hit Points, Melee Damage, and Carry Weight.Perks that require StrengthSlayer (8)Strong Back (6)Bonus HtH Damage (6)Strength also determines the effectiveness of using a weapon depending on its strength rating.Ways to increase:Gain Strength +1Adrenaline Rush perk +1 when Hit Points50%Power Armor +3 (Advanced Power Armor increases it by +4)Buffout +2 (temporary)Heave Ho perk increases Strength by +2 for the purpose of determining throwing rangeWeapon Handling decreases Strength requirement by -3 for weaponsBruiser trait increases Strength by +2 but lowers Action Points by 2Perception (PE)The ability to see, hear, taste and notice unusual things. A high Perception is important for a sharpshooter.Modifies: Sequence and ranged combat distance modifiers.Perks that require PerceptionSniper (8)Scout (8)Sharpshooter (7)Healer (7)Empathy (7)Bonus Rate of Fire (6)Better Criticals (6)Earlier Sequence (6)Night Vision (6)Ranger (6)Awareness (5)Friendly Foe (4)Ways to increase Perception:Mentats +2 (temporary)Gain Perception +1Sharpshooter perk increases perception for the purpose of determining range modifiers of firearms by +2Endurance (EN)Stamina and physical toughness. A character with a high Endurance will survive where others may not.Modifies: Hit Points, Poison  Radiation Resistance, Healing Rate  hit points gained per level.Perks that require EnduranceToughness (6)Pathfinder (6)Survivalist (6)Rad Resistance (6)Faster Healing (6)Flower Child (5)Lifegiver (4)Snakeater (3)Ways to increase Endurance:Buffout +3 (temporary)Gain Endurance +1Charisma (CH)A combination of appearance and charm. A high charisma is important for characters that want to influence people with words.Modifies: NPC reactions, and barter prices.Perks that require CharismaCult of Personality (10)Master Trader (7)Presence (6)Ways to increase Charisma:Gain Charisma +1Mentats +1 (temporary)The Singer random encounter. Speaking to Patrick the Celt increases charisma permanently by +1Intelligence (IN)Knowledge, wisdom and the ability to think quickly. A high Intelligence is important for any character.Modifies: the number of skill points gained per level, dialogue options and many skills.Perks that require IntelligenceSharpshooter (6)Bonus Rate of Fire (6)Educated (6)Healer (5)Empathy (5)Animal Friend (5)Smooth Talker (4)Swift Learner (4)Ways to increase Intelligence:Gain Intelligence +1Mentats +2 (temporary)Agility (AG)Coordination and the ability to move well. A high Agility is important for any active character.Modifies: Action Points, Armor Class, Sequence, and many skills.Perks that require AgilitySilent Death (10)Sniper (8)Slayer (8)Pickpocket (8)Bonus Rate of Fire (7)Bonus HtH Damage (6)Healer (6)Bonus Ranged Damage (6)Bonus HtH Attacks (6)Silent Running (6)Action Boy/Girl (5)Bonus Move (5)Quick Pockets (5)Better Criticals (4)Dodger (4)Ways to increase Agility:Gain Agility +1Buffout +2 (temporary)Psycho +3 (temporary)Luck (LK)Fate. Karma. An extremely high or low Luck will affect the character - somehow. Events and situations will be changed by how lucky (or unlucky) your character is.Modifies: Critical ChancePerks that require LuckFortune Finder (8)Scrounger (8)Mysterious Stranger (7)Better Criticals (6)More Criticals (6)Toughness (6)Bonus Ranged Damage (6)Ways to increase Luck:Gain Luck +1Chuck in Boneyard can increase your luck by +1 via the mysteries of the Tarot*Each skill can also be raised in game with the exception of Charisma and Luck.*The numbers in the brackets specify the level of the attribute required to take a perk.Derived StatisticsDerived statistics, or secondary statistics, are directly influenced, modified and tied with primary statistics. There are several derived stats, and each one is linked with a primary stat. For example, carry weight, which is a derived statistic, is directly influenced by Strength, where as action points are influenced by Agility. There are also ways to increase or decrease derived statistics by traits, or perks. Strong Back raises the carry weight statistic, Action Boy raises action points by 1 point etc.Name and ImageDescriptions and UseAction Points (AP)The amount of actions that the character can take during one combat turn.Every action, from shooting and reloading a weapon, to walking, to opening a door or container and accessing your inventory has a certain action point cost. The number of maximum points is calculated using the following formula.5 + Agility / 2Ways to increase the number of maximum action points in game, or decrease the required AP for completing an action.The Small Frame trait increases agility by 1Action Boy/Girl increase max action points by 1, this perk can be taken 2 times.Bonus move increases action points by 2, each time this perk is taken, for the purposes of movement.Bonus Rate of Fire decreases the number of action points required for firing your weapon by 1.Fast shot does the same, although it eliminates the ability to use aimed shots.Bonus HtH Attack has the same effect as Bonus Rate of Fire, but only for melee/unarmed attacks.Armor Class (AC)Modifies the chance to hit this particular character.Armor class determines the ability to dodge attacks. It does not decrease the amount of damage received. All armors increase AC, but generally speaking, heavier armor doesn't increase armor class as much as light weight armors.Every point of agility increases natural Armor Class by 1.Perks and traits that increase/decrease AC,Invest points into Agility.Use armor (every armor increases AC, even the heaviest).Dodger perk increases AC by 5 each time it is taken.HtH Evade increases AC while unarmed.Kamikaze decreases AC, while it raises sequence.Carry WeightThe maximum amount of equipment your character can carry, in pounds.It is directly influenced by Strength. Every character starts with 25 carry weight +25 per point of Strength. So 25 + Strength x 25. Unless the Small Frame trait in which case the formula is 25 + Strength x 15.Ways to increase carry weight, or decrease the weight of items.Invest points into Strength.Strong Back perk increases carry weight by 50 lbs for each rank.Pack Rat increases carry weight by 50 lbs.Critical ChanceThe chance to cause a critical hit in combat is increased by this amount.Critical chance is directly modified by luck. Each point of Luck increases the critical chance by 1. Critical hits obviously increase the damage done by a certain amount.Ways to increase critical chance, or the damage done by critical hits.Increase Luck.Finesse trait increases critical chance by 10%, while decreasing normal damage by -30%.More Criticals increases critical chance by 5% for each rank taken, up to three.Better Criticals increases critical damage by 50%.Aimed shots have an increased amount to cause a critical hit, eyes and head having the highest chance and limbs lowest.The Sniper perk increases critical chance by making a separate, behind the scenes role. Each point of luck, with the sniper perk, increases critical chance by +10%. 10 Luck would mean 100% critical chance.Damage Resistance (DR)Any damage taken is reduced by this amount. Damage Resistance can be increased by wearing armor.Damage Resistance is directly influenced by the armor a character wears. There are several types of damages, and therefor several types of resistances. These types areNormal (physical damage done by bullets or melee weapons)FireExplosivePlasmaLaser10 DR in any of the damage types decreases the damage received by 10%Ways to increase DRToughness by +5 for each rank taken.Wearing better armor.Using armor piercing ammunition against heavily armored targets increases damage done.Healing RateAt the end of each day, your character will heal 1 HP for each point of healing rate. When you rest, you heal every six hours.Healing rate determines how quickly a character recovers from wounds by waiting. It is directly influenced by Endurance, 1/3 of endurance = healing rate. So 9 endurance means that the healing rate will be 3.Ways to increase Healing RateFast Metabolism increases it by 2.Faster Healing perks also increases it by 2.Hit Point (HP)How much damage your character can take before dying. If you reach 0 HP or less, you are dead.Hitpoints are a statistic that determine how much damage a character can take before death. Initial hitpoints = 15 + Strength + 2 x Endurance. Each level a character gains 2 + Endurance / 2 hitpoints.Ways to increase hitpointsLeveling up.Lifegiver +4 hitpoints each level with this perk.Melee DamageThe amount of bonus damage your character does in hand-to-hand combat.The amount of bonus damage done with melee or unarmed attacks, in addition to the damage done with the weapon. Initial level is equal to every point above 5 Strength, 7 Strength equals 2 Melee Damage.Ways to increase Melee DamageIncreasing Strength above 5.Heavy Handed increases Melee Damage by 4, while decreasing critical chance by -30%.Bonus HtH Damage increases it by 2.Slayer upgrades every melee hit to a critical one, regardless of critical chance.Perk RateThe amount of levels the character will have to gain in order to gain a perk (lower is better).Every character gains a perk every 3 levels, which means that the perk rate is 3. There is no way to decrease the perk rate in Fallout, only increase it to 4 by taking the skilled trait.Poison ResistanceReduces poison damage by this amount.The damage reduction is percentage based. It also decreases the chance to be poisoned. Initial level = Endurance x 5.Ways to increase/decrease poison resistanceTaking the Fast Metabolism decreases this statistic (as well as radiation resistance) to 0.The Snakeater perk increases Poison Resistance by 25 for each rank taken.Radiation ResistanceThe amount of radiation you are exposed to is reduced by this percentage. Radiation Resistance can be modified by the type of armor worn, and anti-radiation chems.As said, this stat decreases the amount of radiation taken. At 100% you are immune to radiation. If a character reaches a radiation level of 1000 they will die after a few days.Initial level = Endurance x 2Ways to increase/decrease Radiation ResistanceRad Resistance perk increases it by 10% for each rank.Rad-X increases it by 50%. Taking 2 increases the resistance above 100, effectively making you immune to radiation. (temporary)Fast Metabolism decreases Radiation Resistance (along with Poison Resistance) to 0.SequenceDetermines how soon in a combat turn your character can react.After the surprise turn, sequence determines who will go the turn after. The higher the sequence value, the better. Initial level = Perception x 2.Ways to increase SequenceKamikaze trait increases it by 5, although it decreases natural armor to 0.Earlier Sequence perk increases it by 2.Skill RateThe number of skill points you'll be able to allocate each time you gain a level.Each time a character gains a level, he/she gains skill points. The amount is determined by 5 + Intelligence x 2. Tagged skills are increased by 2 for each skill point, where as other skills are increased 1:1.Ways to increase Skill RateIncrease Intelligence ,Educated perk +2 for each rank,Skilled trait +10% to each skill, +1 perk rate.SkillsCombat SkillsSkill and ImageDescriptionBig GunsFor Operation and mainenance of really big guns. Miniguns, Rocket Launchers, Flamethrowers and such.Base Skill: 10% + AgilityEnergy WeaponsThe care and feeding of energy-based weapons. How to arm and operate weapons that use laser or plasma technologyBase Skill: 10% + AgilityMelee WeaponsUsing non-ranged weapons in hand-to-hand, or melee, combat. Knives, sledgehammers, spears, clubs and so on.Base Skill: 55% + (Agility + Strength) / 2Small GunsThe use, care and general knowledge of small firearms. Pistols, SMGs and rifles.Base Skill: 35% + AgilityThrowingThe skill of muscle-propelled ranged weapons. Throwing knives, spears and grenades.Base Skill: 40% + AgilityUnarmedA combination of martial arts, boxing and other hand-to-hand martial arts. Combat with your hands and feet.Base Skill: 65% + (Agility + Strength) / 2Active SkillsSkill and ImageDescriptionDoctorThe healing of major wounds and crippled limbs. Without this skill it will take a much longer period of time to restore crippled limbs to use.Base Skill: 15% + (Perception + Intelligence) / 2First AidGeneral healing skill. Used to heal small cuts, abrasions and other minor ills. In game terms, the use of first aid can heal more hit points over time than just rest.Base Skill: 30% + (Perception + Intelligence)LockpickThe skill of opening locks without the proper key. The use of lockpicks or electronic lockpicks will greatly enhance this skill.Base Skill: 20% + (Perception + Agility) / 2RepairThe practical application of the Science skill. The fixing of broken equipment, machinery and electronics.Base Skill: 20% + IntelligenceScienceCovers a variety of hi-technology skills, such as computers, biology, physics and geology.Base Skill: 25% + (2 x Intelligence)SneakQuiet movement, and the ability to remain unnoticed. If successful, you will be much harder to locate. You cannot run and sneak at the same time.Base Skill: 25% + AgilityStealThe ability to make the things of others your own. Can be used to steal from people or places.Base Skill: 20% + AgilityTrapsThe finding and removal of traps. Also the setting of explosives for demolition purposes.Base Skill: 20% + (Perception + Agility) / 2Passive SkillsSkill and ImageDescriptionBarterTrading and trade-related tasks. The ability to get better prices for items you sell, and lower prices for items you buy.Base Skill: 20% + (2 x Charisma)GamblingThe knowledge and practical skills related to wagering. The skill at cards, dice and other games.Base Skill: 20% + (3 x Luck)OutdoorsmanPractical knowledge of the outdoors, and the ability to live off the land. The knowledge of plants and animals.Base Skill: 5% + (Endurance + Intelligence) / 2SpeechThe ability to communicate in a practical and efficient manner. The Skill of convincing others that your position is correct. The ability to lie and not get caught.Base Skill: 25% + (2 x Charisma)TraitsOptional traits describe your character in more detail. All traits will have positive and negative effects. You may choose up to two traits during creation.Trait and ImageDescriptionBloody MessBy some strange twist of fate, people around you die violently. You always see the worst way a person can die.Violent death animations, effects the ending of the game.BruiserA little slower, but a little bigger. You may not hit as often, but they will feel it when you do. Your total action points are lowered but your strength is increased.Gain +2 strength at the cost of -2 action points.Chem ReliantYou crave chems more easily. Your chance to crave chems is twice normal, but you recover faster from their ill effects.Recovers faster from addiction, but also increases the chance of becoming an addict.Chem ResistantChems only affect you half as long as normal, but your chance to crave them is also only 50% of normal.Chems last half the normal amount, but the chance of getting addicted is also lowered by half.Fast MetabolismYour metabolic rate is twice normal. This means that you are much less resistant to radiation and poison, but your body heals faster.+2 healing rate, poison and radiation resistances start at 0%.Fast ShotYou don't have time to aim for a targeted attack, because you attack faster than normal people. It costs you one less action point to use a weapon.Eliminates the ability to make aimed shots, but firing a weapon costs 1 action point less.FinesseYour attacks show a lot of finesse. You don't do as much damage, but you cause more critical hits.+10% critical chance, -30% normal damage.GiftedYou have more initiate abilities than most, so you have not spent as much time honing your skills. Your primary statistics are each +1, but you lose -10% on all skills to start, and receive 5 less skill points per level.+1 to each S.P.E.C.I.A.L. attribute, -10% on all skills and -5 skill points per level.Good NaturedYou studied less-combative skills as you were growing up. Your combat skills start a lower level, but your First Aid, Doctor, Speech and Barter are substantially improved.+15% First Aid, Doctor, Speech and Barter, but -10% Small Guns, Big Guns, Energy Weapons, Melee Weapons, Throwing and Unarmed.Heavy HandedYou swing harder, not better. Your attacks are very brutal, but you lack finesse. You rarely Cause a good critical, but you always do more melee damage.+4 melee damage, -30% critical chance.JinxedThe good thing is that everyone around you has more critical failures in combat, the bad thing is so do you!Both you and your enemies experience more critical misses.KamikazeBy not paying attention to any threats, you can act a lot faster in a turn. This lowers your armor class to just what you are wearing, but you sequence much faster in a combat turn.Armor rating bonus from Agility set to 0, but +5 to sequence.Night PersonAs a night-time person, you are more awake when the sun goes down. Your Intelligence and Perception are improved at night, but dulled during the day.+1 Perception during nighttime, -1 Perception during daytime.One HanderOne of your hands is very dominant. You excel with single-handed weapons, but two-handed weapons cause a problem.+20% to hit with one-handed weapons, -40% to hit with two handed weapons.SkilledSince you spent more time improving your skills than a normal person, you start with better skill levels. The tradeoff is that you do not gain as many extra abilities. You will gain a perk every four levels.+10% to all skills, perk rate increased to 4.Small FrameYou are not quite as big as the other Vault-Dwellers, but that never slowed you down. You can't carry as much, but you are more agile.+1 Agility, but carrying weight reduced to 25 + 15 x Strength.PerksPerks are similar to Traits except that they do not have any drawbacks. You get to choose one every three levels- -unless you have the Skilled Trait-- and some can be chosen multiple times. There are a total of 53 perks available to the player in the game. Here's a list, displayed in alphabetical order.PerkRequiredLevelOverall RequirementsNo. ofRanksDescriptionAction Boy12- Agility 53Adds additional Action Points (AP) in combat turnsAnimal Friend9- Intelligence 5- Outdoorsman 25%1Animals will not attack you unless you attack them firstAwareness3- Perception 51Examining any given target displays Hit Points, weapon and ammunition countBetter Criticals9- Perception 6- Agility 4- Luck 61Adds a 20% bonus to the critical hit damageBonus HtH Attacks6- Agility 61Hand-to-hand and melee attacks cost 1 less APBonus HtH Damage3- Strenght 6- Agility 63Adds 2 points of damage for hand-to-hand and melee attacks (including Melee attacks!)Bonus Move6- Agility 53Adds 2 extra APs per turn, which can only be used for movementBonus Ranged Damage6- Agility 6- Luck 62Adds 2 points of damage for attacks with ranged weaponsBonus Rate of Fire9- Perception 6- Intelligence 6- Agility 71Ranged weapon attacks cost 1 less APCult of Personality12- Charisma 101People will always view you in a favorable light, no matter your reputation and/or their alignmentDodger9- Agility 42Adds 5% to your Armor ClassEarlier Sequence3- Perception 63Adds 2 to attack sequenceEducated6- Intelligence 63Adds 2 skill points at level up (permanently)Empathy6- Perception 7- Intelligence 51Reaction levels are shown when in an indepth conversationExplorer91Higher chance of finding special places and people in random encountersFaster Healing3- Endurance 63Adds 1 bonus point to your healing rateFlower Child9- Endurance 5150% less likely for the player to become addicted to chems; the withdrawal period is also cut to halfFortune Finder6- Luck 81Additional money is found during random encountersFriendly Foe6- Perception 41Characters on your team are highlighted green during combatGhost6- Sneak 60%1Adds 20% to Sneak in dark conditionsHealer3- Perception 7- Intelligence 5- Agility 6- First Aid 40%32 to 5 more hit points are healed whenever using First Aid or Doctor skillsHeave Ho!63Adds 2 points to Strength when determining the range of any thrown weaponLifegiver12- Endurance 43Adds 4 hit pointsMaster Thief121Adds 10% to the Sneak, Lockpick, Steal and Trap skillsMaster Trader9- Charisma 7- Barter 60%125% discount when purchasing items from stores and tradersMedic121Adds 20% to the First Aid and Doctor skillsMental Block151Resistance to Master's psychic attacksMore Criticals6- Luck 63Adds 5% to the critical hit chanceMr. Fixit121Adds 20% to the Repair and Science skillsMutate!91Allows you to change one of your traitsMysterious Stranger6- Luck 71Gives you a chance temporarily gain an ally in any given random encountersNight Vision3- Perception 6310% reduction in darkness levelPathfinder6- Endurance 6- Outdoorsman 40%2Cuts the travel time on the world map by 25%Pickpocket9- Agility 8- Sneak 80%1Size and facing modifiers are now ignored whenever you're stealing from someonePresence3- Charisma 63Adds 10% to the initial reaction of any given NPCQuick Pockets3- Agility 53Inventory access during combat costs 1 AP lessRad Resistance6- Endurance 6- Intelligence 43Adds 15% to Radiation ResistanceRanger6- Perception 63Lowers the chance of hostile random encountersScout3- Perception 81Exploration/Visibility is increased by 1 square in every direction on the world mapScrounger9- Luck 81Doubles the amount of ammo found in random encountersSharpshooter6- Perception 7- Intelligence 62Adds 2 points to Perception whenever determining range modifiersSilent Death18- Agility 10- Sneak 80%1Sneaking Hand-to-Hand attacks from behind inflict twice the damageSilent Running6- Agility 6- Sneak 50%1Running no longer affects your Sneak skillSlayer18- Strenght 8- Agility 8- Unarmed 80%1All Hand-to-Hand attacks inflict critical hitsSmooth Talker3- Intelligence 43Adds 1 point to Intelligence (during dialogue only!)Snakeater6- Endurance 31Adds 25% to Poison ResistanceSniper18- Perception 8- Agility 8- Small Guns 80%1Increased chance to score a critical hit with any ranged weaponSpeaker121Adds 20% to the Speech and Barter skillsStrong Back3- Strenght 6- Endurance 63The player can now carry an additional 50 lbs. of equipmentSurvivalist3- Endurance 6- Intelligence 6- Outdoorsman 40%3Adds a 20% bonus to Outdoorsman during survival checksSwift Learner3- Intelligence 43Adds a 5% bonus whenever XP is earnedTag!121Pick an additional Tag SkillToughness3- Endurance 6- Luck 63Adds 10% to damage resistanceCombatThe battle system in Fallout is turn-based, but certain factors determine the amount and type of actions that a player is able to perform per turn. When combat mode is entered, a player's actions per turn are limited by their AP(Action Points). The number of AP a player gets per turn depends on their Agility attribute. Certain weapons use more AP than others, but the player can also choose to take a targeted shot with their weapons, using one more AP but potentially causing more damage or inflicting conditions onto the enemy. Other actions that consume AP are walking, accessing the inventory, and interacting with items in the game world (such as doors).Non-Combat SkillsAlthough the combat system is usually a large portion of Fallout's game play, what is often said to set the game apart is the fact that players can explore the entire game rarely (if ever) fighting anything, should they choose to do so. Skills such as Speech (which allows the character to have more dialogue options and a greater influence on NPC's) and Science (which allows the character to interact with computers throughout the game world) allow players a greater freedom in how they interact with their environment.WeaponsRANGED weapons can roughly be divided in 4 main groups:Small GunsPistolsSMGsRiflesShotgunsBig GunsEnergy WeaponsPistolsRiflesThrowing WeaponrySmall GunsPistolsNameRangeDamageStrenghtRequiredAmmoTypeClipSize.223 Pistol3020-305.223 FMJ59mm Mauser225-1039mm710mm Pistol255-12310mm1214mm Pistol3012-22514mm6Desert Eagle .442510-164.44 Magnum8Submachine GunsNameRangeDamageStrenghtRequiredAmmoTypeClipSizeSMG25 (single shot)20 (burst shot)5-12410mm30RiflesNameRangeDamageStrenghtRequiredAmmoTypeClipSizeAssault Rifle45 (single shot)38 (burst shot)8-1655mm24Hunting Rifle408-205.223 FMJ10Red Ryder LE BB Gun3225-254BBs100Sniper Rifle5014-345.223 FMJ6ShotgunsNameRangeDamageStreghtRequiredAmmoTypeClipSizeCombat Shotgun22 (single shot)18 (burst shot)15-25512 Gauge12Shotgun1412-22412 Gauge2Big GunsNameRangeDamageStrenghtRequiredAmmoTypeClipSizeMinigun357-1175mm120Flamer540-906Flamethrower Fuel5Rocket Launcher4035-1006Rockets1Energy WeaponsPistolsNameRangeDamageStrenghtRequiredAmmoTypeClipSizeAlien Blaster1030-902Small Energy Cell30Laser Pistol1510-223Small Energy Cell12Plasma Pistol2015-354Small Energy Cell16RiflesNameRangeDamageStrenghtRequiredAmmoTypeClipSizeGatling Laser4020-406Microfusion Cell30Laser Rifle4525-506Microfusion Cell12Plasma Rifle2530-656Microfusion Cell10Turbo Plasma Rifle3535-706Microfusion Cell10Throwing WeaponryNameRangeDamageStrenghtRequiredFrag Grenade1520-353Plasma Grenade1540-904Pulse Grenade15100-1504Molotov Cocktail128-203Rock151-41Flare151-11Spear83-104Throwing Knife163-63Melee Weaponry is in turn traditionally divided in 3 main groups:Common Melee WeaponsPowered Melee WeaponsUnarmedCommon Melee WeaponryNameDamageStrenghtRequiredKnife1-62Combat Knife3-102Club1-63Crowbar3-105Sledgehammer4-96Super Sledge18-365Powered Melee WeaponryNameDamageStrenghtRequiredAmmoTypeClipSizeRipper15-324Small Energy Cell30Cattle Prod12-204Small Energy Cell20Powered Gloves12-341Small Energy Cell25UnarmedNameDamageStrenghtRequiredBrass Knuckles2-51Spiked Knuckles4-101Finally, there are also a couple of explosives available to the player.ExplosivesNameDamageStrenghtRequiredDynamite20-501Plastic Explosive40-801ArmorNameArmorClassNormalResistanceLaserResistanceFireResistancePlasmaResistanceElectricalResistanceExplosionResistanceWeight(in pounds)Robes520251010402010Leather Jacket82020101030105Metal Armor103075102002535Leather Armor152520202030208Tesla Armor1520902080801035Brotherhood Armor2040705060604025Combat Armor2040605060604025Hardened Power Armor25509060505060100T-51b Power Armor2540806040405085NPC FollowersIn Fallout, the Player was able to recruit a couple of NPCs, who helped in his journey. Special requirements were needed to make them join. Charisma also played great role in number of available companions.Many criticized Fallout's team system, because of the teammates' poor AI and clunky system of inventory management. Despite that, gamers and critics alike praised the fact that NPCs in Fallout were characters worth remembering.Here's the list of all available NPCs:Ian -- Found in Shady Sands. Skilled with knives, pistols and sub-machine guns (well, in theory, as giving him SMG often resulted in couple of bullets in player's back). Joined, if the player paid him.Tandi -- daughter of an elder in Shady Sands, kidnapped by Raiders. She followed the protagonist until he returned her to her father. Not very skilled in combat.Dogmeat -- Dog found in Junktown. Joined if the player's character fed him or showed up in Mad Max style leather jacket. Considered by many as one of the best NPCs in video games history, not only for his surprisingly good combat skills, but also for his lovable loyalty to the player. According to Fallout canon, Dogmeat died in Mariposa Military Base, but he can be befriended again during one of the Random Encounters in Fallout 2 and returns again as a recruitable character in Fallout 3.Tycho -- Shotgun specialist from Junktown. Joined the team to get rid of scums in his city and followed the character after the quest was finished.Katja -- member of the Followers of the Apocalypse, found in "Blades" Section of Boneyard (ruined Los Angeles). Character had to have pretty high speech skill and Charisma to make use of her talents. Her weapon of choice was spear and a pistol (and she was better at shooting than Ian)CommunitiesFallout's towns and communities are quite memorable, each displaying unique types of social organization and economic development as a response to life after a nuclear apocalypse. Some communities are more like factions that are major players in the storyline and game universe. The way each community is structured in turn affects the attitude of the town's inhabitants towards outsiders and what kind of quests the player can take on.Vault 13The Vault in which the protagonist has been raised and is compelled to leave could be considered a utopia. Compared to the rigours of the Wasteland, the vault is well-ordered, able to provide for the needs of its inhabitants, free of radiation and typically lacking in social problems. If anything, the vault dwellers have a tendency towards hostility towards the outside world, wishing to have nothing to do with it for fear of contamination. As the Vault Dweller spends more time outside the vault, the less he is able to continue to fit in to this closed society. Technology has a vital role for sustaining those who live inside the vault. Computers transmit and preserve information, and take care of essentials like water supply and food production. Every inhabitant has a role that contributes to the good of the whole under the benevolent guidance of the Overseer who provides direction. The jumpsuit, the iconic uniform of Vault 13, indicates that it is (at least in principle) a classless society.Shady SandsShady Sands wellShady Sands is a struggling agricultural community and it is generally the first settlement the player encounters on his or her travels. The community has not reached a particularly high state of technological advancement; although they farm, which provides their subsistence, they have not even heard of crop rotation. Besides farmers, the town is inhabited by a town leader, guards, and a doctor. Due to the low degree of social stratification the community appears relatively unified and harmonious. However, because of their peaceful ways and technological inadequacy, Shady Sands is quite vulnerable to outside threats. This leaves them slightly on edge when it comes to interacting with outsiders, although they are not entirely unwelcoming if one's intentions are peaceful. The player can if desired help the town deal with its two main problems: the Khan raiders and radscorpions.The RaidersNot much is known about the Khans, a clan of Raiders, as they are extremely hostile to outsiders unless they prove themselves to be as psychopathic and violent as they are themselves. Borrowing from films such as Mad Max, this group represents a regression into tribalism and lawlessness. They are led by a patriarchal leader who commands based on strength and fear. Except for a few female Raiders, women are enslaved as prostitutes, showing the contempt they have for those they capture. Instead of producing anything for themselves, the Raiders pillage from others to satisfy their wants. The interaction that the Vault Dweller can have with the Raiders is unsurprisingly limited, short of challenging the leader or wiping them out entirely.JunktownWelcome to JunktownAlthough still a relatively small town, Junktown is considerably more advanced than Shady Sands. Social differentiation is more obvious: a bar, casino, doctor, sporting bouts, trading, a hotel and so on indicate the beginnings of a capitalistic economy, particularly leisure industries. However, agriculture remains important. With increased size and prosperity also comes social problems. Killian, as mayor of the town, is struggling against the organized crime boss Gizmo as well as the gang violence of the Skullz. Junktown has something of a Wild West feel to it, showing some signs of technological advancement but still with an element of lawlessness. The player can decide to tip the balance towards lawfulness or crime, however.The HubIguana Bob, meat seller in the HubThe Hub, as suggested, is the center of trade in the region. The city is mostly under the rule of law, and its prominent bodies are various merchant guilds. These are mostly trading companies that send guarded caravans to transport goods throughout the wasteland, but also providers of services such as the Water Merchants. The Hub has a sophisticated trade in books, pharmaceuticals, weapons, loans, and other such essentials. Although The Hub still has a strong agricultural base, it has much more severe social differentiation. Besides the prosperous merchants there are also drug addicts, slum-dwellers and other such signs of class division. There is also a much more well-organized crime boss, Decker, who attempts to maintain some control over the Hub's affairs. The Hub is extremely well-policed, indicating that the rule of law is still quite strong, in order to defend the interests of the various capitalistic organizations.BoneyardSimilarly to the Hub, the Boneyard displays a considerable degree of technological advancement. it has knowledge of chemistry and smithing, and is able to grow crops hydroponically. However, it is is a police state. Surrounded by a cage, farmers are forced to work are forced to work for the benefit of the armed soldiers ruling them and the mayor, a figurehead for the oppressive social order. The Razors just outside of the city proper are a gang, but one based on mutual support rather than criminality. They wish to see the soldiers overthrown and the Boneyard freed of their tyranny. Unsurprisingly, the rulers do not view outsiders in a friendly fashion, wishing to keep things as they are and monitoring closely for signs of dissent.Followers of the ApocalypseAkin to a monastic order, the Followers wish to preserve the knowledge that has been mostly lost since the war. Their goal is primarily to spread enlightened ideas throughout the region and prevent the recurrence of such conflict. They are closely monitoring the Brotherhood, as they do not take their religion at face value. Although they have a matriarchal leadership structure, there seems to be no rigid social divisions to speak of; like Vault 13, the Children could be considered a utopian community based on the mutual pursuit of knowledge.Brotherhood of SteelThe Brotherhood's insigniaAs indicated by their ranks (knight, scribe, and paladin) the Brotherhood combine a medieval social structure with a religious fervor for technology. A militaristic order, besides preserving technology they also devote significant resources to training, weapons RD, medical research for physical enhancement, and so on. Although they are by far the most technologically advanced community in the wasteland, they jealously preserve their knowledge and do not willingly share it with others. They are also simply not interested in having dealings with outsiders except for merchants. They send the Vault Dweller on what is presumed a suicide mission if he wishes to join their order. The medievalism of the Brotherhood is reflected in its rigid command structure. The leader of the Paladin, Rhombus, and the Elders command lower ranking members under military discipline. They also have a head librarian, Vree, dedicated to the preservation of knowledge and research. The Brotherhood is a strictly regimented military organization, and this is reflected in how their base is laid out. Although they are not self-sufficient, the Brotherhood trades some of their technology in return for the necessities of life.Children of the CathedralLike the Followers, the Vault, and the Brotherhood, the Children value order highly. However, they also happen to be religious fanatics that seek to impose unity not just on their own community but also on everyone else. They have a typical religious leadership structure. This community is the most actively hostile towards the others in the region, demonstrating a medieval level of tolerance (or lack thereof) for differences of opinion.Special EncountersIn the barren wasteland the player can discover special encounters, depending on the Luck skill. These range from rare items to amusing (but useless) sequences.Bob's Used Car MartBob's Used Car MartBob has, unfortunately, had a little too much radiation for his own good. He will try and sell the player a "used car" that has gone through his patented "100 point service"; these cars are all junk and useless. But if the player explores Bob's hut they will discover two BB guns and ammo.Crashed Alien SpaceshipCrashed Alien SpaceshipHalf buried in the sand, two alien skeletons lie beside the ship. On these bodies can be found the "Alien Blaster" arguably the best weapon in the game; although it is not the strongest, it is lightweight and so is its ammo.The Giant "Three Pronged" FootprintThe Three Pronged FootprintA single large three pronged footprint imprinted in the sand. In the center is a squished mass of body-parts; on this unrecognizable body can be found "the stealthboy."The Wild BrahminWild talking BrahminA random herd of Brahmin (two-headed cows), as the player gets closer they speak phrases like: "Moo" and "Moo, I say." Amusing, but utterly useless.The Over-Turned Nuka-Cola TruckThe Nuke-a-Cola truckDepending on the Luck skill, the player can find in a crate, up to 10,765 caps (the currency of Fallout). With a low luck skill players may only find 1 cap.The Police BoxThe TardisIn a reference to the "Tardis" from "Doctor Who," as the player gets closer it disappears leaving a motion detector in it's place.Voice TalentsThe Game features the iconic voice talent of Ron Perlman as the narrator. One of Perlman's lines from the prologue became a catchphrase for the series: "War. War never changes." Many other well known actors appear in the game, such as: Clancy Brown as Rhombus, CCH Pounder as Vree, Tony Shalhoub as Aradesh, Richard Dean Anderson as Killian, Keith David as Decker and Tony Jay as The Lieutenant.Critical ReceptionAlthough Fallout came out more than a decade ago and is thus hard to find many reviews for, a Gamerankings average of 91.92% and Metacritic of 89 suggests a high degree of critical acclaim (both from a sample of 12 reviews). According to Desslock's review on Gamespot, Fallout "oozes style", is destined to become a classic, and is easily one of the best role-playing game of the past few years (8.7/10). This opinion is echoed by other gaming sites that consider Fallout a standout for RPGs in the '90s (PC Gamer 90/100, Electric Playground 90/100).Though the game received near-universal praise, one common point of criticism was leveled at the main quest, which could end the game prematurely if not completed within a certain number of days. Many reviewers found the time limit on the main quest, as well as the possibility of failing the game outright, to be unnecessarily restrictive. Due to the number of complaints, a later patch removed this time limit, allowing the player more freedom to approach the game at their own pace.AvailabilityThe original retail version of Fallout can be purchased from most major online retailers; brick-and-mortar retailers also have a Fallout Trilogy Pack that contains Fallout, Fallout 2, and Fallout Tactics.Fallout is also now available on the Gametap for free.CD Projekt's service GOG (Good Old Games), which launched in September 2008, features Fallout, as well as its sequel, as one of its launch titles.Fallout, its sequels and spin-offs, are all available on Valve's Steam service. Fallout, Fallout 2, and Fallout Tactics come in a package for $19.99, while each can be purchased individually for $9.99.SoundtrackThe original score for Fallout was written and composed by Mark Morgan.Track No.Song TitleRunning Time01Metallic Monks03.2402Desert Wind03.2003A Trader's Life04.0304The Vault of the Future04.0105Industrial Junk03.2406Moribund World03.0307Vats of Goo03.1808City of the Dead03.2409Second Chance04.0310Underground Troubles03.5311City of Lost Angels03.4612Follower's Credo02.5913Radiation Storm03.5714Acolytes of the New God03.1715Flame of the Ancient World03.0716Khans of New California03.18PC System RequirementsCPU Type: PentiumCPU Speed: 90 MHzHard Disk Space: 80 MBOS Version: 5.0RAM Required: 16 MBGraphics Type: SVGAGraphics Resolution: Multiple Resolutions</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2673">Arcanum: Of Steamworks &amp; Magick Obscura</game><game id="12134">Wasteland</game><game id="2235">Planescape: Torment</game><game id="11725">S.T.A.L.K.E.R.: Shadow of Chernobyl</game><game id="7757">Lionheart: Legacy of the Crusader</game><game id="52">Baldur's Gate</game><game id="10637">Baldur's Gate II: Shadows of Amn</game><game id="17949">The Elder Scrolls III: Tribunal</game><game id="5985">Diablo</game><game id="1119">Diablo II</game><game id="20803">Diablo III</game><game id="12158">MetalHeart: Replicants Rampage</game><game id="23073">The Bibleman</game><game id="11424">The Fall: Last Days of Gaia</game><game id="13246">Project Overkill</game><game id="18067">Alien Earth</game><game id="21544">Hinterland</game><game id="19331">Bad Blood</game><game id="10967">S2: Silent Storm</game><game id="5741">Crusader: No Remorse</game><game id="17533">Deus Ex</game><game id="20">Burntime</game><game id="9442">Roadwar 2000</game><game id="3634">Redmoon</game><game id="16603">Restricted Area</game><game id="32717">HellMOO</game><game id="21194">The Age of Decadence</game><game id="5110">ōdi∙um</game><game id="21198">Shadowrun</game><game id="17437">Evil Islands: Curse of the Lost Soul</game><game id="36857">Krater</game><game id="36256">Cobalt</game><game id="37174">Fallout</game><game id="37721">Wasteland 2</game><game id="10075">Fountain of Dreams</game><game id="39681">Neo Scavenger</game><game id="39775">Project Eternity</game><game id="40588">Eschalon: Book III</game><game id="37894">Shadowrun Returns</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15693/625333-1212697328_fallout_1_cover_1_.jpg</image></root>