<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11701</id><name>Phantasy Star Online Episode I &amp; II Plus</name><description> Differences Between Phantasy Star Online I  II and the Plus Version Phantasy Star Online Episode I  II Plus was released with various bug fixes and hack protections that were absent in the      regular Phantasy Star Online Episode I  II. The Plus version also includes exclusive content on the disc, which beforehand was only available as a    download. Also, the East Tower and West Tower quests for Episode II were added to the Plus Version's offline Episode II mode. In the regular version, those quests were only available online.Additions to Phantasy Star Online Episode 1 and 2 Plus 'Central Dome Fire Swirl' quest is available offline in Episode I. The GBA downloads in 'The Fake in Yellow' in Episode I are now available offline. 'Seat of the Heart','East Tower' and 'West Tower' are available offline in Episode II. The Episode II Challenge Mode is now available offline. Users who have the original release of      Phantasy Star Episode I  II can only play Episode II Challenge Mode while online.  CompatibilityAdditionally, the Plus version does not require you to transfer over your character data to the game unlike with the original      Phantasy Star Online and  Phantasy Star Online Version 2 (When playing Version 2 your character data had to be transferred over and you could no longer use those characters to play the original      Phantasy Star Online). A player can use the same character data to play both the original PSO Episode I  II and the Plus version. This is because there were no gameplay or game balance changes made to the Plus version.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12245">Gauntlet Legends</game><game id="13214">Monster Hunter</game><game id="17843">Phantasy Star Online: Blue Burst</game><game id="27657">Phantasy Star Portable 2</game><game id="32497">Phantasy Star Portable 2 Infinity</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2478682-box_psoe12p.png</image></root>