<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11789</id><name>Dance Dance Revolution 5thMIX</name><description>OverviewDance Dace Revolution 5thMIX (usually shortened to DDR 5th Mix) is the fifth game in the Dance Dance Revolution franchise. It introduces "long version" songs to the series, and is the last arcade release until SuperNOVA to feature characters dancing in the background."Long Version" Songs"Long version" songs are marked on the song selection screen."Long version" songs are twice as long as standard ones, and provide players an extra test of endurance. To compensate for the extra length, when a player selects ones of these songs it counts as two stages. This is especially useful information when playing at the arcade since it gives you one less song per play.This feature has not appeared in any future games in the series.Home/Arcade LinkIf you have a memory card with save data from the Playstation version of the game or previous games in the series that shares songs in the arcade version, some arcade machines have slots in which you can use your memory card. This can be used to save high scores or use custom charts in the arcade.SoundtrackThe arcade and home versions have different songs available.Arcade (Japan)Song TitleArtistBasicTrickManiac.59DJ Taka4671,2,3,4,007Ni-Ni13617才Bambee256AbsoluteDJ Taka358AbyssDJ Taka257Afronova Primeval8-Bit469Against All Odds (Definitive Mix)Dejavu featuring Tasmin357B4UNaoki458B4U Glorious Style [Long Version]Naoki469Baby Baby Gimme Your LoveDivas136Be TogetherNi-Ni357Boom Boom Dollar (K.O.G G3 Mix)King Kong  D. Jungle Girls578Boys (Euro Mix)Smile.dk468Brilliant 2UNaoki456Broken My HeartNaoki feat. Paula Terry459Bumble BeeBambee357Burnin' the FloorNaoki467ButterflySmile.dk345CafeD.D.Sound357Can't Stop Fallin' in LoveNaoki358Can't Stop Fallin' in Love (Speed Mix)Naoki469Captain Jack (Grandale Remix)Captain Jack479Cat's Eye (Ventura Mix)E-Rotic358Celebrate NiteN.M.R467Conga FeelingVivian358Dam DariramJoga468Dam Dariram (KCP Mix)Joga467Dancing All AloneSmile.dk257Dead EndN  S579DiveBe For U458Do Me (H.I.G.E.O. Mix)Mustache Men369Don't Stop! (AMD 2nd Mix)Dr. Vive feat. JP Miles457Dream a DreamCaptain Jack467Drop OutNW260578Dub-I-DubMe  My468DXY!Taq468Dynamite RaveNaoki579Dynamite Rave (Long ver.) [Long Version]Naoki458Eat You UpAngie Gold256EcstasyD-Complex467Electro Tuned (The SubS Mix)Taq569End of the CenturyNo.9478Era (NostalMix)Taq368Furuhata's ThemeC. J. Crew feat. Sedge479Get Me in Your Sight (AMD Cancun Mix)Symphonic Defoggers with 1479368Gimme Gimme GimmeE-Rotic346Gotcha (The Theme from Starsky  Hutch)Andy G's Magic Disco Machine257Have You Never Been Mellow (MM Groovin' Mix)The Olivia Project357Healing VisionDe-Sire368Hero (Happy Grandale Mix)Papaya467Hero (KCP Discotique Mix)Papaya346HigherNM feat. Sunny356HolicTaq468Hot Limit [Long Version]John Desire368Hypnotic CrisisBlue Destroyers569HysteriaNaoki 190468I Believe in MiraclesHi-Rise568I Was the OneGood-Cool357If You Were HereJennifer567If You Were Here (B4 Za Beat Mix)Jennifer468In the Heat of the NightE-Rotic357InsertionNaoki Underground469It Only Takes a Minute (Extended Mix)Tavares356Kick the CanBus Stop367La SenoritaCaptain.T467Leading CyberDJ Taka579Let the Beat Hit Em!Stone Bros.367Let's Talk It OverShin Murayama feat. Argie Phine256Love Again Tonight (For Melissa Mix)Naoki feat. Paula Terry467Lupin the 3rd '78Ventura369Luv to Me (AMD Mix)DJ Kazu feat. Tiger Yamato478Make Your MoveGood-Cool feat. JP Miles467祭 JapanRe-Venge459Moonlight Shadow (New Vocal Version)Missing Heart456Movin On (Extended Moon Mix)Ellen Gee358Mr. T. (Take Me Higher)Risky Men feat. Asuka. M357MusicHabegale467My Generation (Fat Beat Mix)Captain Jack456My Summer LoveMitsu-O! with Geila369Na-NaBus Stop358Never Ending StoryDJ-AC-DC367Never Gonna Make (Factory Dance Team Mix)Morgana357Never Let You DownGood-Cool feat. JP Miles357Night in MotionCubic22367おどるポンポコリンCaptain Jack147No Limit (RM Remix)2 Unlimited469One Two (Little Bitch)Bus Stop467Only YouCaptain Jack247Oops!... I Did It Again (Fired Up Mix) [Long Version]Rochelle257Orion.78 (AMEuro-Mix)Re-Venge359Paranoia EternalSTM 200569Paranoia Evolution200678Paranoia Max (Dirty Mix)190688Petit LoveSmile.dk367Pink DinosaurPapaya457Radical FaithTaq468Remember YouNM feat. Julie135Rhythm and Police (K.O.G. G3 Mix)CJ Crew feat. Christian D469Right NowAtomic Kitten356ロマンスの神様Judy Crystal359サナ・モレッテ・ネ・エンテTogo Project feat. Sana258Sexy PlanetCrystal Aliens567Shake Your BootyKC  The Sunshine Band347Shooting StarBang457Sky HighLucyfer468Still in My HeartNaoki467Stomp to My BeatJS16567Super StarDJ.Rich feat. Tail Bros.568Swing ItBus Stop346Synchronized Love (Red Monster Hyper Mix)Joe Rinoie458Test My BestE-Rotic347The 7 JumpKen D246The CubeDJ Suwami467The Twist (Double Pump Mix)Liberty All Staz357Theme from Enter the Dragon (Revival 2001 Mix)B3-Project468Tribal Dance (Almighty Mix)2 Unlimited468Trip Machine ClimaxDe-Sire579Walkie TalkieKing Kong  D. Jungle Girls357Wild RushFactor-X456Wonda (Speed K Mix)MM469XanaduOlivia Project146Young ForeverRebecca357Playstation (Japan)Song TitleArtistBasicTrickManiac17才Bambee256AbsoluteDJ Taka358AbyssDJ Taka257Afronova Primeval8 Bit469Against All Odds (Definitive Mix)Deja Vu featuring Tasmin357B4U Glorious Style [Long Version]Naoki469Be TogetherNi-Ni357Broken My HeartNaoki feat. Paula Terry459Can't Stop Falln' in Love (Speed Mix)Naoki469Dancing All AloneSmile.dk257DiveBe For U458Dive (More Deep  Deeper Style)Be For U357Do It RightSota feat. Ebony Fay457DXY!TaQ468Dynamite Rave (Long ver.) [Long Version]Naoki458EcstasyD-Complex467Electro Tuned (The SubS Mix)TaQ569Healing VisionDe-Sire368Healing Vision (Angelic Mix)2MB579Hot Limit [Long Version]John Desire368I Was the OneGood-Cool357InsertionNaoki Underground469Look to the SkySystem S.F. feat. Anna357祭 JapanRe-Venge459Moonlight Shadow (New Vocal Version)Missing Heart456Movin On (Extended Moon Mix)Ellen Gee358Mr. T. (Take Me Higher)Risky Men feat. Asuka M357My Generation (Fat Beat Mix)Captain Jack456Never Ending JourneyDJ-AC-DC367No Limit (RM Remix)2 Unlimited469Nori Nori NoriJudy Crystal357おどるポンポコリンCaptain Jack147On the JazzJonny Dynamite!257Oops!... I Dd It Again (Fire Up Mix) [Long Version]Rochelle257Paranoia EternalSTM 200569Radical FaithTaQ468Remember YouNM feat. Julie135Right NowAtomic Kitten356ロマンスの神様Judy Crystal359サナ・モレッテ・ネ・エンテTogo Project feat. Sana258Still in My HeartNaoki467Swing ItBus Stop346Test My BestE-Rotic347The Centre of the Heart (Stonebridge ClubMix)Roxette257The CubeDJ Suwami467The Twist (Double Pump Mix)Liberty All Staz357Tribal Dance (Almighty Mix)2 Unlimited468</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7010">StepMania</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5589/863608-ddr_5th_mix_cover.jpg</image></root>