<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11796</id><name>Star Trek: Armada II</name><description>OverviewStar Trek: Armada II is the sequel to Star Trek: Armada, and picks up shortly after the first game. Like its predecessor, Armada II is a real-time strategy game set in the Star Trek universe. The story concerns the Borg's development of a weapon that is capable of assimilating entire planets, and their plan to use it against the races of the Alpha Quadrant.The game introduces new two new resources to the original game's dynamic (metal and latinum) and two new races (The Cardassian Union and Species 8472). The four races from the previous game ( The Federation, Klingon Empire, Romulan Star Empire, Borg Collective) get many new vessels and abilities, some of which were not seen in the Television series' and were created for this game. However, unlike the first game, only three of the races have playable campaigns (Federation, Klingon and Borg - in that order).  The remaining three races are only available in multiplayer and skirmish matches.Differences from the TV SeriesFor the sake of balance, and to make the game more playable and enjoyable, many departures from the series and the canon universe have been made, especially in regard to the strengths and weaknesses of many of the vessels, as well as the overall size of every entity in the game. Perhaps the most obvious is in regard to the Borg and Species 8472 factions. The overall strength and power of the vessels from these two factions has been greatly reduced in the game. This is obviously for balance reasons, however it is noticeable. For example, the crew compliment of Borg vessels has been greatly reduced in comparison to the TV shows.The game features several vessels of different types that are taken from designs seen in other games or that were created specifically for this game. This was a further attempt by developer Mad Doc Software to balance the 6 different factions and to fill vessel-type gaps of some of the races as seen in the series canon.Requirements    * Windows 95/98/2000/Me operating system * Pentium II 300MHz or equivalent     * 64MB RAM * DirectX 8.0a compliant 8MB video card  * 4X CD-ROM drive</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9115">Sins of a Solar Empire</game><game id="13062">StarCraft</game><game id="17353">Star Wars: Force Commander</game><game id="7756">Star Trek: Armada</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4656/893769-292px_armada_2_cover.jpg</image></root>