<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>11958</id><name>EOE: Eve of Extinction</name><description>Overview Josh in action! You play as a character called Josh Calloway who has a weapon called a “Legacy”. This weapon can take many forms, but you start off with just two; a Sword and Rod. As you progress through the game you will battle various bosses who have their own legacy weapons. Defeating these bosses rewards you with their weapon. This means that you have the ability to switch to that weapon, even in the middle of a fight, allowing you to string large combos together. Contained inside your “Legacy” is the transformed soul of Josh’s girlfriend. According to the Wisdom Corporation (who created the weapon, and also act as the big evil corporation that your character is aiming to bring down) this is supposedly what gives the weapon it’s power, by fusing a human soul with a rare sort of metal found only in the lost city of Atlantis. The problems with the game are mainly down to slight technical issues, like a terrible camera which is rarely in the right position and can’t be controlled manually either. Also, fighting large groups ends up a bit like a Jet Li martial arts movie, in that whilst you fight one baddie the rest sort of dance around you waiting for there turn. Weapons Sword: Fire Element Rod: Lightning Element Dual Katars: Water Element Snake Sword: Time Element Crossbow: Life Element Giant Axe: Gravity Element Broadsword: Earth Element Boomerang: Wind Element Tonfas: Light ElementTwin Blades: No Known Element</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12411">Soulcalibur</game><game id="11822">Soulcalibur II</game><game id="9855">Soulcalibur III</game><game id="20678">Soulcalibur IV</game><game id="11945">Soulcalibur Legends</game><game id="7570">Enter the Matrix</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2314063-box_eoe.png</image></root>