<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12</id><name>Blade &amp; Sword</name><description>OverviewThis game was released in 2003 developed by Pixel Studio and published by Whiptail Interactive. It is an isometric action RPG game like Diablo and also has a few extra mechanics thrown in as well.GameplayThe game plays like Diablo, as an action RPG whereby the player can walk and run around open areas and hack and slash enemies that they encounter.ClassesThere are 3 classes that can be chosen from the game.BarbarianSwordsmanDual-Wielding FighterBarbarian - He is the strongest of the 3 characters who carries a giant sword to swing at his enemies.Swordsman - The balanced character who is strong with his sword and also quick with his slashes and his speedDual Wielding Fighter - She is the faster character of the group who uses daggers to make quick work with the enemies. She is weak with her attacks but makes up for it in attack speed, an additional kick skill and can run much faster then the other characterSkillsAs the player levels up, each character has their own skill tree from different disciplines. They are:DestructionComboChiImpactSystem RequirementsWindows 98/ME/2000/XPPentium II 266MHz128MB RAM8MB Video Memory1.4GB HDD SpaceMicrosoft DirectX 8.1</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15589">Diablo II: Lord of Destruction</game><game id="5985">Diablo</game><game id="5776">Legend of the North: Konung</game><game id="3549">Konung 2: Blood of Titans</game><game id="31832">Konung III: Ties of the Dynasty</game><game id="1119">Diablo II</game><game id="2059">Dungeon Siege</game><game id="11620">Dungeon Siege: Throne of Agony</game><game id="13293">Dungeon Siege: Legends of Aranna</game><game id="3958">Nox</game><game id="5153">Sacred</game><game id="1714">Throne of Darkness</game><game id="52">Baldur's Gate</game><game id="10637">Baldur's Gate II: Shadows of Amn</game><game id="13091">Baldur's Gate: Dark Alliance</game><game id="6795">Baldur's Gate II: Throne of Bhaal</game><game id="12107">Baldur's Gate: Dark Alliance II</game><game id="7392">Baldur's Gate: Tales of the Sword Coast</game><game id="7386">Divine Divinity</game><game id="21229">Mythos</game><game id="9789">Beyond Divinity</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/238/707774-blade_and_sword.jpg</image></root>