<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12022</id><name>Superfrog</name><description>OverviewA rival to Mario and Sonic, Superfrog was the Amiga's very own icon. Fast, slick and loveable, the game was a fantastic looking side scrolling platformer with 4 levels in each of the 6 worlds to complete.GameplayEnd of level slot machine.Similar to Mario and sonic, there is lots of fast running and high jumping, and you collect coins to receive an extra life when you reached 100 coins.Completed Level MinigameAt the end of each level you are awarded credits based on: the time remaining, amount of fruit collected and the number of coins collected. You need to choose whether to gamble these credits using the Superfrog slot machine minigame, or to convert them directly into points and move on to the next level. Prizes on the slot machine include: points, extra lives, more credits and current level codes.StorySuperfrog is a Team 17 made game that featured a frog with super powers. Superfrog was not always a frog however. He started life as a charming prince living in he charming castle with his charming girlfriend. However a witch then decided in stereotypical fashion to turn the prince into a frog and escape with his girlfriend. Although initially the prince quite enjoyed life as a frog he slowly, over time grew to miss his girlfriend and decided he wanted her back.As he decided this, an elixir of power (Lucozade) floated down the stream he was living in and upon drinking it, imbued him with super powers; thus, Superfrog was born. The game details the adventure to recapture his princess back.The game is split over six worlds with 4 stages in each.End of Game RankingsSuperfrog also includes a rating system that give you a rank when you finish the game. Your rank is determined by how many points you scored throughout the whole playthrough.Mr PloppyFrog SpawnTadpole Grade 3Tadpole Grade 2Tadpole Grade 1Rookie Frog Grade 3Rookie Frog Grade 2Rookie Frog Grade 1Frog with a PurposeFrog with a MissionChuffed FrogFrog VeteranMean Green MachineSuper Frog Grade 3Super Frog Grade 2Super Frog Grade 1In Game AdvertisementsOne of the most interesting features of Superfrog was that is featured heavy product placement of the drink Lucozade. The drink is what initially gives Superfrog his powers and is littered throughout all the levels as a health pickup. This is yet more evidence that Team 17 were trailblazers in the world of in game advertising.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10299">Super Mario Bros. 3</game><game id="7406">Super Mario Bros. 2</game><game id="2465">Sonic the Hedgehog</game><game id="7634">Jazz Jackrabbit</game><game id="12488">Jill of the Jungle: The Complete Trilogy</game><game id="798">Math Rescue</game><game id="1796">Word Rescue</game><game id="13382">Fire &amp; Ice</game><game id="11100">Pac-in-Time</game><game id="31282">Jump Jack</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/7/73970/1410650-superfrog_front.jpg</image></root>