<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12071</id><name>Digimon Digital Card Battle</name><description>OverviewDigimon: Digital Card Battle was released in 2001 for the PlayStation and allowed gamers to play the Digimon Trading Card game on their consoles. Each player had a deck of 30 cards, containing Digimon, support and digivolution cards. In-training and baby Digimon cards were not present in the game. GameplayIn Digital Card Battle, players can summon rookie Digimon to the playing field and attack one time per turn during their battle phase. In order to digivolve your DIgimon, players must sacrifice Digimon cards from their hand (meaning cards of actual Digimon, not support cards) in order to build up their "Digivolution Points". Once enough points are earned, a player can digivolve their Digimon during the digivolution phase of their turn.Partner CardsSticking to classic Digimon tradition is partners. Since this is a card game, you chose from one of the three following partners:VeemonArmadillomonHawkmonYour partner card is special and gains experience as you play through the game. In time, they will be able to armor digivolve, such as Veemon armor digivolving to Flamedramon. Partners can also have their attributes boosted as well with Digi-Parts. This will allow players to boost their partners HP, Attack Power, or Support Effects.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="13">Card Game</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3483">Yu-Gi-Oh! Power of Chaos: Joey the Passion</game><game id="17546">Yu-Gi-Oh! The Dawn of Destiny</game><game id="2615">Yu-Gi-Oh! Power of Chaos: Kaiba the Revenge</game><game id="223">Yu-Gi-Oh! Forbidden Memories</game><game id="18673">Pokémon Yellow: Special Pikachu Edition</game><game id="32291">Digimon Battle</game><game id="27976">Koto Battle: Tengai no Moribito</game><game id="13974">Pokémon Mystery Dungeon: Blue/Red Rescue Team</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2375785-box_ddcb.png</image></root>