<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12101</id><name>Dynasty Warriors 4: Empires</name><description>OverviewDynasty Warriors 4: Empires is a turn-based strategy game where you fight against other forces to create your own empire with a general from the semi-legendary romance of the three kingdoms period of Chinese history, or a player created character. You can create alliances with other up-coming empires and trade items, along with fighting them for their territory and capturing their soldiers, opening the possibility of hiring them as Generals or Lieutenants, or just setting them free.CampaignGuan Yu Taking over an Enemy baseYou start off the game by selecting if you want a pre-made team, (like Xiahou Dun, Xiahou Yuan and Cao Cao or Liu Bei, Guan Yu and Zhang Fei), or if you would like to make your own. After selecting your team, you pick your starting land and from then on, you battle with other empires for that land and the resources that land has, like Gold and Items. After each turn, your officers will propose offers, such as restoring 1000 troops to each officer or fire arrows, replacing your archers’ normal arrows with more damaging fire arrows. Other land rulers can attack your lands and you will be given the option to either defend or attack, although a failure to defend successfully (or at all) will result in the targeted land being lost, along with the gold and items received from it.CharactersThese are the Characters that Are in DW4: Empires.(Characters are in alphabetical order)Cao CaoCao RenDa QiaoDian WeiDiao ChanDong ZhouGan NingGuan YuHuang GaiHuang ZhongJiang WeiLiu BeiLu BuLu MengLu XunMa ChaoPang TongSima YiSun CeSun JianSun ShangxiangSun QuanTaishi CiWei YanXiahou DunXiahou YuanXiao QiaoXu HuangXu ZhuYuan ShaoYue YingZhang FeiZhang HeZhang JiaoZhang LiaoZhao YunZhen JiZhou TaiZhou YuZhu RongZhuge Liang Character CustomizationCharacter CustomizationYou can create your own general with a weapon from anyone of the characters in the game, Make up there name, the way they look, there voice and there movement and there special skill likeAmbush, were that general can call an ambush on some enemy soldiers in a battle at any time.Proposal OffersThese are broken down into seven different categories.Product DevolpmentCommerce- Cost: NonePromote a regions industry, acquire 300 gold.Restructure- Cost: 1500~Cancel current production, and begin production of a new product.Expand- Cost: 2000Begin production of a new product in addition to the production of current productions.Accelerate- Cost: 1000Shorten production time by 2 turns.Refine- Cost: 850~Raise the level of a product.Perfect- Cost: 2500Substantially raise the level of a product.Mass produce- Cost: 1000Speed up the production of an entire regions products so that those products can be used in the next battle.Officer AffairsTutor - Cost: 3000Raise the level of one of your officers.Local Search -Cost: 1700~Search your area for free officers.Wide search- Cost: 2200~Search the entire country for free officers.Recruit - Cost: 2000Recruit talent and choose an officer to employ.Bribe - Cost: 3200~Present a product to another force in order to convince an officer to join you. You cannot select which specific officer will join you.Entice - Cost: 6000Present a product to a specific officer from another force to convince him to join you. once completed, A new product will be developed.Promote- Cost: 1000Elect an officer as Grand General or Strategist.DiplomacyTrade- Cost: NoneEncourage an areas commerce, acquire gold.Swap- Cost: 500Exchange production facilities with another ruler.Send Craftsmen - Cost: 1000Support production of another force and form an alliance for 3 turns.Short Alliance- Cost: 400Form an alliance for 4 turns.Long Alliance - Cost: 1000Form an alliance for 8 turns.Joint attack -Cost: 1000Receive ally reinforcements in the next battle.Threaten- Cost: NoneCoerce a force to enter into an alliance and make them pay gold. Alliance lasts for 4 turns.Battle TacticsLt. Skill- Cost: 500Allow Lieutenants to use skills in battle.Hinder- Cost: 400Delay enemy reinforcements.Fast Heal - Cost: 600Hasten the arrival of reinforcements.Incite - Cost: 500During an invasion, friendly local troops will appear to assist you.Blockade - Cost: 800Hinder the arrival of enemy assistance.Defection- Cost: 2000Force the defection of an enemy officer.Take Over- Cost: 1200Begin the battle with half of the bases already secured.Heal ForcesHeal 1- Cost: 200Restore 1000 troops to an officers forces.Heal 2- Cost: 1000Completely restore an officers forces.Triple Heal- Cost: 800Restore 1000 troops to up too 3 of your officers' forces.Heal All 1- Cost: 300Restore 500 troops to all of your officers' forces.Heal All 2- Cost: 2000Restore 1000 troops to all of your officers' forces.Heal All 3 - Cost: 3000Restore 2000 troops to all of your officers' forces.Heal All 4- Cost: 4000Completely restore all forces.Reinforce MilitaryFire Arrows- Cost: 200Equip all archers with fire arrows.Sorcerers - Cost: 300Sorcerers will join your forces.Shamans- Cost: 400Shamans will join your forces.Extend - Cost: 400Increase time limit by 10 minutes.Points Increase- Cost: 600Player controlled officer's point score is doubled.Wood Ox - Cost: 500The wood ox is added to your forces.Juggernaut - Cost: 500Juggernauts are added to your forces.GovernmentSurvey - Cost: 300Conduct a survey to hear the people's needs.Holiday -Cost:300Delay production by one turn to give people a holiday.Forced Labor - Cost: NoneForce people to harder labor to speed up production by one turn.Release- Cost: 300Allow troops to return home with a pension. Forces are reduced by 20%.Emergency Tax - Cost: NoneCollect 500 gold from the people in your kingdom.Conscription - Cost: 1500Conduct a draft. All officers' forces are increased by 2000 troops.Philanthropy - Cost: 2000Donate gold to the people of your kingdom.Grand Tax -Cost: NoneCollect 1000 (Area population x 50)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20531">Kingdom Under Fire: Circle of Doom</game><game id="20678">Soulcalibur IV</game><game id="21972">Samurai Warriors 2: Empires</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2126438-box_dw4e.png</image></root>