<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12108</id><name>Mad Maestro!</name><description>Overview  GameplayMad Maestro is a music/rhythm game made by Eidos under the company name Fresh Games. The game is based to timed button presses on the PS2 controler, and also the sensitivity of the button presses. You as the conductor must press the button according to the pressure and time. The pressure levels are Light, Medium and Hard. There were squeals to this game released in japan under the name of "Let's Bravo Music". In Japan they have also released an optional Baton attachment to give you a more conductor like experience.  PlotTakt and the "Valkyries"    Like most quirky Japanese rhythm games, the story of Mad Maestro is fairly nuts. You play as a young aspiring conductor named Takt as a fairy named Symphony leads him and his band on a quest to save the town concert hall from being demolished. Somehow, UFOs are involved.   Gameplay  In Mad Maestro you are presented the task of playing classical music. The beat is displated by four dots that show up in the middle of the screen and around the edges are colours. You are aiming to hit the glowing dot while it is directly in the middle of the coloured dots. The colours represent with how much pressure you are to press the buttons on the controller, or if you imported the baton attachment how hard you should move the baton. Blue is for pressing the button lightly, green is for medium, and red to for pressing it as hard as you can.   You get more points and a better upgrade to your meter if you press it just enough before it would count as another colour. So if you are pressing lightly for blue there are two bars on the trophy icon and if you hit the button so that both blue lines show up just before it would hit green then you will get maximum points.   As tempo changes in songs the distance between each dot will get bigger or smaller and this can get tricky in some songs since the tempo changes frequently. The bar at the right tells you how close you are to failing and how you are doing overall. When the bar fills up and turns gold that means you are doing very well but if you miss a couple of notes in a row or you are not hitting with the right pressure the bar will turn to black. While the bar is black/dark purple you have to hit a couple notes perfectly or very good in a row to get it back to gold. If you finish a song with a black/dark purple bar you will fail the song.   The background will change depending on the colour of the bar. When you first start off the song the background will be normal but when you get into gold it will change into a happier tone and it looks like everything is going to plan. When the bar is changed to black/dark purple then the background will changes to a much darker tone and everything will be in chaos in the background.  Track ListingHungarian Dance No. 6 in D Major -  Johannes  BrahmsHungarian Dance No.5 in G Minor -  Johannes BrahmsSlavic Dance No. 7  - Antonin DvorakThunder and Lightning -  Johannes Brahms the SecondFinale from Carnival of the Animals -  Camille Saint-SaensThe Marriage of Figaro -  Wolfgang Amadeus MozartScene from Swan Lake -  Piotr TchaikovskyToreador Song from Carmen -  George BizetBaba Yaga's Hut from Pictures at an Exhibition -  Modeste Mussorgaky9th Symphony 4th Movement -  Ludwig van BeethovenEntry of the Gladiators -  Julius FucikMarche Militaire -  Franz SchubertMarch from The Nutcracker -  Piotr TchaikovskyTrepak from The Nutcracker -  Piotr Tchaikovsky40th Symphony K550 1st Movement -  Wolfgang Amadeus MozartOrpheus in the Underworld Overture -  Jacques OffenbachFlight of the Valkyries from The Valkyrie -  Richard Wagner Night on Bald Mountain -  Modeste MussorgskyDance of the Four Swans from Swan Lake -  Piotr TchaikovskyMorning from The Pier Gynt Suite -  Edvard GriegWilliam Tell Overture -  Gioachino RossiniRakoczi March -  Hector BerlinzCsikos Post - Hermann NeckeToy Symphony -  Leopold MozartEine Kleine Nacht Musik -  Wolfgang Amadeus MozartDance of the Reed Flutes from The Nutcracker -  Piotr TchaikovskyAlgerian Suite from French Military March Music -  Camille Saint SaensFlight of the Bumblebee -  Nikolai RImsky KorsakovBallet of  the Uncharted Chicks from Pictures of an Exhibition -  Modeste MussorgskyDivertimento No.1 in E flat Major K113 -  Wolfgang Amadeus MozartL'Arlesienne suite no. 2 from Farandole -  George BizetHall of the Mountain King from The Pier Gynt Suite</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6311">Guitar Hero</game><game id="9860">Rock Band</game><game id="18360">PaRappa the Rapper</game><game id="7466">Space Channel 5</game><game id="21655">pop'n music</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2303978-box_mmae.png</image></root>