<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12139</id><name>Star Wars: Shadows of the Empire</name><description>Overview   Dash Rendar, the game's protagonist.     Star Wars: Shadows of the Empire is a hybrid third-person shooter and flight combat game developed and published by                                                LucasArts for the                                               Nintendo 64 and                                             PC. The player controls the mercenary                                              Dash Rendar as he participates in the Battle of                                            Hoth (during the events of                                           Star Wars: Episode V - The Empire Strikes Back), attempts to rescue the frozen                                          Han Solo from                                         Boba Fett, recovers secret Imperial plans for the second Death Star (with help from                                        Luke Skywalker), and rescues                                       Princess Leia from the game's antagonist (and head of the Black Sun crime syndicate)                                      Prince Xizor.  The game is part of the Expanded Universe multimedia project, Star Wars: Shadows of the Empire. (Which also consisted of an original novel, comic book, and toys). It was first released for the Nintendo 64 shortly after the console's release. It was released on the PC a year later, replacing the use of still images for cutscenes with rendered animated cutscenes (and voiceovers). The game features an orchestral soundtrack, including                                                  John Williams's iconic themes from the original                                    Star Wars trilogy. However, the game also makes use of the officially licensed soundtrack, created by composer                                                  Joel McNeely.  Gameplay Star Wars: Shadows of the Empire tackles many different forms of gameplay. These include third-person shooter/platforming levels, maintaining turrets on his ship (the Outrider) in an          on-rails sequence, and total-control vehicle levels. Only the final level switches between different forms of gameplay mid-game.  Shooter/Platforming Levels In most levels, the player controls Dash Rendar himself, running around and gunning stormtroppers, droids, and other enemies. The player can choose between third-person and limited first-person views. Dash uses a variety of weapons (though primarily his Laser Blaster, which has infinite ammo), including seeker missiles, flamethrowers, pulse cannons, stunners, and disruptors. In later levels, Dash obtains a rechargable         jetpack, which helps him fly over difficult platforming areas.  The Shooter/Platforming levels and the Swoop Bike level contain  "challenge points" which are scattered throughout the level, seen in the  form of a rotating chrome      Rebel Alliance  emblem. These are often put in hard-to-reach areas, encouraging the  player to explore the vast levels. Collecting all of them in certain  difficulty levels will allow certain codes and privileges to be triggered, including gaining all weapons and invincibility, changing to an    X-Wing or   TIE Fighter in the final level, and allowing  wampas to fight for you in the second level. On-Rails Turret Levels In some levels, the Outrider is piloted by Dash's robotic co-pilot,        Leebo, as Dash maintains the ship's guns. Hazards, such as asteroids and enemy ships, must be blasted before they damage the ship. Flight Levels There are three levels in which Dash maintains full control of a vehicle: the beginning of the game (where he pilots a       Snowspeeder), the middle of the game (where he controls a Swoop Bike), and the end of the game (where he pilots the Outrider). Levels  The game features ten levels split into four parts.Part I - The Battle of Hoth  Battle of Hoth - Dash arrives on Hoth with a shipment to the rebels, and Han Solo convinces him to join                             Rogue Squadron. Dash must control a                            Snowspeeder and take out probe droids and Imperial walkers.Escape From Echo Base - As the Imperial forces take over Echo Base, Dash must find his way to his ship, the Outrider, while facing                          stormtroopers, probe droids,                         wampas, and eventually an                           AT-ST walker.The Asteroid Field - Dash and his robotic copilot,                        Leebo, may have escaped Hoth, but they manage to fly towards a                       Star Destroyer in the middle of an  asteroid field. Dash must control the Outrider's turrets, shooting                     TIE Fighters and                    TIE Bombers as well as asteroids.   Part II - In Search of Boba Fett  Ord Mantell Junkyard - In order for Dash to find Boba Fett, who is keeping a frozen Han Solo, he must find one of Fett's rival bounty hunters and rogue assassin droid                   IG-88. Dash must ride hovertrains (and battle drones while jumping between trains) over to IG-88's location, and then battle him.Gall Spaceport - Dash finds out that Fett is hiding on an Imperial moon base. To avoid detection, he must hide the Outrider in a gorge and sneak in on foot to find him. Gall Spaceport is the longest stage in the game, taking over a half and hour to complete.   Part III - Hunting the Assassins  Mos Eisley and Beggar's Canyon -                               Jabba the Hutt, under orders from Prince Xizor, sends a group of swoop bikers to                                Obi-Wan Kenobi's old home, where Luke Skywalker is training. Dash must control a swoop bike and take out the bikers before they reach Luke.Imperial Freighter Suprosa - Luke informs Dash of an Imperial Freighter supposedly carrying secret Imperial construction plans. Dash must infiltrate it and recover the plans.Part IV - Lair of the Dark Prince The Sewers of Imperial City - The Outrider and the                Millenium Falcon have assembled in the sewers underneath the  Imperial City, so they can rescue Princess Leia and blow up Prince Xizor's palace. Dash must navigate through the swears underneath the city, eventually battling a giant beast.Xizor's Palace - As Dash enters the palace, he must battle droids and guards so he can plant pulse bombs on a central structure. Before you escape from the palace, Dash must face Xizor's Gladiator Droid.The Skyhook Battle - Xizor flees to his space station, Skyhook. Dash must fly there and destroy its reactor core, where an epic space battle ensues. The level has two parts: a gunner part (similar to The Asteroid Field) and a total flight control part (similar to Battle of Hoth).</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/118/610322-star_wars___shadows_of_the_empire_coverart.png</image></root>