<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1223</id><name>Mega Man 5</name><description>OverviewMega Man 5 is the fifth game in the Mega Man series. It was released for the NES in December of 1992. It is not to be confused with the Game Boy game, Mega Man V. It is the first game in the series to feature the robot bird, Beat.StoryMega Man only gets to rest for a short period of time, as after a brief period of peace in the year 20XX, disaster strikes when an army, which appears to be lead by Proto Man, is causing chaos worldwide. Not soon after this begins, Dr. Light goes missing, allegedly being kidnapped by the rogue Proto Man. The only signs are a note, and Protoman's signature yellow scarf. Awestruck that his older brother would do such a thing, Mega Man sets off once again to save the world.He's not alone however, as his new ally, Dr. Cossack, has upgraded his mega buster, and created a new robot pal for him, a little bird named Beat. Dr. Cossack aids Mega Man throughout 5, as Dr.Light is missing.Mega Man sets off, once again defeating eight robot masters. He gains access to Proto Man's base, he encounters Proto Man - but wait! - The REAL Proto Man arrives on scene, and defeats this imposter, Dark Man! Mega Man defeats Dark Man, and then goes after his creator and Mega Man's eternal nemesis, Dr. Wily. He finds and defeats Wily, saving Dr.Light. Their reunion is cut short when the ceiling collapses, and is just about to crush them all, Mega Man supporting it as best he can. Once again, Proto Man comes to the rescue, throwing off the ceiling. Everyone, including Dr. Wily, gets away.Robot MastersGravity ManGravity ManWeapon: Gravity HoldWeakness: Star CrashWave ManWave ManWeapon: Water WaveWeakness: Charge KickStone ManStone ManWeapon: Power StoneWeakness: Napalm BombGyro ManGyro ManWeapon: Gyro AttackWeakness: Gravity HoldStar ManStar ManWeapon: Star CrashWeakness: Water WaveCharge ManCharge ManWeapon: Charge KickWeakness: Power StoneNapalm ManNapalm ManWeapon: Napalm BombWeakness: Crystal EyeCrystal ManCrystal ManWeapon: Crystal EyeWeakness: Gyro Attack</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10152">Bucky O'Hare</game><game id="2190">Gunstar Heroes</game><game id="8292">Super Metroid</game><game id="2866">Super Mario World 2: Yoshi's Island</game><game id="16783">The Krion Conquest</game><game id="16188">Clash at Demonhead</game><game id="12296">Metal Storm</game><game id="6657">Blue's Journey</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2362055-nes_megaman5.jpg</image></root>