<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12261</id><name>Space Quest V: The Next Mutation</name><description>Space Quest V is a 1993 comedic sci-fi point-and-click adventure game developed by Dynamix and published by Sierra On-Line, and the fifth and penultimate game in the Space Quest series. It was also the first game in the Space Quest series that was not primarily designed and programmed by the series' creators, the Two Guys from Andromeda (Mark Crowe and Scott Murphy). Serendipitously, not long after Dynamix had been picked to develop the game, Mark Crowe moved from Sierra to Dynamix, and has tasked with developing the next Space Quest game. Scott Murphy remained at Sierra, and would not work on the fifth instalment of the series. Although Dynamix was the chosen development studio for the project, Sierra CEO Ken Williams insisted that they use Sierra's SCI development system.Space Quest V parodies several prominent science fiction franchises, including Star Trek and the Alien film series. The parodies and references are more numerous and direct than they were in past games in the series. PlotRoger Wilco, space janitor, has had it with being a luckless space hero, and enrolls in StarCon Space Academy to fulfill his dream of becoming a spaceship captain. Too bad he forgot to study for the big test. With some cheating and a rodent-induced malfunction at the grading process, Roger gets his own command, the SCS Eureka, and suddenly things are looking up for the space guy!....Except that the Eureka is a garbage scow, his crew is a bunch of misfits and there is a DeathStalker Mark VI Annihilator android, WD-40, out there looking to kill him. And there is a mutating disease spreading across the galaxy, with Roger being the only one who can stop it.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="152">Police Quest 3: The Kindred</game><game id="16771">King's Quest V: Absence Makes the Heart Go Yonder</game><game id="2240">King's Quest VI: Heir Today, Gone Tomorrow</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15568/610293-sq5front.jpg</image></root>