<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12264</id><name>Lufia: The Ruins of Lore</name><description>Story This game takes place 20 years after Lufia 2. The world is at peace and all seems perfect.But war is coming as a power hungry man allies himself with the .  As evil spreads and chaos reigns terror down on hapless villages a hero arises to fight back.CharactersEldinA young man whose father has disappeared. He qualifies as a monster hunter and leaves Parcelyte in search of adventure. His field ability is a sword, to chop through grass and bush.TormaEldin's best friend and fellow monster hunter, his field ability is a whip which can traverse gaps in the terrain.RamiEldin and Torma's friend from their hometown, she too is a monster hunter (qualified through dubious means) whose speciality is magic. Her field ability is that she can light fires, which is used to light candles, fuses, torches and the like.  Dekar  Dekar returns from Lufia 2, having not been involved in the fight against the Sinistrals. He has the same personality as in Lufia 2, being a womaniser whose strength is famed across the land. Throughout the game, however, he tries to become more responsible, as the older character in the story.   </description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="267">Golden Sun</game><game id="4277">Golden Sun: The Lost Age</game><game id="6336">Final Fantasy VI</game><game id="13561">Riviera: The Promised Land</game><game id="17928">Final Fantasy I &amp; II: Dawn of Souls</game><game id="20829">Final Fantasy IV</game><game id="4793">Final Fantasy V</game><game id="3093">Breath of Fire II</game><game id="15629">Breath of Fire</game><game id="23975">Magical Vacation</game><game id="21240">Black Sigil: Blade of the Exiled</game><game id="11497">Final Fantasy XII</game><game id="34076">Final Fantasy IV: The Complete Collection</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2478671-box_ltrol.png</image></root>