<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12298</id><name>WipEout 3</name><description>The main gameplay addition to this version of Wipeout (Wip3out - the sequel to Wip2out, otherwise known as Wipeout XL / 2097) was "hyper boost", which by pressing the R1 button caused your craft of choice to propel itself into the nearest wall, or with a bit of practice and swearing, victory. Hyper boost also rapidly drained your crafts shields, which meant further frustration for the unskilled air-jockey, but for an expert player, this ability added another layer of competitive complexity to the already rather aggressive late-game difficulty level.Teams:Feiser: Ever the sluggish tank, great shields, low top speed and pretty average turning.Auricom: The all-rounder, is just slightly above average with all its attributes.Goteki 45: Slower turning and acceleration than Auricom, but makes up for it with a higher top speed, better shields and a cooler name.Piranha Advancements: Not quite as awesome as it was in Wipeout 2097/XL, but still sporting it's main attributes of strong acceleration and top speed, coupled with above average turning and under-cooked shields.Qirex: Often referred to as the "Big Bouncer" (not really), Qirex has strong shields, sluggish acceleration and a high top speed. Not great at corners though.AG Systems: The second-best turning ability you'll see this side of an election, balanced out with a crappy top speed, shoddy shields and real fast acceleration.Assegai: Mad-fast turning that takes even AG Systems to the proverbial cleaner. The only problem: Shields that don't stop much, a very low top speed and ridiculous (in a good way - until you smash into a chicane) acceleration.Icarus: Top speed: Incredible. Acceleration: Pretty damn fast. Turns: Like an elderly woman with a zimmer-frame. Shields: Where? Oh, that little patch over... (after several minutes of inspection, it was a damp cloth in the shape of a shield).SoundtrackSasha - FeisarUnderworld - KittensSasha - IcarasOrbital - Know Where To RunSasha - AuricomMKL - SurrenderPropellerheads - Lethal CutSasha - Goteki 45The Chemical Brothers - Under The InfluenceSasha - PirhanaMKL - ControlPaul Van Dyk - AvenueSasha - Xpander</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9060">Rollcage</game><game id="21252">F-Zero Climax</game><game id="7880">Jet Moto</game><game id="15636">Forsaken</game><game id="20448">F-Zero GX</game><game id="18808">F-Zero X</game><game id="15242">F-Zero</game><game id="21146">Fatal Inertia EX</game><game id="18126">Kinetica</game><game id="19008">Ballistics</game><game id="23156">F-Zero X Expansion Kit</game><game id="21285">Rollcage Stage II</game><game id="8949">S.T.U.N. Runner</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2210281-box_wout3.png</image></root>