<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12311</id><name>Delta Force: Black Hawk Down - Team Sabre</name><description>Overview: Following the success of  Delta Force: Black Hawk Down, Novalogic released an expansion pack, which contained two new single-player campaigns, changing the locale from 1993-era Somalia to modern-day Colombia and Iran.    ContentsThe expansion pack contained multiple new weapons for use in both single/multiplayer, and the option to control an British SAS Cammando unit as a character skin in online matches.ChangesAside from the additions mentioned above, Team Sabre contained no changes, the engine remained the same with no graphical improvements, and the map editor received no alterations aside from the ability to place Team Sabre -specific stock objects/weapons/etc.PlayStation 2 VersionUnlike the PC expansion pack, the PS2 version was released a year later and  was created from the ground up by a different developer (Rebellion Studios) then that of the PC version or the Xbox version of the original game. While the game's setting and general plot remained the same, there was much variation in missions and direction.PC System Requirements   Video Card: Direct 3D video card with 32MB required. 64MB or greater  recommended. Compatible 3D cards include: Nvidia TNT2, GeForce series,  ATI Radeon series. For a list of supported 3D cards visit  www.novalogic.com.  Operating System: Windows® 98, ME, 2000, XP  CPU: Minimum - Pentium® III 733 MHz equivalent  Recommended - Pentium® 4 1.4 GHz equivalent  Hard drive space: 750MB available  Memory: 256MB or greater required   CD-ROM: 4x or greater CD-ROME drive  DirectX: DirectX 8.1 required  Sound Card: Windows® compatible.  Controllers: Windows® compatible mouse Internet Play: Up to 50 simultaneous players via NovaWorld *(Internet  service provider required)   LAN Play: Up to 50 simultaneous players via IP LAN. May require  dedicated server.    NOTE: Some multiplayer features may only be available through NovaWorld.    NOTE 2: NVIDIA® nForce™ or other motherboards/soundcards containing the  Dolby® Digital interactive Content Encoder required for Dolby Digital  audio.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="178">ArmA: Combat Operations</game><game id="5333">Operation Flashpoint: Cold War Crisis</game><game id="7887">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six</game><game id="8732">Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon</game><game id="6246">SOCOM: U.S. Navy SEALs</game><game id="21912">Planetside: Core Combat</game><game id="25246">Battlefield: Bad Company 2</game><game id="2397">Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon: Advanced Warfighter</game><game id="270">Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon: Advanced Warfighter 2</game><game id="16866">Battlefield 2</game><game id="21646">Battlefield 2: Modern Combat</game><game id="20454">50 Cent: Blood on the Sand</game><game id="8632">Soldier of Fortune: Payback</game><game id="4745">Soldier of Fortune II: Double Helix</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1789587-box_dfbhdts.png</image></root>