<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12328</id><name>Commandos: Behind Enemy Lines</name><description>OverviewCommandos lets the player control a unit of a British special forces, tackling various missions set during World War II. The game is viewed from an isometric perspective and stretches over 20 missions. Each missions features several or all (depending on the mission) specialists and varying goals. The enemy soldiers roam around the maps, control specific areas and follow patrol lines. The player is prone to avoid enemy contact. Thus, a cone of vision follows the enemy soldiers around and the player is advised to sneak around and hide. The game is more a stealth than an action game, and careful planning is usually the best way to succeed. The individual units have unique abilities and like in a puzzle game, the maps offer obstacles which can only be tackled by the respective units.CommandosMugshotsNamesTitleInfoSpecialtiesJerry "Tiny" McHaleThe Green BeretThe strongest and most skillful soldier in the team. An expert in hand-to-hand combat and can kill more enemies that any other team membersCarry heavy objectsCarry dead bodiesDistract enemy soldiers using a DecoySilent kills using a combat knifeHiding himself in the snow or sand using a shovelClimb walls and hillsSir Francis T. Woolridge aka DukeThe SniperHis usefulness is limited but the Sniper is extremely invaluable in taking out enemies from a great distanceAbility to shoot long range enemies using his precision rifleJames Blackwood aka FinsThe Diver/ The MarineA silent killer much like the Green Beret but instead of hiding in a hole, he hides underwater and kills his targest using a knife or a harpoonSwim underwater using his diving gear and stay submerged indefinitelySilent kills using his combat knife and harpoonPilot boats and submarinesRussell Hancock aka InfernoThe SapperA demolition expert and master of explosives. The Sapper is needed when it comes to blowing up buildings, large weaponry and vehiclesPlant time bombs and remote controlled bombsSilent kills using a bear trapAbility to kill a group of enemies using hand grenadesSid Perkins aka TreadThe DriverProbably the least used of all the Commandos. Aside from being the team medic, the Driver's sole purpose is to drive vehicles for escape attempts or for offensive attacksSkilled in driving any land terrain vehicles like trucks, tanks and buggiesPower to mow down enemies using his submachine gunMedical kit for healing woundsRene Duchampaka SpookyThe SpyMaster of disguise and the ultimate silent killer. Skillful in distracting an enemy soldier by making him face in one direction for a long period of time and silencing them with a poisonous syringeAbility to use enemy uniforms to disguise himselfCarry dead bodiesAbility to distract enemy soldiersSilent kills using a lethal injectionMissionsNorwayMissionsImagesAvailable CommandosDatesObjectives1. Baptism of FireGreen Beret, Marine, DriverFebruary 20,1941Blow up the relay station on the northwestern island2. A Quiet Blow UpGreen Beret, Sniper, Marine, Sapper, DriverMarch 1, 1941Blow up the fuel depot within the walled camp3. Reverse EngineeringGreen Beret, Marine, Sapper, SpyMarch 4, 1941Blow up the large dam4. Restore PrideGreen Beret, Sniper, Marine, Sapper, DriverMarch 10, 1941Demolish the German headquarters building5. Blind JusticeGreen Beret, SpyMay 2, 1941Blow up the radar station in the mountaintop base6. Menace of The LeopoldGreen Beret, Sniper, SapperMay 10, 1941Destroy the Leopold cannon7. Chasing of The WolvesGreen Beret, Marine, Sapper, Driver, SpyFebruary 7, 1942Set off explosives on the two submarines at dockNorth AfricaMissionsImagesAvailable CommandosDatesObjectives8. PyrotechnicsGreen Beret, SniperOctober 19, 1942Blow up the water tower and fuel storage tanks at the German supply depot9. A Courtesy CallGreen Beret, Sniper, Sapper, Driver, SpyOctober 20, 1942Destroy the communications control building, the antenna, the weapons store, the command post and the bunker10. Operation IcarusGreen Beret, Sniper, Sapper, DriverNovember 14,1942Rescue the downed pilot named Captain George McRae, destroy the weapons store, and blow up the two Ju-87 Stuka dive-bombers11. Into The SoupGreen Beret, Sniper, Sapper, Driver, SpyDecember 3,1942Destroy all four oil rigs12. Up On The RoofGreen Beret, Sniper, SpyMarch 15, 1943Rescue the Informer from confinementNormandyMissionsImagesAvailable CommandosDatesObjectives13. David and GoliathGreen Beret, Sniper, Marine, Sapper, DriverMay 15, 1944Sink the Bismarck II and destroy the fuel tanks14. D-Day Kick OffGreen Beret, Sniper, Marine, Sapper, DriverMay 25, 1944Destroy all four coastal guns15. The End of The ButcherSniper, Marine, Driver, SpyAugust 26, 1944Assassinate the SS Grupenfuhrer Helmut Schleper and destroy the headquarters buildingGermanyMissionsImagesAvailable CommandosDatesObjectives16. Stop WildfireSniper, Marine, SpySeptember 4, 1944Kill all the German sappers before they can blow up the bridge over the Maas17. Before DawnGreen Beret, Marine, SpyNovember 28, 1944Free French Resistance leader Claude Gilbert and his four collaborators18. The Force of CircumstanceGreen Beret, Marine, Sapper, DriverDecember 16, 1944Destroy the bridge over the River Maas (the very same bridge that you protected in Mission 16)19. Frustrate RetaliationGreen Beret, Sniper, Marine, SapperJanuary 12, 1945Destroy all three V2 rockets and their launch pads20. Operation ValhallaGreen Beret, Sniper, Marine, Sapper, Driver, SpyFebruary 11, 1945Blow up the headquarters in Gundelfingen Castle, as well as both V2 missilesPC System RequirementsMinimum:Microsoft Windows 95/98P166MHz32MB RAM1MB SVGA cardDirectX 6.1 compatible sound cardDirectX 6.1225MB hard drive spaceRecommended:Pentium II 233 MHz64 MB RAM</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6173">Soldiers: Heroes of World War II</game><game id="10756">Desperados: Wanted Dead or Alive</game><game id="25751">Elite Forces: Unit 77</game><game id="9608">Helldorado</game><game id="11730">Soldiers at War</game><game id="19692">Korea: Forgotten Conflict</game><game id="6594">Robin Hood: The Legend of Sherwood</game><game id="4846">Star Trek: Away Team</game><game id="17421">101: The Airborne Invasion of Normandy</game><game id="17029">Hidden &amp; Dangerous</game><game id="39120">Waterworld: The Quest for Dry Land</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/16944/1122156-1zbrngg.jpg</image></root>