<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1234</id><name>John Madden Football</name><description>Overview John Madden Football was developed after EA saw how well Earl Weaver Baseball did a few years before. The game was the first in the long-running Madden NFL franchise. The game featured John Madden on the cover however the franchise started featuring NFL athletes on the cover in 2000 on the cover of Madden NFL 2001.John Madden Football is also the only Madden game to release on the Commodore 64 and Apple II. FeaturesNo Real Teams Although the Madden games are now known for their up-to-date rosters of real NFL teams and players, John Madden Football does not include actual NFL teams or players because no NFL or NFLPA licenses existed for the franchise at the time. There are, however, teams that are based off of actual NFL teams.No Season PlayReal teams aren't the only difference between this version of Madden and latter day versions; there is also no season play in John Madden Football. The only mode of play is single games. Create-A-TeamThe game has a "blank" team that the player can create from scratch and either play as them or let the computer take over. It's possible to change player numbers, names, positions, and ratings.Field ConditionsThe game has four different field conditions options: hot, rain, snow, or cold and windy. Quarter LengthThere are four different quarter length options: 8, 10, 12, or 15 minute quarters. Playbook CreatorAlthough the game comes with two playbooks, one for offense and one for defense, there is a play creator for anybody to create their own.Save SystemPlayers can save their games at any time using a separate disk.Other OptionsThe game featured other options that disabled fatigue, penalties, injuries, cross-hair passing, or the 30 second clock. </description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="21">Football</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15972">NCAA Football</game><game id="21713">NFL Fever 2003</game><game id="21706">NCAA Football 07</game><game id="8480">All-Pro Football 2K8</game><game id="20848">NCAA Football 09</game><game id="11229">Tecmo Bowl</game><game id="7822">Tecmo Super Bowl</game><game id="20920">Blitz: The League II</game><game id="27055">Computer Quarterback</game><game id="27106">Joe Montana's NFL Football</game><game id="33818">Capcom's MVP Football</game><game id="23246">Football</game><game id="44147">Football Fury</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4647/841564-573823_11976_front.jpg</image></root>