<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12393</id><name>Spycraft: The Great Game</name><description>OverviewSpycraft: The Great Game is a 1996 full-motion video adventure game by Activision. Players take control of Thorn, an up-and-coming CIA agent on the trail of an international conspiracy.During the closing credits, a sequel was promised ("Thorn will return in: SPYCRAFT II"), but has so far never materialized. Many members of the development team went on to work on The Fifth Element following Spycraft's completion.GameplayIn Game PDA Interface.While nominally a point and click game, Spycraft is controlled by the user primarily using the game's PDA interface. Puzzle solving includes but is not limited to:Facial RecognitionVoice AnalysisBullet Trajectory AnalysisPhoto DoctoringPhone TappingSound EditingHackingYou have to find clues through puzzle-solving, which includes searching photos for specific details and voice analysis, and collate a large amount of information to solve the game. Your PDA can keep track of most of the important information and facts and highlights the areas to be investigated (to help help with the solution the the puzzles). Several action sequences in the game involve the player issuing orders to a strike team, while others involve point and click gameplay.The game has many Full-Motion Video sequences featuring actors such as James Karen and Charles Napier.StoryOne of several organizational charts found in the game.The game begins with the assassination of a Russian candidate for president. You play as Thorn, a rookie CIA agent that has been called to Washington to investigate and prevent the possible assassination of the President of the United States. During the game, you can choose your actions where available, which can lead to several different possible endings.The game features Cameo roles former head of the CIA, William Colby and Former head of the KGB Major-General Oleg Kalugin. These former heads of the KGB and CIA gave input into the game, in an apparent attempt to make the game as authentic as it can possibly be.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="389">Uplink: Hacker Elite</game><game id="1551">The President is Missing</game><game id="4987">Daryl F. Gates' Police Quest: SWAT</game><game id="17326">Star Trek: Borg</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1330/178693-spycraft___the_great_game_coverart.png</image></root>