<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12460</id><name>Super Mario Bros. / Duck Hunt</name><description>OverviewSuper Mario Bros. / Duck Hunt is a compilation cartridge containing both NES games Super Mario Bros. and Duck Hunt. The compilation was released for the NES in 1988, developed and published by Nintendo. The game was packaged with two controllers and an NES Zapper (for use in Duck Hunt).GameplaySuper Mario Bros.Selecting a game to play.Super Mario Bros. is a side-scrolling 2D platformer. The game stars Mario on his quest to rescue Princess Peach from the evil King Bowser. Mario must battle his way through eight worlds with four levels per world. Naturally, these worlds are filled with Bowser's baddies, including Koopas, Goombas, and Piranha Plants. Mario has power-ups to help him on the way, though. There are three power-ups: Super Mushroom (which grows Mario in size), Fire Flower (gives Mario the ability to throw fireballs), and Starman (gives Mario temporary invincibility). Super Mario Bros. is one of the most well-known and recognizable games of all time, and its inclusion with Duck Hunt only helped spread its popularity.Duck HuntDuck Hunt is a lightgun shooter in which the player can play in one of three game modes. The first two only vary in the amount of ducks (one or two onscreen at a time), but the third is a clay pigeon shooting mode. The clay pigeons are faster moving and smaller, making that mode more difficult. Duck Hunt is infamous for the dog that always accompanies the player, and laughs at any mistakes that the player makes.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="35">Light-Gun Shooter</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6490">Hogan's Alley</game><game id="1201">Wild Guns</game><game id="4116">Wild Gunman</game><game id="2543">Super Scope 6</game><game id="14664">Donkey Kong Classics</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2362278-nes_supermariobrosduckhunt_2.jpg</image></root>