<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12474</id><name>Black &amp; White 2</name><description>OverviewBlack  White 2 is a god simulator developed by Lionhead Studios and published by Electronic Arts. It was released October 7, 2005. The concept of the game is to provide the player with complete "god" abilities; ranging from constructing buildings to picking up people and casting miracles. The idea was originally conceived by Peter Molyneux in the prequel, Black  White.PlotIn the beginning of the game, you witness a grand civilization, which you later find out to be your civilization, under siege by a gigantic army. This army is ruthless, and intends to annihilate your entire country. You also later find out that the civilization killing all of your people are in fact the Aztecs.After this cutscene depicting the slaughter of your people, you are spoken to by an angelic old man, and a similarly stylized devil character. The angelic character depicts "good" and the devilish character depicts "bad". These characters serve as a tutorial device, and teach you the mechanics of the game. They teach you a range of things, such as how to interact with the world, how to build, and eventually allow you to pick a pet. You choose from four beasts. There is a lion, orangutan, wolf, and cow to choose from. The angelic and devil characters explain that the creature will assist you in your godly doings, and eventually mature and grow over time.Once you complete a few quests to gain a bit of "tribute" (the currency in Black and White 2), you are set off into the story mode. The main gist of the story is to rebuild your civilization, gain allies (or conquer them) and eventually exact revenge on the Aztecs. There are several civilizations to befriend or conquer, ranging from the Nords to ancient Japan. Each civilization can take hours to complete, and there are many chances to gain tribute and buy structures that help with progression in-game. The side-quests make use of the "god" like powers, which have you doing things like tossing barrels of alcohol from island to island, or guiding a friendly spy through a dangerous forest. Your creature also grows, and can be upgraded. You can teach it different fighting styles, and damaging magic moves like fireball or thunder, or on the flip-side, you can upgrade it's gathering and building abilities. You can also purchase structures for your population that do everything from increase the birth rate, to housing the elderly.GameplayThe gameplay differs in many respect's from the previous game, in that you see what your beast is thinking, the usefulness of your army and also heads up display that the first game lacked, whilst the game has a HUD it is much less intrusive then other god games.Your beast learns from your actions, if you hit it a few time's when it's trying to eat your towns-folk it will eventually stop trying.The first game had your beast learn from repetition, whilst in this game your beast learns from you (the player) buying a power-up. Your beast learns by the way you interact with it. People have criticized that the first game was more realistic in it's approach to what is essentially a pet, the first game was more obscure in dealing with the creature</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3397">E. V. O.: Search for Eden</game><game id="10027">Powermonger</game><game id="7701">The Lord of the Rings: The Battle for Middle-earth</game><game id="21149">Populous DS</game><game id="21454">Majesty 2: The Fantasy Kingdom Sim</game><game id="14073">Warcraft III: The Frozen Throne</game><game id="13076">Age of Mythology</game><game id="4867">The Lord of the Rings: The Battle for Middle-earth II</game><game id="1370">Age of Mythology: The Titans</game><game id="17677">The Lord of the Rings: War of the Ring</game><game id="10244">Rise of Nations: Rise of Legends</game><game id="12054">Battle Realms</game><game id="18607">Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Dragonshard</game><game id="11751">Majesty: The Fantasy Kingdom Sim</game><game id="24458">Tropico 3</game><game id="21864">Overlord</game><game id="11544">Armies of Exigo</game><game id="1765">Ancient Wars: Sparta</game><game id="17620">Dungeon Keeper</game><game id="19042">Dungeon Keeper: The Deeper Dungeons</game><game id="31033">GodFinger</game><game id="31702">Kinectimals</game><game id="32326">Tropico 4</game><game id="31722">From Dust</game><game id="8460">Diggles: the Myth of Fenris</game><game id="17680">Pharaoh</game><game id="3769">Zeus: Master of Olympus</game><game id="5211">Zeus Official Expansion: Poseidon</game><game id="3144">Cleopatra: Queen of the Nile</game><game id="10942">The Nations</game><game id="625">Alien Nations</game><game id="8592">Caesar</game><game id="19170">Caesar IV</game><game id="5652">Caesar II</game><game id="6645">Caesar III</game><game id="18721">Cultures</game><game id="19132">Cultures 2: The Gates of Asgard</game><game id="2859">Cultures: Die Saga</game><game id="5457">Cultures: Die Abenteuerbox</game><game id="28310">The Settlers 7: Paths to a Kingdom</game><game id="12922">The Settlers</game><game id="10978">The Settlers III</game><game id="2081">The Settlers II</game><game id="16829">The Settlers II: Veni, Vidi, Vici</game><game id="22372">The Settlers IV: The Trojans and the Elixir of Power</game><game id="1128">The Settlers II: 10th Anniversary</game><game id="2815">The Settlers: Rise of an Empire</game><game id="3449">The Settlers II Mission CD</game><game id="3642">The Settlers II: 10th Anniversary - Vikings</game><game id="6946">The Settlers: Fourth Edition</game><game id="9828">The Settlers: Rise of an Empire – The Eastern Realm</game><game id="22371">The Settlers IV: Mission CD</game><game id="15294">The Settlers III: Quest of the Amazons</game><game id="3009">Immortal Cities: Children of the Nile</game><game id="14638">Northland</game><game id="18490">Majesty: The Northern Expansion</game><game id="29811">Majesty 2: Kingmaker</game><game id="36948">Majesty 2: Monster Kingdom</game><game id="6210">Populous</game><game id="10562">Populous II: Trials of the Olympian Gods</game><game id="12757">Tropico</game><game id="30573">Tropico 3: Absolute Power</game><game id="7965">Tropico 2: Pirate Cove</game><game id="16757">Tropico: Paradise Island</game><game id="1489">8th Wonder of the World</game><game id="11466">CivCity: Rome</game><game id="4102">Emperor: Rise of the Middle Kingdom</game><game id="36949">Majesty 2: Battles of Ardania</game><game id="31820">Majesty 2: Pocket Kingdom</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/6384/629733-blackandwhite2boxart.jpg</image></root>