<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12532</id><name>Backyard Baseball 2003</name><description>Backyard baseball is a baseball sim, with characters that are cartoon kids, not realistic player models. While it has a set of fictional kids known to the franchise it also includes a number of real MLB players, as cartoon modeled kids. PlayersMLB PlayersBackyard Baseball has 30 real Major League Baseball players. One from every team during the 2003 MLB season.Nomar Garciaparra Player Select ScreenGreg VaughnAlex RodriguezFrank ThomasJimmy RollinsTodd HeltonAlbert PujolsBarry BondsRandy JohnsonRichie SexsonJeff BagwellJeff ConineChipper JonesDerek JeterTroy GlaussMike PiazzaBrad RadkeCarlos DelgadoKen Griffey Jr.Vladimer GuerreroSammy SosaCarlos BeltranTim HudsonJim ThomePhil NevinCliff FloydJason KendallIchiro Bobby HigginsonJason GiambiFictional PlayersBackyard Baseball 2003 also includs 30 fictional players. These are the same characters that are in other Backyard Sports Games.Jocinda Smith Marky DuboisRonny DobbsMario LunaAchmed KhanTony DelvecchioDimitri PetrovichGretchen HasselhoffLueane LuiKimmy EckmanRicky JohnsonAnnie FrazierMikey ThomasLisa CrocketAmir KhanSally DobbsPete WheelerDante RobinsonVicki KawaguchiReese WorthingtonKenny KawaguchiStephanie MorganSidney WeberAshely WeberAngela DelvecchioMarky DuboisPablo SanchezBilly Jean BlackwoodJorge GarciaErnie SteeleKiesha PhillipsGameplay TypesThere are four main gameplay types:Season ModeManager screenSeason Mode puts you in the Manager chair, letting you draft your team. You may choose from a selection of 30 fiction characters and 30 real MLB players. You put together a team of nine players, one for every position. You may choose where each player will play, and where they will hit in the batting order. If you win enough games, you will go to the play-offs, and then the championship.Single GameSingle Game screenIn this game type, you are first presented with a screen (see right) that lets you choose your difficulty, length (in innings), if errors are on, and what field you will play on. Once done, you go pick your players, dodgeball style, alternating picks. You then go play your single game.Batting PracticeIn Batting Practice, you choose one player who then hits batting practice. Robotic pitching machine, Mr. Clankey, pitches you a selection of pitches. You can choose whether he throws you a fastball, slow ball, right curve, or left curve. Spectator Mode In Spectator Mode, you simply watch a game being played. You do not choose teams or anything. You simply watch the game being played.  Create A Player Mode In this mode, you are able to create a player specific to:GenderEthnicityHair styleHead shapeName Create A PlayerNicknameRight or Left handedAbilities (stats) BirthdayFactsMajor League TeamsThere are four different difficulties. Easy, Medium, Hard and TeeballYou can play Tee-ball in this game. If you create a player, and make his name "Lemon Boy" he will be all maxed out in stats. You can pick to play as 6 custom teams. You can also play as every major league team.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="34">Baseball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20687">MLB Power Pros 2008</game><game id="20686">MLB Power Pros</game><game id="17271">Triple Play 2002</game><game id="7000">Triple Play 2001</game><game id="9670">Triple Play Baseball</game><game id="14025">Triple Play 2000</game><game id="21765">Backyard Baseball '10</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1516/252633-item_87796_2.jpg</image></root>