<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1253</id><name>Road Rash 3: Tour De Force</name><description>Bike ShopRoad Rash 3 features a Bike Shop. Here you can buy new motorcycles and upgrades. There is three types of motorcycle:Rat Bikes- The slowest of the motorcycle classes.Sport Bikes- Sport Bikes are very fast but incredibly hard to control.Super Bikes- The best of the motorcycle classes, this vehicle class is both fast and easy to control.UpgradesYou can upgrade you equipment in four areas:Performance- Increase your engine's overall performance. This includes; quicker acceleration, higher RPM's, and more power.Protection- Strengthen your bike against collisions, endure more spills, and keep your damage gauge strong.Tires- Keep your tires in good condition, this is vital to success.Suspension- This upgrade allows you to control better off jumps, this also helps with general control of the vehicle.Player ModesThere are four player mode options:Solo- This mode is played strictly by yourself and the AI. If you reach a game over screen you may be asked to snitch for the cops or be a Repo Man for the bike shop.Take Turns- Two human players challenge the pack one at a time. One controller is used for both players.Split-Screen- Two human players race against each other in via split-screen multiplayer.Mano A Mano- Challenge a friend to an all-out slug-fest on a split-screen-- no additional opponents and no rules! Choose a weapon and hit the track.Road Rash Also supports a password system that saves your; bike, level, upgrades, track qualifications, and cash information.WeaponsThere are seven weapons in the game that vary in damage and effect.Club- Slow weapon that takes a biker down in 3 hits.Chain- Fast weapon that takes a biker down in 3 hits.Crowbar- Slow weapon with a 3 hit take down. It stuns the biker for a longer period of time.Oil Can- drops oil onto the road to slip up other bikers and crash them. Limited Use.Mace- Sprays other bikers in the face causing them to freeze for 4 seconds.Cattle Prod- Causes bikers to freeze and take a decent amount of damage.Nun chucks- Very fast weapon that takes bikers down in 2 hits. Best weapon in game.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22249">Wingnuts MotoRacer</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2371396-genesis_roadrash3.jpg</image></root>