<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12572</id><name>The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time</name><description>OverviewThe Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time was released in Japan on November 21, 1998, and in North America two days later. It was the first Zelda game to be produced in 3D, and creator Shigeru Miyamoto was almost universally praised for smoothly transitioning Zelda into the 3D space and preserving the feel of the franchise. Ocarina of Time is the fifth game in the series and was developed by Nintendo's Entertainment Analysis and Development division for the Nintendo 64.StorylineThe Great Deku TreeIn the vast, deep forest of Hyrule, the Great Deku Tree served as the guardian spirit. The children of the forest, the Kokiri, lived with the Great Deku Tree. Each Kokiri had his or her own guardian fairy, except one. His name was Link. This is where the game begins, with you playing as Link, a simple young boy living with the Kokiri tribe who are elf-like children that never grow up and can never leave the Kokiri Forest. After having an unexplainable dream, the game's hero, Link, is awakened by a guardian fairy named Navi. She explains that the Great Deku Tree has summoned him and there is no time to waste. After searching the town for the Kokiri Sword, and finding enough rupees to buy the Deku Shield, Link is allowed to enter the presence of the Great Deku Tree. Link finds out that he has been summoned to attempt to save the Deku Tree from death after being cursed by an evil man. After defeating the curse, but failing to save the Great Deku Tree, Link is told the origin of the world of Hyrule….."A long time ago . . .Before life began, before the world had formed, three golden goddesses descended upon the chaotic land of Hyrule.They were Din, the goddess of power, Nayru, the goddess of widdom and Farore, the goddess of courage.Din, with her strong flaming arms, cultivated the land to create the earth.Nayru poured her wisdom onto the earth to give the spirit of law to the world.Farore's rich soul created all life forms who would uphold the law.These great goddesses returned to the heavens, leaving behind the golden sacred Triforce.Since then, the Triforce has become the basis for Hyrule's providence.Where the Triforce Stood became sacred land."The Triforce - A sacred object left by the gods in Hyrule.The Deku Tree then reveals that the “wicked man from the desert” that cursed him was searching for one of three sacred stones, the keys to opening the door of time located in Temple of Time and gaining access to the Triforce. After giving Link the spiritual stone of the forest, the Kokiri's Emerald, the Deku Tree tells Link that he is different from all the other Kokiri and has a destiny that lies beyond the forest. Before he dies he sends Link to search out the other two spiritual stones, and specifically to the Hyrule Castle. As the story unfolds it is learned that Link needs to stop the “wicked man from the desert”, named Ganondorf, from gaining access to all three pieces of the Triforce and gaining the full power of the Goddesses.Just as Link leaves Kokiri Forest, his old friend Saria gives him the Fairy Ocarina. A musical device capable of playing numerous melodies. As he steps onto Hyrule Field, he meets a wise owl, Kaepora Gaebora, who gives advice to Link on his quest. Link makes his way across the Hyrule Field and eventually arrives at Hyrule Castle. He storms through the market and reaches the castle gate. It is here that he meets Malon, a dairy maid and daughter of the owner of Lon Lon Ranch, who she gives him an egg after stating that her dad is missing after doing a milk delivery. Being refused entry to the castle, Link climbs up some vines around the side of the gate and sneaks past all the guards to get into the castle. The only way in being a small trapdoor on the side of the building. However, this is blocked by a sleeping Talon, the missing owner of Lon Lon Ranch. Not being awoken by normal methods, Link waits a night and a day and the egg hatches into a Cuckoo. The Cuckoo wakes up Talon, who runs back home after he realises that Malon is upset. Link now sneaks into the castle via the small trapdoor.As he goes into the Castle, there are more guards patrolling the grounds. Link successfully sneaks past them and is greeted by Princess Zelda. She tells the story of how Hyrule was created and how Ganondorf, the Gerudo King, is trying to harness the power of the Triforce for himself. After agreeing to help the Princess, Link meets Impa, nurse of Zelda, who teaches him Zelda's lullaby and escorts him out of the castle, but not before giving him a note to allow him to climb Death Mountain.Once back in Hyrule Field, Link goes back to Kokiri Forest to get Saria's Song, as it is one of the Goron's favourite songs. However, Saria is nowhere to be seen, so Link searches for her and ends up in the Lost Woods, an eerie forest which seems to be an endless maze. After Link makes his way through the Lost Woods, with the help of Kaepora Gaebora, he eventually finds Saria sitting on a tree stump. It is here Link learns Saria's Song, this allows him to ask for Saria's advice whenever he needs it wherever he may be. Link makes his way to Death Mountain, and his second Spiritual Stone.Making his way back through Hyrule Field, Link heads for Kakariko Village, at the base of Death Mountain. Once here, he shows the guard guarding the entrance to Death Mountain, the letter that Impa gave him and Link is granted permission to make his way up the dangerous mountain. Avoiding various Tektites and other dangers, Link finally arrives at Goron City. Encountering a locked door, Link plays Zelda's Lullaby and meets Darunia, who refuses to talk to him as he is a bad mood. To brighten the atmosphere, Saria's Song is played and Darunia breaks into dance. Finally being in a good mood again, Darunia gives link the Power Bracelet, which allows him to pick up Bomb Flowers. Using this new found strength, Link picks up a Bomb Flower and blows up the entrance to Dodongo's Cavern.Link makes his way through Dodongo's Cavern, fighting various enemies such as Keese, Lizalfos and Dodongo's. He obtains the dungeons' treasure which are bombs. This allows him to carry bombs with him instead of depending on Bomb Flowers and the Goron Braclet. Link makes his way through the dungeon and eventually reaches King Dodongo. After defeating King Dodongo and ridding Dodongo's Cavern of any threats, Darunia congratulates Link making him a 'brother' and gives him the second spiritual stone, the Goron's Ruby.With two out of the three spiritual stones obtained, only the Zora's Sapphire remained. Link makes his way to the Zora domain, gaining entrance by playing Zelda's Lullaby. He speaks to the king of the Zora's who tells him that his daughter, Princess Ruto is missing and asks Link to go find her. Link can then take part in a diving game which if he completes, it will give him the silver scale. Using his new found ability to breathe underwater for longer, Link uses the secret entrance to Lake hylia found in Zora's domain. It is here that he finds a message in a bottle. The message states that Princess Ruto has gone to see Jabu Jabu. Link shows the king this message and the king allows him to pass. Jabu Jabu has been acting strangely recently and when Link feeds him a fish, Jabu Jabu engulfs Link.When inside Jabu Jabu, Link finds Princess Ruto, who is rather rude. Link has to escort her around the body while avoiding the enemies that plague the area. As Link reaches the end of the dungeon, he fights the dungeon boss using his new found boomerang. Once defeated, Princess Ruto is saved and she gives him the Zora's Sapphire as an engagement present stating that she will get married to Link in the future.Now that Link has all three spritual stones he makes his way back towards Hyrule Castle. As he reaches the gates of the market place, he sees Zelda and Impa ride out on horseback, Zelda notices Link and throws the Ocarina of Time back into the moat surrounding the castle. Just after they disappear, Ganondorf comes storming through the gates and asks Link where the princess went. He refuses to answer and then is hit by Ganondorf's thunderball.When Link awakens, he jumps into the moat and finds the Ocarina of Time and proceeds to the Temple of Time. He opens the Door of Time by placing all three spiritual stones on the alter, this reveals the Master Sword resting in the Pedestal of Time. After Link unsheathes the Master Sword from the Pedestal of Time he unknowingly and unwillingly gives Ganondorf access to the Sacred Realm.Ocarina of Time takes place in two different time settings with players controlling both young Link and adult Link. The game starts when Link is a young boy trying to stop Ganondorf from gaining the Triforce. Upon gaining access to the Temple of Time and the Master Sword, Link travels seven years into the future. You learn that the time travel happens because, although Link is the chosen one to remove the Master Sword from its stone sealed sheath, you must be of a certain age to wield it. Therefore Link is trapped in a sort of “hibernation” until he is old enough to fulfil his destiny. When Link awakens he finds that in his absence, Ganondorf has used the Triforce of Power to take control of Hyrule and turn it into a post apocalyptic world. Link must now embark on a quest to save the once beautiful land of Hyrule.Map of Hyrule, from The Legend of Zelda: The Ocarina of TimeThe Legend of Zelda series' first appearance on the Nintendo 64 brought many of the franchise's mainstays along with it. There were dungeons with forest, fire, and water themes, for instance, and trademark weapons and items like the bomb and boomerang were also available. Because this was the first 3D game in the series, many innovations made their first appearance in the game play. This was the first game to feature a lock-on targeting system whereby Link would circle around and direct his attacks at the targeted enemy. The so-called "Z-targeting" system was subsequently adopted by numerous third-person action games.Control SchemeIn a situation similar to the development of Super Mario 64 (released in 1996), Nintendo faced the difficult task of translating one of gaming's most beloved franchises into 3D, which meant a complete overhaul of the series' classic design mechanics.Only the Great King of Evil can stand up to the power of Z-Targeting with his aura of evil.Unlike the previous, top-down 2D Zelda games, Ocarina of Time utilized a completely 3D view. The player could control both Link's direction and the velocity of movement via the Analog Stick. The camera in Ocarina of Time floated around Link (as opposed to the greater camera controls in Super Mario 64), and could be instantly directed behind Link by pressing the Z button. Although the B button permanently controlled use of the sword, the games various other items (such as the Bow and the Hookshot) could be mapped onto the Left, Right, and Down C-Buttons, allowing Link to access more of his weaponry without pulling up a menu.Nintendo brought two major control innovations to bear in Ocarina of Time. The first, and most obvious, new control feature was Lock-On Targeting (referred to as Z Targeting in the game). Pressing the Z button when Link was near a person, enemy, sign or interactive part of the environment caused the camera to lock onto the target (in game, Link's fairy, Navi, would fly to the nearby target, and Link would turn his eyes directly towards Navi's new location). From the locked on position, Link could strafe around his target, use rolls and flips to dodge enemy attacks, and easily interact/talk to NPCs.The idea of locking on to a target was revolutionary: game programmers and designers, who were trying to understand how characters would be able to physically interact in 3D, couldn’t understand how to make a game with the same type of tight control they could achieve in a 2D perspective. Characters could never line up properly with their targets and movement speed was too slow. Many games had awkward control schemes that confused players (a good example of an awkward control scheme: the original Resident Evil Game, with its D-pad tank-style controls, were probably conceived as a half-decent means for a player to move through a 3D environment). In Ocarina of Time however, players could instantly face and run directly to characters, would always be facing toward an enemy, and had more control over Link. As a result of Lock-on Targeting, Ocarina of Time was easily the most fluid, smoothest looking 3D game of its time.The second key innovation of Ocarina of Time was the creation of the context-sensitive button. Rather than map every single one of Link's abilities to a different button on the N64 controller, or only provide Link with a handful of abilities, Nintendo mapped many "secondary" control features to the A button. When in a certain situation or "context" (in front of a door, near a block, in combat, playing the Ocarina, riding Epona), the on-screen A button would display a word, indicating what the button could currently be used for (e.g. opening doors, pushing blocks, jump attacks in combat, putting the Ocarina away, speeding Epona up). This was a more subtle change to the series, but Context-Sensitive buttons became the industry standard way for developers to assign controller buttons, using permanent assignment only for important actions, while letting a player use "secondary functions" only in the proper context.GameplayThe A is used to button scrolls through text, to roll, read signs, and dodge enemy attacks.Perhaps the biggest surprise for players who purchased the game was that, despite the new perspective, brand new controls, and fancy 3-D graphics, Ocarina of Time was still a full-blooded Zelda game. Sticking to its roots, the game led players through nine different dungeons, having them complete tricky puzzles and defeat big bosses along the way. Rather than use the new found power of the N64 hardware to make a New Zelda game, Nintendo used the increased hardware prowess to Expand the Zelda formula. As Jeff Gerstmann put it in his review, "This is a sequel at its finest, expanding on previous themes and bringing plenty of new stuff to the table."Players will still guide Link through dungeons, collect keys, and fight Ganon -- only this time in 3-DOcarina of Time, like the Zelda games that came before it, is primarily a puzzle solving game, with some sword fighting, horseback riding, and boss fighting playing second fiddle. The player progresses through the game by guiding Link to one of the nine dungeons and collecting a mystical artifact at the end(three jewels in the first half of the game, six medallions in the second half) . Each of these dungeon's is filled with puzzles that hamper Link's progress, and the player must solve them to continue onward. In every dungeon (after the first one) players will encounter a "Sub-Boss", a powerful enemy that the player will be forced to do battle with. Defeating the Sub-Boss will lead the player to an item that will be necessary to solve puzzles farther in the dungeon. At the very end, players will encounter the Boss of the dungeon, who can only be defeated with tactical use of the new weapon retrieved in the dungeon (and some well placed sword slashes).Puzzles in the dungeons often share very basic similarities (there's quite a bit of time spent pushing blocks, standing on switches, and pushes blocks onto switches). However, each dungeon has a "theme" that changes the way the player moves through the dungeon. The Water Temple, for example, can only be beaten if the player raises and lowers the water levels, which they can only do at specific parts of the dungeon. The Shadow Dungeon, on the other hand, is filled with invisible walls and traps, not to mention mirages. The player can only see through these disguises with the Lens of Truth. These different "themes" kept the game from ever seeming stale.Main CharactersOcarina of Time boasted a cast of dozens of characters, including both series stalwarts (like Link, Princess Zelda and Ganon) while also introducing new denizens of the land of Hyrule that would go on to be featured in later installments of the series.Link: The Hero of TimeYoung LinkThe main character of Ocarina of Time, and the protagonist of nearly all the Legend of Zelda games (with rare exception). Like previous Zelda games, the player may choose any name they want for the main character(including their own), but the default character name is Link. The name Link, according to Shigeru Miyamoto, comes from a literal interpretation of what the main character is in a video game: a link between the player and the game.The Link featured in Ocarina of Time is not a continuation of his adventures from the NES, Game Boy, and Super Nintendo games, but a whole new Link in a whole new story unrelated to those previous games. Ocarina of Time helped to cement the fact that the Legend of Zelda games were not a series of stories connected together in a linear timeline, but rather a retelling of the same story: different plot details, character interactions, and action sequences may occur, but the core theme(boy saves princess/world) remains the same throughout many of the main story.The player will eventually control two different "versions" of Link: first as a boy, and then later as a young adult, after he travels forward in time 7 years. This older incarnation of Link is widely regarded as the most popular representation of the series' protagonist, and fan clamor for a game starring the older, more "mature" Link was so strong that Nintendo obliged with the release of The Legend of Zelda: Twilight Princess in 2006 for both the Gamecube and Wii, which were designed around the mature Link aesthetic.Link begins Ocarina of Time as a small boy, a native of the Kokiri tribe designated as protectors of the forests of Hyrule. Link is still a child in the eyes of his peers; he's the one member of the tribe that has not been granted a fairy, a companion sprite to help him out in the world (hence his early-game nickname, "The Boy without a Fairy). At the outset of the game, Link is trouble by strange dreams, visions of a man dressed in black from the west whose presence seems to be a threat (effectively predicting the invasion of Hyrule by Ganondorf and the Gerudu Tribe).Adult LinkAs Link is awakened from his slumber, he meets Navi, the fairy and companion throughout the game. Link has been tasked by the Guardian of the Great Deku Tree, to remove a dark curse planted inside it by the Court Adviser and dark Wizard Ganondorf (the Gerudu man seen in Link's dreams). Despite Link's triumph over the monster deep inside the Tree's Roots, Link was too late to save the Great Deku Tree, as the curse had already taken its toll. With it's last wish, the Great Deku Tree gave Link a quest: he must leave the forest and travel across the world to Hyrule, and present a mysterious green stone, the Kokiri Emerald, to Princess Zelda, implying that she would know how to stop Ganondorf from taking over Hyrule.Link's journey will take him to the Princess Zelda, and together the two would hatch a plan to defeat Ganondorf by acquiring the Triforce, the mystical relics that helped to preserve the land and make it flourish after the goddesses created Hyrule. The Triforce was also the object of Ganondorf's desires, as the mystical triangles were able to grant any wish the holder of the relic desired. Link and Zelda decided to get to the Triforce before Ganondorf by getting to the Triforce first. To access the Sacred Realm (where the Triforce has been stored by the gods), Link must locate two more sacred stones, the Goron's Ruby and the Zora's Sapphire. Together with the Kokiri Emerald, Link and Zelda are able to open the Door of Time. When Link draws the fabled Master Sword from it's pedestal from behind the door of time, he opened the Sacred Realm and access the Triforce. However, Ganon managed to get the Triforce before Link and Zelda, and with his first wish, the dark wizard declared himself the new ruler of Hyrule.When Link returns to consciousness, he finds himself inside the fabled Chamber of Sages. Inside, he is given his next task by Rauru, the Sage of Light. In order to combat Ganon and deliver Hyrule from evil, Link must awaken the other 5 sages, denizens of Hyrule that must take on the mantle of protectors of the Triforce and Hyrule. Only Link, the legendary Hero of Time (with the power to travel between the past and future) can defeat Ganondorf's evil forces. With the power of the awakened Sages, Link would be able to seal Ganondorf away inside the Sacred Realm for all time.Upon obtaining all 6 of the Sage Medallions (designators that the sage has been awakened), Link learns that Ganondorf only managed to grab one piece of the three pronged Triforce. Ganondorf possessed the Triforce of Power, while Link himself possessed the Triforce of Courage. The Triforce of Courage would help give Link the strength to rescue the Princess Zelda and defeat Ganondorf once and for all.Princess Zelda/ SheikPrincess Zelda (Young)The titular character of the Legend of Zelda series, Princess Zelda is a member of Hyrule's royal family. The young princess is the only member of her family that suspects Ganondorf's treachery, fearing that his true interests are to take control of the Triforce (which the Royal Family is sworn to protect).Link first meets Princess Zelda at the behest of the Great Deku Tree. His task was to take the Kokiri Emerald to the Princess. After sneaking his way into the castle and avoiding guards in the Castle Royal Gardens, Link finally makes his way into Zelda's room and private garden. At first, Zelda was surprised that the young boy had managed to sneak past the guards, but when she discovers that Link had arrived in the Castle from the forest, and had a fairy companion, Zelda remembered the dream she had of the boy emerging from the forest with a fairy, and was convinced that Link was the one destined to help her keep the Triforce away from Ganondorf. Zelda tells Link of her fears about the dark wizard, and together, the two children hatch a plan to protect the Triforce from Ganondorf's evil.Princess Zelda (Adult)To open the Door of Time and Access the Sacred Realm, the pair would need to play the Song of Time on Zelda's greatest treasure, the Ocarina of Time, passed down throughout the Royal Family.However, before Link and Zelda use the Sacred Stones to open the Door of Time, Ganondorf begins his coup in Hyrule Castle and chases the Princess and her guardian Impa from the Castle. As they cross the gate to Hyrule Castle Town, Zelda throws the Ocarina of Time into the moat for Link to recover, imbued with a secret message from the princess that teaches Link how to play the Song of Time. The young Princess Zelda won't be seen again until the player has completed the game.When Link awakens in the Temple of Time seven years in the future, he is greeted by the mysterious Sheik, the last surviving member of the Sheikas, a tribe dedicated to the protection of the royal family. Sheik describes to Link the new world, one controlled and maintained by Ganondorf from the safety of Hyrule Castle. Sheik points Link towards the first Sage, the Sage of the Forest, and gives Link hints about the tools he will need to help save and awaken the various Sages. Sheik will eventually teach Link special "warp" songs that will instantly whisk the Hero of Time to the entrance of the five dungeons, or send him back to the Master Sword's pedestal at the Temple of Time, making the navigation of Hyrule much easier.After Link awakens all six Sages, he returns to meet Sheik at the Temple of Time. Sheik tells Link that, although Ganondorf was the ruler of Hyrule, his victory of the land was not complete. Ganondorf only possessed one piece of the Triforce, the Triforce of Power. Link himself possessed the Triforce of Courage. The Triforce of Wisdom, on the other hand, was bound on the hand of a mysterious "seventh sage", the leader of the other six. To Link's (and the player's) shock, Sheik removes his mask and vestments, and reveals himself to be none other than the Princess Zelda! Her disguise was a ruse to keep the Princess out of Ganondorf's clutches to protect the Triforce of Courage. As the legendary Seventh Sage, Zelda uses her power to grant Link a weapon, the mystical Arrows of Time, that could penetrate any darkness and fill it with light. However, upon revealing her true self, Ganondorf captures the Princess and brings her to Hyrule Castle. Only Link can rescue her from his clutches, so he sets off to Ganon's castle, and ascends to the top and faces the Evil King. Zelda is released upon Link's victory, but the tower starts to collapse, and the two have to escape before they're buried along with it. She helps open the gates that will lead the two to the exit and escape just as the building is destroyed. After a final battle between Link and Ganon, Zelda uses her powers to hold Ganon in place so Link can deliver the final blow to the beast. She then uses her powers in conjunction with the six sages to seal Ganon within the Sacred Realm. With Hyrule saved, Zelda uses the Ocarina of Time to send Link back to his childhood, where he is supposed to be.Navi the Fairy"Hey!" "Listen!"Navi is one of the mysterious fairy's of the Deku Forest. We are introduced to Navi at the very start of the game when she wakes Link from his nightmare, telling Link the Deku Tree has sent her to aid Link on his journey.Navi is the secondary character that the player controls throughout the game with the new and innovative Z-Targeting mechanic. When the player presses and holds the Z-button, Navi will float over the nearest target in order to keep the players attacks directed to that object or enemy. As well as being a part of a mechanic, Navi is also one of the first characters to have voice acting. She will occasionally yell out "Watch Out" if there is something you need to....well, watch out for. She also says "Hey" when she has something important to tell Link, followed by a "Listen" when the player presses the Up C-button. After doing so Navi will give a hint as to what you should be doing next in terms of the story line, just in case you are lost.GanondorfGanondorfGanondorf (aka Dark Lord, Great King of Evil, and Man from the West) is the main villain in Ocorina of Time as well as most of the other Zelda games. Ganondorf is from the Gerudo Tribe which is made up primarily of women except for their King and is located in the desert to the west of Hyrule. Ganondorf came to power by simply being the chosen male child to be born every hundred years. He then uses his status as King of the Gerudo to make peace with the King of Hyrule and become an adviser to the king. As a young child Princess Zelda senses something dishonest and evil about Ganondorf as he is making a truce with her father. It is through this suspicion that Princess Zelda recruits Link to help her keep Ganondorf from achieving his goal, whatever it may be. Little do they know that Ganondorf will actually use Link as a pawn to get to the triforce.The Six SagesForestSariaSaria Main page: SariaThe first sage you save from the Forest Temple, Saria is also a childhood friend of Link's. Unlike the other Kokiri that teased Link for lack of having a fairy, Saria spent time and often played together. When Link is told by the Great Deku Tree to leave the forest and go to Hyrule Castle, Saria gives him a Fairy Ocarina as a memento. Some moments later in the game, Link returns to the forest and finds Saria in the Sacred Forest Meadow, which is also the entrance to the Forest Temple as an adult. Here Saria teaches Link a new song for his Ocarina, that can let him communicate with Saria if he needs any advice. After becoming an adult and gaining the Hookshot, Link returns to the Sacred Forest Meadow, Saria's favorite spot, to see she isn't there. After fighting through the temple and defeating Phantom Ganon, Saria is saved and is awakened as the Sage of Forest, and gives Link the Forest Medallion.FireDaruniaDarunia Main page: DaruniaDarunia is the second sage to be awakened, and is another character Link meets in his youth. In a grouchy mood initially, Link makes him happy and dancing when he plays Saria's Song. Darunia tells Link of the Goron's predicament, their main food supply in Dodongo's Cavern being cut off by a massive boulder, and promises to give him the Spiritual Stone of Fire, Goron's Ruby, if he destroys the boulder and the monsters inhabiting Dodongo's Cavern. Link defeats the monsters and earns Darunia's respect by becoming his "Sworn Brother." They would soon meet again when the ancient dragon Volvagia was released in Death Mountain, and the two worked to free the Gorons and defeat the beast. Upon doing so, Darunia was awakened as the Sage of Fire, and grants Link the Fire Medallion.WaterRutoRuto Main page: Princess RutoPrincess of the Zoras, Sage of the Water Temple, and another childhood friend of Link. The King Zora asked of Link to find his daughter inside Lord Jabu-Jabu's belly. The reason she was inside? To find her precious gem Zora's Sapphire, the Spiritual Stone of Water. She is initially reluctant and rude towards Link, as she does not want his help. However, after saving her and defeating the monster inside Jabu-Jabu, she becomes impressed by Link's skills, and gives him the stone on the promise that he will marry her. Seven years later, Zora's Domain is frozen, and Ruto travels to the Water Temple to find out the problem. Link catches up, and Ruto had not forgotten the promise they made, though they both realize that there are other matters at hand. After navigating the temple and defeating Morpha, Ruto is awakened as the Sage of Water, presents the Water Medallion to Link.ShadowImpaImpa Main page: ImpaImpa was Zelda's handmaid, and took care of her in her youth. After Link and Zelda meet at the castle, Impa teaches him Zelda's Lullaby, which serves him many purposes, mainly to show connection with the Royal family. She is last seen in Link's youth, riding off from Hyrule Castle Town as Ganondorf is in pursuit of Zelda and the Ocarina of Time. Seven years later, Kakariko village comes under attack by the evil spirit Bongo Bongo, and Impa heads into the Shadow Temple to stop the creature. Link follows as well and defeats the creature, overcoming the illusions of the temple. Upon awakening Impa as the Sage of Shadow, Impa reassures Link that Zelda is safe, and gives him the Shadow Medallion.SpiritNabooruNabooru Main page: NabooruGanondorf's Second in Command, well originally, Nabooru finds Link as a child in the Spirit Temple, and the two decide to work towards finding out the Gerudo King's schemes, though not before Koume and Kotake capture Nabooru, Link is left to finish the job and explore the rest of the temple as an adult. The two witches had taken Nabooru and brainwashed her as an Iron Knuckle, and is forced to fight Link. Link breaks the spell over Nabooru, and Koume and Kotake, rather irritated, casts a spell on Nabooru transporting her to parts unknown. Link must then defeat the two witches in their separate and combined form Twinrova, and with their hold on the temple gone, Nabooru is freed and awakened as the Sage of Spirit, and gives Link the Spirit Medallion.LightRauruRauru Main page: RauruThe Light Sage who resides in the chamber of sages, Rauru wakes up Link from his seven year slumber after removing the Master Sword from the Pedestal of Time. He takes the time to explain to Link what has happened to Hyrule in his absence, how Ganondorf was able to get his hand on the Triforce and become the King of Evil. After providing this exposition on events, he sends him back to the Temple of Time, after handing him the Light Medallion.The Seventh SageZelda's Alter-Ego, Sheik.A childhood friend of Link's are revealed to be the seventh sage. During his quest as an adult, Zelda disguised herself as Sheik and taught him new songs for his Ocarina as well as updating him on the events around Link. After returning to the Temple of Time after awakening the sages, Sheik arrives, provides more exposition on the Triforce, and reveals herself not only to have the Triforce of Wisdom, but also to be Zelda. She uses her powers to grant Link the Light Arrows, the only weapon to destroy Ganondorf, and along with the other sages seals the Evil King in the Sacred Realm.SongsA big part of Ocarina of Time was that in the start of the game you were given a ocarina that came play tunes that can warp you or have special effects on the world around you.Zelda's LullabyHow to ObtainThis is the first song you learn, and will be taught to yo by Impa shortly after you meet Zelda for the first time in the castle courtyard. She explains that the song is a sign of the Royal Family of Hyrule, and a song she used to put Zelda to sleep when she was a baby.How to Use This SongWhenever you need to show your connection to the royal family, play this song. Initially to open Darunia's chamber, but subsequently whenever you see a Triforce sign. It is used to control the water level in the Water Temple, and open the grave where you gain the Sung Song.Saria's SongHow to ObtainFind Saria in the Sacred Meadow when prompted by Navi to learn this song. The quickest route would be to go to Goron City and open the gate into the Lost Woods from there.How to Use This SongTalk to Saria whenever you like. She'll give you advice on what to do next, much like Navi (only less moronic). Perhaps more importantly, play it to Darunia to cheer him up.Epona's songHow to ObtainAfter you wake Talon outside Hyrule Castle as young Link Malon will be singing on Lon Lon Ranch. Go and talk to her about Epona. The horse will initially run from you, but then if you pull out your ocarina, Malon will teach you the song she is singing; Epona's SongHow to Use This SongTo call Epona; instrumental in the quest to obtain her as an adult, but rather useless as Young Link. Thankfully it has another purpose, sing it in front of Cows and they will tell you how it reminds them of the pasture and give you Milk if you have a free bottle. As mentioned before, use it as Adult Link to call Epona, though you can only call her in areas she could normally reach, such as Hyrule Field, Lake Hylia, and The Gerudo Fortress, etc.Sun's SongHow to ObtainIn the Graveyard as Young Link go to the far end where there's a large gravestone with a Triforce symbol in front of it. Play Zelda's Lullaby and the gravestone will be destroyed by lightening. Inside is a tiny dungeon with three chambers. In the first room destroy all the Keese to progress, and in the next room try your best to bypass the Redead. Then Proceed to the final chamber where you'll find an epitaph for the royal family, and scribbled near the bottom... The Sun's Song!How to Use This SongTurns Night to Day and Day into Night. Using the song in the presence of Undead will freeze them where they stand, as if they were struck by Duku Nut allowing them to be killed easily. Note that if you use the song in a area where time doesn't pass in real time, it will return you to the most recent exit.Song of TimeHow to ObtainWhen you find Ocarina in the moat, Zelda as somehow managed to leave you a message, which teaches you the song.How to Use This SongOpens the Door of Time and it also moves "Time Blocks" in general. What is a Time Block! Giant Metal cubes with the same symbol as on the Door of Time, and often blue. Using the Song near them makes them: appear, disappear, or reappear. If Navi goes green but refuses to tell you why, there is a chance that a Time Block lays hidden nearby, awaiting the Song of Time to awaken it. Try it when you need a platform to gain height.Song of StormsHow to ObtainAs Adult Link go to the Windmill in Kakariko and use you ocarina in front of Guru Guru.How to Use This SongA real multi-purpose song, it's first function is to empty the well in the past. It makes rain start and thunder sound in the background. As Young Link play it near a planted Magic Bean to make it sprout into a tall vine-like thing and it will produce 3 fairy's.Scarecrow's SongHow to ObtainTalk to Boniruu the scarecrow as Young Link then pull out the Ocarina. Strum out six or so random notes and he'll remember it.How to Use ItTo activate the song you must talk to Boniruu as Adult Link and play the song again. Then he'll give some rant, the main point of which being that he'll tell Pierre about it. Anyway, if Navi is floating around being green and won't yield a reason, particularly if she's far away try this song. If you in the right place, Pierre will pop up near Navi, allowing you to Hook shot over. There is a point on top of the lakeside Laboratory to test out on, one inside Death Mountain, and there is one inside the Spirit Temple.Warp SongsThese are taught as you enter each of the six temples for the first time by Sheik.Minuet of ForestWarps To: Sacred Forest MeadowBolero of FireWarps To: Death Mountain CraterSerenade of WaterWarps To: Lake HyliaNocturne of ShadowWarps To: Kakariko GraveyardRequiem of SpiritWarps To: Desert ColossusPrelude to LightWarps To: Temple of TimeBossesQueen GohmaQueen GohmaParasitic Armored ArachnidFirst boss in the game, Gohma was the prime source of parasitic infestation within the Kokiri’s fatherly protector, The Great Deku Tree. Link quickly learned to strike Gohma with his trusted slingshot when the creature’s cyclopic eye turned red to stun and prevent her from birthing new Gohma Larvae. While Gohma was stunned, Link drew his sword and finished off this foul beast, leaving behind little else but a pile of ash. Alas, poor Deku Tree, the quest had been"doomed before it started...".King DodongoKing DodongoInfernal DinosaurGoron City was facing starvation upon Link's arrival and the player later discovered the source was all tied to King Dodongo settling his burrow deep within the local cavern feeding-ground. Link relied on his newly acquired bombs this time around to stun the cavern’s boss. By throwing a lit bomb inside the dinosaur’s mouth, Link avoided a vortex of flame and was able to get in a sword slash before the creature recovered. Following this tactic, Link victoriously roasted the King in his own lava pit.BarinadeBarinadeBio-Electric AnemoneThe Bio-Electric Anemone was the creature that tortured Lord Jabu Jabu. With the earlier aquired boomerang, Link must slay each jellyfish guirding Barinade to expose it's body. The mighty Anemone is then vulnerable to Links Kokiri sword. Several repeats of striking Barinade's body cause the monster to be no more. Throughout the fight, Barinade will shoot short bursts of electricity at Link, to avoid this, plenty of movement is crucial to keep distance from the powerful electricity. The reward for defeating Barinade is The Spiritual Stone of water.Phantom GanonPhantom GanonEvil Spirit from BeyondPhantom Ganon is the mysterious guard of the Forest Temple created by Ganondorf. The battle against the Phantom takes place in a circular room with many identical paintings. At the beginning of the fight, Ganon (mounted on a ghostly horse) will jump into one of the paintings and ride deep into it. He will then ride back towards Link from a random painting and will often use a decoy in a different painting. The painting that creates a purple ripple is the one he will jump out of. A quick strike from the fairy bow will send Ganon back into the paintings. After this is repeated several times, Phantom Ganon will leave his horse and fire bursts of energy at Link who must deflect them with either his Master Sword or a bottle. After the energy hits Ganon he will fall to the floor. He is now vulnerable to a sword attack. When this has been repeated Phantom Ganon will be no more.VolvagiaVolvagiaSubterranean Lava DragonThe enormous flaming dragon that was revived by Ganondorf to guard the Fire Temple. The fight takes place on a small platform with nine pits on it and Link must play a Whack-A-Mole style fight to defeat the dragon. At the beginning of the fight. Volvagia will enter one of the pits and pop out of another. Using the Megaton Hammer, Link must pound Valvagia's head to stun it. Then, using the master sword, a strike at the beast will cause it to either retreat to another pit or take flight. If it's the latter, Volvagia will fly out of the pit and cause boulders to fall from the ceiling and unleash a fiery breath before entering a pit. Then repeat the Whack-a-Mole technique to further damage Volvagia and eventually defeat it.MorphaMorphaGiant Aquatic AmoebaThe strange aquatic creature with enormous strength has complete control of the water in the room it is in. This creature is the reason for Zora's domain freezing over and the state of lake Hylia. Morpha itself is the Nucleus (the red ball), Link must use his Hookshot to pull the nucleus out of the water and onto dry land. Then he must be hit with the Master Sword. Do this quickly as Morpha can summon water "tentacles and limbs" to attack and the Nucleus will try to hop back into the water. Avoid the tentacles and repeatedly pull out and strike the nucleus to defeat Morpha and retrieve the Water Medallion.Bongo BongoBongo BongoPhantom Shadow BeastBongo Bongo is the strange, cycloptic shadow spirit that was once imprisoned at the bottom of the Kakariko Village Well. When Ganandorf came to power, the spirit escaped the Well and entered the Shadow Temple. The battle against Bongo Bongo takes place on a giant bongo, the drum is surrounded by a poisonous liquid that should be avoided. At the start of the fight, Bongo will turn invisible. To know where he is going, the Lens of Truth can be used to see him, although it should be used sparingly. To defeat him, fire an arrow at each of Bongo's disembodied hands to disable them, he will then charge at Link. Hit his eye with an arrow at this point and he will become stunned. Using a well timed quick spin attack, strike the eye of the creature repeatedly. Repeat this as many times as required to defeat Bongo Bongo.TwinrovaTwinrovaSorceress SistersKoume, the sorceress of flame and Kotake, the sorceress of ice are the two guardians of the Spirit Temple. The two Gerudo witch sisters are both the surrogate mothers of Ganondorf and can combine to become a more powerful witch known as Twinrova. To defeat the witches, Link must use the mirror shield to redirect the witches' magical attacks on each other (direct the fire attack against Kotake and vice versa). When this has been done several times to each of the witches they will eventually combine. This time Link will fight a single being. Twinrova will fire either of the two elements (fire and ice) at a time. Link must use the mirror shield to absorb any element and continue to absorb two other shots of the same element. Once three spells of the same element have been absorbed, the shield will fire it's own spell, redirect this at the sorcerer and she will fall. She will now be vulnerable to the master sword. Use preferably a jump attack or a quick spin attack. Repeat this process several times to conquer the witch.GanondorfGanondorfGreat King of EvilThe great king of evil follows a similar battle pattern to that of Phantom Ganon. The Gerudo king will summon waves of darkness so Navi can no longer target him (let's be honest it's not a huge loss). Ganondorf will be flying above a central platform. He will then cast a lightening bolt at Link, which must then be hit away with the master sword like phantom ganon. Ganondorf will then stunned for a short amount of time. Use the bow to fire a light arrow at the King and he will fall to the ground. Now he is vulnerable. Link must leap over to him and attack with the sword, the strongest methods should be used to attack ie: Spin attack, jump attack. This will have to be done several times. If the supply of arrows or magic is down, there are a supply of pots at the base of the tower. When the final sword strike is blown, Ganondorf will be finished...for now.GanonGanonAmongst the debris of Ganondorf's fallen castle will lie a final fight which is very tough. Using the triforce of power, Ganondorf transformed into the beast know as Ganon. At the beginning of the fight, the Master Sword will unfortunately be sent flying by Ganon and out of reach (typical) but the megaton hammer is still in Link's arsenal and if you were clever enough to do the trade sequence and got Biggoron's Sword, that will fare even better. Ganon's weak spot is the coloured tail on his rear. The beast won't allow his behind to become exposed easily though. To reach his tail he must be blinded by a light arrow or deku nut, or when the creature is about to attack, roll through his legs. When Link's sights are set on the multi coloured tail, strike it with the sword/hammer. This must be repeated until Ganon falls over. Zelda will call over to Link to collect the Master Sword. When Link once again has the Master Sword, he must run back to the fallen beast. Ganon will get back up and continue the fight. Carry on striking his tail until he falls once again. Zelda will use her power to hold down Ganon and power the Master Sword. Deliver the final blow to kill Ganon once and for all.ReceptionOcarina of Time was often praised for the story. The Legend of Zelda : Ocarina of Time received universal critical acclaim and had a huge commercial success. It was the best selling game of 1998, with up to 2.5 million sales, even though it was released only 39 days before the end of the year. The game was praised for the intuitive controls, depth, and wonderful story. The games received Perfect 10 scores from numerous websites and magazines and won many Game Of The Year Awards. Ocarina of Time has often been called the greatest game of all time and to this day remains a classic.DungeonsThe game has you go through many different dungeons as both an adult and kid.Kid DungeonsDeku TreeYou enter this dungeon almost within the first twenty minutes of playing. You gain access after gaining a shield and sword. Before that a kid blocks your path. The reason you go here is because The Great Deku Tree wants to speak to you. You will find slingshot here. The boss is the Queen Gohma. Upon defeating her you will gain your first Spiritual Stone.Dodongo's CavernYou find this dungeon by going to Goron City. You will meat the King and he lets you know that Ganondorf has closed the entrance to Dodongo's Cavern, cutting off their food supply. You have to go in and kill the King Dodongo. Once you do that, you will gain your second Spiritual Stone.Jabu-Jabu's BellyThis is the third dungeon before you become an adult. After finding a letter in a bottle from Ruto you are allowed to enter Jabu-Jabu from her father. In there you will gain the boomerang. Once you defeat Barinade. You will gain the last Spiritual Stone, and with that you become an adult.Adult DungeonsForest TempleThe Forest Temple is the first dungeon as an adult. You go there to save Saria, your childhood friend. Here you will have to find four Poe's and kill them in order to move on to the boss. The boss in this temple is Phantom Ganon. Once you defeat Phantom Ganon you will gain your first Sage. You gain the bow here.Fire TempleThe Fire Temple is the second dungeon as an adult. You must have the Goron Tunic for this Temple or you will die from the heat. You gain the sledgehammer here. After you defeat Volvagia, you will gain your second Sage.Water TempleThe Water Temple is the third dungeon as an adult. You must also have the Zora's Tunic or you will drown and the iron boots so you can sink. This temple takes a good amount of skill do to it's challenge. You gain the long shot here. You also fight a dark version of yourself. When you defeat the final boss, Morpha, you will gain your third Sage.Shadow Temple The Shadow Temple is the fourth dungeon as an adult. The boss is Bongo Bongo and once you defeat him you gain your fourth Sage. The Shadow Temple and the Spirit temple can be done in either order, but you would first need to get the hover boots from the beginning of the Shadow Temple to help you progress through the Spirit Temple.Spirit TempleThe Spirit Temple is the fifth dungeon as an adult but also have to be a kid to do most of the level. You have to cross a desert to get there. Once there you will gain the Mirror Shield. The boss is Twinrova. Once you defeat them you will gain your fifth and final Sage. It should be noted that you can do the Spirit Temple and the Shadow Temple in either order.Ganon's TowerThe last dungeon in the game. To gain entrance to it you use the power of all the Sage's to make a walkway. You will first fight Ganondorf himself. After a couple of hit he will cause the place to crumble. After you escape, he will turn into Ganon. After defeating him you save all of Hyrule.EquipmentSwordsKokiri SwordKokiri Sword Main page: Kokiri SwordThe Kokiri Sword is found in Kokiri Forest, when you are training in the beginning of the game. You can only use this sword in kid form.Master SwordMaster Sword Main page: Master SwordYou gain the Master Sword after you gain all the Spiritual Stones as a kid. It is much stronger then the Kokiri Sword and can only be used as an adultGiant's Knife/Biggoron's SwordGiant's knifeThese swords are both unique. The Giant's Knife breaks easily but the Biggoron's Sword does not. You have to use two hands to hold them making it hard to defend yourself.ShieldsDeku ShieldDeku Shield Main page: Deku ShieldYou gain this shield after you gain the Kokiri Sword. You need both in order to enter your first dungeon. The Deku Shield is wooden which makes it very fragile and it can burn easily. This can only be used in kid form.Hylian ShieldHylian Shield Main page: Hylian ShieldYou can gain this shield in the town out side of the castle. You can use this as a kid but it is to heavy to lift. So you can not block and attack at the same time. Once you are an adult, you can block and attack with it.Mirror ShieldMirror Shield Main page: Mirror ShieldYou gain this shield in the Spirit Temple. It's basically the same as the Hylian Shield, but it can reflect magic and light.TunicsKokiri TunicLink's Kokiri TunicThe Kokiri Tunic is the standard Tunic. You can wear it both as a kid and adult.Goron TunicGoron TunicThe Goron Tunic can be found in Goron City, in its shop. You can only wear it as an adult. It protects you from heat.Zora TunicZora TunicThe Zora Tunic can be found in the Zora's Shop or given to you buy Ruto before entering the Water Temple. You can only wear it as an adult. It allows you to go deep underwater for unlimited amount of time.BootsKokiri BootsKokiri BootsBoth adult and youth forms can wear the Kokiri Boots. They are the main foot wear. You'll wear them for most of the game.Iron BootsIron Boots Main page: Iron BootsThe Iron Boots can be found in the Ice Cavern. They are used to allow adult Link to sink to the bottom of a body of water or to stay on Link's feet when confronted with strong fans.Hover BootsHover BootsThe Hover Boots can be found in the Shadow Temple. They can be used to hover over empty areas. Though they only do that for a short period of time.StorageDeku Seed Bag This is used to store your deku seeds for your slingshot. The amount you can hold can go up. Only used as a child.Quiver This keeps your arrows for your bow. This also can be upgraded. It can only be used as an adult.Bomb Bag This is what holds your bombs, both regular and Bombchus. It is used by both kid and adult Link. It can be upgraded.OthersOcarina of TimeOcarina of Time Main page: OcarinaZelda throws it at you in one of the games few cut scenes. It replaces your Fairy Ocarina that Saria gave to you. Though the Ocarina of Time allows you to open the Door of Time.Deku NutsDeku NutsThese are one of the first weapons you find in the game. They usually stun enemies. They can be used both as a kid and adult.Deku StickDeku Stick Main page: Deku StickAlong with the Deku Nuts they are one of the first weapons you find in the game. They can be used to help light things on fire. They break easy in combat.Fairy SlingshotFairy SlingshotThis the kid version of the Bow. You find it in the Great Deku Tree. It does almost the same tasks as the bow.Fairy BowFairy BowThis replaces the Slingshot. You get this in the Forest Temple. It can only be used in adult form.HookshotHookshot Main page: HookshotYou gain this by winning a race in the Graveyar d. It allows you to grab a hold of objects and enemies far away. Though the range is limited.LongshotLongshotYou can find it in the Water Temple. This does the same job as the Hookshot, but it can reach much much farther, but only can be used as Adult LinkMegaton HammerMegaton HammerThis hammer is found in the Fire Temple. It is used to smash rusted blocks and smash enemies.Lens of TruthLens of Truth Main page: Lens of TruthFound in the well at Kakariko Village. It is used to help find hidden objects. You can only get it in kid form. But can be used by adult and kid link.BottlesEmpty Bottle In Hyrule there are 4 empty bottles that can be found, which are extremely rare and very useful.Nintendo 3DS RemakeOcarina of Time 3D It was announced at E3 2010 that Ocarina of Time would be getting it's first real remake on Nintendo 3DS. The graphics have been greatly improved and according to Miyamoto there will be significant updates to the gameplay like being able to switch the Iron Boots on and off from the touch screen making the Water Temple less of a hassle. It will also, of course, be playable in 3D.Soundtrack1."Title Theme"1:202."Enter Ganondorf"0:133."Deku Tree"0:364."Fairy Flying"0:235."House"0:366."Kokiri Forest"1:017."Open Treasure Box"0:108."Item Catch"0:049."Small Item Catch"0:0510."Shop"1:0811."Battle"1:0712."Inside the Deku Tree"1:2713."Boss Battle"1:1914."Boss Clear"0:1315."Heart Container Get"0:0516."Legend of Hyrule"1:5817."Spiritual Stone Get"0:1618."Fairy Ocarina Get"0:1119."Hyrule Field Main Theme"4:4320."Kepora Gebora's Theme"1:0021."Market"0:5922."Shooting Gallery"0:3923."Hyrule Castle Courtyard"0:5324."Enter Zelda"0:0625."Ocarina "Zelda's Lullaby""0:1226."Zelda's Theme"0:4927."Ocarina "Epona's Song""0:0928."LonLon Ranch"2:0829."Mini Game"0:3230."Kakariko Village"1:4431."Ocarina "Sun's Song""0:0732."Hyrule Field Morning Theme"0:3733."Goron City"1:3834."Ocarina "Saria's Song""0:0935."Lost Woods"0:3936."Dodongo's Cavern"0:4637."Middle Boss Battle"1:0738."Dinosaur Boss Battle"1:0839."Zora's Domain"1:3040."Great Fairy's Fountain"0:3541."Potion Shop"0:5242."Inside Jabu-Jabu's Belly"0:3443."Ocarina "Song of Time""0:1244."Temple of Time"1:1945."Open Door of Temple of Time"0:1546."Master Sword"0:1347."Ganondorf's Theme"0:4148."Chamber of the Sages"1:4349."Medal Get Fanfare"0:1450."Sheik's Theme"0:3051."Horse Race"0:4652."Horse Race Goal"0:0553."Ingo's Theme"0:3954."Escape from LonLon Ranch"0:0955."Kakariko Village Orchestra Ver."1:4456."Ocarina "Song of Storms""0:0757."Windmill Hut"0:5258."Minuet of Woods"0:1759."Forest Temple"1:5260."Bolero of Fire"0:2061."Fire Temple"0:4262."Ice Cavern"0:4563."Serenade of Water"0:1964."Water Temple"1:4465."Nocturne of Shadow"0:2366."Prelude of Light"0:1867."Shadow Temple"1:4568."Gerudo Valley"1:3469."Spirit Temple"2:5770."Requiem of Spirit"0:2471."Kotake  Koume's Theme"0:5272."Meet Again Zelda"0:5173."Game Over"0:0974."Ganon's Castle Bridge"0:2275."Ganon's Castle Under Ground"0:5376."Inside Ganon's Castle"3:2677."Ganondorf's Battle"1:1278."Escape from Ganon's Castle"0:3379."Last Battle"2:1080."Seal of Six Sages"0:2981."Ocarina of Time"0:3282."End Credits"7:10</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15835">Beyond Good &amp; Evil</game><game id="19026">Star Fox Adventures</game><game id="19228">Kameo: Elements of Power</game><game id="20555">Ōkami</game><game id="13668">Musashi: Samurai Legend</game><game id="12614">Sphinx and the Cursed Mummy</game><game id="10682">Hercules: The Legendary Journeys</game><game id="5570">Alundra</game><game id="20543">Mushroom Men: The Spore Wars</game><game id="6243">Mystical Ninja Starring Goemon</game><game id="21693">Dinotopia: The Sunstone Odyssey</game><game id="22950">Castlevania</game><game id="25405">Melkor</game><game id="21881">Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles: The Crystal Bearers</game><game id="11829">Alundra 2</game><game id="28006">Okamiden</game><game id="6522">Shadow of the Colossus</game><game id="28080">Enslaved: Odyssey to the West</game><game id="7791">Kong: The 8th Wonder of the World</game><game id="42053">Evoland</game><game id="42409">Spud's Quest</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2204862-box_tlozoot.png</image></root>