<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12592</id><name>WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2008</name><description>Game OverviewSmackdown vs. Raw 2008 introduces the new ECW Rules Match (hardcore match) as well as new playable ECW wrestlers. The 9th edition of the franchise was released in November 2007, for platforms such as the Xbox 360, Playstation 3, Playstation 2, Wii, PSP, and Nintendo DS.  It was also the first Smackdown vs. Raw game completely available for all next gen systems.  Game FeaturesThis game introduced a new struggle type submission and release system. Each wrestler would have two fighting styles which were:  high-flyer,  hardcore,  submission artist, powerhouse, showman, brawler,  dirty and technical. Some finishers and signature moves would be reanimated to make it more stronger visually. New weapon selection for weapons underneath the ring was introduced as well as the ability to set fire to tables, guitars and barbwire bats  ModesWWE 24/7 was introduced as a wrestler would make decisions everyday of every hour and it would alter any situation.  However it only gave limited choices and became repetitive as time progressed.  Money in The Bank tournament was introduced, and provided a King Of The Ring style to the game. ECW Hardcore match was introduced along with all of the other match types.  RosterRAWSmackDownECWLegends                                                            Bobby Lashley                                                           Candice Michelle #                                                          Carlito                                                         Jeff Hardy                                                        John Cena                                                       JTG                                                      King Booker                                                     Mr. Kennedy                                                    Melina #                                                   Mickie James #                                                  Randy Orton                                                 Sandman                                                Shad                                               Shane McMahon                                              Shawn Michaels                                             Snitsky                                            Triple H                                           Umaga #                                          Mr. McMahon                                         William Regal #                                        Ashley #                                       Batista                                      Chavo Guerrero #                                     Chris Masters #                                    Edge                                   Finlay                                  The Great Khali #                                 Gregory Helms                                Hardcore Holly ^                               JBL                              Kane                             Kenny Dykstra                            Mark Henry #                           Matt Hardy #                          Michelle McCool #                         MVP                        Rey Mysterio                       Ric Flair                      Torrie Wilson #                     Undertaker                    CM Punk                   Elijah Burke                  Johnny Nitro                 Kelly Kelly #                Marcus Cor Von               Bret Hart #              Eddie Guerrero *             Jim Neidhart *            Mick Foley #           Rick Rude #          The Rock #         Roddy Piper #   Sgt. Slaughter *        Sabu (ECW) #       Steve Austin #      Terry Funk (ECW) #     Tommy Dreamer (ECW) #* Exclusive to PSP version^ Exclusive to Nintendo DS version# Not included in Nintendo DS versionSoundtrackArtistSong 8 Ball  MJG Stand UpAM ConspiracyRight on TimeWeltChevelleWell Enough AloneHellyeahYou Wouldn't KnowNobody FamousGo HardNonpointEverybody DownProject 86Evil (A Chorus of Resistance)Put Your Lips to the TVPuddle of MuddFamousSevendustDrivenFeed Xbox 360 Installation The amount of memory it takes to install this game is 5.7 GB.</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre><genre id="10">Wrestling</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20469">TNA iMPACT!</game><game id="18320">WCW/nWo Revenge</game><game id="557">WCW vs. the World</game><game id="18333">Backyard Wrestling 2: There Goes the Neighborhood</game><game id="20723">WWE Legends of WrestleMania</game><game id="7552">WWE SmackDown! Shut Your Mouth</game><game id="10158">M.U.S.C.L.E.</game><game id="12635">Rumble Roses XX</game><game id="18086">Rumble Roses</game><game id="8697">The Simpsons Wrestling</game><game id="22390">Monday Night Raw</game><game id="22464">Wrestling Encore</game><game id="2308">WWE Day of Reckoning</game><game id="1204">WCW Mayhem</game><game id="3826">WWF Super Wrestlemania</game><game id="13440">Backyard Wrestling: Don't Try This at Home</game><game id="30637">Lucha Libre AAA Heroes del Ring</game><game id="28430">WWF Royal Rumble</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1817088-box_wwesd2008.png</image></root>