<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12621</id><name>TimeSplitters</name><description>The first game in the Timesplitters series takes you through many locations as many characters, from cops to barely clothed women with miniguns to mutant dockworkers to robots in a shopping mall in 2014.CharactersCaptain AshLady JaneDet. Harry TipperLt. Christine MaloneDeacon SwaineChastity DetroitDr. Seth GravenDr. Katje NadirFingers McKenzieRavelle VelvetSebastian PhotonAngel PerezPeekaboo JonesMary-Beth CaseyJacques MisereOlga StromR 108GretelCultistPriestessTeeth MummyEyes MummyPriest MutantFishwife MutantHick HydeInsect MutantOverall MutantPolice ZombieGirl ZombieSkull ZombieJacket ZombieGreen ZombieBrown ZombieChinese ChefChinese WaiterMalehoodMale SWATFemale SWATGasmask SWATVeiled SWATSuit HoodlumMr. BigMale SoldierFemale SoldierShock TooperLumberjackBadass CyborgSiamese CyborgFemale CyborgSpaceways StewardessTuxedo CyborgRed AlienFemale AlienPillar AlienGreen AlienFloat AlienDuckman DrakeRobofishThe ImpersonatorGingerbread ManFarrah Fun-BunnyTimeSplitter #1TimeSplitter #2Critical ReceptionMost critics praised its originality in gameplay and art, as well as its fast paced and addictive multiplayer. A majority of the criticisms stem from its short length and sometimes frustrating level of difficulty. The PC style Map-Maker feature was considered a great feature and also garnered praise. Most reviewers gave this game a 8, or four out of five stars.TriviaAlthough TimeSplitters is the first in the series, it isn't necessarily considered canon. The only information given to the player about the story is that the Timesplitters are searching for the Time Crystals. In each level you must locate a Time Crystal and get to the beginning of the level to win. It isn't explained why or how your character knows about the crystal. Also, many of the main characters' and enemies' stories and appearances have since been drastically changed.This game is considered the second most difficult in the franchise, behind TimeSplitters 2.Out of the nine team members who originally worked on Goldeneye 007 , four of them went on to form Free Radical Design and create Timesplitters shortly after they finished development on Perfect Dark.</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17246">TimeSplitters 2</game><game id="8099">TimeSplitters: Future Perfect</game><game id="11291">Mace Griffin: Bounty Hunter</game><game id="17448">Unreal Tournament</game><game id="20458">Warhawk</game><game id="15481">Star Wars: Battlefront</game><game id="20455">Haze</game><game id="3874">Quake III Arena</game><game id="3207">Quake II</game><game id="25048">Drug Wars</game><game id="10047">Turok 3: Shadow of Oblivion</game><game id="21388">Quake Live</game><game id="21256">Perfect Dark</game><game id="15341">Second Sight</game><game id="24858">Darkest of Days</game><game id="40931">Quake III: Revolution</game><game id="3166">GoldenEye 007</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2151663-box_ts.png</image></root>