<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12633</id><name>Call of Duty: United Offensive</name><description>OverviewCall of Duty: United Offensive is the first and only expansion pack available for any game in the Call of Duty series at this point. It offered a brand new campaign and also a variety of new features, maps, and multiplayer modes. Call of Duty: United Offensive requires the original game to play, it is not a stand alone expansion packStoryThe story follows a similar system as it did in the original Call of Duty. It follows three soldiers through various battles in World War 2. One of these is an American named Scott Riley, a British soldier named James Doyale, and a Russian solider named Yuri Petrenko. The story also follows the 'Call of Duty mold' as the game is mainly made up of well known and famous battles in World War 2. In United Offensives players will find themselves thrown into the Battle of the Bulge, The Liberation of Sicily, and a variety of others.New FeaturesCall of Duty: United Offensive offers a variety of new features which were intended to build on both the singleplayer and multiplayer aspects of the game.Some of the new additions to both multiplayer and singleplayer alike are the additions of vehicles and new weapons.Vehicles addedTanksJeepsWeapons addedSVT-40Degtyaryov 28TT-33Gewher 43MG-34PanzerFlamethrowerBazookaBrowning .30 Caliber Machine GunWebley RevolverMultiplayerThe game also received a massive overhaul on the multiplayer in the game. Many players considered the additions alienating to Call of Duty fans as it brought the game into a more Battlefield-esque style of gaming. Many of the maps added were larger then before like Foy and Sicily which were built for the new modes.New Multiplayer ModesCapture The Flag:This is your standard capture the flag mode where both teams compete to defend your teams flag or capture the other teams flag. This mode was a standard at this time as it was a mode featured in many other online games such as Unreal Tournament.Domination:The goal of this mode is to take over all the control points and defend your own held points from capture. This is similar to conquest mode as seen in the Battlefield games, and would later see precedence in all future Call of Duty titles.Base Assault:Base Assault is a variation on domination where instead of capturing the bases your goal is to destroy it. This is possible through the new use of vehicles or bazookas.New Rank SystemCall of Duty: United Offensive also offered a new rank system. It was not a persistent rank system though, instead in each game you start off at the beginning as a private. Throughout the game you will rank up based on your kill count or score. In turn this will earn you perks like being able to call in artillary, addition ammo, or satchel charges. There are five ranks:Private - NoneRifleman - Additional grenades and pistol ammoSquad Leader - Scouting Binoculars. Squad leaders can use binoculars, which are useful for scouting over long distances, spotting approacing attacks and monitoring combat from afar.Section Sergeant - Satchel Charges. Section Sergeants spawn in the game with satchel charges already in their weapons inventory. Lower ranked players can still use satchel charges, but they must be picked up from the map.Platoon Sergeant - Artillery strike. Platoon Sergeants can now use the binoculars they acquired at rank 3 to call in a deadly artillery strike anywhere on the map.These can be attributed to the primitive forms of killstreaks seen in the later games in the franchise like Call of Duty 4, World at War, and Modern Warfare 2.PC System RequirementsAs displayed on the back cover of the box (Please note that only the minimun requirements are given)Full Version of the Original Call of Duty.Operating System: Microsoft Windows 98 / ME / 2000 / XP.CPU (Processor): Pentium 3 800MHz or Athlon 800MHz processor or higher.RAM: 128MB (256MB recommended).GPU (Video Card): 3D Hardware accelerator card required. 100% Direct X 9.0b compatible 32MB hardware TL capable video card and the latest drivers.Direct X Version: Dirext X 9.0b (included).Sound Card: 100% direct X 9.0b compatible 16-bit sound card latest drivers.HDD (Hard Disc) space: 1150MB of uncompressed free hard disk space (plus 400MB for Windows 98 / ME swap file, 600MB for Windows 2000 / XP swap file).</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16121">Day of Defeat: Source</game><game id="6074">Day of Defeat</game><game id="19230">Medal of Honor</game><game id="6026">Medal of Honor: Airborne</game><game id="8271">Commandos: Strike Force</game><game id="4857">Medal of Honor: Frontline</game><game id="16752">Medal of Honor: Rising Sun</game><game id="20834">Brothers in Arms: Hell's Highway</game><game id="20940">Brothers in Arms: Double Time</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2383339-315.jpg</image></root>