<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12710</id><name>Onimusha 3: Demon Siege</name><description>Overview The 3rd main installment of the       Onimusha franchise follows       Samanosuke Akechi just like the 1st game as he is defeating the Genma army in      Japan.       Nobunaga's demon minions manage to open a time portal which takes everyone to       Paris in 2004. Samanosuke is then also joined by a cop       Jacques Blanc ( who has the face, but not the voice, of French actor Jean Reno) who aids him on his mission. Plot As the game starts Samonosuke is heading for       Honnō-ji Temple, where he defeats Ranmaru Mori and finally approaches Nobunaga. But before they can fight a time portal opens and Samanosuke is pulled through, ending up in Paris in 2004 where the Genma are attacking civilians and wreaking havoc. The French military try to fight them off but are unable to cope with the Genma's large numbers. Jacques Blanc arrives, finding his friend Philippe injured. Samanosuke appears through the portal right where Jacques is fighting the Genma monsters and rescues the Frenchman as he runs out of ammo. They find that they are unable to communicate. Moments later another time portal appears but pulling Jacques and Philippe through to Japan in the feudal era. Arc  de Triomphe in Onimusha 3Samanosuke makes his way to       Arc de Triomphe which seems to be the center of the problem. Near the Arc he meets Michelle, Jacques girlfriend as he then makes his way towards the roof. This is where he meets       Guildenstern and learns that he is over 500 years in the future in Paris. Jacques Blanc and Philippe now arrive in 16th Century Japan. Not long after Philippe dies from mortal wounds from the previous battle with the Genma. Jacques encounters a different Samanosuke in an alternate timeline on his way to Honnō-ji Temple. Both Jacques and Samanosuke understand that to return to their normal time they must save the current time from destruction. In Paris 2004 Samanosuke gets help from Michelle and Jacques son, Henri,  to save the world from the Genma threat. Meanwhile, Jacques and the other Samanosuke battle against Nobunaga's armies. Both Samanosuke and Jacques mus work together across time and space to ensure their survival and the defeat of Nobunaga and Guildenstern.GameplayOnimusha 3 is the first game in the series to feature fully 3D environments - the pre-rendered backgrounds from the previous games are done away with. Another first for the game is the option to play the game with the analog stick. From time to time the player will first play as Samanosuke, then switch to Jacques throughout the game; and sometimes play as Jacques's girlfriend, Michelle, on Samanosuke's playthrough.Other Info 1 Player PlayStation 2379 KB minimum for save dataAnalog Control CompatibleVibration Function Compatible MiscellaneousAn Onimusha 3 pachislot     slot machine was released in Japan to help promote the game.  The pachislot machine features a high quality front panel crafted from a huge 20 inch monitor.An Onimusha 3 slot machine The machine's middle section will display the three slot machine reels. While playing the pachislot version, you'll get to see the characters from Onimusha 3, moving around in real time with PS2 quality graphics. The pachislot has a level of interactivity similar to that of a video game, your earnings will affect events on the screen, and you'll also get bonus scores at certain points in the game.      System Requirements(at launch) Supported OS: Windows 2000/XP (only)Processor: Pentium III 1GHz, AMD Athlon 1 GHz (or better)RAM: 256 MB of RAM (1 GB Recommended)Video Card: 128 MB DirectX 9.0c-compliant AGP or PCI Express graphics card (256 MB or higher for High Graphics Detail support)Sound Card: DirectX 9.0c-compliant sound card (or better)DirectX Version: DirectX 9.0c or higher (Direct X 9.0c included on disk)CD-ROM: 12x or faster CD-ROMHard Drive Space: 2 GB minimumPeripherals Supported: Gamepad and headset    </description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16741">Devil May Cry 2</game><game id="13072">Devil May Cry</game><game id="20461">God of War III</game><game id="6959">God of War</game><game id="11314">God of War II</game><game id="20592">God of War: Chains of Olympus</game><game id="5235">Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time</game><game id="17357">Prince of Persia: Warrior Within</game><game id="21380">Prince of Persia: The Two Thrones</game><game id="6290">Batman: Vengeance</game><game id="14034">Rygar: The Legendary Adventure</game><game id="15790">Castlevania: Lament of Innocence</game><game id="12568">Master Chu And The Drunkard Hu</game><game id="32687">Ninja Gaiden 3</game><game id="2838">Bujingai: The Forsaken City</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2115768-box_onimusha3.png</image></root>