<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12769</id><name>Crystal Kingdom Dizzy</name><description>Crystal Kingdom Dizzy was released in 1992 by Codemasters.  Featuring the egg shaped titular hero Dizzy, it is officially recognised as the final game of the Dizzy series for the home computers of that generation.The game had much improved graphics over the former games in the Dizzy series, featuring vibrant full colour as opposed to the majority of the series which only had a very bland colour scheme.  The game generally looked great in all versions although the ZX Spectrum version did not feature full colour.It was also the first game in the series that retailed for the full price £9.99 compared with previous Dizzy titles which sold for around £2-3.With some slightly tweaked gameplay you once again travel the lands solving puzzles whilst searching for the mystical crystal treasures of the Yolkfolk which had been stolen.  If not returned then prophecy tells the Yolkfolk that their land will be forever cast in darkness. A great game and a fitting end to the Dizzy series.Title screen. The in game instructions featured the following text to help set the scene for Dizzy's adventure:   The sun does not always shine in the Yolkfolk village. In fact, this particular day is looking remarkably grim. Stormy clouds thunder across the sky, the rain hammers down, the electricity flickers and,to top it all, Grand Dizzy is in an awful mood.The source of Grand Dizzy's bad mood is his egg-ache. The old duffer had been practising his somersaults in the kitchen and slipped on the wet floor. "What do you think you're doing bouncing around like that at your age?!" groaned Dizzy under the strain of picking up the old egg. "You'll give yourself a nasty crack on the head.""It's the temple in the Crystal Kingdom," spluttered Grand Dizzy, "it's been robbed. Every egg knows that if the crystal sword, chalice and crown are removed from the temple, strange things will happen to the Yolkfolk!"Dizzy looked outside. Things did look decidedly bad. "It still doesn't explain why you were jumping off the kitchen chair, Grand Dizzy" said Dizzy. "Well, young fella-m'-egg," said Grand Dizzy puffing himself up slightly, "I'm sick and tired of you always sorting things out. I'm going to get into shape, pack my knapsack and save the Yolkfolk myself. I was really heroic in my day, y'know."A salty tear formed in Dizzy's eye. "I don't know, Grand Dizzy, what are we going to do with you?" gushed Dizzy in his best sympathetic, yet caring, voice.Grand Dizzy was packed off to bed. But the moment everyone's back was turned, he jumped up and continued to whinge loudly at anything he could find that would listen.Dizzy decided that he must begin his trek to retrieve the Yolkfolk's treasure. He packed his knapsack and popped on his new safari hat. Dizzy grimaced and, through his gritted teeth, dramaticallydeclared "Don't fear, Grand Dizzy! The lost treasures of the Yolkfolk will soon be found!". And so Dizzy began a whole new adventure - can our hero succeed again?</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="34465">Clover: A Curious Tale</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1013/291749-dizzy___crystal_kingdomc64.jpg</image></root>