<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12771</id><name>World Cup 98</name><description>Overview World Cup 98 is the first FIFA game devloped by Electronic Arts based on the event. Electronic Arts bought the rights to use the FIFA name, teams and players. It is the first World Cup game played in 3D rather than a 2D perspective. The game also used the same graphics engine that was featured in the previously released FIFA Road to the World Cup.   Gameplay   Real teams and players were featured in the gameThe game contained many elements of the World Cup, and this adds realism to the game. Every player and team at the time is featured in the game with realistic stats. There are exhibition, World Cup, Road to the World Cup, tournament and multiplayer modes. You could also customize teams and players to create the team you want to use. The game can be played in many different perspectives. The camera can be moved to a traditional birds eye perspective or it could be zoomed in to show off the 3D graphics.  Shootout is an event that can break a tieYou will always be in control of the player who has the ball on offense. To defend you can cycle through players, but the game will often give you control to the proper man. Games will often end in draws, but you are able to choose sudden death or shoot out modes to break the tie. The game featured authenthic commentarry and licensed music. Real life announcers recorded a large amount of commentary to be used in the play by play of the game. Licensed music was usually featured throughout many of the game menus.  An interesting mode included in the game was Classic. In this mode you put in famous World Cup scenarios, and you are to meet requirements to beat it. There were many inconsistencies in the mode, but it did loosly follow the real life events. Teams Europe  Austria Belgium Bulgaria Croatia Denmark England France Germany Italy Netherlands Norway Romania Scotland Spain  Yugoslavia  Americas  Argentina Brazil Chile Colombia Jamaica Mexico Paraguay USA Africa  Cameroon Morocco Nigeria South Africa Tunisia Middle East  Iran Saudi Arabia  Asia   Japan South Korea Stadiums  Stade de France Stade Velodrome Parc des Prince Stade Felix Bollaert Stade Gerland Stade de la Beaujoire Stade de Toulouse Seutade Geoffroy Guichard Parc de Lecure Stade de la Mosson</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="40">Soccer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9790">International Superstar Soccer 64</game><game id="37">FIFA Soccer 07</game><game id="6106">International Superstar Soccer</game><game id="5089">Michael Owen’s World League Soccer ‘99</game><game id="27488">Three Lions</game><game id="38671">Nippon Daihyou Team: Eikou no Eleven</game><game id="38800">J-League Supporter Soccer</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2266561-box_wc98.png</image></root>