<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12909</id><name>Crash Bandicoot: Warped</name><description>Crash Bandicoot 3: Warped was a platformer developed by the studio Naughty Dog for the original Sony Playstation. The game served the purpose of a sequel to the previous entry in the franchise, Crash Bandicoot 2: Cortex Strikes Back. It was the last platformer developed by Naughty Dog for this franchise, who then went on to make the successful “CTR” or Crash Team Racing which would become the last Crash title developed by them.OverviewThe story centers on our hero known simply to us as Crash and his sister Coco Bandicoot and their on-going goal to gather pink crystals scattered across time before their enemies can do the same. There are sections in which the player plays as Crash, while in other sections the player gets to control Coco. Warped was the first Crash Bandicoot game to feature a demo of Insomniac Games' highly successful Spyro The Dragon. These demos would last until until a later entry in the Crash franchise, “Crash Bash” was released.StoryAt the end of Crash Bandicoot 2 Cortex's Vortex was destroyed and it's pieces fell down to earth. One of those pieces hit an ancient temple located on Cortex's island. This freed the ancient mask known as Uka Uka, Aku Aku's evil brother. We find out that Uka Uka had been commanding Cortex from inside his temple prison and is now angry about the way the past two endeavours have gone. Uka Uka tells Cortex that there are still crystals left, all scattered across time, The two get the help of Dr.N.Trophy to build a time machine and send their minions on a mission to get the crystals. back on N.Sanity Island, Aku Aku senses something wrong and finds the warp rooms so Crash and Coco can stop Cortex and Uka Uka's new plot. After Collecting all of the Crystals, Gems and relics, Crash faces Cortex and Uka Uka for a final time. The Time rift sends Cortex, Uka Uka and N. Trophy through a time rift where they discover that they have turned into babies. If not the two get trapped in a hole after the last fight. Whilst the former ending is the 100% ending, there is speculation whether it is canonical or not if we regard the next game in the series, Crash Team Racing, to be canonical as Cortex, Uka Uka and N.Trophy make an appearance.New ItemsRelicA Sapphire Time RelicAs well as a Crystal and a Gem, levels now had relics. Once the crystal was acquired in a level and Crash went back in a clock was available at the start if Crash hit the clock a timer would start and a time trial began. If crash could beat a time a relic would be unlocked. Whilst the game would accept any relic for the games full ending there were three kinds, which of the three you got depended on your time. The three relics were normal, gold and platinum, you would initially only get the time for the normal relic then once you had it you would get the target for gold however, if you beat the gold or platinum time first time you would still get awarded the respective relic.Timer BoxA new crate that switched its contents depending on when you hit it. The change of contents would get faster the longer you left it and if you did not break the box in time it would turn to steel, meaning the player could not obtain the levels gem.GameplayCrash 3 world mapCrash Bandicoot Warped followed a very similar ply style to it's two predecessors, Crash would have to jump and spin his way through a series of levels and boss fights to complete the game, smashing all boxes in the level to obtain a gem. The game was most like Crash Bandicoot 2 in that Crash had to find a Crystal in each level to complete it. Like in Crash 2, crash would gain a new skill after fighting every boss such as a double jump or a body slam. Crash Bandicoot Warped had the most varied gameplay of the series with new levels such as Jet ski challenges, motorbike races and airplane fights. Coco was playable in the game however was always riding a tiger or in a jet ski or plane. Bonus levels worked the same way that they did in Crash Bandicoot 2, giving puzzles to those who wished to obtain the gem. Crash Bandicoot Warped was the first Crash game not to be set on the three islands alone, Crash would visit a number of locations on the globe spanning millions of years of history in order to get the crystals. The image below shows some of those locations.StructureCrash Bandicoot Warped followed most of the Structure that Crash 2 had set up, the player would be given levels in sets of five through five warp rooms also known as time travel areas in this game. The player could tackle these levels in which ever order they wished. Once the Crystal had been unlocked in all five levels a boss fight would become unlocked and needed to be beaten in order to progress to the next set of levels. The Warp Rooms weren't in scattered locations like in the second game but were in fact all branching off one main hub.Warp Room OneA Medieval looking hub.LevelsToad Village - A fairy tale inspired medieval level with wizards goats and magical transformed frogs to avoid.Under Pressure - An underwater side scrolling level with sharks and turbines in Crash's way.Orient Express - The first animal ride level, Coco must ride Pura the tiger across the Great Wall of China.Bone Yard - Crash must escape from a rampaging triceratops.Makin' Waves - Coco must use her jet ski to avoid bombs and pirate ships.Warp Room End Boss - Tiny TigerGladiator TinyTiny Tiger makes a return in Crash Bandicoot 3 after his original appearance in Crash Bandicoot 2. Tiny demands that Crash give his crystals to him in a colosseum in ancient Rome. Crash must avoid Tiny until he gets his fork stuck in the ground, leaving him open. After Tiny is hit he calls upon lions that run out at Crash. After Tiny is defeated, Crash gets the body slam ability. This differs from the normal body slam in that Crash spins 360 degrees in the air and it has a larger damage radius.Warp Room TwoA Persian looking hub.LevelsGee Wiz- The second Medieval level, wizards will try and turn Crash into a frog here.Hang 'Em High - An Arabian town where sword wielding guards and bouncing carpets face crash.Hog Ride- The first motorbike race, set in the fifties.Tomb Time - A level set in ancient Egypt, Crash enters an ancient tomb.Midnight Run - The second animal ride on the Great Wall, this time at night.Warp Room End Boss - DingodileDingodileDingodile is one of Cortex's experiments. He is half dingo half crocodile, Crash must fight Dingodile in a frozen cave but avoid his lava gun. Dingodile will shoot upward so crash will have to look for the shadows of the lava shots to avoid them. Spinning shards of ice will then fall and obstruct crash from Dingodile, if Crash can get through in time then he can hit Dingodile. Double jump is unlocked after Dingodile is defeated.Warp Room ThreeAn oriental looking hubLevelsDino Might!- another prehistoric level, here Crash crosses tar pits and meets a friendly baby T.Rex.Deep Trouble- The second under water level.High Time- The second Arabian level, Crash has to monkey over pits avoiding scorpions.Road Crash- The second bike race, watch out for alien signs!Double header- A medieval level with double headed giants.Warp Room End Boss - Dr. N. TropyN.TrophyDr N. Tropy will use his time travelling powers to change the area of the boss battle many times. He will remain at one end of a large gap with you at the other. Crash must avoid his shots to eventually get a pathway to hit N.Tropy. After the battle Crash gets a death tornado spin move.Warp Room FourAn ancient Egyptian style hubLevelsSphynxinator- Another Egyptian level inside a Cortex shaped Sphynx.Bye Bye Blimps- The first airplane level where Crash must destroy blimps whilst fending off Cortex's minions.Tell No Tales- The second Jet Ski level.Future Frenzy- A level in a futuristic metropolis, avoiding lasers and minions in hover vehicles.Tomb Wader- An Egyptian level where Crash has to time his jumps over rising and falling water levels.Warp Room End Boss - Dr. N. GinN.GinN.Gin returns with a larger mech than before. This time Coco must use a spaceship to fight N.Gin, After his initial ship is destroyed the machine has a back up, Coco must shoot the weapons of N.Gin's ship when they show their weak points. After the battle Crash gets a Bazooka loaded with wumpa fruit to destroy far away enemies.Warp Room FiveA futuristic style hub.LevelsGone Tomorrow- Another future metropolis level that makes good use of the Bazooka.Orange Asphalt- Another motorbike race taking place at sunset.Flaming Passion - An Arabian level with enemies throwing flammable objects out of windowsMad Bombers- Crash must shoot down bomber planes to get the crystal.Bug Light- Crash must make his way through the dark Egyptian tomb with the aid of fireflies.Warp Room End Boss - Dr. Neo Cortex and Uka UkaCortex and Uka UkaIn this final fight, Crash must face against Cortex whilst Aku Aku faces Uka Uka. Crash must dodge Cortex's shots whilst avoiding what Aku Aku and Uka Uka are doing. Cortex will drop mines which cause his shields to drop, if crash knocks him off his hover board he can be spun into the central hole and damaged before Uka Uka saves him. Eventually the two will fall down the hole and one of the endings will play depending on the players progress. After beating Cortex, Crash obtains the 'Crash Dash' ability. This allows Crash to run much faster than normal and is a very useful ability when attempting to earn relics.Secret Warp RoomWhen the player obtains enough Relics a platform will appear in the middle of the main hub, this leads to a secret warp room.LevelsSki Crazed- A radioactive Jet Ski level.Hang 'Em High- A return to level 7 to get the yellow gem.Area 51- A motorbike race against UFO's.Future Frenzy- A return to level 19 to get the gem.Rings Of Fire- An airplane level that involves flying through rings to complete.Other SecretsIf the player collects 30 gold relics and talks to Coco a fireworks display will occur.There are also 2 more secret levels through 2 levels in the the 3rd warp room, Dino Might!, and Road Crash. The first secret level, known as Eggipus Rex, is in Dino Might!. This level is very similar to Dino Might!, however it is more of a side scroller and has no crystal. In order to gain entrence, you must have the yellow gem (as the way in is on that route). when you first start running from the triceratops you will notice multiple terradactyl s. The 2nd one you see will take you to the first secret level (it will also be on the left side to make it eaiser).The 2nd secret level, known as Hot Coco is a water ski level with Coco. Like the other secret level this one has no crystal in it, so it is not needed to beat the game with the regular ending. To enter Hot Coco you need to in Road Crash. Keep going until you see an unusual sign with an alien on it. Ram it over, and claim your prize. This level is very similar to other jet ski levels except it is ine giant circle and the entrence is also the exit. However in order to get the gem in this level you must still get all the boxes by going around the entire area and hitting them.ReceptionCrash Bandicoot 3: Warped has received positive reviews from fans and major critics alike, and has sold well over 5.16 million copies worldwide, with 3.76 million copies selling in the United States alone, and an additional 1.4 million copies selling in Japan. The game, although being released only to the original PlayStation, was released for download on both the Playstation Portable and PlayStation3 on February 7 2008 on the Playstation Network. Thus giving a new generation of gamers a chance to play this acclaimed sequel of the successful franchise.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19060">Sonic Adventure 2</game><game id="14623">Jak and Daxter: The Precursor Legacy</game><game id="18309">Ratchet &amp; Clank</game><game id="15212">Ratchet &amp; Clank Future: Tools of Destruction</game><game id="4228">Haven: Call of the King</game><game id="6134">The Legend of Spyro: The Eternal Night</game><game id="20330">Gex 3: Deep Cover Gecko</game><game id="15991">Chameleon Twist 2</game><game id="8014">Tomba!</game><game id="18376">Looney Tunes Back in Action</game><game id="9669">Jak 3</game><game id="13795">Pepsiman</game><game id="24704">Frogger</game><game id="9551">Disney's Donald Duck: Goin' Quackers</game><game id="96">Kao the Kangaroo</game><game id="26496">Agent Hugo: Lemoon Twist</game><game id="20963">Wario Land: Shake It!</game><game id="2906">Psychonauts</game><game id="21460">Gurumin: A Monstrous Adventure</game><game id="8660">Crash Bandicoot 2: Cortex Strikes Back</game><game id="5821">Rayman 3: Hoodlum Havoc</game><game id="14055">Disney's PK: Out of the Shadows</game><game id="27562">Disney Epic Mickey</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1803619-box_crashb3.png</image></root>