<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12926</id><name>Pokémon Colosseum</name><description>OverviewWes readying a catch in a Pokemon battlePokémon Colosseum is the first Pokémon game to be released for the Nintendo GameCube. Pokémon Colosseum is also the first three-dimensionally designed Pokémon RPG. The main gameplay strayed from the success of the other three-dimensional releases,Wes during the opening events of the gamethus for this reason, it was deemed less of a successor to the Nintendo 64 Pokémon Stadium series, but rather as an adaptation of the Game Boy console-level editions.Pokemon Colosseum is a role-playing game developed by Genius Sonority and published by Nintendo. It is the first full length 3D Pokemon game on a home console, The Nintendo Gamecube, and features many different gameplay changes from the traditional handheld titles including an emphasis on double battles, no gym leaders to fight, and no wild Pokemon to catch.StoryIn the region of Orre, Pokemon are being turned into heartless fighters by an evil group. You control a teenage boy, Wes, who during the opening of the game is seen destroying the evil Team Snagem's headquarters while also stealing their newest piece of technology, a portable snag machine, a device used for stealing Pokemon from their trainers. During the course of the game Wes travels around stealing Shadow Pokemon from the remaining members of Team Snagem as he discovers another growing threat in the Orre region.GameplayOrre's resting areaPokemon Colosseum features major gameplay changes compared to the Pokemon games of the past. In this title there are no random battles in the wild, meaning no Pokemon to catch by normal means. Instead you obtain new Pokemon by stealing them from other trainers that challenge you through the game. The catch to this though is you can only steal "Shadow Pokemon" which are Pokemon that had been stolen from their original trainers and been put through a painful process to become emotionless fighters. Thus there is a very limited number of obtainable Pokemon until you complete the main story where you are allowed to trade Pokemon over from the Gameboy Advance Pokemon games, Pokemon Ruby/Sapphire, Pokemon Emerald, and Pokemon Fire Red/Leaf Green.A typical battle in Pokemon ColosseumColosseum also features a more fleshed out story than previous Pokemon games with focus on clearing story points instead of going across a region collecting gym badges, as the Orre region has no gym challenge for the player to face. There is also a heavy emphasis on double battles a concept introduced in Pokemon Ruby/Sapphire, with very few one on one Pokemon battles throughout the entire game. The last major addition is with the Shadow Pokemon. These Pokemon start out only knowing one attack which causes recoil damage when used. They must be purified by spending time and fighting alongside Wes in order to gain levels, learn attacks, evolve, and be traded. Other from these changes Colosseum is similar to the other Pokemon games as you spend the majority of your time traveling from area to area while fighting other trainers to level your team of six.Obtainable Pokémon196. Espeon197. Umbreon296. Makuhita153. Bayleef156. Quilava159. Croconaw164. Noctowl180. Flaaffy188. Skiploom195. Quagsire200. Misdreavus218. Slugma162. Furret193. Yanma223. Remoraid226. Mantine211. Qwilfish307. Meditite206. Dunsparce333. Swablu185. Sudowoodo237. Hitmontop255. Entei166. Ledian256. Suicune207. Gligar234. Stantler221. Piloswine215. Sneasel190. Aipom198. Murkrow205. Forretress329. Vibrava168. Ariados210. Granbull243. Raikou192. Sunflora225. Delibird214. Heracross227. Skarmory241. Miltank359. Absol229. Houndoom357. Tropius376. Metagross248. Tyranitar235. Smeargle217. Ursaring213. Shuckle176. Togetic311. Plusle - Obtainable as a gift from Duking250. Ho-oh - Obtainable after all shadow pokemon have been snagged251. Celebi - Obtainable by Japanese bonus disc025. Pikachu - Obtainable by Japanese bonus disc385. Jirachi - Obtainable by American bonus disc175. Togepi - Obtainable by Japanese e-card179. Mareep - Obtainable by Japanese e-card212. Scizor - Obtainable by Japanese e-cardTriviaUntil the fourth generation remakes of Gold and Silver, the only way to obtain several second-generation, Pokemon, including the starters from gold and silver, was to transfer them from this game or from Pokemon XD: Gale of Darkness via the GBA-Gamecube transfer cable. This meant that in order to complete the Pokedex a Player needed to own a prohibitive amount of hardware.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13470">Dragon Warrior Monsters</game><game id="23375">Gangway Monsters</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2171278-box_pkmncol.png</image></root>