<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12939</id><name>Cyberdogs</name><description>OverviewCyberdogs can be played alone or in co-op mode with up to two players. If you choose to play the game in co-op, one person uses the regular arrow keys and the other person has to use regular letter keys to move around. You can change the keys set-up in the options menu, so you basically get to choose which keys you use to move and shoot if you don't like the regular setup. In the co-op mode, you can choose to play "every dog for itself", where you play against the same enemies but you don't share your earnings, or you can play it more "friendly" by sharing everything you get. The game will have more enemies and tougher objectives if you're playing co-op than when you're playing alone.CharactersThere are three characters you can play with:Ice (bald with sunglasses)Jones (bald without sunglasses)Warbaby (red bandana)It doesn't really matter which character you choose, since there are no special qualities tied to the characters. After you have chosen your character, it is time to buy weapons. GameplayObjectives There are several tasks you have to finish before you can go to the next level: Finding a certain amount of itemsKilling a certain amount of enemiesDestroying one or more enemy basesAny combination of the aboveOnce you have reached the goal, you can go to a gate that will lead you to the "shop" so you can prepare for the next level. You cannot leave the level you're in before you have completed your task. There will be a permanent marker showing you how many items / enemies / enemy bases there are still left for you to find or destroy. WeaponsYou can buy weapons at the beginning of the game with a certain amount of money and also in between the different levels. If you do not have any weapon or if you ran out of ammunition (which is possible), you'll have to fight with your bare hands, which is not a very good tactic if you want to make it to the next level. There is a certain amount of weapons available right from the start, and there won't be any new weapons you can add to the list of weapons. If you want to use a weapon, you'll need ammunition which you can also buy (by selecting a weapon you already have and pushing the 'buy-button'). There is one weapon that does not need ammunition: the chainsaw. The chainsaw doesn't do a lot of damage and does only work when you actually touch the enemy, but you can buy more than one chainsaw and you can use it as a secondary weapon, that means besides your firearm. When your firearms run out of ammunition, you'll automatically use your chainsaw instead of your bare hands, so the damage will be higher. The chainsaw seems to be a permanent damage booster. Which weapons you should buy depends on how good you are at aiming at your targets, how many enemies you have to kill and how tough the enemies are. The better weapons are more expensive or have very expensive ammunition, so if you buy this you risk running out of ammunition.Armor and livesAt the same time you are able to buy weapons, you will be able to buy armor or lives with the same money. You'll have to pick a combination of weapons, armor and lives with the (probably) limited amount of money you have. At the start of the game, you (and your co-op partner) will have a certain amount of armor (which can be seen as health). The maximum amount of armor you can have can be increased by buying extra armor. There is a limit to this, so you can only buy extra armor for a certain amount of times but extra armor is permanent so you cannot lose the length of your so-called health bar (which armor actually represents). You can, of course, what's in the armor bar, which means your armor can get damaged or in other words that you can lose some of your health. Since health gets restored to a certain point after every level, you cannot buy health. When you run out of health, you lose a life. You can buy extra lives for a relatively high price, but the maximum amount of lives you can stock is also limited.EnemiesEvery time you go to the next level, the level will get harder. Your objectives will be harder, the enemies will get tougher and there will be more of them. You get to see how many enemies of each kind there are before you start a level, so you can anticipate the difficulty of the level. The enemies vary in strength, health and speed. You can recognize the different types of enemies by the items they wear and the color of their clothes. Each time an enemy is near, you will get a text message on your screen alerting you so you can prepare yourself or run the other way. In certain level, there are enemy bases where a huge amount of enemies lurk to protect their spot. Destroying an enemy base is evidently harder than destroying an enemy, but it does not require special weapons. The enemy base looks like a big black circle with lines coming out of it and has no special abilities to do damage in any way. Objects There are several objects laying around in the game. There are regular items you have to find for some tasks. These items can be all kinds of things, from bears to files laying on the floor. By walking over them, you take the item with you. There are skulls to be found. Skulls represent lives.There are blue suits. Regular blue suits give you some extra armor/ health whilst blue suits with a yellow plus on it give you your maximum amount of armor/health.There are some weapons lying around. If you already have the weapon you found, you'll just receive ammunition instead of the weapon.Earning moneyWays to earn money so you can buy weapons / ammunition / armor / lives: Finish your tasks before the timer runs out and going through the special gateFinding regular items (you get money for every item you find)Selling weapons / ammunition / lives (you can also sell the weapons you found)Killing enemiesAfter you finish your task you can decide if you want to go for the timer-bonus (money you get for being fast) or if you want to keep looking for more items and keep killing more enemies, which also earns you money. MapYou (and your team mate) have access to a map on which you can see all of the walls and items you passed (if they're still there). Sometimes you might come close to an item, armor, a life or an enemy base without realizing it, but there will be symbols on the map. There are different symbols / colors for each type of object you missed. When you open the map, you can only see the parts where you have been to and its close surroundings. The areas where you haven't been close to will appear blackened out. Game over Every time you run out of armor/health, you will lose a life, if you lost all of your lives, the game is over. When you play in co-op, it is possible for one person to die and for the other one to keep playing. If the survivor manages to complete all of the tasks and reach the gate, the dead person will get to play again and he even gets a few of his lives back. When both of the team mates die, the game will be over.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5023">C-Dogs</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/83498/1547489-nothereeither.jpg</image></root>