<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>12964</id><name>Pokémon XD: Gale of Darkness</name><description>Pokémon XD: Gale of Darkness is a stripped down    Pokémon adventure for the    Gamecube. Unlike its handheld counterparts it’s not    open world, instead giving you a map to    fast travel between towns and cities. Another big change in the  Pokémon formula is that Pokémon XD uses  double battles almost exclusively. The biggest difference between XD and other  Pokémon games is how you     catch    Pokémon. Instead of random encounters in tall grass you must bait traps to find wild Pokémon, or you can “snag” shadow  Pokémon from rival trainers. XD-001, A.K.A. Shadow Lugia.  Shadow  Pokémon have had their hearts closed off by Team Cipher and can’t use any of their standard attacks. You unlock their hearts by putting them in a purification chamber with regular  Pokémon    surrounding them and making them listen to music. The order of the surrounding  Pokémon determines the tempo of the purification, the faster the tempo the quicker the heart is unlocked. Shadow Pokemon and MovesIn XD, there are almost twice as many shadow pokemon as compared to    Colosseum. The shadow moves have been expanded from one to a sizeable amount, and are listed as follows; Shadow Moves  Shadow Blast (   XD - 001 only) Shadow Blitz  Shadow Bolt  (shadow    Zapdos only)  Shadow Break  Shadow Chill (Shadow    Articuno only) Shadow Down  Shadow End (shadow    Exeggutor,    Marowak    Rhydon,    Snorlax,  Magnectric) Shadow Fire (Shadow    Moltres Only) Shadow Half (Shadow    Arbok,    Hitmonlee,    Electabuzz,  Swellow) Shadow Hold  Shadow Mist  Shadow Panic  Shadow Rave  Shadow Rush  Shadow Shed  Shadow Sky  Shadow Storm  Shadow WaveTriviaThis game has a total of 388 different Pokemon, unlike its 3rd generation counterparts, it has    Munchlax and  Bonsly, 2 fourth generation Pokemon available in the game, although only the latter is available for battling.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23375">Gangway Monsters</game><game id="33000">Shin Megami Tensei: Persona 2 - Innocent Sin</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2171294-box_pkmnxdgod.png</image></root>