<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13056</id><name>ESPN NFL 2K5</name><description>ESPN NFL 2K5 is a 2004 NFL Football game, developed by  Visual Concepts. In 2004,  SEGA released their entire sports line of games at a price-point of $19.99, as opposed to the standard 49.99 for new releases. The lower price helped earn 2K5 attention from consumers who had previously been more dedicated to  Electronic Arts' " Madden" series, along with causal gamers who typically would not be willing to pay full price for a sports game that is released annually. Today, ESPN NFL 2K5 is regarded as a benchmark for many football games, commonly having its mechanics and presentation cited as strong attributes of the game.To date, ESPN NFL 2K5 has sold nearly 1.6 million copies in the United States, a number that nearly matches that of  Madden 2005. Electronic Arts recognized this, and in 2004, EA signed a deal with the NFL giving it exclusive rights to make NFL games. EA also lowered the price of Madden 2005 in $29.99 in competition of SEGA's price drop, but after receiving exclusive rights brought the MSRP of  Madden 2006 back up to the standard 49.99 price-point. This brought outrage from the football game fan community, many of whom believe Madden has had a massive quality drop since it the contract was signed due to lack of competition from other NFL games.Although Visual Concepts has stopped making NFL licensed games, their next football game would be  All-Pro Football 2K8, which features legends, and fantasy players. With the strong communities still in support of the 2K football series, many unofficial roster updates for both 2K5 and All-Pro 2K8 have been created featuring NFL players.The "Academy of Interactive Arts  Sciences" awarded 2K5 with their "Sports Simulation Game of the Year" award.ESPN 2K5 is also  backwards compatible on the  Xbox 360 and on the 60 and 80 GB  Playstation 3 consoles. Emulation on the Xbox 360 is nearly flawless, with only a few texture errors on the field during gameplay. The online servers for gameplay over  Xbox Live were shut down on April 15, 2009.ModesQuick Game - Allows you to jump into an exhibition game with full control over teams, weather, stadium, etc.Franchise - Allows you to control one team completely for many seasons, including salary caps, trades, individual player training regiments, etc.First Person Football - A mode exclusive to the ESPN NFL series, this mode allows you to play a game through the eyes of a player on the fieldESPN 25th Anniversary - Allows you to relive famous moments from the history of the NFL and change history; these are basically specialized pre-made situationsSituation - In this mode, the player can set up a specific situation with control over field position, time remaining, score, and possession to play throughTournament - Four, eight or 16 teams play in a tournamentBasic Training - This mode is a tutorial for the game; the player takes part in individual drills to learn the ways of the game. This option is under "Practice"Scrimmage - Allows the player to perform specialized practices to improve performance in offense, defense, and special teamsThe CribAchieving certain goals in the other modes of the game (similar to the  Achievement system of  Xbox Live) will earn the player "Crib Points", which can then be used to buy items in "The Crib". The Crib is a virtual mansion that the player can accessorize and furnish to their heart's content. Catalogs of items can be bought after the player has earned a certain number of Crib Points; the player can then buy items from that catalog to place in their Crib. Some of these items include posters, a dartboard, and videos (which can be played in the "Home Theater" section of the Crib). The Crib is also where the player gets access to celebrity matches. After the player earns a certain number of Crib Points, the "Celebrity Phone" in the Crib will ring, and the player will be challenged to a match by who typically would be seen as having no association with football, like "Steve-O" or Carmen Electra.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="21">Football</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8480">All-Pro Football 2K8</game><game id="20986">Backbreaker</game><game id="20711">Madden NFL 09</game><game id="21413">Madden NFL 08</game><game id="21713">NFL Fever 2003</game><game id="20848">NCAA Football 09</game><game id="14735">NFL GameDay '97</game><game id="7171">NFL GameDay</game><game id="7848">NFL GameDay '99</game><game id="2356">NFL GameDay 2001</game><game id="9640">NFL GameDay 2000</game><game id="98">John Elway's Quarterback</game><game id="3333">NFL GameDay ‘98</game><game id="8073">NFL Sports Talk Football '93 Starring Joe Montana</game><game id="20920">Blitz: The League II</game><game id="16405">NFL GameDay 2003</game><game id="25241">Madden NFL 10</game><game id="25614">NCAA Football 10</game><game id="29744">Madden NFL 11</game><game id="33906">Madden NFL 12</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2222534-box_nfl2k5.png</image></root>