<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13132</id><name>Mutan Zone</name><description>Mutan Zone was released alongside another game called Sol Negro in late 1988 by spanish company Opera Soft. It was released for many platforms. The best version was the MSX which had a nice palette of colors and better graphics, the worst being the PC version with CGA cyan and magenta colors.  The game has only 2 "levels", called Parts, which you can choose to play right from the starting menu. Each part is actually pretty long, with a few "checkpoints", although these checkpoints are by no means marked or obvious.Part 1 starts you off on a    Star Raiders-like deal where you're in the cockpit of a ship and you have an aiming reticle and you have to shoot incoming enemy ships, each kill giving you 1 life. Eventually, after a certain time passes, you go on to the actual game which is a sidescrolling platformer. Go to the right without getting killed until you reach the end, and your off to... Part 2 is a sidescroller as well, only this time you're on some kind of hoverbike (like Return of the Jedi's speeders). Again, keep going to the right without getting killed and eventually you'll reach the end and win.  There is also a curious mechanic to this game: You have a small rotating radar dish constantly following you around, and a "visor" right in the middle of the hud shows what it's actually seeing, like a camera. What it shows is not important, though. What is important is that when the display locks on to your character and starts to pan from your head to your feet, that's actually warning you of an imminent weird energy discharge attack that'll spawn right on you and kill you, but you can avoid it by ducking and staying down until the explosion(?) goes off. This happens every set amount of time.  The difficulty of this game is straight up unfair, mostly the fault of bad design decisions. Deaths are one-hit kills. Anything you touch kills you instantly, and unless you've memorized every enemy pattern and obstacle, usually attacks come too fast to react in time.  The controls are clunky and arbitrary. For example: You jump, with only one height, and have to wait for the whole jumping procedure to end, with absolutely no air control, causing you to usually fall into some puddle of acid or straight onto a monster's lap. Likewise, firing the zapper gun thing is a hassle. You can fire straight or diagonally upwards, but the dude stands still while doing so. Also, we have that good ol' system prevalent in many old games where you have to wait for the shots to go offscreen before you can fire again. The hoverbike part (Part 2) is actually easier than the "on foot" part, once you get used to how it handles, which can take while. Despite the awful, almost mockingly hard difficulty, at the time the game was a wonder to behold. The design of the aliens and the landcape is mesmerizingly bizarre and nightmarish. Sort of "metroid-like" even.  This game is not a "classic" by any sense of the word, and it definately had it's unforgivable flaws, but at the time, it really was original in artstyle and atmosphere. With only 2 levels, albeit long levels, it did manage to end up being a memorable experience.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21761">Metroid</game><game id="730">Star Raiders</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/18269/1400663-mutantzo_1.png</image></root>