<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13169</id><name>Ty the Tasmanian Tiger</name><description>OverviewTy the Tasmanian Tiger is a 3D platformer with gameplay elements similar to Super Mario Sunshine. It was produced by Krome studios, and published by EA Gamesin 2002. It is about one of the last Tasmanian Tigers,  TY, as he searches for five  talismans to save his family from the Dreamworld and defeat the evil Boss Cass. It is the first game in the Ty the Tasmanian Tiger franchise, followed by Ty the Tasmanian Tiger 2: Bush Rescue and finished with Ty the Tasmanian Tiger 3: Night of the Quinkan. Ty the Tasmanian Tiger was released on September 10, 2002, in North America and November 22, 2002, in PAL regions. The game was recieved mildly well. StoryTy the Tasmanian Tiger is based in the Australian outback at a hub world called Rainbow Cliffs. The game has Ty running around different-themed levels to collect Thunder Eggs to power a mystical machine operated by Julius, a koala, which can locate the five mystical talismans Ty needs to save his family and entire species. An emu called Boss Cass sealed the Tasmanian tigers in the Aboriginal Dreamworld, and the last tiger to be sucked in dislodged the talismans, closing the portal behind him. Now an orphan, Ty is adopted by the Bilibies. Many years later, a Bunyip (Spirit) reveals the truth to Ty, and he sets off to find the talismans before Boss Cass can, encountering many friends and even more enemies. Creatures like frill lizards, spiders,  crocodiles, giant sharks, robots, and even another Tasmanian tiger called Sly will aid Boss Cass in his attempt to thwart Ty. GameplayTy the Tasmanian Tiger is very similar to other platformers at the time of release, featuring collecting a specific object as the main goal, platforming elements such as overcoming a variety of puzzles, obstacles, and challlenges involving the use of a specific bommerang type to complete.  Boomerang types There are many boomerangs in the game, unlocked by either finding a specific amount of Thunder Eggs or collecting 15 Golden  Cogs. Thunder Egg BoomerangsThese are used to advance in the hub world and usually perform some context-sensitive maneuvers such as creating iceburgs on water, melting/burning ice and spiderwebs, and powering generators. Zappyrang: An electrically charged boomerang, which is used to kill enemies or supercharge generators. Flamerang: A boomerang that's on fire and can be used to burn through spiderwebs and obstructing ice. Frostyrang: A boomerang that's made of ice, used to create stepping stones in water and freeze enemies solid. Aquarang: Used underwater, otherwise unequipable.  Golden Cog Boomerangs (Technorangs) Boomerangs that vary in use, but they all have different purposes. Boomerang:Ty's starting boomerang. Used to deal damage- upgradeed from one to two near the beginning of the game. Multirang: The boomerang, with shorter range but a  much higher rate of fire. Zoomerang: A boomerang equivalent of a sniper rifle. It can zoom in on enemies from afar. Infarang: Emits a blip when it senses hidden content, such as Picture frames or rainbow scales. It makes invisible platforms and crates appear when you go into TY's view (First Person). Megarang: Homes in on enemies and crates; used to hit multiple enemies at once. Kaboomerag: Creates a large explosion. Somewhat different to the other 'rangs, TY throws both at once for  massive damage. Doomerang: Only useable in the final battle against Cass, it is a remote controlled boomerang. It is also the boomerang TY's father used to dislodge the Talismans. Characters There are several characters in TY the Tasmanian Tiger, all with their own quirks: TY the Tasmanian Tiger:  The  main character, he is on a mission to save his family and species from the evil Boss Cass. Maurie: Maurie is a Sulphur-crested Cockatoo, and serves as the guide for TY's adventures. He's one of TY's best friends. Julius: A mad scientist, Julius the Koala helps TY find the Talismans and makes him the special Technorangs. Julius plays a large support role. Shazza: TY's girlfriend, she is always getting into trouble, but can handle herself. Dennis: A Green Tree frog, Dennis has a large collection of Thunder Eggs, and is eaisily frightened. Bilibies: They raised TY from childhood, and now he has to free them from captivity. Bunyip Elder: A spirit that grants TY invulnerability and super strength for a short time if found in level. The reason why TY starts off of his quest is because the Bunyip Elder tells him about his heritage. Boss Cass: The antagonist, he trapped TY's family in the Dreamworld, imprisoned the Bilibies, and is trying to destroy the outback with polloution. Frill Lizards: They often try to gang up on TY, but are weak and cannot do much damage. They are the easiest enemy to incapacitate, and they are also the most numerous. Blue Tounges: Tougher lizards, these take several hits and are about three times as tall as TY. Red Kangaroos: An uncommon enemy, only seen on the last two levels. These deliver a powerful kick and can knock off half of your health bar in one hit.</description><genres><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8035">Dr. Muto</game><game id="18376">Looney Tunes Back in Action</game><game id="18385">Blinx the Time Sweeper</game><game id="3399">Blinx 2: Masters of Time and Space</game><game id="1605">I-Ninja</game><game id="3684">Oddworld: Munch's Oddysee</game><game id="7914">Voodoo Vince</game><game id="13158">Sonic Adventure DX: Director's Cut</game><game id="6649">Super Mario Sunshine</game><game id="20351">Kya: Dark Lineage</game><game id="15835">Beyond Good &amp; Evil</game><game id="20529">Insecticide</game><game id="12614">Sphinx and the Cursed Mummy</game><game id="18926">Malice</game><game id="11470">Scaler</game><game id="68">Crash Bandicoot: The Wrath of Cortex</game><game id="24969">Tokobot Plus: Mysteries of the Karakuri</game><game id="11407">Vexx</game><game id="17133">Tak and the Power of Juju</game><game id="25720">Jak and Daxter: The Lost Frontier</game><game id="19388">Ape Escape 3</game><game id="30746">Ruff Trigger: The Vanocore Conspiracy</game><game id="159">Ty the Tasmanian Tiger 2: Bush Rescue</game><game id="19188">Ty the Tasmanian Tiger 3: Night of the Quinkan</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2261153-box_ty.png</image></root>