<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13293</id><name>Dungeon Siege: Legends of Aranna</name><description>StoryThe story is set in the same realms as the original Dungeon Siege. Once again you begin your quest as a common farmer. Your parents were once great adventurers and you definitely feel your legacy blood. After hearing a lot of stories about adventure, heroes and battles against Krug armies, you decide it is time to take your life into a different direction and follow the footsteps of your parents.Fortunately the staff of Stars was stolen by a creature called Shadowjumper, and it becomes your task to retrieve the powerful artifact.Your quest starts in the ice hills of Arhok and eventually you will discover the lost island of Utraean covered with jungles, ancient cities and lost of caves and dungeon. The Ultraeans were once a powerful people that experimented a lot with chemical and biological substances and created some of the most fearful creatures found in the realm. These creatures include Hassat, the race of great humanoid cats, and Zaurask, the lizard folk, which now mostly occupy the Island.During your journey you will be able to form a party of eight heroes that will offer their services. Included are battle mages, rangers, wizards, barbarians and druids. The player needs a good mix of classes to survive the journey.GameplayThe gameplay is like the gameplay from the original Dungeon Siege. You create a hero (man \ woman) and start somewhere in the field by picking up a stick or scroll and killing monsters you meet along the way. The kind of weapon and the skill you use during your adventures define what sort of character you become. You basically have the melee, hunter and magic arche-types, but it is up to you how much you specialize in one or more area's. It is always possible to switch your class, but the stats associated with that class still need to be developed. It is often better to choose in the beginning and to stick with that class.Dungeon Siege is a game you can play solo, but then it is very hard to beat the game. You can create a party up to 8 characters which you pick along the way of your adventure. Sometimes these heroes are just wandering a town or forest, and ask to join you. Sometimes it takes a quest to solve to unlock certain characters.Dungeon Siege is also about loot! Lots of loot. The game drops a variety in quality, easily identified by its' color. You have a limited amount of space in your backpack, but fortunately you can have a pack animal in your party to carry the bulk of the stuff.In the end it is all about making a strong party to be able to defeat the big evil in the end game.New ContentThe expansion offers the following new content :Play as a half-giantBattle new foes like Dopplegangers and Clockwork beastsTransform into a Wolf, Lava monster or TrollUse a dinosaurus as a mule instead of a ... muleThe pack animal will defend the treasure to deathSort your inventory more easilyArmor setsBonus packA bonus pack called Return to Arhok is available for Legends of Aranna that adds a few quests. You will return to the jungles to and save the king of Hassat.AvailabilityThe game is available for PC and Mac.Compatibility / Widescreen supportThis game runs on Windows7 32/64bits. After installing, you need to run the DSVideoConfig.exe file in the installation map and set the values to the correct ones.After this, you need to check both DungeonSiege.ini files to check if the correct values were set. In these files you can also change the resolution of the game. Widescreen is fully supported.PC System RequirementsMicrosoft® Windows® 98/Me/XP/2000PC with 333 MHz equivalent or higher processor128 MB of system RAM1.5 GB available hard disk space32x speed or faster CD-ROM drive8 MB video card requiredSound card, speakers or headphones required for audioMicrosoft Mouse or compatible pointing device56.6 Kbps or better modem for 1-4 player online play; broadband or LAN for 5 playersMac System RequirementsMac OS X 10.1 or above450 MHz PowerPC G3 processor256MB of RAM16MB video card</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13217">Champions of Norrath</game><game id="5985">Diablo</game><game id="7584">Etrom: The Astral Essence</game><game id="32416">DeathSpank: Thongs of Virtue</game><game id="1119">Diablo II</game><game id="20612">Space Siege</game><game id="8638">Titan Quest</game><game id="25983">Torchlight</game><game id="31832">Konung III: Ties of the Dynasty</game><game id="12">Blade &amp; Sword</game><game id="8590">Dawn of Magic</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/25536/839491-dungeonsiege.jpg</image></root>