<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13319</id><name>Dalek Attack</name><description>The game was released on the PC, ZX Spectrum, Commodore 64, Amiga and Atari ST. It was announced for the Amstrad CPC, but that version was never released.  There were some differences depending on which console you played the game. These mainly consisted of player character choices, however the Spectrum version had fewer characters than the other releases.      Version Exclusive  Commodore 64, Amiga, Atari ST Playable Characters: Fourth, Fifth and Seventh Doctor, Companions: Ace or UNIT soldier  MS-DOS/PC Playable Characters: Second, Fourth or Seventh Doctor, Companions: Ace or UNIT soldier  ZX Spectrum Playable Character: Seventh Doctor, Companion: Ace Other characters you encounter during the game include K-9 (The Doctor's robot dog) and Davros, the creator of the Daleks, who is also the final end of level boss.  Some versions of the game featured special Daleks, such as hovering Daleks from the 1960s TV Century 21 comic strips, the Peter Cushing 'movie' Daleks and the special weapons Dalek from "Remembrance of the Daleks" (the TV serial).  Its relationship with the TV series canon is in dispute, however it has been attempted to fit in between the Virgin New Adventures novel "Head Games", which suggests the game takes place in an alternative universe created by the Doctor whilst he is affected by energy from the Land of Fiction. The PC and Amiga versions both contained a secret room, hidden behind some blocks during one of the levels. It mostly contained  programming credits for the game, in particular for graphics and music. The credits were hidden due to the BBC not wanting individual credits given for the development team, possibly due to their stance on Doctor Who at the time of release.  The game was designed and storyboarded by 221B Software Development, the PC, Commodore 64, Amiga and Atari ST versions were developed and published by Alternative Software.  The ZX Spectrum version was released due to popular demand in 1993.  It had a different first level to other releases of the game - in older versions of the opening level, The Doctor had to travel through a sewer on a hoverboard.   It was also the last licensed Spectrum game due to it no longer being a commercially viable platform.   Although the game was released by Alternative Software, it was advertised as being released by Admiral Software. This was due to Alternative Software being a budget software label, and that wasn't the image they wanted for this game. It was soon recalled due to legal action from a software house already called Admiral Software. The game boxes had stickers placed over the logo, and the in-game graphics featuring the logo were replaced or removed.  Later, the game was re-released in the "Sci-Fi Collection" with two other title (Galactic Warrior Rats and Suburban Commando) for the PC. This was later re-released itself with a slightly different cover in 1995.  The game engine created for the game by 221B Software was later re-used as the basis for the Suburban Commando game. </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10069">Suburban Commando</game><game id="9511">Galactic Warrior Rats</game><game id="37171">Doctor Who Episode 5: The Gunpowder Plot</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9408/726442-dalek_attack.jpg</image></root>