<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13329</id><name>The Pirates of Dark Water</name><description>Overview Pirates of Dark Water is a 2D beat-em-up sidescrolling game developed for the Super Nintendo Entertainment System and the Sega Genesis by Sunsoft. The game features the main crew of the 1990s TV show Ren, Ioz, and Tula searching for the Treasures of Rule in order to rid the world of Mer of the Dark Water and return Mer and Ren's homeland, Octopon, to its former glory.  Story Taken from the game: "On the distant and watery world of mer, the dying king primus escapes from the evil pirate-lord, bloth, to reveal to Ren his past and his destiny.  Ren, the son of king primus, must save the planet mer and  his home, octopon, from the deadly dark water  "By collecting all the treasures of rule, Ren can control the dark water and return mer and octopon to their former glory  "Ren and his crew, Ioz, the hardened ex-pirate and Tula, the  adventure seeking heroine must embark on a journey that will constantly test Ren and his crew's strength and dedication toward the quest for  the treaures of rule.  The evil Pirate-lord Bloth and his army of ruthless pirates also seek the treasures of rule  "Bloth and his ship, the maelstrom are always one step behind Ren.  If Bloth can collect the treasures before Ren and his ragtag crew, the planet mer is doomed to the dark water and Bloth's tyranny forever."  Setting A 2D beat-em-up in the vein of classics such as Final Fight, Double Dragon, and Streets of Rage, Pirates of Dark Water is remarkable for its fantasy setting and varied enemies. Drawing from the cartoon's backstory, players fight rival pirates as well as fantastic creatures sent to hinder the heroes from finding the Treasure of Rule by the evil pirate-lord Bloth. It features 8 different stages in all.  Gameplay The player can control one of the three main characters from the show: Ren   -  well-balanced, medium strength/medium agility Ioz     -  heavy, high strength/low agility Tula  -  quick, low strength/high agility  Differences between the versions The Genesis version of Pirates of Dark Water is an adventure/platforming game while the SNES version is a beat-em-up. In addition, the SNES version sports much improved graphics, colors, and music.  </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9412">QuackShot starring Donald Duck</game><game id="19944">Disney's Aladdin</game><game id="236">The Revenge of Shinobi</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14034/445875-dw02.jpg</image></root>