<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13328</id><name>Wii Sports</name><description>OverviewWii Sports is the pack-in for the Wii for all regions except for Japan. It includes five sports mini-games, corresponding challenges, and a daily trainer that gives the player a score similar to the Brain Age system. It utilizes Miis as the player's avatar.Wii TennisThe player swings the Wii Remote like a tennis racket, hitting a ball back and forth with a friend or a computer-controlled player. Players can shoot forehand and backhand shots, and also put spin on the ball, depending on the way they swing. Four player Vs. matches are available, and two players can play on each team.BoxingWii BoxingThe player holds the Wii Remote and Nunchuk like they're extensions of their hands. The player must mimic the motions of blocking, punching, and jabbing. Two player Vs. matches are available.GolfWii GolfThe player mimics the swing of a golf club. The speed on the swing controls distance, as well as accuracy. It can be played with up to four players.BaseballWii BaseballIn baseball, the player swings the Wii Remote as they would a bat. Players also pitch the baseball as they would in real life. The pitcher can choose different pitches to throw, as well as placement of the pitches. It can be played with two players.BowlingWii BowlingThe bowling arm movement is mimicked with the Wii Remote. Players can put spin on the ball, by twisting the Wii Remote during the bowling motion. The player bowls by holding down the "B" button and pulling back their arm in a bowling motion, then letting go to throw the ball. One to four player games are supported.Updated VersionNintendo has silently updated the Wii Sports game with minor enhancements that were found in European regions at first. This includes NPC baseball players throwing to base, a replay of a knock outs in boxing, players lining up before baseball, etc. This seems to be because the game might have shipped while not being completely finished and Nintendo assumed these updates were not really necessary to delay the release of the game and or console. The game also started coming in a plastic cases instead of the cardboard "fold-up" ones that the first Wii consoles were shipped with.Interesting TriviaSome of buttons in the game are shaped differently in other foreign copies of the game.This website tracks Wii Sports world records: Wii Sports World RecordsAccording to the NPD Wii Sports as surpassed Super Mario Bros. as the best selling game of all time.As of April 2012, Wii Sports has sold 79.60 million units worldwide, according official numbers released during one of Nintendo's investor meetings.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre><genre id="20">Boxing</genre><genre id="25">Tennis</genre><genre id="28">Golf</genre><genre id="29">Bowling</genre><genre id="34">Baseball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20503">Wii Fit</game><game id="9439">Wii Play</game><game id="20902">Big Beach Sports</game><game id="20913">Sports Party</game><game id="20605">High Velocity Bowling</game><game id="21617">Rayman: Raving Rabbids</game><game id="8406">Game Party</game><game id="5494">Carnival Games</game><game id="20632">Deca Sports</game><game id="6550">Victorious Boxers: Revolution</game><game id="22848">MLB '98</game><game id="21099">Wii Music</game><game id="22938">Carnival Games Mini Golf</game><game id="23965">Punch-Out!!</game><game id="24064">Let's Catch</game><game id="23108">Celebrity Sports Showdown</game><game id="24302">Gold's Gym: Cardio Workout</game><game id="24645">My Fitness Coach</game><game id="20859">Ninja Reflex</game><game id="25052">Bowling</game><game id="20978">World Sports Competition</game><game id="24954">Summer Sports 2 Island Sports Party</game><game id="17969">SSX Blur</game><game id="24396">Grand Slam Tennis</game><game id="25648">Don King Boxing</game><game id="25665">Squeeballs Party</game><game id="20686">MLB Power Pros</game><game id="20687">MLB Power Pros 2008</game><game id="26759">Golf Training</game><game id="26537">Daisy Fuentes Pilates</game><game id="27825">Game Party 3</game><game id="28400">Big League Sports</game><game id="28401">Big League Sports: Summer</game><game id="29030">Cyberbike</game><game id="30349">Sports Champions</game><game id="30351">The Fight: Lights Out</game><game id="30634">Deca Sports 3</game><game id="31210">Wii Party</game><game id="31703">Kinect Sports</game><game id="32179">JumpStart Get Moving: Family Fitness featuring Brooke Burke Sports Edition</game><game id="32733">101-in-1 Sports Party Megamix</game><game id="31720">Motion Sports</game><game id="31704">Kinect Adventures!</game><game id="31802">Deca Sports Freedom</game><game id="35069">Dual Pen Sports</game><game id="35531">Kinect Sports: Season Two</game><game id="38552">ESPN Sports Connection</game><game id="39277">Game Party Champions</game><game id="30322">Dragon Ball Z V.R.V.S</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2280537-box_wiisp.png</image></root>