<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13378</id><name>NBA Live 2003</name><description> SummaryNBA Live 2003 is EA Sports' NBA release for the 2002/2003 NBA season. The landmark addition in NBA Live 2003 was Freestyle Control, which was met with some enthusiasm by fans though some did not like the limited moves that were available to keyboard users. Although the concept itself was not unpopular (and continues to be used with Quick Strike Ankle Breakers today) most felt Freestyle Control was too powerful in NBA Live 2003 and the game too fast-paced with scores easily exceeding 150 points apiece when playing twelve minute quarters. NBA Live 2003 was also derided for its "Courtside Comedy" approach to cutscenes which players felt detracted from the intended atmosphere of an NBA simulation. Arcade-like effects such as booming sound effects and blocks which rocketed the ball to the opposite baseline were also amongst the common complaints.The return to the PC platform was welcomed by patchers however and several patches were made including "Tweaked Rosters" which attempted to combat some of the issues with gameplay. The game also corrected some issues from NBA Live 2001 and NBA Live 2002 including the disproportinate rebounds.Features listRevolutionary EA SPORTS™ Freestyle Control: Sweet crossovers, triple threat moves, post moves and strip steals. String your moves together and pull off what you want, when you want it - all with unprecedented two-handec control.The next level of online play: Join EA SPORTS™ Online and access a community where you can meet, chat and play against NBA Live 2003 gamers across the country.Quick plays for quick scores and stops: Call plays on the fly to control the game - run the pick-n-roll or isolation on offense, zone or double team on "D" and much more.Dominate with one-button control: Turn the momentum with the all-new Charge button and clean the glass with one-button rebounding.New EA SPORTS™ TRAX: Featuring hot music releases from Fabolous, Flipmode Squad featuring Busta Rhymes, Just Blaze, Snoop Dogg and more.FactsThe return of NBA Live to the PC platform.Freestyle Control made its debut in NBA Live 2003.Michael Jordan's second and final (official) appearance as an active player in NBA Live.The final NBA Live to utilise DSTATS.Although the NBA updated its Playoffs format to 7-7-7-7 for the 2002/2003 season, NBA Live 2003 did not reflect this change.Don Poier and Bob Elliott's final game as the commentary team.Yao Ming was absent from the console version of the game but appeared in the PC version.For the first time users could select which jersey a team would wear before beginning a game. Retro jerseys were also included for the first time.An official patch was released to correct a couple of bugs, including slowed down gameplay in Windows 98 when using a USB gamepad.Final game to use the 50-99 rating scale.Soundtrack NBA Live 2003 was the first game in the NBA Live franchise to include the soundtrack on a serpate cd. According to Ea and the Recording Industry Association of America the CD went Platnum, selling over one million copies. This is of course becuase the game, not the cd itself, sold over one million copies. Every track on this CD is basketball themed. EA has not included a separate soundtrack disk since this game. Tracklist includes,  Its In The Game, by Fabolous Blao, by Hot Karl Whoa Now, by B. Rich Picture on box Drop Drop, by Joe Budden Let's Go, by Just Blaze feat. Freeway and Mem Fool Moo, by Brandy W feat. Fat Joe If I could Go!, by Angie Martinez ft. Lil' Mo Ballin' Boy, by No Good Too Hood, by Monica feat. Jermaine Dupri Young and Sexy, by Lyric Get Live,by Snoop Dawg Here we Go, by Busta Rhymes feat. Flipmode Squa</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="22">Basketball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21470">NBA 2K8</game><game id="16937">ESPN NBA Basketball 2004</game><game id="1395">ESPN NBA 2K5</game><game id="21363">NBA 2K6</game><game id="20917">NBA 2K9</game><game id="9829">NBA 2K7</game><game id="21762">NBA ShootOut 2000</game><game id="7982">NBA Street</game><game id="6199">NCAA College Basketball 2K3</game><game id="20242">NBA Showdown</game><game id="23864">NBA '08</game><game id="27885">NBA 2K10: Draft Combine</game><game id="3557">NBA 07</game><game id="4632">NBA Showtime: NBA on NBC</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2246598-box_nbal03.png</image></root>