<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13381</id><name>Redneck Rampage</name><description>Overview Redneck   Rampage is a comedic  sci-fi                                        first person shooter developed by                                       Xatrix Entertainment and published by                                      Interplay. It directly lampoons common redneck stereotypes in  every aspect ranging from the core gameplay to the music to the  included readme file, which is named, "helpyall.txt". The game puts the player in the shoes of Leonard, an unintelligent Southerner who, along with his equally stupid brother Cletus, seeks to rescue their favorite pig from the aliens who happen to have invaded            Alabama.The  Cuss PackThe "Cuss Pack" add-on added stronger language to the  game. It changed nearly all sound files to include profanity and vulgar  language. As an example, the Skinny Old Coot (the most common enemy  in the game) usually taunts the player saying "I'm gonna get you boy!  I'm gonna get you!" With the Cuss Pack installed, the line is  changed to "I'm gonna fuck you boy! I'm gonna fuck you!"The  add-on was available for download at Interplay's online store, but users  had to pay $1 with a credit card to ensure that the buyer was adult.  The add-on was included on the CD for the  Mac OS version.Weapons                                   Crowbar - Basic melee weapon. Each non-boss level is ended by having Leonard smack Cletus in the head with the crowbar.               Pistol - Highly accurate .454 pistol  that works well for sniping enemies at long ranges, though it lacks  power.  Scattergun - Standard                                  double barrel shotgun. "Hunting Rifle" (             AK-47) - Fully automatic  assault rifle that climbs as it fires.                               Dynamite -  Explosive projectile weapon useful for blowing open marked walls and  for taking out a room of enemies at a time. Also capable of blowing up the player if they hold it too long.                              Crossbow  - Launches dynamite sticks extended distances. Utilizes the same  ammunition as the dynamite. Functions identically to the RPG from  Duke Nukem 3D.                       Ripsaw - Fires  saw blades at the enemy.Alien Arm Gun - Picked up from the  Alien Hulk Guards, the Alien Arm Gun is a highly damaging plasma-based  weapon. The gun is still attached to the severed Alien Hulk Guard's arm, and Leonard fires it by yanking an exposed tendon.                Powder Keg - Stationary explosive barrel that can  be set by the player and then blown up from a distance using another  weapon. Basically useless.Teat Gun - "Double-barrelled" machine gun brassiere worn  by the Alien Vixens. Useful against the aliens if you don't mind looking stupid(er).                             Bowling Ball - The bowling ball is  first found in E1L4 and can be carried throughout the rest of the  episode. It can be used to bowl at the bowling  alley in which it's found and it must be picked back up after each use. It  can be rolled at the enemy, but it does very, very low damage and must be retrieved after each throw, making it useless as a weapon.Enemies           Mosquito - Weak enemy that  flies around and does minimal damage.          Chicken - Passive  animal that only attacks in self defence.         Cow - Passive animal  that doesn't defend itself very well.        Pig - Passive animal  that will attack in self defence, but does minimal damage.       Dog  - Aggressive enemy that takes multiple scattergun shots to bring down. Turd Monkeys- Weak enemies made of human feces that will try to swarm the player and cause damage by hurling pieces of their smelly bodies at the player. Some are known to self-destruct in close proximity to Leonard.Skinny Old Coot - The most  common enemy type throughout a bulk of the game, the Skinny Old Coot is a  clone of a man from Hickston, Arizona, Leonard's home town. A fairly weak enemy that attacks the player with a revolver. Easily  dispatched with a shotgun blast.Billy Ray Jeter - Another hillbilly clone, Billy Ray is the second most  common enemy throughout the game. An obese gentleman  in overalls, Billy Ray is armed with a shotgun, and takes way more damage than the Old Coot.  Sheriff Hobbes- Rarely seen throughout the game, clones of Sheriff Hobbes  make their first appearance in E2L1 and attack the player with dual six   shooters. After unloading both guns, he has to pause to reload (something he loudly announces) at which  point he's vulnerable to attacks. Alien Hulk Guards - Enormous aliens that attack with Alien Arm Guns and proximity grenades.  Susceptible to basic circle strafing strategies, but deadly in enclosed  areas (hallways, small rooms, etc). Leaves behind an Alien Arm Gun when  defeated.Alien Vixens - Beautiful alien women who seek to dominate the human race. There are three levels of Alien Vixens  separated by colour: Green (basic), Brown (Level 2), and Blue (Level 3).  The level two Vixen has 50% more health than the basic Vixen and the  level three has 100% more health than the basic Vixen. They attack the  player with Teat Guns and kicks, can teleport short distances, and can  withstand a substantial amount of damage (8x that of Billy Ray Jeter). Assface - Final boss of the  first episode, Assface is a colossal beast made of feces. He resides in the sewers under the smelting  plant and is guarded by an army of Turd Monkeys.Vixen Queen -  The final boss of the second episode, the leader of the alien invasion. Looks similar to previous Vixens but doles out far more damage and has a lot more                                    hit  points. Items Like most other games running  on the                                              Build engine,  Redneck   Rampage features an  inventory system. Most items can be used when the player sees fit, but  some--like the Vacuum Hose and Welding Goggles (which functions  as                                            scuba gear) activate automatically. Alcoholic items heal the player's life, but also get them drunk, and as they continue to drink, it becomes harder to aim, walk, and eventually even  see.  Cow Pie - Health.Pork Rinds - Health.              Whiskey - Health, gets you drunk.              Beer - Health, gets you drunk.Skeleton Key. Hip Waders - Protects against harmful ground surfaces. Essentially the Protective Boots from  Duke Nukem 3D.Vacuum Hose and  Welding Goggles - Makeshift scuba gear.     Moonshine - Gives the player super-speed for a short period of time and causes the crowbar to do massive damage. Essentially the    Steroids from   Duke Nukem 3D.Levels Fifteen  levels are included in  Redneck   Rampage and are broken into  two distinct episodes. In a twist to the typical episodic structure of  games in this style, the player does not lose all of their weapons at  the end of the first episode; rather, they lose them all at the end of  the first level of the second episode. Episode 1   E1L1: "Taylor Town"  E1L2:  "Lumberland" E1L3: "Junk Yard" E1L4: "Drive-In" E1L5:  "DairyAir Farms" E1L6: "Sewers" E1L7: "The Smelting  Plant" Episode 2  E2L1: "Downtown" E2L2:  "The Nut House" E2L3: "J.Clucks" E2L4: "The Ruins" E2L5:  "The Mortuary" E2L6: "Uranium Mines" E2L7: "The  Mansion" ENDGAME: A large open field with stone monuments in  the center, over which hovers a UFO. Upon entering the UFO, the player  is faced with the Alien Vixen Queen. SoundtrackWidely  hailed as the dominant trait of the game, the music features a redbook  audio soundtrack comprised by an eclectic mix of psychobilly from Mojo  Nixon, The Beat Farmers, The Reverend Horton Heat, and Cement Pond.  Throughout the game, promotional posters of fictitious concerts for the  bands decorate the walls of the levels.  Track 01: Data Track Track 02: Mojo Nixon - UFOs, Big  Rigs  BBQ (3:49) Track 03: The Beat Farmers - Baby's  Liquored Up (3:05) Track 04: The Reverend Horton Heat - Nurture  My Pig (4:04) Track 05: Cement Pond - Trash Can (4:30) Track  06: The Beat Farmers - Gettin' Drunk (2:10) Track 07: The  Reverend Horton Heat - Wiggle Stick (3:04) Track 08: Cement  Pond - Vixen (3:21) Track 09: Mojo Nixon - You Can't Kill Me  (6:31)</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17543">Destroy All Humans!</game><game id="324">Duke Nukem 3D: Plutonium Pak</game><game id="3407">Duke Nukem 3D</game><game id="11381">Blood</game><game id="11940">No One Lives Forever 2: A Spy in H.A.R.M.'s Way</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15693/623986-redneck_rampage_cheats_pc_2_1_.jpg</image></root>