<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1339</id><name>Star Wars: Republic Commando</name><description>OverviewJust another day at the office...Star Wars: Republic Commando is a squad-based, first-person shooter set between the events of Star Wars: Episodes II and Episode III. The game features an innovative, context sensitive squad-command system. Using a single key, the player orders squad members to take up sniping positions, hack a door, or utilize grenades at predefined locations in the environment. This system is similar to the system that would later be used in the Rainbow Six: Vegas series.Developed internally by LucasArts, it was received well by critics and is regarded as one of the better Star Wars games. One of the common criticisms, however, concerns the shortness of the single-player campaign, which can be completed in only a couple sittings. Unfortunately, the game is also notable for closing on a cliffhanger ending that has never been resolved.Sales figures for Republic Commando were never released, and no sequel has been announced.BackstoryDelta Squad's "family" portraitThe world of Republic Commando is set in the Star Wars universe but is much darker compared to other games in the Star Wars franchise. The darker, grittier tone represents the world as seen through the eyes of a clone soldier, who is born and killed for a singular, violent purpose. This stands in stark contrast to the idyllic vision of the Jedi, whose powers are so great that they have little to fear from the droids that constantly hound the clone soldier.The game is divided into three chapters: Geonosis, the Prosecutor, and Kashyyyk. Throughout all three chapters, the player controls "Boss", leader of Delta Squad. Delta Squad is a group of four Republic commandos. Receiving the standard training of a clone soldier, these elite commandos are augmented with superior strength, endurance, and additional training in specialized roles and squad-based tactics. Boss's three squadmates are "Scorch", "Sev", and "Fixer". Trained to work as a singular unit, Delta Squad is deployed on covert missions that require the finesse and strength that only Delta Squad can provide.Delta SquadDelta Squad is comprised of four members, all of them clones designated by a number preceded by the letters RC, which naturally stand for Republic Commando. They are each easily identified in-game by the color tones in their armor. While each squad member has a different area of specialty, they're all generally trained to carry out any order. Here's a brief description of each of the team members.RC-1138Boss, the Leader-- Nicknamed " Boss"; he is the leader of Delta Squad.He is the undisputed leader of the squad and doesn't talk much, except upon giving orders. In case you didn't know yet, he's the character you play as. RC-1138 was voiced by Temuera Morrison , who also voiced Jango Fett .His armor has an orange tint.RC-1262Scorch, the Demolitions Expert-- Nicknamed " Scorch"; he is the squad's demolitions expert.He is shown having a peculiar sense of humor, a fact he speculates on during the quieter moments of Delta Squad's missions, and often provides the game with several comical relieves. He received the nickname "Scorch" after an accident that left him without eyebrows for a short time.His armor has a yellow tint.RC-1207Sev, the Sniper-- Nicknamed " Sev"; he is Delta Squad's hunter and sniper.He was trained by Mandalorian Sergeant Walon Vau. He has a deep and menacing growl-ish voice, as well as a sadistic sense of humor, and often jokes with "Scorch" before and during missions; this leads to the most unique bond within the squad. RC-1207 isn't really prone to antics; his nickname simply comes from the fact that the last digit of his identification code is seven.His armor has a red tint.RC-1140Fixer, the Hacker-- Nicknamed " Fixer"; he is the hacker and technical expert of Delta Squad.RC-1140 is referred to by his squadmates as "Fixer" because he is an expert at solving problems via computers and equipment. However, Fixer himself will never refer to himself -- or any other clone -- by their nickname. He is a complete by-the-book clone, and acts more distant than his brothers.His armor has a green tint.LevelsCampaign 1: GeonosisPrologueExtreme PrejudiceInfiltrate the Droin FoundryDestroy the FactoryAdvance to the Core ShipInfiltration of the Core ShipCampaign 2: Assault ShipThe Rise of Delta SquadGhost Ship ReconRescue the SquadAttack of the ClonesSaving the ShipCampaign 3: KashyyykCritical DiscoveriesThe Rescue of TarffulObliterate the OutpostThe Bridge at KachiroThe Wookie ResistanceSearch and DestroyThe Final StrikeThe Fate of the SquadWeaponsRanged WeaponsThe improved DC-17 Assault RifleInstead of the standard issue DC-15s assault rifle, the clone commandos are equipped with the improved DC-17m. The DC-17m has three modes (which can be seen in detail in the table below) and it's Delta Squad's primary weapon.Standard blaster automatic fireSniper mode via an attachmentAnti-armor mode (also via an attachment)Delta Squad can only equip 2 weapons at a time, but that doesn't mean the arsenal at their disposition is not varied.The DC-17's Blaster attachmentDC-17m -- Blaster Attachment - This is the DC-17's standard fire mode. It fires and recharges quite fast and it gets the job done on most situations.Ammo TypeClip SizeMaximum ClipsFactionPlasma Rounds605RepublicThe DC-17's Sniper attachmentDC-17m -- Sniper Attachment - The sniper attachment is equipped with two zoom levels (10x and 20x) and it's obviously the best way to get rid of a couple of enemies without having to get your hands dirty. Any head shot is an instant kill. The scope helps you to differentiate friend from foe: enemies will glow red, allies will glow green.Ammo TypeClip SizeMaximum ClipsFactionCharged Plasma Bolts54RepublicThe DC-17's Anti-Armor attachmentDC-17m -- Anti-Armor Attachment - This is the DC-17's most powerful fire mode and one of the most powerful weapon in the game. However, and since the available ammo scattered throughout the game is a little on the low side, it is to be used wisely.Ammo TypeClip SizeMaximum ClipsFactionExplosive Grenades4N/ARepublicYour Side-Arm gunDC-15s Side Arm Blaster - The equivalent to a pistol, this is your sidearm. It has a self-renovating unit that prevents it from running out of ammo, but you will still have to recharge it after 8 shots in a row or so.This weapon makes sure that your squad is never without something to shoot with.Ammo TypeClip SizeMaximum ClipsFactionCharged Plasma BoltsInfinite rechargeable energy roundsN/ARepublicRepublic Commando's Shotgun variationACP Array Gun, aka "the Shotgun" - The Array Gun is pretty much a shotgun, and it will naturally do the most damage in close encounters. If you can keep all the 8 pellets on the target you'll most likely get to kill it with one shot.Ammo TypeClip SizeMaximum ClipsFactionAccelerated Charged Particle Shells8x8 charges per shot3TrandoshanShockingly effectiveLJ-50 Concussion Rifle - This rifle has a low ammo count, but it compensates with a wide explosive blast radius. As a bonus, the rifle butt (melee secondary attack) has a shocking effect on your target.Ammo TypeClip SizeMaximum ClipsFactionConcussive Charged Rounds52TrandoshanShoot, rinse, RepeaterAccelerated Charged Particle Repeater Gun, aka "the Repeater" - The equivalent to a sub-machine gun, it can be quite useful due to its high fire rate. Ideal to cut through shields, but not very effective against armor.Ammo TypeClip SizeMaximum ClipsFactionAccelerated Particle Charges406TrandoshanThis will put you in the mood to mow down anything that movesLS-150 Heavy Repeater - This is the heaviest machinegun you can carry with yourself. It has an excellent rate of fire and the biggest clip size, making it ideal to get rid of a wave of enemies. However, it will slow down your movement speed and on top of it, it takes some time to reload, so be sure to know what you're doing.Ammo TypeClip SizeMaximum ClipsFactionAccelerated Charged Particle Heavy Rounds2002TrandoshanI hear Trandoshan hunting season's openBowcastor, aka "the Crossbow" - This crossbow is the only other scoped weapon in the game (the scope will also isolate your enemies from your allies). This weapon comes with a couple of neat features: its projectiles bounce off walls and can be used to surprise your enemies. It also packs "impaler bolts", which will deliver a painful electric shock to its victims when fully charged; that and they'll nail your poor victims to the wall.Ammo TypeClip SizeMaximum ClipsFactionEnergy BoltsEnergized Impaler Bolts122WookieI've a guided present for you...Guided Rocket Launcher - This rocket launcher has a slow fire rate, but its power surpasses even the DC-17 Anti-Armor attachment's. As a bonus, and as the name indicates, you can guide your shots for betterand utter decimation. It is a very weighty weapon though, and it will slow you down almost to walking speed. It has the biggest blast radius of all the weapons in the game and therefore a well placed shot will allow you to take multiple enemies with a single shot.Ammo TypeClip SizeMaximum ClipsFactionGuided Warhead Tipped Rockets5N/AWookieMelee WeaponsThe Vibroblade is the only real melee weapon in the game, since that apart from it all the player can do is hit the enemies with the butt of his/her rifle or pistol.Vibroblade - The Trandoshans often get up close and personal to you and it pays off to have something to fight back in those situations. The Vibroblade can be used with all the DC-17 fire mode variants and also with the Trandoshan Repeater and can be activated by simply triggering the secondary attack button. After delivering the blow, the blade immediately go back into your armor, so there's no need to worry about changing back to your primary weapon afterwords.The Vibroblade can be incredibly efficient in emergencies and in close-quarters combat and if you aim for the head you'll most likely get a one hit kill.Detonators  MinesThere are 5 types of explosive-like weaponry in Republic Commando, and all of them can get to be very useful if used properly, in the proper scenario and with the right timing. The player can carry a maximum of 5 of each at a time.Electrostatic Charge Detonator - As the name states, this detonator emits an electrostatic charge that will render electronic circuits completely useless and electrocute organic targets. This make it extremely effective against Battle Droids, but also against organic enemies. It should be used with caution because it has a large blast radius and you will not want to be affected by it as well.Diversionary Flash Detonator - The equivalent to a flash-bang, this grenade causes minimal damage, but will blind your enemies for several seconds. It is most useful in situations where you come face to face with superior enemy numbers.Thermal Detonator - The Thermal Detonator pretty much acts like a normal grenade would, and it deals a lot of splash damage.Sonic Detonator - The Sonic Detonator grenade delivers a sonic blast, making it very effective especially against organics. This detonator will attach itself to any surface it hits and it will explode itself due to the proximity of an enemy target or will for you or any of your squad mates to detonate it remotely. If neither of these situations occur, it will simply wait ten seconds and eventually explode.Proximity Mine - This land mine has a motion-detector that will cause it to explode whenever anyone (including you!) walks into its action radius. The motion detector can however be fooled by taking a "slow-crouching" approach to it.GameplayRepublic Commando's gameplay is linear and fast-paced. A brisk, forward motion is encouraged by continuously respawning enemies as the player makes his way to various objectives. As the commandosA glimpse of Commando combat from an encounter on the Wookie homeworld, Kashyyyk.make their way through their missions, they'll encounter battle droids, Geonosians, Trandoshan slavers, and General Greivous' personal MagnaGuards. Dealing with these enemies requires the player to order his squad to use proper tactics, such as utilizing anti-armor shells against heavily armored spider droids. Should the player or his squadmates be disabled, another squadmate can revive the injured using an infusion of bacta. The game ends, however, if all squad members are disabled.EnemiesDuring the Republic Commando campaign, the player will meet an array of different enemies, which can be fit into 3 main categories.DroidsBattle DroidSuper Battle DroidDroidekaScavenger DroidAdvanced Dwarf Spider DroidGrievous’ Magna-GuardTrandoshansSlaverMercenaryHeavy MercenaryGrenadierGeonosiansWarriorEliteDroneLevelsRepublic Commando is divided into 3 Campaigns plus a Proloque level that serves as the game's tutorial and an Epilogue that sets in motion the idea of a possible sequel... that never came into existence, at least so far.- Prologue: the Beginning- The Clone WarsGeonosisExtreme PrejudiceInto the HiveStrength of BrotherhoodInfiltrate the Droid FoundryDestroy the Droid FactoryAdvance to the Core ShipCanyons of DeathTo Own the SkiesTerritoryInfiltration of the Core ShipWaking the GiantBelly of the BeastRepublic Assault ShipThe RAS ProsecutorDelta DownUnwelcome VisitorsRescue the SquadAloneTroikaJailbreakTactical SupremacyAttack of the ClonesLock DownThe Wrath of the RepublicSaving the ShipHolding the LineKashyyykYour HUD has a lot of info, but it's neatly presentedThe Rescue of TarfulHard ContactFrom the ShadowsThe BodyguardsObliterate the OutpostAim for the HeartCritical StrikeBridge at KachirhoTurning PointThe GauntletDetourA Bridge Too FarThe Wookie ResistanceBehind Enemy LinesV.I.W.Saving AmmoLive OrdnanceFate of the ResistanceSearch and DestroyHeart of the CitadelMoving UpstreamThe Final Strike- Epilogue: the Fate of the SquadMultiplayerRepublic Commando also features some extensive multiplayer modes that can be played over system link (2-16 Players), split-screen (4 Players) or through Xbox Live. This Xbox title also supports Content Download, allowing additional maps to be downloaded. Game types include:AssaultEach round consists of one team attacking whilst the other defends, and then the defenders get a chance to attack. The attackers begin with a flag in their base and their objective is to bring this flag into the opponent's base, which scores two points. The defenders must prevent the attackers from bringing the flag inside their base. If the flag is dropped, it automatically returns to the attackers base for a short period of time. If the defenders manage to prevent the attackers from burning the flag into their base for the entire time limit, they score one point. Both teams get to attack in a round, with the winner determined after all rounds are completed.Capture the FlagDeathmatchTeam DeathmatchVoice TalentsVoice TalentCharacterTemuera MorrisonBossAndrew ChaikinFixerJonathan CookSevRaphael SbargeScorchRena OwenTaun We / RAS Ship ComputerTom KaneYoda / Captain TalbotSoundtrackCover Art for Republic Commando's SoundtrackThe music for Star Wars: Republic Commando was written by Jesse Harlin and used to be available for download at the game's official website, when the game still had one. The compositions range from the use of lots of moody segments to the use of plenty of epic awe-inspiring choir themes.Track No.Song TitleRunning Time01Vode An (Brothers All)01.5802Prologue03.2403The Egg Room02.3404Gra'tua Cuun (Our Vengeance)02.3205Improvised Entry01.3306They Must Be Asleep01.2307The Ghost Ship02.2408Ka'rta Tor (One Heart of Justice)01.5409Comm Interference02.1610The Jungle Floor02.4511RV Alpha04.5512Through the Canopy01.1513Rage of the Shadow Warriors02.0214Make Their Eyes Water01.2315Kachirho By Night Vision01.23TriviaIn the demo for Star Wars: The Force Unleashed, there is a hidden Easter egg of Boss' helmet sitting in a difficult to reach position. This has lead to speculation that a sequel is in development.In the Prosecutor level when the player reaches a Trandoshan barricade, there is a little room. There the player finds a lightsaber and triggers the dialogue "An elegant weapon for a more civilized time? Heh. Well... times have changed".Other InfoThe Xbox version supports:Players 1-4In-Game Dolby DigitalSystem Link 2-10HDTV 480pCommunicator HeadsetContent DownloadOnline MultiplayerFriendsVoicePC System RequirementsMINIMUM REQUIREMENTSOperating System: Windows 98SE / ME / 2000 / XPCPU: Pentium III or Athlon 1.0 GHz or faster CPU requiredRAM Memory: 256 MBGraphics Card: 64MB 3D Graphics card with Vertex Shader and Pixel Shader (VS/PS) capability requiredSound Card: 100% DirectX 9.0c compatible Audio DeviceCD-ROM: 8X Speed CD-ROM or DVD-ROM Drive requiredInput Device: Keyboard and Mouse requiredDirectX: Microsoft DirectX 9.0cHard Drive Space: 2 GB of free hard disk space required. Additional free space required after game installation for Windows swap file and save gamesRECOMMENDED REQUIREMENTSOperating System: Windows 98SE / ME / 2000 / XPCPU: Pentium 4 2.0 GHz, or Athlon XP 2400 2.0 GHz or fasterRAM Memory: 512 MBGraphics Card: NVIDIA GeForceFX 5700 or higherSound Card: 100% DirectX 9.0c compatible Audio Device.CD-ROM: 8X Speed CD-ROM or DVD-ROM Drive required.Input Device: Keyboard and Mouse required.DirectX: Microsoft DirectX 9.0cHard Drive Space: 2 GB of free hard disk space required. Additional free space required after game installation for Windows swap file and save games.Video Chipsets Supported at Time of ReleaseATI Radeon 8500ATI Radeon 9x00 FamilyATI Radeon Xx00 FamilyIntelR GMA GraphicsNVIDIA GeForce3 FamilyNVIDIA GeForce4 Ti FamilyNVIDIA GeForceFX FamilyNVIDIA GeForce 6 Family</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10853">Freedom Fighters</game><game id="270">Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon: Advanced Warfighter 2</game><game id="1986">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six: Vegas 2</game><game id="9969">Full Spectrum Warrior</game><game id="9137">Brothers in Arms: Road to Hill 30</game><game id="22107">Interstellar Marines</game><game id="24035">Halo 3: ODST</game><game id="2600">Halo: Combat Evolved</game><game id="30615">Gears of War 3</game><game id="20834">Brothers in Arms: Hell's Highway</game><game id="3617">Brothers in Arms: Earned in Blood</game><game id="7288">SWAT 4</game><game id="17797">SWAT 4: The Stetchkov Syndicate</game><game id="2444">Full Spectrum Warrior: Ten Hammers</game><game id="2397">Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon: Advanced Warfighter</game><game id="3550">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six: Vegas</game><game id="16073">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six 3: Raven Shield</game><game id="17609">Breed</game><game id="15473">Metroid Prime</game><game id="1597">Metroid Prime 2: Echoes</game><game id="4725">Metroid Prime 3: Corruption</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/6/62890/1547001-repcom_boxart.jpg</image></root>