<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13445</id><name>WWE Raw 2</name><description>OverviewLesnar argues with TakerThe game features a Story Mode where your wrestler climbs their way up the ladder to obtain championship gold. On the way, they will make allies and rivals. The story mode can be played through with an existing wrestler or your own wrestler which can be made in the Create a Superstar feature. Gameplay is based on a momentum system. Different attacks and taunting your opponent raises the meter. When it is full, you can perform the wrestlers’ finishing move.Roster The Rock The Undertaker Triple H Hulk Hogan Kurt Angle Brock Lesnar Rob Van Dam Ric Flair Booker T Goldust Kane The HurricaneA-Train Matt HardyRikishi Big Show Chris Jericho Chris Benoit Eddie Guerrero Chavo Guerrero Bubba Ray DudleySpike Dudley Billy GunnChuck Palumbo Edge Rey Mysterio John CenaRicoLance Storm Christian Test William RegalJamie NobleTajiriBilly KidmanNidia LitaTeri Torrie Wilson Trish Stratus Stacy KeiblerMollyJazzJacquelineVictoriaChris NowinskiSteven Richards "Stone Cold" Steve Austin Scott Steiner Batista D-Von Dudley Hardcore HollyCrash Holly Mark Henry Tommy Dreamer Goldberg Bradshaw Randy Orton Val Venis Kevin NashRhyno Shawn Michaels Stephanie McMahonArenasRawSmackDown!Royal Rumble 2003No Way Out 2003Wrestlemania XIXBacklash 2002Judgment Day 2002King of the Ring 2002Vengeance 2002Summerslam 2002Unforgiven 2002No Mercy 2002Survivor Series 2002 (For unknown reasons, the arena is heavily modified from it's set up in Madison Square Garden to being a modified version of the SmackDown arena)Armageddon 2002- All arenas except for Raw and Smackdown have to be unlocked by winning in the game's career mode at that PPV- The spot on the Raw set where the TNN logo would've gone is replaced in the game by the THQ logoMatch TypesBooker T Spinning KickArmageddon (6-player free for all)HardcoreHell in a CellRoyal RumbleLadderTLCBattle RoyalTag TeamCageTablesKing of the RingHandicapFeaturesCustom soundtracksSupports up to 4 playersCustomization of the WWE Roster4 player career modeOver 60 WWE SuperstarsOver 100 Create-a-wrestler slotsCreate an entrance videoTournament mode</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="10">Wrestling</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10775">WWF Royal Rumble</game><game id="2308">WWE Day of Reckoning</game><game id="30637">Lucha Libre AAA Heroes del Ring</game><game id="487">WWE WrestleMania 21</game><game id="28430">WWF Royal Rumble</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2139894-box_wweraw2.png</image></root>