<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13450</id><name>LMA Manager 2002</name><description>LMA Manager 2002 was first released on November 2, 2001 on the PlayStation. It was the final game in the series that was released on the original PlayStation. The game was re-released in 2002  for the PlayStation 2 (for the first time) with many new features and tweaks to the original game.New FeaturesThere were not many new improvements made to the PlayStation version. When it was released on the PlayStation 2, more features were introduced. Here are the PlayStation version new features;The game has been updated to the 2001/2002 football seasonUpdated 3D Match EngineMany European teams to transfer players with. 17,000 players, 722 clubs in 16 divisionsUpdated in-game interfaceLarger and more detailed squadsNew featured commentary with Alan Hansen and Gary Lineker.PlayStation 2 VersionAfter the PS1 game was released, work began on a PlayStation 2 port. The PlayStation 2 version of LMA Manager 2002 was released on April 19, 2002. The game was a very big improvement over the PlayStation version. The game allows players to manage in four new European countries. The new countries include Spain (top two divisions), Italy (top two divisions), Germany (top two divisions) and France (only the top division). The matches were now played out in a full in-game 3D match enviroment. The in-game game play has also been improved with improved AI and animations and new instant replays. There is now an option to watch game highlights with full commentary from Gary Lineker and Alan Hansen. Also, the transfer market had grown bigger in size. The jump to the PlayStation 2 was a big step for the LMA Manager series. This is continued a year later with LMA Manager 2003, also on the PlayStation 2.LeaguesThis is a list of all of the game's leagues from the PlayStation 2 version:EnglandEnglish Premier LeagueEnglish Division OneEnglish Division TwoEnglish Division ThreeScotlandScottish PremiershipScottish First DivisionScottish Second DivisionScottish Third DivisionSpain1st Division2nd Division AItalySeria ASeria BFranceLigue 1Germany1st Bundesliga2nd Bundesliga</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="40">Soccer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8108">Championship Manager Season 97/98</game><game id="3753">FIFA Manager 07</game><game id="13578">Championship Manager 2</game><game id="12974">Championship Manager 2: Scandinavian Leagues</game><game id="27051">Championship Manager 2007</game><game id="10532">Championship Manager 3</game><game id="5444">Championship Manager 4</game><game id="20279">Championship Manager 5</game><game id="16216">Championship Manager '93</game><game id="3248">Championship Manager: Season 1999/2000</game><game id="10275">Championship Manager: Season 00/01</game><game id="17370">Championship Manager: Season 01/02</game><game id="8563">Championship Manager: Season 02/03</game><game id="9111">Championship Manager: Season 03/04</game><game id="1467">FA Premier League Football Manager 2000</game><game id="5605">FIFA Manager 06</game><game id="454">FIFA Soccer Manager</game><game id="24888">FIFA Manager 09</game><game id="13818">Football Manager</game><game id="2662">Football Manager 2</game><game id="26944">Football  Manager Handheld 2009</game><game id="20784">Football Manager 2008</game><game id="22117">Worldwide Soccer Manager 2006</game><game id="23498">Football Manager 2009</game><game id="5762">Premier Manager 3</game><game id="17239">Premier Manager 3 De-Luxe</game><game id="7009">Premier Manager 97</game><game id="13">Premier Manager 98</game><game id="6697">Premier Manager Ninety Nine</game><game id="13826">Premier Manager 2</game><game id="10527">Premier Manager 2005-2006</game><game id="4805">Soccer Team Manager: English and Italian Leagues</game><game id="30751">Football Manager 2011</game><game id="33212">Football Manager 2012</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9261/310343-51by480qtrl._sl500_aa280_.jpg</image></root>