<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13463</id><name>Real Bout Fatal Fury Special</name><description>Overview Real Bout Fatal Fury Special (known in Japan as Real Bout Garou Densetsu Special) is a fighting game developed and published by                                    SNK for the                                     Neo Geo. Similar to                                   Fatal Fury Special, much of the gameplay mechanics and character roster return from                                  Real Bout Fatal Fury. The two-plane fight system returns from Fatal Fury Special, as well as                                Tung Fu Rue,                               Cheng Sinzan,             Laurence Blood, and                              Wolfgang Krauser (who reprises his role as the game's boss).                         Geese Howard, who died in the previous game, returns in a secret "nightmare match". The game was ported to the                             Neo Geo CD,                            Sega Saturn, and                           Game Boy. The original Neo Geo version is included in the                Fatal Fury Battle Archives Volume 2 compilation for the               PlayStation 2. Other than the two-plane fight system, the only change from Real Bout Fatal Fury gameplay-wise is that recovery rolls are now standard for all characters and can only be executed when the player's power gauge is at least half-filled. Real Bout Garou Densetsu Special: Dominated Mind The game was ported to the                          Sony PlayStation in Japan with the "Dominated Mind" subtitle. This version contains a new protagonist,            Alfred Airhawk, and a new boss character,           White. The story centers around White's brainwashing of                        Billy Kane and his attempted takeover of the late Geese Howard's grasp on the South Town underworld. The game features animated cut-scenes, super cancels (known as "final impacts"), and parries (known as "advanced guard") at the cost of plane shifting.Characters and Stages Each character has a unique background and theme.   Character Stage Terry Bogard ,and Blue Mary       Andy Bogard   Joe Higashi  Mai Shiranui        Kim Kaphwan    Billy Kane  Duck King     Ryuji Yamazaki  Jin Chonrei       Jin Chonshu  Sokaku Mochizuki  Bob Wilson  Hon-Fu  Franco Bash  Tung-Fue-Ru  Cheng Sinzan   Laurence Blood  Wolfgang Krauser </description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14669">Virtua Fighter Animation</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="20616">Super Street Fighter II Turbo HD Remix</game><game id="28437">Super Street Fighter IV</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8153/1082002-565711_86409_front.jpg</image></root>