<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13567</id><name>Grand Theft Auto</name><description>OverviewGrand Theft Auto was originally released in 1997 for the  Playstation and  PC. The game is set in three different fictional cities:  Liberty City,  Vice City and  San Andreas. Each city is  loosely based on a real-life city. Liberty City is based on  New York, Vice City is similar to  Miami, and San Andreas is loosely adapted from  Los Angeles.The main character is dropped into the game world and does various odd jobs for the local  crime bosses. Progress through the different cities is done by earning money from completing missions assigned from various pay phones.Evolutionary DifferencesA number of major differences exist between Grand Theft Auto's design and that of the later games in the series:Mission failure is strict and inflexible. There is no option to return to a failed mission, it is simply gone forever.Money can be earned from  killing people and crashing cars.Three distinctly different cities are included. Subsequent games in the franchise would go on to focus on just a single city, with the  Grand Theft Auto III trilogy re-imaging the three cities contained in this game.The only modes of transportation are ground-based vehicles and walking/running. Boats, planes and other, more exotic forms of transportation were not included in the game.Support for internet and LAN multiplayer game modes. These would not officially return again until  Grand Theft Auto IV, though there would be unofficial patches to Vice City and San Andreas' PC versions to include similar functionality.CharactersThe PC version of the game lets players pick from eight characters while the playstation version only lets players choose the four male characters. There is no difference in the characters in the actual gameplay, the only real difference is when players change the characters name.TravisKatNikkiDivineTroyKivlovUlrikeSoundtrackRadio '76 FMGenre: Funk*Ghetto Fingers - "On The Move"*Ashtar - "Aori"*Stylus Exodus - "Pootang Shebang"Brooklyn Underground FMGenre: Trance*Retrograde - "Benzoate"*Government Listening Post - "E104"*Trancefer - "Figiwhiz"The Fix FMGenre: Techno*Animal Testing Centre - "DSP"*Rotorman - "Ride"*Technophiliak - "Lagerstar"The Fergus Buckner Show FMGenre: Country*Sideways Hank O'Malley (and The Alabama Bottle Boys) - "The Ballad of Chapped Lip Calquhoun"Head Radio FMGenre: Pop/Rock*Reality Bubble - "Days Like These"*Meme Traders - "Automatic Transmission"*Ohjaamo - "Complications"It's Unleashed FMGenre: Alternative/Hard rock*Stikki Fingers - "4 Letter Love"*The Hounds - "Let It Out"*Bleeding Stump - "Just Do It"N-CT FMGenre: Hip hop/Rap*Da Shootaz - "Grand Theft Auto"*Slumpussy - "This Life"*CCC Featuring Robert DeNegro - "Blow Your Console"Freeware ReleaseOn December 23rd, 2004, Rockstar announced that they would be releasing both Grand Theft Auto and Grand Theft Auto 2 as freely downloadable packages on their website. The content of both games remains unchanged, but they have been reworked to natively run in Windows XP and Windows Vista.PC System RequirementsMinimum75 MHz Pentium16 MB of RAM1 MB VESA-compatible SVGA graphics cardDOS 6.0 or Win95/9880 MB hard disk spaceSound cardKeyboardRecommended166 MHz Pentium2 MB VESA-compatible SVGA graphics cardWin 95/98Soundblaster-compatible sound cardOptionalJoystick or gamepadModem (Hayes-compatible needed for the DOS version)Local area network using the IPX protocolSerial cable (null modem cable or adapter)Video card or 3D addon card using a 3Dfx-based chipsetExternal Links  Rockstar Classics - Link to Rockstar's site, offering a free download.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12283">Quarantine</game><game id="20679">Saints Row 2</game><game id="22650">Hard Time</game><game id="12282">World's Scariest Police Chases</game><game id="14785">The Getaway: Black Monday</game><game id="18044">Death Rally</game><game id="8186">Road Raider</game><game id="5618">Saints Row</game><game id="4065">Crackdown</game><game id="3345">True Crime: New York City</game><game id="27239">Getaway!</game><game id="27511">Car Jack Streets</game><game id="29265">Zombie Driver</game><game id="31558">Retro City Rampage</game><game id="18120">APB</game><game id="10094">Miami Chase</game><game id="10448">Spy Hunter</game><game id="3619">Crime Fighter</game><game id="34623">Death Rally</game><game id="21960">Miami Vice</game><game id="6608">River City Ransom</game><game id="38451">Smash Cops</game><game id="39452">Hotline Miami</game><game id="20704">Speed Rumbler</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3699/1790087-gta1.jpg</image></root>