<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13685</id><name>WarioWare: Smooth Moves</name><description>OverviewWarioWare: Smooth Moves brings the varied, fast-paced gameplay that the series is known for, this time with microgames designed specifically to take advantage of the Wii's unique features. Like previous installments in the franchise, Smooth Moves is a collection of microgames that the player accesses through a fast-paced series of story chapters. The player utilizes the Wii Remote (referred to as the "Form Baton") to interact with the various minigames using a variety of different poses with names that provide context for the pantomime--for example, holding the Wii Remote vertically is called The Umbrella. Additionally, Smooth Moves has an included multiplayer component, allowing up to 12 players to play the game in turns. The microgames can be played using only the Wii Remote, but there is an extra, separate set of games design to also use the Nunchuk (referred to as the "Balance Stone")Each player has a profile, up to 12 of which can be stored on one game save. Each profile records the player's name, Mii, gender, and the hand they use, as this information is used in some microgames (info can be changed in the Factory menu). A player's profile also holds their single player progress and high scores, which are lost if the profile is deleted.Story"A long time ago..." Ancient drawings depict a race of small creatures which appear to worship a Wii Remote-like object (the "Form Baton"), which humans are shown using. The creatures are shown worshiping the object in a temple. The scene fades into present day Diamond City. The Temple of Form still stands, and Wario rides past on his motorcycle...Character StoriesWario (Mysterious Form Baton Found!): Wario is at home, snacking on a bowl full of confectionery. One of the mysterious creatures sneaks in and grabs the whole bowl. Wario gives chase and runs straight into the Temple of Form, where sees the Form Baton. When he picks it up, though, a rumbling is heard and a boulder appears, Indiana Jones-style, and Wario runs for it. When he bursts from the Temple he holds his prize high in the air, victorious.Mona (Cheerleading to Victory): Mona has a new hobby: cheerleading. Late as usual, she speeds over to the local stadium to cheer at a football game. One of the players has a huge crush on Mona, and realizes he has to focus on the game before he gets too flustered. At the last minute he thinks of Mona and scores a game-winning touchdown, for her. After the game, Mona runs to her scooter while he stands by stammering, only managing to finish saying "I love you" after she's already left.Kat  Ana (Evil Attacks Diamond Dojo!): A colossal red demon approaches the Diamond Dojo. Kat and Ana rush to the scene, ready to take him on. Ana hurries to the sensei's aid, only to find him be bothered by a little demon child. Meanwhile, Kat is tackling the bigger demon head-on outside, until the child shouts for them to stop. As the sun rises, the demon walks away carrying it's child as Kat waves goodbye. Suddenly she notices that she's standing by the young demon, and it's parent is actually walking off with poor Ana.Young Cricket (Enter Young Cricket): Young Cricket and Master Mantis are walking into town, and feeling pretty hungry from their journey. As they walk, they suddenly smell something delicious nearby, which turns out to be a food stand run by Mona and her friends. Seeing the huge line, Cricket decides to simply jump up and run over their heads to the front of the line. When he gets there, he realizes that there are a lot of angry customers waiting behind him, so he goes back (using the heads again, of course) to Master Mantis and decides to get in line.Jimmy T. (Feline Fever): It's a rainy night, and Jimmy's walking to Club Sugar again. A cat peers out from behind a trash can and feeling sorry for him, Jimmy gives it his umbrella. Before long, that cat, and couple dozen others, have decided to join him. Unable to shake them, he realizes that they can join him in in his dancing and they go to Club Sugar together. After dancing all through the night, they leave in the early morning. As they depart the first cat taps Jimmy on the shoulder, and returns his umbrella. Jimmy's stage is a remix of the microgames from Mona, Kat  Ana and Young Cricket's stages.Ashley (The Loquacious Spell Book): In the mansion library, Ashley and Red are researching a new spell. Red transforms into a magic wand, which Ashley uses on a potted plant. To her dismay, this simple turns it into a flower. One of the books suggests that he has an idea. Trying a second time, the plant turns into a massive monster plant, and Red returns to normal just in time to see it grow through the roof of the mansion. As he cowers behind her, Ashley simply smiles.Dribble  Spitz (Tomorrow Hill): It's a beautiful day and Dribble  Spitz are cleaning their cab. A young girl walks up with a suitcase, and asks to be taken to Tomorrow Hill. The duo are ready to go, as always, and they set off. They pull up to Tomorrow Hill as night falls, and the girl walks up to the top. Dribble and Spitz are shocked when all of a sudden a massive spaceship appears, and the girl transforms into an alien. She waves as she is beamed up, and the ship disappears in a flash of bright light. When the dust settles, Spitz remembers that they didn't collect the fare (again).Penny (The Invent-Off): We are introduced to Penny Crygor, the granddaughter of Dr. Crygor. She shows up at the Diamond Academy to face her grandpa in an "Invent-Off". The two stand in a wrestling ring, with Mike at ringside. However, Penny's invention defeats Crygor. The match over, Penny uses on of Mike's mics to perform onstage.9-Volt (The Multiplayer Test): 18-Volt is over at 9-Volt's house again, and 9-Volt is showing him a dual-screen Game  Watch system. 18-Volt watches him play for a while, but while trying to have a go himself, he ends up breaking it in half. 9-Volt, furious, screams at him to get out of the house. 18-Volt, goes to the Toy Express store to try and find a replacement, when he notices a commotion over the road at the game store. The storekeeper holds up a new Game  Watch, but as 18-Volt goes to grab it, he notices that 9-Volt is there to get one too. Realizing the 18-Volt is sorry, they make up and become best friends again.Jimmy P. (Canine Crazed): It's a bright, sunny day, and Jimmy P. (who looks like Jimmy T. but tanned, wearing an open Hawaiian shirt and a yellow afro) is on his way to Club Spice. A dog peers out from behind a trash can and feeling sorry for him, Jimmy gives it a bone. Before long, that dog, and couple dozen others, have decided to join him. Unable to shake them, he realizes that they can join him in in his dancing and they go to Club Spice together. After dancing all through the day, they leave in the early evening. As they depart, Jimmy T. taps Jimmy P. on the shoulder, looking curious. Jimmy P.'s stage is a remix of the microgames from Ashley, Dribble  Spitz, Penny and 9-Volt's stages.Tiny Wario (Forever Form Baton): Back at Wario's home, he receives Penny's invention in the mail. He decides to take the small bike for a ride around town. Suddenly, it starts sucking Wario into itself and starts spitting out a bunch of tiny Warios. They come upon a nearby strawberry field and start ravaging them.ConclusionThe Tiny Warios reform into normal Wario (who still has the Form Baton). The creatures from the Temple appear and start demanding that he return the Baton, so Wario runs for it. They chase him all the way out to the Temple of Form, where he trips over and drops the object back to it's resting place. The creature who stole stole his candy thanks him, and the cast credits roll. Penny's bike finally comes to a stop outside the temple as the story ends.Post-Story StagesOrbulon (The Secret of the Balance Stone): Orbulon's ship is hovering around in outer space, when it's suddenly struck by an object shooting towards it. The ship crash lands in the Temple of Form, where the object (the "Balance Stone") comes to rest near the Form Baton. Both the Baton and the Balance Stone start glowing, and Orbulon picks them up. The temple starts to rumble violently as it pulls itself free of the ground and starts rising. When it reaches all the way to space, Orbulon claims it for himself, only to be set upon by many of the strange creatures. The temple comes crashing back down the the surface and Orbulon and his ship are forcibly ejected. Orbulon's games all require the Nunchuk to be connected.Dr. Crygor (The Kelorometer): Crygor and Mike have developed a new machine (the Kelorometer) which helps players to lose weight. The duo load the player in and start working the machine. The player must play though twenty microgames (pulled from the other stages) designed to help them lose weight, and at the end they tell them how many "kels" they've lost while playing.Remix TowersThe following stages mix up all the microgames of all the characters (except Orbulon). The animal that represents them in this game is an elephant.All Mixed Up: A normal mix, starting at normal speed and difficulty.Super Hard: Starts out very fast.Sudden Death: Player has one life only.Thrilling: No form cards are shown.Unlockable MinigamesTower Tennis: The player holds a ping-pong bat and must keep a ball bouncing as they slowly move up a tower. Dropping the ball ends the game. Blocks appear to hinder progress as the player moves up. Some can be destroyed with the ball, while other cannot. Block must be cleared for the bat to get through.Block Star: An extended version of the Block Party boss microgame in which the player must catch the falling blocks on a platform and hold them there until the end. Ten different levels are available to play.Can Shooter: A retro-styled shooting gallery. The player must shoot as many cans as possible before the timer runs out. In addition to normal cans, there are large red barrels which require multiple hits, bombs thrown from the background, rockets fired towards the screen (which end the game on impact) and special cans which add more time, slow down or speed up the game, or give the player better targeting. The background changes as the game progresses.Tortoise  Hare: Requires the Nunchuk. An endless version of the Hare Raising microgame. The player must raise and lower the red and white flags as instructed. Failure to match the instructions quickly enough ends the game.Balloon Trip: Requires the Nunchuk. An endless version of the Balloon Fight microgame, in which the player must flap their arms and avoid sparks and fish. In this version however, the player uses the nunchuk. The nunchuk flaps the left arm, while the Remote flaps the right. Points are earned by popping balloons and a bonus is given every 1000 yards.Pyoro S: This  Pyoro sequel plays like a vertical shooter. Pyoro is controller by the Remote's pointer, and pressing A or B fires his beak. Eating a whole group of enemies drops a bonus apple, while destroying a group of flashing enemies will drop an apple that gives Pyoro a special ability. Grabbing a honeycomb ball lets Pyoro use it to smash into enemies until it breaks. At the end of a section a boss appears, and when beaten, the speed goes up. Touching an enemy or projectile will end the game.Multiplayer GamesAfter the story mode is completed, Multiplayer mode can be selected from the Main Menu. All games require only one Wii Remote (and in some cases, a Nunchuk.)Microgame MixesMultiplayer action.Survival: 2-12 Players. A standard pass-the-controller mode. Each player is represented as an angel flying through the sky. Each player is called up (in random order) to play a game. Failing will drop them out of the sky; the last player left wins the game. As the game goes on, the speed gets faster and faster.Bomb: 2-5 Players. Players pass a bomb between each other. After beating their microgame, they must choose the Form for the next player (after a Form has been chosen once, it's level goes up giving the victim a harder game). Failing a game or holding the bomb too long while choosing a Form will cause the bomb to explode and the player will lose.Lifeline: 2-5 Players. Players run along a road, performing microgames. After five rounds, players find themselves tied up over a river. In the first part, each round is worth progressively more points. The ranking after five rounds determines how many ropes hold them up in the second part. Each player has to take turns cutting a rope (though which player it's attached to is a mystery). The last player held up wins.Balloon: 2-5 Players. Similar to the Balloon Pop game from  WarioWare, Inc.: Mega Party Game$! Each player takes it in turn to play a game. Before they start they have to pump the balloon, and then they must play microgames until they win one. While they play, the other players are automatically pumping up the balloon. When the balloon explodes, whoever is playing loses.MinigamesDarts: 2-4 Players. Played like a standard game of darts. Players try to reduce their score exactly 300 points total, without going over. The first player to get 300 points, or the person closest after 10 rounds, wins the game.Star Nose: 2 Players; requires Nunchuk. Each player has to guide their Nose-shaped ship though a tunnel, collecting power-ups while trying not to crash. The player that collects three power-ups first, or survives longer than the other player, wins.Bungie Buddies: 2 Players; requires Nunchuk. A cooperative game in which two guys run along a track, jumping over obstacles and going as far possible before the time runs out. Each player holds their half of the controller to their hip, and jumps when they come to a hole or ditch. Falling in will slow the players down. At the end, the players are ranked on how well they know each other and how far they traveled, and given a commemorative pose to perform.Bonus FeaturesIn addition to minigames and multiplayer modes, there are a few bonus features that can be unlocked.Temple of Form: The Temple of Form collects all the microgames encountered by the player, and allows them to be sorted alphabetically, by character, or by form. Each game can be played through through all three version in a row, at a player-set speed (though it only allows on run-through, unlike previous game which offered endless runs of each game). In addition, all the Pose Cards that the player has seen during the story stages are collected here.Movie Theater: Allows the player to view the character intros and epilogues from the story mode.Sound Studio: Feature two sections. The Music area allows the player to either listen to each of the songs in the game properly, or to play them by waving the Wii Remote like a conductor's baton. The Sound Effects area lets the player tap shapes as they fall, each one playing a different sound effect from the game. There are three types of background music and three tempo settings to play around with.Staff Credits: A minigame in which the Miis of all the developers walk out onto a stage to bow, where the player can place a hole beneath them with the Wii Remote. The number of Miis they catch is tracked as a high score.FormsEvery microgame is played using a Form, which is the way in which the player is meant to hold the Remote. All modes except the Thrilling Tower will display the required Form before each game. Each one has a name and is explained to the player the first time they encounter it in the story mode. Intros can be viewed again by selecting the lid of it's card box in the Temple of Form.The Remote ControlThe UmbrellaThe HandlebarThe Sketch ArtistThe ChauffeurThe SamuraiThe Tug-of-WarThe WaiterThe ElephantThe Thumb WrestlerThe DiscardThe Big CheeseThe JanitorThe DumbbellThe MohawkThe Finger FoodThe BoxerThe Mortar and PestleThe Diner (3 variations; requires Balance Stone [the nunchuk]; only used in Orbulon's stage)Complete Microgame ListingListed as they appear under "Story" in the Temple of Form in-game. Unlike other WarioWare games, high scores for each microgame cannot be achieved. Each game lets the player set the speed and play the three difficulty levels and then it ends. There are 205 microgames total in Smooth Moves.WarioForms:The Remote ControlPest Control: Shoot the target areas on the monster.Playing Hooky: Use the hook to pick up the man.Wario PI: Focus on the image.On the Ropes: Swing the jump rope.Take a Stab at It: Catch the objects on the foil.Wokka Wokka!: Toss the food in the air.Crowd Control: Chase everyone off the screen.Wario Fu: Avoid the enemies.You Can Pick Your Friends...: Pick the nose.Poster Child: Fix up the poster.Shaving Scream: Shave all of the facial hair.One In Hole: Drop everyone through the hole.Boss Stage: Biggest Fan: Blow away all the Warios and then the giant robot.Drop!: [This stage does not appear in the Temple of Form, but appears randomly throughout the game and appears as a bonus while playing other games in the Temple.] Drop the Wii Remote.MonaForms:The Umbrella, The HandlebarStage Fright: Find the man.Welcome Committee: Shoot down the UFO.Keep Your Guy on the Ball: Stay balanced on the ball.Fan Boy: Keep the paper butterfly in the air.Shakedown: Shake everything off.Swat Team: Swat the bugs.Carrot Away: Pull up the carrot.Runner's High: Get to the goal.Fired Up: Bounce the man to safety.Dough Boy: Spin the dough.Up for Grabs: Yank the objects.Come to Poppa: Pop the balloon.Closing Time: Close the shutters when everyone is out.Over Easy: Flip the food over into the pan.Honeymoon Fall Out: Grab the woman before she falls.Universal Marionette: Make the puppet deflect the objects.Cupsy Daisy: Swing the ball into the cup.Escape Artist: Rescue the guy.Five More Minutes: Stop the alarm.Tearful Reunion: Reunite the two people by tilting the zipline.Hand Me Down: Hand over the item.Wet Your Whistle: Have a drink.Boss Stage: Toilet Training: Direct the swimmers to the correct restroom.Kat  AnaForms:The Sketch Artist, The Chauffeur, The SamuraiCutting Edge: Slice the object.On the Edge: Trace the shape on screen.Serve Already!: Keep the ball in the air.Paper Trail: Avoid the tree.Objet D'Art: Hit the dartboard.Frequent Flyer: Hand out flyers to passers-by.Extreme Patty-Cake: Push the person down.Writer's Block: Make the pen write.BYOM: Cook the meat.Teeth Polithe: Get the teeth in the granny's mouth.Cookie Rookie: Cut shapes in the dough.A Moment of Reflection: Reflect the light at the person's head.Saving Face: Get a headshot.Stick It Through 'Em!: Skewer the food.Shear Terror: Shear off all the wool.Fitting In: Follow the Mexican wave.S-T-R-E-T-C-H!: Grab the food.Budget Dentistry: Fix the cavities.A-maze-ing: Get the ball out of the maze.Simon Says: Cop the person on screen.Code Dependency: Scan the barcode.Mall Tour: Rock out for the crowd.Boss Stage: Driver's Ed: Drive to the finish.Young CricketForms:The Tug-of-War, The Waiter, The ElephantBroom Shtick: Keep the object balanced.That's How I Roll: Get the ball in the hole.Plane and Simple: Scrape the wood.Logged In: Saw through the wood.Anchor Man: Win the tug-of-war.Castanet, First Chair: Play the castanet.Meet the Eggheads: Get the egg to his family.Pink Eye: Use the eye lasers to destroy the heads.Geared for Landing: Crank the gate open for the plane.This Bites!: Avoid being stung.Suit of Armoire: Open the right drawer.All Wound Up: Unwind the thing.The Outcast: Choose the one that doesn't fit in.Helping Hand: Don't let anything hit the ground.Sweeps Week: Win the curling game.Spring Cleaning: Vacuum everything up.Volley, Y'all!: Return the ball.Clean Your Plate!: Clean the plate.Smile and Nod: Nod if the answer is yes.Junk and My Trunk: Pick up the object with the trunk and put it where it belongs.Boss Stage: Block Party: Collect the falling blocks in a pile and don't let them drop off.AshleyForms:The Thumb Wrestler, The Discard, The Big CheeseUndercover Agent: Open the umbrella when the meter is full.Cold Call: Answer the phone.Spray It, Don't Say It: Shake the champagne and then spray it at the screen.Wiggle Room: Keep the hoop up.Carving Artist: Carve the block.Sticky Shift: Get into gear.Bone Appetit: Steal the bone.You're Fired!: Light the torch and fire the cannons.In the Cards: Pick up the correct card.How the West Was Really Won: Win the quick draw.Shady Characters: Spin the silhouette and pick the right object.Skip It: Jump over the rope.Shoot the Breeze: Knock down all the targets.Cheater!: Find the right side of the die.Marching Orders: Keep up with the marching line.Flask Me Later: Mix the contents of the flask.All Shook Up: Open the bottle.Pool Boy: Pot a ball.Secret Ingredient: Grate the object.Ringmaster: Ring the bell in time with the other players.Boss Stage: Fresh off the Grill: Take the burger when it is ready.Dribble  SpitzForms:The Janitor, The Dumbbell, The MohawkDiddly Squat: Do some squats.Up in Arms: Pump the dumbells.Clean Sweep: Sweep up all the leaves.Eating for Two: Bounce food into the mouth.The Closer: Throw a strike.Stick It to the Man!: Hit people with the bat.When in Rome...: Copy the movements of the other canes.Talk to the Can!: Spray all the bugs.Cut to the Chase: Clip the nails.Catch of the Day: Cover up the creature to make a meal.Bell Captain: Ring the bell.Rally and Cry: Rally the ball back.Soiled Reputation: Use the hoe on the soil.Use Your Head: Header the soccer ball.Unintelligent Life: Abduct everything in sight.Spring Training: Avoid the flying objects.Femme Brûlée: Keep the woman shaded.Sprinkler System: Get some powder into the container.Stick a Fork in It: Jam the fork into the food.Armed and Dangerous: Win the arm wrestle.Boss Stage: Boot Camp: Jump and duck to avoid the barriers, then switch forms and shoot down the attacking nose.PennyForms:The Finger Food, The Boxer, The Mortar and PestleBoarder Patrol: Unlock the door.Slice of Life: Shred the document.Mixed Signals: Find a clear signal.Yes, You Can!: Open the can.The Intern: Get the documents in order.Stir Crazy: Stir the contents of the bowl.Community Service: Scrub the object.Local News: Hold the mic up to the interviewee's mouth.Get to the Point: Sharpen the pencil.Mercury Falling: Reset the thermometer.XYZ!: Close the zipper.Spot On!: Hammer the nails.Airhead: Don't let the puck go into the goal.Cranky Robot: Wind up the robot.Sure, You Can: Defeat the ninja.Burning Sensation: Burn the creatures.Now You're Cooking!: Ignite the cooker.Hit Parade: Whack all the moles.Litter Bot: Pick up all the trash.Stay Tuned: Tune the guitar.Boss Stage: Produce Stand-Off: Deflect the enemy's attacks and defeat him.9-VoltForms:All (excluding The Diner)Wiipeat After Me!: Copy the movements shown on screen.Super Mario Brothers: Collect coins.Light Tennis: Don't lose the game.Animal Crossing: Yank the fish out of the water.Opening Night: Conduct the orchestra.WarioWare: Twisted!: Complete the microgame.Wario Land: Throw the enemy.Game  Watch Octopus: Grab the treasure.Balloon Fight: Don't hit the sparks or enemies.Metroid Prime 2: Knock over the barrel.Pikmin 2: Squash all the Pikmin.Nintendogs: High five the dogs.Super Mario Sunshine: Put out the fire.Punch-Out!!: Count the fighter out.Super Nostalgic Entertainment System: Insert the cartridge.Laser Clay Shooting: Shoot the targets.The Wind Waker: Float over to land.Brain Age: Connect the numbers in order.Ocarina of Time: Pull out the Master Sword.One Hit Wonder: Hit the ball.Clu Clu Land: Avoid enemies and holes.Sifty Character: Sift away the sand to find the prize underneath.Boss Stage: Starwing: Defeat the boss at the end of the stage.Tiny WarioForms:All (excluding The Diner)Sucker Punch: Punch the target.Party Crasher: Pull away the tablecloth without damaging anything.He Who Smelt It...: Get rid of all the gas.Net Profit: Catch all the money.A Tale of One Kitty: Shake the kitty's tail.Wario Hunting: Trap WarioIt'sa Me, Wario!: Knock on the door.Roll Model: Avoid the falling spears.Three's a Crowd: Strike the attacker.Rude Awakening: Wake Wario up.Wario's Gym: Stretch out the apparatus.Bedside Manners: Find out what's wrong using the stethoscope.Paper Wario: Win the paper sumo wrestle.Wario's Pinheads: Knock down the pin.Not the Face!: Deflect the projectiles with the sword.Chop Shop: Throw the broken object into the machine.Dead Ringer: Put the ring on the finger.Climate Control: Sort the ocean and desert objects into the right environment.Safe or Snack: Get the raft to land safely.Closing Night: Take a bow.Boss Stage: Wario Dance Company: Follow along with the other dancers.OrbulonForms:The DinerIt's a Wrap: Unravel all the bandages.Hare Raising: Raise or lower the flags based as instructed.Chunky Salsa: Copy the maraca sequence.Bridge Work: Adjust the bridges to let the characters pass.Safe Cracker: Enter the correct combination/Monkey Dance: Make the monkey dance.Buggin' Out: Grab a bug.Starved for Attention: Get the boat's attention.Clock-Watcher: Get the time to match.Bear-Handed: Juggle the objects.Top Dog: Do the doggy paddleFinishing Move: Copy the motions shown on screen.Look, Ma! No Feet!: Pedal the bike then steer it to the finish line.Stroke of Genius: Row to land.Coming Unhinged: Open and close as necessary.Monkey Crossing: Swing to dry land.Boss Stage: Boom Box: Defeat the opponent.Pose CardsPose Cards are unlocked by beating a Boss in the story mode stages. Beating a level one boss with unlock a 1-star pose, level two gets a 2-star pose, and level three gives a 3-star pose. They appear in the Temple of Form to replay at any time, but no reward is given for collecting them all. There are 70 standard poses plus 12 which use the Nunchuk. There are also several 2-player poses which are shown at the end of Bungie Buddies, but these aren't named or listed in the Temple of Form.0-Star PosePresence of Mind1-Star PosesUmpireRoadblockRoman CandleScout LeaderWordLeaning Tower of PisaKnow-It-AllSluggerArabesqueMobile PhoneShopping CartGigglerYESSSS!RocketCurtainFalsettoTriforceCharlestonLollipop ManBottle OpenerThe LookoutPersonal HygieneGhostJump Rope [Needs Nunchuk]Slingshot [Needs Nunchuk]Hear No Evil [Needs Nunchuk]This Big [Needs Nunchuk]2-Star PosesSumo WrestlerPose DownSupermodelDisco QueenPirouetteBlinded by the LightMagicianCobraTadpoleSpeed SkaterArcherStretchSpySecretBlood DonorCurtsyGymnastVision TestVampire FighterMonkey DanceAir GuitarKitty CatApologyKung-Fu [Needs Nunchuk]Taiko Drum [Needs Nunchuk]The Gamer [Needs Nunchuk]Giddyup! [Needs Nunchuk]3-Star PosesLonerKlutzBroadwayThespianZig ZagTa Da!AtlasLetter YDon't Leave MeSolar EclipseDrama QueenYogaDolphinSetbackIce SkaterMultitaskerSharpshooterBelly FlopLetter MBackup SingerChannel SurferTemper TantrumBack ScratcherDetective [Needs Nunchuk]Dog Walker [Needs Nunchuk]Tail [Needs Nunchuk]Dry Off [Needs Nunchuk]SoundtrackAs with most WarioWare games, a full song including vocals was produced for this game. Two versions of the track Tomorrow Hill were made, and are played during Dribble  Spitz's stage.Tomorrow Hill LyricsSun shining through my windowIt gleams like honey so golden and so sweetYou can almost taste itDrivin' through Diamond CityI wanna escape the crowds and concrete forWhere the hills and skies meetSitting inside my pocketI've packed a cupcake to sweeten up my viewWhen I make it up thereAnd another day fade awayBut it's a magic memoryA magic memoryOne that I'll keep close to my heartFor any gloomy dayWhen the view's not what is sweet as todayYesterday sinks awayDown where the buildingsAnd skiesBut the horizon greets meWith possibility,Just gotta keep on climbing!Concrete, traffic,Street lights,They all fade awayAs I approach the blue skyFeathery clouds in my eyesAlready said my goodbyesI know tomorrow shines bright up at the top of this hill,It always willI know tomorrow shines bright up at the top of this hill,I know that it always willFalling off Tomorrow Hill LyricsSun shining through my windowIt gleams like honey so golden and so sweetYou can almost make senseDrivin' through Diamond CityI wanna escape the crowds and concrete forWhere the hills and skies bleatSitting inside my pocketI've packed a cupcake to sweeten up my viewWhen I make up my hairAnd another day fade awayBut it's a magic memoryA magic jam for meOne that I'll keep close to my heartFor any gloomy dayWhen the view's not what is sweet as toothpasteYesterday sinks awayDown where the buildingsHugs skiesBut the horizon greets meWith possibility,Just gotta keep on rhyming!Concrete, traffic,Street lights,They all fade astrayAs I approach the blue sky,Feathery clouds in my eyesAlready ate my french friesI know tomorrow shines bright up at the top of this hill,It always willI know tomorrow shines bright up at the top of this hill,I know that it always ill</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20568">Rayman Raving Rabbids 2</game><game id="21617">Rayman: Raving Rabbids</game><game id="21824">Cooking Mama: World Kitchen</game><game id="4660">Mario Party 4</game><game id="20963">Wario Land: Shake It!</game><game id="20395">Incredible Crisis</game><game id="3410">Mario Party 5</game><game id="10093">WarioWare: Touched!</game><game id="21312">Rhythm Heaven</game><game id="14091">Addiction Pinball</game><game id="23435">Buzz! Junior: Jungle Party</game><game id="23938">Mainichi Issho</game><game id="32733">101-in-1 Sports Party Megamix</game><game id="35607">Rhythm Heaven Fever</game><game id="38824">McPixel</game><game id="40278">My Little Pony: Friendship is Magic</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1891364-box_wwaresm.png</image></root>