<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13683</id><name>Quake 4</name><description>OverviewQuake 4 is a direct sequel to Quake II, and was one of the first launch games on the Xbox 360 Console. The two game versions were quite different in performance. The Xbox 360 version was criticized for its shaky framerate, muddy textures, and some difficulty running the game's key events, while the PC version on a properly equipped machine did not suffer from these flaws. The game is also known for its long and frequent loading times. The PC version had a DVD Collector's Edition containing a second disc with making of videos and a copy of Quake II and its expansions. The initial release of the Xbox 360 version contained a second disc containing the same videos, as well as an Xbox 360 port of Quake II with several zero-point achievements.StoryMatthew Kane as a HumanThe story of Quake 4 starts off shortly after the ending of Quake II. It starts out with Matthew Kane and his fellow Marines, the Rhino Squad, heading towards Stroggos while in a drop ship. However, partway through the flight, the ship is shot down by an anti-air gun. This shot sends Kane hurtling towards Stroggos, and crashing moments later. Kane awakens to find that he has crashed in the middle of a battle between the Strogg, the alien race that inhabits Stroggos, and separate Marine squads. Kane discovers that his squad is missing, so he ventures off to find help. After finding and helping a smaller squad, Kane reunites with his team and continues his mission, to take advantage of the dead Makron and take the capital of Stroggos. Featuring the trademark corridor-crawling action made famous in previous iterations of the series, Quake 4 boasts a variety of weaponry and set pieces that move the story forward.Transformation into a StroggMatthew Kane as a StroggDuring the beginning of Act 2 Matthew Kane is captured by the Strogg and turned into one. The transformation increases his speed and his max health and armor by 25. In addition, he is also able to read and understand the Strogg's language and use their health stations.His ability to use Strogg technology plays an important rule throughout the remainder of the campaign. For example, towards the end of Act 2 Kane has to pass through Strogg laser defense grids that are lethal to normal humans.WeaponsWeaponDescriptionBlasterThe starting weapon in the game, the Blaster automatically recharges so no reloading is required. Holding down the fire button produces a more powerful charge shot. It also features a mounted flashlight and has unlimited ammo.Machine GunThis assault rifle features fully automatic fire and a mounted flashlight. When using its scope to zoom-in, the weapon switches to semi-automatic fire. This inflicts more damage over a longer range. A magazine extension is unlocked for the machine gun during the game.ShotgunOne of the best weapons in the game for close-quarters combat. During the game, it will upgrade from an 8 shell clip-size, to a magazine loaded 10 clip.Grenade LauncherThe shells the grenade launcher fires will detonate after a few seconds. However, they will also detonate on an enemy on impact.NailgunThis is one of the most devastating rapid-fire weapons in the game. After a few clip extension upgrades, the nailgun is upgraded with a lock-on scope.HyperblasterThe hyperblaster is a rapid-fire weapon. When upgraded, rounds will bounce of walls.Rocket LauncherThe rocket launcher is one of the most powerful weapons in the game. It fires one rocket at a time before automatically reloading. When upgraded, it can fire three rockets in succession without reloading. The upgraded version also allows the player to guide the rockets by moving the targeting reticle.RailgunThe sniper rifle of the game, the Railgun deals high damage at a long range, even though it has a small clip size. Its upgraded version allows the player to pierce through multiple enemies.Lightning GunThe Lighting Gun fires a steady stream of lightning and requires no reloading. The upgraded version damages enemies adjacent to the beam.Dark Matter GunThe dark matter gun is the most powerful weapon in the game. It fires a vortex that inflicts heavy damage on everything it touches. This weapon is very useful when combating large groups of enemies.LevelsAir Defense BunkerAir Defense TrenchesHangar PerimeterInterior HangarMCC Landing SiteOperation: AdvantageCanyonPerimeter Defense StationAqueductsAqueducts AnnexNexus Hub TunnelsNexus HubStrogg Medical FacilitiesConstruction ZoneDispersal FacilitiesRecomposition CenterPutrification CenterWaste Processing FacilityOperation: Last HopeData Storage TerminalData Storage SecurityData Storage Terminal (Revisited)Tram Hub StationTram RailData Processing TerminalData Processing SecurityData Processing Terminal (Revisited)Data Networking TerminalData Networking SecurityNexus CoreThe NexusSystem RequirementsMinimum System RequirementsIntel Pentium 4 2.0Ghz or AMD Athlon XP 2000 processor or higher512MB RAMEnglish version of Microsoft Windows 2000/XP100% DirectX 9.0c compatible 64MB 3D Hardware Accelerator video card required*8X Speed CD-ROM drive and latest drivers2.8GB of uncompressed free hard disk space (plus 400MB for Windows swap file).100% DirectX 9.0c compatible 16-bit sound card and latest drivers100% Windows 2000/XP compatible mouse, keyboard and latest driversDirectX 9.0c (included)Notice: This game contains technology intended to prevent copying that may conflict with some disc and virtual drives.Multiplayer Requirements: Internet (TCP/IP) and LAN (TCP/IP) play supported Internet play requires broadband connection and latest drivers LAN play requires network interface card and latest drivers.Important Note: *Some 3D accelerator cards with the chipsets listed here may not be compatible with the 3D accelerator features utilized by QUAKE 4. Please refer to your hardware manufacturer for 100% DirectX 9.0c compatibility. This product does not support Microsoft Windows 95/98/ME or NT.Supported Chipsets:ATI Radeon 9700ATI Radeon 9800ATI Radeon X300 seriesATI Radeon X550 seriesATI Radeon X600 seriesATI Radeon X700 seriesATI Radeon X800 seriesATI Radeon X850 seriesNvidia GeForce 3/Ti seriesNvidia GeForce 4/Ti seriesNvidia GeForce FX seriesNvidia GeForce 6 SeriesNvidia GeForce 7 seriesXbox 360 Game InstallationQuake 4 requires 5.9GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD.</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10955">Unreal Tournament 3</game><game id="11187">Star Trek: Voyager - Elite Force</game><game id="7754">Doom 3: Resurrection of Evil</game><game id="21471">Warsow</game><game id="7814">Half-Life: Blue Shift</game><game id="16508">Half-Life: Opposing Force</game><game id="65">Serious Sam</game><game id="21256">Perfect Dark</game><game id="22129">Legions: Overdrive</game><game id="2714">C-12: Final Resistance</game><game id="16372">Prey</game><game id="2600">Halo: Combat Evolved</game><game id="17828">Battlefield 2142</game><game id="16922">Star Wars: Jedi Knight - Jedi Academy</game><game id="13286">Unreal Tournament 2004</game><game id="14523">Star Wars: Jedi Knight II - Jedi Outcast</game><game id="7094">Star Wars: Battlefront II</game><game id="10461">Clive Barker's Jericho</game><game id="20576">Section 8</game><game id="7407">Alpha Prime</game><game id="25740">Eliminate</game><game id="20672">Rage</game><game id="35888">Hard Reset</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14912/854052-quake4box.jpg</image></root>