<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13692</id><name>Space Station Silicon Valley</name><description>OverviewSpace Station Silicon Valley is a platformer for the Nintendo 64 released October 1, 1998 in the US. The game was developed by a Scottish studio once known as DMA Design, which was then acquired by Rockstar, and is now known as Rockstar North. The game was critically acclaimed, acheiving praise from many. The game is also well known for negative reasons, as the game had a number of game breaking glitches in it. The game later made a trip to the Game Boy Color, and was ported to the PlayStation under the name Evo's Space Adventures.StoryIn the year 3000 the Space Station Silicon Valley has returned, thought to be lost forever. The station was designed to be a technologically advanced theme park. Upon its arrival, Professor Cheese, designer of the station, has gone missing. Danger Dan and his partner Evo, two heroes for hire, are sent off to investigate this catastrophe. They discover that animals have merged with technology, and that the station is on a collision course with Earth.GameplayThe player controls Evo, a robot who is nothing more than a microchip after an accident in the beginning of the game. Evo can enter the bodies of many animals on the space station, and utilize their abilities to complete his objectives and solve puzzles in order to progress. Each animal has it's own unique ability, which allows the gameplay to change from animal to animal. Missions are assigned by Dan, who is trapped in the ship. As the player goes through the game's many levels, they will reassemble Evo by collecting pieces of his body.Zones and LevelsThe Ice ZoneThere are four different zones contained within the space station each with a varying amount of levels. Each zone also has a specific theme of animals that as EVO you can inhabit. The first zone is the European Zone, and it contains animals that may be found on a farm or countryside. The second is the Ice Zone, which has animals that you would find in arctic regions of the world. The third is the Jungle Zone, which again contains animals indigineous to a jungle type environment. The fourth is the Desert Zone, and this also contains animals found in a desert envrionment. There are other secret types of levels in the game that can be unlocked upon completing the other zones.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15207">Yoshi's Story</game><game id="609">Rayman 2: The Great Escape</game><game id="15000">Donkey Kong 64</game><game id="2871">Banjo-Tooie</game><game id="10920">Banjo-Kazooie</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/82063/2313445-siliconbox.jpg</image></root>