<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1370</id><name>Age of Mythology: The Titans</name><description>AtlanteansAtlanteans!As with the original civilizations in Age of mythology, the Atlanteans have their own strengths and attributes along with the choice of three new Major gods. Kronos, Gaia and Oranos. The atlanteans have many new mythical creatures, god powers and units. Such as the humble villager where for the Atlanteans these are very expensive and do not to take resources to a resource drop point but rather have accompanying donkey which collect the resources automatically. The Atlanteans also have the ability to use god powers more than once and have large houses which can accommodate a large population capHeroesUnlike the other civilizations of Age of Mythology, the Atlanteans create heroes from regular units. The change is instant, and these new hero units have all of the attributes of heroes from other cultures. However the change to a hero costs a significant amount of resources for each unit. Since the heroes are simply created from regular units, it is far easier to mass Atlantean heroes but they have a high cost.FavourThe Atlanteans gather favour through the construction of town centers. Each town center controlled gives a steady stream of favour and the larger of town centres controlled the more favour gathered from each. To accommodate this Atlanteans can build new town centers at an earlier age than the other civilizations.TitanThe Atlanteans can summon a Titan called Chthonian. This is a lava-like creature with large crystals growing out of its back.Major GodsKronosSpecial Bonus:Can Timeshift buildings within own Line of sightMe Crush now!Bonuses:Siege Weapons CheaperMyth Units Cheaper God Power:Deconstruction - The ability to deconstruct an enemy building, but the resources for that building will go back to your enemy.Technology:Focus - Oracle has 10% Speed, -1.0 Seconds LOS Speed.Minor GodsClassical Age - Leto or PrometheusHeroic Age - Hyperion or RheiaMythic Age - Helios or AtlasGaiaSpecial Bonus:All buildings are surrounded by Lush Terrain.Lush terrain can not be built on by enemies.Bonuses:Buildings regenerate HPFishing ships, Caravans more HP  cheaperEconomic bonuses cheaper God Power:Gaia's Forest - Generates a forest, of which you can harvest from or use as a wall.Technology:Channels Ability - 20% Villager Speed.Minor GodsClassical Age - Leto or oceanusHeroic Age - Rheia or theiaMythic Age - Atlas or HecateOranosSpecial Bonus:Ability to build numerous Sky Passages.Bonuses:Shares visibility to all settlements with alliesHuman Military Units move faster God Power:Shock wave - Generates a shock wave which stuns enemy unitsTechnology:Safe Passage - Sky Passages have -25% wood cost, -20% gold cost, 1 ranged attack and 6 Line of Sight.Minor GodsClassical Age - Oceanus or PrometheusHeroic Age - Hyperion or TheiaMythic Age - Hecate or HeliosMinor GodsOceanusGod Power:Carnivora - Generates plants which eat enemy units.Myth Unit:Caladria and servantsPrometheusGod Power:EgyptiansValor - Transforms a group of general units into heroes, instantly.Myth Unit:PrometheanTheiaGod Power:Hesperides - Generates a tree where you can create dryads. You may use this God Power twice, yet you can only have a maximum of five dryads in total.Myth Unit:Stymphalian BirdHyperionGod Power:Chaos - Changes the sentiment of a group of enemy units, causing them to attack any units nearby.Myth Unit:Satyr and NereidHeceteGod Power:Tartarian - Generates a gate to the underworld releasing creatures which attack everybody.Myth Unit:LampadesHeliosGod Power:Vortex - Teleport all military units of a player to another point on the map.Myth Unit:Man O'War and HekagigantesSpecial Myth Building:Mirror Tower - A tower which harnesses sunshine into laser-like rays.RheiaGod Power:Traitor - Converts an enemy unit into a traitorMyth Unit:BehemothLetoGod Power:Spider Lair - Spider burrows which attack enemy unitsMyth Unit:AutomatonAs well as the introduction of the new civilization changed were also made to the existing three. Through the addition of new units and technologies. The ability to build titans was also added to each Civilizations. These are massive mythical creatures with Huge amounts of HP which can level entire towns and large armies of units.New technologiesGreeksThats one big dude!Beast slayer - Unique units (heroes) have 50% attack against myth units.Titan - The Greek Titan is a huge three headed dog named Cerberus.NorseAxe of muspell - Throwing axeman have 200% attack against flying unitsTitan - The Titan for the Norse is a large Frost giant named Ymir.EgyptiansHand of the Pharaoh - Priests can pick up relics, 2 priest rangeTitan - The Egyptian titan is a Part man part bird creature called HorisAll CivilizationsHeroic Fleet - ships have 50% attack against myth unitsSystem RequirementsRequires Age of Mythology to PlayOperating System: Windows 98/2000/XPProcessor: 450 MHzMemory: 128 MB RAMHard Drive: 450 MBVideo Card: 16MB/3DOther: 32x CD Drive, audio board with speakers/headphonesOnline/Multiplayer Requirements56.6 Kbps or better for internet play</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19857">Empire Earth</game><game id="1565">Empire Earth II</game><game id="3693">Empire Earth: The Art of Conquest</game><game id="2846">Age of Empires II: The Age of Kings</game><game id="8546">Age of Empires III</game><game id="10485">Age of Empires</game><game id="14590">Age of Empires II: The Conquerors</game><game id="12483">Age of Empires III: The WarChiefs</game><game id="7701">The Lord of the Rings: The Battle for Middle-earth</game><game id="4867">The Lord of the Rings: The Battle for Middle-earth II</game><game id="3769">Zeus: Master of Olympus</game><game id="12474">Black &amp; White 2</game><game id="738">Black &amp; White 2: Battle of the Gods</game><game id="14073">Warcraft III: The Frozen Throne</game><game id="10244">Rise of Nations: Rise of Legends</game><game id="9719">Warcraft: Orcs &amp; Humans</game><game id="20103">Warcraft II: Tides of Darkness</game><game id="11816">Warcraft II: Beyond the Dark Portal</game><game id="9446">Dominions 3: The Awakening</game><game id="3009">Immortal Cities: Children of the Nile</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14036/654355-aomtteboxart.jpg</image></root>