<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13730</id><name>Austin Powers: Oh Behave!</name><description>OverviewAustin Powers: Oh Behave! appeals to hardcore Austin Powers fans who are rather unorganized. The game comes complete with a mini word processor (shown as Austin's Pad), a calculator (known as the Shagulator), and an imitation web browser that lets you browse facts about the Austin Powers movies. With these things, the game also lets you customize the background, screen saver, sound effects and wallpaper among other things. Not only does the game help fans organize, but it also includes various games inspired by the movie.International Man in a Platform GameThis is the largest of the games where you play as Austin in a side-scrolling adventure inspired by the movie. It involves you climbing obstacles and dispatching foes as you try to find your way to the end of each level.Mojo MazeMojo Maze is a spin-off of Pac-Man.DominationDomination is a board game that is similar to Othello (aka Reversi) in which the player flips chips over their opponent's to change color. Whoever has the most chips of their color on the board by the end of the game wins.Rock, Paper, ScissorsOh Behave! puts a new twist on this classic game as it puts you up against an Austin Powers villain from the movies. You are able to select which villain to face along with the difficulty setting. A stoplight appears and you must cycle between rock, paper, or scissors and "throw" your choice when the light turns green. If you enter your choice too soon or too late you automatically lose, the window of time depends on the difficulty you have selected. The game keeps track of your wins and losses over time.MultiplayerAustin Powers: Oh Behave! supports system link to play a few of the games with friends. Turning off the GameThe game requires you go to the ROM menu and select the power down option. A message appears informing you when it is safe to turn off your system. Failure to do so means the next time the game is started errors will be found, luckily the game will automatically repair any errors found on startup. </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2084">Austin Powers: Welcome to My Underground Lair</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2285622-box_apob.png</image></root>