<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13828</id><name>Terranigma</name><description>OverviewTerranigma is a 1996 Action-RPG developed by Quintet Games and published by Enix Corporation in Japan and Nintendo in PAL territories for the Super Nintendo. Terranigma was only localized for European and Australian territories and never made it's way to the North American shores. Like most of the big RPGs on the SNES, the German and French versions of the game came with an extensive guide book in a big box created by Nintendo of Europe's Club Nintendo editorial staff.Like previous games in the unofficial Soul Blazer saga, the gameplay adapts the top-down perspective as well as the control scheme of The Legend of Zelda: A Link to the Past while incorporating minor role-playing elements inspired by SquareSoft's Secret of Mana. Terranigma is about the resurrection of the world and its progression from pre-historic times to the near future.The game was scored by Miyoko Kobayashi and Masanori Hikichi and the characters were designed by Kamui Fujiwara who now works with Square Enix.PlotIn the distant past the battle between the two sides of light and dark left Earth in a state where no life could grow and the entire surface was scorched completely.Below the Earth's surface--and, it seems, on the underside of the crust--remains the last village of Crysta. Terranigma follows the journey of Ark, a troublesome teenager who due to curiosity, opens a mysterious box behind a door that was forbidden to enter. Little did Ark know that opening this box would lead him on a journey to resurrect the lifeless world above him. By opening the box all residents of Crysta were frozen and Ark is told that the only way to release them is to restore the worlds continents by completing five towers which represent each continent.After Ark does what is required of him, he is then told he must venture to the surface to restore the Earth to its prior state, where life flourishes and people grow. Through his journey Ark discovers more than he expected, and that the reason for his journey wasn't exactly for the reason he was told.GameplayThe game is played from a top-down perspective. Different attacks can be performed based on whether Ark is jumping, running, walking, or standing still. The player can also block projectile attacks. Arks weapon inventory consists of only spears, rods, and pikes. Different weapons can be obtained as the player progresses through the game. Experience points are earned for each enemy that is defeated, and upon leveling up Arks hit points, defense, strength, and luck are increased.The Inventory ScreenArmor can be obtained throughout the game which increases strength, but the physical appearance of Ark's character does not change.Spells can be used in the form of pins or rings. Rings have a one time use only, and also require magic rocks.Along with Magic rings, items can be purchased at stores throughout the game.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15900">Legend of Mana</game><game id="22635">The Legend of Oasis</game><game id="9032">Star Ocean</game><game id="1296">Seiken Densetsu 3</game><game id="16959">Alcahest</game><game id="394">Robotrek</game><game id="12945">Lagoon</game><game id="32942">Brave Prove</game><game id="10276">The Legend of Zelda: A Link to the Past</game><game id="2856">Contact</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/82063/2190016-terranigma_wlp1_1920x1200.jpg</image></root>