<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1393</id><name>Toontown Online</name><description> OverviewDisney's Toontown Online is a kid-friendly take on the  popular Massively Multiplayer genre.  Traditional MMO elements such as  combat, character progression, experience points, and player versus  player competition all make an appearance in varying degrees while under  the safety of a determined chat filter and other grief-eliminating  features.  Players work together to take down the evil Cogs (a band of  robots who seek to make life boring for the residents of Toontown) while  familiar Disney characters, such as Goofy and Mickey Mouse, appear to  help players along the way.  When not saving the city, players can ride  the trolley to player competitive and cooperative mini-games with each  other to earn Jelly Beans, Toontown's official currency.   Character CreationThere are  nine different types of toons to create in Toontown and many different  combinations of species, colors and clothing.  The nine different species of toon the player can choose are:    Rabbit   Pig   Mouse Monkey (Subscriber Only)   Horse (Subscriber Only)   Duck   Dog   Cat   Bear (Subscriber Only)Locations      Toontown Central         Silly Street     Loopy Lane   Punchline Place  Donald's Dock Lighthouse LaneSeaweed StreetBarnacle Boulevard Daisy's Garden  Oak StreetMaple StreetElm StreetMinnie's Melodyland Tenor TerraceBaritone BoulevardAlto AvenueThe Brrrgh Sleet StreetWalrus WayPolar PlaceDonald's DreamlandLullaby LanePajama PlaceChip and  Dale's Acorn Acres  The player can also go into the different Cogs headquarters like Cashbot HQ Sellbot HQ Lawbot HQ Bossbot HQ While  in these HQs the player goes in to face the boss of that Cogs HQ, after  a successful venture into the HQ the player receives the next part of  the next highest level cog to level their cog characters eventually  getting to the top level cog.  Cog TypesEach category of Cogs have eight individual Cogs.  Bossbots                                              Flunky                                             Pencil Pusher              Yesman               Micromanager                Downsizer                  Head hunter                   Corporate Raider            The Big CheeseLawbots                     Bottom Feeder                      Bloodsucker                       Double Talker                        Ambulance Chaser                         Backstabber                          Spin Doctor                           Legal Eagle                            Big WigCashbots                             Short Change                              Penny Pincher                               Tightwad                                Bean Counter                                 Number Cruncher                                  Moneybags                                   Loan Shark                                    Robber BaronSellbots                                     Cold Caller                                      Telemarketer                                       Name Dropper                                        Glad Hander                                         Mover  Shaker                                          Two-Face                                           The Mingler                                            Mr. Hollywood</description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="34491">Monkey Quest</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/7/72665/1338188-toontownawesomepicture.jpg</image></root>