<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13943</id><name>Pac-Attack</name><description>Overview  Pac-Attack Screen  Pac-Attack was a       Pac-Man spin off, in the same vein as      Tetris and/or     Dr Mario. The object of the game is to clear rows of blocks by getting them into straight lines; however, most of the falling puzzle peaces also have ghosts attached which take up valuable space where blocks could be stored. The solution to this problem is, you guessed it, Pac-Man himself! Every once in a while a Pac-Man piece will fall, and all the ghosts on the board will turn blue. If the Pac Man piece is situated in an area where he can easily catch the ghost he will catch it, and the ghost will disappear. The game offers a standard "Normal Mode" in which the game plays out as described above, as well as a "Puzzle" mode in which you're given only a limited number of Pac-Man to eat the various ghost. Critical ReceptionWhen the SNES version was released Electronic Gaming Monthly gave the review scores of 8,7,7,8 and 8 out of ten.  Mike Weigand wrote, "No, don't laugh, just try it! This game looks like nothing but once you start playing you will not be able to stop!  The three games are addictive, and the two-player competition will have you and a friend playing until you drop!".</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1896">Tetris</game><game id="13130">Tetris Attack</game><game id="10234">Tetris DS</game><game id="3049">Tetrisphere</game><game id="10515">Magical Tetris Challenge</game><game id="1737">The New Tetris</game><game id="21539">Tetris Splash</game><game id="796">Tetris DX</game><game id="13982">Tetris Blast</game><game id="9629">Novalight Tetris</game><game id="17641">Dr. Mario</game><game id="20691">Dr. Mario Online RX</game><game id="1072">Dr. Mario 64</game><game id="14788">Dr. Mario &amp; Puzzle League</game><game id="14873">Kirby's Avalanche</game><game id="25427">Korogashi Puzzle Katamari Damacy</game><game id="3117">Panic Bomber</game><game id="33860">Cosmo Gang: The Puzzle</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8412/281336-pacattackboxart.jpg</image></root>