<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13947</id><name>SNK Gals Fighters</name><description>OverviewSNK Gals Fighters was released on February 19, 2000 making it one of the last titles ever released on the Neo Geo Pocket Color. It features ten of SNK's most popular heroines battling it out to become the first ever Queen of Fighters and win the K Talisman that can make any dream come true. This game is based on the same engine that powered other Neo Geo Pocket color fighters such as King of Fighters R-2 and SNK vs. Capcom: Match of the Millennium and as such bears a striking resemblence to them in terms of presentation and basic mechanics. The overall tone of the game is very light hearted and many aspects seem to have been specifically designed to appeal to females in an attempt to broaden the market of the struggling Neo Geo Pocket Color.PlotIt's the year 2000 A.D., the last year of the millenium, and female fighters the world over begin receiving invitations to the first ever Queen of Fighters (Q.O.F.) Tournament. The invitations are signed by a mysterious "Miss X" who promises the K Talisman, a priceless treasure with the ability to grant any single wish, as the grand prize for the competition's victor. And so, the world's greatest heroines come together to do battle in the hopes of making their dreams come true.Character RosterStarting FightersMai Shiranui - Fatal Fury 2Wish: "You know! I want to tie the knot with Andy!"Quote: "I am SNK's mightiest heroine!"Yuri Sakazaki - Art of FightingWish: "Carrying on the Kyokugen tradition. And getting evenskys with Ryo!"Quote: "Lighten up! I'm a pro. You had to lose!"Athena Asamiya - Psycho SoldierWish: "I want my long hair back!"Quote: "My horoscope said I'd win big-time today!"Leona Heidern - King of Fighters '96Wish: "I want this cavity fixed now!"Quote: "Resistance...is just dumb!"Nakoruru - Samurai ShodownWish: "I just wish to go home."Quote: "I am the law of Nature!"Shermie - King of Fighters '97Wish: "I want a luxurious new home for my hamster!"Quote: "I didn't even get started!"Shiki - Samurai Shodown 64Wish: "I want to see my child."Quote: "Over so soon?"Akari Ichijyou - Last BladeWish: "I wish to get more than one wish!"Quote: "Damn, I'm good! No, I am hot!"Hidden FightersYuki Kushinada - King of Fighters '97 (Gals Fighters is her first playable appearance)Wish: "Huh...I...I!!"Quote: "What a wimp! Just joking."Whip - King of Fighters '99Wish: "I want to remove the curse on me."Quote: "Maybe it's time to hang it up?!"Boss FightersMiss X (Iori Yagami) - The King of Fighters '95Wish: N/AQuote: "Remember me next time you see the moon."</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="12312">SNK vs. Capcom: Match of the Millennium</game><game id="6872">King of Fighters R-2</game><game id="6708">Fatal Fury: First Contact</game><game id="21763">Asuka 120% Limited Burning Fest.</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9261/295671-61fsr9hhggl._sl500_aa280_.jpg</image></root>