<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>13998</id><name>Star Wars: Starfighter</name><description>StorySplash Screen.The plot runs parallel to the main events of the film: Star Wars Episode 1 The Phantom Menace. Throughout the game, players take part in set pieces that featured prominently in the film; such as the battle for Naboo. The story is told from the perspective of three characters: Rhys Dallows a Naboo Starfighter pilot, mercenary Vana Sage and space pirate Nym. After banding together, the three are set upon the destruction of the Trade Federation.GameplayEach main character had their own ship that maneuvered and attacked differently. Rhy's Naboo Starfighter was the fastest craft which fired standard lasers and proton torpedos. Vana's ship was the most maneuverable, firing guided missiles and dispensing mines. Nym, being the pirate that he is, had the most powerful ship. What his craft lacked in speed was made up in firepower. Additional craft were unlocked upon the completion of the single player campaign.The game has been noted for including a zoom mechanic, which allowed for easier combat.MultiplayerThe PS2 version contains 2 player competitive missions like races, dogfights, capture the flag missions.The Xbox version included 5 modes total:CTF - standard capture the flag mode.Dogfight - one on one deathmatchTag - one person is "it", and the other need to evade the player.Hunter/Hunted - a 2 player version of Tag.Steal the Beacon - a 1 flag CTF variant.Xbox Special EditionTen months after the Playstation 2 release, a special edition was produced for the Xbox. This included updated graphics and enhanced multiplayer.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="24">Flight Simulator</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4017">Star Wars: Jedi Starfighter</game><game id="1715">Star Trek: Invasion</game><game id="4231">Star Wars: Rogue Squadron II: Rogue Leader</game><game id="19273">Ace Combat 6: Fires of Liberation</game><game id="4544">Colony Wars: Vengeance</game><game id="2943">Wing Commander: Prophecy</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/118/607709-starfighter.jpg</image></root>