<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14081</id><name>Fragile Allegiance</name><description>OverviewIn a future where the Earth can no longer support its ever-increasing population, pioneers have established colonies on countless new worlds. The fortunate ones have prospered and thrived, mining the precious ores and minerals that they found there, and the unfortunate have succumbed to the ravages of deep space.In the year 2496, you are appointed Colony Director for Tetracorp and it is your job to build a thriving colony while defending it from 6 alien species. Fragile Allegiance offers a fast-paced RTS where you can buy blueprints, hunt for asteroids to mine, or even build an Asteroid Engine and use it against an opponent who’s been a thorn in your side! If you favor a more underhanded approach to furthering your goals, you can deploy Spy Satellites and Sabotage Agents to thoroughly undermine your enemies. Once you expand beyond the scope of one colony, you can appoint Colony Managers to take care of the more minor details of running and maintaining your colony.Fragile Allegiance Cheat CodesGo to the DOS prompt and start the game by typing:FRAGILE /cKim.Jon.fmsti for the European version or FRAGILE /c.Osiris.fmsti for the American version.Here's what the arguments mean:f= build everything in one daym= extra moneys= see all asteroidst= change game speed. alt f7 slows time and alt f8 speeds up timei= have all information about aliens and trading items.Minimum System RequirementsProcessor:486 DX2 or fasterRAM:8 MBHard Drive Space:32 MBOperating System:Windows 95, MS-DOS</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11342">Master of Orion</game><game id="14956">Master of Orion II: Battle at Antares</game><game id="7419">Master of Orion 3</game><game id="9115">Sins of a Solar Empire</game><game id="9398">Galactic Civilizations</game><game id="21592">Galactic Civilizations II: Twilight of the Arnor</game><game id="22216">Galactic Civilizations II: Endless Universe</game><game id="20660">Command &amp; Conquer: Red Alert 3</game><game id="20494">Command &amp; Conquer 3: Kane's Wrath</game><game id="17551">Command &amp; Conquer 3: Tiberium Wars</game><game id="20674">StarCraft II: Wings of Liberty</game><game id="13062">StarCraft</game><game id="24092">Sins of a Solar Empire: Entrenchment</game><game id="26939">Light of Altair</game><game id="24079">StarCraft II: Legacy of the Void</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/864/624123-fragile_allegiance.jpg</image></root>