<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14139</id><name>Spore</name><description>OverviewSpore is the latest game from the prodigious brain of Will Wright and aims to simulate the development of an entire species. The player begins the game in the form of a microscopic organism that arrives on a planet via exogenesis or panspermia, deposited in the primordial oceans by a meteorite impact. From this point on, the player has the ability to change the physical shape of the creature, giving it different evolutionary traits depending on what path the player wants his life form to take. Eventually, the creature evolves to the point of sentience, and a new gameplay mode begins in which the species establishes its own civilization. Cities are built, technology is researched, and eventually the player's species becomes capable of space flight; the player is able to first explore and colonize their home solar system and later, the entire galaxy. Will Wright has stated that the game's overall goal is to get to the center of the galaxy, and that the game does, in fact, have an ending. While there is no hard ending that acts as an end to gameplay, the final space section cumulates in a one-off meeting at the galactic core where you are rewarded with the terraforming staff of life item.EA is already planning Spore not just as a game but an entire franchise. The property has already been targeted for post-release expansion packs, Wii, and iPhone adaptations are already underway. Additionally, EA has announced an iTunes-style "Spore Store" which will be built into the game itself, allowing for the digital distribution of future Spore expansion packs as well as Internet sales of Spore merchandise including t-shirts, posters, a collectible card game, and possibly custom figures created from 3D prints of submitted creature designs.Spore Creature is the Nintendo DS version of spore, featuring different gameplay and overall design based more on story and adventure gameplay, the Nintendo DS version of Spore also featured a unique cartoony style.GameplayThe gameplay of Spore takes place on a massive scale, and as such, the game generates many of its assets through procedural programming and system inter-connectivity. The majority of Spore's content is generated both by the game itself, by the player in his own game, and by other players. Spore is being referred to as a "massively single-player" game, in which the procedurally generated content (animals, sentient species, planets, vehicles, civilizations, and so on) of each copy of the game are spread to every other copy of the game on the planet, as long as that person's computer is connected to the Internet. Spore's gameplay is comprised of five individual phases, each based on a previously released franchise and genre. The initial cell or "tide pool" phase is based on a blend of Pac-Man and Flow, the creature phase is based on World of Warcraft, the tribal phase is based on Populous, the civilization phase is based on SimCity or Civilization, and the Space phase is based on Master of Orion.EditorsThere are a total of eight editors in the game, governing the creation of vehicles, buildings, creatures, and more. Each editor has a built in complexity limit to prevent the overpowering of vehicles or creatures. However, this may be easily overridden by a console command.Game StagesThe game consists of five stages in which you will play through using various play styles while following the life cycle of your creature and the galaxy that they are in.CellularCell PhaseAfter a cinematic opening of a meteorite crashing into a planet, the player begins his creature's journey as a microscopic cell, or microbe. During this stage, using the control of the mouse, you must survive by eating smaller microbes and avoiding larger ones, similar to gameplay in Pac-Man or flOw. After you have eaten enough, the microbe will lay an egg, allowing you to enter the first editor. In the Microbe Editor, you edit your cell with various parts including weapons, eyes, appendages, etc. These will aid you in survival and also grow your creature. After you leave the editor, your cell enlarges and the camera zooms out, allowing you to see even larger and more versatile microbes. After eating enough food, you progress into the Creature Stage.CreatureCreature PhaseUpon finishing the Cellular Stage, you will begin constructing your creature that will become your official species throughout the rest of the game. The Creature Editor (along with the other editors) will function the same way as the Microbe Editor, however will allow you to create a sentient, land fairing creature using arms, legs, eyes, mouths, etc. You will then need to carry out tasks such as eating, communicating, and eventually mating. You will encounter many other forms of creatures, both predator, prey, and your own species, and you basically play in a third person free roam. By doing so you will earn DNA points for the editor and evolve your brain, which is required to move onto further stages. After visiting the editor multiple times and meeting the requirements for brain level, mating with another creature of your species will allow you to advance to the Tribal Stage.TribalA village during Tribal PhaseAfter mating, your creature becomes sentient, which means it is intelligent enough to communicate and hold relations with other creatures. The gameplay style now switches to somewhat of an RTS; you can now control multiple creatures of the same species. The goal of this stage is to grow your tribe to fifteen members or conquer/ally with five other tribes on the planet (no matter what the species) by way of violence, diplomacy, or religion. Each tribe has a hut, which acts as a base of operations and can have many things added for the tribe members, such as for entertainment and weaponry, however at the cost of food. Your tribe also has 2 special abilities based on how you played creature, for example a omnivore type creature in tribal will be able to summon all creatures around it at the moment to help in combat and will be able to cause a giant sea monster to knock fish out of the water for free food.CivilizationA city under attack in the Civilization PhaseWhen the Tribal Stage is complete your creatures move on to build a city. Gameplay still acts as a RTS, however also adds in the need to maintain your own city, such as Sim City. Once again the goal is dominate the other cities around the planet, however with the addition of having to collect gas from geysers spread across the planet and keeping your enemies away. Cities are obtained in one of three ways. The first two involve building military or Religious units and sending them at a city. If victorious it will be conquered or converted respectively. Both of these methods likely will start a war. The third way is a peaceful method is building Economic units and sending them to open a trade route, leading to you eventually making an offer to buy the city.SpaceExploration of the Final Frontier dominates the Space PhaseThe final stage of the game allows you to construct a spacecraft, which grants you many abilities to help you explore and possibly conquer the galaxy. Hundreds and hundreds of solar systems are available to be explored, and with the use of the many tools that your spacecraft will gain you will be able to manipulate planets, scan for intelligent life, interbreed creatures, and even obliterate a planet entirely, which in turn may cause a new asteroid belt to form. During your encounters with other intelligent species, you may choose to once again settle things peacefully or start an intergalactic war.SporepediaSpore has a feature called the Sporepedia, the Sporepedia allows you to browse and download any other player in the worlds creatures,vehicles and buildings.Players can also create Sporecasts, which are constantly updating packages of creatures by a user.Players also have a friends system in the Sporepedia and can have their creations featured on the main page.ControversySecuRom DRMEA has limited each copy of Spore to five individual installs by the user at any given time; Also the game will re-authenticate any time you add new downloaded content from the Sporepedia. If the user surpasses the five install limit they will receive an error message that will ask the user to verify the registration code and to reinstall the game. Any further issues may be forwarded to EA's support service.PiracyIronically despite the heavy restrictions put on Spore to prevent piracy it Spore turned out to be the most pirated game of 2008 with over 1,700,000 downloads between its release in September and the lists creation in early December by TorrentFreak. Spore also earned the title of being one of the fastest pirated games of 2008 with over half a million people downloading the game within 10 days of its general release. This is no doubt aided by the fact that Spore was available on torrent websites almost a week before it's official release date.Religion in SporeIn an interview with Eurogamer posted August 11, 2008, Will Wright claimed that most of the "religiously" oriented criticism of the game has come from what Wright called "Militant Atheists", instead of the expected religious audience.AntiSpore.comA newly launched website called AntiSpore.com which claims Spore is teaching kids evolution. Also the website claims to want the E rating pulled and made into a M Rated game. The website was later revealed to be a hoax following references to the often implausible nature of content posted on the internet and Poe's Law.PC System RequirementsMinimum:Windows XP:Processor: Pentium 4 @ 2 GHz or Athlon EquivalentMemory: 512 MBHard Drive: 6 GB FreeVideo Memory: 128 MB with Pixel Shader 2.0 SupportSound Card: DirectX CompatibleDirectX: 9.0cKeyboard  MouseDVD Rom DriveWindows Vista:Processor: Pentium 4 @ 2 GHz or EquivalentMemory: 768 MBHard Drive: 6 GB FreeVideo Memory: 128 MB with Pixel Shader 2.0 SupportSound Card: DirectX CompatibleDirectX: 9.0cKeyboard  MouseDVD Rom DriveFor Computers with Built-In Graphic ChipsetsProcessor: Intel Pentium D @ 2.6 GHz or Intel Core 2 DUO @ 1.8 GHz or EquivalentMemory: 768 MBHard Drive: 6 GB FreeVideo Memory: Intel Integrated Chipset, 945GM or aboveSound Card: DirectX CompatibleDirectX: 9.0cKeyboard  MouseDVD Rom DriveSupported Video CardsATI Radeon series: 9500, 9600, 9800 X300, X600, X700, X800, X850 X1300, X1600, X1800, X1900, X1950 2400, 2600, 2900, 3650, 3850, 3870, 4850NVIDIA GeForce series: FX 5900, FX 5950 6200, 6500, 6600, 6800, 7200, 7300, 7600, 7800, 7900, 7950 8400, 8500, 8600, 8800, 9600, 9800, GTX 260, GTX 280Intel Extreme Graphics: GMA 950, GMA X3000, GMA X3100Mac System RequirementsMinimum:Mac OS X 10.5.3 Leopard or higherIntel Core Duo Processor1024 MB RAMATI X1600 or NVidia 7300 GT with 128 MB of Video RAM, or Intel Integrated GMA X3100At least 4.7GB of hard drive space for installation, plus additional space for creations.The game will not run on PowerPC (G3/G4/G5) based Mac systems (PowerMac).For (Mac) computers using built-in graphics chipsetsIntel Integrated Chipset GMA X3100Dual 2.0GHz CPUs, or 1.7GHz Core 2 Duo, or equivalentSupported Video CardsATI Radeon(TM) series: X1600, X1900, HD 2400, HD 2600NVIDIA GeForce series : 7300, 7600, 8600, 8800Intel(R) Extreme Graphics: GMA X3100Spore will not run on the GMA 950 class of integrated video cards.Graphics ProblemsSpore does not support anti-aliasing and is limited to 30 frames per second at all times. Also, by not being displayed at the standard LCD monitor refresh rates of 60 fps, you will notice screen tearing, which can be very distracting during the later parts of the game. Unfortunately, there is currently no patch to fix these issues. Graphics driver software, however, such as nvidia forceware, can be used to enable anti-aliasing, texture filtering, and vertical sync.Limited EditionGalactic EditionSpore's limited edition is called "Galactic Edition" and will include the following bonus content:The Making of Spore DVDHow To Make a Better Being DVD (a 50 minutes documentary by National Geographic Channel)The Art of Spore (a 128-page hardback book with Spore artwork)100-page Galactic HandbookSpore posterExclusive packagingExpansions and PatchesCreepy and CuteThe Creepy and Cute expansion pack adds 60 new creature parts to the editor, 24 new preview animations, 2 new test drive backgrounds and 48 new paint scripts (split evenly into base, coat and detail layers and 12 complete styles).Spore Galactic AdventuresSpore Galactic Adventures was released in June 2009, It included a mission creator and allowed players to beam their creations down to planets and complete missions with them.Using the Mission creator players can effectively create their own games filled with any creations from the Sporepedia.AchievementsSpore Also features almost 100 unlockable achievementsGalactic God - In one continuous game, evolve a creature from cell to space travelPhotographer - Send a video or photo to a friend while in Test Drive modeArchitect - Create 50 buildings and share themAutomotive Engineer - Create and upload 50 vehiclesBiologist - Creature and upload 100 creaturesSpore Fan - Play 50 hours in your Spore galaxySpore Addict - Play 100 hours in your Spore galaxyCreator - Play 50 hours in the creator toolsUniverse in a Box - Play through each stage, and use each creatorDeja Vu - While exploring the universe, come across something you have createdSocial Engineer - Make 5 Sporecastes of 50 assetsRising Star - 5 Sporecasts must be subscribed to be 10 peopleFront Page News - One of your creatures or Sporecasts must be featured on Spore.comCreature Stage Unlocked - Unlock creature stageTribe Stage Unlocked - Unlock Tribe stageCivilization Stage Unlocked - Unlock Civilization stageSpace Stage Unlocked - Unlock Space stageAluminum Cell - Beat Cell stage on hardLandfall - Beat Cell stage, enter Creature stagePacifist - Beat Cell stage with zero killsCompletist - Unlock every Cell partSpeed Freak - Beat Cell stage in less than 8 minutesCell Addict - Beat Cell stage 25 timesIron Creature - Beat Creature stage on hardEvolver - Beat Creature stageEveryone's BFF - Beat Creature stage by making friends with 20 speciesFoe - Wipe out 20 speciesMax Power - Creature must have maximum stats in 4 abilitiesSurvivor - Beat Creature stage without dyingSocialite - Meet 200 creatures created by othersFlight of the Bumblebee - Fly for 200 meters; can't touch groundDevourer - Eat 50 speciesVillage Folks - 3 posse members must be from different speciesSpeed Demon - Beat Creature stage in under one hourBestial - Beat Creature stage 10 timesCerberus - Evolve creature with three headsGeneral Custer - Lead 30 of your posse members to deathEpic Killer - Kill an Epic Creature in the Creature stageSlugger - Beat Creature stage with no legsSteel Tribe - Beat Tribe stage on hardFounder - Beat Tribe stage, build cityTribal Socialite - Convert all five tribes to your beliefsVicious - Eradicate all five other tribes, kill all, destroy all of their villagersDomestic Bliss - Domesticate three species, and farm themWatchful Parent - Beat Tribe stage with zero tribe member deathsTribal - Beat Tribe stage 10 timesErgonomically Terrific - Beat Tribe stage in under one hourAdamantium Civilization - Beat Civilization stage on hardStarman - Conquer all Civilizations, beat stage, launch first spaceshipEconomist - Beat Civilization stage with 8 economic citiesMilitary Strongman - Beat Civilization stage with 8 military citiesMissionary - Beat Civilization stage with 8 religious citiesSpice Hoarder - Have control of every spice nodeRelentless - Beat Civilization stage 10 timesRolling Thunder - Beat Civilization stage in under one hourGhetto Blaster - Create 10 anthemsSuper Pilot - Fly 40 hours in your shaceshipCivil Engineer - Raise 20 alien tribes up to civilizationsConquistador - Conquer 15 star systemsZoo Keeper - Create 15 zoo planetsBio Engineer - Edit at least 25 creatures using the Creature TweakerPalm Greaser - Pay 50 bribesMaxis Scout - Acquire 100 badgesEmpire Builder - Max out colonies on 10 planetsQuietus Star - Destroy 20 different planetsQuest Master - Finish 150 missionsGunner - Destroy 500 spaceshipsIdentity Crisis - Build an alliance between two races you createdThief - Steal 50 crates of spice42 - Discovery the center of the universeManifest Destiny - Discover EarthCareless Parent - Lose at least five planetsAlter Ego - Play Space stage using all 10 archetypesAlter Ego's Alter Ego - Get Master Badge Level 10 using all archetypesZealot Passion - Play as ZealotWarrior Passion - Play as WarriorBard Passion - Play as BardKnight Passion - Play as KnightWanderer Passion - Play as WandererTrader Passion - Play as TraderShaman Passion - Play as ShamanScientist Passion - Play as ScientistDiplomat Passion - Play as DiplomatEcologist Passion - Play as EcologistZealot Hero - Get Master Badge Level 10 as a ZealotWarrior Hero - Get Master Badge Level 10 as a WarriorBard Hero - Get Master Badge Level 10 as a BardKnight Hero - Get Master Badge Level 10 as a KnightWanderer Hero - Get Master Badge Level 10 as a WandererTrader Hero - Get Master Badge Level 10 as a TraderShaman Hero - Get Master Badge Level 10 as a ShamanScientist Hero - Get Master Badge Level 10 as a ScientistDiplomat Hero - Get Master Badge Level 10 as a DiplomatEcologist Hero - Get Master Badge Level 10 as a EcologistSplit Personality - Complete 'change archetype' mission</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2473">The Sims 2</game><game id="21401">MySims Kingdom</game><game id="250">SimEarth: The Living Planet</game><game id="18623">Black &amp; White</game><game id="3397">E. V. O.: Search for Eden</game><game id="4736">SimCity 4</game><game id="20960">SimCity Creator</game><game id="6210">Populous</game><game id="16457">Sid Meier's Civilization IV</game><game id="15849">flOw</game><game id="7624">Pac-Man</game><game id="11342">Master of Orion</game><game id="9115">Sins of a Solar Empire</game><game id="21663">Galactic Civilizations II: Dark Avatar</game><game id="12922">The Settlers</game><game id="14935">Gazillionaire Deluxe</game><game id="4024">Profitania</game><game id="2909">Zapitalism</game><game id="13355">Worms 4: Mayhem</game><game id="20581">The Sims 3</game><game id="401">Startopia</game><game id="11797">The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy</game><game id="24092">Sins of a Solar Empire: Entrenchment</game><game id="793">Super Stardust HD</game><game id="9293">Designasaurus II</game><game id="15346">Space Colony</game><game id="18440">Feeding Frenzy</game><game id="26939">Light of Altair</game><game id="1842">The Urbz: Sims in the City</game><game id="29320">The Sims 3 High-End Loft Stuff</game><game id="6735">Sacrifice</game><game id="26724">Space Ark</game><game id="31033">GodFinger</game><game id="27575">L.O.L.: Lack of Love</game><game id="4047">Seventh Cross Evolution</game><game id="32496">Shores of Hazeron</game><game id="32130">Darkspore</game><game id="31977">The Sims 3: Fast Lane Stuff</game><game id="36024">The Sims 3: Town Life Stuff</game><game id="36461">Foldit</game><game id="35626">Freakyforms: Your Creations, Alive!</game><game id="15816">Cubivore: Survival of the Fittest</game><game id="37803">Automation</game><game id="36494">Kerbal Space Program</game><game id="9469">Big Bug Bang: Le Retour de Commander Blood</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2243877-box_spore.png</image></root>