<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14148</id><name>Princess Crown</name><description>OverviewPrincess Crown is a fantasy action RPG developed for the Sega Saturn by Japanese developer Atlus in 1997. Featuring real-time combat action mixed with typical RPG elements, Princess Crown is highly regarded as being one of the best looking 2D games on the Saturn with notably large and detailed 2D sprites and fluid animation. Princess Crown was later ported to the PlayStation Portable in 2005 by Atlus and featured a few extras such as an image gallery. The development team behind Princess Crown eventually left Atlus and founded their own studio in 2002 called Puraguru which would later be renamed to VanillaWare. The company has since create several games that are inspired by or are spiritual successors to Princess Crown, such as Odin Sphere, Muramasa, and Dragon's Crown.StoryThe player takes the role of Princess Gradriel, heir to the throne of Valendia - the demon Larva, banished by Gradriel's mother 25 years hence, has re-awakened and is now once again threatening Valendia, so against her advisers wishes the young princess ventures out to dispel the demon forces from her lands and restore order.CharactersGradriel Do Valendia: The main character of Princess Crown. As the newly appointed Queen of Valendia, Gradriel sneaks out of the castle in order to better understand the kingdom she now rules.Edward Glowstar: The fairly tale's knight in shinning armor. Edward pops up in the story every now and again to lead a helping hand to Gradiel.Portgus Chrisford: A pirate who steals from the rich and gives to the poor, a lot like Robin Hood.Prosperpina: Just like Edward, Prosperpina pops in and out of the story at various points to cause trouble for our hero. She's not evil, but the first thing you see her do is her kidnapping kids and turning them into animals.Although Gradriel is the main character, you can play as the other characters in their stories after you beat the main game.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9235">Odin Sphere</game><game id="11602">Valkyrie Profile</game><game id="7769">SEGA AGES 2500 Vol.29: Monster World Complete Collection</game><game id="21222">GrimGrimoire</game><game id="24017">Muramasa: The Demon Blade</game><game id="1335">Tales of Destiny</game><game id="11703">Tales of Rebirth</game><game id="21441">Tales of Destiny 2</game><game id="595">Tales of Eternia</game><game id="255">Tales of Phantasia</game><game id="22872">Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Shadow Over Mystara</game><game id="22870">Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Tower of Doom</game><game id="14216">Castlevania: Symphony of the Night</game><game id="16851">Castlevania: The Dracula X Chronicles</game><game id="31372">Jikandia: The Timeless Land</game><game id="42036">Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Chronicles of Mystara</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/97089/2166475-princess_crown__j__front.jpg</image></root>