<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1417</id><name>DDRMAX Dance Dance Revolution</name><description>Songlist for the Japanese version   BYE BYE BABY BALLOON - JOGA  CANDY★ - Luv unlimited  COW GIRL - BAMBEE DIVE (more deep  deeper style) - Be For U Do It Right - SOTA feat. Ebony Fay DO YOU REMEMBER ME - JENNY Exotic Ethnic - RevenG FANTASY - MELISSA Firefly - Be For U FLASH IN THE NIGHT - FLASHMAN  FOLLOW ME - LADY BABY  GHOSTS (Vincent De Moor Original Mix) - TENTH PLANET Groove - Sho-T feat. Brenda Groove 2001 - Sho-T feat. Brenda Healing Vision (Angelic mix) - 2MB HIGHS OFF U (Scorccio XY Mix) - 4 REEEL I’M IN THE MOOD FOR DANCING - SHARON JUSTIFY MY LOVE - TESS Let the beat hit em! (CLASSIC RB STYLE) - STONE BROS. LET’S GROOVE - TIPS  TRICKS VS WISDOME Look To The Sky - System S.F. feat. ANNA LOVIN’ YOU (ROB SEARLE CLUB MIX) - VINYL BABY  MAX 300 - Ω Midnite Blaze - U1 Jewel Style MIRACLE - ST. JANNARO MY SWEET DARLIN’ - WILDSIDE NORI NORI NORI - JUDY CRYSTAL ON THE JAZZ - Jonny Dynamite! ORDINARY WORLD - AURORA featuring NAIMEE COLEMAN ORION .78 (civilization mix) - 2MB Share My Love - Julie Frost SO DEEP (PERFECT SPHERE REMIX) - SILVERTEAR SOBAKASU FRECKLES - TIGGY SOMEWHERE OVER THE RAINBOW - COSMIC GATE TELEPHONE OPERATOR (Club MIX) - SHELLEY PETER The Centre Of The Heart (STONEBRIDGE CLUBMIX) - Roxette true… ~radio edit~ - Riyu Kosaka  true… ~trance sunrise mix~ - Riyu Kosaka TWILIGHT ZONE (R-C Extended Club MIX) - 2 UNLIMITED WITCH DOCTOR (GIANTS TOONS VERSION) - CARTOONS WWW.BLONDE GIRL (MOMO MIX) - JENNY ROM YOZORA NO MUKO EUROBEAT - LOVERSSonglist for the US VersionSLAKE - 22 DUNK DJ NAGUREO - 5.1.1. DJ TAKA - ABYSS KTZ - AM-3P DIVAS - BABY BABY GIMMIE YOUR LOVE NAOKI - BRILLIANT 2U (ORCHESTRA GROOVE) NAOKI (FEAT. PAULA TERRY) - BROKEN MY HEART LUV UNLIMITED - CANDY JJ COMPANY - CELEBRATE BM CLUB SPACE - CUTIE CHASER (MORNING MIX) STEVE RHYNER - DARK BLACK FOREST (SHORT TRIP) DJ NAGUREO - DEEP IN YOU SOTA (FEAT. EBONY FAY) - DO IT RIGHT (HARMONIZED 2 STEP MIX) SCOTTY D. - DROP THE BOMB -SYSTEM S.F. MIX- NAOKI - DYNAMITE RAVE -DOWN BIRD SOTA MIX- D-COMPLEX - ECSTASY TAQ - ELECTRO TUNED (THE SUBS MIX) TAQ - ERA (NOSTALMIX) REVENG - EXOTIC ETHNIC SLAKE - GAMBOL MR. DOG (FEAT. DJ SWAN) - GENTLE STRESS (AMD SEXUAL MIX) SYMPHONIC DEFOGGERS WITH 1479 - GET ME IN YOUR SIGHT (AMD CANCUN MIX) BIG-O (FEAT. TAKA) - GRADIUSIC CYBER (AMD G5 MIX) SHO-T (FEAT. BRENDA) - GROOVE 2001 DE-SIRE - HEALING VISION 2MB - HEALING VISION (ANGELIC MIX) TAQ - HOLIC REEL 2 REAL - I LIKE TO MOVE IT GOOD-COOL - I WAS THE ONE SLAKE - I'M FOR REAL NAOKI - INSERTION FINAL OFFSET - JAM  MARMALADE OKUYATOS - KIND LADY STONE BROS. - LET THE BEAT HIT EM! (BM IIDX VERSION) STONE BROS. - LET THE BEAT HIT EM! (CLASSIC RB STYLE) SHIN MURAYAMA (FEAT. ARGIE PHINE) - LET'S TALK IT OVER L.E.D. LIGHT - OVERBLAST!! DJ TAKA - LOGICAL DASH SYSTEM S.F. (FEAT. ANNA) - LOOK TO THE SKY SYSTEM S.F. (FEAT. ANNA) - LOOK TO THE SKY (TRUE COLOR MIX) NAOKI (FEAT. PAULA TERRY) - LOVE AGAIN TONIGHT (FOR MELISSA MIX) CHANG MA - LOVE THIS FEELIN' RE-VENGE - MATSURI JAPAN OMEGA - MAX 300U1 JEWEL STYLE - MIDNITE BLAZE CAPTAIN JACK - MY GENERATION (FAT BEAT MIX)MITSU-O! WITH GEILA - MY SUMMER LOVE GOOD-COOL (FEAT. JP MILES) - NEVER LET YOU DOWN AURORA (FEAT. NAIMEE COLEMAN) - ORDINARY WORLD 2MB - ORION.78 (CIVILIZATION MIX) 200 - PARANOIA EVOLUTION 190 - PARANOIA MAX (DIRTY MIX) -CLUB ANOTHER VER.- DJ NAGUREO - PEACE OUT NM (FEAT. JULIE) - REMEMBER YOU CJ CREW (FEAT. CHRISTIAN D) - RHYTHM AND POLICE (K.O.G.G3 MIX) SYMPHONIC DEFOGGERS - RUGGED ASH TOGO PROJECT (FEAT. SANA) - SANA MORETTE NE ENTE DARUDE - SAND STORM DIVAS - SECRET RENDEZ-VOUS JULIE FROST - SHARE MY LOVE THOMAS HOWARD - SILENT HILL CARAMEL S. - SO IN LOVE GOOD-COOL - SPIN THE DISC JS-16 - STOMP TO MY BEAT JOE RINOIE - SYNCHRONIZED LOVE (RED MONSTER HYPER MIX) GOLDEN GATE - TAKE IT TO THE MORNING LIGHT (EXTENDED VOCAL) DJ SUWAMI - THE CUBE L.E.D. (FEAT. SANA) - THE SHINING POLARIS DE-SIRE - TRIP MACHINE CLIMAX KOSAKA RIYU - TRUE... (TRANCE SUNRISE MIX) VENUS - YOU LEAVE ME ALONE </description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7010">StepMania</game><game id="6978">Enthusia Professional Racing</game><game id="4031">Guitar Hero III: Legends of Rock</game><game id="22632">pop'n music 10</game><game id="22628">pop'n music 9</game><game id="22625">pop'n music 8</game><game id="22623">pop'n music 7</game><game id="22622">pop'n music 6</game><game id="22619">pop'n music 4</game><game id="22617">pop'n music 2</game><game id="21655">pop'n music</game><game id="23219">Guitar Rising</game><game id="25024">Dance ManiaX 2nd MIX</game><game id="20403">Dance Factory</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2280566-box_ddrmax.png</image></root>