<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14250</id><name>Rodland</name><description> Overview  Title screen of the home versionRodland was orignally released for the arcades, but was made for several other home systems and computers. The arcade version differs greatly from the home versions because it features better graphics and many more levels. The arcade essentially featured a sequal of Rodland upon completion of the game. It feels like a sequal because it features even better visuals and many orignal levels. The home consoles and computers never recieved a version of Rodland featuring the sequal.  Plot   Tam and Rit holding the Rods of SheesanomoFairies Tam and Rit find out that their mother has been kidnapped by evil monsters. They are each granted with magical wands, called the Rods of Sheesanomo, that give them powers. With their new powers they can defeat the monsters and rescue their kidnapped mother.     Gameplay  Gameplay resembles many platformers of the timeRodland is an action platformer where you play as fairies Tam and Rit. Each level is featured entirely on one screen, and the levels are populated with monsters. The goal is to simply to defeat all the enemies on screen using tricks and the magic wands. The magic wands can only stun the monsters, but once they are stunned you can kill them. The fairies navigate levels by running along multiple platforms that are connected by ladders. There are ladders in each level, but the player can also create ladders. Every time you create a ladder the previous one disappears which allows opportunities to dispose of enemies.  Bonus Levels  The arcade version featured a sequal with a new story, levels and visuals, but the gameplay stayed largely the same. In the sequal you still play as Tam and Rit, but this time they are out to avenge their father's death. Tam and Rit travel through a pyramid where the enemy that killed their father rests. Throughout the game they are guided by the ghost of their father for help in the game.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4995">Bubble Bobble</game><game id="10764">Rainbow Islands</game><game id="185">Bomb Jack</game><game id="19408">Moai Kun</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3413/235923-rodland.jpg</image></root>