<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14255</id><name>The Battle of Olympus</name><description>GameplayThe Battle of Olympus is a side-scrolling action adventure game with a similar style to Zelda II: The Adventure of Link. The game begins with an overworld map displaying the eight locations Orpheus can visit: Phrygia, Phthia, Attica, Argolis, Peloponnes, Laconia, Crete, and the starting area, Arcadia. The player cannot use the map to choose the next location, it is only there to display the current location.LayoutThe layout of the world is similar to Metroid, where there are no set levels, just areas which are all connected together.Towns are also set up similar to Zelda II, in that entering a house will allow the player to talk to NPCs will provide, occasionally cryptic, advice. There is no separation between towns and places where enemies can be fought: Each area contains both.CombatFighting enemies can result in item drops such as olives, which are used as currency in shops, and bay leaves, which are used to restore health. Some bosses will drop items needed to progress further in the game as well.Another important task is to seek out the gods who will give Orpheus crucial upgrades.Completing certain tasks will allow Orpheus to enter new areas that were inaccessible before.StoryThe story takes place in Ancient Greece. Orpheus, the hero, discovers the truth behind the death of his love Helene, who was supposedly poisoned but was really kidnapped by Hades, the god of the underworld. Upon hearing this, Orpheus sets out to save her with the gods assisting him.Game Boy VersionThere was a Game Boy version of the game released only in Europe in 1993. It was developed by Radical Entertainment. The Game Boy port of the game is very similar to the NES version, changing the graphics to fit the Game Boy system.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6959">God of War</game><game id="15154">Kid Icarus</game><game id="16241">Zelda II: The Adventure of Link</game><game id="5915">Valis II</game><game id="4208">Ys III: Wanderers from Ys</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2361164-nes_battleofolympus.jpg</image></root>