<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14336</id><name>Tutankham</name><description>Game Overview Tutankham is an arcade game developed by              Konami in 1982; in this game you play an explorer who is grave robbing Tutankhamun's tomb. As you search for valuable treasure (a map, an urn, a chest of gold  jewels and most importantly the golden death mask of King Tut) you’ll need to fight off the various creatures that guard the tomb and ultimately find your way through the catacombs.Game Play You must guide the explorer through a series of progressively more difficult mazes across four different stages. The explorer may move in four directions, but can only fire in two directions, left and right, making the player helpless in vertical shafts. There are also "warp zones" located in random parts of each maze that allow the explorer to be teleported from one area of the maze to another. There are several different creatures that constantly materialize from “spawning areas” within the maze and attack including asps, vultures, parrots, bats, dragons and curses. Those creatures can be destroyed to score between 20, and 60 points with either bullets or a "flash bomb”.  The explorer has a single “flash bomb” per life and stage that destroys all enemies on the screen.On each stage, the explorer must pick up keys in order to unlock the door to the room where each of the treasures are kept, allowing progress to the next stage. Along the way the explorer may grab optional treasures (Rings, Crowns, etc.) for bonus points. If the timer reaches zero, the player's ability to fire is removed. Bonus points are awarded based on the amount of extra time left over when a level is completed. After you have recovered all four of King Tut's treasures, the game starts over again with increased difficulty.Ports Tutankham was ported to the         Atari 2600,        Atari 8-bit computers,       ColecoVision,      IntelliVision,     Odyssey 2,    Vic-20,   TI-99/4A and most recently the original arcade game is one of the launch games for          Game Room on Xbox Live Arcade.Fun FactsThe game was originally titled Tutankhamen, but the publisher discovered the full name could not fit on the final production arcade cabinet, so the title was shortenedThis game is also known as Horror Maze on           Konami Classics Series: Arcade Hits for the             Nintendo DS.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/23546/1272694-t1.jpg</image></root>