<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14366</id><name>25 to Life</name><description> Overview 25 To Life is third person shooter, released, Jan 27 2006 in North America, Jun 1 in Europe and June 7 in Australia. Released on the Xbox, PS2 and the PC, it was developed by Avalanche Software Ritual Entertainment, Brying Graphics (Multiplayer) as well as published by Eidos entertainment.  Story Freeze the main character commits crimes with his friend Shaun, which in turn he spends the loot on he’s family.  One day freezes wife asks him about his doings and that he should stop because they have a son and his criminal life will become to be a bad influence on the son. Freeze agrees and informs his friend Shaun of his decision, Shaun after hearing this, pulls put a gun and directs it at freezes head and tells him he has to do one last job.  Freeze embarks on this final job where he is to take out some Columbian drug cartel, and take the cash and drugs, but when Freeze arrives he finds the Columbians dead and a cop waiting. After fleeing Freeze looses the cops and decides to rob a bank during which cops arrive and arrest him. Freeze is then incarcerated after which he escaped and decides to hunt down Shaun who has set him up. After Freeze kills Shaun he, holds his son and fights to the death against the cops.  Gameplay During gameplay you are the main character freeze, but you are also able to control Shaun and Mendosa at certain times in the story. 25 To Life controls like most action crime third person shooters, with the joystick for movement and various buttons for your actions, e.g. shooting, running and taking cover.   25 to Life also featured online gameplay that essentially devolved into cops vs. robbers.  One group of participants would play as cops while the other group would play as criminals in gameplay scenarios that ranged from robbing a bank and getting away with the loot to raiding a criminal stronghold in a siege-like mode.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20454">50 Cent: Blood on the Sand</game><game id="20989">CrimeCraft</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2314051-box_25tl.png</image></root>