<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14441</id><name>Pajama Sam 2: Thunder and Lightning Aren't so Frightening</name><description>OverviewDeveloped by Humongous Entertainment and released in 1998, Pajama Sam 2 is a point and click adventure game that centers around a young boy named Sam who idolizes the fictional comic book hero Pajama Man. This sequel, much like the original, employs simple logic and collecting puzzles. Centered at the 3-8 age group most puzzles have relatively simple solutions. The game features a more streamlined version of Ron Gilbert's SCUMM engine rather than selecting an action the player only needs to click on an object to interact with it.GameplayAs with most point and click adventures, the majority of the game is spent picking up items and figuring out where to use them with the occasional purely environmental puzzle. In order to increase replayability, certain puzzles are altered or completely replaced on subsequent playthroughs. Each room is filled with whimsical objects that, although unrelated to the main quest, provide amusing animations when clicked that are simply there entertain the player.PlotDuring a viewing of a Pajama Man cartoon show, Sam is scared by the start of a thunder storm. He decides to don his cape and go up to the clouds to investigate the issue via a path in his attic. After climbing into his attic Sam stumbles upon the World Wide Weather Center. His problems only worsen when he falls on a big red button that destroys the weather creation systems and is tasked with fixing the machines before Mother Nature comes to inspect the facility. In the end, he fixes everything in the nick of time, only to destroy it again after Mother Nature’s arrival when he turns the “Kaboom” lever up to too high a volume.MinigamesBoard Game- If “Fun” is selected in the menu, you can play a Sorry-like board game in which you chose one of four weather piece sets (themed after rain, wind, snow, and sun), and try to get all of your pieces around the board before the other players do.Tic-Tac-Toe- If the ketchup and mustard are clicked in the cafeteria area, the player can play a simple game of Tic-Tac-Toe against the computer.Snow Flake Creation-In the snowflake room players can create their own snowflakes using the classic paper cutting method and print their favorite designs.Comic Book Hunt- When on the rooftop accessible via the elevator, the player can look through binoculars and try to find hidden comic books.CollectiblesStrewn throughout the game are a number of puzzle pieces that the player can collect to assemble into a complete image. These collectible challenges are present in all Pajama Sam games as a side quest. When the puzzle is finished, the puzzle can be printed.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="8">Educational</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14824">Spy Fox in "Dry Cereal"</game><game id="931">Putt-Putt Travels Through Time</game><game id="3785">Putt-Putt Saves the Zoo</game><game id="10431">Putt-Putt Joins the Circus</game><game id="15183">Putt-Putt Enters the Race</game><game id="13134">Putt-Putt Goes to the Moon</game><game id="13465">Spy Fox 2: Some Assembly Required</game><game id="5914">Spy Fox: Operation Ozone</game><game id="2373">Freddi Fish and the Case of the Missing Kelp Seeds</game><game id="7662">Freddi Fish 5: The Case of the Creature of Coral Cove</game><game id="9720">Freddi Fish 3: The Case of the Stolen Conch Shell</game><game id="10911">Freddi Fish 4: The Case of the Hogfish Rustlers of Briny Gulch</game><game id="15666">Freddi Fish 2: The Case of the Haunted School House</game><game id="3090">Fatty Bear's Birthday Surprise</game><game id="11177">Putt-Putt Joins the Parade</game><game id="18816">Spy Fox in Cheese Chase</game><game id="3136">Putt-Putt and Fatty Bear's Activity Pack</game><game id="7793">Putt-Putt: Pep's Birthday Surprise</game><game id="13791">Putt-Putt and Pep's Balloon-o-Rama</game><game id="9805">Freddi Fish's One-Stop Fun Shop</game><game id="5449">Freddi Fish and Luther's Water Worries</game><game id="13067">Freddi Fish &amp; Luther's Maze Madness</game><game id="4615">Putt-Putt and Pep's Dog on a Stick</game><game id="19472">Fatty Bear's FunPack</game><game id="22727">Spy Fox in: Hold the Mustard</game><game id="11852">Sam &amp; Max Hit the Road</game><game id="5729">The Curse of Monkey Island</game><game id="2037">Maniac Mansion</game><game id="4372">Maniac Mansion: Day of the Tentacle</game><game id="3019">The Secret of Monkey Island</game><game id="10528">Monkey Island 2:  LeChuck's Revenge</game><game id="21174">Full Throttle</game><game id="14748">Indiana Jones and The Last Crusade: The Graphic Adventure</game><game id="13230">Grim Fandango</game><game id="14743">Blue's 123 Time Activities</game><game id="14412">Blue's Reading Time Activities</game><game id="17810">Blue's Clues: Blue's Art Time Activities</game><game id="11848">Blue's ABC Time Activities</game><game id="5784">Blue's Treasure Hunt</game><game id="16775">Blue's Clues: Blue's Birthday Adventure</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/6497/278448-pajama_sam_2_thunder_lightening_thumb.jpg</image></root>