<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14484</id><name>Dungeon Maker: Hunting Ground</name><description>Dungeon Maker: Hunting Grounds is a hack-and-slash with light RPG elements. The main feature of the game that separates it from hack and slash games is being able to create your own dungeons to attract monsters. You arrive in monster-plagued town as an amateur dungeon architect. The towns people are tired of being constantly assaulted by the monsters so they are ready to take any help they can get. They quickly point you toward a cave just a bit outside the city gates that could supposedly be repurposed into a dungeon that would attract monsters there instead of toward the town. You are handed a few room kits and dungeon pieces by the local carpenter, and head off to the cave to see what you can do.  First of all, you will need to lay down some hallway pieces. You get to your inventory of building kits using one button and then select what you want to use from a list. At first you can only access hallway and small room kits, but eventually you will get things like: treasure rooms where monsters where occasionally hide their valuables, fountain rooms for attracting thirsty monsters, and chapels for attracting the undead.  Along with the basic rooms, most rooms can also be skinned with different floors to make them appeal to different monsters. For example, goblins will like to dwell in dirty, untouched corridors, rooms, and wooded areas, but an evil knight will most likely only be found if you set up a fancy bedroom. Every day you will travel through the dungeons that you have set up and kill monsters to collect loot and money. Loot is mainly new weapons and armor; the money you collect can be used to purchase new rooms and building kits from the carpenter, as well as potions from your local old hag, and spell books from a set of young mage twins. Character growth is handled through what kind of armor and weapons you use as well as cooking. During your dungeon scrounging you will find ingredients like different meats and plants that can be used in dishes. Cooking a dish will usually give you a moderate to large boost in a certain stat depending on the ingredient's rarity.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17620">Dungeon Keeper</game><game id="4820">Dungeon Keeper 2</game><game id="20223">Monster Hunter Freedom 2</game><game id="19042">Dungeon Keeper: The Deeper Dungeons</game><game id="27640">Fighter Maker 2</game><game id="30580">Monster Hunter Portable 3rd</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2478654-box_dmhg.png</image></root>