<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14525</id><name>Syndicate Wars</name><description>OverviewDeveloped by the now-defunct, legendary development studio Bullfrog Productions, Syndicate Wars is a top-down "Real-Time Tactics" game which has you take control of four agents or acolytes to complete missions in free roaming environments that mainly consist of assassination or persuasion (i.e. destroying buildings). The developers made a mutual deal with anime distributor Manga Entertainment to include an extended trailer for the game on the VHS of Ghost in the Shell, while the game features FMV trailers for Manga Entertainment on billboards, as well as their logo on vehicles in the game.The game debuted on the PC on the 31st of October, 1996 with a PlayStation version following in July, 1997. EA released the game in Australia on the PlayStation Network on the 27th of November, 2008. The PSN version of the game is playable on both the Playstation 3 and the PSP and is a 113MB download. Syndicate Wars was the last Syndicate game to be released in the series and runs on a modified version of the Magic Carpet Engine.PlotThe start of the game has the player play as the Eurocorp Syndicate, which is in its prime and is part of an alliance of corporations which are controlling the world's population through the use of private militaries and high tech mind control devices.As the game begins, the corporations control over the population is threatened as a virus named 'Harbinger' is set loose throughout the global communications system, which damages mind control implants of many people. Many of these newly 'awakened' people decide to fight against the corporations in an armed uprising.Following this, a new group emerges calling itself the Church of the new Epoch which seeks to destroy the corporations' control over the world and implement its own brand of mind control; the virus was their first step.You take control over one of the two sides in the conflict.Minimum System RequirementsWindows XP / Vista / 71.8 GHz processor512MB RAM (1 GB recommended)3D graphics card compatible with DirectX 9.0c2GB HDDMouseKeyboard</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13710">Chaos Overlords</game><game id="21100">Grand Theft Auto: Chinatown Wars</game><game id="1802">Abomination: The Nemesis Project</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8830/673686-syndicatewarsbox.png</image></root>