<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14523</id><name>Star Wars: Jedi Knight II - Jedi Outcast</name><description>Overview Star Wars Jedi Knight II: Outcast was developed by Raven Software and released for the PC in March of 2002. It was ported later that year to the Xbox, GameCube, and Mac. It is technically the fourth game in the series being proceeded by  Star Wars: Dark Forces,       Star Wars Jedi Knight: Dark Forces II, and      Star Wars Jedi Knight: Mysteries of the Sith respectfully. All versions were generally well received and a sequel entitled:     Star Wars Jedi Knight:  Jedi Academy was released the following year. The PC version of Jedi Outcast was re-released in 2006 as part of a compilation entitled: Star Wars: The Best of PC. Story Opening CrawlIt is a time of relative peace in thegalaxy. Eight years have passedsince the Empire's defeatat the BATTLE OF ENDOR, but theNEW REPUBLIC still struggles torestore order and vanquish its enemies.After defending the VALLEY OF THE Kyle KatarnJEDI from the evil JEREC andnearly falling to the Dark Sidehimself, former Jedi Knight KYLEKATARN has severed his connection with the Forceand returned to his mercenary ways.With his longtime partner, JAN ORS,Kyle continues to aid the Republic in thefight against the IMPERIAL REMNANT.As the Remnant launches its latest gambit toregain control of the galaxy, Kyle and Jan havebeen sent by the New Republic to investigate theplanet KEJIM, a long-dead Imperial outpost… PlotThe game takes place in 12 ABY, a few years after the end of           Jedi Knight: Mysteries of the Sith      . Like its predecessors, it is based around the character           Kyle Katarn. Since nearly being taken in by the dark side, Kyle has given up his           lightsaber and the Force      . He once again works with his partner (and now love interest)           Jan Ors  doing missions for the New Republic     . Kyle swinging his Lightsaber Mon Mothma contacts them to investigate an Imperial Remnant base on Kejim. A part of a transmission sent from the base was decrypted and some keywords such as "Reborn" or "Valley of the Jedi" were revealed. In the base, they discover murdered prisoners, and a link to another planet on the outer rim where the Imperials are doing experiments on infusing the Force into living subjects.   Jan and  Kyle infiltrate the facility and free the prisoners, but Jan is captured by two Dark Jedi  . Katarn is initially eager to rescue his love interest, but   Desann ignites his lightsaber and Katarn has no choice but to fight him. Desann easily defeats the mercenary but spares him, saying he would be a worthier adversary if he had the power of the Force. Desann then ordered  Tavion to kill Jan, which she seemingly does. Kyle embarks to the           Valley of the Jedi         to regain his Force powers and then to Yavin 4  to retrieve his lightsaber from                    Luke Skywalker, intent on revenge, to which Luke warns him of the  dangerous path he is following. What Kyle doesn't know is that he was set up and that Desann had followed him to the Valley, using its power to infuse the Force into his soldiers, creating the          Reborn and with  Galak Fyyai's help the Shadowtroopers. He plans to use this army to invade the          Jedi Temple on Yavin IV and restore the                    Empire. When Kyle spares his apprentice, Tavion, she admits the plan, and tells him Jan is still alive. He radios Rogue Squadron and stows away on  Desann's personal ship, where he finds Jan unhurt and alive.  After knocking out the shields of Desann's flagship,    Doomgiver and killing Galak, he takes an escape pod to Yavin 4 and helps fend off Desann's attack, fighting his way through Reborn and Shadowtroopers, eventually killing the Dark Jedi. At the end of the game, he accepts Luke's offer of a teaching position at the Academy, but not before he spends some time off with Jan Ors.   Combat Slice 'n Dice 'emThere were two distinct gamplay styles in Jedi Outcast. It was a first person shooter reminiscent of such games as Doom or Quake III.  As a shooter it was considered solid but fairly standard of the genre, but where the game really excelled was in the lightsaber combat. Jedi Outcast was the first Star Wars game to implement lightsaber fighting in a successful and satisfying way. As Kyle the player could perform a wide range of attacks based on both player inputs and an enemy's location in relation to the player. There was only one primary attack button, but the player still had several different moves at his disposal depending on if he/she moved one way or the other, which direction the mouse or thumb-stick was moved, hitting the attack button a second time, and so on. The Player also had three different fighting styles to choose from; speed (represented by a blue line), strength (represented by a pink/reddish line) and medium(represent by a yellow line, also this is your default fighting style). All of which are self-explanatory.    Weapons Arakyd 3t3 missileBactaBlast doorBryar pistolBowcasterBlaster rifleComlinkDEMP 2DetpackDisruptorFlechetteHologramHolopadLight Amplification GogglesLightsaberMedpackMerr-SonnNeuro-Saav Model TD2.3 electrobinocularsPersonal shield (Armor)Planetary ion cannonRepeaterScomp linkSeeker DroneSensor ArrayShield generatorStun batonThermal detonatorTrip mine  Force Powers The player is also given a considerable amount of force powers to use, necessary for certain puzzles, and very helpful in combat.  These included such powers as force push, force pull, force lightning, Jedi Mind Trick, and Lightsaber Throw. The force powers really helped to round out the gaming experience and solidified the games attempt to make you feel like a Jedi. However, unlike Jedi Knight: Dark Forces 2, you cannot choose which force power you receive, instead at the beginning of each mission (after you get your lightsaber and basic force powers) you get a new force power or an upgrade to a power you already have. Kyle Katarn uses force lightning on stormtroopers. MultiplayerThe multiplayer component  was a very key part in this game and is still played by many people today.  Many modes are available such as free-for-all (deathmatch/slayer), team free-for-all, and capture the Flag.  There are also many customization options available to let the host do things like disable force powers, make the the match lightsabers only, and other things which can make multiplayer more interesting or more of a challenge. Also, bots can be used in all modes in multiplayer.   PC Requirements Windows 95 OSR2/98/ME/2000/XP; Pentium II or AMD class 350 MHz or faster CPU; 64 MB RAM required, 128 MB required for Windows 2000 and XP; 16 MB OpenGL compliant 3D accelerator card; 16-bit DirectX 8.x compatible sound card; 4x CD-ROM drive; 665 MB hard drive space (Min.)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2832">Tribes 2</game><game id="22547">Soldier of Fortune</game><game id="11187">Star Trek: Voyager - Elite Force</game><game id="12306">Star Trek: Voyager - Elite Force Expansion Pack</game><game id="15362">Incoming Forces</game><game id="7574">Battle Engine Aquila</game><game id="7570">Enter the Matrix</game><game id="14819">Tron 2.0</game><game id="15509">Star Trek: Elite Force II</game><game id="13683">Quake 4</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2285709-box_swjk2.png</image></root>