<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14550</id><name>Bleach: The Blade of Fate</name><description>Overview   Bleach: The Blade of Fate is a fighting game for the Nintendo DS based on the Bleach series. The story is divided in many chapters with the story of every character. New chapters are unlocked once the first chapter is completed.GameplayThe gameplay is really basic 2-D fighting game. The top screen shows all the action while the bottom screen has some interesting features. You can use your special attacks by pressing on the lower screen the different names of the attack (ex: Special A, Special B) or you can choose some boosts you want to use. Those attacks however are limited to your energy bar that slowly regenerates as you fight... The different boosts can only be used once per match.The boosts available include invincibility, preventing your opponent from jumping, making your weapons inflict poison on your enemy and a variety of other buffs/de-buffs and they all have different levels of effect.  Being able to use these boosts depend on which ones you put in a pre-set deck that you can change at any time. Different boosts are collected by beating certain scenarios in story mode, or achieving a certain amount of points in a character's arcade mode.MultiplayerThe real bonus to this game is the Wi-Fi mode. You can fight against friends or random people from all around the world with a varied character selection. This aspect of the game is the one that got most of the appreciation gamer-wise as the real fans were already pleased with the story mode.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18303">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja 2</game><game id="5206">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="21697">Katekyo Hitman Reborn! DS Flame Rumble Hyper - Moeyo Mirai</game><game id="22980">Windy x Windam</game><game id="8862">YūYū Hakusho: Makyō Toitsusen</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2209402-box_btbof.png</image></root>