<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14584</id><name>Team Yankee</name><description>OverviewTeam Yankee is a tank simulation/strategy game based on the novel by Harold Coyle. Team Yankee was developed by Oxford Digital Enterprises (Atari ST and Amiga versions), and The Assembly Line (PC version). The game was published by Empire Interactive Entertainment for all releases.GameplayThe scenarios in Team Yankee are based on the chapters of the novel, also called Team Yankee written by Harold Coyle.Tank Identification TestOne of the test ScreensIf the player chooses to play a scenario other than the practice scenario a test must be taken. A tank (either NATO or Warsaw) profile (10 different views) will be shown and the player must name the type of tank. If the player can get three answers correct than the scenario can be played. Knowing the various types of tanks is very important in Team Yankee as friendly tanks are not labeled as such during gameplay.Mission BriefingsBefore each scenario the player is presented with a mission briefing screen. On the mission briefing screen there is a map of the battlefield, a text briefing describing the mission, and the ability to place artillery strikes.BattlesIn Team Yankee the player can take control of any of the four tanks in any of the four platoons, which makes sixteen tanks able to be controlled in all. The display screen can be changed from a quadrant mode or a full screen mode. In the quadrant mode the player can see all four platoons in their own split screen. In full screen mode the view zooms in on one specific platoon.WeaponsWeaponDescriptionHeat RoundAn explosive round that blows up on contact.Sabot RoundAn armor piercing round that is made up of tungsten.T.O.W MissileAn anti-tank missile that has a very long range that must be fired from a stationary tank.Smoke GrenadeA smoke grenade that when used creates a cloud of smoke.Machine GunThe machine gun is a typical tank mounted machine gun and has an infinite number of ammo.TanksM-1 Abrams Main Battle TankM-1 Abrams Main Battle TankCrew - 4Weight (In Tons) - 54.5Length (In cm) - 977Engine Type - TurbineRoad Range (In km) - 498Max Speed (On Road) - 72.4Max Speed (Off Road) - 48.3Front Armor (In mm) - 380Main Gun Type - SmoothCaliber (In mm) - 105Effective Range (In m) - 2500Max Rounds Per Minute - 8Total Rounds - 55Heat Rounds - YesSabot Rounds - YesT.O.W Rounds - NoM-113 Armored Personnel CarrierM-113 Armoured Personnel CarrierCrew - 2Weight (In Tons) - 11.2Length (In cm) - 486Engine Type - DieselRoad Range (In km) - 321Max Speed (On Road) - 64.4Max Speed (In Water) - 5.8Front Armor (In mm) - 38Main Gun Type - Machine GunCaliber (In mm) - 12.7Effective Range (In m) - 500Max Rounds Per Minute - N/ATotal Rounds - 1200Heat Rounds - NoSabot Rounds - NoT.O.W Rounds - NoM-2 Bradley Infantry Fighting VehicleM-2 Bradley Infantry Fighting VehicleCrew - 3Weight (In Tons) - 22.7Length (In cm) - 645Engine Type - DieselRoad Range (In km) - 483Max Speed (On Road) - 66Max Speed (Water) - 7.2Front Armor (In mm) - 60Main Gun Type - CannonCaliber (In mm) - 25Effective Range (In m) - 1000Max Rounds Per Minute - 100Total Rounds - 900Heat Rounds - NoSabot Rounds - NoT.O.W Rounds - 7M-901 Improved TOW VehicleM-901 Improved TOW VehicleCrew - 4Weight (In Tons) - 11.2Length (In cm) - 486Engine Type - DieselRoad Range (In km) - 321Max Speed (On Road) - 55Max Speed (Off Road) - N/AFront Armor (In mm) - 38Main Gun Type - noneCaliber (In mm) - N/AEffective Range (In m) - N/AMax Rounds Per Minute - N/ATotal Rounds - N/AHeat Rounds - NoSabot Rounds - NoT.O.W Rounds - 12T-62 Main Battle TankT-62 Main Battle TankCrew - 4Weight (In Tons) - 37.5Length (In cm) - 933Engine Type - DieselRoad Range (In km) - 450Max Speed (On Road) - 50Max Speed (Off Road) - N/AFront Armor (In mm) - 200Main Gun Type - SmoothCaliber (In mm) - 115Effective Range (In m) - 1500Max Rounds Per Minute - 3-5Total Rounds - 40Heat Rounds - YesSabot Rounds - YesT.O.W Rounds - NoT-72 Main Battle TankT-72 Main Battle TankCrew - 3Weight (In Tons) - 41Length (In cm) - 953Engine Type - DieselRoad Range (In km) - 450Max Speed (On Road) - 70Max Speed (Off Road) - N/AFront Armor (In mm) - 250Main Gun Type - SmoothCaliber (In mm) - 155Effective Range (In m) - 2000Max Rounds Per Minute - 6-8Total Rounds - 39Heat Rounds - YesSabot Rounds - YesT.O.W Rounds - NoBMP-2 Infantry VehicleBMP-2 Infantry VehicleCrew - 3Weight (In Tons) - 14.5Length (In cm) - 674Engine Type - DieselRoad Range (In km) - 500Max Speed (On Road) - 70Max Speed (Off Road) - N/AFront Armor (In mm) - 19Main Gun Type - Auto-CannonCaliber (In mm) - 30Effective Range (In m) - 1000Max Rounds Per Minute - N/ATotal Rounds - 40Heat Rounds - NoSabot Rounds - NoT.O.W Rounds - YesBTR-60 Armored Personnel CarrierBTR-60 Armoured Personnel CarrierCrew - 2Weight (In Tons) - 10.2Length (In cm) - 722Engine Type - PetrolRoad Range (In km) - 500Max Speed (On Road) - 80Max Speed (Off Road) - N/AFront Armor (In mm) - 9Main Gun Type - Machine GunCaliber (In mm) - 14.5Effective Range (In m) - 500Max Rounds Per Minute - N/ATotal Rounds - 500Heat Rounds - NoSabot Rounds - NoT.O.W Rounds - No</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23150">Panzer Command: Operation Winter Storm</game><game id="18337">Abrams Battle Tank</game><game id="1313">Arcticfox</game><game id="5608">M1 Tank Platoon</game><game id="10944">M1 Tank Platoon 2</game><game id="19787">Armored Fist</game><game id="2506">Armored Fist 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/10/103881/1759901-ty1.jpg</image></root>