<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14608</id><name>Final Fight 2</name><description>Overview Final Fight 2 is the sequel to the 1989 arcade beat-em-up,  Final Fight. Released by             Capcom for the            Super Nintendo in 1993. The game features Mike Haggar as the returning character from the original. Plot   Haggar, piledrives his way to victory.  After the fall of the Mad Gear gang in the original game, two of the original heroes, Cody and Guy, go their separate ways. Cody goes off on vacation with his girlfriend Jessica, and Guy off on a journey to hone his fighting skills. Mike Haggar remains in Metro City in charge as mayor. The period of peace soon ends as surviving members of Mad Gear join up with a new leader to   plot a revenge plan against the heroes of Metro City. They head to Japan and kidnap Guy's fiancee Rena and his sensai Genryusai. Rena's sister and Genryusai's daughter, Maki, gives a call to Mike Haggar to let him known what just happened. Mike Haggar, Maki, and friend Carlos Miyamoto join together to rescue the kidnap victims. Their journey leads them Eurasia where they come across many members of Mad Gear. First there in           Hong Kong, they run into Won Won. After Won Won's defeat, Haggar, Carlos and Maki find out that Mad Gear is in          Europe, and Rena and Genryusai were taken there.Once Haggar, Carlos, and Maki head for another part of Europe. And there they encounter an original member of Mad Gear,         Rolento. The heroes manage to defeat Rolento and got information about the where abouts of Rena and Genryusai. Rolento tells them that there in Japan with his new leader. They head to        Japan and face the new leader of Mad Gear, Retu. Haggar, Carlos and Maki finally save Rena and Genryusai by defeating Retu. Maki is reunited with her family, and the game ends.GameplayFinal Fight 2 plays very similar to the original game. The player has a choice to pick one of three characters, and goes through six levels with enemies. The objective for the player is to beat up every enemy on screen that appears, and the boss at the end of each level. The game makes use of two buttons, attack and jump. The player can grab an enemy and perform an throwing technique. With the combination of the attack and jump buttons, the player can activate a special move that can attack every enemy that's near the player, but it can drain the player's health.  Several enemies differ from each other; for example, one enemy can charge at the player with a device that can electrocute the player, and another can block the player's attack.  The bonus stage.  The game has two bonus stages. One stage is a returning stage from the first Final Fight, the smash the car stage; the player has a certain amount of time to destroy a car to earn extra points. The other bonus stage is the player has to destroy a certain amount of oil drums before the time runs out, some of the oil drums flame up and can be a hazard to the player.   Items such as health items and weapons can be found in the game. The player can restore his or her health with a turkey or with other food items.  Weapons can also be use to defend against enemies.   Characters         Mike Haggar -     The character select screen.   the main hero of the original Final Fight. Mike Haggar gets a call from Maki to inform him that Guy's wife and his sensai have been kidnap and Maki needs Haggar's help. Without hesitation, Haggar agrees.       Carlos Miyamoto -  a Japanese/South American decent . He fights with two swords against  his enemies.        Maki Genryusai  -  The sister-in-law of Guy. Maki enlist the help of Mike Haggar and Carlos Miyamoto to save her kidnap father and sister.  Localization Like the original Final Fight, some censoring has been done to the U.S and European version of the game. In the Japanese version, two female enemies were presented in the game, but were changed into male enemies much like   Poison and  Roxy in the first Final Fight. </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20436">Streets of Rage</game><game id="18122">Streets of Rage 2</game><game id="15924">Streets of Rage 3</game><game id="20752">Double Dragon</game><game id="18034">Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles IV: Turtles in Time</game><game id="1618">The Ninja Warriors</game><game id="2840">Sonic Blast Man</game><game id="14351">Golden Axe</game><game id="4325">Magic Sword</game><game id="4816">Double Dragon II: The Revenge</game><game id="7711">Super Double Dragon</game><game id="5546">Sengoku 2</game><game id="13074">Sengoku 3</game><game id="22953">Ultimate Fighter</game><game id="17660">The Combatribes</game><game id="5888">God Hand</game><game id="25040">Tokyo Beat Down</game><game id="11814">The Bouncer</game><game id="26595">Crime Fighters</game><game id="27063">Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Turtles in Time Re-Shelled</game><game id="9710">Batman Returns</game><game id="20754">Double Dragon Advance</game><game id="14906">Stone Protectors</game><game id="36070">64th Street: A Detective Story</game><game id="7950">The Peace Keepers</game><game id="33387">UFO Kamen Yakisoban: Kettler no Kuroi Inbou</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2363833-snes_finalfight2_2.jpg</image></root>