<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14615</id><name>Every Extend</name><description>Overview Every Extend is a  freeware PC game created by Japanese game designer   Kanta Matsuhisa under her “  Omega” pseudonym. It is the forerunner to the more well known games   Every Extend Extra and   Every Extend Extra Extreme, both of which were developed by   Tetsuya Mizuguchi's   Q Entertainment with input from Kanta Matsuhisa. Story Although the game itself does not contain any story to speak of, the game's manual does include the following: One day suddenly,you receive 12 UCHU- guided bombs. What do you do?No thank you. No increase so much!Less time to play. Soon the game is over.so No thanks.Therefore I can't use so much.Oh, no more. To make a sortie,give me a turn. Here.Why do you increase!? No more increse. No more!I can't make full use. Too many! Too many! Give me a turn.Ohhh! Ohh ! Why increase SO MORE? It becomes a terrible thing!How many bombs!? No! No! I CAN'T USE!Do you listen? No more! Why increase! NO! NO!Who in the world use so many bombs! No more. Already enough!Hey,PLEASE no increase! You listen!? NO NO MORE! STOP STOP! No increase! It's enough!STOP! STOP NOW! NO! NO! NO INCREASE! NO MORE!What are you doing!? Increase,no increase,or WHAT ARE YOU DOING!?HEY! Really what are you doing!? Soon it's overflow! Terrible!NO MORE! NO! NOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOO!!! Gameplay  With a familiar control scheme (arrow keys to move, Z key to attack) and scenario (enemies appear from the edges of the screen; the player must kill them to gain points) Every Extend is most easily classified as a shooter. However, while the game may superficially appear to resemble a number of similar games, it has one core mechanic which sets it apart from other shooters: rather than destroying enemies by shooting them, the player blows up their own ship in order to explode nearby foes and, with luck, set off chain reactions to kill enemies further away. However, as the player does not have an infinite supply of lives, they must earn more by accumulating points and collecting items which are left behind by destroyed enemies.  At the start of a stage, a timer begins to count down from two and a half minutes towards zero, although this can be extended a little by the collection of certain items dropped by enemies. When the timer reaches a certain time, a large boss enemy will appear. If the player can defeat this boss before they run out of lives or time they will complete the stage and earn bonus points for any lives or time they have remaining. Should the player run out of lives or time before they manage to defeat the boss though, the game will be over.Game modes The game features two game modes, light mode and heavy mode. As one might expect, heavy mode is the harder of the two. This is mostly because the fact that destroyed enemies leave bullets behind them that the player must dodge. Heavy mode also features an alternative boss, which the player can face if he fullfills one of the following during the session:He/she has collected seven quickens and have at least five lives remaining. The score must be either above 800,000 or below 100,000.The player has managed to collect more than seven quickens.BossesEasy Mode: AKR I-C-EThe player faces of against AKR I-C-E's first form, Spread SwordThis boss has three forms and each of them can be defeated by a direct attack from the player. Attacks via chained explosions gives a score bonus.Heavy Mode: KW MOTORThis boss has four forms and each of them can be defeated by a direct attack from the player. Attacks via chained explosions gives a score bonus.Heavy Mode Alternative Boss: A-BA HEDRONThis boss has five forms. The first four forms must be defeated via chain attacks, and each new form demands a longer chain. The last form can be defeated via a direct attack.SequelsEvery Extend got two sequels,   Every Extend Extra and   Every Extend Extra Extreme. Both of these were developed by   Q Entertainment and got commercial releases for   PSP and   XBLA respectively. These sequels features a more beat driven soundtrack, whereas the tracks in the original are more melody focused.Q Entertainment supposedly learned of Every Extend when one employee skipped work for several days when he stayed home and played the game.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17578">Rez</game><game id="20320">Synaesthete</game><game id="5057">Lumines: Puzzle Fusion</game><game id="9960">Everyday Shooter</game><game id="22034">Rez HD</game><game id="22478">PowerUp Forever</game><game id="24502">Evasive Space</game><game id="22383">Otocky</game><game id="37318">AVSEQ</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14097/886031-ee0.jpg</image></root>