<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14646</id><name>Kirby's Pinball Land</name><description>GameplayBoss fights, pinball-style.Kirby's Pinball Land is a pinball game starring  Kirby and many familiar characters from the Kirby series. The object of the game is to take Kirby to the top of three separate pinball tables themed after a stage from  Kirby's Dream Land. Each table has three individual floors. The only way to lose a life is to fall through the bottom of the third floor and fail to return by bouncing off of the springboard located underneath each table. By reaching the top of the table and finding a warp star Kirby will be taken to a fight against that table's boss. There are three different bosses: Whispy Woods The Poppy Bros. KrackoOnce Kirby has defeated all of them he will be taken to a fight against  King Dedede. Defeating him will start the game over again, allowing Kirby to return to each of the three tables once more and build up an even higher score.ScoringThere are no rain delays in pinball.Kirby earns points by coming into contact with just about anything on the game boards. Defeating enemies, attacking boss characters, and collecting items will all bestow differing amounts of points on him. In addition to the basic ways of earning points, Kirby also banks a bonus score in the lower right corner. This bonus score consists of a multiplicand and a multiplier. Performing specific actions, especially during mini-games, increases either the multiplicand or the multiplier, with the multiplier being more difficult to increase. When Kirby dies, the product of these two numbers is applied to his total score.High scores are not kept for each individual table. Instead they are kept for the total score of each playthrough.Mini-GamesThere are three different mini-games, one for each table. The mini-games can all be reached by locating a warp star on the second floor. In these games Kirby can score bonus points and even earn 1-Ups. Each has a different objective. The Whispy Woods game revolves around breaking blocks to earn bonuses. The Poppy Bros. game involves shooting Kirby into a soccer goal guarded by  Squishy. Finally, the Kracko mini-game requires you to knock items passing by up to a second Kirby who is standing over the playing area awaiting a meal.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="30">Pinball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19154">Pokémon Pinball</game><game id="8812">Pokémon Pinball: Ruby &amp; Sapphire</game><game id="22540">Powershot Pinball Constructor</game><game id="4195">Muppet Pinball Mayhem</game><game id="18592">Sonic the Hedgehog: Spinball</game><game id="4130">The Pinball of the Dead</game><game id="25403">Digital Pinball: Necronomicon</game><game id="9709">Revenge of the 'Gator</game><game id="34717">Pokémon Pinball Mini</game><game id="12971">Disney/Pixar's Monsters Inc.: Pinball Panic</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1865075-box_kpl.png</image></root>