<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14684</id><name>Tekken 4</name><description>OverviewTekken 4 is the fifth installment in the Tekken series. It was developed and published by Namco for the arcades in 2000 and PlayStation 2 in 2002. Namco soon was obsorbed by Bandai Co., Ltd., in 2005 then in March of 2006, Namco and Bandai's video game operations merged into Namco Bandai Games Inc. It was released as an arcade game worldwide in July 2001, having first been unveiled in Europe in 2000. Due to various gameplay alterations, Tekken 4 is the least liked game in the series according to many fans of the Tekken series.StoryTekken 4 takes place two years later from Tekken 3. Heihachi and his scientists has captured some of Ogre's blood to make Heihachi immortal. SInce Hehachi lacks the Devil Gene, the project fails. Heihachi finds his grandson, Jin Kazama, who posseses the Devil Gene, Heihachi studies his body and is stored in the labs of the Mishima Zaibatsu's main business rival called G Corporation.Heihachi sends his Tekken forces to raid G Corporation and find Kazuya's body, but the mission fails since the force got wiped out by Kazuya himself. Kazuya was revived by G Corporation after the events of Tekken 2 and is stronger then he was ever was.In a desperate attempt to get Jin and Kazuya out, Heihachi announces The King of Iron Fist Tournament 4.GameplayTekken 4 introduces a significant new gameplay changes from the previous Tekken games. For the first time, players are able to maneuver around an arena and interact with walls and other things for extra damage. This new feature allows players to juggle with their opponent for consecutive combos. Position changes and moving before the fight starts were also introduced in Tekken 4, but later removed in future iterations. The game also introduces a brand new graphics system, that had increased lightning, smoother surfaces, and dynamic physics. Tekken 4 brings back "Tekken Force" a beat 'em up minigame with enhanced new features. It was first introduced in Tekken 3. Players were also allowed to maneuver their opponents around during a match but pressing the left punch and right punch simultaniously along with a respective directional button, this was taken out in tekken 5 and given to Steve Fox as a special throw.Character RosterReturning CharactersMarshall LawPaul PhoenixKing llBryan FuryYoshimitsuNina WilliamsKuma Jr.Kazuya MishimaHeihachi MishimaLee ChaolanLei WulongHwoarangLing XiaoyuEddy GordoPandaNew CharactersSteve FoxCraig MardukChristie MonteiroCombotMiharu HiranoVioletAwardsE3 2002 Game Critics Awards: Best Fighting Game.It was also nominated for Best Fighting Game of 2002 at GameSpot.SoundtrackDisc 1Track 1 Fist for a Fist 2:06Track 2 Acid Timpani 0:41Track 3 Jet 1:18Track 4 Fetus 2:26Track 5 Uninhabited 3:20Track 6 Didgerhythm 6:24Track 7 Authentic Sky 4:55Track 8 Mob 3:28Track 9 Kitsch 3:49Track 10 Quadra Introduction 0:07Track 11 Quadra 2:08Track 12 Bit Crusher 4:47Track 13 Fear 4:24Track 14 Gym 4:21Track 15 Touch and Go 2:56Track 16 The Inner Shrine 4:31Track 17 Wirepuller Appearance 0:25Track 18 The Strongest Iron Arena 2:34Track 19 Nothingness 2:24Track 20 Lights 1:51Track 21 Hex 3:03Disc 2Track 1 Draw the Waveform 2:01Track 2 Heihachi Mishima 1:19Track 3 Craig Marduk 1:00Track 4 Julia Chang 1:53Track 5 Christie Monteiro 0:48Track 6 Ling Xiaoyu 2:24Track 7 Steve Fox 1:10Track 8 Kuma 0:33Track 9 Kazuya Mishima 3:29Track 10 Yoshimitsu 1:00Track 11 Combot 0:43Track 12 Bryan Fury 1:41Track 13 Lei Wulong 0:52Track 14 Jin Kazama 2:37Track 15 Lee Chaolan 0:50Track 16 Hwoarang 1:15Track 17 Marshall law 1:19Track 18 Paul Phoenix 1:09Track 19 Panda 1:08Track 20 Nina Williams 1:20Track 21 King 1:00</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7792">Dead or Alive 4</game><game id="707">Virtua Fighter 5</game><game id="15532">Urban Reign</game><game id="2895">Battle Arena Toshinden 3</game><game id="10651">Mortal Kombat: Unchained</game><game id="20678">Soulcalibur IV</game><game id="3839">Dead or Alive</game><game id="3760">Street Fighter: The Movie</game><game id="9603">Star Wars: Masters of Teräs Käsi</game><game id="4313">Virtua Fighter 4</game><game id="4891">Virtua Fighter 4: Evolution</game><game id="19043">Fighters Megamix</game><game id="2045">Dead or Alive 2</game><game id="15584">Virtua Fighter</game><game id="22292">Dead or Alive 2: Hardcore</game><game id="11065">Shaman King: Power of Spirit</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="16842">Street Fighter: Anniversary Collection</game><game id="13753">Dead or Alive Ultimate</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="23220">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja</game><game id="22519">Naruto: Uzumaki Chronicles 2</game><game id="23007">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja Heroes</game><game id="21582">Naruto Shippuuden: Gekitou Ninja Taisen! EX 2</game><game id="10126">X-Men: Next Dimension</game><game id="9855">Soulcalibur III</game><game id="5206">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai</game><game id="21195">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai Tenkaichi 3</game><game id="13875">Plasma Sword: Nightmare of Bilstein</game><game id="21277">Ultimate Mortal Kombat</game><game id="22305">Street Fighter III: 2nd Impact</game><game id="35032">Kinnikuman Muscle Grand Prix Max 2: Tokumori</game><game id="866">Kakuto Chojin: Back Alley Brutal</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2114382-box_tekken4.png</image></root>