<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14714</id><name>Half-Life 2: Deathmatch</name><description>OverviewHalf-life 2: Deathmatch is a 3D multiplayer first-person shooter developed and released by Valve for the PC (via Steam) on November 30, 2004. Set in the Half-Life 2 universe, the game uses many of the original game's assets and pits players together in simple deathmatch.In addition, the game includes a themed "team deathmatch" variant based on the factions in the game's story (the Combine forces against the human resistance).WeaponsMost of the weapons from Half-Life 2 return in this game with the same functionality (including their respective alternate firing mechanisms). New to the series is a stun baton (the Stunstick) and a satchel charge (the S.L.A.M.).Gravity Gun - Formally known as the Zero Point Energy Field Manipulator, the Gravity Gun is the game's default weapon and is automatically given to all players. Players can use it to pick up and throw objects (including filing cabinets, toilets, and enemy grenades) at other players. Primary fire sends a blast that knocks objects in front of the player (including one that's picked up) while alternate fire attracts objects, picks them up, or sets down picked-up objects gently.Crowbar - A standard crowbar (Gordon Freeman's signature weapon in the Half-Life series) that is automatically given to all players in the Deathmatch mode and all Rebel players in Team Deathmatch mode.Stunstick - A standard stun baton that is automatically given to all Combine players in Team Deathmatch mode. Has a slower swing than the Crowbar, but deals almost double damage per hit.9mm Pistol - A standard fast-firing semi-automatic pistol that is given to all players. Despite being accurate, having a high ammo capacity, and having a fast firing speed, it deals significantly low damage (with the exception of headshots).SMG - A standard fast-firing MP7 sub-machine gun that is given to all players. Despite its low damage-per-shot, it has the highest rate-of-fire in the game and a high ammo capacity. Alternate fire tosses a small, but powerful impact grenade (which must be collected prior to firing, with a grenade capacity of 3) from the weapon..357 Magnum - A powerful revolver that has a slow firing rate and very small ammo capacity. Can one-hit-kill on headshots.Pulse Rifle - Formally known as the Overwatch Standard Issue Pulse Rifle, the Pulse Rifle is a pulse-powered Combine assault rifle that deals more damage than the SMG (despite its lower ammo capacity and firing rate). Alternate fire fires a large Energy Ball (which must be collected prior to firing, with an ammo capacity of 3) that bounces off surfaces and vaporizes enemy players before exploding.Shotgun - A standard SPAS-12 pump-action shotgun that is powerful at short-to-medium range. Alternate fire has the weapon firing twice in quick successionCrossbow - A powerful bolt-firing crossbow that is very effective in distant ranges, but is very hard to use (due to its very low ammo capacity, very slow reloading speed, and slow projectile speed of the bolt). Alternate fire toggles the weapon's scope, allowing players to zoom-in on their targets.Grenade - A standard (yet powerful) timed grenade that explodes several seconds after being thrown (via primary fire) or dropped (via alternate fire). Two grenades are given to all players as they spawn, with a maximum grenade capacity of 5.RPG - A very powerful rocket-propelled grenade launcher with a laser-guidance system (toggled with the alternate fire button) that allows players to steer the rocket towards the laser's destination. Has a maximum rocket capacity of 3.S.L.A.M. - A multi-purpose satchel charge (formally known as the Selectable Lightweight Attack Munition) that doubles as both a laser trip mine and a remotely-detonated explosive (which is detonated by the alternate fire button). Despite its lower blast radius than the other explosive weapons, it has the highest damage output. Has a maximum ammo capacity of 5.System RequirementsPC System RequirementsMinimum:1.2 GHz Processor256MB RAMDirectX速 7 level Graphics CardWindows速 XPMouseKeyboardInternet ConnectionRecommended:2.4 GHz Processor512MB RAMDirectX速 9 level Graphics CardWindows速 XPMouseKeyboardInternet ConnectionMac System RequirementsMinimum:OS X version Leopard 10.5.8Snow Leopard 10.6.31GB RAMNVIDIA GeForce 8 or higher, ATI X1600 or higher or Intel HD 3000 or higherMouseKeyboardInternet Connection</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3874">Quake III Arena</game><game id="13286">Unreal Tournament 2004</game><game id="32956">GoldenEye: Source</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2491505-box_hl2dm.png</image></root>