<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14759</id><name>Two Worlds</name><description>StoryTwo Worlds begins with our Nameless Protagonist escorting his wounded sister, Krya, to receive medical attention. However, on the way they are intercepted by a stranger who kidnaps Kyra after overpowering our hero. In order to rescue his kin, the Hero is asked to gather several key relics from various dangerous locales scattered throughout Antaloor. According to Antaloor lore, when the various pieces of the relic are assembled a gate to the other world will be opened. Once opened, this gate will allow the crossing of a horrible evil into our world. The main character and his sister share a telepathic-type bond which allows them to communicate with each other when the main character stands in certain locales. This eventually leads to the revelation of various plot points which fuel your motivation to retrieve the artifacts and rescue your sister, despite her wishes.During the game, it's revealed that your ancestors are actually the guardians of the gate to the other world, and were the ones responsible for sealing away an evil God named Aziraal. In order to ensure that the gate remained closed, the key was split into various pieces and given to important members of the family who participated in the event. Being a descendant of those who banished Aziraal, only our hero and his sister are capable of using the key to open the gate.GameplayTwo Worlds is an action-RPG base in an open-world medieval-fantasy setting, similar to games in the Gothic series. Players can fight with a wide range of melee weapons, bows, and can use magic for both offensive/defensive fighting. The player progresses through the game by completing a series of quests, and can also engage in a number of side-quests. Upon defeating enemies and completing quests, the player earns experience points that go towards leveling up. There is also an alchemy system in the game for creating potions.CombatCombat in Two Worlds is real-time, and the player can choose to participate in one or all of three basic methods of combat: Melee, projectile, and magic. There is a wide range of melee weapons, including swords, daggers, halberds, spears, hammers, clubs, staves, and so on. Weapons can do one or more physical types of damage (bludgeon, slash, and piercing) as well as do various types of magic damage. Some enemies are more susceptible to one damage type versus another. The player can also learn skills as they level up that allow them to perform special melee attacks, or give them melee abilities such as dual-wielding single-handed weapons.Non-magic projectile combat is limited to bows and arrows. Bows and arrows do not come in a set, allowing the player to have a bow with one set of attributes, and arrows with another. Projectile weapons can perform the same types of damage as melee weapons, and special skills can be learned to allow the player to gain an advantage over enemies when using a bow.The players can choose dozens of spells from multiple schools of magic to use in combat that can range from performing damage to enemies, or causing status ailments or other impediments. Some offensive spells only target one enemy, while others can target multiple enemies. Others simply summon a creature to fight with you for a certain amount of time. There are also mage-staves that can be used as melee weapons, but primarily are used to give the player a boost in ability.Defense comes in the form of equipment such as armor, robes, and shields. There are also spells and potions (either found or made through alchemy) that provide protection, or improve the player's stats either temporarily or permanently.LootingTwo Worlds places a large focus on collecting loot. There are hundreds of different weapons, sets of armor, spells, and miscellaneous items to be taken off of enemies in the game, and even more things to be found in chests either in the open gameworld, or in people's homes (these usually require a lock-pick). On top of the large number of things to find, many items are also stackable; two of the same item can be combined into a better version of that item. Weapons, magic spells, armor, and stat-increasing rings are all stackable.LevelingAs a character gains experience, they level up and gain skill points that can enable and increase various skills related to combat, defense, and magic. The character also gains attribute points that can be used to increase their base stats. If the player ever regrets their use of stat or attribute points, there are NPC's in most major cities that will remove points from various stats and skills, allowing the player to reallocate them any way they desire.The World: AntaloorThe world of Antaloor is a huge microcosm, from snowy glaciers and highland forests in the north, to smolderingAntaloor!volcanoes and deserts in the south, the world is extremely varied. The continent is separated in two by the river Gon, and the climates between are completely opposite. There are many settlements and cities in Antaloor, but many have seen better times. Dotted all around the map are teleports and shrines, making travel--and death--a non issue in most cases.Many species inhabit the world of Antaloor. Simple wildlife such as bears and wolves are what the hero will mostly encounter, but there are many more dangerous creatures and monsters out there, even demons and dragons!Monsters and RacesA GromGroms"These wild barbarian tribes are a threat to the life of travelers throughout Antaloor. As fighters, the Groms can’t compare to the warlike Orcs, but many who made the mistake of underestimating them are now in the spirit world." Groms are typically low level enemies, that provide little threat in the long run. They carry barbaric weapons that amount to little value...however, they do use bows that are unique. Many Groms specialize as shamans practicing the art of fire magic, to little effect, however.OrcsAn Orc"This proud warrior race probably suffered more from the effects of the Great War than any of the other races. The banishment of the rebel-god Aziraal by the other gods not only deprived them of their warlord - they also lost faith in their own fighting abilities and the Orcs were almost entirely wiped out." Orcs could be considered "tougher" Groms, and play a large role throughout the game.Special EditionsAlong with the standard edition of the game two other special editions were released as well, the collector's edition and the royal edition. The collector's edition of Two Worlds comes with a paper map of the overworld which details locations of shrines, graveyards, caves etc. and a DVD of special features which includes some concept art, music and some brief 'making of' videos. It also comes with the rulebook for the pen-and-paper RPG that the Two Worlds video game is based on. The royal edition of Two Worlds comes with a t-shirt, playing cards, a two-sided poster, a letter opener (only in the Windows version), and the DVD from the collector's edition.PC System RequirementsMinimumRecommendedOS: Windows XP SP2 / Vista (32 bit only)Processor: 2.0GHz Intel Pentium IV (Equivalent or higher)Memory: 512MB RAMHDD: 5.0GB free hard disk spaceVideo Card: DirectX 9.0c compatible 128MB with shader 2.0 support (or higher)Sound Card: DirectX 9.0c compatible 16-bit sound cardDVD-ROM, Keyboard, MouseProcessor: 3.0GHz Intel Pentium IV (Equivalent or higher)Memory: 1GB RAMVideo Card: DirectX 9.0c compatible 256MB with shader 3.0 support(NVIDIA GeForce 7 Series or ATI X1300 PRO or above)Xbox 360 Game InstallationTwo Worlds requires 3.4GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1804">Gothic II</game><game id="16927">Gothic II: Night of the Raven</game><game id="1982">Gothic</game><game id="20238">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion</game><game id="1727">Dungeon Siege II</game><game id="21505">Project Offset</game><game id="11142">Final Fantasy XI Online</game><game id="7753">Gothic 3</game><game id="21846">Gothic 3 : Forsaken Gods</game><game id="3264">Fable</game><game id="2092">Fable: The Lost Chapters</game><game id="10473">The Witcher</game><game id="14565">Dungeon Lords</game><game id="20621">Viking: Battle for Asgard</game><game id="23139">Divinity II: Ego Draconis</game><game id="12107">Baldur's Gate: Dark Alliance II</game><game id="10637">Baldur's Gate II: Shadows of Amn</game><game id="20901">Sacred 2: Fallen Angel</game><game id="21365">Rise of the Argonauts</game><game id="24057">Demon's Souls</game><game id="33129">Divinity II: The Dragon Knight Saga</game><game id="25313">Venetica</game><game id="23796">Arcania: Gothic 4</game><game id="27878">Fable III</game><game id="23317">Overlord II</game><game id="21864">Overlord</game><game id="27218">Two Worlds II</game><game id="20718">Dungeon Siege III</game><game id="28178">The Witcher 2: Assassins of Kings</game><game id="33149">Risen 2: Dark Waters</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1814909-box_tworlds.png</image></root>