<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14786</id><name>WCW vs. nWo: World Tour</name><description>ABOUT THE GAMEWCW vs. NWO: World Tour is the first in a line of wrestling games developed for the Nintendo 64 that was developed by AKI Corporation and published by THQ, it is the sequel to the PS-one game WCW vs the World, and the sequel WCW/NWO Revenge was the second and last WCW game for the Nintendo 64, followed by WWF WrestleMania 2000 once the WWF license had expired from Acclaim, and finally WWF No Mercy. Each game shows a huge progression from the last, and probably makes the Nintendo 64 the console of choice for any wrestling fan of the era, and still considered by many as the best era in wrestling games and wrestling too, the “Attitude” Era.AKI also developed two games in Japan Virtual Pro Wrestling 64 and Virtual Pro Wrestling 2.GAME MODESWCW VS NWO - 5 vs. 5 Elimination style match pitting only WCW vs. NWOExhibition - Featuring 1 vs. 1, 2 vs 2 Tag Team match, 2 vs. 1 Handicap Match and Battle Royal 4 player elimination matchLeague Challenge - Main single player mode where player competes against all wrestlers from the four Promotions to unlock hidden leagues and wrestlersLeague - Round Robin style league for for up to eight singles wrestlers or Tag Teams to compete against each other inTournament - Knock out tournament for up to eight singles wrestlers or Tag TeamsGAMEPLAYWCW vs. NWO has a very simple combat system, based on the Fire Pro Wrestling series. Grapple moves are performed by using a strong or light grapple, performed by holding down the A button or tapping it. Also, a strong or light strike can be performed by holding the B button down or tapping it.Once in a grapple, a move can be executed by pressing the A or B buttons, either with the D-pad in the neutral position or a combination of up and down being pressed, offering a wide variety of moves that could be executed.Also in a grapple, the opponent can be "whipped" towards the ropes or turnbuckle using the Left-C button. Upon bouncing off the ropes and returning to the player, either variant of the grapple or strike could be executed. In the turnbuckle, much like with standard grapples, up and down on the D-pad with a press of either A or B will execute different maneuvers.Players can run using the left-C button and perform a running strike by pressing the B button. Also running into the turnbuckle will cause your wrestler to climb up it and releasing the button would perform a diving attack, depending on the position of your opponent and if they were standing or lying. With certain wrestlers it is also possible to dive out of the ring by pressing A at the correct time while running at the ropes as your opponent is outside.Taunting was also controlled by the use of the analog stick by pushing it in any direction, allowing you to raise your spirit meter. Once raising the meter to maximum it flashes with the word SPECIAL, giving you a limited time to perform the wrestlers special attack, which is often the wrestler's signature finishing maneuver. This is done by a strong grapple either from the front or rear of the opponent and tapping a direction of the analog stick.Over the course of the game series AKI further refined the control scheme, improving it with each passing game and offering a wider range of moves and ways that can be done by the time they finally released WWF No Mercy.ROSTERWCWChris BenoitRic FlairEddie GuerreroLex LugerDean MalenkoRick SteinerScott SteinerStingUltimo DragonRey Mysterio Jr.Steven RegalDiamond Dallas Page - HiddennWo"Hollywood" HoganScott HallKevin NashSyxxEric BischoffnWo StingBuff BagwellScott Norton"Macho Man" Randy Savage - HiddenDOASumo JoeKim CheeBlackheartPuchtecaHannibalPowder KegDim SumSaladinAli BabaWrath - HiddenIndependent UnionBlack NinjaShaolinThe UnknownThe ClawBlack BeltPacoLocoShamanMaster FujiGlacier - HiddenWhole World WrestlingJoe Bruiser - HiddenBlack Widow - Hidden</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="3">Sports</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3667">WWF Wrestlemania 2000</game><game id="18801">WWF War Zone</game><game id="21620">WWE Day of Reckoning 2</game><game id="26888">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2010</game><game id="9216">Power Move Pro Wrestling</game><game id="30637">Lucha Libre AAA Heroes del Ring</game><game id="13440">Backyard Wrestling: Don't Try This at Home</game><game id="18333">Backyard Wrestling 2: There Goes the Neighborhood</game><game id="31640">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2011</game><game id="28430">WWF Royal Rumble</game><game id="557">WCW vs. the World</game><game id="23213">Virtual Pro Wrestling 2: Ōdō Keishō</game><game id="11394">WWF No Mercy</game><game id="23212">Virtual Pro Wrestling 64</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2409919-box_wcwnwowt.png</image></root>