<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1483</id><name>Mega Man X Collection</name><description>Mega Man XStoryFront CoverThe first in the X series, Mega Man X is also the first game to introduce Zero. Set many years after the original Mega Man series, the world is populated by many robots that interact with the humans. A man named Dr. Cain, during an investigative dig, discovers a capsule containing " X", as well as instructions for the opening of the capsule, written by none other than Dr. Light, the creator of the original Mega Man! Dr. Cain opens the capsule, releasing X from his many years of containment, and he realizes that X is much more than an average robot. He has true Artificial Intelligence.Using X as his inspiration, Dr. Cain creates robots, classified as Reploids. Not too long afterwards, a virus infects many of these Reploids, and causes them to turn Maverick, killing humans and destroying towns. The strongest of the Mavericks, Sigma, rallies all of the other Mavericks together to take over the world.Now, to combat these new menaces to the world, X, along with the enigmatic Zero, band together to defeat Sigma and his minions.General InfoMega Man X is the first Mega Man game to feature ZeroFirst Mega Man game to feature a wall slide/wall jump moveFirst Mega Man game released on the SNES ( Mega Man 7, while continuing the original series, came out a year later)Features an Upgrade system, featuring capsules that you walk into in order to unlock an upgrade to a particular part of X's body.Features a secret upgrade capsule that unlocks the Hadouken move for X's use. It is a one hit kill attack, as well.First Mega Man game to feature a charge system that not only applies to the Mega Buster, but also all of the weapons that X acquires from the bosses.Robot Masters (Maverick Reploids)Armored ArmadilloBoomer Kuwanger (later renamed to Boomerang Kuwanger)Chill PenguinFlame MammothLaunch OctopusStorm EagleSpark MandrillSting ChameleonSigma's Fortress Boss RobotsVileBospiderRangda BangdaD-RexSigma's DogSigmaVelgauder SigmaMega Man X2Robot Mastersfront coverBubble CrabCrystal SnailFlame StagMagna CentipedeMorph MothOverdrive OstrichWheel GatorWire SpongeOther Boss RobotsViolenSergesAgileZeroSigmaHolograph SigmaFeaturesFeatures a secret capsule to allow X to learn the Shoryuken, which, like the Hadouken, is also an OHKO.Mega Man X3Robot Mastersfront coverBlast HornetBlizzard BuffaloCrush CrawfishGravity BeetleNeon TigerToxic SeahorseTunnel RhinoVolt CatfishOther Boss RobotsMac (Zero only)Moah the GiantBitByteVileGodkarmachine O InaryPress DisposerVile Mk-2Vile KuragielDr. DopplerSigmaKaiser SigmaSigma VirusFeaturesThis is the first game to feature Zero as a Playable Character (albeit hidden for most of the game)This is also the first game to allow X to limit the number of upgrades he can receive in one playthrough (the diverse upgrades can be used all at once by finding a secret amour.)Mega Man X4Playable CharactersMega Man XZeroRobot Mastersfront coverMagma DragoonFrost WalrusJet StingraySlash BeastWeb SpiderSplit MushroomCyber PeacockStorm OwlOther Boss RobotsColonelDoubleIrisGeneralSigmaSigma part 2Sigma's Final FormMega Man X5Playable CharactersMega Man XZeroRobot Mastersfront coverGrizzly SlashDuff McWhalenSquid AdlerIzzy GlowDark DizzyMattrexAxle the RedThe SkiverIt should be noted that the above localized names of the bosses in Megaman X5 were all based off of the names of members of the American rock band Guns N' Roses. Grizzly Slash represents the lead guitarist, Slash. Duff McWhalen represents the bassist Duff McKagan. Squid Adler is based off of the original drummer Steven Adler, who drummed on the Appetite For Destruction album. Izzy Glow represents Izzy Stradlin the rhythm guitarist. Dark Dizzy represents Dizzy Reed, the keyboardist brought on for the Use Your Illusion tours. Mattrex represents Matt Sorum, the drummer that replaced Adler and played on the Use Your Illusion I  II albums. Axle the Red represents Axl Rose, the lead singer for the band. It should also be noted that Axle the Red is also a rose.Other Boss RobotsSigmaDynamoShadow DevilRangda Bangda IIMaverick Zero/Mega Man X (Depends on who you are playing as.)Sigma part 2Sigma's Final FormMega Man X6Megaman X6 continues the story after X5, with the space colony crash of Eurasia. After the battle with Sigma, X is alone, with Zero assumed to be dead and X investigates a "Zero Nightmare" that has recently been plaguing the Earth. Armed with his old comrade's sabre, he searches for the Nightmare.Playable CharactersMega Man XZeroRobot Mastersfront coverCommander YammarkGround ScaravichBlaze HeatnixBlizzard WolfangRainy TurtloidMetal Shark PlayerShield SheldonI nfinity MijinionOther Boss RobotsGiant MechaniloidZero Nightmare (For X Only)High MaxDynamoNightmare KingGateSigmaSigma's Final FormMega Man Battle  ChaseThe first 3-D Mega Man game ever made, Mega Man Battle  Chase was never released in the United States. More comparable to Mario Kart than any other Mega Man game, this is a racing game through-and-through. After defeating any other competitor, you can pick a part of their vehicle that you want to keep for yourself. If you beat them enough times, you can earn their entire vehicle for use.There are a total of 12 playable characters. Wily and Duo both need to be unlocked.Playable CharactersMega ManProto ManRollBassDr. WilyDuoGuts ManIce ManQuick ManShadow ManNapalm ManSpring Man</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6141">Mega Man Anniversary Collection</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2525217-box_mmxc.png</image></root>