<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1490</id><name>Dragon Ball Z: Ultimate Battle 22</name><description>OverviewDragon Ball Z: Ultimate Battle 22 is a 2D fighting game developed and published by Bandai for the PlayStation in Japan (on July 28, 1995) and Europe (on July 1996). It was later released in North America by Atari on March 25, 2003. The sequel to 1994 game Dragon Ball Z: Super Butōden 3 (for the SNES), Dragon Ball Z: Ultimate Battle 22 features 2D character sprites (in similar vein to the animated series) on 3D backgrounds.The "22" in the game's name is due to the fact that the game features 22 playable characters from the Dragon Ball Z franchise on the start (and the player can unlock 5 more, which changes the title to Dragon Ball Z: Ultimate Battle 27).Most of the character assets were re-used in the Saturn sequel, Dragon Ball Z: Shin Butōden.GameplayUltimate Battle 22 is a 2D fighting game. This game resembles mechanics from earlier Dragon Ball Z games for the Super Famicom. Each character has an array of standard and special techiques, and is also capable of flight; however, the ability to fly has no actual effect on the gameplay.Game Modes1P Versus COMThe standard mode, in which the player picks a character and battles randomly selected AI opponents.1P Versus 2PA standard one-on-one versus mode.Build UpA mode in which the player chooses a character to level up, extending the character's life bar.Playable CharactersGokuGohanVegetaFuture TrunksCellAndroid 16Android 18FriezaZarbonRecoomeCaptain GinyuDaburaGotenKid TrunksSupreme KaiMajin Buu(Good)Super BuuSuper Saiyan GotenksGreat SaiyamanKrillinTienPiccoloUnlockable CharactersGogetaHerculeMaster RoshiSuper Saiyan 3 GokuKid Goku</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12411">Soulcalibur</game><game id="11065">Shaman King: Power of Spirit</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1814883-box_dbzub22.png</image></root>