<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>14929</id><name>Real Bout Fatal Fury 2: The Newcomers</name><description>Overview Real Bout Fatal Fury 2: The Newcomers (known in Japan as Real Bout Garou Densetsu 2: The Newcomers) is a fighting game developed and published by                       SNK for the                      Neo Geo. The game features new graphics (such as backgrounds) and two new characters:                     Li Xiangfei and  Rick Strowd, while reverting the two-plane system of                    Real Bout Fatal Fury Special back to a modified version of the "oversway" system of                   Real Bout Fatal Fury (with two planes instead of three).                  Geese Howard returns as a playable character, with Alfred Airhawk from the                 PlayStation version of Real Bout Fatal Fury Special entering as a secret boss. The one-line hazard stages from                Fatal Fury Special also return. Before two-player matches, players can determine if they want a two-line or one-line stage. The game was also released for the               Neo Geo CD and the              Fatal Fury Battle Archives Volume 2 compilation for the             PlayStation 2. The game was also ported to the            Neo Geo Pocket Color under the title Fatal Fury: First Contact. Characters                                        Terry Bogard                                      Andy Bogard                                     Joe Higashi                                    Mai Shiranui                                   Kim Kaphwan                                  Billy Kane                                 Duck King                                Blue Mary                               Ryuji Yamazaki                              Jin Chonshu                             Jin Chonrei        Sokaku Mochizuki                            Bob Wilson       Hon-Fu      Franco Bash                           Tung Fu Rue                          Cheng Sinzan     Laurence Blood                         Wolfgang Krauser                         Li Xiangfei     Rick Strowd                        Geese Howard   Alfred Airhawk (secret boss, only playable in PS2 version)Lao (only in the versus mode in NGPC version)</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21344">Hokuto no Ken: Shinpan no Sousousei Kengou Retsuden</game><game id="8867">Art of Fighting 3: The Path of The Warrior</game><game id="10827">World Heroes Perfect</game><game id="14669">Virtua Fighter Animation</game><game id="3744">Def Jam: Fight for NY</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1408746-rbfatalfury2_box.jpg</image></root>