<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15024</id><name>Cool Boarders 2</name><description>The focus remains to race down the hills in the fastest possible time. However, UEP took a giant leap forward by adding trick competitions and other computer controlled racers to compete against. The game has 7 snowboarders and a total of 11 courses.ModesFreestyleAs the name suggests, in this mode you traverse a course anyway you want. Whether that means pulling off tricks off of every jump, racing your way for a record time, or a mixture of both. Scoring in freestyle mode involves tricks performed, wipeouts, and time.HalfpipeIn Halfpipe mode, the player goes down a halfpipe trying to rack up as many points as possible utilizing various tricks. The scoring is based on the tricks performed.BIg AirThis mode acts like a ski jump, where scoring is based on the maximum distance and rotation achieved. Additionally, pulling off some grabs during the jump allows for points to be achieved.CompetitionThis mode allows for split-screen play and the chance to compete against A.I. in the three previously mentioned modes.Board ParkSimilar to Freestyle mode, but the track tends to be easier and there is no scoring.TracksWhite ResortSunset DownhillBear in the ForestRailroad TripTake It EasyPipeline CanyonFreezing PointWinding RiverSnow RuinsDive into the CaveCharactersCharacters are rated based on their Jump, Balance, Technique, Quickness, Power, and Maximum Speed stats.YaggiJinCindyIrinBossSnowmanGray</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="33">Snowboarding/Skiing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21727">MTV Sports: Snowboarding</game><game id="16640">Rippin' Riders</game><game id="31945">Phat Air: Extreme Snowboarding</game><game id="30947">Tony Hawk: SHRED</game><game id="5510">X-Games: Pro Boarder</game><game id="12112">Cool Boarders</game><game id="42370">R: Rock'n Riders</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/6843/1897798-cool_boarders_2_box_art.jpg</image></root>