<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1503</id><name>Aliens Versus Predator 2</name><description>OverviewAliens versus Predator 2 is the sequel to the first person shooter Aliens versus Predator. Developed by Monolith, the sequel takes the core gameplay concepts of the first game and creates a detailed interwoven story between all three species, rather than three separate unrelated stories for each race like in the first game. The Alien campaign lets you strike terror in your prey as you crawl on walls and pounce at your enemies. The Predator has all the weapons and abilities you can imagine, like the cloaking ability and the Plasmacaster. The Marine campaign, while the most familiar from a gameplay stand point, provides plenty of tension and scares as you play a lone Marine facing hundreds of Xenomorphs coming from every direction.CampaignsBack storyThere are key events involving characters in the game that set up the conflict in Aliens versus Predator 2. 19 years before the start of the game, Vasili Rykov and his team of Colonial Marines are ambushed by a Predator hunting party on the planet Korari. Rykov survived the ordeal, but not without suffering paralysis from a plasma caster shot. After undergoing an experimental procedure that replaced his spine, which requires black market narcotics for him to function properly, Rykov has harbored a deep hatred for the Predators.A year before the game, Dr. Eisenburg was the survivor of the first expedition to LV-1201, which went horribly wrong. Dr. Eisenburg was left wounded by acid blood, and it is presumed that he resorted to cannibalism to survive (there’s blood on his hands and mouth). Much like Rykov’s experience with the Predators, Eisenburg harbors a deep hatred and fear for the Xenomorphs. Yet he chooses to return to LV-1201 and continue studying the species and their hive structure.Shortly before the events of the main game, Observation Pod 5 is destroyed, causing setbacks for the research team on LV-1201. The event is briefly mentioned at the start of the Alien campaign, and the story behind the destruction of Pod 5 is revealed in Aliens versus Predator 2: Primal Hunt.MarineCorporal Harrison is the main character in the Marine campaign. A very calm soldier, even in heated situations, he’s nicknamed “Frosty” by his team, and is often on his own during the game. For reasons that range from understandable to contrived, Harrison receives next to no back up as he fights Xenomorphs, the Iron Bears, and a Predator within a day’s time on LV-1201.---Unwelcome GuestsDate: January 06, 2231Time: 05:25 AMIncident: +6 Weeks, 0.25 hoursMission Time: 0.25 hoursLocation: Approaching Primary Operations Complex (POC)---The USS Verloc is en route to the planet LV-1201 to investigate an incident with the planet’s POC and Forward Observation Pods, which lost contact with Weyland-Yutani six weeks prior. The Marines on board are under staffed and lacking supplies, but are still sent to secure the facilities. Two dropships are deployed, but hurricane winds cause Johnson to fly off course and crash Dropship One. Major McCain splits up his marines into teams, sending Blackwell, Shugi, and Harrison towards the Primary Operations Complex.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix G – Major McCain’s Log.Hard landing. Dropship has sustained minor damage. Contact lost with Dropship Two and White Team. We’ll need the landing beacons on-line at the Northern Landing before I’ll feel safe enough to order Johnson airborne again. That means Hall’s team is headed to restore the power core. Blackwell’s boys will make for the landing. There’s just three of them, but Harrison’s been lucky for me in the past. They call him Frosty for a reason. Cool under pressure.On their way to the Northern Landing, Harrison gets separated from Blackwell and Shugi after running a bypass on a door. The Marine’s lose communication with Harrison, but he can still hear them over the feed. The team can only assume that he’s alive. As Harrison continues on his own, he sees escaped convict laborers being killed by an unseen creature. Unusual readings appear briefly on the motion tracker. After crossing a bridge and heading up hill, Harrison reaches the entrance to the Primary Operations Complex, being greeted by skinned bodies hanging upside down.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix G – Major McCain’s Log.Situation bad. Getting worse. Blackwell’s team tripped some sort of booby trap. Harrison was inside, but I think he’s alive. His A/V feeds are down, but his life signs are still coming through. I’m hoping he can still hear me on the radio. Bottom line is we’re cut off from the landing now, so it’s up to him to get the beacon up and wave us home. He’d better hurry too. We’re getting ghost readings on the motion trackers. Something’s out there – and I think it’s hunting us.Harrison reaches the Northern Landing of the POC, and proceeds to turn on the auxiliary generator. With the power on for the area, Harrison heads inside the complex to activate the landing beacon. The beacon is activated, and the dropship lands. Major McCain’s sends Harrison back inside to turn on the POC’s automated defenses. Harrison grabs a grenade launcher and heads inside the complex.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix G – Major McCain’s Log.If I survive, I’m recommending Harrison for a medal. He pulled through for us – landing beacon and all. Unfortunately, security is still down. Until we restore the security, this dropship feels like a breached whale waiting for the gulls to feed. Good news, if you call it that, the plans show a security station on sub-level three – ten minutes run. Bad news is that I can’t spare the manpower. If we lose this dropship, no one goes home. I hate to even send one soldier, but security isn’t coming on by itself. Let’s hope Harrison is a good fast runner.Harrison proceeds inside the POC and finds the place trashed and in disarray. Dim lights are flickering and there are holes burnt away in the floor. Harrison reaches the security station and runs a bypass on the system. With the automated systems back online, movement appears on the motion tracker. A Xenomorph drops down from the ceiling and another bursts through a ventilation shaft. A hive of Aliens awoke, and Harrison proceeds to get out of there. As Harrison makes his retreat, he steals a company APC and drives off to regroup with his fellow Marines.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix G – Major McCain’s Log.The Op’s all wrong. Xenomorphs everywhere. Harrison woke them when he activated security. White team reports the southern landing is still pretty clean though, so we’re going airborne to meet them there. Johnson says the dropship can fly at least that far. That leaves Hall’s team, trapped. I told Harrison to come back, but the S.O.B. won’t listen. He’s gone after them in a corporate APC. If he survives, I’ll decide whether I write him up for insubordination. Big if.Harrison follows Sergeant Hall’s signal in order to save her, despite his team’s insistence. Harrison fights through swarms of Drones and Runners before reaching the POC’s hive. The Xenomorphs have cocooned Sergeant Hall inside within a mini egg chamber. Harrison finds Hall, but it is too late to save her as a Chestburster comes out of her body and kills her. Whether or not Harrison decides to kill her or let her die from the Chestburster, the Hive gets disturbed, and Harrison runs back to the APC, with dozens of Xenomorphs following closely behind.McCain’s LogBased on Harrison’s report, I have declared Sgt. Hall KIA as of eight-thirty two A.M. I will advance her name for a commendation. It feels like empty consolation. Soldiers shouldn’t die that way – torn apart from the inside.At least most of her team made it out, thanks to Harrison and his stolen APC. White team picked them up just beyond the POC perimeter and brought them back to the Southern Landing. We’ve dug in here, and the bugs have pulled back for now. So much for saving anyone here.---Collateral DamageDate: January 06, 2231Time: 06:55 AMIncident: +6 Weeks, 1.75 hoursMission Time: 1.75 hoursLocation: Road system leading from the Primary Complex to the Forward Observation Pods.---The Marines meet up outside the entrance to the tunnel connecting the POC and the Forward Pods. They can’t proceed through the gate, and Harrison is quick to volunteer to open the gate. Major McCain, having faith in Harrison’s abilities, agrees to send him first while the rest of the team waits inside the APC.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix G – Major McCain’s Log.Despite casualties, White Team has secured the Southern Landing. Clearly, there are no survivors here. The Forward Pods remain another question.Self-sufficient, if highly isolated, they could have survived. However, our attempts to contact them have failed. Either the landline is dead, or the Pods are. Either way, we’ll have to drive there – three hours by APC. Let’s hope the famed Dr. Eisenburg gives us a better greeting than our last.Harrison is outfitted with an Image Intensifier and enters a large maintenance tunnel next to the main entrance. Harrison makes it inside and opens the first security tunnel for the APC. The doors operate like an air lock system, so Harrison must go between each station sealing the doors behind the APC and opening the next one. Shortly after opening the first tunnel, Xenomorphs begin to attack the team. Harrison holds them off on his own, and the APC’s turret destroys any other Xenomorphs. Three Marines are killed inside the tunnel, and Harrison reaches the final security station. Harrison runs a bypass on the system, and the final door is opened. As a consequence for the Marine’s actions, the Forward Observation Pod’s defense grid becomes compromised, allowing a possible Xenomorph contamination.---BetrayalDate: January 06, 2231Time: 09:40 PMIncident: +6 Weeks, 16.50 hoursMission Time: 16.50 hoursLocation: Forward Observation Pods---The Marines arrive at the Forward Observation Pods, and the situation is bad for the people inside. Eisenburg and Rykov inform the Marines about their recent breach by the Xenomorphs and that their archeological team has been isolated. Major McCain offers his Marines for Eisenburg’s use, and sends Harrison inside to establish communication with the Verloc. When the Marines leave, Rykov speaks with his right-hand man Ivan about their plan to eliminate the Marines, starting with Harrison.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix G – Major McCain’s Log.The good news: we have found survivors. Dr. Eisenburg and his head of security, General Rykov greeted us on arrival – only they weren’t happy. Reportedly, Mother’s virus didn’t just take down the tunnel security. It also tore a hole in the Pod’s defense grid big enough for a herd of bugs to run through. They’ve had fatalities in the Pods and lost contact with a large archeological team – two dozen scientists and laborers. I’ve offered to assist, starting with getting Harrison to restore contact to the Verloc. We may be needing her cold sleep chambers – for emergency medical evacuation.Harrison attempts to establish a communication link with the Verloc and the Primary Operations Complex, but is unsuccessful. Major Dunya comes and escorts Harrison out of the terminal and knocks him out with the butt of her rifle. Harrison later wakes up in a holding cell with a convict. It’s not long until a security guard comes in to retrieve Harrison, but shoots the fellow convict when he is attacked. The convict dies, and Harrison pulls out his knife and kills the guard. He takes the guard’s pistol and escapes from the holding cell.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix C –Training Manual.Consider using convict labor when planning high-risk planetary developments. Contrary to popular legend, convict escape rates are uniformly low. Frankly, the convicts have nowhere to run, and given their steeply reduced penal terms, escapees are trading a few years of danger for a lifetime of incarceration. Naturally, escapes do occur – but seldom involving rational men. For this reason, escapees should be considered extremely dangerous. SOP is to terminate with prejudice.Harrison climbs up an elevator shaft, and the Pod security is on full alert, looking to apprehend Harrison and the single Xenomorph running loose through the Pods. As he goes up a few levels in the pods, Harrison finds a torch welder and a human getting facehugged. The Facehugger dies shortly after, and Harrison uses his welder to open up a hatch above.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix G – Major McCain’s Log.Rykov assures me that the Pod’s security has been restored, yet the personnel remains nervous and edgy. I also heard warning klaxons periodically and reports that Deck 24 has been sealed due to an ongoing contaminant. Rykov explained that this is normal procedure. The floors are evacuated and sealed until chemical treatments can be applied. No guards get hurt that way. Of course, this takes time. I pity the man who fails to get out in time. I can’t imagine being trapped in there with one of those things – not after what they did to Hall.As Harrison proceeds through the Pods, he sees signs of conflict in the halls, walls and floors covered in blood both human and Xenomorph. A scientist gets pulled underneath a door, and Harrison descends one level in the pods. The creature responsible is a single Predalien, who drops down from the ceiling and attacks Harrison. Harrison kills the creature, and then goes through more ventilation shafts as he tries to escape.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix G – Major McCain’s Log.Harrison is dead. Rykov’s lieutenant Dunya just delivered the news. In the aftermath of the bug attack, a convict laborer jumped a guard. Harrison walked straight into the fight. A flamethrower went off – then Harrison’s ammo belt.Somehow the convict survived. They are hunting him now. Dunya seemed especially intent on this. Obsessive almost. I shouldn’t blame her. From what Rykov said, she lost her fiancé when we took down the defense grid. I hope she finds the escaped S.O.B. and kills him. Maybe that will bring her some peace.Harrison arrives in a room with a Predator being held inside a stasis pod. He activates a console moving the tube and opening a shaft underneath. However, the stasis is shut off and the Predator inside is awoken. Security spots Harrison and makes a move on him. Harrison arrives inside a room holding hundreds of Facehuggers in stasis. A security camera spots Harrison, and a voice communicates with him. The person does not seem to be affiliated with the rest of the Pod security, and asks for Harrison to retrieve a piece of data “he” stashed away. In return for this favor, Harrison will receive help from this person. Harrison agrees, since he has no choice, and activates a conveyor belt and turns off the Facehugger containment cells. Harrison goes through two egg pits and shuts off the stasis pods. Harrison reaches an elevator and escapes from mess that’s been created.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix G – Major McCain’s Log.Ten minutes ago, Dr. Eisenburg’s team made limited contact with their missing team. They are alive, but isolated. Eisenburg’s team is drawing plans for their evacuation now; I’ve put my soldiers at his disposal. Still, I am uneasy. Our communications are limited to our own radio channels. The Pod comms are isolated and encrypted – to deter industrial espionage – says Eisenburg. Apparently they had problems with sabotage as well – as if I don’t have enough to worry about already.Harrison fights through a maze of hallways and security guards until he finds the package that he was sent to find. Harrison finds a hacking tool to let him bypass the pod security and finds a security card. With this card he takes it to the elevator at the other end of Core Access and finds a disc, the package the person sent Harrison to find. With the data in hand, Harrison returns to the main elevator heads down to the loading bay.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix A – Summary.McCain’s log is complete through his departure from the Pods and the commencement of Operation Savior. Their exact time of departure is unclear, but painfully evident that a difference of mere minutes would have meant the difference for the terms.Harrison fights through more security guards as he crosses the catwalks connecting the Pods, both on the inside and out. Harrison reaches the loading bay of Pod 4, and sees a massive hole blown in the side and hears radio chatter from a nearby dropship. Ivan, two Iron Bears and an Exosuit are the last enemies Harrison faces before he takes the lift down to the surface, after grabbing some new Marine gear from the bay.---A Long DetourDate: January 06, 2231Time: 11:10 PMIncident: +6 Weeks, 18.00 hoursMission Time: 18.00 hoursLocation: Remnants of the outer POC -- LV-1201---As Harrison leaves the Pods, he hears the voice of a girl talking to him over the radio, who turns out to be the one that had him retrieve the data disc. The girl’s name is Tomiko, and she served an internship with the research team on LV-1201 to find evidence of the company’s illegal activities and the death of her brother, Kenji. The disc Harrison retrieved supposedly has this information. Harrison says he needs to get back to the POC and regroup with White Team, which was left stationed at the POC when the rest of the Marines went to the Pods.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix H – Comm Logs.Okay, Harrison, I’ve got you as close as I can. The POC is locked up tight as a drum. Assuming your White Team’s still here, you’ve got two choices. Stand in the courtyard and shout until they hear you, or head down into the outflow system. That should get you past the primary security net and into the Southern Landing. Or get you killed. ‘Course, I can say the same for staying here.Harrison arrives at the POC, and it has been heavily cocooned by the Xenomorphs. Drones crawl through the tunnels and hallways underneath and humans are cocooned in the walls, already impregnated by Facehuggers. As Harrison passes by and approaches the victims, Chestbursters erupt from their chests. Harrison arrives in a room with a massive egg pit and tons of Xenomorphs. Tomiko tells Harrison to find the power box to the area and activate it. With the Xenomorphs temporarily pushed back, Harrison continues through the POC looking for White Team.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix H – Comm Logs.Half way there. Listen, Harrison. Something’s up at the Southern Landing. White Team just went dead – the Verloc called asking our people if we’d taken down the communication link. We haven’t, but they’re still not answering. I’d hurry if I were you.Harrison continues through the POC fighting Xenomorphs as he turns on the automated defenses. He activates a power box on sublevel 2 and activates a crane to move some crates out of the way of a door. A hole has been blown in the door and Xenomorphs attack again. When Harrison opens up a ventilation shaft, a Praetorian appears, and Tomiko urges Harrison to run. Without any weapons capable of penetrating the Praetorian’s thick shell, Harrison has no choice but to retreat.---Price of AdmissionDate: January 07, 2231Time: 12:10 AMIncident: +6 Weeks, 19.00 hoursMission Time: 19.00 hoursLocation: Primary Operations Complex, Secured Zone---A combat synthetic places a beacon on a cocooned human. In another end of the Hive, Major McCain’s team picks up a signal on the motion tracker and go to find it, unaware of the trap that’s been put in place.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix A – Summary.Tracking the Marine expedition becomes increasingly difficult with the commencement of Operation Savior, particularly in regards to White Team. From reliable records, it’s clear that shortly after the Verloc’s second dropship departed for the Forward Pods, White Team broke off contact with the Verloc. From this period onwards, we are left only with uncorroborated testimony of a single low-ranking Marine. Given the events he describes, we find it hard to accept his depiction as fact. Simply put, we need not introduce a third species to explain the destruction of the Southern Landing.Harrison proceeds to take a lift up to the surface, but it stops midway. A corpse is thrown onto the lift and multiple Xenomorphs jump on to kill Harrison. Harrison jumps off the elevator and takes an alternate route, and the lift gets destroyed by a plasma bolt. A creature is hunting Harrison, and can be briefly seen in the halls and on the roofs of the buildings. Harrison makes his way to landing bay #3, looking for White Team, until the creature hunting him comes down to fight Harrison one on one. It’s revealed to be a Heavy Predator, and Harrison wins the battle against the alien hunter. With the Predator dead, Xenomorphs start to attack again, but Harrison continues on with his mission.---Loose EndsDate: January 07, 2231Time: 1:25 AMIncident: +6 Weeks, 20.25 hoursMission Time: 20.25 hoursLocation: Primary Operations Complex. White Team Operation Zone -- LV-1201---Major McCain and his marines find the signal they were picking up. Duke speaks his mind about this mission being a trap, and the squad agrees as they are surrounded by hundreds of eggs.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix I – Scientific Journal.The Praetorian is the warrior of the Hive, tough, massive, and ferocious. However, she is born quite humbly. Under the right pheromone conditions, runners and drones undergo a molting process extending over several years. During this time, the Xenomorph skin thickens and hardens. As the Praetorian enters mid-phase, it emits its own behavioral pheromone, which in turn enrages the Hive. Most Praetorians die during this phase. One strong enough to escape will wander the surrounding environs until her shell completes its hardening. Then, with a skin capable of reflecting small arms fire and a temper to match, she will return to assert her presence in the Hive.Harrison sees several Marines from White Team fighting against Xenomorph Drones and Runners, but they either get killed or saved if Harrison helps. When Harrison reaches the landing bay, he hears the roar of a Praetorian from far away. Two Marines open a door for Harrison and stand guard until he finds a weapon powerful enough to take out the Praetorain. Inside, Harrison establishes a communication link to the Verloc and finds a minigun. Shortly after, a Praetorian attacks, but Harrison’s new minigun makes short work of the giant Xenomorph. The landing bay is swarming with Xenomorphs, so Harrison clears them all out so the Dropship is able to land.---SaviorDate: January 07, 2231Time: 2:40 AMIncident: +6 Weeks, 21.50 hoursMission Time: 21.50 hoursLocation: Airborne, en-route to the hive---Harrison and Tomiko discuss their plans to rescue the Marines and escape. Harrison will take his Exosuit down into the excavation site and look for his team. When he does and gets them out of there, the dropship will make a quick stop at the Auxiliary Landing Pad to pick up Tomiko. She tells him that she can leave the pods and take the tunnel to the landing pad within ten minutes. With their plans established, Harrison proceeds to locate his team.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix H – Comm Logs.Listen Harrison. I’m sending you down the old synthetic access system. It dates from the first studies, before the Hive learned to tear the synths to pieces. I’m pretty sure Eisenburg sent his synths down through one of these throughways, so the equipment oughta work. If your team is heading up, they’ll be coming this way. If they’re heading down – just hope they’re heading up. Once you find them, head up to the surface and I’ll coordinate the dropship evac. Good luck.Harrison descends down the excavation site in his Exosuit. Tomiko explains the significance of these ruins and why they were excavated. As to be expected, Xenomorphs are crawling all over the hallways. Harrison takes an elevator down, and sees two combat synthetics fighting against some Xenomorphs. There is a large blast door that’s closed shut, and two small rooms to the side housing very large, alien power generators. There are branches clogging up the generator that Harrison clears with his Exosuit’s rockets. With both generators cleared, the main door opens, and Xenomorphs begin to pour out. As Harrison proceeds down the hallway, he falls through a hole and his Exosuit takes significant damage.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix V – Scientific Briefing.Once the Xenomorph population reaches a critical environmental mass – we judged somewhere between a thousand and two thousand base-living-units – the Hive pheromones change. What we call Spreading begins – as the Young Queens search out new territories. This is the normal state of affairs.Of course, should the Empress die – or even abdicate if such a thing were possible – one of the Young Queens would have to replace her. One can only imagine the fury and storm generated by such an instinctive and violent urge.With the Exosuit inoperable, Harrison continues on foot. Major McCain’s team picks up Harrison’s signal, seemingly having forgotten the bogus report McCain received about Harrison’s death. Harrison goes through a tunnel and arrives in a big chamber with a fossilized Space Jockey in the center. Out comes a Xenomorph queen and kills a Marine. Harrison gathers all the weapons he can get and defeats the Queen and her drones. The Marines blow open a hole in the chamber for them to escape through, and many Xenomorphs give chase. The dropship waits on the other side of the cliff and the Marines jump onboard.---Ending---As the dropship leaves the area, Harrison tells Tomiko that they’re coming to pick her up. Tomiko tells him there isn’t enough time, and that he needs to leave and pass the data disc on to her father. Before closing their communication, Tomiko asks Harrison what his first name is. He replies “Andrew,” and Tomiko says good bye to him. Johnson notices a massive energy surge coming from the Pods and tells the crew to brace for impact. A giant explosion engulfs the Pods as the dropship leaves the planet.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix A – Summary.USCM Emergency Dispatch.McCain reporting.LV-1201 abandoned. Casualties extreme. One dropship still missing. Evacuation failed.Recommend scrubbing further evac by the 6 Battalion. Primary Operations Complex has been overrun. Forward Observation Pods appear unsalvageable. Sensors indicate a massive rupture of the fusion reactor cells in the Pods. Likelihood of finding additional survivors: negligible. Requesting medical intercept ASAP.PredatorThe player controlled Predator in the game is presumed to be a Prince, a high ranking member of his clan based on the design of his armor and equipment. He was part of the hunting party that attacked Rykov’s team on Korari, and has now come to LV-1201 with his clan mates to begin a new hunt.---HuntDate: December 01, 2230Time: 09:08 AMIncident: +6 days, 4 hoursHunt: +4.0 hoursLocation: Canyons, 3 KM south of the Forward Observation Pods---Nearly one week after the incident at the Primary Operations Complex, a Predator ship lands on LV-1201 holding three Predators beginning a new hunt. General Vasili Rykov sees the ship come in on their remote monitors, and orders his men to go after them.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix M – Rykov’s Journal.I have seen enough. The Zeta site is not Pilot technology. The scientists have dated the artifacts found there. They are young – hundreds of years old at most. I recognize the carvings. It is my enemy. Returned.I should have anticipated as much. This land is too rich with trophies; it is perfect for their kind. Still, I will not fail this time. Although the scientists do not understand the full technology, they have already begun to unravel the strange gear. Given time, we will find their weakness. Given time.The young Predator traverses the canyons, hunting any humans he finds. Halfway across a bridge he meets a fellow clan mate, who offers the young Predator a Combistick. The hunt continues and the Predator sees another clan mate as he kills two corporate guards. The Predator receives the Disc from his clan mate and continues forward. Shortly after he hears over a human radio that two specimens have been captured thanks to EMP grenades. Rykov then orders his men to return with them to the Forward Observation Pods. After killing more humans, the Predator comes across a skirmish between the humans and the Xenomorphs. The Predator disposes of both and is faced by a Praetorian. The Predator defeats the creature and proceeds through the canyons.---TrapDate: December 01, 2230Time: 05:13 PMIncident: +6 days, 12 hoursHunt: +12.00 hoursLocation: Canyons, 3 KM south of the Forward Observation Pods---Human scientists carry two unconscious Predators to the APC and proceed to the Forward Observation Pods. The Predators in question appear to be the specimens that were mentioned over the radio. The Predator goes forth to rescue his brethren.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix M – Rykov’s Journal.The attack has begun. Our modified EMP grenades work. It is fitting that we use their own technologies against them.We have taken two of the creatures – I shall call them Predators. With surprise gone, I have ordered the teams to withdraw. It is one matter to sacrifice a scientific team as bait; it is another to throw my soldiers carelessly into the Predator’s path. We must not underestimate the killing power of these beasts.The Predator faces many soldiers on his way to the Forward Observation Pods. Turret defenses are found throughout the canyons, and a combat synthetic is left stationed, and can see through the Predator’s invisibility. None of these are a match for the Predator, as he kills his enemies and claims their skulls as his trophies.---InterloperDate: December 01, 2230Time: 11:15 PMIncident: +6 days, 18 hoursHunt: +18 hoursLocation: Beneath the Forward Observation Pods---The Predator arrives just outside the Forward Observation Pods. He sees the APC carrying his clan mates taken up the lift to the Pods, and two combat synthetics are left on guard with sniper rifles, along with several automated turrets.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix M – Rykov’s Journal.The teams have returned. I should say that some have returned. We have lost many. What else could I do though? They would have found us soon – I am certain – just as they may have found the POC. Eisenburg will not hear of this possibility – he insists that the Aliens alone possessed the power to destroy the POC. His imagination is too small. It will be his undoing. I will not make the same mistake; more creatures will come for their brethren. We must be ready.The Predator sneaks past the fence around a broken sentry gun. The synthetics in the middle tower can see through his cloaking, but the Predator disposes of them. The lift to the Pods is on the other side of a large puddle, which would disable the Predator’s invisibility should he step in it. He leaps onto a truck as a platform and then jumps to the other side. A guard notices his presence, and calls for the lift to be pulled up. It’s too late, as the guard is killed, and the Predator takes the lift up into the Pods.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix M – Rykov’s Journal.I told Dunya to take the first creature to implantation immediately. I wanted it to die slowly. I would happily kill them all for what they have done to me. They should have finished me when they had the chance and not left me broken. Unfortunately, I was not as quick with the second. Eisenburg intervened before I could dispatch it. He wants it alive, for study. Again, he misunderstands what he holds. He doesn’t need to understand them. He needs to kill them.The guards inside ambush the Predator with EMP grenades, but are unsuccessful, and killed off by the Predator. He jumps on top of crates to reach the top of the cargo bay and another elevator. The person inside locks the doors to protect him, but the Predator comes in through the ceiling and kills the human. The rest of the Pod security are aware of the Predator’s presence, and are prepared to attack him outside of the elevator. All their attempts to kill or capture the Predator are still unsuccessful.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix M – Rykov’s Journal.So, we have not taken them all. One comes for me. We track it through our cameras and sensors. I have studied some of the footage. Something about the mask draws my attention. Under magnification, I can just make out markings. They are different from the masks on the other two – more ornamental. Different and yet familiar. I feel I am staring into my past – into the face of my would-be killer. Does this mean I have found him – my attacker from so many years ago? Or more likely, his friend, his brother – ha, perhaps it is no more than a brand like a logo on a shoe. No matter. I will think of him as my nemesis – and enjoy his undoing all the more.The Predator ascends a flight of stairs and finds another elevator. However, the elevator does not respond, so he navigates a series of beams and catwalks along the outside of the elevator. Combat Synthetics await him at the top, and the Predator’s cloaking is ineffective against them. The Predator enters a room and is locked inside. A turret drops down from the ceiling and fires bolts of plasma everywhere, incapacitating the Predator. Rykov sees the unconscious Predator and takes his mask, as a trophy of his own.---Unexpected AlliesDate: January 06, 2231Time: 10:22 PMIncident: +6 weeks, 17.25 hours.Hunt: +5 weeks, 1 day, 17 hours.Location: Inside the Forward Observation Pods---The Predator is held in a stasis pod for the next five weeks. He briefly wakes up to see a Xenomorph standing over a scientist and a human activating a console to the right of the Predator. He wakes up again with the pod completely turned off and is now free. However, he is without his mask and equipment, so he must regain them.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix K – Scientific Records.Holding time: five weeks, three days. The predator remains strong with high antibody count and little fever. I am surprised at its resilience after our…test. Based on the blood loss alone, it should be weak and sickly. Instead, sustained only by intravenous fluids, the creature’s immune system resists all introduced strains. Still, our understanding of its physiology increases day by day. We have time now – to work without fear. Without weapons, the creature is weak – I should say without most of its weapons. Our surgeons are still reluctant to attempt removal of its forearm bands. Eisenburg was not pleased with the death of the last one – no need to repeat that so soon.The Predator uses his wristband’s hack function to bypass the Pod’s security systems and escape the room. He uses this device to blow electrical panels and security consoles to allow him past locked doors. He sees a scientist in a room with some Predator equipment. He retrieves a net gun, a remote bomb, and a clan mate’s mask, allowing him the use of his vision modes, but is still without his cloak and other equipment.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix M – Rykov’s Journal.Perhaps I was wrong on Eisenburg. Perhaps the captured Predators can open the door to a final solution. After all, their physiology is not magical – they have hemoglobin – they require oxygen – they can die. One sickness, one contagion, one carrier.If I kill this one, they will return. Perhaps, there are other options.The Predator over hears two guards talking about two switches that should not be both turned on simultaneously. The Predator uses this to cause an explosion and kill a few humans on the other side. The Predator proceeds through the hole and finds a Combistick and cloak generator. The Predator enters a lab with a clan mate on an autopsy table, and finds a Medicomp, Energy Sift, and the Plasmacaster. Pod security begins to call in Combat Synthetics to deal with the problem, but they are no match for the Predator. He later finds the spear gun, and makes his way to the cargo bay of the Pods.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix M – Rykov’s Journal.Damn Eisenburg. I should have killed the creature when I could. Between him and the clumsy Marines, I am surrounded by fools.No, that is not fair. I could have fought Eisenburg harder. I gambled that we could learn from the creature. Perhaps we can. With the creature’s blood physiology, a good team could fashion a proper solution. I imagine something similar to Anthrax 9. Without the risk of human infection, we could make it much more contagious and long lasting. If we can just catch it again, I will even have a host to carry home the death of its people.The Predator has to get past several sentry turrets and Combat Synthetics, making the use of his cloak ineffective. After fighting his way to the bottom of the cargo bay, the Predator shoots some explosive barrels near a parked APC and blows a hole in the side of the Pods. A dropship is called to investigate the problem, and the Predator uses this as his chance to escape. He jumps on the dropship and causes it to crash into the nearby canyons.---Old DebtsDate: January 06, 2231Time: 11:25 PMIncident: +6 weeks, 18.25 hoursHunt: +5 weeks, 1 day, 18 hoursLocation: Canyon beside the Pods leading to the canyon heights---Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix M – Rykov’s Journal.It has escaped from the Pods, hijacking a dropship in flight. No human could have survived the crash, but it is hardly human. I pray the Xenomorphs will finish it, or failing that, Dropship 2 should finish it if we detect it trying to reach its mates.Still, I cannot be too sure. I have ordered the team to prepare evacuations – the medical data must survive.The Predator survives the dropship crash and proceeds through a series of tunnels underground. Xenomorphs come out in full force, but the Predator destroys them all with the help of his EM vision and Plasmacaster. While crossing over some pipes, the Predator is attacked by two Predaliens. The Predator destroys them, and continues to fight more Xenomorphs until he reaches an elevator that leads to the Auxiliary Landing Pad. The Predator activates a beacon at the pad, sending a signal to his clan. Xenomorphs come rushing in, followed by a Praetorian. A dropship arrives after intercepting the signal and blows open the main gate to the landing pad, but it is disposed of by the Predator’s ship. The Predator exits the pad and sees a fellow clan mate offer him a Disc. The predator takes the weapon and proceeds through the door to find Rykov.---New TargetDate: January 07, 2231Time: 01:50 AMIncident: +6 weeks, 20.50 hoursHunt: +5 weeks, 1 day, 20.50 hoursLocation: Tunnels leading from abandoned landing to Hive entrance---Rykov and his personnel are proceeding towards the Hive. A Corporate informs Rykov that they’ve lost contact with Ivan from the Pods. Rykov assumes he is dead, and his pain killers have worn off, supposedly much faster than they have before. The Corporate offers to get him another dose, but Rykov refuses. He wishes to remain alert and effective, and is confident that the mask in his possession will lure the Predator to him.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix M – Rykov’s Journal.Ivan is dead; the artificial Hive has been breached. The creature has escaped; I have lost my carrier. Enough sadness. I have the report on the third Predator’s mask. It is unique – much older and more complex than the others. The scientists speculate the creature was either rich or royal or both. Given its youthfulness, I’d guess, a prince. With no ordinary crown. It is speculation, but I believe that the mask tracks their hunts – a tribal record book. If so, the mask may lead me to their homeland.Let me return the prince’s crown draped in a fabric made of death.The Predator takes an elevator underground to pursue Rykov. He meets heavy resistance with sentry turrets and Corporates. Both do very little to slow down the Predator as he makes his way to the Hive, in pursuit of Rykov.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix M – Rykov’s Journal.I have the mask. I am certain that the creature knows. Fifteen minutes ago, the mask became active – most likely in response to some signal.Excellent. Let the creature come. Dunya and the team have copies of the blood work; they understand our stakes. One of us will survive. This fight will not end with me.Xenomorphs start appearing in great numbers and fight against the humans. The Predator uses this opportunity to his advantage to dispose of both creatures. He proceeds through a large flooded tunnel with catwalks and fights his way past Xenomorphs and humans. The Predator enters a ventilation shaft and proceeds deeper underground.---TrophyDate: January 07, 2231Time: 02:36 AMIncident: +6 weeks, 21.33 hoursHunt: +5 weeks, 1 day, 21:33 hoursLocation: Hive Entrance---Rykov has equipped himself with an Exosuit, and tells his men to leave. He wishes to fight the battle against the Predator on his own, and proceeds into the Hive.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix H – Comm Logs.Dunya! Dunya! It is here. I have entered the Hive and it follows. If I kill it, I will head for the surface and the old Access Point #3. If I don’t radio again, get out. You have my codes – the funds are yours. They are covered in the blood of the POC, but you can wash away the stain. Create the weapon! Finish my battle.The Predator appears just above the door Rykov entered, but is already long gone. The Predator finds the body of a clan mate next to a dead Facehugger and a plasma pistol. The Predator takes the weapon, and is shortly after attacked by a Facehugger. The Predator uses the vent the Facehugger came out of and uses to reach the Hive. He’s met by many Xenomorph Drones and Runners, but they are all quickly disposed of.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix C –Training Manual.The Exosuit combines the firepower of a light armor vehicle with the maneuverability of a foot soldier. Against light infantry and insurgent forces, the Exosuit dominates the battlefield. Only a madman would challenge a combat Exosuit – and he would certainly not live to tell about it.The Predator has reached the Hive. As he enters, Rykov communicates with the Predator, taunting him and his race. He navigates a maze of egg chambers, all of which have been destroyed by Rykov’s Exosuit. The eggs are either crushed or set on fire. One lone Facehugger lurks around the Hive’s tunnels, but is destroyed along with the other Xenomorphs that attack the Predator. After exiting the labyrinth, the Predator finds Rykov, and they both fight one on one.---Ending---The Predator is victorious over Rykov. His Exosuit is destroyed, and Rykov is badly damaged. He tries to grab the Predator’s mask but dies before he can. The Predator takes back his mask and takes Rykov’s spine as a trophy, and lets out a victorious roar.Weyland-Yutani Security AlertDate: July 12, 2231Yesterday morning, our top WY biological weapons scientist was abducted from his quarters on Gateway. Thirty minutes later, the wife of our division lead at the New Brazil WD plant reported that her husband had not returned from his daily golfing. By the end of the day, WY confirmed three abductions and two missing persons reports.By all accounts, this sudden activity is not a coincidence, but a highly organized operation. Intel experts match the MO to that of the Iron Bears – however, it is well known that Vassili Rykov, the Iron Bears leader, died during the Incident on LV-1201. Besides, at least one onlooker to the Gateway incidents described the team’s leader as a young, dark-haired woman.As we have yet to receive ransom demands, the motivation for these attacks remains hazy.AlienA simple Xenomorph drone that single handedly sparked the incident on LV-1201. Its goals are the same as any other Xenomorph, to propagate the hive and destroy any and all creatures that pose a threat to their species.---BirthDate: November 23, 2230Location: Cargo ship. Western landing. Primary Operations Complex (POC) -- LV-1201---Cargo Ship Aurora arrives on LV-1201 to receive a nearly doubled expected shipment of crates. Elsewhere in the Primary Operations Complex, Dr. Eisenburg has a heated argument with a fellow scientist about the committee’s suspicions of Eisenburg’s activities on the planet. He brushes off the rumors being made by the committee, as he is absolutely focused on his research of the Xenomorphs. Later, Captain Richter of the Aurora receives another crate, this time larger than the other ones they’ve received. Richter takes it to the ship and attempts to scan the item, but the contents inside are shielded. A guard by the name of Lyoid calls for Richter to see General Rykov, messing up his departure schedule. When the ship is sealed up, the crate on the edge of the table gets bumped and falls over. The lid falls off, and inside is an egg. The egg opens to reveal a Facehugger.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix C – WY Training Manuals.In laboratory conditions, containment fails less than one percent of the time. Most failures, when they occur, result in the escape of the first life-stage of the Xenomorph – the Facehugger.Facehuggers are remarkably quick and cunning, possessing an innate drive to avoid detection and to find an appropriate, isolated host.The Facehugger escapes from the cargo ship and crawls around inside the POC’s ventilation system. The Facehugger follows the pheromones of Sergeant Cisco, who is revealed in his interactions with the people in the POC to be a very cantankerous and rude person. Some guards talk behind his back saying that he has no friends back at the Forward Observation Pods. The Facehugger sneaks past security guards and scientists, looking for a proper host in an isolated area so that it can implant an embryo. The Facehugger finds Cisco asleep in his chair, and leaps at him. The Facehugger latches onto Cisco and the door to his room closes and locks automatically, sealing Cisco inside.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix C – WY Training Manuals.During the second stage of life, the Xenomorph is at its most vulnerable. Even inexperienced teams can contain and eliminate the Chestburster with minimal loss of life. Unfortunately, during this phase, the Xenomorph displays an instinctive caution, avoiding all contact. Worse, if given time, the Chestburster will eat, molt, and grow into a full-sized drone.The embryo implanted by the Facehugger has grown into a Chestburster and proceeds to eat its way out of Cisco’s chest. Guards outside hear Cisco’s screams and they try to open the door to his room. The Chestburster escapes through an open window and sneaks past several security guards looking for food. The Chestburster finds an animal holding pen, and kills a cat. The Chestburster eats the animal and proceeds to grow into a Drone.---SurpriseDate: November 23, 2230Location: Primary Operations Complex (POC) -- LV-1201---Two workers at the complex find the molted skin of the Chestburster. One proceeds to investigate it closely, while the other has a bad feeling about what’s about to happen. The Drone hisses, and the workers run for their lives.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix C – WY Training Manuals.Successful Xenomorph containment depends on a single factor – tracking and locating the offending specimen. This is doubly true when dealing with full-grown drones or larger Xenomorph specimens. During the first twenty minutes of a Xenomorph contamination, mortality rates are twenty to thirty times higher than the later stages of contamination.The fully grown Xenomorph begin its massacre of the humans on LV-1201 and has one primary objective: return to the hive. The creature begins preying on the workers and security guards at the POC. A dropship lands at the complex to pick up some POC personnel, but they are all brutally murdered by the lone Xenomorph. It proceeds inside the complex and infiltrates the ventilation system. However, a POC officer detects the Xenomorph inside the ventilation, and he continues to monitor it from the security station.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix C –Training Manuals.The LV 1201 Primary Operations Complex was designed with redundancy. However, when dealing with Xenomorphs, no system is foolproof. Sufficient damage to the circulation and waste flow systems could create the conditions for massive Xenomorph infiltration. For this reason, security should flush any contamination upwards – towards the office and living quarters sections – despite the certainty of increased short-term fatality counts.As the Xenomorph crawls through the complex, the personnel start talking to each other about rumors of a loose contaminant. Security is now fully aware of the presence of the Xenomorph, but they are unsuccessful in containing the creature. The Xenomorph finds a containment cell holding several Drones, and destroys the console, freeing the other Xenomorphs. Freeing its brethren, the Xenomorph crawls down a shaft, continuing through the POC.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix A – Summary.Engineering studies of the Primary Operations Complex identified the primary outflow system tunnels as the weak link in the POC defenses. However, these studies also concluded that nothing short of a bomb could breach tunnel walls and expose the POC to complete contamination. While a catastrophic failure in the pumping equipment could have led to an explosion in the flow control systems, this should have been small and contained. One can only conclude that either the analysis was wrong, or that someone wanted the POC to fail.Security begins to ramp up in force to combat the Xenomorph, but like past efforts it ends in heavy casualties. The Xenomorphs that were freed earlier begin to attack the POC security, and some are either killed or survive the skirmishes. After brief encounters outside the complex buildings, the Xenomorph crawls back into the POC’s ventilation system, approaching animal storage.---EscapeDate: November 25, 2230Time: 05:18 PMIncident: StartLocation: Animal Storage. Primary Operations Complex (POC) -- LV-1201---A security guard asks the POC officer to contact Rykov, showing concern for the Primary Operations Complex being compromised by the Xenomorph. The Officer refuses, confident that they’re only dealing with one contaminant and that it is no different from past Xenomorph containment failures. Rykov is only three hours away, and the Officer is sure that the POC will not be overrun.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix A – Summary.Throughout the early morning, all evidence points towards an atypically violent, but contained Alien contamination. After eight o’ clock, however, new security reports appear that refer to a second set of confrontations. Oddly, these reports contain no direct mention of Xenomorph involvement. However, one must assume these were Xenomorph incidents as well, and not the work of some other hostile species.The Xenomorph makes its way through animal storage, and faces heavier resistance from security and sentry turrets. It uses alternate paths to get past the turrets and cuts the power to several ventilation fans to proceed forth. The Xenomorph bypasses and destroys security and all personnel in storage.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix C – WY Training Manuals.The flamethrower provides excellent firepower in all situations – against the Xenomorph, this is amplified by the natural shield it places between the security officer and the offending creature. However, officers should not overestimate their protection. If you cannot find your enemy, you cannot fight him.As the Xenomorph continues its murderous rampage, a Predator is thrown into the mix. The lone Xenomorph faces off against the Predator and defeats it in combat. However, as it dies, the Predator activates its wristband’s self destruct mechanism. Sensing the danger, the Xenomorph retreats from the Predator before it explodes. The explosion creates a sizable hole in the POC and the Xenomorph escapes to the Hive. POC security fears what has happened, the explosion allowing for a Xenomorph infestation from the Hive, and they send attempt to send a distress transmission to the company. Dr. Eisenburg intercepts this signal while in the Forward Observation Pods, and realizing what it could do to his career, demands the transmission be cut in order to keep his pride from being destroyed by the committee.---VengeanceDate: January 06, 2231Time: 09:50 AMIncident: +6 Weeks, 16.50 hoursLocation: Inside the Forward Observation Pods---Six weeks have passed since the incident at the Forward Observation Pods. A female scientist is tending to the defense system surrounding the pods, and is escorted by Dimitri, Major Dunya’s fiancé. However, the defense system completely shuts down, caused by Corporal Harrison and the Colonial Marines unknowingly. Xenomorphs enter the area and kill Dimitri and the rest of the personnel outside. The Xenomorphs then proceed inside the Pods to murder everyone inside.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix A – Summary.On January 6 at approximately ten P.M., the defense system of the Forward Pods collapsed due to a massive software failure. Records indicate some number of Xenomorph drones and runners entered the pods during the fifteen minutes of downtime. These reports also mention the loss of Archeological Team Omega, working at Dig Site #12, near the Xenomorph hive. We believe that the focus on saving these men – code-named Operation Savior – distracted Pod security from a more immediate threat.The Xenomorph infiltrates the Pods before the security system is back online, but that is already too late for everyone inside. The creature causes havoc inside the Pods, and releases a Predalien from stasis. This creature goes on a rampage of its own, killing everything in sight, before later being run into by Corporal Harrison. Meanwhile, Eisenburg receives word of a Xenomorph infestation in the Pods that security “thinks” is isolated. The doctor begins to shake in fear and starts seeing Xenomorphs all around him. He blocks the door to his office with furniture and huddles in a corner, having flashbacks to the horrific first expedition to LV-1201. General Rykov and his men get inside and are rather disgusted with Eisenburg’s cowardly behavior. Both men leave the office to a safer place where they can discuss their plan of action.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix A – Summary.Based on a crude analysis of the events at the Forward Pods, some have linked the loss of the Artificial Hive to Operation Savior. Such attempts to create poetic justice from mere coincidence should be summarily ignored. As if Aliens could have known of the Savior plans or have reacted intelligently to such behavior – clearly such theories stretch the bounds of Xenomorph abilities.The Xenomorph reaches Dr. Eisenburg’s office, but he and Rykov have left. It crawls through the Pod’s ventilation shaft and crawls past a meeting about “Operation Savior,” the humans’ plan to send the Marines to rescue the archeological team, a trap for them, while Eisenburg and his team capture the Empress and leave the planet on one of the Verloc’s dropships. The Xenomorph finds several drones held within an artificial Hive, and the creature frees its kind and escape through a broken fan at the top of Core Access in one of the Pods. The Xenomorph proceeds to the Hive in order to protect the Empress.---AbductionDate: January 06, 2231Time: 11:35 PMIncident: +6 Weeks, 18.25 hoursLocation: Hive. LV-1201. 6 KM northeast of the Forward Pods---Eisenburg and his team arrive in the Empress’ chamber, and combat synthetics are stationed at the perimeter holding off Drones and Runners. According to Eisenburg’s theory, holding the Empress hostage, in this situation with a flame thrower, will force her to call off her subjects so that she will survive. The theory initially appears confirmed, but the Xenomorphs rush back in even greater numbers. Not hesitating, Eisenburg orders the Empress be taken immediately and destroy the Hive.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix B – Recovered Email.From: Dr. EisenburgTo: All PersonnelWe have planned for a Large Mass Specimen Extraction [LMSE] targeted at the rarer Xenomorph species within the Hive. The loss of our archeological expedition, while unfortunate, forces our hand. I have assured the Colonial Marines Major that the LMSE is the perfect operation to distract the Hive so that his team can rescue our companions safely. To eliminate confusion on this, forward any Marine questions to me immediately.The Xenomorph enters the Hive and assists its brethren in removing the combat synthetics and soldiers stationed inside. Because they are not human, the combat synthetics do not have any pheromones for the Xenomorphs to track. The creatures destroy the explosive charges set by the synthetics and rush to the Empress’ chamber. However, she is already gone, and the Xenomorph goes after Eisenburg in order to take the Empress back.---PursuitDate: January 07, 2231Time: 01:50 AMIncident: +6 Weeks, 20.50 hoursLocation: Near Hive. Access tunnel and neighbouring archaeological dig -- LV-1201---Dr. Eisenburg calls a team of combat synthetics at the Primary Operations Complex, and is told that a dropship from the Verloc has arrived, and the synthetics have killed the remaining members of White Team. Eisenburg tells the synthetics to prepare the dropship for a “guest.”Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix B – Recovered Email.From: Dr. EisenburgTo: Auxiliary Pod Landing ControlThe Large Mass Specimen Extraction is proceeding well. We will not need to evacuate medical casualties. However, I feel that Gateway would provide a better site for further research on the Empress. McCain concurs. A dropship will arrive shortly. Please prep all teams for immediate loading and departure.The Xenomorph chases furiously after Eisenburg and the captured Empress, killing every human and synthetic in its path. It destroys sentry turrets and machinery in order to open a way to the Empress.---FreedomDate: January 07, 2231Time: 02:55 AMIncident: +6 Weeks, 21.50 hoursMission Time: 0.25 hoursLocation: Tunnels leading to the Auxiliary Landing Pad. LV-1201. 2 KM northeast of the Forward Observation Pods.---Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix D – Dissenting Analysis.Despite overwhelming evidence, the committee on the Incident continues to ignore reports of a third species participating in the fall of LV-1201. Are we so arrogant as humans to assume that a more technologically advanced species than ours might exist and not wish to reveal themselves to us? They probably see us as bloodthirsty fools intent on killing one another, and wish to stay hidden until we have matured as a race and are ready to embrace their utopian ideals. –Dr. Chris Lund.The Xenomorph continues to follow Eisenburg to the Auxiliary Landing pad, and they are aware of the creature following them. However, things are made complicated once again for the humans because of a Predator in the area. The Xenomorph decides to either kill the Predator or ignore it in order to find the Empress.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix A – Summary.The fate of Dr. Eisenburg remains uncertain. Given the disappearance of the Verloc’s second dropship, we cannot state with certainty that the Doctor died on LV-1201. The possibility remains that the Doctor and at least some of his research specimens escaped from the final chaos. Company security remains very interested in his potential whereabouts.The Xenomorph figures out that destroying the equipment necessary for the dropship to land at the Auxiliary Landing Pad will prevent Eisenburg from escaping with the Empress. The Xenomorph goes and sabotages the Landing Hydraulics. After that, it proceeds to a room overlooking the landing pad and destroys the Flight Telemetry Relay. The Xenomorph heads outside to the pad to intercept the captured Empress.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix D – Dissenting Analysis.The conduct of this board towards the Eisenburg family borders on reckless. We refuse to ask the most obvious of questions and accept the most ridiculous of answers. The medical explanations for Eisenburg’s recovery from Expedition One are frankly preposterous. The unburied innocents on LV-1201 deserve better than the whitewash perpetrated by this commission.Out on the landing pad, the Xenomorph is greeted by two Predators, possibly looking to kill the Empress. The Xenomorph destroys the threat and heads back inside the building to destroy one last device: the landing beacon. Without it, the dropship is unable to land and crashes. Dr. Eisenburg is furious and shocked at this predicament, and decides to kill the creature responsible. The Xenomorph returns outside to tend defeat Dr. Eisenburg, who mysteriously emits no pheromones.---Ending---Dr. Eisenburg is revealed to be an android, created by the real Dr. Eisenburg’s father who ported his son’s consciousness to an identical synthetic body. His limbs have been ripped off, leaving him only his torso and head cocooned within the Hive. His screams of agony are heard throughout the hive, and the Xenomorphs surround the severely damaged synthetic, gloating in their victory.Weyland-Yutani Debriefing, the Incident. Appendix A – Summary.Our satellite at LV-1201 confirm that the Hive is alive. Nevertheless, the Forward Pods are clearly inoperable without considerable investment. Given our need for expedient progress on Research Project X11, we are recommending immediate reallocation resources to Site #3.Final TransmissionAfter completing all three campaigns, an extra cutscene is shown. The USS Verloc continues through space, leaving LV-1201 behind. A transmission is displayed.Remote transmission acquired. Boosting for outgoing dispatch. Routing now.………The mule has been acquired. Package is en route.…ETA: Unknown…Mission Complete.…Extraction required. Priority status.The message is very cryptic, but the “package” seems to refer to the data disc Tomiko had Harrison retrieve. It is possible that Tomiko escaped from the Pods before they exploded, and that she was likely a spy for the company.The Verloc continues to drift through space, but is followed by the Predator ship, possibly targeting the humans on the Verloc as their next hunt.Campaign IntersectionsMost of the campaigns run concurrently with each other, but the majority of events for each race are separate from each other. The three main characters encounter each other in the Forward Observation Pods, roughly halfway through each character’s campaigns. Other actions made by the three characters cause effects for each other before, during, and after the conflict inside the Pods.Corporal Harrison cut the Pod’s security grid, as it was necessary if the Marines were to reach the research team at the Pods. As a consequence for Harrison’s actions, the Xenomorphs (including the one you play as in the Alien campaign) are able to infiltrate the pods. During the Alien campaign inside the Pods, the player controlled Xenomorph will release a Predalien in stasis, and it goes on a rampage inside the Pods. This same Predalien is most likely the same one encountered during the Marine campaign, since it was the only one found in the area. During his escape, Harrison arrives in a room with a Predator in a stasis pod. The Predator in the stasis pod is the same one you play as in the Predator campaign, and after Harrison moves the pod in order to keep going, the Predator is released. When Harrison escapes the pods, he sees a hole blown open by the Predator who escaped minutes before. The three campaigns proceed to go their separate paths after the events in the Forward Observation Pods.MultiplayerMultiplayer in Aliens versus Predator 2 allows you to play as all three races of different classes against each other on multiple maps and game modes. Specific to the multiplayer mode are the Corporates, which are extensively part of the human race but aren’t affiliated with the Marines. Each faction has four playable classes, six for the Alien if you allow the option for Alien life cycle in multiplayer.Marine ClassesHarrison - SpecialistScoring Class: MarineNormal Weapons:-- Knife, Pistol, Shotgun, Pulse Rifle, Grenade Launcher, Flame Thrower, Smartgun, Rocket Launcher, Minigun, Sniper RifleClass Weapons:-- Knife, Pistol, Shotgun, SmartgunSpecial Abilities:-- NoneIchiro - SniperScoring Class: MarineNormal Weapons:-- Knife, Pistol, Shotgun, Pulse Rifle, Grenade Launcher, Flame Thrower, Smartgun, Rocket Launcher, Minigun, Sniper RifleClass Weapons:-- Knife, Pistol, Grenade Launcher, Sniper RifleSpecial Abilities:-- NoneJohnson - DemolitionsScoring Class: MarineNormal Weapons:-- Knife, Pistol, Shotgun, Pulse Rifle, Grenade Launcher, Flame Thrower, Smartgun, Rocket Launcher, Minigun, Sniper RifleClass Weapons:-- Knife, Pistol, Pulse Rife, Flame ThrowerSpecial Abilities:-- NoneJones - Heavy WeaponsScoring Class: MarineNormal Weapons:-- Knife, Pistol, Shotgun, Pulse Rifle, Grenade Launcher, Flame Thrower, Smartgun, Rocket Launcher, Minigun, Sniper RifleClass Weapons:-- Knife, Pistol, Shotgun, Rocket LauncherSpecial Abilities:-- NonePredator ClassesPredatorScoring Class: PredatorNormal Weapons:-- Wristblades, Combistick, Pistol, Spear Gun, Plasmacaster, Disc, Net Gun, Remote BombClass Weapons:-- Wristblades, Combistick, Pistol, Disc, Net GunSpecial Abilities:-- Medicomp, Energy SiftAssault PredatorScoring Class: PredatorNormal Weapons:-- Wristblades, Combistick, Pistol, Spear Gun, Plasmacaster, Disc, Net Gun, Remote BombClass Weapons:-- Wristblades, Pistol, Plasmacaster, Net Gun, Remote BombSpecial Abilities:-- Medicomp, Energy SiftHeavy PredatorScoring Class: PredatorNormal Weapons:-- Wristblades, Combistick, Pistol, Spear Gun, Plasmacaster, Disc, Net Gun, Remote BombClass Weapons:-- Wristblades, Combistick, Disc, Net GunSpecial Abilities:-- Medicomp, Energy SiftLight PredatorScoring Class: PredatorNormal Weapons:-- Wristblades, Combistick, Pistol, Spear Gun, Plasmacaster, Disc, Net Gun, Remote BombClass Weapons:-- Wristblades, Spear Gun, Disc, Remote BombSpecial Abilities:-- Medicomp, Energy SiftAlien ClassesDroneScoring Class: DroneNormal Weapons:-- Claws, Headbite, TailClass Weapons:-- Claws, Headbite, TailSpecial Abilities:-- Wall-walking, pouncePraetorianScoring Class: PraetorianNormal Weapons:-- Claws, Headbite, TailClass Weapons:-- Claws, Headbite, TailSpecial Abilities:-- Extra strength, high damage resistance against small caliber projectilesRunnerScoring Class: RunnerNormal Weapons:-- Claws, Headbite, TailClass Weapons:-- Claws, Headbite, TailSpecial Abilities:-- Extra speed, limited strength, wall-walking, pouncePredalienScoring Class: PredalienNormal Weapons:-- Claws, TailClass Weapons:-- Claws, TailSpecial Abilities:-- Extra strength, wall-walking, pounceCorporatesIvan - SpecialistScoring Class: CorporateNormal Weapons:-- Knife, Pistol, Shotgun, Pulse Rifle, Grenade Launcher, Flame Thrower, Smartgun, Rocket Launcher, Minigun, Sniper RifleClass Weapons:-- Knife, Pistol, Shotgun, Grenade Launcher, Flame ThrowerSpecial Abilities:-- NoneDunya - TrooperScoring Class: CorporateNormal Weapons:-- Knife, Pistol, Shotgun, Pulse Rifle, Grenade Launcher, Flame Thrower, Smartgun, Rocket Launcher, Minigun, Sniper RifleClass Weapons:-- Knife, Pistol, Flame Thrower, Sniper RifleSpecial Abilities:-- NoneRykov - Heavy WeaponsScoring Class: CorporateNormal Weapons:-- Knife, Pistol, Shotgun, Pulse Rifle, Grenade Launcher, Flame Thrower, Smartgun, Rocket Launcher, Minigun, Sniper RifleClass Weapons:-- Knife, Pistol, Shotgun, Pulse Rifle, Grenade LauncherSpecial Abilities:-- NoneDimitri - AT OfficerScoring Class: CorporateNormal Weapons:-- Knife, Pistol, Shotgun, Pulse Rifle, Grenade Launcher, Flame Thrower, Smartgun, Rocket Launcher, Minigun, Sniper RifleClass Weapons:-- Knife, Pistol, Shotgun, MinigunSpecial Abilities:-- NoneMultiplayer ModesDeathmatchDeathmatch works just like it does in other games. Players kill each other for points, and based on which class you choose, your kills go towards a specific scoring class. Each Alien class has their own scoring class, while all the Marine classes share the same scoring class.Team DeathmatchWorks just like it does in Deathmatch, except the players are split up into teams. One team is tasked with killing the other team and vice versa. However, team killing takes away one point from the team’s score.HuntHunt is a team deathmatch variant with two specific teams, “hunters” and “prey.” The hunters earn points for killing the prey. However, should the hunter be killed by the prey, they are switched to the opposite teams, making the hunter the prey in some situations.SurvivorSurvivor is a mode where the last person alive wins. Everyone else that dies during the game becomes a mutant, and they receive 10 points for every survivor they kill. The survivors earn one point for every second they’re alive, so the longer they’re alive the higher score they’ll get.OverrunOverrun has a time limit. The defenders have a finite number of lives and must hold out until the round is over. The attackers must then kill everyone on the opposing team before the round’s done in order to win.EvacAnother game mode with attackers and defenders. The defenders not only need to survive until the end of the round, but they must reach an evac point and hold its position for ten seconds. The attackers meanwhile have to kill every defender and protect the evac points.Multiplayer MapsThere are twelve multiplayer maps in Aliens versus Predator 2. The majority of the maps are based on areas that are shown in the single player campaigns, while some are designed as tributes to locations from the Alien or Predator movies. The Alien series inspiration is fairly dominant in the multiplayer maps, as it is in the single player.A Lesser FateA Lesser Fate's design is based on Weyland-Yutani complexes on colony worlds, like the Primary Operations Complex in the single player game. This map was also featured in the original multiplayer demo for the game.AurigaAs the name suggests, this map is based on the USM Auriga from Alien Resurrection. The big set piece on the map is the Betty docked inside the ship, as shown in the picture on the right.BunkerBunker is a very small and simple two story multiplayer map. There are a few pipes along the lower level that connect to different areas of the map.ColonyColony follows the same design aesthetic of Weyland-Yutani complexes. As to be expected on a planet infested with Xenomorphs, the interior is completely cocooned and extremely dark. Outside the sky is bright green, and an atmosphere processing station can be seen in the background.CompoundCompound has a jungle outpost aesthetic, an obvious tribute to the first Predator film. The map is very small, a few small buildings within a fenced perimeter, with a tunnel underneath the area.DepotDepot is another map that follows the Weyland-Yutani complex designs. Two towers are situated near the middle of the map, and the roofs are protected by electric fences. It is impossible to get on top without getting fried.LeadworksLeadworks is based on the designs of the refinery on Fury 161 from Alien 3. There are small pits with molten metal and very small narrow trenches. Unlike the movie, the map has plenty of weapons for Marines, Corporates, and Predators to use.Lucifer's FateLucifer's Fate very closely resembles the design of A Lesser Fate. However, there have been small yet significant changes to the layout that changes up the strategies used in A Lesser Fate. Also to distinguish it from the previous map is the red, ominous sky and celestial bodies in orbit.Outpost 4Outpost 4 is another Weyland-Yutani themed level, although it is one of the smaller ones. There is a power loader left idle on the map (as pictured on the left), but cannot be used. Another distinguishing feature of this map is the pair of solar panels near the gate. Also, third map in the game to feature green sky.QuarantineQuarantine is a sterile white containment area that clearly failed to contain the Xenomorphs held captive for research. A row of containment cells can be seen with the doors open, and the center piece of the map is the large tube filled with Xenomorphs.ReservoirReservoir is a very dark map with little lighting and a small pool of nearly drained water. The dim lighting of the map is ideal for the Xenomorphs, as well as ventilation shafts for the creatures to get around the map.VerlocThe USS Verloc is the ship holding the team of Marines that were sent to LV-1201. The design of the Verloc is similar to the Sulaco from Aliens, as both ships are of the same class. The big set piece on this map is the dropship in the large center room. There are ramps that lead to other areas of the ship, such as a garage holding parked APCs.System RequirementsOperating System: Windows 98Processor: 450 MHz CPURAM Memory: 128 MB RAMVideo Card: 16 MB video card RAMDirectX: DirectX 8.0Hard Disk Space: 750 MB available</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16372">Prey</game><game id="8015">Quake</game><game id="21912">Planetside: Core Combat</game><game id="12494">RoboCop Versus the Terminator</game><game id="16238">Alien Shooter 2</game><game id="2699">Alien Breed 3D</game><game id="34553">Resident Evil: Operation Raccoon City</game><game id="10630">Star Trek: The Next Generation - Klingon Honor Guard</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/13692/915549-avsp2box.jpg</image></root>