<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15048</id><name>Killzone</name><description>OverviewKillzone is a First-Person Shooter developed by Guerrilla Games and published by Sony Computer Entertainment. It was marketed as the Playstation 2’s answer to Microsoft's Halo: Combat Evolved but only received average reviews upon the game's release.PlotYou take on the role of Captain Jan Templar and his squad, members of the Interplanetary Strategic Alliance (ISA). You are stationed on Vekta, a planet colonized by the ISA, which is under attack by the Helghast - an estranged branch of humanity from the planet Helghan. Your mission is to find a half-Helghast, half-human ISA operative Gregor Hakha who is in possession of a key required to enable the planet's network of Strategic Defense (SD) platforms.Taking control of one of the four playable characters (Captain Templar, Sgt. Rico Velasquez, Shadow Marshall Luger and Gregor Hakha), you fight your way through the waves of invading Helghast forces to reach and enable the SD platform network in order to prevent Helghast reinforcements from reaching the planet's surface.GameplayCampaignKillzone features all of the standard first person shooter conventions, with numerous weapons available to the player with each side having there own weapon types. Each playable character in the game represents a certain class type; while Luger is a stealthy assassin, Rico is the heavy weapons expert. These specialties affect the characters starting load out of weapons, health levels as well as the way in which the level can be completed. For example, Luger may be able to use her increased agility to reach areas that other characters cannot, allowing her to sneak around the level via a different route, silently taking out her unsuspecting targets. This provides the player with different available routes to the end of the level depending on the chosen character.MultiplayerThe multiplayer option in Killzone (known as ‘Battlefields’) allows you to play offline or online. Offline enables up to two players to play locally, with a maximum of 14 AI controlled bots. The online multiplayer supports up to 16 human players in each match. Both offline and online multiplayer modes feature six game types (deathmatch, team deathmatch, defend  destroy, assault, domination and supply drop) on a total of eight playable maps. As in the single player campaign mode, multiplayer matches take place between ISA and Helghast forces, with the player able to choose which side to fight on.LevelsHelghast AssaultSouthern HillsIndustrial SectorShuttle Repair BaysHeadquartersVekta EvacuatesHeadquartersCourtyardScience BuildingCommunications BuildingNew AlliesPark TerminalThe ParkThe Fourth TierStrange CompanyThe Apartment BuildingThe SlumsWaypoint MallHakhaEscapeDunesBeachheadThe DocksTransportationMisty WatersMangroveCode 3-3 FirebaseThe FortressHunting the TraitorThe SwampUp HillThe Trap</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2133">Call of Duty 4: Modern Warfare</game><game id="2347">Call of Duty 2</game><game id="20455">Haze</game><game id="8994">Reign of Fire</game><game id="14560">World War Zero: Iron Storm</game><game id="20777">Call of Duty: World at War</game><game id="7547">Warhammer 40,000: Fire Warrior</game><game id="10461">Clive Barker's Jericho</game><game id="97">Serious Sam: Next Encounter</game><game id="25246">Battlefield: Bad Company 2</game><game id="24713">Modern Warfare 2</game><game id="29221">Call of Duty: Modern Warfare Reflex Edition</game><game id="30544">Conduit 2</game><game id="26423">Call of Duty: Black Ops</game><game id="3857">Project: Snowblind</game><game id="11757">Crysis</game><game id="17828">Battlefield 2142</game><game id="6235">7th Legion</game><game id="23708">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine</game><game id="43056">Avert Fate</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2491510-box_kz.png</image></root>