<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15050</id><name>Atelier Iris: Eternal Mana</name><description>WorldThe game is set in the world of Regallzine, the home of alchemy and Mana, but more specifically; The Kingdom of Esviore. Wars and disputes has divided the kingdom, and the southern parts are no longer under the influence of King Slaith. Instead, each separate city-state of South Esviore runs their own  affairs, trading with one another and conducting own businesses.There exists a legend regarding Avenberry, a city of alchemists that existed many hundreds of years prior to  the game's beginning. No one knows exactly what happened, but it is  said that Avenberry fell because of the misuse of alchemy. Many alchemists and treasure hunters have tried to enter Avenberry and unlock its secrets ever since that time, and the city of Kavoc  was built for that purpose. However, none have been able to get past the  gate that guards the citadel, and Avenberry's secrets have so far been  preserved. Alchemists today are scarce, most basing their research on  the studies of Iris, an alchemist who lived before the fall of  Avenberry, and her theories/books about alchemy called Iris' Theories. They travel the world in search of new alchemaic artifacts, ruins of the past, information and Mana Spirits. The Mana are a race of  beings that allow alchemists to use their power. They augment the power of elements which alchemists extract from objects in the world and  can use them to create magical items. Mana have feelings,  emotions, and personalities just as people do, and many become good  friends with their alchemist, though a few people only sees them as tools.PlotThe young alchemist Klein Kiesling and his Wood Mana friend Popo is trying to crack the mysteries surrounding an old notebook about alchemy which belonged to Klein's grandma, Daphne. They traverse the world in search of special items and more information about alchemy. In the start of the game Klein is attacked by a monster in a forest, and rescued by a girl named Lita Blanchimont whom invites Klein to become a Galgazit, a monster hunter. She appears just like any normal girl at first sight, but it is soon revealed that she is the bearer of a mysterious disease and a pair of wings. An important part in the master plan by the games antagonist, Mull, who wants to resurrect an old abomination called Amalgam. Created by forcibly fusing a lot of different Mana into one being. Something which already occurred hundreds of years ago and brought with it the destruction of Avenberry. Klein and his party has to stop this resurrection at all costs. GameplayThe gameplay in Atelier Iris: Eternal Mana is very typical for a j-rpg, with turn-based battles, random encounters and experience points for leveling up. The battle system is very similar to Final Fantasy X's Conditional Turn-Based system (CTB) as it is not a real time battle system, but not a total turn-based system either where characters (and enemies) does one action per turn. It means that the game pauses when you select prompts for your characters, so you can act without time pressure, but fast characters and enemies can still act several times before others can act even once. A display in the top of the screen shows the order of turns for every character and enemy so that you can use strategic thinking when selecting actions. Klein is the only character who can use mana items and mana synthesis (which duplicates the mana item's effect, at the expense of MP) in battle, as he is the only alchemist. Once the enemies are defeated the party gains experience, gold and possibly items. Players can select skills to level up for each character, and when that character levels up an ordinary level, he/she gains 3 points to that skill. Characters equipped with Mana spirits can get bonus skill points. The player can switch between characters both in battle and out of battle.The game also features several forms of item synthesis. Mana items can be created by Klein using elements extracted from objects and enemies. To create lasting Mana items, Klein requires the help of the Mana spirits, whose health is used in the process. Normal items can be created by shop owners if the player brings them the right items. This often includes food (health) and equipment. Weapon Synthesis involves creating "mana crystals" by combining Mana  stones that you find throughout the game. Each crystal can have up to three abilities or effects, and can be inserted or removed on certain pieces of equipment.  The game lets you explore the world via j-rpg-typical world maps, towns and dungeons. You also have a few abilities available to you throughout the exploration part of the game. A few examples are flying, changing into a rabbit, using a Mana as a footstool, or healing  the whole party. These actions are gained each time a specific Mana joins the  party.Mana SpiritsMana spirits are the key part of the games alchemy system and is used for item synthesis, exploration tools and leveling up skills on characters by "equipping" a Mana spirit to that character. Some Mana have the power to transform into new, even more powerful Mana  forms.Below is a list of each Mana, and their element.  Dour: The Mana Spirit of Wood. He is with Klein, who  named him Popo, at the start of the game. He also provides the player  with tutorials on certain aspects of the game. Uru: The Mana Spirit of Fire. His special ability,  Destruction Blast, allows the player to destroy certain objects on the  screen.Plua: The Mana Spirit of Darkness. Her special  ability gathers nearby monsters for the player to battle, though it does  not always work.Diemia: The Mana Spirit of Stone. His special  ability allows him to act as a stepladder so the player can reach places  otherwise inaccessible.Nymph: The Mana Spirit of Water. Her special  ability, Barrier, creates a barrier that allows the player to travel  over hazards that would otherwise prove a hindrance, such as lightning  and lava.Silwest: The Mana Spirit of Air. She also has  the Barrier action, but some rumors point to her granting flight later  in the game.Aion: The Mana Spirit of Life. She is one of the  oldest of the Mana Spirits, second only to the Mana Spirit of Creation,  Lilith. She has the ability to heal the entire party at will, when the  player calls on her.Eital: The Mana Spirit of Light. Her special  ability drives away monsters for a limited time.Luplus: The Mana Spirit of Time. He is often seen  with Arlin.Grupt: The Mana Spirit of Power, and final form of  Uru.Fanatos: The Mana Spirit of Evil, and final form  of Plua.Flay: The Mana Spirit of Spirit, and final form of  Nymph.Zeilia: The Mana Spirit of Lightning, and final  form of Silwest.Paltia: The Holy Mana Spirit, and final form of  Eital. MusicThe games soundtrack was composed by Akira Tsuchiya, Ken Nakagawa  Daisuke Achiwa. It was released in May  19, 2004 in Japan by TEAM Entertainment.  Tracklist (Translated):  Disc OneWhite Night IllusionGenesisMana, Noisy TimeThe Forest of MeetingIRISTown Where the Bells ChimeRevelation ~introduction~Flask BoyFun Shopping in KavocTo the Unseen WorldWind Over TimeAlchemic BlastWinning Shot!Waterdrop WaltzRefreshing PowerPopo's Pleasant Money LectureThe Name Is Beggur!BullfightThe Story is OverLakesideSleeping RealityLost TechnologyTraveling CompanionThe Forest Where the Witch LivesCute WitchKlein and His Pleasant FriendsBreakSpending the Night TogetherMiraculous Little UniverseAnchor and PickaxeFun Shopping in ArcoseHager's SongTwo Funny PeopleHot or Cool?Popcorn StrategyLooming CrisisFerocious DriveThe Path You WalkWhite Night Imagination (with SE)Total Time: 63 minutes and 24 seconds. Disc TwoDistant HometownBeat of IllusionCrack in the EarthKonkon FountainVillage of Snow and GlassFun Shopping in DuranHuge Game TableAnd Fate Was ChangedThe Way to the Spirit KingSpirit's HometownTree Spirit in the MistEternal GroundSmall WorkshopDO · TA!AlbionHorned EnigmaSucceed on EarthAnimal VillageFinished!Phantom WingsWhat Was Left BehindEternal EyesThe Tower of No ReturnDuke of StratosphereInfernoFrozen LithographUndeveloped RegionVoiceless PoemA Girl's MemoriesRevelationWhistleSadness Is Whisked Away by the WindDrive into the DarkBeat of the Rumbling EarthDeceitful WingsFutureTo Each Their Own WaySilent RhymeIRIS (without Vocals)Total Time: 71 minutes and 38 seconds.  Opening Song: 白夜幻想譚 (Byakuya Gensoutan / White Night Illusion) by Haruka Shimotsuki. Ending Songs: 歩む道 (Ayumu Michi / Walking Path) by Mami Horie (Normal  Ending).Silent Rhyme by Mami Horie (True Ending).  Prequels/Sequels            Atelier Iris: Eternal Mana is a spiritual sequel to the first few Atelier games;           Atelier Marie,          Atelier Elie,         Atelier Lilie,        Atelier Judie and      Atelier Violet, released on Playstation and Playstation 2 between 1997 and 2003 only in Japan. The Iris series is not connected to the first games other than being the same franchise, though. There are two more games in the Iris' series of the Atelier franchise and sequels to Atelier Iris: Eternal Mana;      Atelier Iris 2: The Azoth of Destiny and     Atelier Iris 3: Grand Phantasm. Released on Playstation 2 in 2005 and 2006 (Japanese release date). They are not direct sequels, but is set in the same world and a few characters have cross-game mentions. Atelier Iris 2 is actually a prequel to Atelier Iris, chronologically.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17621">Ar tonelico: Melody of Elemia</game><game id="17659">Grandia</game><game id="21541">Ar tonelico II: Melody of Metafalica</game><game id="1861">Dark Cloud</game><game id="10129">Grandia II</game><game id="259">Grandia III</game><game id="21237">Tales of Symphonia</game><game id="21073">Tales of Symphonia: Dawn of the New World</game><game id="14210">Tales of the Abyss</game><game id="5315">Tales of Legendia</game><game id="11703">Tales of Rebirth</game><game id="595">Tales of Eternia</game><game id="9249">Chrono Trigger</game><game id="20829">Final Fantasy IV</game><game id="6336">Final Fantasy VI</game><game id="4793">Final Fantasy V</game><game id="8918">SEGA AGES 2500 Vol.1: Phantasy Star - Generation:1</game><game id="2924">SEGA AGES 2500 Vol.17: Phantasy Star - Generation:2</game><game id="25349">SEGA AGES 2500 Vol.32: Phantasy Star Complete Collection</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2154862-box_aiem.png</image></root>