<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15051</id><name>Medal of Honor: Allied Assault - Spearhead</name><description>Overview In Medal of Honor: Allied Assault - Spearhead puts players in the shoes  Sgt. Jack Barnes (voiced by                                       Gary Oldman)   who is a paratrooper in the 501st Parachute Infantry Regiment, 101st   Airborne Division. Players will experience the battle of D-Day, the   Battle of the Bulge, and storm Berlin. Spearhead also adds British and   Russian weapons for use in the Single Player campaign and the online   Multiplayer. 12 new maps and one new multiplayer mode, Tug-of-War, were  also added.   Campaign Spearhead spans three campaigns and focuses on the airborne  invasion of        Normandy, the Battle of the       Ardennes Forest in Belgium and  the Battle of      Berlin.   Mission 1: D-Day  In the first mission, Barnes takes part in Operation Neptune where  American airborne forces are dropping behind enemy lines in Normandy.  During the jump Barnes is separated from his squad, but soon afterward  links up with a British commando unit.    Barnes helps the commandos in destroying a train carrying 88mm artillery  pieces and anti-aircraft guns as well as eliminate a high ranking  German officer in the process.     Mission 2: The Bulge         After the Normandy invasion, Barnes returns to the 101st where he is deployed to the Ardennes forest to help hold the line.   With food and ammunition running short, Barnes leads a squad of  paratroopers through the foggy forest and breaks in a German supply  depot, where they steal two supply trucks and make it back to friendly  lines safely.    Though later that night, enemy artillery fires on the paratroops and  German tanks and soldiers attempt to overrun the American line. Barnes  and the troops beat back the attack, and finally, on Christmas Day, the  American forces launch an offensive and successfully push the Germans  out of Bastogne.     Mission 3: Berlin  In the final mission, Barnes is sent to Berlin as part of a covert op  with the  Red Army. As the downfall of the Third Reich is near, Barnes is sent to  capture important documents in the city's Chancellory. He retrieves the  documents and soon after finds a T-34 tank. The tank crew, under the  command of Barnes, fights their way back to friendly lines, where they  find that the Soviets are under heavy fire from German tanks.   After holding out against German counterattack, Soviet bomber planes  come to their aid, eliminating the remaining tanks and troops and ending  the Battle.    Weapons                              Thompson                             MP40                            Sten Mk. II                        PPSH                      M1 Garand                    Kar-98                   Lee-Enfield                  Mosin-Nagant                 SVT-40 (Scoped)    Kar-98 (Scoped)               MG42               Panzerschreck              M1911            Webley Revolver  Walther P38           Nebelwerfer          Flak 88 Flakvierling   Sticky bomb</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13970">World War II: Sniper - Call to Victory</game><game id="14482">Medal of Honor: Allied Assault - Breakthrough</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1987/692976-moh_spearhead_front.jpg</image></root>