<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15065</id><name>Dark Messiah of Might &amp; Magic</name><description>OverviewDark Messiah of Might and Magic is a first-person spin-off of the long-running Might  Magic franchise. The story follows Sareth, a wizard's apprentice, in his attempts to retrieve the "skull of shadows", an artifact found near the beginning of the game. The game was developed by Arkane Studios, makers of Arx Fatalis and later Dishonored.GameplayDark Messiah's gameplay mixes first-person melee combat with RPG elements, similar to the Elder Scrolls series. A variety of weapons are available, including swords, staves, and bows. Each weapon or armor type has several variants with different enchantments that enhance their properties.Much importance is placed on using the environment in combat. Throwing or kicking enemies against spike beds, off cliffs, into fire, or into breakaway supports are among the most effective strategies.Later, the player earns demonic powers that grant added strength when using melee, but slowly siphons health as a consequence (as well as frightening nearby friendly NPCs, which can cause mission failure).Up-close and personal melee combatDark Messiah also features a skill system similar to those found in other RPGs. By accomplishing missions or reaching specific points, the player earns skill points which may then be used to unlock and develop new skills and techniques. The points can be placed into three categories:CombatMagicMiscellaneousThis allows the player to specialize their character to their personal needs. There is no way to max out all skill trees in a playthrough, even by completing optional mission objectives, so specialization is encouraged.The game has up to four multiple endings, though all choices appear only in the last two levels. The first choice relies on completing an optional objective to purge yourself of your demonic abilities, and the second is immediately after the final boss on whether to join or destroy the soon-to-be-awakened lord of darkness.Dark Messiah also has an inventory system. Items can be picked up from dead enemies, looted from crates, given, or pickpocketed, similar to many other RPG releases.Combat SkillsMelee CombatLevel 1: Flurry of Blows - Allows you to deliver an unlimited number of Fast Strikes in a flurry.Level 2: Charge - A powerful attack to stun your enemies. (Sprint Power Strike)Shield - You can now use a shield to block enemy attacks like arrows and flame arrows.Level 3: Break Parry - Enables Flurry of Blows to sometimes break enemy parry.Leaping AttackA powerful strike that will knock the enemy off balance. (Jump Power Strike)Whirlwind AttackA rotating attack that hits several enemies at once, killing most of them on the spot. (Crouch Adrenaline Power Strike)ArcheryLevel 1: Allows you to zoom in when using the bow.Level 2: Gives you a steadier grip on the bow, making shots more accurate.Level 3: Allows you to reload more quickly.StrengthLevel 1: All attacks with a weapon do 2 Damage.Level 2: All attacks with a weapon do 3 Damage.Level 3: All attacks with a weapon do 6 Damage.Critical HitLevel 1: Gives you 2% chance to do double damage on each of your Power Strikes.Level 2: Gives you 4% chance to do double damage on each of your Power Strikes.AdrenalineAllows you to stock more Adrenaline and in fact two Fatalities (instant kills) in a row.Magic SkillsDark VisionAllows you to see in the dark.Flame ArrowCast a magic fire projectile. Cast and Hold to guide the projectile. Deals fire damage.Adrenaline Effect: casts multiple projectiles at the same timeFire TrapSets a magical trap that your enemy can't see. Explodes when an enemy is near. Inflicts fire damage.FreezeSprays a non-lethal ice-cold substance that freezes an enemy for a couple of seconds. Creates a slippery pool of ice if it hits the ground.Adrenaline Effect: permanently freeze a creatureLightning BoltCreate a lightning projectile that will electrocute the target enemy. Bounces off walls. Deals electrical damage. Cast on enemies standing in the water to enhance the damage!Adrenaline Effect: creates a chain of Lightning that will jump from the main target to any nearby enemiesFireballSend out a ball of fire that will explode on contact, hitting the target enemy and all nearby creatures. Cast and hold to guide the projectile. Deals fire and area damage.Adrenaline Effect: instantly kills your target opponentInfernoThrow flames in front of you and set enemies on fire. Deals fire damage over time.Adrenaline Effect: deals extra damageTelekinesisGrab and move objects from a distance. The more mana you have, the heavier the objects you can lift.Adrenaline Effect: allows you to grab living creatures and massive objectsHealHeal your wounds and regenerate your Health.CharmCharm a hostile creature and get it to fight alongside you for a limited time.SanctuaryCreate a magical shield that will protect you from physical attacks and magic projectiles for a short period of time.WeakenWeaken an enemy for a short period of time.Adrenaline Effect: permanently shrinks your targetted enemyMiscellaneous SkillsStaminaAllows the player to use stamina-based skills such as sprinting, swimming and kicking for a longer time before having to rest.EnduranceRaises the player's maximum Health and also effects the kind of armor the player can wear.Poison ResistanceMakes the player almost invulnerable to any kind of poison.VitalityIncreases the health regeneration rate of the player.AlertnessHighlights hidden items and secret areas if the player remains still for a moment.Magic AffinityGreatly raises your base maximum mana.StealthAllows the player to creep up on enemies from behind and stab them for a quick kill.BurglarAllows the player to pick locks on doors and chests.Mana RegenerationIncreases the Mana regeneration rate of the player.WeaponsSwordsWeaponDamageSpecial TraitsSkill RequirementsShort Sword2Long Sword3Melee Combat 1Naga Silksword3Adds 2% chance of Critical HitCritical Hit 1Souldrinker4Adds 30% of damage dealt to the player's healthStrenght 3Superior Naga Silksword6Adds 4% chance of Critical HitCritical Hit 2Earthfire Sword6Adds 6 damage points (total of 12) to enemies vulnerable to fireStrenght 2Cleaver7Strenght 2Sword of the Dragonclaw9Adds 9 damage points (total of 18) to Undead creaturesStrenght 3DaggersWeaponDamageSpecial TraitsSkill RequirementsDaggers1Can be thrown at enemies whenever:the player performs a Power Strikethe enemy is fleeingthe adrenaline meter is fullPoison Kriss2Poisons enemy when dealing a Power Strike with the weapon chargedStealth 3Daggers of Frost2Freezes enemy when dealing a Power Strike with the weapon chargedStealth 2Gutting Kriss4Adds 4% chance to Critical HitStealth 2Lightning Daggers4Adds 4 damage points (total of 8) to enemies vulnerable to lightningMelee Combat 2Daggers of the Dragonfang7Adds 7 damage points (total of 14) to Undead creaturesGlows when Undead creatures are nearStealth 3StaffsWeaponDamageSpecial TraitsSkill RequirementsWooden Staff1Combat Staff2Melee Combat 1Staff of Reflection2Launches a lightning bolt when dealing a Power Strike with the weapon chargedPress the "Parry" key to capture any magical projectile cast at you to charge your staffMagic Affinity 1Soulreaver Staff2Steal's your enemies' Mana upon any successful hitsMagica Affinity 3Staff of the Firelord3Adds 3 damage points (total of 6) to enemies vulnerable to fireMelee Combat 1Staff of the Dragonbone7Adds 7 damage points (total of 14) to Undead creaturesMagic Affinity 3NOTE: Staffs are slow weapons and don't really inflict much damage, but can be quite useful when fighting packs of enemies, seen that they can easily stun or knock down your enemies.Misc. MeleeClub -- deals 1 damagePickaxe -- deals 2 damageAxe -- deals 2 damageHook -- deals 3 damageRangedWeaponDamageSpecial TraitsSkill RequirementsRope Bow1Arrows fired with this bow spawn a rope when they hit a wooden surfaceBow2Poison Bow2Creates a magical poison cloud around the targetArchery 2Bow of Winter's Breath2Freezes target when a charged arrow is firedArchery 2Long Bow4Archery 1Elven Bow5Adds 3% chance of Critical HitCritical Hit 2Bow of Fiery Rage7Adds 7 damage points (total of 14) to enemies vulnerable to fireArchery 3Bow of the Dragonhorn8Adds 8 damage points (total of 16) to Undead creaturesArchery 3Shields  ArmorShieldsNameHit ResistanceSkill RequirementsOrc Shield60Melee Combat 2Wooden Shield120Melee Combat 2Stonehelm Guard's Shield180Melee Combat 2Black Guard's Shield180Melee Combat 2Orc Buckler240Melee Combat 3Vampire Knight's Shield240Melee Combat 3Earthfire ShieldIndestructibleIncreases the player's protection from fire attacksMelee Combat 3Lightning ShieldIndestructibleElectrifies enemy upon any successful blockMelee Combat 3Robes  ArmorNameArmor ClassSpecial TraitsSkill RequirementsWizard Robe1Adds 10 Mana pointsMagic Affinity 1Arcane Robe2Adds 20 Mana pointsMagic Affinity 2Chainmail Armor2Endurance 1Master Thief's Outfit2The player makes no sound when he/she movesStealth 3Plate Armor3Endurance 2Shadowsteel Armor4Adds 10 Health pointsEndurance 3RingsRing of Arcane Brilliance -- adds 10 Mana pointsRing of the Weaponmaster -- adds 2% chance to Critical HitRing of Phoenix -- if the player's health reaches 0, the ring prevents you from dying and restores your healthRing of Might -- adds 1 damage dealt pointRing of Regeneration -- slowly regenerates the player's healthRing of Fire Protection -- increases the player's protection from fire attacksEnemiesCommon EnemiesA NecromancerBlack Guards -- your run of the mill evil hired mercenariesZombies -- the weakest of all the undead minionsGhouls -- these undead creatures are a lot harder to kill than Zombies, see that they are feral and incredibly agileNecromancers -- masters of dark magicNecrolords -- this class of Necromancers will promptly summon the dead to their aid and use ranged magic on youOrcs -- fearsome warriors that fight with honor; they are resistant to fire based attacks, but are weak to lightningFacehuggers -- flying octopus-like creatures that attack in groups and use lightning-based magic attacksA Vampire KnightGoblins -- small weak creatures that fight in packs, hoping to overwhelm their victims; they are somewhat resistant tofire, but not to lightningSpiders -- these agile venomous arachnids come in various sizes; they're weak to fire-based weapons and attacksVampire Knights -- the most skilled members of the Black Guard; they are quite fast and skilledLich -- powerful Necromancers that have become undead, they can hide themselves with invisibility magicCyclops -- big and slow, but powerful enough to pose a considerable threat; strong against fire magic, but weak against lightning. Their weakness is the eyePao Kai -- ancient blind dragons that use powerful lightning-based attacks to stun their opponents; they're generally too strong to be killed without the some external assistanceChaptersDark Messiah of Might and Magic is divided into 9 Chapters plus a Prologue and an Epilogue.PROLOGUECHAPTER ONEThe Gate of StonehelmCHAPTER TWOThe Gleam of a Cold KnifeCHAPTER THREEDead Man's TrailCHAPTER FOURAcross the Sea of BloodCHAPTER FIVEThe Temple of the SpiderCHAPTER SIXThe Altar of the SkullCHAPTER SEVENFire In the BloodCHAPTER EIGHTIn the House of AshesCHAPTER NINECity of FlameEPILOGUEMultiplayerDark messiah features a Multiplayer portion that was developed independently, by Kuju Entertainment. Many people have drawn parallels to it and the battlefield franchise. Two playable factions exist: Human, and Undead. The two teams compete on a large map, vying for strategic positions.SoundtrackThe original score for Dark Messiah of Might  Magic was composed by Cris Velasco and Sascha Dikiciyan.Track No.Song TitleRunning Time01The Gates of Stonehelm01.2802Crawling from the Deep02.3703Redskull Island01.2004Soulmate02.0605Avatar of the Goddess04.5506The Dark Messiah01.4007Dark Revelation02.1808Leana's Theme00.5809Wings of Destruction02.4210Summoning the Soul-Dragon01.3111Awakening01.17PC System RequirementsAs displayed on the back of the box.Operating System : Windows XP (will sometimes work with Vista, but it's not guarranteed)Processor : AMD Athlon, Pentium IV 2.6 GHz (3 GHz Recommended)Memory : 512 MB RAM (1 GB Recommended)Video Card : 128 MB DirectX 9 - compliant video card (256 MB recommended)Sound Card : DirectX 9 compliant sound cardDirectX : DirectX 9 or HigherDVD Drive : 4x or fasterHard Drive Space : 7 GB freePeripherals : Windows compatible mouse and keyboardMultiplayer : Broadband internet connection with 64kbps upstream orfaster.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20238">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion</game><game id="1567">Die by the Sword</game><game id="11254">Savage 2: A Tortured Soul</game><game id="1528">Savage</game><game id="21505">Project Offset</game><game id="21192">Mount &amp; Blade</game><game id="4523">Thief: The Dark Project</game><game id="10784">Arx Fatalis</game><game id="15660">Hexen II</game><game id="13385">Breakdown</game><game id="25453">Pirates, Vikings and Knights II</game><game id="21473">Blade of Darkness</game><game id="2870">Ian Livingstone's Deathtrap Dungeon</game><game id="8456">An Elder Scrolls Legend: Battlespire</game><game id="33394">The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim</game><game id="26490">Zeno Clash II</game><game id="22011">Zeno Clash</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/151/846003-dark_messiah_of_might_and_magic_pc.jpg</image></root>