<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15092</id><name>Turrican</name><description>OverviewThe story (like found in the home computer manuals) is fast told: A long time ago the three-headed creature called Morgul was banished by the hero Devolon to an unknown dimension. The reason for this feat was that Morgul tormented the mankind with fears and nightmares. After Morgul's banishment fear and sleepless nights disappeared out of peoples lives. But since lately the people suffer again from a serious state of dread and fear and the nightmares come back. The apprehension is great that Morgul has returned to his kingdom. So armed with the latest weapons and technical equipment the player has to find and destroy Morgul in his kingdom.An alternate story is given in the Genesis/TurboGrafx-16 versions: Here is Morgul (Multiple-Organism-Unit-Link) a powerfull ecosystem generation network which the early colonists used to render the world of Alterra inhabitable. After a cataclysmic quake all system interface functions were severed and Morgul rebelled. He twisted all lifeforms of Alterra to his brutal, destructive purposes. To recapture Alterra genetic scientists created Turrican, a bio-engineered mutant warrior. Turricans task is to eliminate hostile organisms from Alterras five colonies and to destroy the three faces of Morgul.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2190">Gunstar Heroes</game><game id="20743">Metal Slug 7</game><game id="1421">Ranger X</game><game id="4350">Contra</game><game id="21761">Metroid</game><game id="847">Metal Slug</game><game id="16837">Switchblade II</game><game id="17939">Konami Collector's Series: Castlevania &amp; Contra</game><game id="1713">Doom Troopers: Mutant Chronicles</game><game id="12270">Subway Vigilante</game><game id="7473">Universal Soldier</game><game id="8292">Super Metroid</game><game id="5708">Metroid II: Return of Samus</game><game id="5744">Hard 'n Heavy</game><game id="9308">Assassin</game><game id="7227">Abuse</game><game id="8582">Fatal Rewind</game><game id="3253">Jim Power in "Mutant Planet"</game><game id="37786">Devastator</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/7/73970/1256262-turrican_genesis_front1.jpg</image></root>