<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15106</id><name>Fullmetal Alchemist 2: Curse of the Crimson Elixir</name><description>Characters  Edward Elric: The Fullmetal Alchemist, his nickname is given because the term "Fullmetal" is used to describe a person who is stubborn. In the series it is often mistakenly attributed by minor characters to Ed's automail arm and leg, or Al's armor body.   Alphonse Elric: Al is the younger brother of Edward Elric, but is often confused to be older than Ed because he is trapped in a suit of armor twice as large as he is.   Roy Mustang (sidekick, non-playable): The Flame Alchemist, a man who specializes in flame alchemy. He is Ed's immediate superior in the military and seems to have his own ambitious objectives unknown to those but his closest confidantes. He is also quite the ladies' man.   Riza Hawkeye (sidekick, non-playable): One of Mustang's most trusted confidantes, a severe woman who can remain cool under even the greatest pressure. She is an officer highly capable of accomplishing any designated mission and is an excellent shot with the gun.   Maes Hughes (non-playable): One of Mustang's most trusted confidantes, a warm-hearted family man whose favorite thing to do is show off pictures of his young daughter to anyone. He is a skilled knife thrower.   Alex Louis Armstrong (sidekick, non-playable, mini-boss): Another member of Mustang's group, a man who can use alchemy to increase the muscular strength of his already extremely well built body.   Winry Rockbell (non-playable): The childhood friend of Ed and Al, an automail mechanic.   Arlen Glostner (non-playable): An archaeologist who specializes in certain ancient civilizations. This old codger is stubborn and cranky, but his soul still burns with a fiery passion. And yet he seems to be haunted by shadowy memories of the past...   Jack Crowley (non-playable): Once nicknamed "The Silver Bullet Alchemist", this former state alchemist was stripped of his certification long ago.   Elma (non-playable): A beautiful but enigmatic woman who appears to Ed and Al time and time again. She seems to be pleading for their help...   List of Enemies    Lion Chimera Cornello (Boss)  Bald (Boss)  Scar (Boss)  Armstrong (Mini Boss)  Phantom (Boss)  Dragon Golem Spider Golem Phantom (Boss)  Jack Crowley (Boss)  Jack Crowley - Golem (Final boss)      DescriptionBased on the anime and manga of the same name, Fullmetal Alchemist 2 follows the journey of the two brothers Edward and Alphonse Elric. It's a prequel to Fullmetal Alchemist and the Broken Angel for PS2, with 30 minutes of original animation exclusive to the game.In the action RPG style gameplay, players control Edward while Alphonse tags along as a sidekick.Edward can use alchemy to transmute mundane objects into a variety of weapons for him or Al to use. The game includes a DVD with two new episodes of season two in the series!</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14300">Dragon Ball Z: Sagas</game><game id="4214">Naruto: Uzumaki Chronicles</game><game id="23866">Fullmetal Alchemist and the Broken Angel</game><game id="30801">Fullmetal Alchemist: Brotherhood</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2193289-box_fma2.png</image></root>