<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15134</id><name>MechWarrior 4: Vengeance</name><description>OverviewMechWarrior 4: Vengeance is a computer game developed by FASA Interactive and published by Microsoft. It was released on November 24, 2000. This game is the fourth game in the MechWarrior series. It takes place in BattleTech universe where the pinnacle of all war machines are huge, heavily armed robots called BattleMechs. The player pilots one of these 'Mechs and uses a variety of available weapons to battle enemy 'Mechs, tanks and other vehicles. An expansion pack, MechWarrior 4: Black Knight, was released on October 31, 2001, and a subsequent stand-alone expansion, MechWarrior 4: Mercenaries was released in November 7, 2002.Free ReleaseTo celebrate the BattleTech Universe's 25th anniversary, a free release of MechWarrior 4 was planned, but legal red tape held the release back by a year. Fortunately, the MechWarrior 4 Free Release saw the light of day and is available at MekTek.com. For more information, please consult the MekTek MechWarrior 4 Free Release page.PlotThe game takes place on the Inner Sphere planet Kentares IV and its moon. The player takes control of Ian Dresari, son of famed Clan War hero Duke Eric Dresari and heir to the throne of Kentares.A civil war erupts on the planet after William Dresari, a cousin of Ian, betrays the family and seizes the throne for himself under the banner of Katherine "Katrina" Steiner. A surprise attack by Steiner forces on the Dresari royal palace leaves the majority of the royal family dead. Ian meets up with his uncle Sir Peter Dresari on the moon orbiting Kentares to launch a guerrilla campaign to take back Kentares IV from Steiner. Ian fights alongside fellow resistance MechWarriors, Casey Nolan, Jen McQuarrie, and Jules Gonzales, and their commander Elise Rathburn in various missions. The resistance abandons its base on the moon and sets up camp for the first time in Kentares' arctic regions.There are two possible endings to this game which depend on actions taken by the player throughout the game.Game ModesCampaignThe campaign contains 26 missions divided into 7 "ops", each with different environments. Each operation contains about 3-6 objectives, with the exception being Op 7. In the first few missions only a few smaller 'Mechs are available. As the game progresses, more 'Mechs and weapons become available. These come in the form of salvage from previous missions. Between missions the player can outfit 'Mechs with different weapons and also assign 'Mechs to one of your three Lancemate slots.Instant ActionThis mode lets you play with any of the 21 'Mechs in the game. You can play any of the campaign missions (even those which you cannot access in campaign yet) or wave missions in which you can select up to four other 'Mechs and fight them in a deathmatch.There is also a master trial mode in which the computer randomly picks a stock 'Mech for you. It also randomly picks one map to play on and three stock 'Mechs as enemies. You have to successively destroy all three enemies in a one-on-one fight.MultiplayerMultiplayer has 9 game types and about 12 maps built in, with more user-made maps available for download.The hud of a mechGame types:Destruction - simple deathmatchTeam Destruction - team deathmatch.Attrition - similar to deathmatch, but points are awarded for damage dealt.Team Attrition - Attrition, but in teams.Capture the Flag - points are awarded for bringing the flag from enemy base to yours.King of the Hill - points are awarded for staying in specific area of the map.Team King of the Hill - King of the hill, but in teams.Steal the Beacon - points are awarded for carrying the beacon.Escort - points are awarded for destroying enemy VIP (a small 'Mech).The multiplayer is no longer hosted by Microsoft, and it isn't supported by MSN Zone. However, Gamespy Arcade still works.The 'Mechs'Mechs are classified into four weight categories. They are also either from Clans or Inner Sphere. Clan 'Mechs are generally superior to Inner Sphere 'Mechs of the same weight.Inner Sphere ‘MechsLight ‘MechsNameInformationRavenManufacturer:	Hellespont 'Mech WorksModel: RVN-3LClass:	LightCost: 5,701,725 C-billsMass:	35 tonsChassis:	Hellespont Type RArmor:	Hellespont Lite Ferro-FibrousEngine:	Hermes 210 XLCommunications System: Ceres Metals Model 666 w/Guardian ECM SuitSpeed:	97.2 km/h km/hJump Jets:	NoneArmament: 1xSRM-6, 2xMedium Lasers, 1xBeagle Active Probe, 1xNarc Missile Beacon, 1xTAG, 1xGuardian ECM SuiteOsirisManufacturer:	Achernar BattleMechs[1]Model: OSR-3DClass:	LightCost: 5,243,550 C-billsMass:	30 tonsChassis:	FITES-O Endo SteelArmor:	StarGuard Ferro-FibrousEngine:	Pharaoh 240 XLCommunications System: Achernar Electronics HID-8.7Speed:	129.6 km/hJump Jets:	Rawlings 61Armament: 5xER Medium Lasers, 1xSRM-6, 1xMachine GunMedium ‘MechsNameInformationBushwackerManufacturer:	TharHes IndustriesIntroduced: 3053Model: BSW-X1Class:	MediumMass:	55 tonsChassis:	Earthwerk GRFArmor:	Kallon Unity Weave Ferro-Fibrous with CASEEngine:	Hermes 275 XLSpeed:	86.4 km/hJump Jets:	NoneArmament: 1xAutocannon/10, 2xLRM-5s, 1xER Large Laser, 2xMachine GunsChimeraManufacturer:	Brigadier Corporation, Independence Weaponry, Kressly Warworks (under license)Introduced: 3063[1]Model: CMA-1SClass:	MediumCost: 6,737,500 C-billsMass:	40 tonsChassis:	Chameleon Light Endo 2 Endo SteelArmor:	StarGuard CCMEngine:	GM 240 XLCommunications System: Corean Transband-J12Speed:	97.2 km/hJump Jets:	Rawlings 40Armament: 1xMachine Gun, 1xER Large Laser, 1xER Medium Laser, 1xMRM-20HellspawnManufacturer:	General Motors[1]Introduced: 3062[2]Model: HSN-7DClass:	MediumCost: 8,375,200 C-billsMass:	45 tonsChassis:	GM Fury-M Endo SteelArmor:	StarGuard IIIEngine:	GM 270 XLCommunications System: Dalban SuperMicronics w/Guardian ECMSpeed:	97.2 km/hJump Jets:	Rawlings 80Armament: 3xMedium Pulse Lasers, 2xLRM-10sUzielManufacturer:	Defiance IndustriesModel: UZL-3SClass:	MediumCost: 9,785,700 C-billsMass:	50 tonsChassis:	Foundation E50 Endo SteelArmor:	Maximillian 100Engine:	GM 300 XLSpeed:	97.2 km/hJump Jets:	Rawlings 50Armament: 1xLB-X Autocannon/2, 1xER Medium Laser, 1xLarge Pulse Laser, 2xER Small Lasers, 1xSRM-6Heavy ‘MechsNameInformationArgusManufacturer:	Achernar BattleMechs, Robinson Standard BattleWorksIntroduced: 3059[1]Model: AGS-4DClass:	HeavyCost: 11,978,400 C-billsMass:	60 tonsChassis:	1A Type 12 Endo SteelArmor:	StarGuard II with CASEEngine:	GM 300 XL EngineCommunications System: Achernar Electronics HID-8.7Speed:	86.4 km/hJump Jets:	NoneArmament: 1 x Rotary Autocannon/5, 1 x Machine Gun, 1 x LRM-10, 2 x ER Medium LasersCatapultManufacturer:	Hollis Incorporated, Yori 'Mech WorksIntroduced: 2561[1]Model: CPLT-C1Class:	HeavyCost: 5,790,125 C-billsMass:	65 tonsChassis:	Hollis Mark IIArmor:	10 tons of Durallex HeavyEngine:	Magna 260Speed:	64.8 km/hJump Jets:	Anderson Propulsion 21Armament: 2xLRM-15s, 4xMedium LasersThanatosManufacturer:	StarCorps IndustriesModel: TNS-4SClass:	HeavyCost: 19,339,249 C-billsMass:	75 tonsChassis:	StarFrame Heavy Endo SteelArmor:	Durallex HeavyEngine:	PlasmaStar 375 XLSpeed:	86.4 km/hJump Jets:	Audi-Fokker Mark IVArmament: 1xMRM-20, 1xER Large Laser, 2xER Medium Lasers, 1xMedium Pulse Laser, 1xC3 Slave Unit, 1xECM SuiteAssault ‘MechsNameInformationAtlasManufacturer:	Yori 'Mech Works, Defiance Industries, Independence Weaponry, Robinson Standard BattleWorksIntroduced: 2755Model: AS7-DClass:	AssaultCost: 9,626,000 C-billsMass:	100 tonsChassis:	Foundation Type 10XArmor:	Durallex Heavy SpecialEngine:	Vlar 300Communications System: Angst DiscomSpeed:	54.0 km/hJump Jets: NoneArmament: 1xAutocannon/20, 1xLRM-20, 1xSRM-6, 4xMedium LasersAwesomeManufacturer:	Technicron Manufacturing, Irian BattleMechs UnlimitedIntroduced: 2665Model: AWS-8QClass:	AssaultCost: 6,598,170 C-billsMass:	80 tonsChassis:	Technicron Type GArmor:	Durallex HeavyEngine:	Pitban 240Speed:	54.0 km/hJump: Jets	NoneArmament: 3xPPCs, 1xSmall LaserMaulerManufacturer:	Luthien Armor WorksIntroduced: 3048[1]Model: MAL-1RClass:	AssaultCost: 18,399,600 C-billsMass:	90 tonsChassis:	Alshain Class 101Armor:	New Samarkand Royal Ferro-Fibrous with CASEEngine: Hermes 270 XLSpeed:	54.0 km/hJump Jets:	NoneArmament: 2xER Large Lasers, 2xLRM-15s, 4xAutocannon/2sClan ‘MechsLight ‘MechsNameInformationCougarManufacturer:	Ironhold Alpha Complex (Clan Jade Falcon)Introduced: 3058[1]Model: PrimeClass:	LightCost: 6,065,438 C-billsMass:	35 tonsChassis:	JF 3 Light Endo SteelArmor:	Compound JF Ferro-FibrousEngine:	175 JF ExtralightSpeed:	86 km/hJump Jets:	NoneArmament: 2x Large Pulse Lasers, 2x LRM-10sMedium ‘MechsNameInformationShadow CatManufacturer:	Barcella BetaIntroduced: 3003Model: PrimeClass:	MediumCost: 11,785,510 C-billsMass:	45 tonsChassis:	Type 79-45 Endo SteelArmor:	Compound H17 Ferro-Fibrous with CASEEngine:	RFUM 270 XLSpeed:	97 km/h (130 km/h with MASC)Jump Jets:	Model KY BoostersArmament: 1x Gauss Rifle, 2x ER Medium LasersHeavy ‘MechsNameInformationLokiManufacturer: VariousIntroduced: 2926Model: PrimeClass:	HeavyCost: 19,074,687 C-billsMass:	65 tonsChassis:	T-E H65 StandardArmor:	Forging Omni-H24Engine:	Fusion 325 XLCommunications System: CH2B Alpha-ComSpeed:	86.4 km/hJump Jets:	NoneArmament: 1xAnti-Missile System, 2xER PPCs, 4xAnti-Personnel Pods, 3xER Medium Lasers, 1xStreak SRM-6, 2xMachine GunsMad CatManufacturer:	Wolf Clan Site #2, Wolf Clan Site #1Introduced: 2945Model: PrimeClass:	HeavyCost: 24,233,124 C-billsMass:	75 tonsChassis:	Type W3 Endo-SteelArmor:	Composite A-2 Ferro-FibrousEngine:	Starfire 375 XLSpeed:	86.4 km/hJump Jets:	NoneArmament: 2xER Large Lasers, 2xER Medium Lasers, 1xMedium Pulse Laser, 2xLRM-20s, 2xMachine GunsNova CatManufacturer:	Barcella Alpha, Irece AlphaModel: PrimeClass:	HeavyCost: 17,672,917 C-billsMass:	70 tonsChassis:	Mynx Type HeavyArmor:	Alpha Compound PlateEngine:	Consolidated 280 XL FusionSpeed:	65 km/hJump Jets:	NoneArmament: 3 ER Large Lasers, 2 ER PPCsThorManufacturer: Eagle Craft Group, St. Louis MechWorksIntroduced: 2872Model: PrimeClass:	HeavyCost: 21,320,834 C-billsMass:	70 tonsChassis:	JFS-703Armor:	J63-3E Ferro-FibrousEngine:	Redline 350 XLSpeed:	86.4 km/hJump Jets:	JF StandardArmament: 1xLB 10-X Autocannon, 1xLRM-15, 1xER PPCVultureManufacturer:	VariousIntroduced: 2963Model: PrimeClass:	HeavyCost: 15,292,000 C-billsMass:	60 tonsChassis:	Eden Mk 60-OMArmor:	Compound SJ6CW Ferro-FibrousEngine:	300 Type I XLCommunications System: Build OSJ-41Speed: 86.4 km/hJump Jets:	NoneArmament: 2x LRM-20s, 2x Medium Pulse Lasers, 2x Large Pulse LasersAssault ‘MechsNameInformationDaishiManufacturer:	Wolf Clan Site #1Introduced: 3010Model: PrimeClass:	AssaultCost: 29,350,000 C-billsMass:	100 tonsChassis:	Titan HX StandardArmor:	Compound 12B2 StandardEngine:	Starfire 300 XLSpeed:	54 km/hJump Jets:	NoneArmament: 4 x ER Large Lasers, 4 x Medium Pulse Lasers, 2 x Ultra Autocannon/5s, 1 x LRM-10Mad Cat Mark IIManufacturer: Manufacturing Plant DSF-94Introduced: 3066Class:	AssaultCost: 24,036,900 C-billsMass:	90 tonsChassis:	DSAM Endo 4Armor:	Forging ZM15 Ferro-FibrousEngine:	Type 79 360 Fusion XLSpeed:	68 km/hJump Jets:	Grandthrust Mk. 5Armament: 2 x Gauss Rifles, 2 x LRM-10s, 4 x ER Medium LasersGameplayMechwarrior 4 features vastly simplified gameplay compared to previous Mechwarrior entries. Players use their 'Mechs weaponry to attack other 'Mechs as well as tanks, aircraft and buildings. Like previous BattleTech games, weapons generate heat and players must manage their firing rates to prevent overheating.In Mechwarrior 4, players no longer have to worry about cooking off their ammunition at high heat levels however. Destroying a 'Mech's legs is no longer instant death. Instead destroying a leg means the leg is merely "crippled" causing a severe speed drop as well as removing the ability to walk backwards. Players can no longer direct their jump jets and jump jets merely allow the 'Mech to jump into the air for a period of time.Like previous games, the damage model is color coded ranging from Green, Yellow, Orange, Red, flashing Red and Black; Green is full or near full armor and Black is completely destroyed. Weapons destruction typically happens when the part is flashing Red. There is an odd property in the damage model where attacking a destroyed body part will not only transfer the damage to another body part but also bypass some of the armor on that part. The leg will transfer damage to the other leg and the left and right torsos will transfer damage to the center torso.The 'Mech Lab has also been simplified. In previous entries, players must assign where they want to carry ammunition and heatsinks. This is no longer the case in Mechwarrior 4. Ammunition and heatsinks simply take up weight. Heatsinks cannot be destroyed and destroying the weapon will also destroy the ammunition assigned to that weapon. Players can no longer assign what type of engines they want and the types of equipment that a 'Mech can carry is preset. Jump jets can only be put on certain 'Mechs and players can no longer choose how many jump jets they want.Weapon placements are now color coded: Red for energy, Green for missiles and Yellow for ballistics. Weapons take up slots, with more powerful weapons such as the PPC taking up three or even four slots. The 'Mechs have a certain amount of color coded slots on each hardpoint and only weapons that match the color can be placed there. Clan 'Mechs and some Inner Sphere designs have white colored "Omni slots" which allow any weapon to be placed there. Ammunition for missiles and ballistics can be added in one ton increments.Players can assign the tonnage of armor to each part of the 'Mech in 0.1 ton increments, with minimum being 0.1 tons of armor on the part and the maximum predetermined based on the 'Mech. There are three types of armor. The standard Ferro Fibrous armor provides the base amount of protection. Reflective and Reactive armor types weight twice as much but halves the damage from energy and ballistics weapons respectively. Parts in Mechwarrior 4 require at least two hits to destroy regardless of armor. Therefore a 'Mech with only 0.1 tons of armor on the center torso can take a direct hit from a PPC but still operate. Because of this mechanic, players often remove all the armor from the head and rear torso; these parts are incredibly hard to hit and even if they are hit, they require at least two shots to be completely destroyed.'Mech PacksIn August 2002 Microsoft released two add-ons to MechWarrior 4: Vengeance, the Clan 'Mech Pack and Inner Sphere 'Mech Pack. Each pack contains four new 'Mechs and a few other bonuses. Many players were disappointed by the fact that new 'Mechs can be used only in instant action or multiplayer, and not in campaign.'Mechs from Clan 'Mech Pack:Arctic Wolf - MediumCauldron-Born - HeavyKodiak - AssaultMasakari - Assault'Mechs from Inner Sphere 'Mech Pack:Dragon -HeavyHighlander - AssaultHunchback - MediumZeus - AssaultSoundtrackCD CoverThe Mechwarrior 4: Vengeance soundtrack was composed by Duane Decker and released on CD in 2000.#TitleLength1.Aftermath3:012.Daggers3:243.Mystic2:544.Push2:255.Indecision2:166.T12:237.Mechwarrior 4 Opening Sequence4:188.Ominous0:309.Kick It2:3710.Action Pack1:4711.Campaign Opening Video3:0612.DFA2:3513.Eerie Theory1:1014.Emmity Road2:0115.Closing Video A1:2916.T22:1517.Rockque2:1318.Slow Burn2:2519.Vista0:4420.Wednesday 71:3221.Let There Be3:0422.Impact1:0823.Recharge0:4624.Closing Video B1:2625.Steiner Defeat2:3326.Core2:3227.Panarama3:0428.Armed1:5229.Sander2:2430.T32:1631.Stutter Shark2:2832.Davion Theme2:20</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25296">Lore: Aftermath</game><game id="13569">Heavy Gear II</game><game id="17302">War World: Tactical Combat</game><game id="27284">MechWarrior Online</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/15/155745/2273266-61ngwt9bm2l._sl500_ss500_.jpg</image></root>