<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15156</id><name>Tobal 2</name><description>GameplayTobal 2 improves upon Tobal No. 1's fighting system by adding a link system, via which the player may chain together combos. It also adds a fireball for each character, that takes part of the player's life away, but can deal massive damage. A fireball charged for two seconds will kill the opponent in one hit. To compensate, the fireball is easy to avoid.The quest mode returns from the first game, but greatly expanded with the addition of a central town, allowing you to train and rest your character, leveling him up until each individual body part deals more damage. The player will navigate six different dungeons each divided into levels, all populated with a large variety monsters that the player can capture using a purple stone when low on health (very similar to Pokémon).Once a monster is captured, the player may use that monster in the Versus mode. This is what takes the playable character count up to 200. Most of the monsters are generic with a basic style being shared between many of them. Some of them are unique, like Chocobo, the lovable bird from the Final Fantasy series, that makes a guest appearance.The game was released only in Japan, on April 25, 1997. The same day that Sony's dual analog controller came out. This makes Tobal 2 the first fighting game to use the controller.The six dungeons are: Practice Dungeon, Pyramid, Desert Spaceship, Molmoran Mine, Castle and Final Dungeon.CharactersThe following is a list of all of Tobal 2's playable characters.Chuji WuGren KutsChaco YutaniFei-PusuHomIll GogaMary IvonskayaDoctor VEponOliemsMufuNorkEmpereur UdanMark The DevilMark2OhmaOhma2DogBrown LizardWyvern (boss)DeinoShopkeeperBrown ApeSkeletonSilver WizardChocoboAzurite GoremBronze GoremMono EyeWraithWhite FerretThin ManZircon GoremRed ZeppelZombieDragon PuppyTategami (boss)LichRipperTotem 1stTotem 2ndTotem 3rdMujakiPhantomAxe BeakBlue EmuCockatriceBlue JellyTie Tamper LDBearOwl BearRed JellyYellow JellyExecuterPunk HeadBlind BeastDeep BlueStarBlue StarRed StarGreen StarBlack StarGray GhoulGreen GhoulBlue SkeletonWightIkkaku (boss)GrellPenguinGrimlockKnockerRed CapJakiDark ElfRed CrestGray MouseWhite MouseBrown MouseBlack MouseFatherGreen LizardGray LizardBattle EmuGaze EyeSmall HelmViolet WormRepair DroidPatrol DroneAlien's Cocoon (boss)AttackerHammer HeadDual HammerGreat HammerCarrierEmpty CarrierHeavy AttackerM1 DroidPower CarrierRed AttackerThor's HammerGae BolgGiga PilePile DriverBrown MoleGray MoleRed FrogGreen FrogYellow FrogGray FrogGreen ManLaser DroneVortex ShellGharbiFrost BearPurple BearDark ThingSilver ApeGold ApeCoelophysisStruthiomimusDagger TailShilhpidDryadBig HandSnaky HeadBishopUndineWater DevilTie TamperGiga HammerGravel CarrierPower Carrier2Black FerretDual PileSeekerAnalyzerD PurpleFeelerDark FeelerRed SpikeRock BreakerLode HammerCarrier LDEPower HammerBlack WormWhite DogOhma (boss)Ohma 2 (boss)TrixSuper TrixWisemanMine BossWorkerInn MasterGate KeeperElderWizard PhantomTaximGhostViolet PenguinTri HornSpike SheildBrown FerretMohican PenguinOrcDark OrcOrc GuardSilver EmuBlue LizardKiller ApeViolet DevilKasyaboJokerPsycho Chuji (boss)Psycho Epon (boss)Psycho Oliems (boss)Psycho Ill (boss)Psycho Mary (boss)Psycho Fei (boss)Psycho Hom (boss)Psycho Gren (boss)Psycho Doctor V (boss)Psycho Chaco (boss)Black AttackerBox ManPuppetSpecterBerserkerThe following are the non playable characters.CougarSilver GoremGreen JellyPriestHoundNebakBlack ChocoboMad PlantBlack DogArcheologistAncient HornDual HornLoaderCritical ReceptionThe game received very good reviews at the time of it's release, with Famitsu scoring it a 36/40.Giant Bomb's own Jeff "The Mess" Gerstmann reviewed an import for Gamespot, scoring it an 8.1, and saying:"Tobal 2 may not ever be anyone's favorite fighting game, but it's a solid title that will keep players occupied for quite some time. It makes for a great diversion from the norm (much like Bushido Blade does). Even so, it doesn't pose much of a threat to the Street Fighters, Tekkens, and Mortal Kombats out there."</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="721">Ehrgeiz: God Bless the Ring</game><game id="21878">Tobal No. 1</game><game id="6409">Kensei: Sacred Fist</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2891/794839-tobal2a.png</image></root>