<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15199</id><name>Privateer 2: The Darkening</name><description>Privateer 2 is a sequel to the original Privateer in name only. No connection to Privateer 1 or the Wing Commander universe exists in the game.StoryThe game begins with a cargo ship named "Canera" coming under attack and crashing into the Mendra City on planet Crius. The only survivor is the game's protagonist, a man named Lev Arris and with no memory of who he is and no record of his existence prior to two weeks before the crash. The man must take on the life of a privateer while he tries to find out about his past.GameplayThe player is free to roam around the universe between plot missions. Earning money by taking on missions and transporting goods between planets. The player does not need to always journey alone, he/she can hire ships for the protection and increased cargo space.Some found the game's interfaces for trading to be cumbersome and annoying. While the game universe map is in 3D, instead of the normal 2D.Full Motion Video CastSteve Hilliker (Director)Erin Roberts (Director)Diane Duane (Writer)John RoweMary TammNadia Cameron-BlakeyBob GoodyDavid McCallumDon WarringtonChristopher WalkenKevork WarringtonHetty BaynesDouglas FieldingJohn VernonAde SaparaSu Lin LooiSteven CrossleyStasha FrenchLynn ThompsonNick HutchisonStephen JennJohn HurtClive OwenEric CarteLiana BridgesNizwar KirantThomas CraigStephen BentMathilda MayJohn BoswallNadim SawalhaBruce ByronJohn FrancisTim PearceDavid WarnerJonathan ChestermanFairmang SinghatehNichola CordeyBrian BlessedAmanda PaysJürgen ProchnowNicola JeffriesJohn Vernon</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2112">SunDog: Frozen Legacy</game><game id="10902">Elite</game><game id="5565">Freelancer</game><game id="4432">Frontier: First Encounters</game><game id="22979">Dark Horizon</game><game id="12111">Independence War 2: Edge Of Chaos</game><game id="433">Star Wars: X-Wing Alliance</game><game id="16330">Frontier: Elite II</game><game id="4806">Commander Blood</game><game id="40419">Elite: Dangerous</game><game id="2572">X³: Reunion</game><game id="23652">X2: The Threat</game><game id="452">X-Tension</game><game id="39092">Evochron: Alliance</game><game id="26013">Evochron Legends</game><game id="32102">Evochron Mercenary</game><game id="2943">Wing Commander: Prophecy</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5150/2126625-1.png</image></root>