<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15201</id><name>Legend of the Red Dragon</name><description>OriginsLegend of the Red Dragon was Created by Seth Robinson in 1989. It was originally made as a way to keep people coming back to Robinson's own BBS. After word of mouth spread, he began sell copies to others to host it as a door game on their bulletin board systems.Character ClassesWhen first starting out  you are given the choice of three starting classes: Death Knight, Mystic, and a Thief. Each class gains use points via events in the forest, at random times. You gain skill points, which add up to use points, with each successful event in the forest. Death KnightAs the Death Knight, you gain skill points by being brought to a dungeon by other Death Knights. There you are judge and jury to a prisoner, and either release them if innocent or send them to their death if guilty. If you choose correctly you are you are awarded a skill point. 1 use point requires 4 skill points.MysticAs the Mystic, you gain skill points by stumbling upon a house of an old mage. You will be given an opportunity to knock or bang on the old mage's door, and will randomly answer the door. If he answers the door, you are asked to guess a number between 1 and 100 within six guesses. Whereas the Death Knight and Thief classes require multiple skill points for a use point, the Mystic gains 1 use point for each skill point. The mystic SpellUse Points RequiredDescriptionPinch1An offensive spell, that does little more than a basic attackDisappear4Guranteed escape from battleHeat Wave8An offensive spell, that does equal damage as a Death Knight/Thief skillLight Shield12Reduces the damage you take by halfShatter16The most powerful skill in the game. Equal to the damage as 2 Death Knight/Thief skills in one attackMind Heal20Completely heals you during battleThiefAs the Thief, you gain skill points via being confronted by members of the Thieve's Guild. They will ask you for a gem in return for a lesson. You are rewarded gems by finding them in random events in the forest, or after battle sometimes. 1 use point requires 4 skill points. Since gaining skill points as a thief does not involve chance, it is the fastest class to gain use points.Another perk to being a Thief is the chance to rob the bank in the main town. This requires a fairy, which can be caught via a random event in the forest. The amount of money you take from the bank depends the the level you are; the higher you level the more you will be able to get away with. King Arthur's Weapons Weapon NamePriceStrength AddedStrength RequiredStick20050Dagger1000100Short Sword30002015Long Sword10,0003022Huge Axe30,0004032Bone Cruncher100,0006044Twin Swords150,0008064Power Axe200,00012099Able's Sword400,000180149Wan's Weapon1,000,000250224Spear of Gold4,000,000350334Crystal Shard10,00,000500334Nira's Teeth40,000,000800334Blood Sword100,000,0001200334Death Sword400,000,0001800334 Abdul's Armor ArmorPriceDefense AddedDefense RequiredCoat20010Heavy Coat100030Leather Vest3000102Bronze Armor10,000155Iron Armor30,0002510Graphite Armor100,0003520Erdrick's Armor150,0005035Armor of Death200,0007557Able's Armor400,00010092Full Body Armor1,000,000150152Blood Armor4,000,000225232Magic Protection10,000,000300232Belar's Armor40,000,000400232Golden Armor100,000,000600232Armor of Love400,000,0001000232</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="36">Text Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17137">Magocracy</game><game id="10776">Operation: Overkill II</game><game id="32244">The Pit</game><game id="34916">The Kingdom of Loathing</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8273/658064-1142891666_09.png</image></root>