<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15212</id><name>Ratchet &amp; Clank Future: Tools of Destruction</name><description>OverviewHeroes Ratchet and ClankRatchet and Clank: Tools of Destruction is the sixth game in Insomniac Games' long running Ratchet and Clank series. This game also marks the franchise's debut on the PlayStation 3 hardware. The game is a third-person platformer with shooting and puzzle mechanics. Players control Ratchet as travels the universe to bring down evil Emperor Tachyon and discover the secrets about his origins.PlotThe opening scene of Tools of Destruction feature Ratchet and Clank repairing a small hovercraft, when the pair are interrupted by Captain Qwark's call for help. On their way to theTachyon's ArmyPlanetary Defence Center they find a large army in the process of destroying the city of Metropolis. Cornered by the opposing forces, Ratchet and Clank meet Emperor Tachyon, the leader of the Cragmites. Tachyon reveals his hatred for the Lombaxes, and offers to halt the destruction of Metropolis in exchange for Ratchet's life. They refuse the offer, and manage to escape from the city, only to crash land in the Polaris galaxy.Clank then experiences a dream where he is told by strange hovering aliens called the Zoni, that claim to have knowledge of his past. The dream is cut short with Ratchet waking Clank up, where the pair decide to search for more information about Tachyon. They run into a mysterious alien, known only as the Smuggler, who brings them to Startus City before realizing Ratchet is a Lombax, at which point he promptly dropped them out of the ship. While here, the Zoni, who only Clank can see, provide him with a set of robo-wings, and help reveal the origin of the Lombax species.They then receive a message from Qwark, inviting them to attend the Imperial Fight Festival. It is then revealed that Qwark agreed to work for Tachyon in order to save his own life. Qwark manages to get Ratchet in undetected using the alias ‘Mustachio Furioso.' After successfully completing the challenge, Qwark presented Ratchet with an infobot containing Tachyon’s plans to find the Lombax secret, as well as a copy of ‘Body by Qwark.'From the infobot, they found out that details of the Lombax secret were in the Apogee Space Station. While there, they encountered Talwyn Apogee and her two robots Cronk and Zephyr, who were about to kill the pair, when they realize Ratchet was a Lombax. Talwyn then told them of how space pirates had stolen a Lombax related artifact from her father, and gave them the location of where she thought they had taken it.The DimensionatorThey travelled to the pirate station where they managed to obtain the artifact undetected. While Ratchet was holding it, a map appeared which contained coordinates to Rykan V, to which the group travelled. After defeating a significant number of Tachyon’s Cragmite soldiers, they found out about a device called the ‘Dimensionator’ - a helmet that allowed the owner to open a portal, to access different dimensions. Later Qwark gave them the location of Zordoom Prison, where he believed the Dimensionator was being held.At the prison, Ratchet learned that Tachyon had been found by Lombaxes while he was still an egg, and was adopted by a family on Fastoon; however, after finding out that the Lombaxes had a part to play in the death of his species, he set about trying to destroy all of them. After this, Ratchet has an argument with Clank, who is insistent that the Zoni exist. They also manage to free Talwyn who was imprisoned there at the time.They manage to track down the location of the Dimensionator, but are faced by Captain Slag and Rusty Pete, who also want the device. After defeating Slag, Ratchet is declared the new leader of the space pirates by Rusty Pete. Before Ratchet could get the Dimensionator, Captain Qwark stole it, saying he would make himself a hero again by destroying it himself. They later manage to track down Qwark’s location, but by now Tachyon has taken the Dimensionator. In the ensuing scramble, Ratchet was knocked unconscious and Tachyon managed to escape.The group travel to Meredian City, where they knew Tachyon was. Tachyon then revealed that to escape the attack, the Lombaxes had escaped through a portal using the Dimensionator. Only two remained behind - Ratchet and his father, who sent his son to Veldin, to save him from Tachyon’s rampage. He then offered Ratchet the chance to go through the portal to his own kind, an offer which he rejected - realising the danger that could be caused if the Dimensionator was not destroyed.Clank being captured by the ZoniThe resulting battle causes Ratchet and Tachyon to be sucked into a portal, where Tachyon is eventually defeated. Ratchet and Clank then repair the now-damaged machine using the 3 and 3 quarter Centicubit Hexagonal Washer, that the Plumber had previously given them. Together, they manage to escape the portal before it closed up.The game ends at the Apogee Space Center, where Rusty Pete is seen trying to help Captain Qwark perfect his pirate ‘yarrr.' Ratchet also speculates about how much Tachyon could have told him about his past, while the others assure him he did the right thing. The Zoni then re-appear and inexplicably capture Clank before anyone can stop them and disappear.SecretsLike all Ratchet and Clank games, Tools of Desruction has alot of different easter eggs, secret collectibles, unlockable skins and cheats.Golden BoltsGolden Bolts make their return in this game. There are a total of 32 Gold Bolts hidden across the galaxy. You can use the Bolts to unlock new skins for RatchetThe skins you can unlock are:Rusty Pete - 6 Golden BoltsCronk - 4 Golden BoltsDan Johnson - 6 Golden BoltsSnowman - 3 Golden BoltsMustachio Furioso - 3 Golden BoltsZephyr - 4 Golden BoltsCragmite - 6 Golden BoltsSkill pointsPlanet CobaliaA Smashing Good Time - Destroy all crates and Consumer robots in the spaceport and gelatonium plant. [10 points]I Should Have Gone Down In A Barrel - Jump into each of the two gelatonium waterfalls in the Cobalia gelatonium plant. [10 points]Giant Hunter - Kill all Basilisk Leviathans in the Cobalia wilderness. [10 points]Planet KortogWrench Ninja 3 - Use only the wrench to make it to the robo-wings segment. [10 points]We Don`t Need No Stinkin` Bridges! - Cross the tripad sequence without activating the bridge. [10 points]Surface To Air Plasma Beasts - Take out 3 flying targets using Plasma Beasts. [10 points]Been Around - Take-off from every robo-wing pad in Stratus City. [10 points]Voron Asteroid BeltCollector's Addition - Collect all 10 cargo containers. [10 points]Mine Sweeper - Clear out 10-15 mines. [10 points].Whats That, R2? - Barrel Roll 10 Times. [10 points]MukowI Think I'm Going To Be Sick - Ride the ferris wheel 5 times without taking damage. [10 points]Fast and Firey-ous - Use the charge boots to cross the bridge to the arena without being burned. [10 points]One Heckuva Peep Hole - Use the Geo-laser to blast throught he wall. [10 points]Nundac Asteroid RingAlphabet City - Teleport to each of the six asteroids in Alphabetical order. [10 points]Knock You Down to Size - Wrench slam 5 Cerullean Centipedes. [10 points]Dancin With The Stars - Make 5 enemies dance at once on an asteroid. [10 points]ArdolisTaste O' Yer Own Medicine - Destroy all Corsairs with the Combuster. [10 points]Preemptive Strike- Destroy 5 thwogs while they are still sleeping. [10 points]It's a Mutanty Cap'n! -Change 5 pirates into penguins in one shot. [10 points]Rakar Star ClusterYou Sunk My Battleship!- Shoot down at least 75% of the flying ships. [10 points]Pretty lights- Complete the level without destroying any of the snatchers. [10 points]I've Got Places to Be - Kill the boss in less than 2:30. [10 points]Rykan VThe Consumer Is Not (Always) Right - Destroy 18 consumer bots in the area near your ship. [10 points]Live Strong - Complete the Gyro-Cycle area in under 1:45. [10 points]Untouchable- Don't take damage while driving the Gyro-Cycle. [10 points]SargassoIt Sounded Like A Freight Train - Get 11 anthropods in one tornado. [10 points]Head Examine - Land on the head of all 5 Troglosaurs in Sargasso. [10 points]Extinction - Kill all the Sargasso Grunthers. [10 points]Kreeli CometLombaxes Don't Like Cold - Break all the breakable icicles. [10 points]Mow Down Hoedown - Use turrets to destroy 10 dancing pirates. [10 points]Saucy Wrench - Destroy all 4 campfire Cauldrens with the wrench. [10 points]ViceronDancin' On The Ceiling - Successfully use a Groovitron while on a gravity ramp. [10 points]Seared Ahi - Use the Pyro Blaster on 3 Drophyd Creatures after freeing them from their robotic suits. [10 points]Verigris Black HoleExpert Marksman - Kill 75% of all the enemies. [10 points]Can't Touch This - Avoid making contact with anything before fighting the boss. [10 points]Pyew Pyew! - Complete the level without secondary fire. [10 points]JasinduDead Aim - Destroy 3 destructible towers while on the pirate barges. [10 points]Fire with fire - Kill 2 Kerchu Pyroguards with the Pyro Blaster. [10 points]Ublik (Slag's Fleet)Six Gun Salute - Get six pirates in a row to salute to Ratchet while in the pirate disguise. [10 points]ReeporGotta Catch Them All - Hit all cragmite soldiers with the Mag-Net Launcher. [10 points]IgliakStay Still So I Can Shoot You!- Use strafe flip 10 times while fighting cragmite soldiers. [10 points]Now Boarding... - Complete the Gyro Cycle area in 0:55 seconds. [10 points]Low Flying Owls - Fly underneath an electrified barrier in the robo wing segment. [10 points]Fastoon (Second visit only)Nowhere To Hide - Destroy every piece of breakable cover. [10 points]General (Can be obtained on any planet)No, Up Your Arsenal - Upgrade every weapon to its maximum level. [40 points]Roflcopter - Turn one enemy into a penguin then use the visicopter to destroy it. [20 points]Golden Children - Find all the gold bolts. [40 points]Cheapskate- Purchase a single combuster shot [ 10 points]Everybody Dance Now- Make every type of enemy in the game dance.(not including bosses) [40 points]Chorus Line - Get 11 enemies to dance together at the same time.[10 points]Happy Feat - Get 9 penguins to dance at the same time. [10 points]Disco Inferno - Use the Groovitron followed by the Pyro Blaster. [10 points]Bolts in the Bank - Sell 20 leviathan souls to the smuggler.[10 points]It's Like The South Pole Here - Turn 15 enemies and/or citizens into penguins at the same time.[10 points]Say Hello To My Little Friend - Kill 15 enemies with one RYNO shot. [10 points]For The Hoard - Get every combat device. [10 points]Promoted to Inspector - Get every gadget.[10 points]Global Thermonuclear War - Get every weapon. [20 points]Its Even Better The Second Time - Complete challenge mode.[40 points]The Hardest of Core - Get everything else in the game.[20 points]You unlock different Cheats for getting these skill points. The cheats are as follows:Cheats2007 E3 Trailer - 25 Skill Points - Unlocks the 2007 trailer of RCF:ToDBig-Headed Ratchet - 50 Skill Points - Allows you to make ratchets head biggerCharacter Concept Art - 75 Skill Points - Unlocks concept art for the games charactersBig-Headed Enemies - 100 Skill Points - Allows you to make the heads of your enemies bigger2006 GDC Trailer - 150 Skill Points - Unlocks the 2006 trailer for RCF:ToDEnvironment Concept Art - 250 Skill Points -Unlocks concept are for the enviormentsReplacement Wrench - 300 Skill Points - allows ratchet to get a new wrench skin such as a pirate swordRatchet's Drawing Tutorial - 350 Skill Points - A video of the artists of insomniac games teaching you how to draw ratchetJames the Galactic Defender - 400 Skill Points - You can make Mr.Zurkon look like James The Galactic DefenderWeapon Concept Art - 450 Skill Points - Unlocks concept art for RCF: ToD weaponsMirrored Levels - 500 Skill Points - Allows you to mirror the levelsScript-to-Screen - 600 Skill Points - A video o how the games cinematics make it from a drawing to 3dRatchet Paintings - 750 Skill Points - Paintings of the games hero, RatchetPlanetsCerullean SectorPlanet Cobalia - Cobalia also known as the "Gel Capital of the Polaris galaxy," is a swamp planet best known for being the Polaris Galaxy's richest source of Gelatonium, the most commonly used spacecraft fuel in the galaxy. GrummelNet's famous Confuzzler Gas was dervired from the seeds of the Cobalian Worm Plant. Basilisk Leviathans are commonly found in caves and jungles on Cobalia.When Emperor Percival Tachyon took over Cobalia, he gained control over the largest source of Gelatonium in the galaxy, making the rest of the galaxy dependent on Tachyon's rationing of Gelatonium fuel for all interstellar travel.EnemiesCerulllean swarmer - Small but vicious creatures that are common throughout the Cerrulean sector. They use their sharp teeth to attack anyone who comes near them. They are usually sleeping during the day so you can often surprise attack them.Cerullean Centipede - A very large multi-legged insectoid that resembles a centipede. They spit acid at their attackers and have very hard outer shells.Basilisk Leviathan - The top of the food chain on Cobalia these gigantic flying beasts , they will either try to rush you or spit powerful electrical balls at youTumfoids - Located only where Gelatonium was abundant, Tumfoids get crazed at the mere sight of the substance. While they are not aggressive toward Ratchet or other creatures,they make the gelanator very hard to use because they immideatly started eating the gel.Planet Kortog - Home to Stratus City which is suspended high above the planet. It is a part of Tachyon's empire and used to be the Educational District of the Polaris Galaxy before Tachyon invaded. You will get a new gadget called Robo-Wings on this planet. The city is full of robo-wing launchers that the player could fly anywhere in the city and explore.Its famed hall of knoledge is said to hold the secrets of the Great War and the history of both the Lombaxes and Cragmites. However, the hall of knoledge has been strictly off limits after Tachyon conquered the city.This was where Ratchet and Clank discover a Lombax planet called Fastoon. The otherwise reddish color was probably let off by the number of red coloured architechture throughout the planet, along with amount of red-coloured gases seen throughout the cities.EnemiesDrophyd Gunship - They are flying saucers that fire at you when they see, they aren't very tough.Drophyd Trooper - These enemies come equipped with an arm cannon that can fire from long range. While they didn't exactly graduate at the top of the sharpshooter class, when multiple foes are grouped together, they can become a moderate threat.Tesladrones - They are robotic guards that charge toward their targets in an attempt to shock them with their electrified arms.They are often more irritating than deadly.Drophyd Cyclocannon - An enemy that was in a form of a ball that shot bolts of energy (not bolts) at you. While tough, destroying them gained the player a massive amount of Raritanium each time.Planet Fastoon - Planet Fastoon was once the homeworld of the Lombax race and is desert planet. The planet was ravaged by Tachyon's Drophyd troopers and his Enforcers who mercilessly decimated the Planet years ago when Ratchet was just a child. The planet is now solely occupied by Nanophyte scavengers. The scavengers look for the any pieces of lombax technology that hasnt been destroyed.Ratchet comes here in an esacape pod so he has to find a new ship to get off the planet. It is here where they find the Lombax engineered fighter, Aphelion who tells them a bit more about the fate of the LombaxesEnemiesBomber Nanophyte - Nanophytes are small creatures that live on fastoon and scavenge for technology. Bombers throw grenades but they do so rather carelessly often killing their friends.Clubber Nanophyte - They are weaker than their brothers, carrying large clubs. They can be a bother if their in a big group thoughPlanet Mukow - Mukow is a stormy aquatic planet in the Cerullean Sector. It was home to Emperor Percival Tachyon's Imperial Fight Festival, an exclusive battle resort for Tachyon's most elite Drophyd troopers. Tachyon used the Fight Festival as a means to both entertain his troops, to capture his enemies or lure them into fighting to their deaths. At such an occasion, Tachyon put the Holo Pirate Disguise as a prize in the Festival in hopes of luring Captain Slag there to his doom.Surrounding the gladiator arena of the Fight Festival was a large carnival park. The carnival park featured things such as a large and deathly ferris wheel and Emperor Tachyon's Trail of Turning Terror. The area near the entrance to the arena was heavily guarded by non-vacationing Drophyd troops and Enforcers.EnemiesPaladrone - Paladrones are armed gladiators that attack with guns in the Mukow arena. Their strength is moderate, their armor is weak and they are capable of attacking up to long range.Detonoid - Detonoids are little machines that self-destruct . You have to destroy them before they reach youTerraklon - Cousins of the Paladrones, exept they have swords instead of guns.Argonoid - The other cousins of the Paladrones, these throw grenadesCrushto - Crusto is a giant amphibious creature that had cyborg arms and legs. His two most common attacks are shooting missles from the missle launcher that was connected to his right arm, and shooting his bullets from the machine gun on his left arm at you . He is a boss at the Fight FestivalZorthan the Irritable - Zorthan's species is not confirmed, however he has a humanoid face, and an loose tail. Zorthan will try to fry you with his eye laser beam, electrify you with electrical charges that multiply, and catch you with his rapid Tornado Attack .Hug Me-Tight Nanny Bot - Robots that have gigantic arms that they kill you with. They are slow, but their hits 1hit-kill you.Tesladrone - They are robotic guards that charge toward their targets in an attempt to shock them with their electrified arms.They are often more irritating than deadly .Drophyd Gunship - they are flying saucers that fire at you when they see you, they arent very tough.Drophyd Trooper - These enemies come equipped with an arm cannon that can fire from long range. While they didn't exactly graduate at the top of the sharpshooter class, when multiple foes are grouped together, they can become a moderate threat .Nundac Asteroid Ring - The Nundac Asteroid Ring is the location to Apogee Space Station where Ratchet and Clank meet Talwyn, Cronk, and Zephyr. This was also the place where the Zoni give Clank the Geo-Laser Gadget. This area is also a Basilisk breeding ground and has a good source of raritanium and some small gel sources. The asteroids in the ring are all named after the Greek alphabet. The Smuggler is here and he will trade you bolts for killing basilisks.EnemiesCerulllean sawrmer - Small but vicious creatures that are common throughout the Cerrulean sector. They use their sharp teeth to attack anyone who comes near them. They are usually sleeping during the day so you can often surprise attack them.Cerullean Centipede - A very large multi legged insectoid that resembles a centipede. They spit acid at their attackers and have very hard outer shells.Basilisk Leviathan - The top of the food chain on Cobalia these gigantic flying beasts , they will either try to rush you or spit powerful electrical balls at youThermosplitter - These droids attack you by spinning toward you while shooting a heat laser to the ground.Fusion Turret - These machines pop out from the ground when someone is close by, and then shot at them with a gatling gun.Planet Ardolis - Ardolis is a water filled planet with some cliffs sticking out from the seas and the planet and was home to the pirate base. On this planet, Ratchet and Clank attempted to explore the base in hope to find the Lombax secret.They find a mysterious Lombax artifact that only Ratchet can activate. However, this turned out to not be Lombax secret, instead it is a map to another planet. which only turned out to be coordinates to another planet. Ratchet and Clank first met Captain Slag and his right-hand man Rusty Pete on Ardolis. EnemiesBuccaneer - Buccaneers were grog-guzzling enemies that kept it classy with a saber in hand, aiming to chop up Ratchet into sizeable portions .Thwogs - Thwogs were three-eyed bat-like creatures that could be found in the Sarrdollow caves of the pirate base on planet Ardolis .Swab - Swabs often hid in the shape of a Raritanium Chest, which then popped out and headed toward their unsuspecting prey .Rogue - They are Large and in charge. These huge, relentless, ape-like Robot Pirates liked to jump into battle and shot explosive cannon balls that rolled and ricocheted around the immediate area, exploding on contact. .Corsairs - Corsairs have opted for long range firepower instead of the traditional sword . Otherwise, they are very similar to BuccaneersHardy Buccaneer - Hardy Buccaneers are Robot Pirates that carry large shields that make them more difficult to eliminate .Verdigris Sector Planet Rykan V - This volcanic wastleland was site of Lombax activity in previous years. This is why Tachyon took over this planet to search for Lombax tech. The lava refineries of Rykan V are the source of the metals used in most advanced weapons and armor in the galaxy. After retrieving the artifact from the planet Ardolis, it showed the Rykan V globe hologram where Ratchet, Clank, and their new allies Talwyn, Cronk and Zephyr could find the Lombax Secret. .When the heroes found the door for any Lombax return, they found a movie tape that told that the Lombax Secret was a gadget called the Dimensionator. EnemiesTesladrone - They are robotic guards that charge toward their targets in an attempt to shock them with their electrified arms.They are often more irritating than deadly .Drophyd Gunship - they are flying saucers that fire at you when they see you, they arent very tough.Drophyd Trooper - These enemies come equipped with an arm cannon that can fire from long range. While they didn't exactly graduate at the top of the sharpshooter class, when multiple foes are grouped together, they can become a moderate threat .Planet Sargasso - Planet Sargasso is a dangerous and mostly uninhabitable primordial swampland. The planet was infested with large, deadly creatures who would quickly make a snack out of any unwary Lombax explorer. The only advanced race known to travel to the planet were the fiercely territorial Kerchu. Being advanced architects, they had built Gelatonium Derricks, refineries, and gel plants to take advantage of the large amounts accessable, plus the fact that the planet was not yet under Imperial control.The Lombax race once had a Testing Facility for all their latest weapons and gadgets, the most notable being the Dimensionator. EnemiesGrunthors - The Grunthors were mammoth-dinosaur creatures who guarded the Leviathan Souls on planet Sargasso. They attacked by shooting fireballs from their mouths, with their tusks, or by stomping their feet if Ratchet got too close . They are basically T-rexes.Anthropods - burrowing beetles that popped out of the ground in groups, on planet Sargasso, to attack Ratchet when he least expected it. They attacked in groups of 10 or more.Grubsnuckers - Flying creatures that attacked Ratchet from far away. They are in groups of 2 or 3Kerchu Pyroguards - Tanks operated by Kerchu guards. The tanks had 2 flamethrowers that he attacked with.Troglosaurs - Troglosaurs are large dinosaur-like creatures from the planet Sargasso. Ratchet was able to climb onto their backs and heads using Clank's Robo-Wings. They were too gigantic to even notice RatchetKreeli Comet - The Kreeli Comet is a comet and the location to the IRIS Supercomputer but was taken over by Captain Slag and his Robot Pirates. It is an icy comet, with caves and caverns.The IRIS Supercomputer is the most ancient and powerful computer in the galaxy. Who created it and why has been long forgotten, but IRIS continues to be used as a form of intergalactic encyclopaedia and oracle. Some believe that the sheer computing power and massive storage of this supercomputer give the eerie ability to predict the future. The computer has been stolen by space pirates so you have to fight and sneak your way through the comet to access the computer. EnemiesBuccaneer - Buccaneers were grog-guzzling enemies that kept it classy with a saber in hand, aiming to chop up Ratchet into sizeable portions .Thwogs - Thwogs were three-eyed bat-like creatures that could be found in the Sarrdollow caves of the pirate base on planet Ardolis .Swab - Swabs often hid in the shape of a Raritanium Chest, which then popped out and headed toward their unsuspecting prey .Rogue - They are Large and in charge. These huge, relentless, ape-like Robot Pirates liked to jump into battle and shot explosive cannon balls that rolled and ricocheted around the immediate area, exploding on contact. .Corsairs - Corsairs have opted for long range firepower instead of the traditional sword . Otherwise, they are very similar to BuccaneersHardy Buccaneer - Hardy Buccaneers are Robot Pirates that carry large shields that make them more difficult to eliminate .Planet Viceron - Viceron was the dismal planet where treacherous Zordoom Prison was located. There were constant breakouts which were hunted down by the guards stationed on the planet. Many of the past enemies and "bad" characters of past Ratchet and Clank games had been jailed here like Dr. Nefarious, Ace Hardlight, and Slim Cognito.The planet itself is very dark with murky waters and dark brown rocks. There wasn't alot of vegetation and it seemed uninhabited, besides the prisoners and imperials. The majority of the area was water with tall rocks coming out, where the Zordoom prison was built on that was large enough to be seen from orbit. EnemiesEnforcers - Enforcers were large 4-legged machines that served as heavy infantry in the Imperial Defense Force. They were armed with two rapid fire turrets attached to the sides of the Enforcer.Drophyd Gunship - they are flying saucers that fire at you when they see you, they arent very tough.Drophyd Trooper - These enemies come equipped with an arm cannon that can fire from long range. While they didn't exactly graduate at the top of the sharpshooter class, when multiple foes are grouped together, they can become a moderate threat .Tesladrone - They are robotic guards that charge toward their targets in an attempt to shock them with their electrified arms.They are often more irritating than deadly .Praxus Sector Planet Jasindu - Planet Jasindu in Praxus Sector was a jungle planet that was the home of the Kerchu species, with Kerchu City on the planet being the capital of the Kerchu domain. GrummelNet's Intergalactic travel guide considered Jasindu the worst vacation spot in the Polaris galaxy due to the Kerchu's habit of killing any outsiders who wandered into their building sites. The planet was rich with Gelatonium, and the Kerchu have several underground Gelatonium plants near Kerchu City.After finding the Dimensionator on Rykan V, Max Apogee relocated it in Kerchu City to keep it away from Captain Slag. What happened to Max was unknown, but the Kerchu of Kerchu City were later guarding the Dimensionator.EnemiesCorsairs - Corsairs have opted for long range firepower instead of the traditional sword . Otherwise, they are very similar to BuccaneersHardy Buccaneer - Hardy Buccaneers are Robot Pirates that carry large shields that make them more difficult to eliminate .Buccaneer - Buccaneers were grog-guzzling enemies that kept it classy with a saber in hand, aiming to chop up Ratchet into sizeable portions .Kerchu Pyroguards - Tanks operated by Kerchu guards. The tanks had 2 flamethrowers that he attacked with.Kerch Spinners - Kerchu that have incredibly strong armor and attack enmies by rolling up into a ball and rolling twoards their enemiesUblik Passage - The Ublik Passage was the location of Slag's Fleet. This was where Ratchet and Clank defeated Captain Slag. The Ublik Passage was previously used for connection between the Praxus and Verdigris Sectors, however after being taken over by Slag's Fleet it was unaccessable.The Slag's Fleet in Ublik Passage was an inhospitable space station where the pirates docked there ships. Here Ratchet fought Slag's army of robot pirates, including Swabs and two Rogues. He also had to fight many pirates and a ship raid while on a pirate ship. EnemiesCorsairs - Corsairs have opted for long range firepower instead of the traditional sword . Otherwise, they are very similar to BuccaneersHardy Buccaneer - Hardy Buccaneers are Robot Pirates that carry large shields that make them more difficult to eliminate .Buccaneer - Buccaneers were grog-guzzling enemies that kept it classy with a saber in hand, aiming to chop up Ratchet into sizeable portions .Rogue - They are Large and in charge. These huge, relentless, ape-like Robot Pirates liked to jump into battle and shot explosive cannon balls that rolled and ricocheted around the immediate area, exploding on contact.Planet Reepor - Reepor was the Cragmite home world that had been dormant for years thanks to the Lombaxes. It was home to the Cragmite Ruins. They encountered Emperor Percival Tachyon who had the Dimensionator and used it to bring back the Cragmites. Ratchet and Clank got seperated and had to regroup Talwyn, Cronk, and Zephyr.The planet itself was very dark and creepy looking. The "water" was green in color, and most of the plants and soil was black (making it look very dark and burnt from orbit).EnemiesCragpole - the smallest form of Cragmites that attack by spitting acid out of their mouth.Cragmite Warrior - a fully grown form of the Cragmite species, and is known as the deadliest creature to exist within an eight galaxy radius. The Cragmite Warriors once terrorized the entire galaxy, extinguished hundreds of species and obliterating entire planets in their headlong rush to conquer the galaxy. They can also teleportCragmite Hunter - Something significant must have occurred during a Cragmites growing process, because these older beasts were much fiercer and combat-ready than their younger siblings, Cragpoles. With the ability to de-molecularize into thin air and then appear a short distance away, they could be very difficult to eliminate.Planet Igilak - Igliak is a planet in the Praxus Sector of Polaris, orbiting a radioactive sun and was the home of Meridian City, the capital of Free Polaris. Meridian City is probably the largest city of the galaxy as well, well comparable with Metropolis of the Solana galaxy and Megapolis of the Bogon galaxy.During the Great War of Polaris, the warbot Zephyr was stationed in the Zenith Outpost in Meridian City. Later, during the perilous Phylax intrusion, he was joined by another warbot named Cronk, who later became his lifetime partner. The two were later sent on a mission to secure a Gelatonium Refinery on the planet to be able to transport fuel to the Meridian Armory. The refinery was infested by undead zombie dung dragons created by Igliak's radioactive sun.EnemiesCragpole - the smallest form of Cragmites that attack by spitting acid out of their mouth.Cragmite Warrior - a fully grown form of the Cragmite species, and is known as the deadliest creature to exist within an eight galaxy radius. The Cragmite Warriors once terrorized the entire galaxy, extinguished hundreds of species and obliterating entire planets in their headlong rush to conquer the galaxy. They can also teleportCragmite Hunter - Something significant must have occurred during a Cragmites growing process, because these older beasts were much fiercer and combat-ready than their younger siblings, Cragpoles. With the ability to de-molecularize into thin air and then appear a short distance away, they could be very difficult to eliminate.Enforcers - Enforcers were large 4-legged machines that served as heavy infantry in the Imperial Defense Force. They were armed with two rapid fire turrets attached to the sides of the Enforcer.Planet Fastoon - You return to Fastoon in the last mission of the game after following Tahcyon here. However, he has amassed his entire army between him and Ratchet so Ratchet has to fight hordes of Drophyids and Cragmites along with the defenses of the city. This time, more of the city is opened up along with the Court of Azimuth in the middle of the city where Tacyon is waiting for Ratchet. Also, to make things creepier, iits night this time when you enter the planet.EnemiesCragpole - the smallest form of Cragmites that attack by spitting acid out of their mouth .Cragmite Hunter - a fully grown form of the Cragmite species, and is known as the deadliest creature to exist within an eight galaxy radius. The Cragmite Warriors once terrorized the entire galaxy, extinguished hundreds of species and obliterating entire planets in their headlong rush to conquer the galaxy. They can also teleport .Cragmite Warrior - Something significant must have occurred during a Cragmites growing process, because these older beasts were much fiercer and combat-ready than their younger siblings, Cragpoles. With the ability to de-molecularize into thin air and then appear a short distance away, they could be very difficult to eliminate .Drophyd Defender - the Drophyd army's elite. They have black robot armor that is more resistant than that of the Drophyd Troopers' and the Drophyd Sentries' armor.Plasmaturrets - large green turrets created by Emperor Percival Tachyon .Drophyd Sentry - The Drophyd Sentry is a Drophyd on wheels that was able to turn. It has a gun that fired 5 bolts of energy and had a damage of 1-100 making it very hard to defeat. .Drophyd Trooper - These enemies come equipped with an arm cannon that can fire from long range. While they didn't exactly graduate at the top of the sharpshooter class, when multiple foes are grouped together, they can become a moderate threat .Tachyon Transport Ship - mini ships that carry Drophyd Troopers and Drophyd Sentries .Drophyd Gunship - they are flying saucers that fire at you when they see you, they arent very tough.WeaponsThe weapons in Ratchet and Clank Future: Tools of Destruction can be upgraded in various ways. The first is leveling the weapon up by killing enemies and gaining experience, this will change the weapon's apperance and increase its power level. The other way of upgrading your weapons is through Raritanium which is a resorce that is more rare than regular bolts. Raritanium upgrades can increase a large variety of stats from shooting speed to bolt multipliers that make you earn bolts faster when using that weapon. Each weapon only has four of these upgrade options. In addition, once you have leveled your weapon to Level 5 and have beaten the game at least once you can buy the Omega version of that weapon which makes the weapons significantly more powerful.Omniwrench 3000 - A standard melee weapon that has a three hit combo. This is the only weapon that you cant upgrade and level up. But if get the box basher 2000 you can destroy all crates and destructable things around you if you jump up and hit the ground with your wrench. It also doesent need ammo.Combuster - A blaster that shoots high velocity plasma balls at your enemies. It can be leveled up to the Magma Combuster that shoots three shots instead of one with the same ammo cost.Raritanium upgrades: You can upgrade the weapons Damage, Range, Speed and Raritanium drop rate. The special upgrade is Pyrocidic Precipitation that makes magma fly out of the plasma balls when they hit enemies. The magma damages enemies that move through it.Fusion Grenade - A glove that throws out powerful thermonuclear grenades that have a large area of effect. It can be leveled up to the Fusion Bomb which makes each grenade act like a cluster bomb exploding into multiple grenades when it hits.Raritanium upgrades: You can upgrade the weapons Damage, Area of effect, Ammo capacity and bolt drop rate. The special upgrade is Concussion Detonators which knocks enemies down when it hits.Shock Ravager - A whip that is made of electricity that shocks enemies. Its useful for knocking enemies out of their blocking state and also in keeping enemies stunned so they cant hit you. It can be leveled up to the Lightning Ravager which makes shockwaves of energy fly out of the whip when you swing it.Raritanium upgrades: You can upgrade the weapons Raritanium drop rate, Bolt drop rate, Ammo Capacity and Damage. The special upgrade is Voltage Multiplier which doubles the range of the shockwaves prduced by the whip.Tornado Launcher - A weapon that launches Tornados at enemies sucking them in and damaging them at the same time. It can be leveled up to the Tempest Launcher which makes it so the tornado also shoots out lightning as it moves.Raritanium upgrades: You can upgrade the weapons Damage, Area of effect, Bolt drop rate and Raritanium drop rate. The special upgrade is Gyro-Turbine which allows the tornados to last significantly longer.Buzz Blades - This is a weapon that shoots out razor sharp blades that can bounce off walls and enemies making it so that you dont have to aim, just press the fire button and watch as the enemies die. It can be leveled up to the Doom Blades and it makes it so that the enemies would continualy take damage after being hit.Raritanium upgrades: You can upgrade the weapons Ammo capacity, Number of ricochets per blade, Damage and Bolt drop rate.The special upgrade is Cesium Blade Edges that make the blades explode after they have stopped bouncing.Predator Launcher - A rocket launcher that can lock on to enemies. It can be leveled up to the Raptor Launcher that makes the rockets explode into napalm that hurts enemies that get hit by it.Raritanium upgrades: You can upgrade the weapons Damage, Ammo capacity, Number of lock-ons at once and Speed.Alpha Disruptor - A cannon that you charge up to release a ridiculously powerful beam of isokinetic energy. It has by far the most powerful single shot in the game but it takes time to charge up. It can be leveled up to the Alpha Cannon which makes the beam last longer so you can kinda swing it around.Raritanium upgrades: You can upgrade the weapons Time to charge up, Damage, Ammo capacity and Bolt drop rate.The Special upgrade is Anti-MatterTransfluxorwhich allows the beam to travel through multiple enemies.Pyro Blaster - A flamethrower that sets enemies on fire. It can be leveled up to the Incinerator Which fires 3 streams of fire instead of one with the same ammo cost.Raritanium upgrades: You can upgrade the weapons Ammo capacity, Range, Damage and Raritanium drop rate.Plasma Beast - Its a glove that throws out synthetic blob-like creatures that dwell underground and sense enemies and attack them as they approach. It can be leveled up to the Plasma Stalkers and then the blobs can follow ratchet making them more effective.Raritanium upgrades: You can upgrade the weapons Damage, Ammo capacity, Area of effect and Raritanium drop rate. The special upgrade is Proximity Sensors which allow the beasts to detect enemies from farther away than before.Shard Reaper - This is basically a shot gun that shoots out high-velocity shards of trillium ore. It can be leveled up to the Nitro Reaper which also freezes enemies that it hits.Raritanium upgrades: You can upgrade the weapons Ammo capacity, Damage, Area of effect and Speed. The special upgrade is Pyrocidic Nano-Clusters that make the shards explode increasing damage.The Negotiator - A rapid-fire rocket launcher that is a useful weapon against weapons that are stronger than the average grunt. It can be leveled up to the The Judicator which fires three rockets instead of one with the same ammo cost.Raritanium upgrades: You can upgrade the weapons Damage, Speed, Ammo capacity and Area of effect. The special upgrade is Napalm Cells which makes the rockets explode into napalm.Nano-Swarmers - Is a glove that deployes a turret that shoots enemies who get near it. It can be leveled up to the Toxic Swarmers which poison the enemies that it hits causing damage over time.Raritanium upgrades: You can upgrade the weapons Damage, Area of effect, Ammo capacity and Bolt drop rate. The special upgrade is Zero-Kelvin Laser Diode that allows the weapon to freeze enemies.Mag-Net Launcher - A weapon that traps even the strongest enemies in a electrical net which makes this weapon very useful near the end of the game. It can be leveled up to the Mag-Net Cannon which also makes the nets explode for big damage when they are broken.Raritanium upgrades: You can upgrade the Weapons Raritanium drop rate, Speed, Ammo capacity and Damage. The special upgrade is Inductor Coils which make the nets last a lot longer.Razor Claws - A pair of laser claws that are mounted to your wrists which do alot of damage but you need to get close with them. It can be leveled up to the Shredder claws which causes the claws to do more damage with each hit as long as you dont get hit.Raritanium Upgrades: You can upgrade the weapons Ammo capacity, Damage, Raritanium drop rate and Bolt drop rate. The special upgrade is Fission Accelerator which makes the claws power up faster.RYNO IV - And finally, the most badass weapon in the Ratchet and Clank universe has returned! The RYNO IV is the most powerful weapon in the game able to destroy anything in seconds. It shoots out deadly laser beams that destroy anything that gets in their way. It can be leveled up to the RYNO IV Extreme which makes the weapon even more powerful.This weapon can be acquired via Holo-Plans throughout the game. These are schematics that must be turned in to the Smuggler on Sargasso. There is a piece of the completed plans on every planet except Cobalia. Raritanium upgrades: You can upgrade the weapons Speed, Ammo capacity, Bolt drop rate and Damage. It has no special upgrades...Trivia: If there werent cutscenes in the middle of the final boss, you could theoretically kill Tachyon in 6 seconds with this weapon.DevicesRatchet and Clank Future: Tools of Destruction also featured a new type of item, Devices. Devices are ideas that the Insomniac team had but couldnt implement because they were too powerful. So they made them a new type of thing that have alot less ammo than regular weapons, cost alot more and are for use in difficult situations. These are things that can turn enemies into penguins, command them to dance etc.Groovitron - A Disco ball that when you throw it, rises into the air and starts spinning. Like a regular disco ball it emits beams of light but the light from the Groovitron hypnotises enemies to dance. Insomniac games has said that this weapon has been their dream for the last three games but was scrapped each time because of the amount of animation it would require to implement a weapon that makes everyone dance. But in the transition to the ps3, they finally agreed to make the weapon a reality.If you have beat the game you can upgrade the groovitron to a Golden Groovitron which has unlimited ammo. However, this costs 2,000,000 raritanium( Which is alot).The Visi-Copter - A small helicopter that the player can control with the SIXAXIS. It can shoot rockets or just hit enemies with its blades. Its useful for scouting out areas and also for taking out some enemies before you enter the fight yourself.The transmorpher - A grenade that looks like a snowball. It turns enemies in a small radius into penguins making them harmless and cute. Its useful when you get into a difficult situation and just need to get the enemies off your back. NOTE: The Transmorpher does not actually damage the enemies and they return to their original form once the effect wears off.Mr. Zurkon - A tough talking, ass kicking robot that will kill everyone close to its master. He speaks with a robotic-german accent and says alot of humorous things."Mr Zurkon destoy little fishy man.""Say hello to Mr. Zurkon's little friend!"You can unlock a different skin for Mr.Zurkon of a small boy on a flying saucer. This is a tribute to a little boy who got paralyzed in a car accident.Death Springs -This is a bomb that explodes into small red mortar coils once it came in contact with a surface. The coils gravitate around and explode if they made physical contact with an enemy. Ratchet can carry as many as three.Leech Bomb - A bomb that drains nanotech(health) from enemies and heals Ratchet.Mega Leech Bomb - The Bigger version of the Leech Bomb that heals more health than the regular Leech bomb.Confuzzler Gas - Confuzzler Gas is a psychotropic hallucinogen that is derived from the seeds of the Cobalian Werm Plant and packed into pods. When thrown, the pod expelles the gas, which makes the target nauseous, so the enemies shoot each other instead of Ratchet.GadgetsIt wouldn't be a Ratchet and Clank game without gadgets! Gadgets are items that help Ratchet get through puzzles and platforming parts throughout the game. So here they are:The Swingshot - This is a gun that shoots out a grappling hook and attches to targets letting Ratchet swing through the world and access secret areas. This is the only gadget that has been in every Ratchet and clank game since the start. You dont actually have to equip this gadget, just jump and press circle and Ratchet will auto-equip the swingshotGeo-Laser - The Geo-Laser was one of Clanks upgrades in Tools of Destruction. The Zoni upgrade Clank with this gadget . It is used by using the SIXAXIS motion-sensitive controller to guide the laser. The laser can cut through natural surfaces . A bright green beacon would appear on Clank's head to navigate Ratchet to an area where he could use the Geo-Laser.Armor Magnetiser - A modification to ratchets armor that attracts bolts from greater distances.Heli- pack - An upgrade that Ratchet and Clank acquired in the first game on planet Kerwan by paying 1,000 bolts to Big Al . Since then clank has always had the heli-pack on him.Thruster Pack - An upgrade similar to the Heli-pack except it also has a butt stomp move used to activate large buttons.Robo-Wings - Robo-Wings are a gadget that Clank is upgraded with by the Zoni in Stratus City in order to get to the Hall of Knowledge. The Robo-Wings were made of a peculiar zeptotech technology (Zepto being smaller than Nano) which, despite being more technologically advanced than Polaris technology, are compatible with Gelatonium-fuel pads commonly found throughout the galaxy.Hydro-Pack - The Hydro-Pack was a black market upgrade to Clank that you could acquire in the first Ratchet  Clank game on Planet Hoven. It could be bought from Edwina's Robo Shack for 2,000 bolts. The Hydro-Pack is a useful upgrade that allows Ratchet move through water faster.Gyro-Cycle - The Gyro-cycle was a gadget given to you by the Smuggler for 5000 bolts. It was a hovering motorcycle like device that got you from one place to the other quickly. The lombax the Smuggler bought it from modified it with a terra thruster which allowed the Lombax to cover more ground faster.The Decryptor - The Decryptor is a hacking device that lets Ratchet pass through doors that are locked. The hacking was actually a puzzle mini game that you played by moving a metal ball between connection spots to allow a bolt of electricity to move to the end of the course.The Gelanator - This is a gadget that sucks in and shoots out gelatonium crating bouncy platforms that ratchet can jump from. The problem is that in all the spots where gelatonium is found there are also small creatures that eat gelatonium making some of these parts difficult.Holo Pirate Disguise - The Holo Pirate Disguise is a gadget that allows Ratchet to disguise himself as a Space Pirate and traverse through Space Pirate-filled areas without being attacked, and allows him to do the Pirate Jig in order to pass by pirate doorkeepers and access secret areas.Heli-pod Glove - A glove that throws out a ball with propellers on it to raise platforms.Grindboots - A pair of boots that let Ratchet grind rails and power lines and anything similar. This is also a gadget that you have in every ratchet and Clank game.Gravity Boots - A pair of boots that let ratchet walk up metal walls and pipes. This has been in most Ratchet and Clank games.Charge Boots - A pair of boots that let you get a short speed boots to let you travel through levels faster and easierArmorThere are also different armors you can buy from the Armor vendor. Different suits look different and have different properties. Armor vendors are found on most planets now, unlike the other games where there was only a few in the entire game.Pilot Suit - The suit Ratchet is wearing at the beginning of the game, it offers no armor bonus. This suit is made for flying, not fighting.Cost - 0 BoltsFirst Available - KerwanBlackstar armor - This armor was designed by Captain Blackstar. The armor uses biostatic Nanomites to absorb up to 25% of any damage received.Cost - 30,000 boltsFirst Available - CobaliaHelios Armor - This armor was engineered by the Kerchu Phalanxes of Planet Jasindu. It boasted three layers of cryofoam and duraplate omniguards for added protection, and absorbed up to 40% of all damage.First Available - Rykan VTerraflux armor -The damage reducing Terraflux armor was used by the Elite Cragmite assassains during the Great War. This historical armor contained triple-stitched Warthog scales plated with durable raritanium. The armor absorbed 55% of all damage. It was told to be very flexible but still robust.Cost - 300,000 boltsFirst Available - ReeporTrillium armor - This was armor worn by the Lombax warriors of Fastoon. It was designed by the centre for advanced Lombax research, and provided 65% damage reduction. It completely covered the Lombax wearer, and contained a bionic endoskeleton galvanized with Trillium ore.cost - 10,000,000 boltsFirst Available - Challlenge mode Cobalia</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9463">Mega Man X</game><game id="15835">Beyond Good &amp; Evil</game><game id="14623">Jak and Daxter: The Precursor Legacy</game><game id="12909">Crash Bandicoot: Warped</game><game id="7836">Spyro the Dragon</game><game id="10384">Jak II</game><game id="9669">Jak 3</game><game id="14604">Daxter</game><game id="5821">Rayman 3: Hoodlum Havoc</game><game id="3438">MediEvil II</game><game id="4228">Haven: Call of the King</game><game id="15353">Sly Cooper and the Thievius Raccoonus</game><game id="15573">Sly 2: Band of Thieves</game><game id="1563">Spyro 2: Ripto's Rage</game><game id="6134">The Legend of Spyro: The Eternal Night</game><game id="8006">Metal Arms: Glitch in the System</game><game id="3457">MediEvil</game><game id="7804">Rocket: Robot on Wheels</game><game id="20330">Gex 3: Deep Cover Gecko</game><game id="15991">Chameleon Twist 2</game><game id="18376">Looney Tunes Back in Action</game><game id="16094">Super Mario Galaxy</game><game id="2727">Star Fox Assault</game><game id="21000">Secret Agent Clank</game><game id="7212">Klonoa 2: Lunatea's Veil</game><game id="15000">Donkey Kong 64</game><game id="21115">Ratchet &amp; Clank Future: Quest for Booty</game><game id="20586">Banjo-Kazooie: Nuts &amp; Bolts</game><game id="20327">Ratatouille</game><game id="20975">Mega Man 9</game><game id="21181">PixelJunk Eden</game><game id="21141">Elefunk</game><game id="22313">LocoRoco Cocoreccho</game><game id="20602">LittleBigPlanet</game><game id="11120">LEGO Star Wars: The Complete Saga</game><game id="23579">Noby Noby Boy</game><game id="31304">Ape Escape Move</game><game id="22042">Tokobot</game><game id="34833">Sonic Generations</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1832157-box_racftod.png</image></root>