<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15329</id><name>Agent USA</name><description> Overview   Agent USA is an adventure/educational game developed by Tom Snyder Productions, Inc.  The game was released for the Atari 8-bit, Apple II, PC, and Commodore 64.  In the game you take on the role of a character whose goal is to save the world from the Fuzzbomb, and travel from city to city across the US.    StoryA scientist named Elma Sniddle was working on a television set, when she decides to use some crystals she discovered in her backyard to power the device.  However these mysterious crystals unexpectedly turn her television into the Fuzzbomb, which can in turn transform people into FuzzBodies, which is basically a formation of TV static.  These FuzzBodies can spread this onto others by coming into contact with them and keeping the transformation cycle going.  The only way to reverse the FuzzBody effects is for a person to touch one of the crystals, transforming them back into humans.  The main character of the game, Agent USA, is up to the task of eliminating the Fuzzbomb and stopping the fuzz madness.   GameplayThe game takes place in train stations located within various cities in the United States.  You begin the game at a random train station with 10 crystals at your  disposal, however 100 crystals are needed to eliminate the Fuzzbomb.  Each train station includes an information booth, which allows you to get information on the location of the Fuzzbomb and also purchase train tickets for that specific destination.  The game includes a clock, and you have to make sure that you are waiting for the train as specified on the arrival time of your ticket, otherwise you will miss it.  Once the player nears the city where the Fuzzbomb is located, you will start to encounter FuzzBodies, which will be exploring the train stations.  If a FuzzBody touches you, you will lose half of your crystals, and if you have no remaining crystals then you turn into a FuzzBody yourself and the game is over.  If you drop a crystal and a FuzzBody walks into it, then they will turn back into a regular human.  If you have accumulated 100 crystals, you can eliminate the FuzzBomb once and for all by simply approaching it, and facilitating the return of Elma's TV.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="8">Educational</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/94457/1374332-ausa1.png</image></root>