<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15341</id><name>Second Sight</name><description>OverviewSecond Sight is a video game that was developed by Free Radical Design and published by Codemasters for the Playstation 2, Xbox, Gamecube, and PC. It was released on September 21, 2004 for consoles and February 18, 2005 for PC.StoryJohn Vattic making his escape.The story begins with John Vattic waking up in a mysterious medical facility with no memory of who he is or how he got there. Vattic soon uncovers that he has the ability to manipulate the physical world with his mind and uses this newfound power to escape and try to discover the forgotten secrets of his past.   A series of playable flashbacks within the game help to unravel the mysteries of what lead to John Vattic's incarceration. The flashbacks follow a military operation codenamed "WinterICE", headed by  colonel Joshua Starke, and with Vattic and his old aquintance Jayne Wilde on board, as they attempt to track down a doctor wanted for practicing unethical psychic experiments on unwilling child subjects. Vattic is initially skeptical of the exsistence of any paranormal abilities whatsoever, however along the way  Vattic  soon discovers he has his own innate psychic abilities that are unlocked when he finds himself in a point of extreme desperation. Colonel Starke greeting John Vattic on their first meeting. The plot thickens when John begins to realize that his flashbacks are actually happening in the past, and his actions have a direct effect on the present. The effects usually result in saving the life of someone who has previously been killed while on the mission.   In order to figure out what happened in the past, and possibly change it, John seeks out the surviving members of operation WinterICE, notably Wilde and Starke, in order to discover what exactly happened and how it lead to the events of the present day.GameplayThe gameplay of Second Sight involves the use of both firearms and psychic abilities. John's psychic arsenal includes telekenisis, a psychic attack (either in the form of a psychic shockwave or a The sniper rifle mechanic in Second Sight, with the scope view in the corner.concentrated ball of energy), healing, invisiblity, projection, and possesion. The games arsenal of weapons includes the basic shooter weaponry, ranging from pistols to SMGs, and assault rifles to sniper rifles. There is also a stealth element to the game, allowing the player to sneak past enemies to reach their objectives, mostly relying on their charm ability (using John's psychic influence to trick the enemy into thinking John isn't there) or their projection ability to scout the area ahead. However, the game does include some instances where stealth is not an option and the player must eliminate all enemies by force (either using firearms or psychic powers). Due to his inherent ability to heal himself, Vattic can, if hurt, retreat to a safe place to heal and then return to the fight, although enemies will sometimes tend to respawn if the player retreats too far. Though much of the game is built up to emphasize the possibility of sneaking past enemies, there are also elements of traditional shooter games, especially when teamed up with WinterICE in the past.  The game doesn't contain any bosses of any sort, mainly due to the story-intensive nature of the game. The only real boss in the game is the main antagonist, Hanson. However there isn't any traditional boss fight, i.e; the player doesn't need to change the way they battle or use any special tactics on certain enemies to finish the game.     The WinterICE team. From left: William Robert 'Tex' Jackson, Joshua Starke, John Vattic, Anthony Cortelli, Patrick Ballard, Juan Carlos 'JC' Verdes, Martha Franklin and Jayne Wilde. Originals System Requirement Windows XP or Windows Vista 1 GHz Processor (2 GHz recommended) 512 MB RAM (1 GB recommended for Vista) DirectX 8-compatible 3D graphics card with Hardware TL support (GeForce FX 5xxx and above, ATI Radeon 9xxx and above recommended) Mouse, Keyboard  </description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9051">Psi-Ops: The Mindgate Conspiracy</game><game id="12621">TimeSplitters</game><game id="17246">TimeSplitters 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2428428-box_ss.png</image></root>