<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15461</id><name>Ninja Rabbits</name><description>OverviewNinja Rabbits is a beat 'em up developed and published by Micro Value for the Amiga, Atari ST, Commodore 64, and DOS platforms in the UK in 1991. Ninja Rabbits was followed by a sequel titled International Ninja Rabbits which was a very similar game to the original, but with updated graphics.GameplayIn Ninja Rabbits the player travels from the left of the screen to the right, fighting enemies and dodging projectiles. Ninja Rabbits can be controlled using either the keyboard or a joystick. There are three different difficulty levels to choose from in Ninja Rabbits: Easy, Medium, and Hard.The player has a staff weapon that can be used as a melee attack against the enemies. The staff is used when the player presses the attack button while standing still. A kick attack can also be used by pressing forward and attacking. There is also the ability to jump by pressing up, however the jump is very small.HealthCarrot Health MeterThe players health meter is represented by a carrot. When damage is taken an amount of the carrot will disappear, starting from the left and working to the right. When the health meter is completely depleted, one of the lives is lost.LivesLives LeftIn Ninja Rabbits a player has three lives to start with. The lives left are represented by rabbit heads. Once a player loses a life, one of the rabbit heads will disappear and the player will start again from the beginning of the current screen. Once a player has lost all three lives a game over will happen.Power-UpsPower-Up BlockThere are falling question mark blocks with wings that will fall from the top of the screen. These blocks will contain various power-ups such as: points, health, lives, or a shield that allows the player to take more hits before losing a life.ScoreThe ScoreNinja Rabbits features high scores. A player will receive points for various activities in the game such as defeating an enemy or getting a point power-up. The score is represented by a six digit number at the top of the screen.Version DifferencesThere are some differences between the games on the various platforms. The biggest change is the layout of the hud, which is different in the DOS version than it is in the other versions. The levels are also in different orders in some of the versions.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="244">CheetahMen II</game><game id="5996">Kung-Fu Master</game><game id="7421">Samurai Warrior: The Battles of Usagi Yojimbo</game><game id="525">Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Manhattan Missions</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/10/103881/1856670-nrataristeuro.jpg</image></root>