<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15480</id><name>Yie Ar Kung-Fu</name><description>OverviewPlayers control  Oolong, who must fight all martial arts masters in the game to gain the name of "Grand Master" and keep the memory of his father.  Characters Buchu Buchu is a sumo wrestler who uses a leaping motion to land on the player. Buchu's size means he is a slow opponent though. Buchu does not use weapons to fight and he is the first opponent the player faces.  Star Star is the first female opponent the player faces.  She is a ninja dressed in pink who wield shrunken, which slow down the player, as well as an array of punches and kicks  Nuncha Nuncha attacks the player with nunchuks, dressed in bright yellow.  Like Star, his weapon can slow down the player.  Pole Not surprisingly, Pole attacks the player with a pole, which he also uses to vault for extra speed and distance in his attacks.  Feedle Feedle is an odd enemy, in that he replicates himself to attack the player from every side.  Feedle is not present in the Commodore 64 and some other ports of the game.  Chain Chain starts off the second gauntlet.  He attacks the player with a giant chain with a claw weapon attached to the end.  Club Club wields a large spiked club, and uses a shield to block the player's attacks.  Fan Another character whose name is their weapon, Fan throws steel fans at the character, and launches ferocious attacks.  Sword Sword uses a sword, and is adept at launching arial attacks at the player.  Tonfun The penultimate opponent, Tonfun tries to best the player using tonfa and martial arts.  Key to victory is proper timing and waiting for openings in Tonfun's attacks.  Blues  Blues is the final opponent, and looks just like the player, except he wears no shirt.  After defeating Blues, the game starts over again at Buchu.  Characters in NES and MSX ports Wang Wang is armed with a Pole, but does not use it as effectively as Pole.  Tao Tao throws fireballs and is similar to Star.  Chen Chen is basically a copy of Chain.  Lang A quicker version of Star.  Wu/Mu  Wu in the MSX version, and MU in the NES, he is very similar to Buchu, and after he is defeated, the challenge starts again.  Hidden Characters in the GBA version Bishoo  A woman who uses daggers to attack the player. Clayman  A statue whoa attacks with a gigantic sword.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19786">Boot Camp</game><game id="7250">Karate Champ</game><game id="1235">Street Fighter</game><game id="243">Street Fighter II: The World Warrior</game><game id="2396">Fatal Fury</game><game id="15974">Shao-Lin's Road</game><game id="12660">Bushido</game><game id="11220">Altered Beast: Guardian of the Realms</game><game id="7090">Fuuun Shourinken</game><game id="8260">Fuuun Shaolin Kyo: Ankoku no Maou</game><game id="40136">Hiryu no Ken II: Dragon no Tsubasa</game><game id="40169">Big Challenge! Judo Senshuken</game><game id="16203">Fighting Road</game><game id="43454">Kung-Fu Street</game><game id="43936">Long Life</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1389145-yie_ar_kung_fu_flyer.png</image></root>