<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15483</id><name>Star Wars: X-Wing Vs. TIE Fighter</name><description>Unlike the previous titles in the series,    X-Wing and   Tie Fighter, this title's single player campaign consists of a series of missions not tied together by a story. Instead it plays as a series of scenarios intended for multiplayer, that are also playable with only one player - in which case the other players are A.I.-controlled.   This entry in the series saw a minor bump-up in graphics, adding more detailed textures (the previous games used goraud-shading and virtually no texturing) and SVGA resolution. The soundtrack consists of selections from John Williams's Star Wars trilogy scores, in contrast with the dynamic MIDI soundtrack of the previous two games.   The game box included 2 discs: one with the complete game and a second disc which allowed only multiplayer, to play with a friend buying just one copy of the game. Both discs carried also the game soundtrack, formed by 8 tracks.  An expansion of the game was successively released,  Balance of Power.Game Modes Although the game did not feature the classic single player, story-driven campaign, it was possible to play different game modes, for a total of 60 missions, all available also for multiplayer with up to 7 other people. The scores obtained in all missions contributed to player statistics and ranking.ExerciseExercise missions teach the basics of flying, shooting, power management and team work. They usually start with some simple tasks for beginners, but if played for their entire length they can become tough challenges.  MeleeMelee was the most classic mode for competitive multiplayer: teams of pilots can fight in straightforward deathmatches or try to achieve the most points destroying special targets.  TournamentA series of 3 or 5 melee matches are played, choosing a specific side (Rebel Alliance or Empire). The winner is the faction that wins most of them.  CombatCombat mode includes complex missions, playable on the same side ore competitively, with different situations and objectives, like defending a rebel convoy or attacking an imperial platform. These missions require good dogfighting skills but also attention to ship choice, squadron roles and organization.  Battle3, 5 or 7 missions are played, from the Combat mode, choosing one faction for all of them. Playing the whole 7 missions on one side can be thought as the substitute of the classic campaign.  Playable Ships  I mperial ships:  TIE Fighter: quite fast and maneuverable fighter, lacking shields and armed with only two laser cannons. TIE Interceptor: faster and a bit more resistant than the TIE fighter, armed with 4 cannons, but still lacking shields. TIE Advanced: an upgraded version of the TIE Interceptor, with shields and 4 cannons but less mneuverability. TIE Bomber: a heavy ship (although lacking shields) that can carry many warheads. It's large and slow, and it has only 2 cannons.Assault Gunboat: armed with 2 laser cannons and 2 ion cannons (used to disable other ships), the Assault Gunboat is hard to destroy (thanks to the shields and tough hull) and powerful, but it's slow and less maneuverable than the other imperial ships.  Rebel ships: X-Wing: the standard rebel fighter is armed with 4 cannons and has average performances in speed, resilience and maneuverability. A-Wing: the fastest of rebel ships, it has low fire power (2 cannons) and light shields, and it is a great incursion fighter.Z-95 Headhunter: Z-95 is the precursor of X-Wing, having worse performances than its upgrade (2 cannons and lighter shields) but a little more maneuverability. Y-Wing: a heavy bomber, armed with 2 laser and 2 ion cannons. It has strong shields and hull, and is used for attacks to great starships. Minimum Requirements Windows 95Intel Pentium 9016 MB RAMPCI graphic cardDirectX 516 bit sound card2X Speed CD-ROM drive required. 4X or better recommendedJoystick required    </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16002">Wing Commander</game><game id="10309">Descent: Freespace - The Great War</game><game id="4011">Star Wars: Rogue Squadron</game><game id="19727">Star Wars: TIE Fighter</game><game id="22334">Light Speed</game><game id="22979">Dark Horizon</game><game id="17257">Wing Commander: The Secret Missions 2 - Crusade</game><game id="25338">Beyond the Red Line</game><game id="12317">X: Beyond the Frontier</game><game id="39107">Starshatter: The Gathering Storm</game><game id="10232">Wing Commander Academy</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/10831/897931-xvtbox.jpg</image></root>