<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15499</id><name>Armadillo Run</name><description>OverviewArmadillo Run is a physics based puzzle game developed by Peter Stock. Armadillo Run made the shortlist (nominated for the Seumas McNally Grand Prize and the Design Innovation Award) at the 2007 IGF awards. It is independantly published, and is only available from the games website armadillorun.com.GameplayThe main aim of the game is to move the armadillo textured ball into the blue sphere for 5 seconds. This is done using the physics engine and a number of different materials to build a structure that will do this. The different types of matierials available are:ropeclothmetal barmetal sheetselasticrubberrocketsEach of the materials have a cost associated with them, they are listed in cost order above. The secondary goal of each level is to remain under budget.Most levels have anchor points which are solid points that do not move, allowing the structure to be built around them. There are also levels which do not use these, requiring rockets to hold up a lightweight structure.The game comes with 50 developer-made levels; however users can use the included level editor to make their own and then share them with other users of the game online. This gives the game unlimited potential as there will always be new levels released by other users.There is a sort of classification of levels called Spectator levels. These are levels the editor made so that crazy chain reactions, or something humorous happens, without any input from the player except the initial press of Start.PC System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows 95/98/ME/NT/2000/XPProcessor: Pentium 3 @ 500 MHzMemory: 64 MBVideo Memory: SVGA, OpenGL CompatibleCD/DVD Rom DriveMinimumOS: Windows 95/98/ME/NT/2000/XPProcessor: Pentium 3 @ 1 GHzMemory: 128 MBVideo Memory: SVGA, OpenGL CompatibleSound Card: Windows Compatible</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21141">Elefunk</game><game id="7654">The Incredible Machine</game><game id="24960">Tiki Towers</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/630/239095-66b595eac93f4093845132c275204b7b_armadillorun1.png</image></root>