<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15550</id><name>Kirby Air Ride</name><description>OverviewKirby's Air Ride is a kart racer starring the puffy, pink hero, Kirby. The game is notable for its simplistic control scheme that only uses the analog stick for direction and one button on the Gamecube controller for decelerating and using power ups. Unlike most other driving games, acceleration occurs regardless of player input. The game is primarily intended to be played with multiple people, as there are no dedicated career modeGame ModesAir RideRace to the Finish on one of several courses. You can utilize boost pads, triggers, copy abilities and more to gain an advantage. Free Run mode also acts as a Time Trial mode that allows to set records.Top RideThis mode plays the most differently compared to the other two which the various tracks only fill a single screen (reminiscent of Super Off Road) You have access to only two vehicles in this mode; the free star (Where you can point in the direction you want to go) and the steer star (which has relative controls)City TrialPlayers have a limited time to traverse a city, collecting stat-building powerups to be used against other players in various minigames after the allotted time limit expires. You'll start in the Compact Star which has lower stats. By holding the action button and down on the control stick, you can dismount your Air Ride in order to board another one. However you won't be able to obtain any power ups while not riding a vehicle. Playing in Free Run mode allows you to use any unlocked vehicleLAN PlayFour players playing in system link mode.This game is one of the few titles compatible with the Broadband Adapater. Up to four systems can be linked together. When two systems are linked, up to two players can play on one system, however when playing with three or more systems, only one player per console can play. Any unlocked content located on the memory card can be used for LAN play. Only Air Ride and City Trial modes are playable with most of the customizable options available.ChecklistThe game also features several unlockables that become available via an achievement system labeled as the Checklist. This consists of a board with several panels that turn around only when certain conditions have been met. Some challenges will also reward additional vehicles, characters, songs in the Sound Test and more. Revealing purple spaces also allows you to clear a challenge without actually having to fulfill it's normal requirements. Not all challenges can be unlocked through this method however. This system would later appear in Super Smash Bros. Brawl and Kid Icarus Uprising.Air Ride MachinesMachine NameDescriptorGame ModesFree StarMachine will steer based on the control stick's direction.TopSteer StarMachine can be steered left or right.TopCompact StarSlower, but easy to control. Starter for City TrialCityWarpstarAll-round type of vehicleAir, CityRocket StarGrants a strong speed boost after 100% chargeAir, CityWinged StarGoes faster in the airAir, CityShadow StarAttacks the strongestAir, CityWagon StarUnable to charge for boosts.Air, CitySwerve StarCan only steer while charging (Which immediately stops the vehicle)Air, CitySlick StarHas slippery handlingAir, CityTurbo StarVery fast, tough steeringAir, CityFormula StarBest top speedAir, CityBulk StarMoves after charging, very strong.Air, CityJet StarMoves faster while in the airAir, CityWheelie BikeControl is unorthodox.Air, CityRex WheelieVery fast if you can keep it under control.Air, CityWheelie ScooterHigh jumper, can quick turnAir, CityKing DeDeDeAlways has hammer ability, great power.Air, CityMeta KnightAlways has sword ability, great at flyingAir, CityFlight WarpstarHas upgraded gliding capabilitiesAir, CityHydraLegendary machine, has extra battle power. Must be assembled in City mode.CityDragoonCan stay in the air for as long as possible. Must be assembled in City mode.CityCoursesCourse NameDescriptionGame ModesFantasy MeadowsAir, CityCelestial ValleyAir, CitySky SandsAir, CityFrozen HillsideAir, CityMagma FlowsAir, CityBeanstalk ParkAir, CityMachine PassageAir, CityChecker KnightsAir, CityNebula BeltAir, CityGrassTopSandTopSkyTopFireTopLightTopWaterTopMetalTopCityCityCopy AbilitiesDefeating enemies with the different copy abilities allows you to gain a speed boost. You can attack rival racers to slow them down.AbilityDescriptionSwordRun into enemies to attackPlasmaTap the control stick to charge, press Action to fireWingGain a speed boostWheelObtain better flying abilitiesSleepWiggle the control stick to regain control.BombHold the action button to throw your bomb farther. This also causes you to break however.NeedleAttack enemies around you.MicrophoneImmediate use, has greater area of damage</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15802">Sonic Riders</game><game id="20582">Sonic Riders: Zero Gravity</game><game id="2260">Sonic R</game><game id="20448">F-Zero GX</game><game id="20858">NASCAR 09</game><game id="19071">Super Mario Kart</game><game id="20644">Donkey Kong: Barrel Blast</game><game id="39998">Hugo Bukkazoom!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1865067-box_kar.png</image></root>