<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15569</id><name>Genji: Days of the Blade</name><description>StorylineYoshitsune and his friend Benkei battle against the evil Heishi clan along with two other new characters, Lady Shizuka, and Lord Buson. Together they battle the Heishi soldiers that have merged with mashogane and have become demons. This takes place three years after the previous game, Genji: Dawn of the Samurai. They must do whatever they can to protect the "amahagane". The "amahagane" is what allows you to activate your "kamui", which looks like a sphere and comes in several different colors.MemesWhen unveiling PlayStation 3 hardware at E3 2006 during the Sony Press Conference, Genji: Days of the Blade (then "Genji 2") was among the first live stage demonstrations. Presenter Bill Ritch, who produced the game, described Genji 2 as "an action game based on Japanese history," with "battles that actually took place in ancient Japan," despite the game's obvious fantasy elements. Poor word choice and an unremarkable feature set are said to have birthed three separate internet memes: "Giant Enemy Crab," "Attack its Weak Point for Massive Damage," and "Real-time Weapon Change," the latter two having been described by Ritch as "new" features that were previously impossible on lesser hardware."Giant Enemy Crab" and "Attack its Weak Point for Massive Damage" have been frequently reference in other games. In Heavenly Sword, Kai threatens a guard by shouting "attacking your weak point for massive damage." Both LittleBigPlanet and Scribblenauts featured Giant Enemy Crabs as items. MotorStorm features a race event called "Giant Enemy Crab." Both Wrath of the Lich King and Castlevania: Order of Ecclesia feature Giant Enemy Crabs as boss characters. The third area in Stage 2 of God Hand is titled "Giant Enemy Crane".</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20816">Dynasty Warriors 6</game><game id="21424">Dynasty Warriors: Gundam</game><game id="5552">Warriors Orochi</game><game id="10139">Samurai Warriors</game><game id="13072">Devil May Cry</game><game id="2136">Onimusha: Dawn of Dreams</game><game id="7876">Heavenly Sword</game><game id="26431">Kengo: Legend of the 9</game><game id="29924">GoDai: Elemental Force</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1832140-box_genjidotb.png</image></root>