<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15584</id><name>Virtua Fighter</name><description>OverviewThe game plays in a 3D format. The Saturn technology and NV1 architecture in the game relied on quadratic surfaces instead of polygons that are used in modern 3D graphics. The images were created by using wire frames and flat-shaded quads. The game retains it's staple of multiple characters, who all have their own distinctive moves.It differed from other fighting games from the same era as the game relied on only the control stick and three buttons, punch, kick and guard. The game is highly regarded for the real world fighting techniques and it's in-depth fighting engine, and it was as a result viewed as revolutionary when it was first came out.CharactersAkira YukiSarah BryantWolf HawkfieldDuralJacky BryantKage-MaruJeffry McWildLau ChanPai ChanAn Arabian character named Siba was originally scheduled to be featured in the game. His character model did in fact appear on some Virtua Fighter arcade cabinets. He was eventually dropped, but he makes an appearance in Sega Saturn Fighters MegaMix.Launch Game:Virtua Fighter was a North American launch game for the Sega Saturn (SS) on May 11, 1995. The game launched alongside other Saturn launch titles that included:* Panzer Dragoon* Daytona USAThat's right, the Saturn launched with only three games in North America.Rushed to meet the Saturn launch, the Saturn version is considered inferior to the Arcade and 32X versions. The game featured lesser graphics and more sluggish gameplay.Sega later released Virtua Fighter Remix, an improved version of the original that came free by mail with registration of a Saturn.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5238">Battle Arena Toshinden</game><game id="10081">Tekken</game><game id="21878">Tobal No. 1</game><game id="6153">Soul Blade</game><game id="3744">Def Jam: Fight for NY</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="6421">Mortal Kombat 4</game><game id="3965">X-Men: Mutant Academy 2</game><game id="25109">Dragonball: Evolution</game><game id="13172">Fighters Destiny</game><game id="31276">Yusha - Heaven's Gate</game><game id="6409">Kensei: Sacred Fist</game><game id="36592">Noite Animal</game><game id="11081">FX Fighter</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1791105-box_vf1.png</image></root>