<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1563</id><name>Spyro 2: Ripto's Rage</name><description>GeneralSpyro 2: Ripto's Rage! is the sequel to the 1998 PlayStation hit Spyro the Dragon. Ripto's Rage was developed by Insomniac Games, as was its predecessor. It is known as Spyro 2: Gateway to Glimmer in Europe and Australia, and Spyro x Sparx: Tondemo Tours in Japan.The series protagonist, Spyro the Dragon, decides that he wants a take a vacation to Dragon Shores with dragonfly friend Sparx a few years after defeating Gnasty Gnorc. Instead the portal that he enters leads into Avalar. This is because the Professor, Elora and Hunter were trying to bring a dragon to Avalar. A sorcerer known by Ripto has invaded the world of Avalar and is wreaking havoc all over Avalar. Spyro must travel throughout Avalar, undoing the damage which has been caused by Ripto and ultimately defeating him.The game was made available on Playstation Network on July 27, 2007, though it was removed a week later due to emulation problems.GameplaySpyro 2: Ripto's RageSpyro 2 is a platform game, and most gameplay elements from the original were carried over to the sequel. Spyro has two main attacks, the traditional dragon power of fire breath, and a charging attack. Players must creatively utilize Spyro's abilities to take down the enemies throughout the game. Using his wings, Spyro can glide across each level, depending on how high Spyro is when he begins his glide. Spyro uses his gliding abilities to get past many obstacles, and use updrafts to travel further.The main point of the game is to get through each level and earn that level's talisman, collecting gems along the way. There are also "sidequests" that can be completed for orbs, which are necessary to unlock certain levels.Spyro also gains new abilites in this sequel. A character named Moneybags is introduced, and Spyro can purchase new moves from him. Over the course of the game, you can eventually buy swimming, ladder climbing, and headbash skills. Spyro can also power up using special gates that are activated once a certain number of enemies are defeated.Spyro also features some events which alternate how the game is played, such as roller coaster sections.LevelsThe game is divided into three worlds, each with their own unique levels. There is also a bonus world, Dragon Shores.Summer ForestGlimmerIdol SpringsColossusSunny BeachHurricosAquaria TowersOcean SpeedwayCrush's DungeonAutumn PlainsSkelos BadlandCrystal GlacierBreeze HarborZephyrScorchFracture HillsMagma ConeShady OasisIce SpeedwayMetro SpeedwayGulp's OverlookWinter TundraMystic MarshCloud TemplesRobotica FarmsMetropolisCanyon SpeedwayRipto's LairDragon ShoresSoundtrack by Stewart Copeland"Gateway to Glimmer Forest""Summer Forest""Idol Springs""Colossus""Let's Play Hockey!""Hurricos""Sunny Beach""Aquaria Towers""Clash With Crush!""Ocean Speedway""Autumn Plains""Skelos Badlands""Save The Cavemen!""Save Them Again!!!""Crystal Glacier""Crystal Glacier II""Breeze Harbor""Harbor Trolley Trouble!""Zephyr""Scorch""Magma Cone""Grab The Crystal Popcorn!""Shady Oasis""Gulp's Overlook""Metro Speedway""Icy Speedway""Winter Tundra""Mystic Marsh""Cloud Temples""Track Agent Zero!""Robotica Farms"Metropolis""Ripto's Arena""Canyon Speedway""Dragon Shores"ESRBThe ESRB rated the game Everyone for Mild Animated Violence.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7380">Crash Bandicoot</game><game id="20330">Gex 3: Deep Cover Gecko</game><game id="18309">Ratchet &amp; Clank</game><game id="3438">MediEvil II</game><game id="4228">Haven: Call of the King</game><game id="10384">Jak II</game><game id="14623">Jak and Daxter: The Precursor Legacy</game><game id="9669">Jak 3</game><game id="14604">Daxter</game><game id="21000">Secret Agent Clank</game><game id="21115">Ratchet &amp; Clank Future: Quest for Booty</game><game id="15212">Ratchet &amp; Clank Future: Tools of Destruction</game><game id="4966">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Up Your Arsenal</game><game id="4618">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Going Commando</game><game id="8837">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Size Matters</game><game id="18745">Ratchet: Deadlocked</game><game id="8660">Crash Bandicoot 2: Cortex Strikes Back</game><game id="68">Crash Bandicoot: The Wrath of Cortex</game><game id="732">Crash Bandicoot Purple: Ripto's Rampage</game><game id="3457">MediEvil</game><game id="2931">Super Mario 64</game><game id="7406">Super Mario Bros. 2</game><game id="8224">New Super Mario Bros.</game><game id="7852">Sonic Adventure</game><game id="19060">Sonic Adventure 2</game><game id="11120">LEGO Star Wars: The Complete Saga</game><game id="20822">LEGO Batman: The Videogame</game><game id="15773">LEGO Island 2: The Brickster's Revenge</game><game id="20640">Kung Fu Panda</game><game id="16337">Sly 3: Honor Among Thieves</game><game id="15573">Sly 2: Band of Thieves</game><game id="15353">Sly Cooper and the Thievius Raccoonus</game><game id="7804">Rocket: Robot on Wheels</game><game id="15991">Chameleon Twist 2</game><game id="18376">Looney Tunes Back in Action</game><game id="7212">Klonoa 2: Lunatea's Veil</game><game id="24704">Frogger</game><game id="21460">Gurumin: A Monstrous Adventure</game><game id="8698">Tail Concerto</game><game id="35545">Fuse</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1803986-box_spyro2.png</image></root>