<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1567</id><name>Die by the Sword</name><description>OverviewDie by the Sword is a computer sword fighting game developed by Treyarch (who later went on to create some of the Call of Duty games), and released on February 28th, 1998.GameplayThe title's unique selling point was the introduction of the V.S.I.M. control system, which allowed players to independently command the movement and sword fighting of their character by running, jumping, and turning with one hand, while simultaneously slashing, stabbing, and parrying with the other. While many games of this type allow for a similar systems, Die by the Sword remains to this day unique in its treatment of physically correct and force-based melee combat. The combat system is comparable to that of Squaresoft's Bushido Blade released a year earlier.Much of the fun in Die by the Sword came from its deathmatch and cooperative multiplayer play in its arena mode, where players could stage fights with up to three other players or AI characters. However, the lack of a match-making service precludes any significant online community, which when combined with a poor online interface relegates the title to local games only.V.S.I.M. Move EditorThere was a separate executable in which players could record a sequence of mouse moves. Players could then recall these moves with a keypress in the main game.ReceptionWhile the game was well received by critics, the recent PC release of Tomb Raider crippled Treyarch's sales figures. In a large part this was due to the game as having difficult controls, challenging gameplay, and a steep learning curve for novice players.AvailabilityThe game was re-released on digital distribution service GOG.com for $5.99.</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15065">Dark Messiah of Might &amp; Magic</game><game id="13474">Rune</game><game id="19285">Moonstone: A Hard Days Knight</game><game id="19907">Heretic II</game><game id="4796">Sword of Sodan</game><game id="5405">Sword of the Berserk: Guts' Rage</game><game id="10746">Shadow Man</game><game id="4254">Crusaders of Might and Magic</game><game id="21473">Blade of Darkness</game><game id="9641">Age of Conan: Hyborian Adventures</game><game id="4973">Xena: Warrior Princess</game><game id="1804">Gothic II</game><game id="1982">Gothic</game><game id="1132">Wild Wild West: The Steel Assassin</game><game id="38006">Chivalry: Medieval Warfare</game><game id="36170">War of the Roses</game><game id="21192">Mount &amp; Blade</game><game id="6399">Bushido Blade</game><game id="7960">Draconus: Cult of the Wyrm</game><game id="2694">Ultima IX: Ascension</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5911/764239-dieby.jpg</image></root>