<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15692</id><name>MechWarrior 4: Black Knight</name><description>OverviewMechWarrior 4: Black Knight is an expansion pack to MechWarrior 4: Vengeance that contains new 'Mechs, multiplayer modes and a black market for trading equipment. This expansion requires the MechWarrior 4: Vengeance to be installed and is not a stand-alone adventure.StoryThe story follows Eric McClair, a recently discharged 'Mech pilot from House Davion. Eric joins the Black Knight Legion, a mercenary group led by Colonel Lawhorn. Initially taking on mundane escort contracts from the Corvatti Corporation, the Legion is approached by Lyran Alliance mercenary liaison officer, Major Clarrisa Dupree. The major offers a contract for the Legion to assist in the retake of Kentares IV on behalf of House Steiner and gives free 'Mechs to the Legion as a gesture of goodwill. On Kentares IV, the Legion runs disruption missions, taking out key assets to Duke Ian Dressari's forces.The Legion is soon double-crossed by Major Dupree who is now in allegiance with Ian Dressari. The Legion is attacked by Steiner mechs, killing Colonel Lawhorn and putting Eric McClair in charge of the company. McClair decides to continue the original contract, going after Ian Dressari. Working with rebels, McClair works his way to Dressari's palace and kills him along with his closest supporters. McClair then sets his sights on Major Dupree. Hunting her down to the planet Voltrat III, the Legion kills Dupree and her entire garrison of Lyran 'Mechs. McClair decides to make Voltrat III the new home of the Black Knight Legion.GameplayThe campaign features 23 new missions divided into five "Ops". The player salvages weapons and 'Mechs like in the first game. New to campaign is persistent inventory. Destroyed 'Mechs and weapons disappear from the armory. Damaged or crippled 'Mechs require time to repair and if the player chooses to pilot these 'Mechs on the next mission, they start out damaged. The campaign also features the black market, allowing players to trade for the 'Mechs and weapons they need.Additional Multiplayer modes have been addedAbsolute Attrition: Like Attrition but now tonnage is factored into the score. Lighter 'Mechs are rewarded for taking on heavier 'Mechs'Mech Strongholds: Both teams have a headquarters and must destroy the other team'sSiege Assault: Destroy or defend the HQGolaiths: A small team of assault 'Mechs against a larger team of light 'MechsClan vs Inner Sphere: One team is Clan and the other team is Inner Sphere. Teams are restricted to their faction's equipment and 'MechsNew 'Mechs and WeaponsWeaponsAutocannon 20Ultra Autocannon 10/ 20Clan Ultra Autocannon 10/ 20Cluster BombSmall/ Medium/ Large X-Pulse Laser'MechsNameInformationWolfhoundManufacturer:	TharHes Industries, Arc-Royal MechWorksIntroduced: 3028Model: WLF-2Class:	LightCost: 3,141,180 C-billsMass:	35 tonsChassis:	Arc-Royal KH/3Armor:	Durallex MediumEngine:	GM 210Speed:	97.2 km/hJump Jets:	NoneArmament: 1xER Large Laser, 4xMedium LasersUllerManufacturer:	Babylon MechWorks V, Production Line Gamma 2, Ironhold Plant 9Introduced: 2890Model: PrimeClass:	LightCost: 5,368,837 C-billsMass:	30 tonsChassis:	Process 12 Endo SteelArmor:	Compound H18 Ferro-FibrousEngine:	Starfire 180 XLCommunications System: CobraTalk 12Speed:	97.2 km/hJump Jets:	NoneArmament: 1xLB-X Autocannon/5, 1xER Large Laser, 1xSmall Pulse Laser, 1xStreak SRM-4RyokenManufacturer:	Tokasha MechWorks GammaIntroduced: 2930Model: PrimeClass:	MediumCost: 14,771,112 C-billsMass:	55 tonsChassis:	Model MHO-7E Endo SteelArmor:	Compound H17/2 Ferro-FibrousEngine:	Fusion 330 XLSpeed:	97.2 km/hJump Jets:	NoneArmament: 3xER Medium Lasers, 2xER Large LasersBlack KnightManufacturer:	Kong Interstellar Corporation, Robinson Standard BattleWorksIntroduced: 2578Model: BL-6-KNTClass:	HeavyCost: 7,136,938 C-billsMass:	75 tonsChassis:	Technicron 1L Endo SteelArmor:	Numall DuraBondEngine:	Vlar 300Speed:	64.8 km/hJump Jets:	NoneArmament: 1xPPC, 2xLarge Lasers, 4xMedium Lasers, 1xSmall LaserSunderManufacturer:	Luthien Armor Works, StarCorps St. Ives, StarCorps Crofton[2]Model: SD1-OClass:	AssaultCost: 27,693,687 C-billsMass:	90 tonsChassis:	Alshain Class 98 OmniArmor:	Mitchel ArgonEngine:	Hermes 360 XLSpeed:	64.8 km/hJump Jets:	NoneArmament: 1xAutocannon/20, 2xLarge Lasers, 3xSRM-4s, 2xMedium Lasers</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19442">MechWarrior 4: Clan 'Mech Pak</game><game id="5305">MechWarrior 4: Inner Sphere 'Mech Pak</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4748/617498-mw4blacknight.jpg</image></root>