<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1570</id><name>Bloody Roar 3</name><description>GameplayThe game uses a total of six buttons - thought the shoulder buttons on the PS2 controller are optional. The button commands are punch, kick, throw, beast form button, and the L2  R2 button is side-step left and side-step right - the player has the option to double tap up or down to side-step.Long, in beast form.The main feature in the Bloody Roar series,the Beast Form, returns in Bloody Roar 3. A fight in the game starts with both fighters meters filled up and both players have the option to transform into a beast. While in beast form, the player can recover some of the health that was lost over time and can perform "Beast Drive" - in other words, super combo that was seen in Capcom and SNK fighting games.The Beast Drive is pretty much the Super Combo. When perform, the player can recover all of the health that the player can get back instead of waiting to recover it in a short amount of time.Another feature is "Hyper Beast Form", what it is it's a faster  stronger version of the Beast Form that can be use for about twelve seconds.CharactersCharacter select screen.Yugo/WolfAlice/RabbitBakuryu/MoleShina/LeopardBusuzima/ChameleonLong/TigerUriko/Half BeastJenny/BatStun/InsectGado/LionShen Long/TigerXion/UnbornCritical ReceptionGame Informer gave the review scores of 8 and 8 out of 10. Reiner wrote, "The series hasn't made the gigantic leap that Tekken and Dead or Alive have, yet its gameplay continues to improve and comes across as a well-balanced and addictive fighter. Structured as a culmination of the first two releases, Bloody Roar's cast now includes 14 characters -- 12 of which are available from the outset... The character models are fantastic and include the smallest of details. On the other hand the environments are as plain as can be... When all is said and done, however, this is a fine release, and another PS2 fighter with a vicious gameplay bite".Electronic Gaming Monthly gave the review scores of 6.0, 6.0 and 5.0 out of ten. Jonathan Dudlak, who gave a 6.0, wrote, "...plays a lot like the second Bloody Roar. The sidestep is now part of the normal game, which is handy, and the three new fighters are all pretty fun to play... You can painstakingly land a ton of combos to ship away at your opponent, but all it takes is one easily enacted super attack to eben the score. Even as a fan of the Bloody Roar games I got frustraed fast...".</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11822">Soulcalibur II</game><game id="10162">Tekken Tag Tournament</game><game id="2045">Dead or Alive 2</game><game id="4313">Virtua Fighter 4</game><game id="20678">Soulcalibur IV</game><game id="19043">Fighters Megamix</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="11065">Shaman King: Power of Spirit</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="11189">Tekken 3</game><game id="21550">Super Dragon Ball Z</game><game id="21948">Street Fighter III: New Generation</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2171261-box_broar3.png</image></root>