<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1572</id><name>Myst Online: Uru Live</name><description>Overview Myst Online: URU Live is a continuation of the singleplayer game URU: Ages Beyond Myst. This is an MMOG (Massively Multiplayer Online Game). There are no Role-Playing elements or other identifiers for this. It is simply just an experience of exploring and puzzle solving in different worlds either alone or with friends as you would in the traditional Myst games.            Gameplay The gameplay is very familiar MMO/Third-Person/First-Person control style. It can be played in third or first person, by scrolling the mouse wheel to change your view from far away third person closer until finally into the eyes of the player. Movement is done with the WASD keys. It is also consistant with that of the more recent Myst games (Myst IV: Revelations and Myst V: End of Ages) where you are free to move around without having to click screen to screen, as it is in a fully 3D world(s). You'll interact with the world by left-clicking to solve the various puzzles.    HistoryThe 2007-2008 attempt at bringing URU back, this was canceled by GameTap in 2008.In 2008-2009, Cyan Worlds, Inc. was looking to bring it back in the form of MYST Online Restoration Experiment (MORE). Info about this is forthcoming, however, it will be using content from the fan-run, Cyan-sanctioned Guild of Writers, with no Cyan-created content foreseeable for the near future.  On February 8th, 2010, Cyan Worlds, Inc. has brought one server online and allows for new account creation and downloading the client to get going again. They have now referred to this project as "Myst Online: URU Liveagain". You can sign-up and get the client here. All the Ages are unlocked and most of the original content is there, of course with time it will be 100%. The client and use of the Myst Online service is completely free. However, it is optional to make donations via PayPal.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="42">Uru: Ages Beyond Myst</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/19013/760967-uruwallpaper2.jpg</image></root>