<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15819</id><name>Castlevania Chronicles</name><description>Overview Simon Belmont, the game's main protagonist (sporting his 2001 redesign).     Castlevania Chronicles (known in Japan as Castlevania Chronicle: Akumajō Dracula, translated to Castlevania Chronicle: Devil's Castle Dracula) is an action horror platformer developed by              KCE Tokyo and published by             Konami for the            Sony PlayStation on October 8, 2001. Originally a Japan-only 1993 game for the Sharp X68000 (titled Akumajō Dracula, translated to Devil's Castle Dracula), Castlevania Chronicles is an enhanced remake of the original         Castlevania, improving the graphics, music, and game engine while being more accurate to the original game (as opposed to        Super Castlevania IV, which completely revamped the levels and content). The plot and premise for Castlevania Chronicles remains the same as the original Castlevania (and its other recreations): players control heroic      vampire hunter    Simon Belmont, wielder of the     Vampire Killer whip, as he sets out through a dark, unholy castle in the year 1691 to search and destroy the evil       Count Dracula.Gameplay It includes two modes: Original mode, which is a faithful emulation of the original game.Arrange mode, which updates the art in some places and uses new music.Simon Belmont's design for the original version. Extras:If you hold L1 and R1 while selecting either original or arrange mode and press start, you are given the option to choose which of three sound modules you would like to use.  The FM synthesizer module is the lowest quality, while the Roland GS module offers the highest quality.  In original mode, it defaults to the lowest quality module, so this can be used to improve the audio experience significantly.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="28250">Rusty</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1773363-box_cvc.png</image></root>