<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15867</id><name>Time Crisis</name><description>This arcade game was released into arcades in 1995.  It was later brought to the PlayStation in 1997.  The game is a first person rail shooter that is played with a light gun and a foot pedal.  The foot pedal is used to move out from behind cover to begin shooting.  While the pedal is released the player is moved behind cover so that he can reload without being hit.  The light gun that this arcade game used had a blowback function where the top of the gun would slide back to simulate a real gun.  The game is moved along by a constantly decreasing timer that is only increased by completing a stage.StoryThe plot of this game is that there is an attempted coup in the republic of Sercia.  The Garo family had ruled Sercia for a millennium.  But in 1995, the VSSE Interantonal Intelligence Agency sent William MacPherson, who was able to topple the Garo regime and become the first democratically elected president.Sheruda Garo, the last member of the Garo family, sought to recapture the throne from the new president, President MacPherson.  Sheruda sends a mercenary to kidnap the president's daughter, Rachel.  Garo tries to blackmail the new government by demanding military secrets in trade for the president's daughters life.  If the secrets were not delivered by sunset or else Rachel would be killed.  The VSSE decides to send an agent, Richard Miller (The Player), to infiltrate Garo's castle and rescue Rachel.  After being sent into a trap, Miller discovers the real location of Rachel.  He battles his way up Garo's castle to the upper levels and eventually finds Rachel.  But as he attempts to rescue her, the mercenary, Wild Dog, captures her again and and drags her away.  Miller pursues Wild Dog outside of the castle to their final battle point, a bridge.  Wild dog begins to blow up the castle in a last ditch effort to escape. Miller is able to get Rachel and escape before the castle and WIld dog is engulfed in the explosion.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="35">Light-Gun Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="508">The House of the Dead</game><game id="1074">Link's Crossbow Training</game><game id="20519">Ghost Squad</game><game id="18347">Killer7</game><game id="19571">T2: The Arcade Game</game><game id="17486">Mad Dog McCree</game><game id="6490">Hogan's Alley</game><game id="19246">Vampire Night</game><game id="15008">Confidential Mission</game><game id="16218">Battle Clash</game><game id="10543">Virtua Cop</game><game id="2817">Corpse Killer</game><game id="14411">The Punisher: Ultimate Payback</game><game id="1744">Lethal Enforcers</game><game id="23055">The House of the Dead EX</game><game id="24019">Beast Busters</game><game id="3484">Metal Combat: Falcon's Revenge</game><game id="21751">Star Wars Trilogy Arcade</game><game id="23425">The House of the Dead: OVERKILL</game><game id="7500">Dino Stalker</game><game id="14613">Die Hard 2: Die Harder</game><game id="28482">Ninja Assault</game><game id="29501">Lethal Enforcers I &amp; II</game><game id="27011">Doom Resurrection</game><game id="30164">2 Spicy</game><game id="30607">Ranger Mission</game><game id="27102">Terminator Salvation</game><game id="9341">Virtua Cop 2</game><game id="35407">Deadstorm Pirates</game><game id="13495">Major Mayhem</game><game id="26883">Police 911</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1832171-box_tcrisis.png</image></root>