<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1591</id><name>Need for Speed Underground: Rivals</name><description>Premise Capitalising on the overwhelming popularity of Need for Speed: Underground, and it's equally well received sequel, Rivals tries to deliver a similiar experience on the PSP. The game features numerous import-friendly cars, as well as many ways in which the player can customise said vehicle; including decals, vinyls, spoilers and numerous paint jobs. Thematically the game dons the same badittude that has featured (Read: Plagued) the previous two installments. GameplayFeaturing the same arcade racing mechanic that introduced the previous two games to the masses, Need for Speed: Underground Rivals features tight corners and long straights. The street courses feature shortcuts that occasionally the AI will use. While not as graphically powerful as it's console brethren, it was considered a good looking portable game and for a short period of time was in the PSP's advertising campaign.Soundtrack1. The Bronx -Notice of Eviction2. Fluke - Switch/Twitch3. Capone - I Need Speed4. Rise Against - Give it All5. Killradio - Scavenger 6. Septembre - I am Weightless7. Sly Boogy - That'z my Name8. Killing Joke - The Death  Resurrection 9. Helmet - Crashing Foreign Cars10. Cirrus - Back on a Mission11. Spiderbait - Black Betty12. Christopher Lawrence - Rush Hour13. Felix Da Housecat - Rocket Ride (Soulwax-Rock it Right Mix)14. Xzibit - LAX15. Skindred - Nobody16. Snapcase - Skeptic17. Terror Squad Featuring Fat Joe - Lean Back18.Ministry - No W19. Unwritten Law - The Celebration20. Freeland - Mind Killer (Jagz Kooner Mix)21. Chingy - I Do22. Paul Van Dyk - Nothing But You (Cirrus Remix)23. Sonic Animation - E-Ville24. Sin - Hard EBM25. Snopp Dogg Featuring The Doors - Riders on The Storm (Fredwreck Remix)26. Queens of The Stone Age - In My Head27. Mudvayne - Determined28. DJ Tiesto - Breda 8pm (DJ Montana Edit)29. The Donots - We Got The Noise30. My Chemical Romance -Thank You For The Venom31. Hot Water Music - The End of The Line32. No Warning - Breeding Insanity</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9651">Need for Speed Underground 2</game><game id="11055">NASCAR 08</game><game id="21310">Juiced: Eliminator</game><game id="941">Project Gotham Racing</game><game id="10124">Midnight Club: Street Racing</game><game id="20418">Midnight Club II</game><game id="5875">Midnight Club 3: DUB Edition</game><game id="20927">Midnight Club: Los Angeles</game><game id="21114">Midnight Club: Los Angeles Remix</game><game id="7777">Juiced</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1793310-box_nfsur.png</image></root>