<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15986</id><name>Legaia 2: Duel Saga</name><description> Characters  Lang: Lang is the main protagonist of the story, and main character of the game. He is a young swordsman from the town of Nohl who was found as a child by Galvan, the leader of the Vigilante Corps -- the towns militia and protection. Lang is a Mystic who was chosen by the Source Forge who can control it and the three sacred stones. As a mystic he can also summon an origin, which in his case is Galea the origin of fire.  Maya: Maya is a decendent of the ancient group of people known as the Kabel. The Kabel were powerful magicians, and so it is no surprise that Maya can use magic herself. Unfortunately, Maya lost control of her magic at an early age, the result of which was the death of her parents. This brought great suffering upon Maya and the shock of the incident caused her to lose her voice.  Kazan: Kazan is a master of the Sky Fang martial art, and is introduced to the Lang by Maya early on. Kazan is an older man of 60 years but is a feirce opponent in battle. He has a number of regrets from ealier times in his life. He worked for Sharon's father for a long time, but after being forced in to killing his apprentice Rause, Kazan left the group and headed out on his own. Kazan controls the Deva, the origin of earth.  Sharon: Sharon is the leader of her own pirate ship. She's a bit full of herself and has many servants to make sure she never wants of anything. Arrode, the origin of thunder, is what she controls.   Ayne: Ayne is a massive tribesman, the strongest of his kind, and only non-mystic party member. He agrees to help the group after he is ordered by the tribe's chief.    Avalon: Avalon is the main antagonist of the story. As a child he witnessed the slaughtering of every mystic in his village. This enraged Avalon and awoke his own origin, Igohl, the strongest of all origins which controls ultimate power. His hatred drives him to want for a new world and so wishes nothing but destruction of the current one. Like Lang, he was chosen by the Source Forge.  Velna: Velna is a mystic who, like Maya, is from the bloodline of the Kabel. The big difference is that Velna is 100 years old and had survived the destruction of her tribe thanks to her origin Vestra -- so long as Vestra is alive, Velna can not die. Velna follows Avalon throughout the story. Rause: The former apprentice of Kazan, Rause was revived by Velna and bound to his armor to keep him alive. Since his revival, he has served Avalon. Doplin: Doplin is the ruler of Darakin castle and adoptive father of Marianne and Elliot. He is a cruel bishop, and hopes to one day rule the new world that is to be created by Avalon. Elliot: Elliot is the foster child of Doplin, and old er brother of Marianne. His origin is unnamed, but his sword like hands and is deep red in color. Marianne: The short and stubby younger sister of Elliot, Marianne enjoys tortchuring people and has a very short temper. Her origin has the likeness of a woman in a white dress and like Elliot's, is unnamed. Bubba: Bubba is the servant to Elliot and Marianne under the orders of Doplin. He is a very powerful human, but does not posess an origin, and so Elliot and Marianne enjoy pushing him around. Elfin: Elfin is a female yeti, and Bubba's pet and best friend.  OriginsIn Legaia 2, Origins are a form of summon that each character possesses within them. They have powers and abilities that regular humans cannot perform. Because of this, they prove useful in dungeons by performing tasks that humans cannot do. Origins are also quite useful in battle. Each of them has multiple abilities to aid your party during battles.  Lang's Origin: GaleaFlaming Fist: An attacking ability learned at level 1. It costs 32 mp to perform.Flame Crest: An enhancement ability learned at level 16. It costs 48 mp to perform.Hellfire Wings: An attacking ability learned at level 25. It costs 64 mp to perform.Final Flash: An attacking ability learned at level 34. It costs 96 mp to perform.Blazing Smash: An attacking ability learned at level 44. It costs 150 mp to perform. Maya's Origin: RivasLife Blessing: A restorative ability learned at level 1. It costs 16 mp to perform.Life Heal: A restorative ability learned at level 12. It costs 22 mp to perform.Solar Guidance: A restorative ability learned at level 22. It costs 34 mp to perform.Gospel: An enhancement ability learned at level 33. It costs 46 mp to perform.Glorious Mercy: A restorative ability learned at level 44. It costs 68 mp to perform.Kazan's Origin: DevaEarth Energy: An attacking ability learned at level 1. It costs 48 mp to perform.Earth Protector: An enhancement ability learned at level 27. It costs 64 mp to perform.Earth Charge: An attacking ability learned at level 34. It costs 80 mp to perform.Earth Rage: An attacking ability learned at level 44. It costs 120 mp to perform. Sharon's Origin: ArrodeLightning Arrow: An attacking ability learned at level 1. It costs 80 mp to perform.Thunder Serpent: An attacking ability learned at level 35. It costs 100 mp to perform.Thunderbolt Bow: An attacking ability learned at level 44. It costs 120 mp to perform. Ayne is a unique character who instead of having an origin to summon, he performs his own abilities.  Ayne's AbilitiesGaia Spirit: An enhancement ability learned at level 1. It costs 40 mp to perform.Firebeast Spirit: An enhancement ability learned at level 40. It costs 46 mp to perform.Wind God Spirit: An enhancement ability learned at level 50. It costs 54 mp to perform.Thunder Spirit: An enhancement ability learned at level 52. It costs 62 mp to perform.Holy Tree Spirit: An enhancement ability learned at level 54. It costs 78 mp to perform.Victory Spirit: An enhancement ability learned at level 57. It costs 85 mp to perform. Battle SystemSimilar to Legend of Legaia, Legaia 2 allows each character to enter a string of directional based combinations. The combination of directional entries are used to perform specific attacks called Arts. As well as regular arts, there are also Super, Hyper, Variable and Mystic arts which are advanced versions of arts that are stronger than standard arts. As characters level up, the amount of attacks that they can input increases. Each art requires ap to be performed. To build ap, you must use normal arts. By inputting the correct combination, you can learn both normal and super arts. Hyper arts are learned by specific character scrolls, story events or by leveling other hyper arts. Variable arts are arts that are performed jointly with 2 characters. Variable arts are learned by simply putting in the correct inputs. Mystic arts are the most powerful arts, however you must meet certain requirements to use them. Your character must have 100 ap, less than half your hit points, and at least 100 mp.   Lang:    Normal Arts   Blue Moon Buster: 16 ap (RDR)Mountain Crusher: 16 ap (URU)Hawk Stroke: 16 ap (LDD)Blade Dance: 16 ap (DLL)Shadow Split: 20 ap (LRUL)Chaos Strike: 20 ap (UDRU)Demon Thrust: 20 ap (DDDU)Thunderflash: 20 ap (DUUU)Battle Flash: 24 ap (UDDLR)Rabid Attack: 24 ap (DUDLR)Wind Blade: 24 ap (LRDUL)   Super Arts  Sandstorm: 16 ap (RLR)Thunder Moon: 24 ap (UURR)Red Whirlwind: 24 ap (DUUL)True Moon Slash: 24 ap (UDDU)Moonflower: 32 ap (RLDLR)   Hyper Arts  Raging Fang: 30 ap (UDU) This ability upgrades to Roaring Fang.Roaring Fang: 40 ap (URLU) This ability upgrades to Sky Fang.Sky Fang: 50 ap (UDRLU)Diving Bolt: 40 ap (UDDR) This ability upgrades to Thunder Sky.Thunder Sky: 50 ap (DLDRU)Sleeping Dragon: 60 ap (LURLDU)   Variable Arts  Solid Strike: 80 ap (LRLDUD)Airborne Fury: 80 ap (DLURDL)   Mystic Art  Flaming Sword: 100 ap (URDLURD) Maya's arts are different from the rest of the party. Instead of up, down, left and right, she has elements: Earth, Wind, Fire and Water. Her arts cannot be chained like other character's arts either.  Maya:    Normal Arts  Ice Flow: 16 ap (URR)Inferno: 16 ap (LDL)Thunderhead: 16 ap (RUL)Dark Disaster: 16 ap (DDU)Blind Fury: 16 ap (LUR)Windblade: 16 ap (RLU)Bedrock Buster: 16 ap (DRD)Magma Mayhem: 20 ap (LLLD)Aqua Spear: 20 ap (RDUR)Nova Heat: 20 ap (LUUL)Ice Pyre: 20 ap (RRDD)    Super Arts  Toxic Cloud: 16 ap (RUD)Ballistic Light: 24 ap (DDLL)Blizzard Blast: 24 ap (UURU)Spirit Storm: 24 ap (URUR)Skysplitter: 24 ap (LLRL)Gravity Crush: 24 ap (DUDD)Meteor Storm: 32 (DLLLR)    Hyper Arts  Big Bang: 40 ap (DURL)Raging Sky: 40 ap (UUUU)Absolute Zero: 40 ap (RRRR)Dust to Dust: 40 ap (DDDD)Dancing Flames: 50 ap (LLLLL)Nether Gate: 60 ap (DULRDD)     Variable Arts  Pyro Fury: 80 ap (RLLUDR)Shockwave: 80 ap (LRDULR)    Mystic Art  Forbidden Rite: 100 ap (DURDULD) Kazan:    Normal Arts  Moon Splitter: 16 ap (DLR) Critical Thrust: 16 ap (URR)Lightning Kick: 16 ap (LUD)Jawbuster: 20 ap (RRUU)Double Kick: 20 ap (DUUU)Double Fists: 20 ap (DDDU)Goblin Dance: 20 ap (RRLR)Fever Dance: 24 ap (DLLDR)    Super Arts  Deadly Hands: 24 ap (UDRU)Iron Fist: 24 ap (URLL)Aerial Attack: 24 ap (LRDU)Cannon Blast: 32 ap (UULDR)    Hyper Arts  Fists of Rage: 30 ap (LLL) This ability upgrades to Fists of Glory.Fists of Glory: 40 ap (LLRL)Earthshatter: 40 ap (RLUU) This ability upgrades to Skyshaker.Skyshaker: 50 ap (ULRUD) Hyper Blast: 50 ap (ULRDD) This ability upgrades to Ultimate Fury.Ultimate Fury: 60 ap (ULRLDD)    Variable Arts  Demon Crusher: 80 ap (ULDRUL)Fatal Impact: 80 ap (RRLLDU)    Mystic Art  Fists of Stone: 100 ap (DRLURLD) Sharon:    Normal Arts  Slay Cutlass: 16 ap (RLU)Spike Anchor: 16 ap (UDR)Riot Flag: 20 ap (ULLU)Bloody Fang: 20 ap (LUDL)Rumble Spike: 20 ap (LUUU)Rising Stars: 20 ap (RDRR)Range Wave: 20 ap (DRDL)Rave Storm: 24 ap (DURLR)Blood Spark: 24 ap (DRLRU)    Super Arts  Fear Galgarin: 16 ap (LLD) Crescent Heel: 24 ap (UURR)Spiral Blade: 24 ap (LLRU)Peach Surprise: 24 ap (DUDL)Surf Divide: 24 ap (RLDD)    Hyper Arts  Fearful Arc: 30 ap (LRR) This ability upgrades to Merciful Arc.Merciful Arc: 40 ap (RULD)Lord of Eden: 40 ap (LRLR) This ability upgrades to Skylord.Skylord: 50 ap (LRDLR)Windmill Rose: 50 ap (DUUUU) This ability upgrades to Detonating Rose.Detonating Rose: 60 ap (DDDUUU)    Variable Arts  Splash Rave: 80 ap (DDLRUU)Phantom Burst: 80 ap (LDURDR)     Mystic Art  Apokolips: 100 ap (UDLRUDU)  Ayne does not have a mystic art. Ayne:    Normal Arts  Disaster Master: 16 ap (ULR) Earthrazor: 16 ap (RUD)Whirlwind Attack: 16 ap (LDU)Shockforce: 16 ap (DRL)Tidal Wave: 20 ap (URDL)Full Impact: 20 ap (RLUD)    Super Arts  Solid Blow: 16 ap (DDR)Gale Force: 16 ap (LLU)    Hyper Arts  Firestorm: 30 ap (LDD) This ability upgrades to Raging Warrior.Raging Warrior: 40 ap (RULU)Power Blade: 30 ap (DRD) This ability upgrades to Axe Crush.Axe Crush: 50 ap (ULDLR)    Variable Arts  Armageddon Star: 80 ap (UDLLRR)Soaring Axe: 80 ap (LLRRDU) CampIn Legaia 2, camping sets that allows you to set up camp and in camp you gain the ability to cook. There are many recipes that give you various stat boosts.  Rice Ball: A rice ball with a yummy filling. Great for lunch! Ingredients: RiceCooked by LangEffect: HPR and ATK up 5% Cocoa Cake: A soft sponge cake filled with cocoa. Ingredients: Dessert Set, Cocoa PowderCooked by MayaEffect: HPR, MPR, INT, MEN, and CHA up 5% Lynx Special Stew: A Lynx Inn specialty! Attracts guests like a magnet. Ingredients: Beef, Vegetables, CreamCooked by LangEffect: HPR and ATK up 10%, DEF up 5% Tomato Risotto: A warm risotto brimming with diced tomato and chicken. Ingredients: Poultry, VegetablesCooked by LangEffect: HPR up 10%, ATK, DEF, INT, MEN, AGL and CHA up 5% Cabbage Roll: Soft meat wrapped with cabbage and used in consomme. Ingredients: Pork, Vegetables, HerbsCooked by LangEffect: HPR, MPR and AGL up 5%, ATK and DEF up 10% Caeser Salad: Fresh lettuce, special dressing and grated cheese. Ingredients: Vegetables, Cheese, Cooking Oil Cooked by Lang Effect: HPR, ATK, DEF, INT, MEN, AGL and CHA up 5%, MPR up 10% Bacon and Eggs: A marvelous combo of crispy bacon and soft eggs. Ingredients: Pork, EggsCooked by LangEffect: All stats up 5% Beef Sandwich: A sandwich using the finest, juiciest beef. Ingredients: Beef, BreadCooked by MayaEffect: HPR and ATK up 10%, MPR, DEF, INT, MEN, AGL and CHA up 5% Spicy-Hot Salad: Kazan's special salad. Packs a spicy punch, Ingredients: Vegetables, Red PepperCooked by KazanEffect: HPR, ATK, INT, MEN and AGL up 5%, MPR up 10%, DEF down 5% Spanish Omelet: A hearty omelet full of potato and other ingredients. Ingredients: Vegetables, Eggs, HerbsCooked by SharonEffect: HPR up 10%, MPR, ATK, DEF, INT, MEN and AGL up 5% Custard: Ayne handmade pudding. Simple but nostalgic. Ingredients: Egg, Cookie SetCooked by AyneEffect: MPR, ATK, DEF, INT, MEN, AGL and CHA up 5% Atomic Heat: Legendary dish using premium seared monster meat. Ingredients: Monster Meat, Spices, Herbs, Red WineCooked by LangEffect: All stats up 20% Balsamic Veggies: Summer veggies and oil with a balsamic tang. Ingredients: Vegetables, Cooking Oil, SpicesCooked by LangEffect: HPR up 10%, ATK and DEF up 20%, MPR, INT, MEN and AGL up 5% Lobster in Wine: Hearty lobster, simmered for hours in red wine. Ingredients: Lobster, Spices, Red Wine, MisoCooked by LangEffect: HPR up 10%, ATK and DEF up 20%, MRP, AGL and CHA up 5% Heavenly Beef: Looks like normal beef, but it'll take ya to heaven! Ingredients: Premium Beef, Miso, Red WineCooked by LangEffect: HPR, AGL and CHA up 10%, ATK and DEF up 20% Kazan Curry: Spiciness that'll hit you from your head to your toes! Ingredients: Beef, Vegetables, Red Pepper, Curry SetCooked by KazanEffect: HPR up 10%, MPR down 10%, ATK and AGL up 20%, DEF down 5% Pancakes: Lightly browned cakes drizzled with syrup and butter. Ingredients: Dessert Set, EggCooked by LangEffect: HPR, MPR, AGL and CHA up 5%, INT and MEN up 10% Chocolate Pie: Soft, fresh, and positively packed with chocolate. Ingredients: Egg, Chocolate, Cocoa PowderCooked by MayaEffect: MPR, INT, MEN and AGL up 10%, CHA up 5% Strawberry Sweet: A strawberry wrapped in sweet bean paste and pastry. Ingredients: Fruit, Cookie SetCooked by KazanEffect: MPR and AGL up 10%, INT and MEN up 5% Applie Pie: Fresh apples baked in pastry with a hint of cinnamon. Ingredients: Fruit, White Wine, Pie DoughCooked by SharonEffect: HPR up 5%, MPR and DEF up 10% Brownies: Chocolate based and packed with walnuts and almonds. Cookie Set, Chocolate, Cocoa PowderCooked by AyneEffect: HPR and MPR up 10%, INT, MEN, AGL and CHA up 5% Princess Cake: Surprisingly solid for its size, it packs a caloric punch! Ingredients: Cream, Cooking Oil, Dessert Set, Cookie Set, PorkCooked by LangEffect: HPR, MPR, INT, MEN, AGL and CHA down 20%, ATK and DEF up 20% Fried Vegetables: Perfect for times when you're light on ingredients. Ingredients: Vegetables, Pork, Soup Broth SetCooked by KazanEffect: HPR up 10%, MPR, ATK, DEF and AGL up 5% Pasta Carbonara: A creamy pasta accented with bacon and black pepper. Ingredients: Pork, Milk, Pasta, Cooking OilCooked by MayaEffect: HPR, MPR and DEF up 10%, MEN, AGL and CHA up 5% Shrimp Au Gratin: Lightly browned cheese full of sauce and shrimp. Ingredients: Shrimp, Milk, PastaCooked by SharonEffect: HPR and AGL up 10%, MPR, ATK, INT and MEN up 5% Sukiyaki: Meat and veggies simmered in a huge pot. Flavorful! Ingredients: Beef, Vegetables, Tofu, Soup Broth SetCooked by LangEffect: HPR up 20%, ATK up 10%, MPR, DEF and AGL up 5% Cheese Fondue: An extravagant dish of melted cheese and wine with bread. Ingredients: Cheese, Bread, White WineCooked by MayaEffect: MPR, INT and MEN up 10%, HPR, DEF, AGL and CHA up 5% Spicy Crab Bisque: Crab-filled soup that'll set your body on fire. Ingredients: Crab, Rice, Red Pepper, TofuCooked by KazanEffect: HPR and AGL up 10%, MPR down 20%, ATK up 20%, DEF down 5% Udon Noodles: Tempura, eggs and udon noodles flavored with red pepper. Ingredients: Pork, Vegetables, Southern Noodles, Soup Broth SetCooked by SharonEffect: HPR up 20%, ATK up 10%, MPR, DEF, INT, MEN, AGL and CHA up 5% Pot-Au-Fou: A dish that warms body and heart with delectable meat. Ingredients: Beef, Vegetables, Soup Broth SetCooked by AyneEffect: HPR, MPR and DEF up 10%, ATK and AGL up 5% Tempura Noodles: A dish based on on 60 years of experience of Chef Suda. Ingredients: Shrimp, Southern Noodles, Soup Broth SetCooked by LangEffect: HPR, ATK and DEF up 10%, MPR up 5% Pirate Pasta: A pasta using whatever's on hand. Popular among pirates. Ingredients: Poultry, Shrimp, Pasta, Red PepperCooked by SharonEffect: AGL up 20%, HPR and ATK up 10%, MPR and DEF up 5% Yakitori Skewers: Basted skewered chicken cooked on a charcoal grill. Ingredients: Poultry, SpicesCooked by LangEffect: HPR, ATK and AGL up 5% Hamburger Steak: Ground beef patties cooked in an oven. Crisp yet juicy! Ingredients: Beef, Pork, Spices, Red WineCooked by LangEffect: HPR, ATK and DEF up 20%, MPR up 5% Bolognese: Pasta mixed with tomatoes and clams. Zesty and tangy! Ingredients: Vegetables, Shellfish, White WineCooked by MayaEffect: HPR, MPR, INT, MEN and AGL up 10% Clam Chowder: Clams simmered in milk. Packs a full-bodied flavor. Ingredients: Pork, Shellfish, MilkCooked by SharonEffect: HPR, INT and MEN up 10%, AGL up 20%, MPR up 5% Pork Cutlet Bowl: Breaded pork cooked with eggs and served on rice. Ingredients: Pork, Rice, Soup Broth SetCooked by LangEffect: HPR, ATK and DEF up 20% Almond Float: A fruity desert with almond flavor. Ingredients: Milk, Cream, FruitCooked by MayaEffect: MPR and INT up 10%, MEN up 20% Sashimi Deluxe: A dish consisting only of fresh fish and the chef's skill. Ingredients: Fish, Shellfish, SpicesCooked by KazanEffect: HPR up 10%, DEF up 20% Uni Bowl: A bowl of rice extravagantly topped with sea urchin. Ingredients: Shellfish, Rice, Soup Broth SetCooked by SharonEffect: HPR, MPR, ATK, DEF, INT and MEN up 10% Baked Crab Shell: A dish of succulent crab meat cooked in the shell. Ingredients: Crab, Tofu, Soup Broth SetCooked by AyneEffect: HPR and DEF up 10% Jambalaya: Rice cooked with pork sausage. Mouth-watering and spicy. Pork, Vegetables, Rice, SpicesCooked by LangEffect: HPR up 20%, ATK, DEF, INT and MEN up 10% BBQ Veggies: Charcoal-grilled meat and veggie skewers eaten by hand. Ingredients: Animal Meat, Vegetables, Cooking Oil, SpicesCooked by LangEffect: HPR and ATK up 20% Curry Spaghetti: Seafood pasta and curry powder. Mildly spicy and flavorful. Ingredients: Pork, Pasta, Curry SetCooked by MayaEffect: HPR and DEF up 10%, MPR, ATK, INT and MEN up 5% Wild Wild Beef: Grilled beef that'll make you give thanks before eating. Ingredients: Beef, Cooking Oil, Spices, HerbsCooked by AyneEffect: HPR, ATK and DEF up 10%, MPR up 5% Tang o' the Sea: Soup based on two types of clam. Resembles miso soup. Ingredients: Shellfish, Shrimp, Miso, TofuCooked by AyneEffect: HPR, INT and MEN up 10%, MPR up 5% Club Sandwich: A sandwich stacked with ham, tomato, cheese and more. Ingredients: Pork, Poultry, Vegetables, BreadCooked by LangEffect: HPR, ATK, DEF, INT and MEN up 10% Fried Turkey: Turkey thighs deep fried with their skin to seal in flavor. Ingredients: Poultry, Cooking Oil, SpicesCooked by LangEffect: HPR, ATK and AGL up 10% Fruity Pie: A sweet pie brimming with the freshest fruits. Ingredients: Fruit, Cookie Set, Pie DoughCooked by MayaEffect: MPR up 10%, INT and MEN up 20% Seafood Pizza: Pizza piled with clams, bacon and shrimp. Filling! Ingredients: Pork, Fish, Shellfish, Pie DoughCooked by KazanEffect: HPR, DEF, INT, MEN and AGL up 10%, MPR up 5% Wild Gratin: A wild yet hearty gratin, but can cause upset stomachs... Ingredients: Animal Meat, Milk, Pasta, HerbsCooked by SharonEffect: HPR and AGL up 10%, ATK and DEF up 20%, MPR down 20% Sirloin Steak: Steak from the choicest beef. A pleasure to be savored. Ingredients: Premium Beef, Spices, Red WineCooked by LangEffect: HPR and ATK up 20% Oden Stew: A seafood stew that's a specialty of Edo in the south. Ingredients: Fish, Shellfish, Soup Broth SetCooked by KazanEffect: HPR up 20%, MPR and ATK up 10%, DEF, INT, MEN, AGL and CHA up 5% Beef Stroganoff: Simmered premium beef. Pungent and delicious! Ingredients: Premium Beef, Vegetables, Spices, Soup Broth SetCooked by MayaEffect: HPR, MPR and DEF up 20% Bouillabaisse: A hotpot using the choicest lobster and crab. A luxury! Ingredients: Fish, Shellfish, Shrimp, Crab, HerbsCooked by SharonEffect: HPR, MPR, INT, MEN and AGL up 20% Sunny Melody: A premium cheese and egg soup with mystery noodles. Ingredients: Egg, Cheese, Southern Noodles, Miso, Soup Broth SetCooked by AyneEffect: HPR and ATK up 10%, MPR up 5% Muddy Soup: A banned soup that causes vomiting and other fun symptoms. Ingredients: Slime GelureCooked by LangEffect: HPR down 20%, MEN up 20% Rotten Steak: Rank and fetid, it'll make you a hero if you try it. Ingredients: Suspicious meatCooked by MayaEffect: HPR Down 20%, ATK up 20% Eyeball Stew: A grotesque dish, but makes you super-intelligent. Ingredients: Huge EyeballCooked by KazanEffect: HPR down 20%, INT up 20% Sick Shroom Soup: Using mystery mushrooms, death is mercifully quick. Ingredients: Creepy MushroomCooked by SharonEffect: HPR down 20%, DEF up 20%  Mini-games Sidejumping: A mini-game in which Lang jumps left and right by using the left and right analog sticks. The goal is to make as many jumps back and forth as possible within the time limits.Gardening: In Yuno, you gain the ability to plant different seeds which allow you to grow various things.Tanza Planting: In this mini-game you compete by planting rice patties.Tanza Pop-quiz: A simple quiz given by a man in Tanza.Knife Throwing: A contest in which you throw knives to earn points.Phorcoon Casino: The casino consists of slot machines and roulette in which you can earn coins and items.Battle Arena: An arena where you partake in a tournament against various enemies. SoundtrackFight, then Riot!Wasteland of Far Away Places Wind, Tree and WaterFragments of SoulThe Repressed SoulGod of the Evil OnesAdvancing to Far Away PlacesInaccessible RoadEri and MariAvoided DestinyDecadence and CorruptionKnight's KingdomTrust Tomorrow to the WindTraining CaveAlready RentedPaying the Worthless WarSetting of GloryForgotten InheritanceYour VoiceStatus ChangeHoly Banderasu Requiem SongEvil DesiresGoing to my HometownBlack SunLost ForestEveryday TranquilityMayaBoss' Pipe OrganKaravaiaTanzaPirate's PrideRoars of the Sea and SkyBarracksDream of ParadiseElegy of WarSoldier's OrdealShriek of the EarthHeaven and Earth's ValleyBeast of DarknessEnd of the WorldGod's FistUnique Person's BanquetSeeing the End of the EarthEndingThe Ones Who Obtain TomorrowMark of the Vanquished  </description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16716">Legend of Legaia</game><game id="11237">Final Fantasy X</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2303977-box_legaia2.png</image></root>