<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>15990</id><name>Diddy Kong Racing</name><description>OverviewDiddy Kong Racing is a racing game for the Nintendo 64, developed by Rareware and released in 1997. Diddy Kong racing made its way into the Guinness Book of World Records due to a staggering 800,000 copies being ordered in the two weeks prior to Christmas 1997. Diddy Kong racing allows the player to choose between three vehicles; car, hovercraft and plane and includes Adventure, Battle and Racing modes in a similar style to Mario Kart 64.Character select menuIn Adventure mode, Diddy Kong receives a distress call from one of his friends, Timber the Tiger. Timber's parents have gone on vacation and left him in charge of the usually peaceful island they live on. However, unfortunately for Timber and his friends, an evil pig wizard from outer space called Wizpig has dropped in to ruin Timber's fun. Wizpig wants to take over Timber's Island and claim it as his own by conquering all of the island's race tracks, as he has done on his home planet Future Fun Land. Hearing the news, Diddy Kong recruits his friends Banjo the bear and Conker the squirrel (this game is actually the first appearance of Conker and Banjo, though Kazooie had yet to be created) and heads over to Timber's Island whilst Timber enlists the remaining inhabitants of the island. They then join forces to go up against the evil Wizpig. Wizpig, however, has been doing some recruitment of his own, and has turned the islands four guardians Tricky the Triceratops, Bubbler the Octopus, Bluey the Walrus and Smokey the Dragon into his henchmen. He also turned veteran racer Drumstick into a frog that looks just a little bit like a rooster. Diddy and his friends must race against Wizpig and his friends and complete all of their challenges to prevent Wizpig taking over the island for good. Drumstick is eventually turned back into a proper rooster.The evil WizpigThe gameplay takes place in various worlds on the island, each containing several race tracks, a battle stage and race against one of Wizpig's henchmen. A golden balloon is awarded after each race won and the player must collect a certain number of golden balloons to progress to the next stage. Some golden balloons can be found in the hub world that connects the game's areas. Diddy and his friends must eventually defeat Wizpig in a race, causing him to flee back to his home planet Future Fun Land. Uncertain that Wizpig won't return to try and take over the island again the characters follow him to his home planet for the final showdown where victory blasts Wizpig off on a rocket into distant space never to be seen again.Silver Coin ChallengesIn order to extend the length of the game (and add more difficulty) after beating races the first time, the player must go and complete Silver Coin Challenges. These take place on the same tracks, but the player must collect eight Silver Coins hidden throughout the tracks, and win. Of course these coins are not simply sitting in the middle of the track, and many involve going well out of the way to collect.Mirror ModeCompleting Adventure Mode once unlocks a new mode where all of the courses in the game are mirrored, and the player must complete them all again. This includes the aforementioned Silver Coin Challenges.CharactersPlayableKrunch the big male KremlingDiddy Kong the "Chimpanzee"Drumstick the Big Rooster (unlockable)Bumper the BadgerBanjo the BearConker the SquirrelTiptup the TurtleT.T. the Stopwatch (unlockable)Pipsy the MouseTimber the TigerNon PlayableTaj the GenieWizpig the giant alien PigTricky the TriceratopsBluey the WalrusBubbler the OctopusSmokey the DragonTaj the elephant genie who helps you out throughout the game.Game AreasThe open world was split into five game areas, each with four tracks, a boss event, and a multplayer combat minigame.Dino DomainAncient LakeFossil CannonJungle FallsHot Top VolcanoBoss: Tricky the TriceratopsSnowflake MountainEverfrost PeakWalrus CoveSnowball ValleyFrosty VillageBoss: Bluey the WalrusSherbert IslandWhale BayCrescent IslandPirate LagoonTreasure CavesBoss: Bubbler the OctopusDragon ForestWindmill PlainsGreenwood VillageBoulder CanyonHaunted WoodsBoss: Smokey the DragonFuture Fun Land (Accessible after beating Wizpig the first time)Spacedust AlleyDarkmoon CavernsSpaceport AlphaStar CityBoss: Wizpig</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6539">Mario Kart DS</game><game id="19071">Super Mario Kart</game><game id="18757">Mario Kart: Double Dash!!</game><game id="10084">Mario Kart 64</game><game id="16769">Mario Kart: Super Circuit</game><game id="15000">Donkey Kong 64</game><game id="6196">Crash Team Racing</game><game id="20644">Donkey Kong: Barrel Blast</game><game id="20645">Mario Kart Wii</game><game id="15977">Walt Disney World Quest Magical Racing Tour</game><game id="4622">Pocketbike Racer</game><game id="8942">Super Mario 64 DS</game><game id="14277">Banjo-Pilot</game><game id="18062">Snowboard Kids</game><game id="11105">Wave Race</game><game id="310">NASCAR Rumble</game><game id="11174">LEGO Racers</game><game id="13178">Speed Punks</game><game id="11718">Skunny Kart</game><game id="12544">Wacky Wheels</game><game id="6368">Mickey's Speedway USA</game><game id="25772">Cro Mag Rally</game><game id="26848">ModNation Racers</game><game id="22190">Street Racer</game><game id="23754">Action Girlz Racing</game><game id="16588">Freaky Flyers</game><game id="21821">Sonic Drift 2</game><game id="32225">Crash Bandicoot Nitro Kart 2</game><game id="4515">RC Revenge</game><game id="31744">Raving Rabbids Travel In Time</game><game id="21285">Rollcage Stage II</game><game id="1145">Pokémon Dash</game><game id="31747">Mario Kart 7</game><game id="37413">SD F-1 Grand Prix</game><game id="37441">LittleBigPlanet Karting</game><game id="38173">Sonic &amp; All-Stars Racing Transformed</game><game id="40574">Monster High Skultimate Roller Maze</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3509/647307-diddykongracing_na.jpg</image></root>