<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16018</id><name>MechWarrior 2: Ghost Bear's Legacy</name><description> OverviewDeveloped and published by       Activision, Ghost Bear's Legacy is the first of two expansion packs for      MechWarrior 2. The title is a reference to Clan Ghost Bear, an important faction in the     BattleTech fiction. This expansion pack puts the player in control of a warrior from the titular Clan, with an arsenal of fourteen new    BattleMechs; it also adds a new campaign with 17 playable missions to complete.  PlotMad Cat BattleMech The player takes on the role of a new Clan Ghost Bear MechWarrior working out of a facility in the   Inner Sphere after the end of the Refusal War. This large-scale conflict has split Clan Wolf in half and left much of Clan space in disarray; alliances between the Clans are fragile. When small-scale mercenary attacks on the player's base escalate into a much more agressive raid by the Draconis Combine, the remains of the founders of Clan Ghost Bear are stolen. Clan leadership quickly responds with deadly force, only to discover than the Draconis Combine 'Mechs            used in the raid had previously been captured by the Smoke Jaguars.  The already weak Clans must now treat this situation with even more caution, as any unnecessary infighting between faction will make Clan space especially vulnerable to attacks by Inner Sphere powers. The investigation uncovers two rogue commanders of the supposedly friendly remnant of Clan Wolf. As such, the true Wolf leadership allows the Ghost Bear units to withdraw from their territory in order to better prepare for a final showdown with the thieves.  Campaign StructureThere are twelve core missions in the campaign to recover the Clan founders' genetic material. If a player is able to complete all 12 missions in succession without dying a single time or failing to complete a mission, this feat is rewarded with an additional five bonus missions that tell the story of the warrior's trial to gain higher status within Clan Ghost Bear.New Clan 'MechsIn addition to the fifteen 'Mechs featured in the previous game, Ghost Bear's Legacy includes nine new playable Clan 'Mechs during its campaign. This list includes two new Light 'Mechs, one Medium, two Heavy, and four Assault. Several new Inner Sphere 'Mechs such as the Atlas make appearances as well, though only as enemies. 'MechClassificationWeightTop SpeedJump JetsDefault WeaponsIncubus Light 'Mech30 tons151 kphNone1 Machine Gun1 ER Small Laser2 ER Medium Lasers1 ER Large LaserHorned Owl Light 'Mech35 tons97 kphSix2 ER Medium Lasers1 ER Large LaserPhantom Medium 'Mech40 tons151.2 kphNone1 ER Small Laser1 ER Medium Laser1 LRM-5Linebacker Heavy 'Mech65 tons97.2 kphNone2 ER PPCs1 Streak SRM-41 LRM-5Grizzly Heavy 'Mech70 tons65 kphFour1 Small Pulse Laser1 Medium Pulse Laser1 Large Pulse Laser1 Gauss Rifle1 LRM-10Naga Assault 'Mech80 tons86 kphNone3 ER Medium Lasers2 LRM-20sExecutioner Assault 'Mech95 tons64.8 kphFour1 Machine Gun2 ER Large Lasers1 Gauss RifleKodiak Assault 'Mech100 tons64.8 kphNone6 ER Medium Lasers1 ER Large Laser2 Streak SRM-6s1 Ultra Autocannon 20Stone Rhino Assault 'Mech100 tons54 kphThree2 Medium Pulse Lasers1 Large Pulse Laser2 Gauss RiflesPC System RequirementsGhost Bear's Legacy is not a stand-alone expansion like the later MechWarrior 2: Mercenaries, and as such, the game requires a valid installation of the base game.  HardwareRequirement Processor: 90 MHz Pentium Memory: 12 MB RAM Optical Drive: 4X CD-ROM DriveIt is also possible to run the game through DOS.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="34304">Iron Brigade</game><game id="19719">Chromehounds</game><game id="17675">Armored Core 4</game><game id="16656">Armored Core</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/30/1122688-mechwarrior_2_gbl_cover.jpg</image></root>