<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1602</id><name>Ace Combat 04: Shattered Skies</name><description>Release HistoryAce Combat 04: Shattered Skies is a flight combat game developed by Namco for the PlayStation 2. It was released in Japan and North America on October 23rd, 2001 and in Europe on February 8, 2002, where it was distributed under the name Ace Combat: Distant Thunder. It was the first Ace Combat game released on the PlayStation 2 and was met with critical and commercial success. Ace Combat 04: Shattered Skies was the first in three PlayStation 2 Ace Combat branded titles released for the console, and was followed by Ace Combat 5: The Unsung War, and Ace Combat Zero: The Belkan War.StoryStonehenge Turret NetworkIn 1999 a massive asteroid known as Ulysses 1994 XF-04 struck the continent of Usea. The impact killed half a million people and caused widespread destruction. In the aftermath, the country of Erusea saw an opportunity to catch its neighbors off guard and occupy much of the continent. Helping the Eruseans in their conquest was Stonehenge, a giant railgun system the Eruseans had developed to shoot down incoming asteroids. The Eruseans quickly realize that Stonehenge could be used in warfare to gain air superiority.The game opens at the high point of the war for the Eruseans. The player takes on the ambiguous role of Mobius 1, a skilled fighter pilot of the Independent States Allied Forces, or ISAF. The ISAF finds itself pushed back to the extreme East Coast of Usea with most of its military might located on a small island known as Northpoint. Mobius 1 stops a bombing run against Northpoint, singlehandedly saving the remaining ISAF military. A counterattack is then launched that ultimately results on the liberation of the Usean continent. Mobius 1 is in large part responsible for many of the military victories, and as such is seen as a hero throughout the game.A separate, parallel side story is told through narrated slide-shows between missions. These cutscenes tell the tale of a young boy who lived through the war, occupation, and subsequent liberation. At the beginning of the war, this young boy sees his parents killed when a jet fighter crashes into his house. The jet fighter was shot down by an Erusean pilot named Yellow 13. The boy goes to live with his uncle, a drunk who lives above a tavern. Following their city's occupation, Yellow 13 and his squad become stationed there and frequent the tavern that the boy lives above. The boy ultimately befriends Yellow 13 viewing him as somewhat of a father figure. At the end of the game, Mobius 1 shoots down Yellow 13 and the story in the cutscenes are revealed to be a letter from the boy to Mobius 1.GameplayAce Combat 4 is an arcade style flight combat game. The game has 18 singleplayer missions and two multiplayer modes.SingleplayerThere are 18 singleplayer missions. Missions usually involve reaching a certain amount of points in a certain amount of time through destroying aircraft, ground vehicles, and facilities. Most missions have story specific unique targets which have to be destroyed in order for the level to be completed. Money is earned by completing missions, the more points one accrues during a mission, the more money they earn. There are 21 airplanes that a player can purchase; each plane has additional weapons and 2 paint schemes that can be bought. The weapons are available for purchase once the aircraft has been unlocked whereas the paint schemes need to be unlocked by getting an S rank on every mission, or by completing the game on different difficulties, and shooting down the aircraft's named ace pilot, who usually appear during missions depending on a player's performance.MultiplayerThere are two multiplayer modes in Ace Combat 4. The first mode is a 1 on 1 dogfight while the other mode has two players competing to score the most points. Multiplayer is limited to split-screen as there is no online multiplayer available.MissionsMissionsOperationsDateLocation(s)Mission 01: Sitting DucksUmbrellaSeptember 19, 2004Newfield IslandMission 02: Imminent ThreatHarvestOctober 5, 2004Rigley Air BaseMission 03: The Northern EyeWhite OutOctober 10, 2004Mount SheznaMission 04: BlockadeHunting HawkNovember 7, 2004NW of Comberth HarborMission 05: LifelineEarly BirdNovember 19, 2004Petrochemical ComplexMission 06: Invincible FleetRought SeaNovember 23, 2004Comberth HarborMission 07: Deep StrikeBlackoutDecember 16, 2004Faith ParkMission 08: Shattered SkiesCountdownDecember 31, 2004Comona IslandsMission 09: Operation Bunker ShotBunker ShotJanuary 24, 2005Halle/Crowne/Caranda BeachMission 10: Tango LineWoodpeckerFebruary 28, 2005Tango LineMission 11: EscortNoah's ArkMarch 14, 2005North of ChcoinburaMission 12: Stonehenge OffensiveStone CrusherApril 02, 2005StonehengeMission 13: Safe ReturnBlindman's BluffMay 07, 2005Gnome RavineMission 14: Breaking ArrowsAuroraJune 18, 2005Ice CreekMission 15: EmancipationFireflyJuly 10, 2005San SalvacionMission 16: Whiskey CorridorSandstormAugust 15, 2005Whiskey CorridorMission 17: Siege of FarbantiAutumn ThunderSeptember 19, 2005FarbantiMission 18: MegalithJudgement DaySeptember 26, 2005MegalithAircraftsF-4E Phantom IIF-5E Tiger IIF-16C Fighting FalconA-10A Thunderbolt IIMirage 2000F-14A TomcatTornado IDSF/A-18C HornetF-15C EagleMIG-29A FulcrumF-117A NighthawkEF-2000 TyphoonRafale MF-15E Strike EagleF-2A Viper ZeroSU-35 Super FlankerF-22A RaptorSU-37 TerminatorF-15S/MTDS-37AX-02 WyvernAcesF-5E WangCallsign: WangAircraft: F-5E Tiger IIMission: 01A-10 CiffreoCallsign: CiffreoAircraft: A-10A Thunderbolt IIMission: 02F-16 TempelCallsign: TempelAircraft: F-16C Fighting FalconMission: 03MIR-2000 RigauxCallsign: RigauxAircraft: Mirage 2000Mission: 04MIG-29 MrkosCallsign: MrkosAircraft: MiG-29A FulcrumMission: 05F-14 LevyCallsign: LevyAircraft: F-14A TomcatMission: 06TND-IDS De VicoCallsign: De VicoAircraft: Tornado IDSMission: 07F/A-18 VaisalaCallsign: VaisalaAircraft: F/A-18C HornetMission: 08F-15C TuttleCallsign: TuttleAircraft: F-15C EagleMission: 09R-M01 FayeCallsign: FayeAircraft: Rafale MMission: 10SU-35 NeujminCallsign: NeujminAircraft: Su-35 Super FlankerMission: 11F-2 UrataCallsign: UrataAircraft: F-2A Viper ZeroMission: 12F-15E GunnCallsign: GunnAircraft: F-15E Strike EagleMission: 13F-22 AbellCallsign: AbellAircraft: F-22A RaptorMission: 14EF-2000 OlmsteadCallsign: OlmsteadAircraft: EF-2000 TyphoonMission: 15F-117 KweeCallsign: KweeAircraft: F-117A NighthawkMission: 16F-15 Active HalleyCallsign: HalleyAircraft: F-15S/MTD "Active" EagleMission: 17S-37 SmirnovaCallsign: SmirnovaAircraft: S-37AMission: 18</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="24">Flight Simulator</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18750">Top Gun: Combat Zones</game><game id="11494">AirForce Delta Storm</game><game id="20458">Warhawk</game><game id="4589">Independence Day</game><game id="20671">Tom Clancy's H.A.W.X</game><game id="24983">Stormbirds</game><game id="18377">Heroes of the Pacific</game><game id="12289">Heatseeker</game><game id="23698">Aero Elite: Combat Academy</game><game id="7790">AirForce Delta</game><game id="26515">AirForce Delta Strike</game><game id="4075">Wing Arms</game><game id="31188">Tom Clancy's H.A.W.X. 2</game><game id="34846">Lethal Skies II</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2092577-box_ac4.png</image></root>