<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16073</id><name>Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six 3: Raven Shield</name><description>Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six 3: Raven Shield is a pc game developed by Red Storm and published by Ubisoft, for release on March 16, 2003. The game used a modified version of the Unreal 2 engine, and stands to die-hard fans of the series as one of the last true tactical shooters to be released -- before the supposed mainstream popularity sunk into the franchises pores.The game was later re-released on consoles with slightly different game mechanics, storyline, and features. The subtitle was dropped from the name, and was published for the Xbox, Playstation 2, and Gamecube. This version of the game is arguably what catapulted the Rainbow Six franchise into mainstream popularity, and even spawned an expansion, called Rainbow Six 3: Black Arrow. Plot (PC Version)Raven Shield's story spans a good sixty years, as the prologue centers around World War II and the holocaust, beginning in Croatia. Two people have fled the country with a hefty sum of cash, and escape the Allied forces right in the nick of time. Fast forward to the year 2005, where the Rainbow team takes to task a Neo-Fascist terrorist group.The terrorist organization has apparently been attacking various South American oil interests and European financial institutions. The story leads you to Argentina, in search for Nikola Gospic (Argentinian billionaire) and Alvero Guitierrez (presidential candidate). Rainbow team discovers that Gospic is one of the surviving members of the Ustashe regime, the group that got away with the Holocaust loot. As Gospic is on his death bed, he plans to use his large wealth to resurrect global Fascism -- with the use of chemical weapons.John Clark, member of the Rainbow team, interrogates a captive Guitierrez and learns of Gospic's scheme. He plans to kill masses of people in South America, and create an economic crisis as the price of oil plummets. He would then throw around some cash to obtain the oilfields, and use them to finance an international Fascist movement.You find that Guitierrez's presidential campaign was financed by Gospic, in exchange for political protection.Gospic is described as a "raven picking the bones of an old war," and that Guitierrez would be his shield. It's just too bad that all had to be put to a stop, as Gospic is now dead, and Guitierrez behind bars, thanks to the Rainbow team. Gameplay (PC Version)As with the titles in the franchise before this, Raven Shield for the PC takes place entirely from a first-person perspective. Your gun is shown by default, but can be turned off in the options, just in case your a hardcore Rainbow fan. There is no jumping to be heard of, and the movement speed is what players of today may consider to be slow, but all is done to convey a sense of realism, as your weighted down by all the gear that a special-operative would be carrying.  He's in my sights!The single-player game focuses around a strict mission-structure, for a total of 15. Each mission begins with a briefing, at which point you can change your teams load-out, skim through blueprints of the location, and even plan your course of action. After you wrap your head around all that, you'll be dropped into your location, and will receive instructions through radio transmission of your objectives. The game centers heavily around the combined effort of up to three teams of people, in which you will be put into situations that call you to rescue hostages, disarm bombs, retrieve intel, and take down terrorists.The multi-player game uses the same basic functions of the single-player game, but put into the context of an online environment. All the standard gameplay types of most FPS games are here, with the usual Rainbow twist to them, which people clamor for. Most Rainbow Six game types for the PC version are on a one-life basis, which means that there is no re-spawning system, and at the start of each round teams spawn from either the preset Red or Green position for that map.Primary Weapons Sub-Machine GunsMP5A4 9mmMP5SD5 9mmUMP .45TMP 9mmMac 11/9 9mmSR-2 9mmP90 5.7mmUzi 9mmM12 9mmMicro-Uzi 9mmMP5K PDW 9mmMP5/10A2MTAR-21 9mmCZ-61 9mm Assault RiflesM4 5.56mmM16A2 5.56mmAUG 5.56Galil ARM 5.56mmTar-21 5.56mmAK-47 7.62mmL85A1 5.56mmFAMAS G2 5.56mmG36 5.56mmG3A3 5.56mmM14 7.62mmM82 5.56mmFAL 7.62mmAK-74 5.56mmFNC 5.56mmType 97 5.56mm ShotgunsSpas-12 USAS-12 M1  Sniper RiflesM82A1 .50PSG-1 7.62mmDraganuv 7.62mmAW Covert 7.62mmSSG-3000 7.62mmVSS Vintorez 7.62mmWA-2000 7.62mm Light Machine GunsM249 SAW 5.56mmM60E4 7.62mm21E 7.62mm23E 5.56mmRPD 7.62mm Secondary WeaponsPistols92FS 9mmUSP .40Mark 23 .45Desert Eagle .357Desert Eagle .50P-228 9mmSPP 9mmAP Army 5.7mm Machine PistolsMac 11/9 9mmMicro-Uzi 9mmSR-2 9mmCZ-61 9mm Single-player Missions Stolen Flame  Amuay, Venezuela Oil Refinery Cold Dagger  Jura Canton, Switzerland Alpine Village Mountain Watch  Jura Canton, Switzerland Mountain Highway Sentinel Wolf  Bergen, Norway Shipyard Falcon hour  Cayman Brac, Cayman Islands  Private Airport Pearl Castle  Cayman Brac, Cayman Islands Island Estate Crimson Hook  Pilar, Argentina Meat Packing Plant Stone Cannon  Porto de Alegre, Brazil Import/Export Shattered Glass  Buenos Aires, Argentina Penthouse Lion Shadow  London, England Banking House Broken Stone  Pilar, Argentina Meat Packing Plant 2 Briar Gate  Cayman Brac, Cayman Islands Island Estate 2 Talon Steel  Cayman Brac, Cayman Islands Private Airport 2 Whisper Blade  Rio de Janeiro, Brazil Garage Steel Rose  Rio de Janeiro, Brazil Parade LineupMultiplayer GametypesMission: Experience a single-player like experience as you and a group of your friends work together to complete missions.Terrorist Hunt: This is fairly straight-forward, you and a group of players work on a map of your choosing to take out a user-defined number of terrorists.Survival: Survival is a free-for-all gametype, which supports up to 16 players, and continues until there is one person living, or time expires.Team Survival: This is Raven Shield's version of Team Deathmatch, for up to 16 players, with a user-set time-limit and that special Rainbow flavor.Expansions Athena SwordRaven Shield received two expansions over the course of its lifecycle, the first of which being Rainbow Six 3: Athena Sword. Developed in Ubisoft-Milan, the add-on featured eight new missions (along with a new story arc), five multiplayer missions, seven new weapons and three new multiplayer gametypes. It was released on the 9th of March, 2004 to moderate success. The expansion ultimately wasn't a huge part of the online community, and was eventually filtered out of server listings.The second and final expansion for Raven Shield appeared June 9th, 2005, and was available exclusively on FilePlanet. Iron Wrath was developed by Ubisoft-Casablanca, and featured seven new missions, two classic missions, eight multiplayer maps, and six weapons. MapsAirportAirport 2Alpine VillageBankGarageImport/ExportIsland EstateIsland Estate 2Meat Packing PlantMeat Packing Plant 2Mountain HighwayOil RefineryParadePeaksPenthousePresidioShipyardStreetsWarehouse Console Versions PlotA series of terrorist attacks American interest and its citizens.  As a war looms in the background, it is up to Team Rainbow; a top secret organization of the best field officers the United Nations has in its disposal to eradicate the threat before it is too late.  GameplayThe console version gameplay differs from the PC version.  There is no mission planning stage and the player is responsible to command their own team, not control them.  In the game, you control Ding Chavez and lead your team (Eddie Price, Louis Loiselle, and Dieter Weber) to success.  Orders can be given through the in-game commands or voice commands through a headset connected to the Xbox controller.    Xbox LiveOnline gameplay with Xbox Live created a large community that was long lived through the Xbox console life.  The game consisted of 8 maps and 5 more with downloadable content.   Modes consisted of both team oriented goals and traditional deathmatch. Modes Mission: Co-operative play which sets you in single player maps and situations while playing with your friends or players through Xbox Live.Terrorist Hunt: Four players kill terrorists in the single player maps.Survival: Up to 16 players attempt to kill as many terrorists as possible without dying.  Last man standing wins.Team Survival:Up to 16 players are divided to two teams and the first to eliminate the other team wins.Sharpshooter: More traditional deathmatch mode, attempt to achieve the most kills within the time allotted or reach the kill limit to win.     PC - Minimum System RequirementsSupported OS: Windows 2000/XP/XP-x64/VistaProcessor: Pentium IV 1.6GHz / AthlonXP 1600 Graphics: 3D accelerator 16 MB DirectX 9.0c compatible graphics cardDirectX Version: DirectX 9.0c or betterMemory: 256 MB (512 MB with Vista)Sound: 16 bit DirectX compatible sound cardHard Drive: 1.5 GB free disk space</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7288">SWAT 4</game><game id="12934">Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon 2 - 2007: First Contact</game><game id="25246">Battlefield: Bad Company 2</game><game id="12896">Half-Life: Uplink</game><game id="30615">Gears of War 3</game><game id="1339">Star Wars: Republic Commando</game><game id="30185">Blacklight: Tango Down</game><game id="26423">Call of Duty: Black Ops</game><game id="32909">Code of Honor 3: Desperate Measures</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/431/474185-rvsbox.jpg</image></root>