<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16130</id><name>Imperial Glory</name><description>OverviewImperial Glory was developed by     Pyro Studios, released by    Edios Interactive in 2005. The game was set in   Napoleonic times when five strong empires were pulling their forces over Europe. With its similarity to  Rome: Total War, the game takes you to the throne of five kingdoms, you may manage politics, fight in land or naval battles. Or, If you can't wait to be a king. You may have a quick battle all over Europe and North Africa. There are also five historic battles, all covering about Napoleon.  Imperial Glory offers mutiplayer for up to 2 or 3 players.     Single PlayerThree available Single-player mode:Campaign: Control an empire and lead it to victory. Make economic friends, political enemies. Rule the Europe in the end.Historic Battles: Five historic campaigns available for both France and Alliance side. A good taste of Napoleon.Quick Battles:: Do not have the guts to be a king? Start a quick battle with your enemy. Enjoy the fantastic gamepley and  fight to the end!Five available Empires:Great Britain: The Great influence of the British Empire is still all over the world. Enjoy the strong army and the great influence!France: Hey, Napoleon is in here. Watch him carefully.Prussia: A great empire which is now part of Germany. It has elite army, and strong soldiers.Austria: Situated in inland, with no ports to build an vessel. However, its land troops can make others lose face.Russia: Elite cavalaries. Unique battle techique. Its soldiers will defend their Mother Russia to the end.  captioncaptioncaptioncaptioncaption</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20509">Empire: Total War</game><game id="19887">Rome: Total War</game><game id="8546">Age of Empires III</game><game id="12483">Age of Empires III: The WarChiefs</game><game id="11993">Rise of Nations</game><game id="14291">Stronghold Crusader</game><game id="14590">Age of Empires II: The Conquerors</game><game id="1565">Empire Earth II</game><game id="19857">Empire Earth</game><game id="9264">Rome: Total War - Barbarian Invasion</game><game id="186">Stronghold</game><game id="27879">Napoleon: Total War</game><game id="4686">Waterloo: Napoleon's Last Battle</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4656/927972-imperial_glory.jpg</image></root>