<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16194</id><name>Smash TV</name><description>OverviewSmash TV is a spiritual successor to Robotron: 2084, an early arcade game that is one of the first examples of the twin stick control method. Smash TV retains this same gameplay, using the left joystick to move and the right to shoot, allowing a player to move in one direction while firing in another.The year is 1999. A new game show called Smash TV was created which puts its contenders to the fight for their lives. They will have to kill hundreds of enemies and collect money and prizes (from toasters to a big-screen TV). The inspiration for Smash TV seems to be the Arnold Schwarzenegger film, The Running Man. Two players can play simultaneously, and at the end of each of the three levels, the two players' performance is compared, with one being declared the winner.Evil M.C.Each of the levels in Smash TV ends with a boss battle. The first level pits the players against Mutoid Man. The second boss is a giant, round face named Scarface. The third level seemingly ends with a fight against two large, robotic snake heads called Die Cobros. But this is immediately followed by the game's true boss, the game show host himself called Evil M.C. This battle is essentially a tougher version of the Mutoid Man boss fight.Home VersionsSuper Smash TV for the SNES, one of the few console versions of the game to truly capture the gameplay of the arcade original.After its success in coin-operated form, Smash TV was brought to the home market on many different console and computer platforms. Few of the home machines were able to properly duplicate the arcade's control. Some got around this with buttons that let you switch from firing ahead to firing behind, some allowed you to clumsily attempt to use multiple controllers, but most of these failed to capture the sharp control that makes the hectic gameplay of the original work. The lone exception from the era of its release is the SNES version. Acclaim's SNES version of the game was called Super Smash TV (at least on the box--once in the game, it was only referred to by its original name), and it used the D pad and face buttons to properly duplicate the two joysticks of the original. The SNES version also contained a few additional secret rooms.The same style of home version control was used in the Xbox Live Arcade version of the game, which is an emulation of the original arcade release. It is also the only version to include online play, letting two players play the game over the Internet.This game is featured on Midway Arcade Treasures for the Gamecube, Playstation 2, Xbox, and PC.AchievementsDue to a glitch in the xbox live arcade version of the game, 360 users are unable to obtain the full 200 achievement points available in the game. The Game Master Achievement (in theory obtained by beating the game without continuing on default systems) does not unlock, denying gamers the game's final 50 points. The publishers have acknowledged the problem, but there are currently no plans to fix the issue.SequelsThough Smash TV never received a proper sequel, many of the same people responsible for the game went on to produce Total Carnage, a game that maintained the same control style and applied it to a vertical scrolling world, similar to Ikari Warriors or Mercs. There are plenty of references to Smash TV in Total Carnage.</description><genres><genre id="31">Dual-Joystick Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11061">Total Carnage</game><game id="11233">Robotron: 2084</game><game id="8582">Fatal Rewind</game><game id="20756">The Grid</game><game id="11099">Geometry Wars: Retro Evolved</game><game id="1619">Ikari Warriors</game><game id="20725">NovaStrike</game><game id="18777">The Club</game><game id="21562">Zoombies - Animales de la Muerte</game><game id="21167">Geometry Wars: Retro Evolved 2</game><game id="2027">Crystal Quest</game><game id="13155">Heavy Weapon Deluxe</game><game id="2893">Re-Loaded</game><game id="20657">Assault Heroes 2</game><game id="5222">Assault Heroes</game><game id="20600">Blast Factor</game><game id="6823">Apocalypse</game><game id="24253">Burn Zombie Burn!</game><game id="3061">Will Rock</game><game id="21173">MadWorld</game><game id="7382">Loaded</game><game id="20332">Shock Troopers: 2nd Squad</game><game id="24547">BIOLOGY BATTLE</game><game id="27866">Dead Nation</game><game id="28063">Zombies 2.0</game><game id="29993">Dudebro™ — My Shit Is Fucked Up So I Got to Shoot/Slice You II: It’s Straight-Up Dawg Time</game><game id="31207">Murky Horizon</game><game id="29806">Monday Night Combat</game><game id="27332">Cloak &amp; Dagger</game><game id="32811">Resident Evil: The Mercenaries 3D</game><game id="33875">Voxatron</game><game id="14991">Crack Down</game><game id="34614">Guerrilla Bob</game><game id="34896">Ikki Online</game><game id="35050">Hit &amp; Myth</game><game id="35503">Warhammer 40,000: Kill Team</game><game id="35899">The Binding of Isaac</game><game id="35922">Onslaught! Arena</game><game id="19413">Space Dungeon</game><game id="37389">Pineapple Smash Crew</game><game id="37446">Cannon Fodder 3</game><game id="39485">The Border Lands</game><game id="39824">Gerztron</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3413/236922-smash_tv.jpg</image></root>