<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16202</id><name>Dead or Alive: Xtreme 2</name><description>OverviewDead or Alive Xtreme 2 is the sequel to Dead or Alive: Xtreme Beach Volleyball, and features the female characters of many Team Ninja games. The game revolves around the obtainment of credits. Credits can be earned by playing volleyball, racing on jet skis, and other activities. Those credits can then be used to buy collectible swimsuits, gifts, or for gambling. Xtreme 2 focuses mostly on expanding that collection of swimsuits; a feature appealing to fans of collecting objects like Pokemon, or cars in the Gran Turismo series. A notable controversy exists surrounding the prominent use of scantily clad women as a draw. Unlike the first game, which pitched itself as a valid beach volleyball game that just so happened to feature a cast made entirely out of busty, scantily-clad women, going as far as to hide all other elements of gameplay from marketing, Xtreme 2 makes no pretense about it, openly admitting that the central draw to the game is ogling virtual women in bikinis.CharactersAll playable characters hail from the Dead or Alive series. A particular girl's favorite color, food, and hobby are all information to be considered when making gift-giving decisions; an integral part of winning over a girl's favor and fostering friendships. Friendships are built by giving hobby-relevant gifts in the correct color wrapping paper. Another way to pursue relationships can be found in the minigames scattered about Zack Island.AyaneNationality: JapaneseHobbies: Beauty TreatmentsFavorite Food: Marrons GlacesFavorite Color: Dark PurpleKokoroNationality: JapaneseHobbies: PianoFavorite Food: Japanese Fruit CocktailFavorite Color: OrangeKasumiNationality: JapaneseHobbies: Fortune TellingFavorite Food: Strawberry MillefeuilleFavorite Color: Milky PinkLisaNationality: AmericanHobbies: SurfingFavorite Food: Cherry PieFavorite Color: Crimson RedChristieNationality: BritishHobbies: DrivingFavorite Food: Tomato JuiceFavorite Color: BlackLei FangNationality: ChineseHobbies: Aroma TherapyFavorite Food: Almond TofuFavorite Color: Lemon YellowHelenaNationality: FrenchHobbies: Walking Her DogFavorite Food: Blanc MangerFavorite Color: Pearl WhiteHitomiNationality: GermanHobbies: CookingFavorite Food: SachertorteFavorite Color: Sky BlueTinaNationality: AmericanHobbies: Sports Games, CyclingFavorite Food: SeafoodFavorite Color: Sapphire BlueXbox 360 Game InstallationDoesn't exist. For reasons unknown, Xtreme 2 doesn't allow HDD installations. Game save files can also not be moved or copied. If the user migrates HDD saved data to a new HDD via the Xbox transfer cable kit the data will not be moved from the original save destination.Activities and Mini-gamesUnlike its predecessor Xtreme 2 doesn't focus solely on volley ball. Originally there were 42 suggested mini-games to be included in the game out of the suggested ideas seven mini-games actually are featured in the game. Like the first however the relationship aspect the game is again played up heavily. Beach Volleyball:Like the original game volleyball consists of two teams with two competitors. First to seven points wins. to participate in this activity you must have a partner.Pool Hopping:A timing mini-game that can be played solo to earn money or in a competition against another girl. Players tap the "A" button in rhythmic timing to jump from floating platform to floating platform. First girl to the other side wins. If playing solo more money is awarded for faster times.Water slide: Players slide down the waterside in a inner-tube. Money is earned for faster times and players are disqualified if they go off course. Players must go to the sports shop and purchase a Water Slide ticket for 150 Zack dollars in order to participate in the water slide event.Beach Flag: A race competition against another girl. Both competitors lay on the sand belly down upon the signal to start players must rapidly tap the "A" button to make their character run faster. First girl to retrieve the flag at the end of the course wins. Like the water slide a ticket must also be bought in the sports shop to participate in the event.Jet-Ski Race:Several players race around various courses. Players are provided with a default jet-ski but several more jet-skis with varying stats are available to purchase in the sports shop. Players can also preform tricks to make extra money during the races.Tug-o-War: Two girls stand on floating platforms inside the pool holding the rope. Players can either tug the rope or feign tugging the rope in hopes of fooling your opponent. This mini-game requires a ticket from the sports shop.Butt Battle:Two girls on a floating platform use their hips and butt to try to knock the other competitor into the pool. Players can either strike, dodge or if the stick is flicked back and forth quickly preform a power move. Best of 3 rounds wins the match. A ticket from the sports shop is required.Casino:Players can engage in multiple forms of gambling including slots, blackjack, roulette and five-card poker. The casino is only available at night after players retire to their hotel rooms.Poledancing:A gravure event which can be unlocked by getting a "Secret ticket" the ticket is obtained by getting nine jackpot wins in one sitting on the Christy themed slot machine in the casino. The ticket can be used once to view the event after which the item is expended and removed from the players inventory.Soundtrack"Summer Breezin" by Diana King"How Crazy Are You" by Meja"Double Lovin" by Baha Men featuring Reiss"Sweet Sixteen" by Hilary Duff"Quiero Que Me Quieras" by Olga Tanon"Like That Girl" by Fatty Koo"Holla" by Baha men"Is This Love" by Bob Marley"Lovin' You" by Janet Kay"Brazilian Sugar" by George Duke"Dreamin" by Sweet Female Attitude"Flower ( Cutfather  Joe Mix )" by Sweet Female Attitude"Nothing To Lose" by Sweet Female Attitude"Reggae Dancer" by Inner Circle"Another Love Story" by Play"Sweet Sensual Love" by Big Mountain"The Kids Don't Like It" by Reel Big Fish"If It Don't Fit" by B*Witched</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="13">Card Game</genre><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5406">Outlaw Volleyball</game><game id="11105">Wave Race</game><game id="11793">Wave Race: Blue Storm</game><game id="11969">Wave Race 64</game><game id="5957">Outlaw Volleyball: Remixed</game><game id="15228">Outlaw Volleyball: Red Hot</game><game id="12635">Rumble Roses XX</game><game id="18086">Rumble Roses</game><game id="16696">RapeLay</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1894017-box_doax2.png</image></root>