<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16200</id><name>The King of Fighters: Neowave</name><description>Overview The King of Fighters: Neowave is a 2D 3-on-3 fighting game developed and published by                                 SNK Playmore for the Atomiswave arcade platform. It is the first out of the five games SNK Playmore developed for the platform. (The others being                                NeoGeo Battle Coliseum,                               Samurai Shodown VI,                              The King of Fighters XI, and                             Metal Slug 6) Although released after                            The King of Fighters 2003, the gameplay and non-canonical concept of "Dream Match" is based on                           The King of Fighters 2002. It is the first                         King of Fighters game to feature a fifth button, which is used here to power-up at the cost of slowly depleting the life gauge. It is also the only arcade version of King of Fighters to feature a 3D polygonal background in front of the 2D character sprites. The game was first ported to the    Xbox worldwide, then ported to the     PlayStation 2 in Japan and PAL regions only, featuring new hidden characters. Due to licensing issues with   Eolith prior to the PS2 release, the Arcade and Xbox versions do not have characters who made their debut on  The King of Fighters 2001.Characters Japan Team                        Kyo Kusanagi (also with a hidden EX version, known as the evil clone Kusanagi, that is exclusive to the PS2 and Xbox versions)                                                       Benimaru Nikaido                                                       Goro DaimonFatal Fury Team                                                       Terry Bograd                                                       Andy Bograd                                                       Joe HigashiArt of Fighting Team                                                       Ryo Sakazaki                                                       Robert Garcia                                                       Takuma Sakazaki Ikari Warriors Team                                                 Leona                                               Ralf Jones                                              Clark Steel Psycho Soldier Team                                              Athena Asamiya                                            Sie Kensou                                           Chin GentsaiWomen Fighters Team                                                       Mai Shiranui                                                       Yuri Sakazaki                                                       King Korea Team                                           Jhun Hoon                                         Chang Koehan                                        Choi Bounge                  King of Fighters '96 Team                         Iori Yagami                                                       Mature                                                        Vice                 King of Fighters '97 Team                                                       Ryuji Yamazaki                                                       Blue Mary                                                       Billy Kane                 King of Fighters '98 Team      Yashiro Nanakase (with Orochi Yashiro as a hidden character)      Shermie (with Orochi Shermie as a hidden character)      Chris (with Orochi Chris as a hidden character)               King of Fighters '99 Team                                                       K'                                                       Maxima                                                       Whip Mixed Team                  Saisyu Kusanagi                Kula Diamond               Shingo YabukiOther              Kim Kaphwan (hidden character)             Vanessa (hidden character)            Ramon (hidden character)           Geese Howard (boss, younger form from           Art of Fighting 2)         Seth (hidden character exclusive to the PS2 and Xbox versions)        Rugal Bernstein (hidden character exclusive to the PS2 and Xbox versions)       May Lee (hidden character exclusive to the PS2 version)      Angel (hidden character exclusive to the PS2 version)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18484">Killer Instinct</game><game id="21952">Killer Instinct 2</game><game id="10614">Killer Instinct Gold</game><game id="243">Street Fighter II: The World Warrior</game><game id="20616">Super Street Fighter II Turbo HD Remix</game><game id="1615">Street Fighter III: 3rd Strike</game><game id="1251">Super Street Fighter II Turbo</game><game id="4762">Street Fighter Alpha Anthology</game><game id="21948">Street Fighter III: New Generation</game><game id="2396">Fatal Fury</game><game id="11400">Fatal Fury 2</game><game id="2760">Art of Fighting</game><game id="13327">Art of Fighting 2</game><game id="10674">Garou: Mark of the Wolves</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2199355-box_kofnw.png</image></root>