<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16206</id><name>The Warriors</name><description>OverviewThe Warriors is a brawler from Rockstar Games that is based off the 1979 movie of the same title. The game begins well before the events of the movie take place, and shows how the Warriors began to build their reputation in New York. While the majority of the game is effectively a precursor to the film, the later levels do follow the events of the movie.GameplayThe game plays as a traditional 3-D brawler, and includes grapples, light attacks, strong attacks, reversals/counterattacks, and blocks. Group attacks and "Rage Mode" are part of the gameplay as well. Also, almost any object can be used as a weapon and once picked up, they can be thrown or used as a melee weapon. These items range from traditional (bricks and other similar items) to bizarre (bongs and some even more weird items).MultiplayerThe game can be played entirely in co-op, but only locally. The game also has Rumble Mode which is made up of eight separate multi player modes. The modes featured are:1 on 1: a two player one on one fightWar Party: two gangs with five to a sideArmy-Ing: two gangs with nine to a sideHave Mercy: a capture the flag modeBurner Battle: finish a burner while being attacked by other gangsBattle Royal: an elimanation modeWheels of Steel: a racing mode using a wheel chairKing of the HIll: stand on a platform while a timer ticks down without being knocked offArmies of the NightOnce the main game is completed, Armies of the Night is unlocked. This small mini-game is essentially a 2D brawler, very similar to Double Dragon (the opening scene is actually a direct parody of Double Dragon's opening scene).Unleash The Fury ModeThis mode allows you to play the main game as the Baseball Furies. It is unlocked by beating the game 100% on Hardcore Soldier mode.The WarriorsThe Warriors are the primary gang featured in the game, and they reside over their turf in Coney Island. Along with hundreds of other gangs, The Warriors are summoned to send nine delegates to a meeting where Cyrus, leader of the most powerful gang in New York City, The Gramercy Riffs, is expected to give an important speech.CleonThe best.Cleon is the leader of The Warriors, and he is responsible for creating the gang with the help of Vermin. He has a strong presence and is well-respected by his fellow Warriors.SwanSwan is second in command among The Warriors. After a certain turn of events, Swan must step up and fulfill the role of Cleon, their fallen leader. He is calm, cool, and brave.AjaxAjax is the hot-headed muscle of The Warriors. He's always looking for a fight, even with other Warriors if they get in his way.VerminVermin is one of the co-founders of The Warriors, along with their leader, Cleon. Vermin is more laid-back than the others, but always loyal.CochiseCochise is a soft-spoken tough guy. He was initially rejected by The Warriors because he lived in Harlem, which is the turf of a rival gang known as The Boppers. However, he boldly rises to Cleon's challenge and proves his worth.FoxFox is the scout of The Warriors. He's a very observant member of the group, and provides The Warriors with valuable information.SnowMost of the characters are voiced by the original actorsSnow is one of the more quiet and reserved members of The Warriors, though he clearly demonstrates that he is a solid fighter.CowboyCowboy isn't nearly one of the strongest members of The Warriors, but he shows that he's an excellent companion. He's always loyal and will do what he can to help out his comrades.RembrandtRembrandt is the primary tag artist for The Warriors, and he is initiated into the gang during the outset of the game. He may not be as tough as the others, but he always represents for his crew.AshAsh is a member of The Warriors exclusive to the video game. He is not one of the nine delegates present during Cyrus' speech.Other GangsAlong with the Warriors, there are several other gangs, spanning all of New York. Many of them were featured in the movie, and all have a mission featuring them. Other gangs can also be played in the multiplayer modes.RoguesThe Rogues, led by Luther, are a chaotic group, focused on creating mayhem just for fun. They are the main antagonists of the Warriors , due to the fact that Luther killed Cyrus and blamed the Warriors for it. Just like in the movie, the Rogues are confronted by the Warriors at Coney Island. The played must defeat the Rogues and injure Luther. Once beaten, the Riffs show up to finish off the Rogues. During the credits, the player controls the Riffs as they finish the Rogues off.Gramercy RiffsThe most powerful gang in the city, led by Cyrus, are the Riffs. Cyrus plans to unite New York City's many gangs, but is killed by Luther. Luther blames the Warriors' War Chief Cleon, who is killed by the Riffs. The Riffs put a call out to the whole city to bring the Warriors to them, or kill them.Baseball FuriesA silent, but intimidating group, who dress in traditional baseball attire and wear face paint. The Furies chase the Warriors around their turf many times in the game. If the game is beaten 100% on the highest difficulty, the Furies are unlocked in the story mode. They can be played in their own difficulty mode and follow the main story of the Warriors.OrphansA small-time gang from Tremont, led by Sully. The Orphans claim they defeated the Warriors, even though they didn't. To rectify this, the Warriors go to the Orphans turf and confront them. The player must destroy Sully's car and take out 40 Orphans to complete the mission.Hi-HatsOperating out of SoHo, the Hi-Hats focus on art more than gang activities. The members wear top hats and mime clothing and are silent much like the Furies. They are led by Chatterbox, a large, stuttering clown.LizziesAn all female gang from the Bowery they try to seduce The Warriors before trying to kill them.PunksA gang from the Bowery whose leader wears roller skates. They are seen wearing overalls over their striped shirts.Turnbull AC'sA gang from Gun Hill Road, they have shaved heads and travel around in a bus with graffiti tags all over it. The Warriors have to run from there bus to get to the subway.DestroyersAnother gang from Coney Island that Cleon and Vermin used to be a part of until the leader Virgil got paranoid and tried to set the up to be killed during a drug deal. They are The Warriors main rivals.Warchief CommandsWhile playing as the Warchief, or leader of the Warriors, the player can give one of six commands to his soldiers. Some commands are unavailable in certain missions.Wreck 'Em All- The Warriors focus their efforts on attacking and getting weapons.Mayhem-The Warriors smash anything in sight.Let's Go-The Warriors follow their Warchief.Scatter-The Warriors separate and hide from cops or enemy gangs.Watch My Back-The soldiers defend the player. Used while spray painting or picking a lock.Hold Up-The Warriors stop and defend their ground.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5888">God Hand</game><game id="7649">Mortal Kombat: Shaolin Monks</game><game id="20752">Double Dragon</game><game id="6722">Final Fight</game><game id="7180">Yakuza</game><game id="13297">Two Crude Dudes</game><game id="13147">Yakuza 2</game><game id="12835">Fantastic 4</game><game id="25283">The Warriors: Street Brawl</game><game id="21847">Watchmen: The End is Nigh</game><game id="12365">State of Emergency 2</game><game id="11898">Beat Down: Fists of Vengeance</game><game id="18122">Streets of Rage 2</game><game id="27256">Kenka Bancho: Badass Rumble</game><game id="26889">Undead Knights</game><game id="23312">Dirty Harry</game><game id="26913">Watchmen: The End is Nigh Part 2</game><game id="30469">Kick-Ass</game><game id="10281">Bully</game><game id="5092">Bully: Scholarship Edition</game><game id="15532">Urban Reign</game><game id="15032">Urban Chaos</game><game id="9963">Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles 3: Mutant Nightmare</game><game id="41836">Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Out of the Shadows</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2285756-box_twarriors.png</image></root>