<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1628</id><name>SimCity Societies</name><description>OverviewSimCity Societies is the fifth game in the              SimCity franchise, and the first not to be developed by             Maxis, though this was due to the fact they were busy making          Spore. Developer duties were instead handed over to            Tilted Mill Entertainment, the team behind           Caesar IV.    GameplayThe game itself marks a massive departure from the traditional SimCity gameplay, stripping away most of the systems that had made SimCity so complex. The long-time realistic         city-building simulation was shifted away from its roots and into a "social engineering simulator".     Perhaps the most immediately apparent gameplay change from previous  games is the removal of 'zoning', replaced now by placing actual  buildings. Construction of these buildings is now instantaneous.  Revenue has been radically altered; as it is now earned per day from  buildings instead of calculated from taxes. Public works such as water  and garbage disposal have been removed from the game and are now handled  automatically. Electric plants must still be constructed, but power  lines are no longer required.      Power plants can now be considered by how 'green' they are, with polluting power plants creating heat waves and other negative events.  A new addition are the "Special Sims", who are randomly generated by sims visiting certain buildings or by using a building's special ability. Faith Healers can cure the sick and the lame, while Tycoons temporarily improve a workplace's efficiency at the cost of workplace happiness. Not all Special Sims positively affect the city; Arsonists set fire to buildings and Pickpockets will rob Sims blind. Instead of building one large metropolis, the game now centers around creating a society. As a city grows larger, it requires more of six societal values: productivity, prosperity, creativity, spirituality, spirituality, authority, and knowledge. All of these values are generated and consumed by buildings and city ordinances. For example, a clock tower would generate three points of authority.  SocietiesAs previously stated, cities can generate and consume societal values. Several unique types of cities can be made by focusing or neglecting certain values. As a city edges closer to a certain type of society, the aesthetics of the city change and the color of the menus shifts.Authoritarian: Focuses on authority. Authoritarian cities echo shades of George Orwell's 1984 and totalitarian states. People are conditioned to not be happy or disgruntled, but merely satiated. Capitalist: Focuses on prosperity. A Wall Street executive's dream with numerous shopping malls, stock exchanges, and corporate police. Contemplative: Focuses on spirituality. The people will worship whatever flying spaghetti monster they please, just as long as there's a church on every corner.Cyberpunk: Focuses on knowledge, prosperity, and authority. Somewhat dystopian in execution with holographic advertisements and polluted streets. Fun City: Focuses on creativity. Everyone is happy since there's amusement park rides all over town and free candy for all. Industrial: Focuses on productivity. Similar to cities prior to the Great Depression, everyone works at a factory and lives in a slum. Romantic: Focuses on prosperity and creativity. Couple will walk the cobblestone streets to spend the night on the town.Small Town: Focuses on spirituality and prosperity while keeping a low population count. Haunted: A "secret" society, based around building haunted buildings. Special Sims such as Zombies and Ghosts will appear in your town.'Normal': While no city is truly normal, you can avoid creating a different society by neither focusing nor neglecting any one societal value. ReceptionSimCity Societies came under criticism shortly after being announced by long-time fans of the franchise over its changes from the traditional SimCity formula. The criticism was so severe that then-President of Tilted Mill Entertainment Chris Beatrice actually responded to the fans.   Opinions were mixed upon the game's release. The game was widely criticized by its critics and many fans for a lack of challenge and for being a system hog. However, some outlets praised the game, such as GameZone's applauding the new direction for the game.   The developers responded to the criticism by adding additional content, such as more challenging gameplay modes, additional buildings, and new disasters.  ExpansionsAn expansion has since been released,  SimCity Societies: Destinations. The expansion compounded upon the transportation systems in place in the original game, and tourism was expanded.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20648">Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles: My Life as a King</game><game id="2447">SimTower: The Vertical Empire</game><game id="20960">SimCity Creator</game><game id="4736">SimCity 4</game><game id="1628">SimCity Societies</game><game id="22080">SimCity Societies: Destinations</game><game id="15236">SimAnt: The Electronic Ant Colony</game><game id="23725">Prison Tycoon 4: SuperMax</game><game id="21729">Cities XL</game><game id="21544">Hinterland</game><game id="21149">Populous DS</game><game id="24980">Grand Ages: Rome</game><game id="13927">Airport Tycoon 3</game><game id="738">Black &amp; White 2: Battle of the Gods</game><game id="1128">The Settlers II: 10th Anniversary</game><game id="3642">The Settlers II: 10th Anniversary - Vikings</game><game id="16757">Tropico: Paradise Island</game><game id="32326">Tropico 4</game><game id="24458">Tropico 3</game><game id="1489">8th Wonder of the World</game><game id="7965">Tropico 2: Pirate Cove</game><game id="11466">CivCity: Rome</game><game id="6645">Caesar III</game><game id="5652">Caesar II</game><game id="12757">Tropico</game><game id="30573">Tropico 3: Absolute Power</game><game id="4102">Emperor: Rise of the Middle Kingdom</game><game id="18721">Cultures</game><game id="19132">Cultures 2: The Gates of Asgard</game><game id="5457">Cultures: Die Abenteuerbox</game><game id="3009">Immortal Cities: Children of the Nile</game><game id="36949">Majesty 2: Battles of Ardania</game><game id="17680">Pharaoh</game><game id="6210">Populous</game><game id="10562">Populous II: Trials of the Olympian Gods</game><game id="5211">Zeus Official Expansion: Poseidon</game><game id="3769">Zeus: Master of Olympus</game><game id="9828">The Settlers: Rise of an Empire – The Eastern Realm</game><game id="2815">The Settlers: Rise of an Empire</game><game id="22372">The Settlers IV: The Trojans and the Elixir of Power</game><game id="22371">The Settlers IV: Mission CD</game><game id="16829">The Settlers II: Veni, Vidi, Vici</game><game id="3449">The Settlers II Mission CD</game><game id="15294">The Settlers III: Quest of the Amazons</game><game id="10978">The Settlers III</game><game id="2081">The Settlers II</game><game id="6946">The Settlers: Fourth Edition</game><game id="12922">The Settlers</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2352264-box_scs.png</image></root>