<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1636</id><name>BloodRayne 2</name><description>StoryBloodRayne 2 does not directly follow on from the first game. Instead it is set some 60 years later and follows Rayne as she battles against the Cult of Kagan; the offspring of Rayne's evil father.The Cult of Kagan has developed a substance known as "The Shroud" which not only renders the sun's rays harmless to vampires but corrupts nature itself. Using this substance, the Cult of Kagan plans to bring about a new age of vampiric supremacy and reduce humanity to mere cattle.GameplayVery much akin to the original BloodRayne you fight in a third person perspective. Using Rayne's arm mounted blades you cut and slice your enemies much like the Devil May Cry or God of War games. In addition to her blades, Rayne can also use her dragon pistols and has a harpoon to catch and throw enemies.Many areas of BloodRayne 2 have been changed from its predecessor.BloodRayne 2 introduces a manual lock on. Manual lock on is used for harpoon an enemy or object, aim in gun combat, and to attack an individual enemy in melee combat. BloodRayne 2's manual lock on replaces its predecessor's auto lock on for all gun combat.Rayne's dragon pistols replace human weapons for gun combat. Improved shot types replace the finding of new weapons. These include: blood shot, blood stream, blood spray, blood bomb, blood flame, and blood hammer.BloodRayne 2 adds environmental and combat oriented acrobatic moves to Rayne's move list. In the environment, she can now climb pipes, jump back and forth between chain link fences, swing on and jump from poles, and grind along rails. In combat, Rayne can now dodge toward away, over, and around enemies while locked onto them.Re-ReleaseKorea's Game Rating Board has rated the game for release on the PlayStation 3.Special PowersAs a Dhampir, a child of a human mother and vampire father, Rayne is able to feed on her enemies to restore her health. This also provides her with the ability to remain in sunlight while taking only minimal damage.Rayne also has a three tier set of other special powers. They are an attack/defense upgrade tier, a passive power tier, and time related tier. Each tier has three special powers that are acquired throughout the game.Attack/Defense TierBlood RageBlood FuryBlood StormPassive TierAura VisionGhost FeedEnthrallTime TierDilated PerceptionSuper SpeedFreeze TimeTriviaThe game was lightly modified for use in the movie "Grandma's Boy" (2006) where it appeared as Eternal Death Slayer 3.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10037">Bullet Witch</game><game id="19261">Drake of the 99 Dragons</game><game id="21984">WET</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2116205-box_brayne2.png</image></root>