<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16372</id><name>Prey</name><description>                                        Overview  Prey is a Sci-Fi FPS made by                                                                                      Human Head Studios, using            id's           Doom 3 engine. The game features the traditional shooter banter, as well as some unique          puzzles. To solve these puzzles, you need to walk on the ceiling, walls, and go through portals to complete. Also the game had an online multiplayer component and a soundtrack composed by                                                                                      Jeremy Soule, the man behind                                                                                      Oblivion and                           Guild Wars'                                                                                      soundtrack. Marketing for the "sequel",  Prey 2, would imply that the title of the game referred to the fact that the aliens were hunting Tommy throughout the Sphere, but this is not the case, and in truth, it referred to the fact that the aliens intended to consume all of humanity. Plot Tommy, the game's protagonist.  The game begins, oddly enough, in a dank, dirty                                                                                     bathroom. The main character                                                                                   Tommy is gazing at himself through the grime covered                                                                                    mirror, and as you venture out into what appears to be a bar, you meet the supporting roles in the adventure. These two support characters are Jen, Tommy's girlfriend, and Tommy's grandfather Enisi. Tommy speaks to Jen about leaving their                                                                                  Native American reservation and pursuing other things. After a quick scuffle between Tommy and a few of the bar's patrons, the bar's walls begin to shake and the roof is torn off. Green tractor  beams shoot through the open ceiling and Tommy, Jen and Enisi are pulled up into the air.Tommy wakes up and is strapped into a moving                                                                                 coffin-like contraption. He has his grandfather and girlfriend in sight, and his grandfather tries to calm him and Jen down. Along the ride, Tommy sees strange alien  lifeforms, and it appears that these aliens are performing tests on humans. Just as the characters are about to be split up, a strange man seems to detonate a bomb, and de-rail Tommy's cart from the rail system. This is when the player assumes control of Tommy, and begins to traverse the horrible alien spaceship. Tommy makes his way throughout the ship, and encounters strange things like anti-gravity walking strips, and portals. After some exploration, Tommy witnesses the brutal killing of his grandfather Enisi. After this, Tommy becomes extremely emotional and vows to rescue Jen.The Spirit WorldNavigating through the ship, Tommy comes to a narrow and shoddy bridge.It collapses when he tries to cross it, and Tommy "dies". Instead of being dead for good though, Tommy is transported to a spirit world. In this spirit world, Tommy meets his grandfather Enisi. Enisi explains how his, and the spirits of his ancestors live on in this spirit world, and also tells Tommy that the spirit of his childhood pet bird Talon is his guardian. After some quick tutorials on how to spirit project, Tommy is sent back to the world of the living. Tommy continues through the ship, and meets the leader of the resistance against the                                                                                aliens, Elhuit. She explains to Tommy that the Mother, whatever that is, needs to be destroyed in order to destroy the ship and it is operations, and Tommy accepts the task. Along the way to the final controntation, Tommy is confronted by Jen, who has been grotesquely spliced onto the body of a hideous monster over which she has no control. After defeating the monster, Tommy is forced to mercy-kill the suffering Jen to prevent the monster from reviving. When Tommy finally confronts the Mother, it is revealed that she is human, and  that she had defeated the previous Mother and assumed the role. Now, centuries later, she took a special interest in Tommy because of his Spirit abilities and was training and testing him all along to take her place, to rule the Sphere as its "Father". An enraged Tommy does battle with the Mother, and upon the brink of death, she forcefully begins to fill Tommy's mind with the vast knowledge that she possesses, somehow teleporting him into her chamber at the very heart of the Sphere. Overwhelmed with the power, Tommy briefly considers becoming the Father, until Enisi contacts Tommy and advises him to not accept it. Tommy rejects the power, and destroys the Sphere by flying it straight into the sun. He returns to the spirit world, and sees Enisi and Jen, who reveal that he isn't dead yet, as they protected him during his intended sacrifice. They return him to Earth, to live his life until the day that he will see his grandfather and Jen again. However, some time later, when the bar has been rebuilt and is now run by Tommy, Elhuit appears to him, to tell him that his adventure is just beginning, and opens a portal to an unknown destination.  WeaponsName DescriptionPrimary FireSecondary Fire Wrench   A standard monkey wrench, taken from Tommy's job as a mechanic on Earth, and the only human-made weapon Swing WrenchSwings back the Wrench for extra damage RifleBiological weapon; a combination of fully automatic rifle and bolt-action sniper rifleStandard automatic fire-modeTriggers zoom mode on/off; rate of fire drops but damage increases while zoomed. CrawlerSmall insectoid creatures whose volatile chemicals within allow them to operate as living grenadesBreak one leg off the creature, throw, takes one second to explodeFlip creature over, break off all legs, acts as a trip mine when tossed  Leech Gun Large cannon with four ammo types    Plasma (red glow): fires fast-moving balls of energy  Freeze (light-blue glow): short-range attack that turns enemies into ice  Lightning (white sparks): fires a bolt of electricity Sunbeam (orange glow): a violent incandescent beam that cuts down most enemies almost instantly Fires the currently equipped ammo typeCharge up the gun by leeching the energy from nodes (one colour for each ammo type) found around in the Sphere  Auto CannonA                                                                            machine gun  with rocket firing capabilities, built into the arm of a particularly  powerful enemy, collected by Tommy from the severed arm of such an  enemy. High-rate fire; highly damagingRockets  Acid SprayerThis is a                  Shotgun variant that spews yellow acid, also featuring some grenade launcher capabilitiesShotgun acid blastFires an entire canister of acid, almost like a grenade launcher would  LauncherRocket Launcher with a defense mechanismFires rockets Fires a gas cloud that acts as a shield  Spirit BowAn ethereal bow and arrow, the Spirit Bow is the only weapon available  to Tommy while he is Spirit Walking, as all of his "real" weapons are  naturally stuck with his body. It uses Tommy's Spirit Energy as ammunition.Fires an arrow----- Talon  Tommy's spirit guide, appearing in the form of a translucent blue hawk.   In addition to helping guide the player through levels, Talon also attacks any nearby  enemies (glowing red when he does so). Talon cannot be controlled by the player.---------- Enemies Common Enemies A Fodder, a rather unpleasant enemy.   Fodder -- these are the weakest of the enemies faced on the Sphere and can be  killed easilyHarvester -- these beings have a vital role in  harvesting the protein from captives to feed the SphereHunter -- the foot-soldiers of the invading force, it is their  responsibility to track down and eliminate any captives who might get looseMutilated Human -- humans who have had machinery implanted into their bodies, leaving them in a  zombie-like state; they only fight when provokedHound -- the Hunters' sidekicks; they can knock Tommy  around and temporarily impair his visionGasbag -- floating, tentacled creatures that spit acid.  Gasbags attack anyone who gets too close to them, even your         enemiesMutate -- the product of the splicing of DNA genes of both human and other alien   victims held captive in the SphereDrone -- drones are flying robots that do maintenance and repairs in the SphereCenturions -- after your first encounter with this                                                  Cyberdemon-looking guy more will spawn against you, even though they'll be considerably weakerWraiths of Fallen Spirits -- when Tommy loses all his health,  he falls into the Death Realm. He must then battle the Wraiths of Fallen Spirits  to regain both his health  and spirit energy before being able to return to his body.  Creature X -- After Tommy encounters the grotesque form of Jen spliced to a giant monster (referred to as "Girlfriend X" by the Art of  Prey book), he will encounter similar, though vastly weaker creatures who have generic human males spliced into the position Jen held. Bosses    CenturionThe Centurion. Girlfriend XKeeperMotherLevelsPrey's engaging and fearsome story develops throughout the course of 22 levels, or chapters.   Last CallEscape VelocityDownward SpiralRites of PassageSecond ChancesAll Fall DownCrash Landing Sacrifices There are Others Guiding Fires The Old Tribes Hidden Agenda Jen The Dark Harvest Following HerThe Complex Ascent Center of GravityResolutions Oath of Vengeance Facing the Enemy Mother's EmbraceMinigames Video Poker Before the aliens begin to beam everything up, you can walk over to the game machines and play them. There is a blackjack machine, a poker machine, and a game called Rune Man, with graphics patterned after  Rune, another game by Human Head studios. Rune Man is very similar to                                                                        Pac-Man except is features a                                                                       viking helmet, and the pickup items are                                                                      runes. Even if you miss the opportunity to play these, you can find them at later points throughout the game, strewn about the alien ship.    Jukebox Before the aliens begin to beam everything up, you can also walk over to the jukebox and select a song to listen to, and change the volume as well. There are many songs from real artists like Judas Priest, MXPX, Halifax, etc. You also re-visit the torn-up bar at a later point in the game and the jukebox is still functional, but stuck on the song "Don't Fear the Reaper", at full volume.  Also note, Blue Oyster Cult's "Don't Fear the Reaper" was not a song that could be chosen prior to the opening events of aliens attacking the bar, only when it happened did the song come on. MultiplayerPrey's multiplayer consists of two modes:                                                                     Deathmatch and                                                                    Team Deathmatch. The multiplayer is standard FPS fare and utilizes all of the features of the single player mode such as the "Spirit Walk" in which                                                                   Tommy exits his body as a Ghost-like entity to find hidden paths and weapons. However, while in spirit walk mode, the player's body is left vulnerable to attack and can only be used for a limited amount of time. Though there were many free downloads in the form of maps and character skins for multiplayer, the community quickly dispersed as the game waned in popularity. It was regarded by many critics as "tacked on" and "unpolished".Development  Talon Brave, the original protagonist of Prey   Prey was officially announced in 1995, eleven years before the game came out.             Tom Hall worked on the original design of the game but was replaced by Paul Schuytema after he left to form another company. Hall envisioned an alien abduction that the story would be based around; the new team kept that concept but changed the setting to a huge space ship inhabited by the Trocara and the Keepers. The protagonist was to be a stereotypical Native American named "Talon Brave". At E3 1997 and E3 1998, the development team showed off some of the game's concepts including the use of portal technology and highly destructible environments. These features impressed those that saw it and it received much acclaim. At this point in the development, it seemed like 3D Realms was on its way to releasing a great game. The visuals were looking great for its time and people were confident in the studio due to the successful Duke Nukem 3D. Unfortunately, it didn't last. Devastating technical issues started coming up, and Prey fell apart. When Schuytema's version of Prey was officially done for, 3D Realms brought on Corrinne Yu in November 1998 in an attempt to revive the game. Despite their efforts, this new version of Prey also failed, and the project went on hiatus in 1999. In 2001, the portal technology that the studio needed was already being used in many other titles, so all 3D Realms had to do was license it instead of creating their own. Rumors began circulating the following year that 3D Realms was making Prey, but the game was kept a secret until 2005 when 2K Games announced the game. The game was finally released on July 11, 2006, using the id Tech 4 engine and a new protagonist named Tommy.Critical Reception  Prey was technically in development since 1995, but had been cancelled for several years until the project was restarted in the early 2000s, ultimately being released on the                                                                  Xbox 360 and                                                                 PC. With all of this build up, it's fair to say that critics and gamers alike were waiting to see what the game had turned out to be. The critical reception of this game was varied, but overall, the game received average reviews. It received a 79 out of 100 on metacritic for the 360 version, while the PC version got a 83 out of 100, but both scores are favorable. Although the portal technology used in the game, allowing a player to walk into a portal in one place and instantly emerge somewhere else, was revolutionary at the time, it was unfortunately eclipsed just a year later by  Portal, which featured the exact same technology, except it also gave the player the ability to place the portals wherever they wished.SoundtrackPrey -  Artwork for CD 1 Prey's                                                         soundtrack was composed by                                                        Jeremy Soule.        DISC ONETrack No.Song TitleRunning Time 01 Prey Overture 05.49 02 Aniwyah Calling 02.05 03 Dark Harvest Begins 01.24 04 Upside Down 02.23 05 Where In the Hell Am I? 01.03 06 The Land of the Ancients 02.57 07 As if Appearing from Nowhere 02.09 08 Cries In the Darkness 02.28 09 Back to the Ancient Land 01.36 10 Finding the Warrior Within 01.31 11 Breaching the Surface 01.33 12 Smoke and Mirrors 05.27 13 Desperate Measures 02.45 14 Battle at the Superportal 05.11 15 Primal Instincts 02.32 16 Strenghtened Resolve 03.12 17 Hundreds of Your Miles Tall 04.57 18 Full Ascension 02.47  Prey - Artwork for CD 2         DISC TWOTrack No.Song TitleRunning Time 01 Cutting the Power 02.31 02 Survival of the Fittest 12.12 03 You're Becoming a Nuisance 03.17 04 Pushing Towards Fate 04.49 05 Splitting the Arrow 04.12 06 Sacred Realm Desanctified 05.10 07 The Power of the Keepers 05.30 08 Raiding the Keeper's Fortress 04.02 09 What Lies Before You 02.20 10 Immortality or Oblivion 04.18 11 Redemption and Finale 03.46 12 Prey Super Trailer (bonus track) 03.18PC System Requirements Minimum Operating System: Microsoft Windows 2000 or XPProcessor: Intel Pentium 4 2.0Ghz / AMD Athlon XP 2000Memory: 512MB system RAMGraphics Card: 100% DirectX 9.0c compatible 64MB video card with latest manufacturer driversHard Drive Space: 2.2GB of uncompressed free hard drive spaceSound Card: 100% DirectX 9.0c compatible 16-bit sound cardDirectX: DirectX 9.0c Recommended Processor: Intel Pentium 4 2.5Ghz / AMD Athlon XP 2500Memory: 1GB system RAMGraphics Card: ATI Radeon X800 series or higher video card with latest manufacturer driversSound Card: Creative Sound Blaster X-Fi series sound card.  Xbox 360 Game Installation Prey requires 5.0GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7754">Doom 3: Resurrection of Evil</game><game id="3407">Duke Nukem 3D</game><game id="1503">Aliens Versus Predator 2</game><game id="10047">Turok 3: Shadow of Oblivion</game><game id="13683">Quake 4</game><game id="15473">Metroid Prime</game><game id="20333">Geist</game><game id="11051">Turok</game><game id="1539">Half-Life 2</game><game id="21119">Wolfenstein</game><game id="21170">Portal</game><game id="17646">Unreal</game><game id="21169">Portal: Still Alive</game><game id="21478">Cryostasis</game><game id="17280">BioShock</game><game id="8870">System Shock 2</game><game id="20800">Dead Space</game><game id="11757">Crysis</game><game id="20721">Duke Nukem Forever</game><game id="35888">Hard Reset</game><game id="21507">Moon</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2226789-box_prey.png</image></root>