<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>164</id><name>NFL Football '94 Starring Joe Montana</name><description> FeaturesOn the gridiron, NFL Football '94 featured authentic team playbooks, an improved passing game and increased speed bursts leading to many games being offensive slug-fests.  Other in game features included audibles, screen passes, 360 degree spins, diving catches and instant replays. Thanks to the 16mb battery powered save feature, NFL Football '94 Starring Joe Montana allowed users to play an entire 16 game Football season including the playoffs and the Superbowl.  Users could select team schedules from the 1991, 1992 and 1993 seasons. Battery backup allowed users to track team standings as well as league leaders in passing, rushing, sacks, etc.   Stats were presented in a weekly round up made to look like the pages of a newspaper called 'SEGA Sports Page', This game introduced a lower viewing angle while playing offense referred to as ''Behind the QB'', which would soon become the standard viewing angle for most NFL Football video games.  The camera system also featured a action-zoom feature which was met with middling reactions.   The play calling in this game was provided by Lon Simmons the  legendary sportscaster for both San Francisco's NFL and MLB franchises, the 49ers and Giants respectively.Put On Your Game Face!As the game manual states; "You thought '93 was intense? Then NFL Football '94 Starring Joe Montana will really blow your dome!" </description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="21">Football</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12957">Madden NFL 96</game><game id="98">John Elway's Quarterback</game><game id="7715">Madden NFL '95</game><game id="7106">Madden NFL '94</game><game id="4511">John Madden Football '93</game><game id="17667">John Madden Football '92</game><game id="8417">NFL Blitz</game><game id="15179">Tecmo Super Bowl II: Special Edition</game><game id="27106">Joe Montana's NFL Football</game><game id="27133">Bill Walsh College Football</game><game id="29301">Joe Montana II: Sports Talk Football</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2371285-genesis_nflfootball94.jpg</image></root>