<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16436</id><name>Twisted Metal 2</name><description>OverviewTwisted Metal 2 is the second game in the Twisted Metal series, and was a huge success for the franchise as it was the most successful game in the series. In Twisted Metal 2, players are pitted against each other in a variety of arenas that span across the globe. Players have the choice of entering the story mode and competing against AI opponents or playing locally in versus mode. Each vehicle has its own unique firearms, and in addition players are able to obtain pick-ups that are scattered across the stages. Whoever manages to be the last man standing is declared the winner, giving the game a sort of survival of the fittest feel.The story follows up on the same general concept from the first game. A mysterious man named Calypso is the host of the Twisted Metal tournament, and several different individuals are going to compete in said tournament. The winner of the tournament is able to receive one wish, but it is common for Calypso to twist the wishes in such a way that the winner is left with an unfortunate demise.GameplayThe game’s gameplay is very similar to that of its predecessor. However, Twisted Metal 2 does feature many new notable gameplay mechanics. One addition is vehicle-common advanced moves. These moves allow players to press button combinations in order to perform special rechargeable maneuvers such as cloak , shield, and a napalm blast. Cars can catch on fire after being attacked with weapons such as napalm, which will slowly deteriorate their health. Health pick-ups allow players to heal themselves in a more sensible fashion than that of the first game.CharactersAxelOutlaw 2Axel - Imprisoned in a two wheeled vehicleGrasshopper - A dune buggy driven by Krista Sparks, the daughter of CalypsoHammerhead - A large monster truck driven by two teenage guysMinion - A tank driven by a demon from hellMr. Grimm - The motorcycle of the Grim ReaperMr. Slam - A front end loaderOutlaw 2 - A police carRoadkill - A car made of various parts driven by a homeless manShadow - A hearse, driven by MortimerSpectre - The sports car of movie actor Ken MastersSweet Tooth - An ice cream truck driven by a psychotic clownThumper - A pink lowrider driven by Bruce Cochrane, a gangster from South CentralTwister - A Formula-1 race carWarthog - Military Humvee driven by the 105 year old Captain RogersDark Tooth - A giant ice cream truck and the final boss of the game</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13200">Vigilante 8</game><game id="18499">Motor Mayhem</game><game id="10616">Streets of SimCity</game><game id="10553">Carmageddon II: Carpocalypse Now</game><game id="4315">WWE Crush Hour</game><game id="11124">Carmageddon TDR 2000</game><game id="22883">Red Asphalt</game><game id="14204">Mashed: Drive to Survive</game><game id="23277">Vigilante 8 Arcade</game><game id="9733">RoadKill</game><game id="12364">Battle Cars</game><game id="23527">Hardware 2</game><game id="16728">Powerslide</game><game id="7468">Vigilante 8: 2nd Offense</game><game id="2392">Rogue Trip: Vacation 2012</game><game id="12142">Full Auto 2: Battlelines</game><game id="25512">Clutch</game><game id="23930">Wild Metal</game><game id="5917">Cyber Sled</game><game id="16473">Breakneck</game><game id="9461">Critical Depth</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2011580-box_tmetal2.png</image></root>