<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16458</id><name>Jurassic Park Part 2: The Chaos Continues</name><description>OverviewThe original Jurassic Park games on Nintendo's platforms were a huge success. In response, Ocean, the development house responsible for the originalOne mission required you to defeat a t-rex. titles began work on a sequel. In 1994 The Chaos Continues was released for the Game Boy and Super Nintendo. For the new game, Ocean took a new design. Unlike the original games, which were all mainly top-down perspective games, The Chaos Continues was a side-scrolling shooter.SNES VersionThe version for the Super Nintendo was a fairly standard side-scroller. Upon starting a new game the player is confronted with a menu screen that gave him or her several missions to choose from. Completing one mission brought you back to select another. Finishing missions progressed the player through the game. The main plot was that the bio-engineering company Biosyn, rival to John Hammond's Ingen, dispatched troops to Isla Nublar to take control of the facilities and the dinosaurs.  Hammond asks Dr. Alan Grant and soldier Michael Wolfskin to head to the island and stop Biosyn.The game's arsenal consisted of a charging stun gun, machine guns, and shotguns. Utilizing the stun gun was an important factor in the game, because killing too many non-velociraptor enemies would result in the island's ecosystem being destroyed, sending you to the game over screen. Game Boy VersionThe Game Boy version was still a side-scrolling shooter, but it unfolded slightly differently. Abandoning the mission structure of the SNES version, the Game Boy version progressed strictly linearly. The game was divided into a series of similarly themed levels called zones. Most zones would have two levels whichThe GB version had a much different look than the SNES version. required you to gather a set number of key cards in order to open a gate at the end of the level, with the third level being a boss battle.Interspersed between these normal zones was the occasional t-rex zone, which required navigate a maze-like level while a tyrannosaurus chased you. Collecting all the keycards in these levels resulting in an extra continue.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4350">Contra</game><game id="2190">Gunstar Heroes</game><game id="847">Metal Slug</game><game id="17939">Konami Collector's Series: Castlevania &amp; Contra</game><game id="28508">Matt Hazard: Blood Bath And Beyond</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2363890-snes_jurassicparkii.jpg</image></root>