<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16457</id><name>Sid Meier's Civilization IV</name><description>OverviewSid Meier's Civilization IV is a turn-based 4X strategy game developed by Firaxis and published by 2K for the PC on October 25, 2005. The fourth installment of the Civilization franchise, Civilization IV builds upon the gameplay from Sid Meier's Civilization III, adding 3D graphics, a simpler user interface, reasonable (and more transparent) AI players, and other gameplay improvements (including the concept of religion, improved military unit promotions, the more flexible "civics" model (replacing the simple "governments" model), and the concept of "Great People").The game received two official expansions over two years: Sid Meier's Civilization IV: Warlords (adding gameplay mechanics based on war dominance) and Sid Meier's Civilization IV: Beyond the Sword (adding various new gameplay mechanics, from the concept of corporations to random events). Both expansions add new civilizations, leaders, units, and buildings. All the content from Warlords (with the exception of the expansion's scenarios) is included in Beyond the Sword (which also includes twelve custom mods, ranging from historically accurate to medieval fantasy to science fiction). An official standalone game was made using the game engine, dubbed Sid Meier's Civilization IV: Colonization, which remakes the 1995 game Sid Meier's Colonization.GameplayLeader TraitsEach leader in Civilization IV has 2 traits that reflect the leader's rule in history. There are 8 traits in the base game, and Warlords adds an additional 3.NameAttributesAggressiveMelee and gunpowder units receive Combat I promotion when builtConstruction speed doubled for Barracks and DrydockCreativeAdditional 2 culture per city.Construction speed doubled for Coliseum and Theater.ExpansiveAdditional 2 health per city.Construction speed doubled for Granary and Harbor.Financial1 extra commerce to tiles that have 2 commerce.Construction speed doubled for Banks.IndustriousWonder construction rate increased by 50%.Construction speed doubled for ForgeOrganizedExpense of Civic upkeep reduced by 50%.Construction speed doubled for Courthouse and Lighthouse.PhilosophicalBirth rate of Great People is doubled.Construction speed doubled for University.SpiritualNo AnarchyConstruction speed doubled for Temple.WondersCivilization IV features wonders of the world that any civilization can build that are separated into national and world wonders. World wonders can only be built once per game, while national Wonders can be built once by each nation or team. There are 46 wonders in total:World WondersStonehengeThe ParthenonThe Great LighthouseThe Great PyramidsThe OracleThe ColossusThe Hanging GardensThe Great LibraryThe Hagia SophiaChichen ItzaAngkor WatNotre DameSistine ChapelSpiral MinaretVersaillesHermitageTaj MahalStatue of LibertyThe PentagonThe Kremlin (Saint Basil's Cathedral is shown)Mount RushmoreBroadwayThe Manhattan ProjectThe Eiffel TowerRock N' RollThree Gorges DamHollywoodThe United NationsThe InternetThe Space Elevator7 of the World Wonders are religious shrines that can only be built in their respective Holy Cities:The Church of the NativityThe Temple of SolomonThe Kong MiaoThe Dai MiaoThe Masjid al-Haram (The Dome of the Rock is depicted)The Kashi VishwanathThe MahabodhiNational WondersNational EpicHeroic EpicGlobe TheatreOxford UniversityWest PointWall StreetIronworksScotland YardRed CrossCivilizationsThere are 18 Civilizations in Civilization IV, each with 1 or 2 leaders:CivilizationLeadersOther TraitsAmericaGeorge Washington: Financial, OrganizedFranklin Roosevelt: Industrious, OrganizedStarting Techs: Fishing, AgricultureUnique Unit: Navy SEAL (replaces Marine)Capital City: WashingtonArabiaSaladin: Philosophical, SpiritualStarting Techs: Mysticism, The WheelUnique Unit: Camel Archer (replaces Knight)Capital City: MeccaAztecsMontezuma: Aggressive, SpiritualStarting Techs: Mysticism, HuntingUnique Unit: Jaguar (replaces Swordsman)Capital City: TenochtitlanChinaMao Zedong: Philosophical, OrganizedQin Shi Huang: Industrious, FinancialStarting Techs: Agriculture, MiningUnique Unit: Cho-Ku-Nu (replaces Crossbowmen)Capital City: BeijingEgyptHatshepsut: Spiritual, CreativeStarting Techs: Agriculture, The WheelUnique Unit: War Chariot (replaces Chariot)Capital City: ThebesEnglandVictoria: Expansive, FinancialElizabeth: Philosophical, FinancialStarting Techs: Fishing, MiningUnique Unit: Redcoat (replaces Rifleman)Capital City: LondonFranceLouis XIV: Creative, IndustriousNapoleon Bonaparte: Aggressive, IndustriousStarting Techs: Agriculture, The WheelUnique Unit: Musketeer (replaces Musketman)Capital City: ParisGermanyFrederick II: Creative, PhilosophicalOtto von Bismarck: Expansive, IndustriousStarting Techs: Hunting, MiningUnique Unit: Panzer (replaces Tank)Capital City: BerlinGreeceAlexander: Aggressive, PhilosophicalStarting Techs: Fishing, HuntingUnique Unit: Phalanx (replaces Spearman)Capital City: AthensIncaHuayna Capac: Aggressive, FinancialStarting Techs: Agriculture, MysticismUnique Unit: Quechua (replaces Warrior)Capital City: CuzcoIndiaMahatma Gandhi: Industrious, SpiritualAsoka: Organized, SpiritualStarting Techs: Agriculture, MysticismUnique Unit: Fast Worker (replaces Worker)Capital City: DelhiJapanTokugawa Ieyasu: Aggressive, OrganizedStarting Techs: Fishing. The WheelUnique Unit: Samurai (replaces Maceman)Capital City: KyotoMaliMansa Musa: Financial, SpiritualStarting Techs: Mining, The WheelUnique Unit: Skirmisher (replaces Archer)Capital City: TimbuktuMongoliaGenghis Khan: Aggressive, ExpansiveKublai Khan: Aggressive, CreativeStarting Techs: Hunting, The WheelUnique Unit: Keshik (replaces Horse Archer)Capital City: KarakorumPersiaCyrus the Great: Expansive, CreativeStarting Techs: Agriculture, HuntingUnique Unit: Immortal (replaces Chariot)Capital City: PersepolisRomeJulius Caesar: Organized, ExpansiveStarting Techs: Fishing, MiningUnique Unit: Praetorian (replaces Swordsman)Capital City: RomeRussiaCatherine: Creative, FinancialPeter I: Expansive, PhilosophicalStarting Techs: Hunting, MiningUnique Unit: Cossack (replaces Knight)Capital City: MoscowSpainIsabella - Expansive, SpiritualStarting Techs: Fishing, MysticismUnique Unit: Conquistador (replaces Knight)Capital City: MadridPitBoss ServerThe Civilization IV PitBoss is basically a dedicated server for multiplayer Civilization IV matches. The PitBoss server didn't ship with the original game, but was later made available and updated versions have been included with both of the game's expansions. PitBoss games work in one of two modes. If everyone is connected at the same time it works exactly like any other multiplayer game. However, if one or more players are not connected the game will wait for those players to take their turns before continuing. The only time a player might be skipped is if the game has a turn timer enabled and the missing player does not take their turn within the alloted amount of time.Despite requiring that the game and any expansions you wish to use be installed, the PitBoss server does not use the game's normal user interface. Instead a slimmed down interface, that looks similar to any other standard Windows application, is presented for starting and maintaining games. Once the PitBoss server has been started the game's admin can start a new game using any mod, map or game type or load an existing game from a save made from either the PitBoss or a regular multiplayer game.WarlordsThe first expansion for Civilization IV, Warlords, was announced on 16 March, 2006. It adds 3 new leader traits, 6 new civilizations, 10 new leaders (including 4 for existing civilizations), 3 new wonders, 9 new units, and unique buildings for all the civilizations. Also added was the vassal state mechanic where defeated civilizations can act as a tributary to the victor, biding its time to rise again.Civilization IV: Warlords was released on 24 July, 2006 in America and July 28, 2006 worldwide.Beyond the SwordAnnounced 28 March, 2007, the second expansion, Beyond the Sword, focuses on the late game. It introduces Corporations, a late game alternative to religion, and adds new units, buildings, and technologies to the post Gunpowder eras. It also adds 10 new civilizations, 16 new leaders (6 for existing civilizations), 5 new wonders, 16 new buildings, 23 new units, and 6 new technologies. Also included are 11 new scenarios, ranging from medieval to science fiction.Civilization IV: Beyond the Sword was released 23 July, 2007 in America.ColonizationCivilization IV: Colonization is a special standalone expansion, a remake of the old 1994 game Colonization in the Civilization IV engine. Announced 9 June, 2008, it focuses on the European colonization of the New World. Players play as one of the colonies, struggling both against the natives and their colonial masters back home. Players win by declaring independence and fighting off the European armies trying to take back their colonies.Civilization IV: Colonization was released 22 September, 2008 in America.System RequirementsPC MinimumPC RecommendedOS: Windows 2000/XP/Vista/7Processor: 1.2GHz Intel Pentium 4 or AMD Athlon processor or equivalentMemory: 256MB RAMVideo: 64 MB Video Card w/ Hardware TL (GeForce 2/Radeon 7500 or better)Sound: DirectX7 compatible sound cardHDD: 1.7GB of free hard drive spaceSoftware: DirectX9.0cOS: Windows 2000/XP/Vista/yProcessor: 1.8GHz Intel Pentium 4 or AMD Athlon processor or equivalent/betterMemory: 512 MB RAMVideo: 128 MB Video Card w/ DirectX 8 support (pixel and vertex shaders)Sound: DirectX7 compatible sound cardHDD: 1.7GB of free hard drive spaceSoftware: DirectX9.0cMac MinimumMac RecommendedOS: Mac OS X 10.5.8 or higherProcessor: Intel chipsetCPU Speed: 1.8 GHzMemory: 512 MB RAMHard Disk Space: 3.5 GB free disk spaceVideo Card: (ATI): Radeon 9600 Video Card (NVidia): GeForce FX 5200Video Memory: (VRam): 64 MB or higherMultiplayer: Internet (TCP/IP) and LAN (TCP/IP) play supported. Internet play requires broadband connection.Media Required: DVD Drive Supported Video cards: NVIDIA GeForce 5200, 6600, 6800, 7800 ATI Radeon 9600, 9650, 9700, 9800, X600, X800, X850, X1600OS: Mac OS X 10.5.8 or higherProcessor: Intel chipsetCPU Speed: 2.0 GHzMemory: 512 MB RAMHard Disk Space: 3.5 GB free disk spaceVideo Card: (ATI): Radeon 9600 Video Card (NVidia): GeForce FX 5200Video Memory: (VRam): 128 MB RAMMultiplayer: Internet (TCP/IP) and LAN (TCP/IP) play supported. Internet play requires broadband connection.Media Required: DVD Drive Supported Video cards: NVIDIA GeForce 5200, 6600, 6800, 7800 ATI Radeon 9600, 9650, 9700, 9800, X600, X800, X850, X1600NOTICE: This game is not supported on volumes formatted as Mac OS Extended (Case Sensitive).TriviaThe theme to Civilization IV "Baba Yetu" was the first, and so far only piece of music composed for a video game to win a Grammy Award in 2011.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="8">Educational</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19887">Rome: Total War</game><game id="4685">Medieval II: Total War</game><game id="20509">Empire: Total War</game><game id="12343">Call to Power II</game><game id="12379">Sid Meier's Alpha Centauri</game><game id="9264">Rome: Total War - Barbarian Invasion</game><game id="11993">Rise of Nations</game><game id="21645">Europa Universalis: Rome</game><game id="9115">Sins of a Solar Empire</game><game id="14391">Heroes of Might and Magic: A Strategic Quest</game><game id="11342">Master of Orion</game><game id="5822">Star Wars: Rebellion</game><game id="7419">Master of Orion 3</game><game id="21592">Galactic Civilizations II: Twilight of the Arnor</game><game id="19549">Freeciv</game><game id="17753">Europa Universalis II: Asia Chapters</game><game id="5861">Galactic Civilizations II</game><game id="19829">Europa Universalis II</game><game id="19390">Conquest of the New World</game><game id="21663">Galactic Civilizations II: Dark Avatar</game><game id="13710">Chaos Overlords</game><game id="14139">Spore</game><game id="15262">Imperium Romanum</game><game id="24092">Sins of a Solar Empire: Entrenchment</game><game id="24522">Dominions: Priests, Prophets, and Pretenders</game><game id="20674">StarCraft II: Wings of Liberty</game><game id="942">Genghis Khan</game><game id="29207">Europa Universalis: For the Glory</game><game id="8349">Hearts of Iron</game><game id="30965">Lord of Ultima</game><game id="4686">Waterloo: Napoleon's Last Battle</game><game id="3750">Sid Meier's Civilization</game><game id="19287">Sid Meier's Civilization IV: Beyond the Sword</game><game id="217">Sid Meier's Civilization II</game><game id="1594">Sid Meier's Civilization III</game><game id="24079">StarCraft II: Legacy of the Void</game><game id="35522">Reign: Conflict of Nations</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2492897-box_civ4.png</image></root>