<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16473</id><name>Breakneck</name><description> EU Box OverviewOriginally released in                  Europe as N.I.C.E. 2, this sequel to                 Have A N.I.C.E. Day! gives players access to more than 40 cars and 24 tracks, each featuring multiple unique variations. The game includes two distinct styles of    US Back     play, a fairly standard simulation racing experience and another arcade racing mode that includes light                vehicular combat elements. This mode does not feature               power ups in the traditional              Mario Kart style, but rather gives the player a loadout of weapons to cycle through at their discretion.  Vehicles Breakneck has a very unique selection of             vehicles, many of which are modeled after real world cars such as the Porsche 911 and Ford         Mustang. The game does not feature licensed cars. Players have access to anything from a small            go-kart to a           monster truck or large          tour bus, though in the arcade mode, selection is limited to more comparably sized cars. In the straight racing mode, all types of vehicles can be on the track at once, creating a unique driving experience. The game features         damage modeling for every vehicle, putting it ahead of the        Gran Turismo series, and also includes multiple paint schemes for many cars.   Locations Many of the track locations in the game, such as Corsica, are based on real-life places, though for the most part the tracks do not mirror any actual         roads. Each track has a few unique options like a reverse mode, and most can be played in either the arcade or simulation mode.  PC System RequirementsCategoryRequirement Processor: Pentium II, 233 MHz or equivalent RAM: 32 MB Video Memory: 4 MB Hard Disk Space: 120 MB</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2000">Midtown Madness</game><game id="20415">Midtown Madness 2</game><game id="12359">Midtown Madness 3</game><game id="12318">Twisted Metal</game><game id="16436">Twisted Metal 2</game><game id="4635">Twisted Metal III</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/89246/1698397-2360497220103374198s425x425q85.jpg</image></root>