<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16492</id><name>Burnout Revenge</name><description>OverviewReleased by  Criterion Games for  PS2 and  Xbox on September 13, 2005, Burnout Revenge puts a little more emphasis on the arcade style of the  Burnout series. Revenge features some new additions as well as some tweaking to gameplay modes found in earlier Burnout titles. In this game racers can, for the first time, ram same way traffic into other racers to get a “Takedown”, the quickest and most entertaining way of gaining points and boost in the game. This traffic checking effectively lets ram through traffic turns other cars into tools of destruction rather than a nuisance to maneuver around. Players can also rain hell down upon opponents through vertical takedowns, done through going off ramps and landing on top of others.In terms of gameplay modes, Revenge more-or-less follows the precedent set by its predecessor Takedown. However, a new mode is added in Revenge, called "Traffic Attack". In this mode, players use same way traffic ramming to accumulate points. Changes to the series' Crash mode are also made in Revenge, though the premise is basically the same.In single-player, drivers compete in a world tour of 169 events traversing three continents in ten different ranks. Completing events increases the player's rank and unlocks new events as a result. Revenge also features online support where players can either do traditional races or compete in Crash modes to see who can cause the most destruction in intersections and gain the most points as a result.Xbox 360 ReleaseXbox 360 Version with more damage model.On March 7th, 2006, Criterion released the game on the  Xbox 360. It was the first game to take advantage of kiosk downloads in  North America. Players would be able to take their memory unit to a retailer (Best Buy, GameStop, and Circuit City) and get a car detailed with the specific retailer's decals. The game also has seven other sponsored vehicles available for download on the  Xbox Live Marketplace.The most recent full release,  Burnout Paradise, deviated slightly from the original formula by moving to an open world. For this reason, many still played Revenge on the Xbox 360 after  Burnout Paradise's release.EventsWorld TourRace - Race against rivals as you rampage though the tracks in an explosive race to the finish line.Traffic Attack - Traffic Check vehicles to keep the clock ticking in a boost-blasting scramble to beat time targets.Burning Lap - Drive around the track to as fast as possible to beat the clock.Road Rage - Takedown as many rivals as you can within the time limit but watch out for critical damage to your ride.Eliminator - A race around the track as a rival in last place has 30 second to escape or they are eliminated.Preview - Test drive some of the fastest vehicles in Burnout Revenge against the clock.Grand Prix - Finish in a medal-winning position in this insane Grand Prix multi-race battle to pick up GP points.Crash Events - Unleash hell though the streets in an explosive mayhem and nail the target vehicle.Split-Screen MultiplayerCrash Battle - See who can rack up the biggest pile-up in this head-to-head competition.Crash Party - Who can wreak the most havoc in a single junction?Online MultiplayerCrash Battle (read above on Split-Screen Multiplayer)Crash Party (read above on Split-Screen Multiplayer)Crash TourVehiclesRaceNameCrash BreakerWeightBoost SpeedScreenshotFactory M-Type STLevel 1Light160mphFactory M-Type STFactory R160 STLevel 1Light160mphFactory R160 STModified M-Type STLevel 2Light165mphModified M-Type STModified R165 STLevel 2Light165mphModified R165 STCustom M-TypeLevel 3Light170mph Works M-Type STLevel 3Light170mph Custom R170 STLevel 3Super Light170mph Works R170 STLevel 3Light170mph Prototype M-Series STLevel 4Super Light175mph Limited M-Type STLevel 4Light175mph Prototype R175 STLevel 4Super Light175mph Limited R175 STLevel 4Super Light175mph Tuned M-Type STLevel 5Light180mph Criterion M-Type STLevel 3Light180mph Tuned R180 STLevel 5Super Light180mph Criterion R180 STLevel 5Light180mph Factory M-Type DXLevel 6Light185mph Modified M-Type DXLevel 6Light185mph Factory R185 DXLevel 6Light185mph Modified R185 DXLevel 6Super Light185mph Custom M-Type DXLevel 7Light190mph Works M-Type DXLevel 7Light190mph Limited M-Type DXLevel 7Light190mph Custom R185 DXLevel 7Super Light190mph Works R185 DXLevel 7Super Light190mph Limited R180 DXLevel 7Super Light190mph Tuned M-Type DXLevel 8Light195mph Prototype M-Series DXLevel 8Light195mph Criterion M-Type DXLevel 8Light195mph Tuned R195 DXLevel 8Super Light195mph Prototype R195 DXLevel 8Super Light195mph Criterion R195 DXLevel 8Light195mph Factory M-Type GTLevel 9Light202mph Custom M-Type GTLevel 1Light202mph Modified M-Type GTLevel 9Light202mph Works M-TypeLevel 9Light202mph Factory R190 GTLevel 9Light202mph Custom R202 GTLevel 9Super Light202mph Modified R202 GTLevel 9Super Light202mph Works R202 GTLevel 9Super Light202mph Tuned M-Type GTLevel 10Light205mph Prototype M-Series GTLevel 10Light205mph Criterion M-Type GTLevel 1Light205mph Limited M-Type GTLevel 10Light205mph Tuned R205 GTLevel 10Super Light205mph Prototype R205 GTLevel 10Super Light205mph Criterion R205 GTLevel 10Light205mph Limited R205 GTLevel 10Light205mph Low RiderLevel 10Medium209mph Revenge RacerLevel 10Super Light209mph Black Elite RacerLevel 10Light209mph Logitech World RacerLevel 10Light209mph Hot RodLevel 10Light209mph Nixon SpecialLevel 10Super Light205mph Custom ClassicLevel 10Super Light209mph Euro Classic LMLevel 10Super Light209mph EA Racer GTLevel 10Super Light209mph Criterion Racer GTLevel 10Super Light209mph Etnies RacerLevel 10Medium209mph CrashNameCrash BreakerWeightBoost SpeedScreenshotStock C170 MidLevel 4Medium170mph Stock C175 SuperLevel 6Heavy170mph Compact C180 LiteLevel 5Medium180mph Compact C185 SuperLevel 6Medium185mph Sport C180 LiteLevel 8Super Heavy180mph Sport C190 SuperLevel 7Super Heavy190mph SUV C150 HVYLevel 7Super Heavy150mph SUV C160 SuperLevel 8Super Heavy160mph Saloon C175 MidLevel 7Heavy175mph Saloon C180 SuperLevel 8Heavy180mph 4x4 C165 MidLevel 6Heavy170mph 4x4 C180 SuperLevel 7Heavy180mph Off Road C170 MidLevel 8Super Heavy170mph Off Road C180 SuperLevel 9Super Heavy180mph Utility C140 HVYLevel 8Super Heavy140mph Utility C150 SuperLevel 9Super Heavy150mph Classic Crasher C170Level 10Medium170mph Dominator AssassinLevel 6Medium160mph Madden Challenge BusLevel 7Super Heavy140mph Mobile DinerLevel 10Super Heavy140mph Xbox 360 DLC and KioskThe DLC and Kiosk cars are free and only available in Xbox 360 version. They either be downloaded on the Xbox LIVE Marketplace or by downloading them from a Participating Retailers Kiosk. After download, they are only available by unlocking then though the World Tour.NameTypeCrash BreakerWeightBoost SpeedScreenshotAlienware CarRaceLevel 10Light209mph Dolby CarRaceLevel 10 209mph Plantronics CarRaceLevel 10Super Light209mph Spike TV CarRaceLevel 10Light209mph Xbox LIVE CarRaceLevel 10Super Light209mph Circuit City CarRaceLevel 10Light209mph BestBuy CarRaceLevel 10Medium209mph Gamespot CarRaceLevel 10Light209mph Monster CarCrashLevel 10Super Heavy150mph Yellowcard CarCrashLevel 10Super Heavy150mph LocationsUSAMotor CitySunshine KeysLone PeakAngel ValleyEuropeEternal CityWhite MountainAsiaCentral RouteEastern BayRanksThe single player portion of the game features ranks to signify the player's progress in the game. First off, a player can earn up to five stars in each event; * (OK), ** (Good), *** (Great), **** (Awesome), ***** (Perfect). Only by getting a four star rating for your event performance and a gold medal can the player get five stars for the event. So essentially a gold medal gives you one more star, a silver none, and a bronze will subtract one. The stars received in the event will be subtracted from the amount need to reach the next rank.Stars needed to get to each rankRank 1: HarmlessRank 2: Unsafe - 20 starsRank 3: Reckless - 24 starsRank 4: Offensive - 28 starsRank 5: Fearless - 34 starsRank 6: Dangerous - 42 starsRank 7: Insane - 50 starsRank 8: Maniac - 58 starsRank 9: Assassin - 67 starsRank 10: Dominator - 77 starsRank 11: Elite - 148 starsStars available on each rank levelRank 1: 60 starsRank 2: 70 starsRank 3: 70 starsRank 4: 75 starsRank 5: 80 starsRank 6: 80 starsRank 7: 90 starsRank 8: 90 starsRank 9: 115 starsRank 10: 115 starsThis means that you need 548 stars out of the 845 stars in the game to reach the "Elite" rank.Challenge SheetsSunshine KeysGet triple paybackWin a race without crashingDo a vertical TakedownDo 2 revenge Takedowns in a raceTakedown a special carCheck 100 vehicles in Traffic AttackBlow up 25 vehiclesHigh score target: $3,000,000Car unlocked for completing Challenge Sheet: Custom ClassicMotor CityGet 4-way paybackWin a race without crashingDo a vertical TakedownDo 3 revenge Takedowns in a raceTakedown a special carCheck 50 vehicles in Traffic AttackBlow up 25 vehiclesHigh score target: $10,000,000Car unlocked for completing Challenge Sheet: Etnies RacerAngel ValleyGet double paybackWin a race without crashingDo a vertical TakedownDo 1 revenge Takedowns in a raceTakedown a special carCheck 100 vehicles in Traffic AttackBlow up 35 vehiclesHigh score target: $15,000,000Car unlocked for completing Challenge Sheet: Low RiderLone PeakGet triple paybackWin a race without crashingDo a vertical TakedownDo 2 revenge Takedowns in a raceTakedown a special carCheck 30 vehicles in Traffic AttackBlow up 25 vehiclesHigh score target: $6,500,000Car unlocked for completing Challenge Sheet: Hot RodEternal CityGet double paybackWin a race without crashingDo a vertical TakedownDo 2 revenge Takedowns in a raceTakedown a special carCheck 70 vehicles in Traffic AttackBlow up 15 vehiclesHigh score target: $5,000,000Car unlocked for completing Challenge Sheet: Euro Classic LMWhite MountainGet explosive paybackWin a race without crashingDo a vertical TakedownDo 1 revenge Takedown in a raceTakedown a special carCheck 50 vehicles in Traffic AttackBlow up 20 vehiclesHigh score target: $10,000,000Car unlocked for completing Challenge Sheet: Criterion GT RacerCentral RouteGet explosive paybackWin a race without crashingDo a vertical TakedownDo 1 revenge Takedowns in a raceTakedown a special carCheck 70 vehicles in Traffic AttackBlow up 22 vehiclesHigh score target: $8,000,000Car unlocked for completing Challenge Sheet: EA GT RacerEastern BayGet 4-way paybackWin a race without crashingDo a vertical TakedownDo 3 revenge Takedowns in a raceTakedown a special carCheck 90 vehicles in Traffic AttackBlow up 24 vehiclesHigh score target: $6,500,000Car unlocked for completing Challenge Sheet: Nixon SpecialSignature TakedownsSunshine KeysStrike!Game description: Slam a rival into the bowling alleyLocation: ReverseCatch Of The DayGame description: Get a Signature Takedown in the marinaLocation: ReverseSunk  DisorderlyGame description: Hit a rival into the boat stackLocation: ReverseMotor CityAlley Ooops!Game description: Score a Signature Takedown in the alleywaysLocation: Short ReverseCrane In The NeckGame description: Hit a rival into the dockside cranesLocation: Long ReverseSerial PillerGame description: Get a Signature Takedown into the pillars under the freewayLocation: Long ReverseAngle ValleyTake-Out TakedownGame description: Hit a rival into the giant burger signLocation: ForwardsTerminatedGame description: Hit a rival into the walls of the storm drainLocation: ReverseTakin' Out The TrashGame description: Smash a rival into the dumpsters in the back alleysLocation: ReverseLone PeakLumber PartyGame description: Slam a rival into the logging machineryLocation: ReverseDe-RailedGame description: Get a Signature Takedown near the old Lone Peak RailroadLocation: Long ForwardTrailer CrashGame description: Hit a rival into the trailers in the trailer parkLocation: ReverseEternal CityElevated ActionGame description: Slam a rival under the raised covered pathwayLocation: Long ReverseArch EnemiesGame description: Hit a rival into the columns between the four archesLocation: Long ReverseStairs In Their EyesGame description: Get a Signature Takedown on the dividing wall, heading up the stepsLocation: Long ReverseWhite MountainCliffhangerGame description: Get a Signature Takedown over the cliff edge in the open tunnel sectionLocation: ReverseRock The ClockGame description: Get a Signature Takedown near the opening in the clock towerLocation: ForwardsBridge OutGame description: Hit a rival off the broken bridgeLocation: ForwardsCentral RouteDepot-LitionGame description: Hit a rival into the bus stationLocation: ForwardsTramapolineGame description: Smash a rival into the tram line stopsLocation: Long ReverseEnter The DragonGame description: Get a Signature Takedown in the alley with the neon dragon signLocation: Long ReverseEastern BayDestruction SiteGame description: Hit a rival into the freeway construction siteLocation: Long ForwardsHair-PinnedGame description: Get a Signature Takedown on the hairpin bend of Lower Link courseLocation: Lower Link ForwardsPillar Of StrengthGame description: Hit a rival into the monorail supportsLocation: Lower Link ForwardsSoundtrackSongArtistAlbum"Almost Here"The Academy Is...Almost Here"Top of the World"The-All America RejectMove Along"Come On"Andy Hunter*Life"Bundy"Animal AlphaPheromones"Life Burns!"ApocalypticaApocalyptica"Flyover"Asian Dub FoundationTank"Beast and the Harlot"Avenged SevenfoldCity if Evil"Red Flag"Billy TalentBilly Talent II"Fear and Loathing"The Black VelvetsThe Black Velvets"Helicopter"Bloc PartySilent Alarm"An Honest Mistake"(Superdiscount Remix)The Bravey "Break on Through" (To the Other Side) (BT Remix)BT vs. The Doors "Hand of Blood"Bullet for My ValentineHand of Blood"The Big Jump"The Chemical BrothersPush the Button"As the Tables Turn"CKYAn Answer Can be Found"Wake the Dead"Comeback KidWake the Dead"Riot Radio"The Dead 60sThe Dead 60s"Tuned to a Different Station"DogsTurn Against This Land"The Hey Man!"EmanuelSoundtrack to a Headrush"Dance, Dance"Fall Out BoyFrom Under the Cork Tree"Ink"FinchSay Hello to Sunshine"All the Rage"Funeral for a FriendHours"I Want"GoldfingerDisconnection Notice"Better World" (Adam Freeland Remix)Mindless Self IndulgenceStraight To Video: The Remixes"Today"Junkie XLToday"Daft Punk Is Playing At My House" (Soulwaz Shibuya Remix)LCD Soundsystem "Apply Some Pressure"Maximo ParkA Certain Trigger"Straight to Video" (KMFDM Remix)Mindless Self IndulgenceStraight To Video: The Remixes"Nü Rock"MorningwoodMorningwood"Heard That Sound"MxPxPanic"Shot Down"Nine Black AlpsEverything Is"Do What You Want"OK GoOh No"Shotgun"The OutlineYou Smash It, We'll Build Around It"Stand Up"PennywiseThe Fuse"The World"The Starting LineBased on a True Story"Lullaby"ThriceVheissu"First Day" (General Midi Remix)Timo MaasPictures"Band-Girls-Money"TsarBand-Girls-Money"F.I.G.H.T."Unwritten LawHere's to the Mourning"The Great Escape"We Are ScientistsWith Love and Squalor"Lights and Sounds"YellowcardLights and SoundsXbox 360 Game InstallationBurnout Revenge requires 4.4GB of space to install on an Xbox 360  HDD.Xbox 360 Games on DemandOn August 25, 2009, Burnout Revenge became available on the Xbox 360's Games on Demand service. It costs $19.99 or 1600  Microsoft Points.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6836">FlatOut: Ultimate Carnage</game><game id="12142">Full Auto 2: Battlelines</game><game id="12976">Need for Speed: Most Wanted</game><game id="21606">Crash Time: Autobahn Pursuit</game><game id="13776">Destruction Derby 2</game><game id="7019">Ridge Racer V</game><game id="10124">Midnight Club: Street Racing</game><game id="21307">Juiced 2: Hot Import Nights</game><game id="14204">Mashed: Drive to Survive</game><game id="9813">Crashday</game><game id="16728">Powerslide</game><game id="689">Jak X: Combat Racing</game><game id="20957">Pure</game><game id="20998">FlatOut: Head On</game><game id="453">Need for Speed: High Stakes</game><game id="25627">Smash Cars</game><game id="24793">MotorStorm</game><game id="20451">MotorStorm: Pacific Rift</game><game id="20698">Wheelman</game><game id="20418">Midnight Club II</game><game id="5875">Midnight Club 3: DUB Edition</game><game id="20927">Midnight Club: Los Angeles</game><game id="21114">Midnight Club: Los Angeles Remix</game><game id="25523">Split/Second</game><game id="31698">Need for Speed: Hot Pursuit</game><game id="34090">Ridge Racer Unbounded</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2116200-box_boutrev.png</image></root>