<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16511</id><name>Dungeons &amp; Dragons Online: Stormreach</name><description>OverviewThe famous table top game Dungeons and Dragons gets the MMO treatment in the form of Dungeons and Dragons Online: Stormreach. Based loosely on the ADD 3.5 ruleset, set in the Eberron campaign setting, DD Online stays true to the formula by sticking to dungeon raiding, dice rolling, and loot gaining.Updates are released in Modules, in the same form as the table top game. Subscription comes in the form of monthly fees as well as free to play with VIP services. Also the game is free to play now, with currency in the form of turbine points. These points allow you to buy extra races, faster leveling, etc. You can either get these points while playing the game or buy them with real currency.In August 2010, the European service was shut down under Codemasters and players in were moved over to the new Global DDO service under Turbine.RacesDrowCharacter selection from the free to play betaThe Drow are similar to other elves but have greater intelligence and charisma. They also have a spell resistance racial that makes them harder to hit with enemy spells. Drow are considered the dark cousins of the elves. While most Drow decide to live underground or in the wild away from civilization, some Drow have emerged to join with society and mingle with other races.Drow start with a higher dexterity, intelligence, and charisma, while having to have a lower constitution for balance. Since they are burdened with a lower constitution, they have fewer hit points then other classes.Favored Class: WizardRacial Abilities2 Dexterity, 2 Intelligence, 2 Charisma, -2 Constitution: Also known as dark elves, drow are nimble, clever, and magnetic, but physically delicate.Magical Defense: Drow are immune to magic sleep effects, and they gain a 2 bonus to saves against Enchantment spells.2 Bonus on Listen, Search and Spot: A Drow's senses are extremely sensitive.Bonus Weapon Proficiency Feats: Drow are proficient with rapiers, shortsword, and shuriken.DwarfDwarves are extremely tough and hardy, naturally resistant to many forms of magic attributes, and sturdy on their feet. However, they are not as charismatic as other races. Dwarves are considered a proud folk that often live in massive caverns and strongholds made of stone, which comes straight from their ancestral mountain ranges. The other races consider the Dwarves materialistic, but the Dwarves themselves would say they just love fine craftsmanship, whether that be weapons, jewelry, or stonework.Dwarves start with higher constitution and lower charisma. Their strength lies in their resistance to poison and many enemy spells, receiving various bonuses when fighting certain types of creatures, and being harder to trip or knockdown than other races.Favored Class: FighterRacial Abilities2 Composition, -2 Charisma: Dwarves are stout and tough, but tend to be gruff and reserved.2 bonus to Search checks: The Stonecunning ability gives the dwarf a sixth sense about stonework.4 bonus to Balance checks: Dwarves are exceptionally stable on their feet.2 bonus to saves against poisons: Dwarves are hardy and resistant to toxins.2 bonus to saves against magic: Dwarves have an innate ability resistance to magic spellsDwarven Waraxes: Dwarves that have martial weapon proficiency receive proficiency in the Dwarven Waraxes, an exotic weapon, for free.ElfElves are very dexterous, have keen senses and a resistance to enhancements, but are less hardy than other races. The Elves have a extremely rich and ancient culture, thus making them more willing to learn about the ancient ancestors and appreciate the accomplishments they have completed so they can be proud of where they came from. Most elves are at peace with nature, often dwelling in peaceful forest homes high in the trees.Elves start with higher dexterity and lower constitution. Their strengths are their resistance to enemy enhancement spells, and keen senses to allow them to spot hidden traps, doors, and hiding enemies better than other races. Their weakness is having lower hit points than other races due to their low constitution.Favored Class: Ranger or WizardRacial Abilities2 Dexterity, -2 Constitution: Elves are graceful but frail, and are better at taking the stealth and archery approach.Immune to magic sleeping effects and 2 bonus to saves against Enhancement spells: Elves do not sleep, but meditate in a deep trance in order to rest.2 bonus to Listen, Search, and Spot checks: An Elf's senses are very sensitive.Bonus Martial Weapon Proficiency Feats: Elves are proficient with the longsword, rapier, longbow, and shortbow.HalflingHalflings are very agile race, but because of their small stature they are not as strong as other races. They are naturally good at hiding and using throwing weapons, while being a bit luckier than the other races. Halflings are a diminutive people with great spirit and tenacity, thus making them very adaptable by learning to use their small stature to their advantage, often overcoming huge obstacles in resourceful ways.Halflings start with higher dexterity and lower strength. Their strengths are a luck bonus to saves, a bonus to attack and defense due to small size, bonuses to jump and move silently skills, and bonuses when using thrown weapons. However, their small size gives them less strength.Favored Class: RogueRacial Abilities2 Dexterity, -2 Strength: Halflings are quick, agile, and good with ranged weapons, but are not as strong as other humanoids.1 Armor Class Bonus, 1 attack roll bonus, 4 to Hide checks, and 3/4 carrying limit: As small creatures, Halflings are harder to hit and can hide better, but can't carry as much as other races.2 Bonus on Jump, Listen and Move Silently checks: Halflings are surefooted and nimble.1 bonus on all saves and 2 bonus to saves against Fear: Halflings are surprisingly capable of avoiding mishap.1 attack roll bonus with thrown weapons: Throwing stones is a universal sport among halflings and they have excellent aim.HumanVersatility is the greatest strength of all Humans, thus making them proficient in any of the classes. They are most adaptable of all of all the races and live in all sorts of environments. Although considered short-lived by the other races, humans have more ambition and drive than most, and with work, they can achieve success in whatever they set their minds to.Humans start with a bonus feat and, on average, are able to learn more skills than any other races as they level up. Their strength is their versatility and increased capacity to learn skills, and they have no weaknesses.Favored Class: NoneRacial Abilities1 bonus feat at first level: Humans are quick to master specialized tasks and are varied in their talents.4 extra skill points at first level and 1 extra skill point at each additional level: Humans are versatile and capable.WarforgedWarforged are sturdy creatures of living wood and metal and are immune to many dangers that plague the other races. They have less capacity for wisdom, and because of being so different from others, they have a difficulty connecting with other races. Warforged begin their lives in amazing creation forges built by the most skilled engineers. They are not completely like other living beings, but are far from being robotic structures. Being originally built for battle, the Warforged are trying to adapt to normal life.Warforged start with higher constitution and lower wisdom and charisma. They are naturally immune to many effects including poison, disease, and paralysis, and they can be healed by wizard or sorcerer repair spells. They receive significantly less healing from heal spells.Favored Class: Barbarian or FighterRacial Abilities2 Constitution, -2 Wisdom, -2 Charisma: Warforged are resilient and powerful, but their difficulty in relating to other creatures makes them seem aloof or even hostile.Immune to poison, sleep effects, paralysis, disease, nausea, fatigue, exhaustion: As living constructs, warforged have a natural immunity to the sickened condition.Stabilized by Repair skill, Repair Damage Spells regenerate, Positive energy healing spells are half as effective: Damage dealt to a warforged can be healed by Repair Damage spells and warforged are stabilized by the Repair skill, however, Cure and Heal spells and potions only provide half their normal effect.2 armor bonus and 5% chance arcane spell failure: The Composite Plating used to build a warforged takes the place of armor or robes and interferes slightly with spell casting.Light Fortification: There is a 25% chance that when a critical hit or sneak attack is scored, it is negated and damage is rolled normally.System RequirementsMinimum System RequirementsO.S.: Windows® XPProcessor: P4 1.6 GHz or AMD equivalent with SSEMemory: 512 MB RAMGraphicsCard: 64 MB Hardware TL -compatible video cardNetworkConnection: 56.6 K modemDirectX: DirectX 9.0cDiscSpace: 3GB, 5GB for high resolutionRecommended System RequirementsO.S.: Windows® XP/VistaProcessor: P4 3.0GHz or AMD equivalent with SSEMemory: 1GB RAMGraphics Card: GeForce FX or better with 128MB of memoryNetwork Connection: Cable Modem or DSL connectionDirectX: DirectX 9.0cDisc Space: 3GB, 5GB for high resolution</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12376">The Lord of the Rings Online: Shadows of Angmar</game><game id="32295">EverQuest: House of Thule</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1992/1516929-dndo.jpg</image></root>