<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16534</id><name>Neverwinter Nights: Shadows of Undrentide</name><description>OverviewShadows of Undrentide is the first expansion to    Neverwinter Nights and it features a new story with new characters; the story will move on to the game's second expansion,     Hordes of the Underdark.Summarization of Added ContentFive New Prestige Classes: Arcane Archer, Assassin, Blackguard, Harper Scout, and Shadowdancer.New creatures, feats, skills, spells, monsters.Ability to alter your henchman's inventory.    CharactersDeekin Scalesinger rockin' his... guitar-thingyDeekin ScalesingerDeekin is a member of the kobold clan "Dripping Fang". Unlike most kobolds, Deekin is not satisfied with looting and stealing. His greatest wish is to become a bard and write an epic saga that will stand the test of time. Seeing as most kobolds are anything but "epic", Deekin has decided to look for a hero more fitting of his talents.  Drogan DrogansonThe mentor of the protagonist of SoU.  He tasks the player with recovering the artifacts while he recovers his health after an attack early in the story.  Later, he teleports and meets the player in a ruin and helps him activate a portal.  He sacrifices himself for the player by holding up the ruins with magic while the protagonist escapes.  HeurodisThe main antagonist in SoU, a medusa and eventually a lich.  Killed by the protagonist at the end of the expansion.  Prestige ClassesThis section is about the newly-added Classes in this expansion pack; if  you're interested in getting to know more about all the races and  classes available to the player in the game, just visit the    Neverwinter Nights wiki page.  Arcane ArcherThe Arcane Archer is a warrior skilled in using magic to increase his combat prowess.  Hit Dice: d8Proficiencies: all simple and martial weapons, light and medium armor, and shieldsSkill Points: 4   int modifierSkills: craft armor, craft trap, craft weapon, heal, hide, listen, lore, move silently, ride, spotUnavailable Feats: brew potion, craft wand, curse song, deflect arrows, divine might, divine shield, extra music, extra turning, lingering song, quicken spell, scribe scroll, spell focus, weapon specializationPrimary Saving Throw(s): fortitude, reflexBase Attack Bonus:  1 per level gainedRequirementsTo qualify as an Arcane Archer, the player must meet all of the following criteria:Base attack bonus:  6Feats: weapon focus (longbow or shortbow), point blank shotRace: Elf or Half-ElfSpellcasting: ability to cast arcane spells (Bard, Sorcerer, or Wizard classes) AssassinThe Assassin is a master of dealing quick, lethal, precise blows.  Hit Dice: d6Proficiencies: simple weapons, light armorSkill Points: 4   int modifierSkills: appraise, bluff, craft armor, craft trap, craft weapon, disable trap, heal, hide, intimidate, listen, lore, move silently, open lock, pick pocket, search, set trap, spot, tumble, use magic deviceUnavailable Feats: brew potion, craft wand, curse song, deflect arrows, divine might, divine shield, extra music, extra turning, lingering song, quicken spell, scribe scroll, spell focus, weapon specializationPrimary Saving Throw(s): reflexBase Attack Bonus:  3 at every 4 levels gained RequirementsTo qualify as an Assassin, the player must meet all of the following criteria:Alignment: any evilSkills: Hide (8 ranks), Move Silently (8 ranks)BlackguardA Blackguard epitomizes evil, equivalent in power to the most righteous paladin, but devoted to the powers of darkness instead.  Hit Dice: d10Proficiencies: all simple and martial weapons, all types of armor and shieldsSkill Points: 2   int modifierSkills: concentration, craft armor, craft trap, craft weapon, discipline, heal, intimidate, lore, parry, persuade, ride, tauntUnavailable Feats: brew potion, craft wand, curse song, deflect arrows, extra music, extra turning, lingering song, quicken spell, scribe scroll, spell focus, weapon specializationPrimary Saving Throw(s): fortitudeBase Attack Bonus:  1 per level gainedRequirementsTo qualify as a Blackguard, the player must meet all of the following criteria:Alignment: any evilBase Attack Bonus:  6Skills: Hide (5 ranks)Feats: CleaveHarper ScoutHarpers are a secret society, dedicated to hold back evil, preserving knowledge and maintaining the balance between civilization and the wild.  Hit Dice: d6Proficiencies: simple weapons, light armorSkill Points: 4   int modifierSkills: appraise, bluff, craft armor, craft trap, craft weapon, discipline, heal, hide, listen, lore, move silently, persuade, pick pocket, tumbleUnavailable Feats: brew potion, craft wand, divine might, divine shield, extra music, extra turning, lingering song, scribe scroll, spell focus, weapon proficiency (martial)Primary Saving Throw(s): reflex, willBase Attack Bonus:  3 at every 4 levels gainedRequirementsTo qualify to become a Harper Scout, the player must meet all of the following criteria:Alignment: any non-evilFeats: Alertness, Iron WillSkills: Discipline (4 ranks), Lore (6 ranks), Persuade (8 ranks), Search (4 ranks) ShadowdancerShadowdancers operate in the border between light and darkness.  Hit Dice: d8Proficiencies: simple weapons, light armorSkill Points: 6   int modifierSkills: heal, hide, listen, lore, move silently, persuade, pick pocket, search, spot, tumbleUnavailable Feats: brew potion, craft wand, curse song, divine might, divine shield, extra music, extra turning, lingering song, scribe scroll, spell focus, weapon specializationPrimary Saving Throw(s): reflexBase Attack Bonus:  3 at every 4 levels gainedRequirementsTo qualify as a Shadowdancer, the player must meet all of the following criteria:Feats: Dodge, MobilitySkills: Hide (10 ranks), Move Silently (8 ranks), Tumble (5 ranks)</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10637">Baldur's Gate II: Shadows of Amn</game><game id="17949">The Elder Scrolls III: Tribunal</game><game id="2235">Planescape: Torment</game><game id="8890">Icewind Dale II</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15693/618108-563551_24164_front_1_.jpg</image></root>