<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16656</id><name>Armored Core</name><description>OverviewArmored Core is set in a future where a war known as the Great Destruction has devastated Earth and killed the majority of humanity. Due to the uninhabitable conditions of the surface of Earth, the survivors of the Great Destruction were forced into living underground for a period of fifty years. During the fifty year period a number of corporations came to power and the two largest of these corporations were Chrome and Murakumo Millennium who were locked in a constant power struggle, much to the detriment of the rest of humanity. A group of mercenaries known as The Ravens were able to take advantage of the opportunities presented by the power struggle and used it to their advantage. The player takes on the role of a Raven pilot of an armored core, a type of giant mech and acts as a gun for hire for various corporations and groups.Throughout the game the player has a choice of which missions he or she chooses to accept and based on which missions he or she accepts the story will progress differently. Players are also ranked based on their relative success in each mission and can check the results of each mission via their mail. The player can buy interchangeable parts for their armored cores and due to the differing nature of the various situations players are placed in success often relies on building and choosing the right armored cores for the right missions.BackgroundChromeChrome is a megacorporation based out of Isaac City, one of the underground human settlements, and is one of the two corporations that will provide missions for the player. They have a partnership with Chemical-Dyne Co. and exert every inch of power and control that they have over Isaac City. Ultimately, in the end game, Chrome takes desperate measures to maintain control but falls apart, along with its rival MurakumoMurakumo MillenniumMurakumo Millennium is a megacorporation known for the manufacturing of AC parts and technological advances, specifically the Human PLUS Project. They are actively against Chrome’s exertion of power over Isaac City and see it as their biggest rival. However, Murakumo falls apart as a company, alongside Chrome during the endgame.The Ravens’ NestThe Ravens’ Nest is a mediation group that serves as a sanctuary for Ravens, mercenaries that will take on any mission provided by the warring corporations. The Nest is absolutely neutral in all affairs, not interfering with which job a Raven chooses, and what a Raven is allowed to do, including cooperating with or killing other Ravens. Supplies and repair for ACs are provided by the Nest, as well as messages and contracts forwarded by the Nest’s sole operator, “R.”The Great DestructionThe Great Destruction was a catastrophic event in human history that drove mankind underground after thirty years of war left the surface inhospitable. This migration to the underground cities took place 50 years before the events of the game, and now the corporations have succeeded the government in power, and war is raged underground (and above) between Chrome and Murakumo Millenium.GameplayGameplay in Armored Core revolves around customizing your AC and using it during missions provided to you by the Nest. You are provided multiple missions at a time and can choose to accomplish them in whichever order you prefer. While there is a compensation with each mission, for every Armor Point you lose or ammunition you spend during a mission, the pay will be deducted to cover the cost of AC repairs and ammo refills. Using energy weapons instead of solid rounds can reduce the cost needed to restore the AC after a mission. Sometimes a mission can result in the player losing more money than they do earn, and can even go into debt. While in debt, the player cannot buy or sell any parts in the shop until the balance is out of the red.If the player reaches 50000C in debt, the game will play a cutscene from the player's perspective showing that he is about to undergo a Human PLUS procedure. After this cutscene, the game starts from the beginning, but with the player's AC parts and credits carried over as well as a boost in abilities. This can be done multiple times, and for various bonuses, including twice as much energy, the ability to shoot beams from the laser blade with the proper button press, and the ability to use back cannon parts without the need to be stationary.StoryStory is extremely thin and loose in the game. The game starts with the main character completing a two minute test to become a Raven and join the Ravens’ Nest. After doing this, the Raven pursues missions offered by either Chrome or Murakumo Millennium. Whichever missions are chosen leads down different paths, working for one corporation while taking down the other.However, after taking down one of the corporations, the other one declines as well, and the concern arises that there will be little need for Ravens anymore now that the conflict has been resolved. That is not the case, as the Raven is called to one final mission to clear out “floating mines” but it turns out to be a trap. The Raven faces against the top ranked AC Nine-Ball twice, and then finds and destroys an AI computer revealed to be the Ravens’ Nest operator “R.” As the AI is about to die, it questions the Raven about whether his decision will prove to be the right one, if destroying order led by “R” is the right choice for humanity. An explosion is seen on the surface, and the effects of the Raven’s decision can be easily guessed based on the events of its sequels.PartsThere are over 130 parts in Armored Core. Most of these are available in the shop right from the beginning, but other conditions must be met for certain parts to be available. They must be either found during missions, completing a certain number of missions, or receiving them as a reward rather than regular money.HeadsHeads provide radar and sensor functions to the AC, some features including noise cancellation or bio sensors for specific bio organisms. The AC's computer voice is also determined by the type of head chosen. When beginning a new game, the player's AC has the HD-GRY-NX as their starting headHD-01-SRVTPart Type: HeadPrice: 26500Weight: 122Energy Drain: 350Armor Points: 816Def Shell: 154Head unit with built-in bio sensorDef Energy: 149Computer Type: DetailedMap Type: Area MemoryNoise Canceler: NoneBio Sensor: ProvidedRadar Function: NoneHD-2002Part Type: HeadPrice: 29000Weight: 156Energy Drain: 457Armor Points: 787Def Shell: 140Def Energy: 154Head unit equipped with radar functionComputer Type: StandardMap Type: Area MemoryNoise Canceler: NoneBio Sensor: NoneRadar Function: ProvidedRadar Range: 6000Radar Type: StandardHD-X1487Part Type: HeadPrice: 19000Weight: 166Energy Drain: 420Armor Points: 975Def Shell: 160Full range of sensors but without the auto-map functionDef Energy: 185Computer Type: RoughMap Type: No MemoryNoise Canceler: ProvidedBio Sensor: ProvidedRadar Function: NoneHD-REDEYEPart Type: HeadPrice: 41000Weight: 146Energy Drain: 538Armor Points: 840Def Shell: 148Def Energy: 151Equipped with radar and an enhanced auto-map functionComputer Type: DetailedMap Type: Area  Place NameNoise Canceler: NoneBio Sensor: NoneRadar Function: ProvidedRadar Range: 5980Radar Type: StandardHD-D-9066Part Type: HeadPrice: 43200Weight: 138Energy Drain: 657Armor Points: 885Def Shell: 165Def Energy: 232Full range of options and good EG shieldsComputer Type: StandardMap Type: Area MemoryNoise Canceler: NoneBio Sensor: ProvidedRadar Function: ProvidedRadar Range: 6120Radar Type: StandardHD-GRY-NXPart Type: HeadPrice: 14700Weight: 232Energy Drain: 218Armor Points: 1004Def Shell: 194Economy unit with good shields but no optional equipmentDef Energy: 134Computer Type: RoughMap Type: No MemoryNoise Canceler: NoneBio Sensor: NoneRadar Function: NoneHD-06-RADARPart Type: HeadPrice: 51800Weight: 145Energy Drain: 875Armor Points: 741Def Shell: 109Def Energy: 194Equipped with wide-area radar and various optionsComputer Type: StandardMap Type: Area  Place NameNoise Canceler: ProvidedBio Sensor: NoneRadar Function: ProvidedRadar Range: 8120Radar Type: StandardHD-ONEPart Type: HeadPrice: 68100Weight: 161Energy Drain: 304Armor Points: 800Def Shell: 132Def Energy: 129Full equipped with wide-area radar and all optionsComputer Type: DetailedMap Type: Area MemoryNoise Canceler: ProvidedBio Sensor: ProvidedRadar Function: ProvidedRadar Range: 7980Radar Type: StandardHD-08-DISHPart Type: HeadPrice: 33200Weight: 133Energy Drain: 716Armor Points 870Def Shell: 205Equipped with an enhanced auto-map functionDef Energy: 162Computer Type: StandardMap Type: Area  Place NameNoise Canceler: NoneBio Sensor: NoneRadar Function: NoneHD-ZEROPart Type: HeadPrice: 22500Weight: 185Energy Drain: 431Armor Points: 925Def Shell: 221Def Energy: 149Head unit equipped with radar functionComputer Type: RoughMap Type: No MemoryNoise Canceler: NoneBio Sensor: NoneRadar Function: ProvidedRadar Range: 6300Radar Type: StandardCoresCores are a very integral part of the AC. There are only three cores to choose from, ranging from heavy to light armor, as well as the number of optional parts that can be equipped. When beginning a new game, the player's AC has the XCA-00 as their starting core.XCA-00Part Type: CorePrice: 61500Weight: 1103Energy Drain: 1046Armor Points: 2710Def Shell: 530Standard core unit with average performance overallDef Energy: 505Maximum Weight: 2770Anti-Missile-Response: 48Anti-Missile-Angle: 48Extension Slots: 8XCL-01Part Type: CorePrice: 88000Weight: 885Energy Drain: 1380Armor Points: 2380Def Shell: 492Electronic warfare core with many slots for special equipmentDef Energy: 610Maximum Weight: 2450Anti-Missile-Response: 48Anti-Missile-Angle: 64Extension Slots: 16XCH-01Part Type: CorePrice: 72000Weight: 1384Energy Drain: 873Armor Points: 3015Def Shell: 615Heavyweight core with an excellent shoulder load and heavy armorDef Energy: 543Maximum Weight: 3600Anti-Missile-Response: 48Anti-Missile-Angle: 32Extension Slots: 12ArmsArms are divided into two categories. Normal arms allow you to wield a right arm weapon and equip a laser blade on the left arm. Weapon arms are weapons themselves and cannot hold any additional fire arms. When beginning a new game, the player's AC has the AN-201 as their starting arms.AN-101Part Type: ArmsPrice: 19000Weight: 1228Energy Drain: 1006Normal arm units with average performanceArmor Points: 1670Def Shell: 384Def Energy: 374AN-201Part Type: ArmsPrice: 15300Weight: 1054Energy Drain: 877Low energy consumption version of the AN-101Armor Points: 1635Def Shell: 352Def Energy: 334AN-K1Part Type: ArmsPrice: 49000Weight: 905Energy Drain: 930Reduced-weight arm units with full AP and shieldsArmor Points: 1790Def Shell: 339Def Energy: 402AN-D-7001Part Type: ArmsPrice: 23000Weight: 1445Energy Drain: 1512Average arm units with enhanced performanceArmor Points: 1743Def Shell: 306Def Energy: 453AN-3001Part Type: ArmsPrice: 39500Weight: 1612Energy Drain: 1258Middleweight arms with maximum energy shieldingArmor Points: 1935Def Shell: 487Def Energy: 353ANKS-1A46JPart Type: ArmsPrice: 42100Weight: 2120Energy Drain: 1415Offers the maximum AP but interferes with some partsArmor Points: 1990Def Shell: 679Def Energy: 496AN-863-BPart Type: ArmsPrice: 34000Weight: 1726Energy Drain: 1394Weight is increased for added durabilityArmor Points: 1880Def Shell: 517Def Energy: 406AN-25Part Type: ArmsPrice: 28400Weight: 853Energy Drain: 682Lightweight type arm units with better performanceArmor Points: 1826Def Shell: 344Def Energy: 284AW-MG25/2Part Type: ArmsType: Machine GunPrice: 54500Weight: 1193Energy Drain: 78Armor Points: 812Def Shell: 0Def Energy: 0Can strafe with 4 rifles at onceWeapon Lock: SpecialAttack Power: 158Number of Ammo: 400Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 33Range: 8800Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 2AW-GT20000Part Type: ArmsType: Gatling GunPrice: 48600Weight: 1415Energy Drain: 92Armor Points: 1132Def Shell: 0Def Energy: 0Dual gatling guns can concentrate high-speed rounds at a single pointWeapon Lock: SpecialAttack Power: 305Number of Ammo: 300Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 62Range: 7800Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 2AW-RF105Part Type: ArmsType: CannonPrice: 77600Weight: 1530Energy Drain: 106Armor Points: 1280Def Shell: 0Def Energy: 02 cannons with incredible fire powerWeapon Lock: Narrow  DeepAttack Power: 1530Number of Ammo: 100Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 220Range: 9300Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 15AW-30/3Part Type: ArmsType: Dual MissilePrice: 56400Weight: 480Energy Drain: 377Armor Points: 688Def Shell: 0Def Energy: 0Fires 2 rounds of 3 small missiles for a total of 6 missilesWeapon Lock: StandardAttack Power: 830Number of Ammo: 80Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 130Range: 9000Maximum Lock: 3Reload Time: 10AW-RF120Part Type: ArmsType: CannonPrice: 67200Weight: 1827Energy Drain: 137Armor Points: 1420Def Shell: 0Def Energy: 0Enhanced dual cannons. Somewhat fewer shotsWeapon Lock: Narrow  DeepAttack Power: 2120Number of Ammo: 50Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 300Range: 9800Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 18AW-S60/2Part Type: ArmsType: Dual MissilePrice: 66600Weight: 762Energy Drain: 420Armor Points: 725Def Shell: 0Def Energy: 0Fires 2 rounds of 2 missiles at once for extra shotsWeapon Lock: StandardAttack Power: 830Number of Ammo: 120Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 130Range: 9000Maximum Lock: 2Reload Time: 10AW-XC5500Part Type: ArmsType: Plasma CannonPrice: 83600Weight: 1688Energy Drain: 547Armor Points: 875Def Shell: 0Def Armor: 0Energy weapon. Fires twin bursts of lightWeapon Lock: Narrow  DeepAttack Power: 1241Number of Ammo: 70Ammo Type: EnergyAmmo Price: 0Range: 12000Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 7AW-XC65Part Type: ArmsType: Laser CannonPrice: 98500Weight: 1905Energy Drain: 625Armor Points: 792Def Shell: 0Def Energy: 0Energy Weapon. Fires two beams.Weapon Lock: Narrow  DeepAttack Power: 2322Number of Ammo: 40Ammo Type: EnergyAmmo Price: 0Range: 8300Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 10LegsLegs provide support for the AC and come in four different forms. Humanoid legs are humanoid looking in shape. Reverse joint legs can move faster and jump easily, but cannot carry as much. Four legged parts move about twice as fast as humanoid legs and can allow the AC to fire back cannons without being stationary. Caterpillar legs are tank treads that move very slowly but provide the most defense, and can also allow the AC to fire back cannons without being stationary. When beginning a new game, the player's AC has the LN-1001-PX-0 as their starting legsLN-1001Part Type: LegsType: Humanoid LegsPrice: 28500Weight: 1966Energy Drain: 1725Armor Points: 3235Balanced, standard humanoid legsDef Shell: 556Def Energy: 531Maximum Weight: 4470Speed: 277Stability: 1018Jump Function: ProvidedLN-SSVTPart Type: LegsType: Humanoid LegsPrice: 44000Weight: 1528Energy Drain: 2338Armor Points: 2795Light, fast humanoid legs but with low load capacity and APDef Shell: 482Def Energy: 507Maximum Weight: 3560Speed: 445Stability: 596Jump Function: ProvidedLN-3001Part Type: LegsType: Humanoid LegsPrice: 52200Weight: 3137Energy Drain: 2206Armor Points: 3703Heavily armored humanoid legs with a high load capacity. Poor speedDef Shell: 870Def Energy: 594Maximum Weight: 6600Speed: 153Stability: 2518Jump Function: ProvidedLN-1001-PX-0Part Type: LegsType: Humanoid LegsPrice: 25000Weight: 1892Energy Drain: 1844Armor Points: 3035Balanced humanoid legs for combat on all terrainDef Shell: 528Def Energy: 508Maximum Weight: 4100Speed: 280Stability: 904Jump Function: ProvidedLN-501Part Type: LegsType: Humanoid LegsPrice: 71800Weight: 1675Energy Drain: 2910Armor Points: 2947Has the shield performance and load capacity of a middleweightDef Shell: 508Def Energy: 535Maximum Weight: 3990Speed: 451Stability: 854Jump Function: ProvidedLN-SSVRPart Type: LegsType: Humanoid LegsPrice: 32400Weight: 2750Energy Drain: 2013Armor Points: 3606Lightest of the heavily armored humanoid legsDef Shell: 805Def Energy: 532Maximum Weight: 5400Speed: 148Stability: 2150Jump Function: ProvidedLN-1001BPart Type: LegsType: Humanoid LegsPrice: 45200Weight: 2305Energy Drain: 1889Armor Points: 3383Enhanced version of the LN-1001Def Shell: 585Def Energy: 543Maximum Weight: 4630Speed: 272Stability: 1320Jump Function: ProvidedLN-3001CPart Type: LegsType: Humanoid LegsPrice: 64100Weight: 3528Energy Drain: 2418Armor Points: 3977Best AP and shields among the humanoid legsDef Shell: 889Def Energy: 602Maximum Weight: 7100Speed: 151Stability: 2977Jump Function: ProvidedLN-502Part Type: LegsType: Humanoid LegsPrice: 35800Weight: 1790Energy Drain: 2466Armor Points: 3343This middleweight has reduced weight without sacrificing performanceDef Shell: 538Def Energy: 592Maximum Weight: 3800Speed: 275Stability: 843Jump Function: ProvidedLN-D-8000RPart Type: LegsType: Humanoid LegsPrice: 49000Weight: 2426Energy Drain: 2350Armor Points: 3532Humanoid legs with special anti-energy armorDef Shell: 510Def Energy: 656Maximum Weight: 4720Speed: 269Stability: 1200Jump Function: ProvidedLNKS-1B46JPart Type: LegsType: Humanoid LegsPrice: 48000Weight: 3065Energy Drain: 2304Armor Points: 3788Shock absorbing structure reduces recoil from shell hitsDef Shell: 822Def Energy: 618Maximum Weight: 6100Speed: 146Stability: 3802Jump Function: ProvidedLB-4400Part Type: LegsType: Reverse JointPrice: 17300Weight: 2520Energy Drain: 1400Armor Points: 3560Standard reverse joint type. Good maneuverability and inexpensiveDef Shell: 617Def Energy: 451Maximum Weight: 4020Speed: 294Stability: 2084Jump Function: ProvidedLB-4401Part Type: LegsType: Reverse JointPrice: 31800Weight: 2910Energy Drain: 1456Armor Points: 3810Best overall performance of the reverse joint typesDef Shell: 672Def Energy: 468Maximum Weight: 4510Speed: 287Stability: 2713Jump Function: ProvidedLB-4303Part Type: LegsType: Reverse JointPrice: 24000Weight: 2647Energy Drain: 1585Armor Points: 3575Increased ground contact area for enhanced shock absorbing capacityDef Shell: 643Def Energy: 488Maximum Weight: 4180Speed: 291Stability: 2505Jump Function: ProvidedLB-1000-PPart Type: LegsType: Reverse JointPrice: 20500Weight: 2095Energy Drain: 1228Armor Points: 3514Phenomenal maneuverability but low load carrying capacityDef Shell: 609Def energy: 444Maximum Weight: 3775Speed: 286Stability: 2310Jump Function: ProvidedLBKS-2B45APart Type: LegsType: Reverse JointPrice: 27000Weight: 2480Energy Drain: 1703Armor Points: 3731Deluxe type with enhanced shielding against energy weaponsDef Shell: 584Def Energy: 515Maximum Weight: 3990Speed: 299Stability: 1985Jump Function: ProvidedLF-205-SFPart Type: LegsType: Four Legs TypePrice: 42600Weight: 2137Energy Drain: 2810Armor Points: 2841Standard four-leg type. Top-class maneuverabilityDef Shell: 446Def Energy: 654Maximum Weight: 3450Speed: 483Stability: 580Jump Function: ProvidedLFH-X3Part Type: LegsType: Four Legs TypePrice: 56000Weight: 2400Energy Drain: 2988Armor Points: 3100Energy gage recovers quickly when haltedDef Shell: 468Def Energy: 610Maximum Weight: 3810Speed: 421Stability: 710Jump Function: ProvidedLF-DEX-1Part Type: LegsType: Four Legs TypePrice: 69000Weight: 2650Energy Drain: 4016Armor Points: 3179Increased load carrying capacity requires vast amounts of powerDef Shell: 557Def Energy: 553Maximum Weight: 4450Speed: 360Stability: 820Jump Function: ProvidedLFH-X5XPart Type: LegsType: Four Legs TypePrice: 82000Weight: 2880Energy Drain: 3584Armor Points: 3328LFH-X5XDef Shell: 497Def Energy: 700Maximum Weight: 5000Speed: 442Stability: 1110Jump Function: ProvidedLC-MOS18Part Type: LegsType: CaterpillarPrice: 16000Weight: 4182Energy Drain: 978Armor Points: 3928Maximum load carrying capacity but poor speed and weightDef Shell: 858Def Energy: 572Maximum Weight: 8000Speed: 105Stability: 4245Jump Function: NoneLC-UKI60Part Type: LegsType: CaterpillarPrice: 25500Weight: 3860Energy Drain: 1104Armor Points: 3822Economy wheeled truck type with finely adjusted performanceDef Shell: 812Def Energy: 589Maximum Weight: 6950Speed: 138Stability: 3710Jump Function: NoneLC-HTP-AAAPart Type: LegsType: CaterpillarPrice: 38500Weight: 2915Energy Drain: 2877Armor Points: 3688Has performance near that of a four-legged typeDef Shell: 728Def Energy: 694Maximum Weight: 4130Speed: 250Stability: 630Jump Function: ProvidedLC-MOS4545Part Type: LegsType: CaterpillarPrice: 59000Weight: 3610Energy Drain: 2609Armor Points: 3990A dreadfully durable monster machineDef Shell: 905Def Energy: 753Maximum Weight: 7400Speed: 211Stability: 5101Jump Function: NoneGeneratorsGenerators provide power to your AC. Depending on the generator you have your AC can boost longer and the red zone on the energy meter will be smaller. When beginning a new game, the player's AC has the GPS-VVA as their starting generator.GPS-VVAPart Type: GeneratorPrice: 19500Weight: 308Low in both power and capacity. Wide red zoneEnergy Output: 4728Maximum Charge: 28000Redzone: 7800GPS-V6Part Type: GeneratorPrice: 32000Weight: 363Load increased to nearly twice that of the GPS-VVAEnergy Output: 4728Maximum Charge: 43000Redzone: 5000GRD-RX5Part Type: GeneratorPrice: 23300Weight: 225Balanced-performance generatorEnergy Output: 5300Maximum Charge: 38000Redzone: 4000GRD-RX6Part Type: GeneratorPrice: 27800Weight: 286Performance not bad, but the equipment is so-soEnergy Output: 6000Maximum Charge: 33000Redzone: 4000GRD-RX7Part Type: GeneratorPrice: 38700Weight: 348Very good power but poor staminaEnergy Output: 6810Maximum Charge: 31500Redzone: 5000GBG-10000Part Type: GeneratorPrice: 43500Weight: 398High power provided by a wide selection of equipmentEnergy Output: 9988Maximum Charge: 34000Redzone: 2980GBG-XRPart Type: GeneratorPrice: 56000Weight: 452Custom-made unit having both power and capacityEnergy Output: 8207Maximum Charge: 48000Redzone: 3250FCSFCS is the targeting system for your AC. These determine the size of the aim box in conjunction with certain weapons, and the number of lock ons you can get. When beginning a new game, the player's AC has the COMDEX-C7 as their starting FCS.COMDEX-C7Part Type: FCSPrice: 11100Weight: 14Maximum of 4 lock-ons, average performanceEnergy Drain: 24Maximum Lock: 4Lock Type: StandardCOMDEX-G0Part Type: FCSPrice: 22500Weight: 14Maximum of 4 lock-ons, fast lock-onEnergy Drain: 24Maximum Lock: 4Lock Type: StandardCOMDEX-G8Part Type: FCSPrice: 16400Weight: 14Maximum of 6 lock-ons, long distance lock-onEnergy Drain: 24Maximum Lock: 6Lock Type: StandardQX-21Part Type: FCSPrice: 20300Weight: 8Maximum of 1 lock-on, short lock over a wide areaEnergy Drain: 12Maximum Lock: 1Lock Type: Wide  ShallowQX-AFPart Type: FCSPrice: 35700Weight: 10Maximum of 2 lock-ons, short lockEnergy Drain: 16Maximum Lock: 2Lock Type: Wide  ShallowTRYX-BOXERPart Type: FCSPrice: 48100Weight: 10Maximum of 3 lock-ons, vertical sightEnergy Drain: 19Maximum Lock: 3Lock Type: TallTRYX-QUADPart Type: FCSPrice: 63000Weight: 18Maximum of 6 lock-ons, horizontal sightEnergy Drain: 38Maximum Lock: 6Lock Type: WideQX-9009Part Type: FCSPrice: 96000Weight: 24Maximum of 6 lock-ons, longest lock distanceEnergy Drain: 55Maximum Lock: 6Lock Type: Narrow  DeepBoostersBoosters allow your AC to increase speed and fly in mid air. Boosters require varying amounts of power from your energy meter, and are required in order to elevate Caterpillar leg types. When beginning a new game, the player's AC has the B-P320 as their starting boosters.B-P320Part Type: BoostersPrice: 10800Weight: 208Low priced but seems a bit underpoweredEnergy Drain: 28Boost Power: 9800Charge Drain: 4360B-P350Part Type: BoostersPrice: 13700Weight: 162Economy type with high power but high energy consumptionEnergy Drain: 33Boost Power: 12800Charge Drain: 4410B-T001Part Type: BoostersPrice: 34000Weight: 149Achieves both enhanced power and low weight at the same timeEnergy Drain: 30Boost Power: 17300Charge Drain: 4600B-T2Part Type: BoostersPrice: 31500Weight: 235Power itself is low but offers the highest efficiencyEnergy Drain: 38Boost Power: 14800Charge Drain: 3850B-P351Part Type: BoostersPrice: 25500Weight: 288High-performance model with both high power and energy consumptionEnergy Drain: 41Boost Power: 21000Charge Drain: 6980B-VR-33Part Type: BoostersPrice: 48500Weight: 255Maintains the top-class power to achieve good efficiencyEnergy Drain: 35Boost Power: 19000Charge Drain: 5070Back UnitsBack units can either provide extra fire power to your AC, or extra radar functions. Back units can be assigned to either the left or right side of the AC's back, and some units take up both sides. When beginning a new game, the player's AC has the WM-S40/1 and the RXA-01WE as their starting Back Units.WM-S40/1Type: Small MissilePrice: 18700Weight: 240Energy Drain: NoneRadar Function: StandardWeapon Lock: StandardAttack Power: 830Pod that fires single small missilesNumber of Ammo: 40Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 130Range: 9000Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 10WM-S40/2Type: Small MissilePrice: 23000Weight: 337Energy Drain: 320Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: StandardAttack Power: 830Fires up to 2 small missiles at onceNumber of Ammo: 40Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 130Range: 9000Maximum Lock: 2Reload Time: 10WM-S60/4Type: Small MissilePrice: 28800Weight: 520Energy Drain: 349Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: StandardAttack Power: 830Fires up to 4 small missiles at onceNumber of Ammo: 60Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 130Range: 9000Maximum Lock: 4Reload Time: 10WM-S60/6Type: Small MissilePrice: 38100Weight: 583Energy Drain: 353Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: StandardAttack Power: 830Fires up to 6 small missiles at onceNumber of Ammo: 60Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 130Range: 9000Maximum Lock: 6Reload Time: 10WM-MVG404Type: MissilePrice: 31000Weight: 620Energy Drain: 280Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: StandardAttack Power: 1560Pod that fires single missilesNumber of Ammo: 24Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 252Range: 10000Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 10WM-MVG802Type: MissilePrice: 44000Weight: 718Energy Drain: 220Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: StandardAttack Power: 1560Fires up to 2 missiles at onceNumber of Ammo: 32Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 252Range: 10000Maximum Lock: 2Reload Time: 10WM-L201Type: Large MissilePrice: 46200Weight: 835Energy Drain: 180Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: StandardAttack Power: 4300Powerful large missiles fired singlyNumber of Ammo: 12Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 897Range: 12500Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 10WM-X201Type: Multi MissilePrice: 62250Weight: 720Energy Drain: 250Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: StandardAttack Power: 980Multi-warhead missiles that scatters warheads in flightNumber of Ammo: 18Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 1125Range: 12000Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 15WM-X5-AAType: Bomb DispenserPrice: 19300Weight: 616Energy Drain: 85Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: NoneAttack Power: 675Drops 8 ground-attack mines. For expertsNumber of Ammo: 10Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 270Range: 0Maximum Lock: 0Reload Time: 50WM-X10Type: Bomb DispenserPrice: 24800Weight: 939Energy Drain: 105Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: NoneAttack Power: 675Drops 16 powerful ground-attack mines.Number of Ammo: 10Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 560Range: 0Maximum Lock: 0Reload Time: 50WM-P4001Type: Dual MissilePrice: 43800Weight: 755Energy Drain: 320Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: StandardAttack Power: 830Fires 2 left or right curving indirect attack missilesNumber of Ammo: 60Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 130Range: 9000Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 10WM-PS-2Type: Triple MissilePrice: 66700Weight: 1125Energy Drain: 360Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: StandardAttack Power: 830Fires 3 up-curving indirect attack missilesNumber of Ammo: 90Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 130Range: 9000Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 10WR-S50Type: Small RocketPrice: 15900Weight: 218Energy Drain: 8Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: NoneAttack Power: 1310Carries 50 small rocketsNumber of Ammo: 50Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 110Range: 12500Maximum Lock: 0Reload Time: 8WR-S100Type: Small RocketPrice: 32400Weight: 846Energy Drain: 15Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: NoneAttack Power: 1310Carries 100 small rocketsNumber of Ammo: 100Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 110Range: 12500Maximum Lock: 0Reload Time: 12WR-M50Type: RocketPrice: 27600Weight: 677Energy Drain: 13Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: NoneAttack Power: 2240Carries 50 rocketsNumber of Ammo: 50Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 220Range: 14000Maximum Lock: 0Reload Time: 12WR-M70Type: RocketPrice: 36500Weight: 718Energy Drain: 24Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: NoneAttack Power: 2240Carries 70 rocketsNumber of Ammo: 70Ammo type: SolidAmmo Price: 220Range: 14000Maximum Lock: 0Reload Time: 16WR-L24Type: Large RocketPrice: 29460Weight: 805Energy Drain: 18Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: NoneAttack Power: 3980This rocket has the greatest firepower of any single weaponNumber of Ammo: 24Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 417Range: 17700Maximum Lock: 0Reload Time: 16WC-CN35Type: Chain GunPrice: 32750Weight: 593Energy Drain: 11Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: SpecialAttack Power: 338Fast reloading rifle. Easy to useNumber of Ammo: 250Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 52Range: 10000Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 2WC-ST120Type: Slug GunPrice: 56000Weight: 827Energy Drain: 6Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: SpecialAttack Power: 183Fires 7 simultaneous shots that scatter over a wide rangeNumber of Ammo: 80Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 156Range: 8100Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 22WC-LN350Type: Linear GunPrice: 41800Weight: 425Energy Drain: 8Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: SpecialAttack Power: 690Burst-fire type weapon emphasizing firepower over number of shotsNumber of Ammo: 120Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 108Range: 9000Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 6WC-GN230Type: Grenade LauncherPrice: 75200Weight: 1230Energy Drain: 8Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: Narrow  DeepAttack Power: 3520An AC's symbolic weapon that mows down enemies in a firestormNumber of Ammo: 15Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 985Range: 12000Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 32WC-XP4000Type: Pulse CannonPrice: 61000Weight: 318Energy Drain: 364Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: Narrow  DeepAttack Power: 770Energy Weapon. Reloading ion cannonNumber of Ammo 100Ammo Type: EnergyAmmo Price: 0Range: 9000Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 5WC-XC8000Type: Laser CannonPrice: 78700Weight: 1110Energy Drain: 455Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: Narrow  DeepAttack Power: 2065Energy Weapon. Fires laser roundsNumber of Ammo: 50Ammo Type: EnergyAmmo Price: 0Range: 8500Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 10WC-01QLType: Plasma CannonPrice: 69500Weight: 273Energy Drain: 618Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: SpecialAttack Power: 1531Energy weapon. Beam cuts down enemiesNumber of Ammo: 80Ammo Type: EnergyAmmo Price: 0Range: 12000Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 7RXA-01WEType: RadarPrice: 12100Weight: 210Energy Drain: 243Old-style antenna but still holds up well in useRadar Function: ProvidedRadar Type: 8650Radar Type: StandardRZ-A0Type: RadarPrice: 17900Weight: 480Energy Drain: 387This radar uses 2 dishes for enhanced enemy-search capabilityRadar Function: ProvidedRadar Range: 11500Radar Type: CircleRXA-99Type: RadarPrice: 14500WEight: 160Energy Drain: 267New-type radar permits an even wider area to be searchedRadar Function: ProvidedRadar Range: 8800Radar Type: StandardRXA-77Type: RadarPrice: 23000Weight: 125Energy Drain: 274This radar can detect the approach of homing missilesRadar Function: ProvidedRadar Range: 8700Radar Type: StandardRZ-A1Type: RadarPrice: 33000Weight: 433Energy Drain: 403Expands the enemy-search range up to the current technological limitRadar Function: ProvidedRadar Range: 15700Radar Type: CircleRZT-333Type: RadarPrice: 27700Weight: 343Energy Drain: 451Combines both missile detection and wide-range search capabilityRadar Function: ProvidedRadar Range: 11700Radar Type: OctagonRZ-BBPType: RadarPrice: 40900Weight: 454Energy Drain: 566Highest-quality radar with highest-class performanceRadar Function: ProvidedRadar Range: 16300Radar Type: CircleWX-S800/2Type: Dual MissilePrice: 69400Weight: 1650Energy Drain: 415Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: StandardAttack Power: 1120Fires 2 missiles with 1 lock-onNumber of Ammo: 60Ammo Type: solidAmmo Price: 515Range: 11000Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 12WX-S800-GFType: Dual MissilePrice: 90900Weight: 1110Energy Drain: 656Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: StandardAttack Power: 1120Fires 6 missiles with 1 lock-onNumber of Ammo: 6Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 515Range: 11000Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 10XCS-9900Type: Multi MissilePrice: 94500Weight: 1480Energy Drain: 310Radar Function: NoneWeapon Lock: StandardAttack Power: 980Fires 2 multi-warhead missiles simultaneouslyNumber of Ammo: 20Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 1125Range: 12000Maximum Lock: 1Reload time: 15Arm UnitsArm Units are weapons that can be wielded by the AC. The right hand holds the main fire arm while the left hand wields a laser blade that can be used as an off hand melee weapon. When beginning a new game, the player's AC has the WG-RF35 and the LS-2001 as their starting Arm Units.WG-RF35Type: RiflePrice: 11400Weight: 415Energy Drain: 6Weapon Lock: Wide  ShallowAttack Power: 218Standard portable rifle. Suitable for various missionsNumber of Ammo: 200Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 18Range: 8500Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 1WG-MGA1Type: Machine GunPrice: 14000Weight: 370Energy Drain: 4Weapon Lock: Wide  ShallowAttack Power: 85Fast-reloading solid round machine gun. Low single-round firepowerNumber of Ammo: 500Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 9Range: 6300Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 1WG-MG500Type: Machine GunPrice: 28400Weight: 458Energy Drain: 4Weapon Lock: Wide  ShallowAttack Power: 135Enhanced version of the machine gun with higher firepowerNumber of Ammo: 500Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 15Range: 7800Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 2WG-AR1000Type: Machine GunPrice: 42300Weight: 516Energy Drain: 8Weapon Lock: SpecialAttack Power: 105Most powerful portable type machine gunNumber of Ammo: 1000Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 12Range: 7000Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 1WG-HG235Type: Hand GunPrice: 19000Weight: 170Energy Drain: 22Weapon Lock: Wide  ShallowAttack Power: 226Wide scatter-shot pistol. Very short rangeNumber of Ammo: 100Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 68Range: 4800Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 5WG-RF/5Type: Sniper RiflePrice: 41500Weight: 295Energy Drain: 5Weapon Lock: SpecialAttack Power: 530Long-barrel sniper rifleNumber of Ammo: 80Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 83Range: 20000Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 10WG-RF/PType: Sniper RiflePrice: 33100Weight: 308Energy Drain: 4Weapon Lock: SpecialAttack Power: 612Superior firepower and range, but low reload rateNumber of Ammo: 60Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 95Range: 16000Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 12WG-HG512Type: Hand GunPrice: 26200Weight: 324Energy Drain: 10Weapon Lock: Wide  ShallowAttack Power: 437Lower performance but inexpensiveNumber of Ammo: 120Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 48Range: 5800Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 8WG-FG99Type: FlamethrowerPrice: 58300Weight: 352Energy Drain: 9Weapon Lock: NoneAttack Power: 512Close-in combat gun shows off its true worth in hand-to-hand combatNumber of Ammo: 500Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 41Range: 900Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 1WG-B2120Type: BazookaPrice: 59740Weight: 778Energy Drain: 13Weapon Lock: Narrow  DeepAttack Power: 1250High firepower but slow moving bazooka fire is easily avoidableNumber of Ammo: 80Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 163Range: 8200Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 16WG-B2180Type: BazookaPrice: 75900Weight: 905Energy Drain: 16Weapon Lock: Narrow  DeepAttack Power 1930Ultra-attack bazooka for betting it all on one shotNumber of Ammo: 50Ammo Type: SolidAmmo Price: 348Range: 7800Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 22WG-XP1000Type: Pulse RiflePrice: 46000Weight: 188Energy Drain: 246Weapon Lock: SpecialAttack Power: 302Energy weapon. Noted for its long range and reload speedNumber of Ammo: 180Ammo Type: EnergyAmmo Price: 0Range: 15000Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 3WG-XP2000Type: Pulse RiflePrice: 61500Weight: 265Energy Drain: 285Weapon Lock: SpecialAttack Power: 435Energy weapon. Emphasizes its long range and number of shotsNumber of Ammo: 200Ammo Type: EnergyAmmo Price: 0Range: 18000Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 6WG-XC4Type: Laser RiflePrice: 51000Weight: 686Energy Drain: 308Weapon Lock: SpecialAttack Power: 820Energy weapon. High firepower and energy consumptionNumber of Ammo: 100Ammo Type: EnergyAmmo Price: 0Range: 8000Maximum Lock: 1Reload time: 10WG-1-KARASAWAType: Laser RiflesPrice: 75000Weight: 1000Energy Drain: 422Weapon Lock: SpecialAttack Power: 1550Energy weapon. Strong but heavyNumber of Ammo: 50Ammo Type: EnergyAmmo Price: 0Range: 10000Maximum Lock: 1Reload Time: 80LS-2001Part Type: Laser BladePrice: 11500Weight: 123Infinitely reusable laser bladeEnergy Drain: 28Charge Drain: 2050Attack Power: 738LS-200GPart Type: Laser BladePrice: 29000Weight: 181Powerful weapon exclusively for close-in combatEnergy Drain: 45Charge Drain: 1700Attack Power: 950LS-3303Part Type: Laser BladePrice: 37200Weight: 224Enhanced blade weapon. Both power and energy consumption are higherEnergy Drain: 43Charge Drain: 2630Attack Power: 1210LS-99-MOONLIGHTPart Type: Laser BladePrice: 54000Weight: 336Blade weapon with more than twice the power of conventional bladesEnergy Drain: 93Charge Drain: 810Attack Power: 2801Optional PartsOptional parts can be equipped to the core of the AC to increase its abilities. There are a multitude of different optional parts and the amount you can equip depends on the slots available on the core. When beginning a new game, the player's AC does not have any optional partsSP-MAWPart Type: Optional PartType: Radar OptionPrice: 142000Slot Spend: 1Function: Adds Missile indicator to RadarAdds a missile display function to the radarSP-JAMPart Type: Optional PartType: Missile JammerPrice: 26000Slot Spend: 3Function: Missile lock-on interference deviceRegularly generates pulses that disable missile lock-onsSP-M/AUTOPart Type: Optional PartType: Auto LauncherPrice: 12900Slot Spend: 1Function: Automatic missile launcherFires a missile automatically on full lock-onSP-ABSPart Type: Optional PartType: Balancer OptionPrice: 29600Slot Spend: 1Function: Decreases impact shockReduces the recoil from shell hitsSP-SAPPart Type: Optional PartType: Absorber OptionPrice: 31800Slot Spend: 1Function: Decreases cannon recailReduces the recoil of cannon fireSP-CND-KPart Type: Optional PartType: Charge ExpanderPrice: 21000Slot Spend: 4Function: Increases energy outputIncreases the number of capacitors in the generatorSP-AXLPart Type: Optional PartType: FCS AcceleratorPrice: 24000Slot Spend: 2Function: Accelerates lock-on timeShortens lock-on timeSP-S/SCRPart Type: Optional PartType: Shell ScreenPrice: 33000Slot Spend: 2Function: Decreases projectile damageReduces damage from solid roundsSP-E/SCRPart Type: Optional PartType: Energy ScreenPrice: 38500Slot Spend: 1Function Decreases energy damageReduces damage from energy roundsSP-EHPart Type: Optional PartType: Rapid ChargePrice: 45000Slot Spend: 1Function: Increase energy weapon rechargeIncreases the burst fire rate of energy weaponsSP-E+Part Type: Optional PartType: Energy AmplifierPrice: 45000Slot Spend: 1Function: Increase energy weapon powerIncreases the fire power of energy weaponsRankingThroughout the game you can check the top 10 ranked Ravens, and see your place on the leader board rise as you progress.Rank: 1Pilot: Hustler OneAC: Nine-BallThe No. 1 Raven. Said to be the strongest ever. Has the reputation of always handling the tough jobs.Rank: 2Pilot: LosvaizeAC: ValkyrieThought to be a woman from the name of her AC, yet nothing certain is known. A top-ranking Raven.Rank: 3Pilot: BarutazaruAC: FefnirRanks among the top Ravens in mission success rate and targets destroyed in battle. A true ace.Rank: 4Pilot: WolfAC: Fenrir"Do the job reliably in a heavily-armed AC" is his creed. Always has an edge and is very successful.Rank: 5Pilot: Crescent MoonAC: Crescent MoonAlways a gentleman, but in battle he is feared for the cool, professional way he gets the job done.Rank: 6Pilot: Lynx MinxAC: Pretty KittyThis Raven excels at high-speed combat in a 4-legged AC. Prefers wide-open areas with few obstacles.Rank: 7Pilot: Nick KawasakiAC: Dragon KillerUses a lightweight AC with enhanced radar. Good one-shot sniper: does the job with minimal combat.Rank: 8Pilot: Mizuho KamuiAC: Kamui mk.17Noticed as a spirited up-and-coming Raven. Takes full advantage of his heavily-armed tank AC.Rank: 9Pilot: Peace MakerAC: Blue SteelKnown for his unique combat style that relies on guns only, no precision guided weapons.Rank: 10Pilot: White QueenAC: Check Mate IILoves close-up combat and excels at swordplay. Also known on the Net as a chess champion.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19719">Chromehounds</game><game id="13931">MechWarrior</game><game id="15264">Krazy Ivan</game><game id="22533">Another Century's Episode 3: The Final</game><game id="15559">Metal Warriors</game><game id="25684">Murakumo: Renegade Mech Pursuit</game><game id="26008">Front Mission Evolved</game><game id="210">Battlecorps</game><game id="34304">Iron Brigade</game><game id="16018">MechWarrior 2: Ghost Bear's Legacy</game><game id="22133">Armored Core: for Answer</game><game id="23375">Gangway Monsters</game><game id="20512">Exteel</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1810132-box_ac.png</image></root>