<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16679</id><name>Electro Man</name><description>OverviewElectro Man, a platformer released by Epic Megagames, is the story of a man turned cyborg seeking revenge for his murdered wife.GameplayThe start of the game.Electro Man is equipped with a gun, which at first doesn't shoot at first. You must first power up your gun by collecting batteries. With one battery your gun shoots a blue laser beam which fades out after a certain distance. With two batteries your gun shoots out a pink, thicker laser beam which will travel the length of the screen or until impact. With three batteries your gun will shoot revolving fireballs. With four batteries your gun will shoot a green laser beam which can travel through all enemies and targets. With five batteries your gun shoots a laser wall the height of Electro-Man. If the gun is fired too quickly, it will over-heat and Electro-Man will lose a battery. Batteries will also be lossed with prolonged use. Any contact with enemies or projectiles will cause Electro Man to blow up and return to the last checkpoint. If Electro Man returns to a checkpoint, all batteries are taken a way and reappear throughout the level. There are eight levels within the game.OtherElectro Man is widely considered to look eerily similar to Robo-Cop.Because Electro Man was originally released under a Microsoft Dos platform, the game will not run on Windows XP, or Vista. It is unplayable on most systems available today, and runs without sound on older itterations of Windows. There are, however, websites dedicated to emulating classic DOS titles.Electro Man was originally released as shareware, giving the user an invitation to purchase the full game at the conclusion of the first level. The game is now freeware.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5239/395147-electroman.jpg</image></root>