<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16696</id><name>RapeLay</name><description>OverviewRapeLay is a 3D rape simulator by Illusion Soft, makers of the Artificial Girl series. The player takes the role of a rapist who stalks a family consisting of three young women, raping them repeatedly until their will breaks and they become his slaves.StoryThe main character is a sexual predator who attempts to grope a teenage girl named Aoi Kiryuu, only to wind up arrested when she screams bloody murder. Your wealthy parents bribe the police into letting you go, so you decide that as punishment for her wholly lawful act, you will rape Aoi, as well as her mother and younger sister.GameplayRapeLay's gameplay is divided into three main parts:Phase OneThe games begins with the player following their victim at the train station. In this first phase one of the few things you can do is pray to the gods for a quick gust of wind that will blow up the victim's skirt, exposing her panties. Classy.Phase TwoOnce on the train, the assault begins, with a traditional Japanese train groping. Once the victim becomes aroused against her will, the train will conveniently stop, and the next phase of the game begins.Phase ThreeThe third and final phase of every scene is the actual rape scene. The location of the rape depends on the character being raped. Yuuko's location is in the park, Manaka gets raped in a public bathroom and Aoi in her bedroom.Free PhaseOnce the "story" is done the player gains access to free play mode. Here, the player can select which character they wish to rape, and where this character should be raped. In addition to the three different rape locations that the player had access to in the story mode, three new locations become available: a hotel room, an alley and the subway train itself. NPC rapists can be called on to add more people to the group. Also there are "3 player" and "4 player" modes available; not actually multiplayer, these are rapes in which a player has sex with two or all three of the girls in the game simultaneously. These only become available once a girl's will is broken: once she is bent to your will, you can bring her in to help molest one of her relatives. Again, classy.Pregnancy and AbortionOnce "Free Phase" is unlocked the different girls can get pregnant if you choose to ejaculate inside them during vaginal sex. If the child is born, the player will be thrown in front of the subway train. Forced abortion will result in the girl committing suicide by poison pill.EndingsThere are only two different endings in Rapelay, both of which involve the player character dying. If you have sex with Aoi in the cowgirl position before her will is broken, you will get an ending where she takes advantage of the position to stab you to death with a pair of scissors. The other ending occurs if you impregnate a girl and let her carry her baby to term. Unwilling to let the child be raised by you, the mother pushes you in front of a train the next time you're at the subway station. There is no "happy" or "good" ending in RapeLay (at least not for the player character); if you avoid these two endings, the game lets you go on raping the women forever.Nature of the Sex in RapeLayAlthough the sex depicted in RapeLay is non-consensual, the actual rapes involve neither violence nor torture. The victims only resist for a brief period before giving in and enjoying it. In RapeLay, despite being a sex-themed adult-only game, the characters have their private parts hidden by a pixel filter. This is because in Japan, it is illegal for genitalia to be shown uncensored, even in hardcore pornography.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15380">Sexy Beach 3</game><game id="22041">Artificial Girl 3</game><game id="23633">Pick Me, Honey!</game><game id="5210">SimuSex</game><game id="16531">X-Change</game><game id="12174">Biko 3</game><game id="11902">Biko 2</game><game id="32581">Biko</game><game id="33437">Sexy Beach</game><game id="35450">Sexy Beach Zero</game><game id="16202">Dead or Alive: Xtreme 2</game><game id="24964">3D Custom Girl</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3715/890678-c243925package.jpg</image></root>