<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16728</id><name>Powerslide</name><description>Story Powerslide is based on a post apocalyptic world, where virtually the whole population has  died. Those that remain are split into two groups; the "freaks" who have been mutated by the radiation, and the "rich" who have set up villages underground to escape any radiation. Powersliding is the freaks recreational activity in which they compete in championships for fresh fruit, which is very rare due to the fallout.  In the game you can control any one of a number of characters and compete in these championships (Novice, Advanced, and Expert) to try and become the top Powerslider.  Gameplay Powerslide was coined as a "go anywhere" arcade racer, this means that within the set courses the player was free to explore any routes they think may be quicker, or to find entirely new routes.  There are three modes: Single race: where you can race on any of the tracks you have unlocked.Timetrial: Where you try to set the fastest time on any of the unlocked tracks.Championship: This is the main mode of the game where you work your way through the three championships to become the top racer. As you complete races and win championships you unlock tracks and cars for use in the other modes. Once beating Expert championship a further Insane championship is unlocked as well as the "supercar" which is the fastest car in the game.Multiplayer Up to 8 players were able to play online and had a choice of two modes to choose from: Single race: which is the same as in singleplayer Fox and hounds: A deathmatch mode where you attempt to destroy as many of the other players as you can using a bomb or the flame shot.  Technology The graphics and sound were very advanced for their time and were praised by the media. The graphics allowed 300,000 polygons on screen at one time while the sound was able to recognise when you moved inside and altered to for echos, making a more immersive experience.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20451">MotorStorm: Pacific Rift</game><game id="1893">POD: Back to Hell</game><game id="20135">POD SpeedZone</game><game id="5279">Interstate '76</game><game id="7436">The Interstate '76 Arsenal</game><game id="8246">Interstate '82</game><game id="13177">FlatOut</game><game id="20998">FlatOut: Head On</game><game id="6836">FlatOut: Ultimate Carnage</game><game id="859">FlatOut 2</game><game id="9707">WipEout</game><game id="3654">WipEout XL</game><game id="20610">WipEout HD</game><game id="20596">WipEout Pulse</game><game id="14796">WipEout Pure</game><game id="15636">Forsaken</game><game id="20484">Burnout</game><game id="8459">Burnout Dominator</game><game id="13514">Burnout 2: Point of Impact</game><game id="4970">Burnout Legends</game><game id="16492">Burnout Revenge</game><game id="357">Burnout 3: Takedown</game><game id="5648">Burnout Paradise</game><game id="11473">Full Auto</game><game id="12142">Full Auto 2: Battlelines</game><game id="12318">Twisted Metal</game><game id="9259">Twisted Metal: Head-On</game><game id="6426">Twisted Metal: Black</game><game id="4635">Twisted Metal III</game><game id="16436">Twisted Metal 2</game><game id="18394">Carmageddon</game><game id="10553">Carmageddon II: Carpocalypse Now</game><game id="11124">Carmageddon TDR 2000</game><game id="786">Destruction Derby</game><game id="13776">Destruction Derby 2</game><game id="16810">Destruction Derby 64</game><game id="21146">Fatal Inertia EX</game><game id="18103">Bandits: Phoenix Rising</game><game id="11573">POD: Planet of Death</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/16706/1653018-powerslide_ar.jpg</image></root>