<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16741</id><name>Devil May Cry 2</name><description>StoryDante and LuciaDevil May Cry 2 starts out with Dante meeting a woman named Lucia while fighting a group of demons. They travel together to Dumary Island and Dante is introduced to Matier, Lucia's mom. Matier at one point had helped Sparda, Dante's father, in protecting the island against demons. Dante is asked to help them fight Arius, a man who uses demonic power and seeks to conquer the world. Dante flips a coin and when it lands on heads he agrees to help.Dante goes in search of the Arcana to prevent Arius from obtaining the items, which he need to summon Argosax. Once Dante retrieves all of the pieces, he tries to hand them off to Matier. She refuses to take them and asks Dante to take them to save Lucia, who has gone to fight Arius. Dante flips a coin again, it lands on heads and he goes to aid Lucia. As he arrives, Lucia is captured by Arius. Dante trades the Arcana to save her life and Arius is able to escape while he saves her.Dante on his motorcycleArius completes the ritual to summon Argosax when Dante arrives. Not worried about it, Dante defeats Arius before the portal to the demon world opens. Lucia and Dante argue over who will go into the portal and close it from the other side. The coin is flipped by Dante. It lands on heads and he leaves the coin with Lucia as he travels on his motorcycle through the portal to fight Argosax. As Dante battles with Argosax, Arius returns to life with demonic power to battle Lucia. Both end up defeating their foes and the portal closes leaving Dante in the demon world.Matier reassures Lucia that Dante should be able to make his way out of the demon world just like his father Sparda did. Lucia takes a look at the coin Dante left her and discovers that both sides are identical. Sometime later, Lucia is at the Devil May Cry, Dante's business, and hears a motorcycle pull up in front of the building. It is left up to the player to speculate whether it was Dante.WeaponsDanteRebellion - Dante's default sword and the most balanced of the swords between reach, speed, and power. Great for the beginning of the game.Vendetta - This is Dante's most powerful sword, but it also has the shortest reach and the slowest movement. Works well for bosses.Merciles - The last sword that Dante can find has a slightly longer reach than any of the other swords.Ebony  Ivory - Dante's trusted firearms. Dante can shoot multiple targets at once with the guns. While DTed, the guns will fire at lightning speed.Sub-machine guns - Dual guns that Dante can use just like Ebony  Ivory. They have an incredibly fast rate of fire with a small amount of recoil.Shotgun - This gun sacrifices speed and maneuverability for tons of power. Proper dodging techinques can make it deadly in the right hands.Rocket Launcher - The most powerful firearm available to Dante, but also the slowest and heaviest one too. It has terrible recoil and can not be fired from the air.LuciaCutlaseer - Lucia's default weapons. A short reach means you will have to get very close to use them.Klyamores - A longer reach and more power make these blades very helpful.Zambak - These are the most powerful melee weapon for Lucia, though they are also the slowest.Throwing Knives - Lucia's default range weapons.Darts - These are less powerful than the knives, but Lucia is able to throw out multiple darts at a time. Can be very useful on groups or flying enemies.Cranky Bombs - These bombs can be set down or thrown depending upon how hard you throw them. Helpful for large groups of enemies.Bow Gun - This gun isn't very powerful but is the only weapon you can use while underwater.SoundtrackDisc One1) Dance with devils2) Overture3) Mission Start4) Eye of the Wind (Lower Town)5) Fire Away (Dante Battle 1)6) Wings of the Guardian (Lucia Battle 1)7) A prayer for Goddes (Lucia Battle 2)8) Mission Clear9) Old Lady10) Underground (Catacomb)11) Eternal (Clock Tower)12) Cursed Giant (Orangguerra/Tartarussian Battle)13) Continue14) Game Over15) Bust the Beast (Goatling/Phantom Battle)16) New Factor17) Parasitic Evil (Jokatgulm Battle)18) Eye of the Wind (Uppertown)19) Assault (Infested Chopper Battle)20) Evil Tower (Nefasturris Battle)21) Mad Factory (Factory)22) Faithful Servant (Furiataurus Battle)23) Realize, Regret...Resolution24) Defective Truth25) Blast Off!Disc Two1) Mysterious Ruins (Dante Ruins)2) Unholy Relics (Lucia Ruins)3) Shoot the Works (Dante Battle 2)4) Demon's Paradise (Lucia Battle 2)5) Uncanny Noise (Noctpteran/Trismagia Battle)6) Encounter7) Power of Will8) Destructive Step (Lower Town, Hell Version)9) Blasphemy (Uroboros Building)10) A Praise of Evil11) Cry for the Moon (Arius Battle)12) Please Kill Me13) Chaotic Gloria14) Sacred Tears15) Against the Fate16) Darkness Instinct (Argosax the Chaos Battle)17) Ragnarok (The Despair Embodied Battle)18) Jackpot!19) All the Way to Hell20) Telling Sweet Lies21) Heads or Tails (Staffroll)22) ~Epilogue~23) Total Result24) Mode Select25) Show Time! (Trish Battle 1)26) Spark it up! (Trish Battle 2)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20553">Ninja Gaiden II</game><game id="6959">God of War</game><game id="11314">God of War II</game><game id="20592">God of War: Chains of Olympus</game><game id="6602">Ninja Gaiden Black</game><game id="2136">Onimusha: Dawn of Dreams</game><game id="9088">Onimusha: Warlords</game><game id="12710">Onimusha 3: Demon Siege</game><game id="19861">Onimusha 2: Samurai's Destiny</game><game id="7337">Van Helsing</game><game id="9037">Gungrave</game><game id="21604">Onechanbara: Bikini Zombie Slayers</game><game id="3440">Zombie Zone</game><game id="11800">Zombie Hunters</game><game id="5554">The Matrix: Path of Neo</game><game id="21497">Simple Series 2000 Vol. 90: The Oneechanbara 2</game><game id="21876">Ninja Gaiden</game><game id="5571">Dirge of Cerberus: Final Fantasy VII</game><game id="1653">Ninja Gaiden</game><game id="1850">Ninja Gaiden III: The Ancient Ship of Doom</game><game id="5581">No More Heroes</game><game id="23866">Fullmetal Alchemist and the Broken Angel</game><game id="20710">Bayonetta</game><game id="18615">Tim Burton's The Nightmare Before Christmas: Oogie's Revenge</game><game id="7043">Evil Dead: A Fistful of Boomstick</game><game id="22999">Onechanbara: Bikini Samurai Squad</game><game id="24987">Harker</game><game id="21637">WarDevil: Unleash the Beast Within</game><game id="10983">Kingdom Hearts</game><game id="22696">The Dishwasher: Dead Samurai</game><game id="5235">Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time</game><game id="9638">ICO</game><game id="15835">Beyond Good &amp; Evil</game><game id="8370">Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets</game><game id="20351">Kya: Dark Lineage</game><game id="577">Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone</game><game id="6290">Batman: Vengeance</game><game id="28001">God of War Collection</game><game id="10990">Genma Onimusha</game><game id="15790">Castlevania: Lament of Innocence</game><game id="2077">The Mark of Kri</game><game id="24042">Ninety-Nine Nights II</game><game id="23035">Nano Breaker</game><game id="32688">Asura's Wrath</game><game id="24309">Dynasty Warriors: Strikeforce</game><game id="32687">Ninja Gaiden 3</game><game id="36285">Onechanbara Z: Kagura</game><game id="39749">Ninja Gaiden 3: Razor's Edge</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1875218-box_dmc2.png</image></root>