<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16842</id><name>Street Fighter: Anniversary Collection</name><description>OverviewHyper Street Fighter II: The Anniversary EditionThis special version of Street Fighter II is based on Super Street Fighter II Turbo as you can choose any incarnation of a certain character from the original Street Fighter II, Championship Edition, Hyper Fighting, Super SFII, and Super Turbo. Of course, this applies to whichever game they debuted as for example Cammy is only allowed to use Super or Super Turbo while Sagat cannot use the original since he wasn't playable then. There are certain advantages towards using a certain style like Super Turbo allowing super moves while using pre-Super styles allows more damage and more chances to get an oppoent dizzy. All four Turbo speeds are in this version of Street Fighter II as well as new arranged music for all the stages.Click here for the article about the individual game.Street Fighter III: 3rd StrikeThe third and final installment in the Street Fighter III series of games features several new characters, a wealth of gameplay changes, brand new stages, sound effects and soundtrack. It is often regarded as one of the best 2D fighters ever made and is still very popular in the tournament scene.Click here for the article about the individual game.PS2 / XBOX version differencesThe major difference between the PS2 and XBOX versions is that the PS2 version came out first in August 2004 while the XBOX version came out later in early 2005 with the inclusion of online play for both Hyper Street Fighter II and Street Fighter III: 3rd Strike. Both versions are backwards compatible on their next-gen counterparts.Other featuresAnother bonus feature for fans of the series is the inclusion of Street Fighter II: The Animated Movie on the disc, but it is an edited version of it.Dreamcast/PS2  Xbox version differencesThe major difference with the Dreamcast/PS2  Xbox version of Third Strike is the PS2  Xbox version ran at a higher resolution and gave players the option to switch to the arcade version of the music(arrange).But with some addtions came with some subtractions.Q's strange winning comments from the Dreamcast version wasn't present in the PS2  Xbox version of the game. Also, in the bonus stages, at the end a horn gets blown. That also wasn't present in the PS2  Xbox version.</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14918">Hyper Street Fighter II: The Anniversary Edition</game><game id="7699">Street Fighter Collection</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/19222/2395328-sfa.jpg</image></root>