<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16859</id><name>Mappy</name><description>Get those electronics back!In Mappy, you are a police mouse whose goal is to to recover stolen electronics stashed away in Nyamco's hideout. To do so, you'll have to avoid Nyamco and his kitty flunkies, the Mewkies. You can slow them down by throwing the door in their face, ringing a bell to stun them, or even get rid of them for good by putting them in the microwave (Argh! Poor little kitties! Don't do that!!). Actually, you don't put them IN the microwave, there are special doors which you can use that blast the cats all the way out of the house. I'm going to assume they survive.The music featured has a very late 19th, early 20th century feel. It can be heard here and the game over music here.Scoring features a multiplier if you gather items in pairs. The items are:RadioTelevisionComputerMona LisaSafeWith the radio being worth 100 points, increasing in 100 point increments with the safe being 500.If the mouse takes too long gathering up the stolen goods, a warning will issue, and then an indestructible enemy will appear and chase it throughout the level. Unlike with the cats, should the enemy meet Mappy in midair he will get hit. There is also a limiter for how many times a player can use a trampoline in a row. Should Mappy bounce too often on one it'll break, causing the mouse to fall (and die if there isn't another trampoline below to break its fall).CharactersMappy: Mappy is the lovable mouse cop hero of the game. He can jump on trampolines, stun Mewkies and Nyamcos with doors, and confiscate stolen items. He also has a billy club that he doesn't use.Mewky: Mewkies (also known as Meowkies in the US version), are the little pink kitty flunkies of the bigger cat mastermind, Nyamco. They will chase after Mappy if they see him. Mappy can knock them silly by opening doors on them, or temporarily get rid of them with the flashing microwave door.Nyamco: Nyamco (also known as Goro in the US version), is the big head honcho cat crime boss. He will also chase after Mappy if he sees him. Sometimes, he'll hide behind a random electronic item and if Mappy takes the item he's hiding behind, he'll score a sweet score bonus for catching Nyamco red-handed. Nyamco is also vulnerable to door slams and the microwave door.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8179">Elevator Action</game><game id="7624">Pac-Man</game><game id="2587">Dig Dug</game><game id="20782">Q*Bert</game><game id="4995">Bubble Bobble</game><game id="24579">Bugs Bunny Crazy Castle 4</game><game id="20020">The New Zealand Story</game><game id="25524">Lode Runner</game><game id="16881">Super Drinker</game><game id="12914">Flicky</game><game id="19743">Gubble</game><game id="19408">Moai Kun</game><game id="23549">Devil World</game><game id="2872">Boggy '84</game><game id="38965">Tasmania Story</game><game id="10038">From the Legend of Balubalouk: Aigiina no Yogen</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5315/369913-mappy.jpg</image></root>