<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>16948</id><name>Mega Man X3</name><description>OverviewThe 3rd installment to the succesful Mega Man X series, X must face a new threat as Dr. Doppler works to obtain a hidden goal that involves destroying everything X had fought for. Released in 1995 and sadly is the last of the X series to appear on the Super Nintendo Entertainment System. Tokura Fuijiwara (producer) Keiji Inafune (characters) and Kinuyo Yamashita (composer) return again to bring you this masterpiece. The game had a short print run and is considered to be somewhat rare. An enhanced version was also released on the Sega Saturn, PlayStation, and PC (referred to as the 32-bit CD version) later that year, and the PC version arrived in North America in 1998; the enhanced version included remixed music and anime-style cutscenes. This was also the last of the X series to use a password system, future Mega man X installments use memory cards to save your progress with.GameplayThe gameplay has only somewhat differed from Mega Man X2 by making the wall jumping slightly easier to preform while reploids become tougher. The gameplay compared to the Mega Man series is much more fast paced with more tricky and more powerful mavericks than ever giving rise to more difficult battles. As a side point, their battles can be completed faster than other bosses in previous games, as they are more susceptible to their weakness, and take more damage from their attacks.StoryThe Doppler research reploid has inspired a revolt in DopplerTown. The Maverick virus has broken through the Doppler anti-virus, and it appears Doppler has caused it. All previous postings here about the anti-virus are incorrect. The anti-virus is a placebo. DopplerTown is over-run with Mavericks. Utopia has ended before it even started. Take cover quickly Virus is spreading rapidly. Cain Laboratory is being infiltrated. Maverick Hunter Units on full alert. Mega Man X and Zero mobilize, there is grave danger!CharactersMega Man X - Reploid leader of the 17th Unit, Maverick Hunters. His creation is shrouded in mystery; nobody knows why he was built and then buried. X is famous among Maverick Hunters for defeating Sigma twice and leading to its ultimate demise. X understands his role, and believes deeply in the need to protect reploids and humans alike. But he has an inner conflict about fighting and violence.Zero - Zero is Mega Man X's best friend and partner. His creation is a mystery as well, yet many rumors and much speculation has arisen. Recently destroyed to protect X, Zero has been revived to continue the aid he has offered X in the past. Once part of the 17th Unit, Maverick Hunters, Zero now leads a Special #0 Class Unit. Always cool and calm, Zero takes quick action against the evil forces he hates so much.Dr. Doppler - A scientist reploid created to support humans in creation of reploids. Equipped with a high-performance neuro-computer, Doppler was instrumental in determining the cause of the recent Maverick outbreak. Its' anti-virus was revolutionary and once again brought peace to the world. Re-programmed he built a Utopian world called DopplerTown where humans and reploids lived in harmony. It grew too quickly and became infected with the same virus it was believed to remedy. Doppler has incited a new Maverick outbreak and has created chaos in DopplerTown. It changed its computer body into one geared for battle and has gathered all the reploids in its first move in war against humans.Bit and Byte - After two Maverick bosses are defeated, Dr. Doppler will send the "Nightmare Police" after X to bring him in. Vile - Once a top henchman for Sigma, Vile was destroyed at the hands of Mega Man X and Zero. When Doppler became virus-infected, its first move was to revive Vile. When Vile became infected with the same computer virus, he went completely nuts. Doppler could not revive Vile. Vile went on a rampage, and has become so stricken with hatred for Mega Man X and Zero, who knows what his intentions are?The PSX version.Playstation/Saturn versionA version of the game was released on the Playstation and Saturn. The version of the game features anime cut-scenes and a remixed soundtrack.Boss Robots(Mavericks)At the end of every level you must fight a boss to proceed, and after fighting all 8 bosses you go to the final fight against Doppler and his army. Here is a list of the boss robots in order to exploit all of their weaknesses.Boss selectionBoss- Blizzard BuffaloWeapon: Frost shieldPower-9200rpSpeed-3200rpWeakness-Parasitic BombBoss- Toxic SeahorseWeapon: Acid BurstPower-5800rpSpeed-4300rpWeakness-Frost ShieldBoss- Tunnel RhinoWeapon: Tornado FangPower-4200rpSpeed-8000rpWeakness-Acid BurstBoss- Volt CatfishWeapon: Triad ThunderPower-8200rpSpeed-1600rpWeakness-Tornado FangBoss- Crush CrawfishWeapon: Spinning BladePower-4000rpSpeed-7600rpWeakness-Triad ThunderBoss- Neon TigerWeapon: Ray SplasherPower-3600rpSpeed-9900rpWeakness-Spinning BladeBoss- Gravity BeetleWeapon: Gravity WellPower-6200rpSpeed-3600rpWeakness-Ray SplasherBoss- Blast HornetWeapon: Parasitic BombPower-3400rpSpeed-8600rpWeakness-Gravity WellUpgradesArmor CapsulesDr. Light has once again hidden some secret capsules that will enhance Mega Man X's abilities. When Mega Man X steps into one of these capsules, it will come to life and change the appearance of Mega Man X. Here are descriptions of some of the Capsules:Boots(Nothing required)-Give you the ability to dash again while in the airLocation-Blizzard Buffalo's lairGun(Boots and T.Fang)-Allows you to charge up one level and fire two powerful shots; also you can charge special weapons.Location-Neon Tiger's lairHelmet(Gun and Triad T.)-A map will appear at the beginning of the level to show you where hidden items are located.Location-Drill Rhino's lairArmor(Boots, G. Well and Gun)-Automatically creates a defense shield on Mega Man X's chassis that reduces damage by 50%. After getting hurt a shield will automatically form around you to lessen damage by 1/2Location-Volt Catfish's lairRobot Ride ArmorIn addition to the armor capsules, Dr. Light has set out 4 different armors known as robot ride armor. Mega Man X and Zero must find these 4 armors, each with different capabilities and functions. The armor looks like a giant robot that they can activate by jumping into it. Once you find an armor, you may use the armor in any stage where you may find the Robot Ride platforms.If you have found an armor, the platform will activate. A menu will appear just to the left of the platform, so use the game pad or the arrow keys to select which armor you would like to use. While in the robot ride armor, Mega Man X and Zero will not be damaged. The armor can be damaged, but can be healed by returning to the platform. If the armor is destroyed, you cannot use it again until you enter a new stage. You can also jump out if need be by jumping while holding up on the D-pad.Robot Ride ArmorsChimeraHawkFrogKangarooSoundtrackCover ArtIn 2005 Capcom released a 5-disc box set called Capcom Music Generation Rockman X1~6. It contains the original music of Mega Man X through Mega Man X6 as well as some unused tracks. Mega Man X3 tracks span the entire second disc containing both the SNES (tracks 1-29) and Saturn/Playstation (tracks 30-69) arranged tracks. The track listing is as follows:Track #TitleLength1.OPENING0:542.TITLE0:123.PASS WORD0:414.OPENING STAGE0:445.ZERO1:136.STAGE SELECT0:217.STAGE START0:148.EXPLOSE HORNECK STAGE1:429.FROZEN BUFFALIO STAGE1:3510.GRAVITY BEETBOOD STAGE1:5711.ACID SEAFORCE STAGE1:4912.ELECTRO NAMAZUROS STAGE1:5213.SCISSORS SHRIMPER STAGE1:3314.SCREW MASAIDER STAGE1:5815.SHINING TIGERD STAGE2:1016.VAVA STAGE1:2717.BOSS 10:2418.BOSS 20:3419.STAGE CLEAR0:0620.STAGE SELECT 20:3121.DOPPLER STAGE 11:1722.DOPPLER STAGE 22:3123.DOPPLER STAGE BOSS0:4024.SIGMA 1st0:4725.SIGMA 2nd1:1426.DOPPLER DEMO1:0927.Dr.RIGHT0:4928.ENDING1:2829.CAST ROLL2:3130.OPENING1:1831.TITLE0:1432.PASS WORD0:4133.OPENING STAGE DEMO0:2834.OPENING STAGE2:0035.ZERO0:5236.STAGE SELECT 10:1937.EXPLOSE HORNECK DEMO0:2538.EXPLOSE HORNECK STAGE1:5239.FROZEN BUFFALIO DEMO0:2940.FROZEN BUFFALIO STAGE1:4941.GRAVITY BEETBOOD DEMO0:2642.GRAVITY BEETBOOD STAGE1:5843.ACID SEAFORCE DEMO0:2544.ACID SEAFORCE STAGE1:5345.ELECTRO NAMAZUROS DEMO0:2346.ELECTRO NAMAZUROS STAGE1:5247.SCISSORS SHRIMPER DEMO0:2348.SCISSORS SHRIMPER STAGE1:3649.SCREW MASAIDER DEMO0:2250.SCREW MASAIDER STAGE1:4851.SHINING TIGERD DEMO0:2352.SHINING TIGERD STAGE1:3653.VAVA STAGE1:3054.BOSS 10:4555.BOSS 20:3656.STAGE CLEAR0:1057.DEMO0:2158.STAGE SELECT 20:2859.DOPPLER STAGE 11:3760.DOPPLER STAGE 22:2061.DOPPLER STAGE BOSS0:3662.SIGMA 1st0:5063.SIGMA 2nd0:5964.DOPPLER DEMO1:1365.Dr.KEIN DEMO0:3266.Dr.RIGHT DEMO0:4867.ENDING 12:0068.ENDING 20:2269.CAST ROLL2:41</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8292">Super Metroid</game><game id="5708">Metroid II: Return of Samus</game><game id="10323">Metroid Fusion</game><game id="17356">Metroid: Zero Mission</game><game id="21761">Metroid</game><game id="14216">Castlevania: Symphony of the Night</game><game id="6673">Castlevania</game><game id="20627">Castlevania: Order of Ecclesia</game><game id="16851">Castlevania: The Dracula X Chronicles</game><game id="1063">Metal Slug 3</game><game id="2190">Gunstar Heroes</game><game id="17452">Alien Hominid</game><game id="8583">Metal Slug Advance</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2363969-snes_megamanx3.jpg</image></root>