<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17041</id><name>MechWarrior 2: Mercenaries</name><description>Overveiw Mercenaries' Title Card Developed and published by Activision, MechWarrior 2: Mercenaries was released in September of 1996 as a stand-alone sequel to MechWarrior 2: 31st Century Combat; it would be the last MechWarrior title created by Activision before the company lost the rights to the BattleTech franchise. As with previous games in the MechWarrior 2 line, gameplay focuses on the actions of large BattleMechs (or 'Mechs) in various combat situations, with an emphasis on simulation-style controls over straightforward action. Unlike the previous games, Mercenaries includes an detailed economy in which players can salvage parts from the battlefield and purchase new 'Mechs with the credits earned from their missions. While it uses the MechWarrior 2 graphics engine, Mercenaries features a number of tweaks such as more detailed textures and lighting.  While MechWarrior 2 and its expansion Ghost Bear's Legacy focused on Clan activites, Mercenaries' story unfolds from the perspective of an Inner Sphere mercenary. Due to this change, many new Inner Sphere 'Mechs are introduced in Mercenaries, with the total number of usable vehicles being more than twice that of the previous games. Plot Happening before the Refusal War conflict depicted in MechWarrior 2, the plot of Mercenaries focuses on an independent mercenary unit taking contracts from various factions within the Inners Sphere. The War of 3039 has recently ended, and it is a period of relative calm, with both major powers, the Draconis Combine and the Federated Commonwealth, recuperating and rebuilding in order to prepare for their next war. The player can take various jobs from either faction, as well as from others such as Comstar and the Free Rasalhague Republic, in addition to participating in closed arena competitions. The player's mercenary activities are abruptly interrupted by the Clan invasion, and during the latter part of the game their mercenary unit is swept up in the ensuing war. The final event depicted in the campaign is the Battle of Tukayyid, the decisive confrontation between the Clans and the Inner Sphere that precipitated the Refusal War of MechWarrior 2.Gameplay The Starport functions as the hub for all activities during the campaign. The gameplay of MechWarrior 2: Mercenaries remains largely unchanged over previous iterations in the series. Players are still required to display adept handling of various BattleMechs while simultaneously keeping tabs on its various systems, such as heat dissipation, targeting, and radar display. While the missions themselves are unchanged, Mercenaries allows a larger degree of freedom outside of battle by giving players more control of the specifics leading up to each engagement. From their office players are allowed to purchase and sell 'Mechs, hire new pilots, and decide which missions to take. Furthermore, players must be aware of the game's economy even during missions, as performance determines what is salvaged; anything from individual parts to full 'Mech chassis can be taken from the battlefield. The single-player component of Mercenaries is split into three modes: Mercenary Commander, Mercenary, and Instant Action. Mercenary Commander is the main campaign mode, with all of Mercenaries' economic elements enabled, while Mercenary is a simplified version of the campaign which plays more similar to previous games in the series. Finally, Instant Action is a slightly expanded version of the Trials of Grievance and Combat Simulation modes of the past two games. Players can choose 'Mechs (both theirs and their opponents') and mission objectives before engaging in a randomly generated combat scenario.'MechsMercenaries introduces roughly 40 new 'Mechs for players to pilot, the majority of which are of Inner Sphere design. In addition, many of the Clan 'Mechs featured in the previous MechWarrior 2 games return, though the campaign focuses mostly on the new Inner Sphere additions. Finally, two types of 1-ton battle armor are selectable during Instant Action.'MechClassificationWeightTop SpeedJump JetsDefault WeaponsHornet Light 'Mech20 tons86.4 kphThree1 Medium Laser1 LRM-5Commando Light 'Mech25 tons97.2 kphNone1 Medium Laser1 SRM-41 SRM6Mongoose Light 'Mech25 tons130 kphThree1 Small Laser3 Medium LasersBattle Hawk Light 'Mech30 tons86.4 kphFive3 Medium Pulse Lasers1 Streak SRM-2Javelin Light 'Mech30 tons97.2 kphSix2 SRM-6sUrbanMech Light 'Mech30 tons32.4 kphTwo1 Small Laser1 Autocannon 10Jenner Light 'Mech35 tons118.8 kphFive4 Medium Lasers1 SRM-4Panther Light 'Mech35 tons64.8 kphFour1 PPC1 SRM-4Raven Light 'Mech35 tons92.7 kphNone3 Medium Lasers1 SRM-6Assassin Medium 'Mech40 tons118.8 kphSeven1 Medium Laser1 SRM-21 LRM-5Cicada Medium 'Mech40 tons129.6 kphNone1 Small Laser2 Medium LasersClint Medium 'Mech40 tons97.2 kphSix2 Medium Lasers1 Autocannon 5Sentinel Medium 'Mech40 tons97.2 kphNone1 Small Laser1 Autocannon 51 SRM-2Whitworth Medium 'Mech40 tons64.8 kphFour3 Medium Lasers2 LRM-10sVindicator Medium 'Mech45 tons64.8 kphFour1 Small Laser1 Medium Lasr1 PPC1 LRM-5Wolf Trap Medium 'Mech45 tons97.2 kphThree1 Medium Laser1 LRM-5Centurion Medium 'Mech50 tons64.8 kphNone2 Medium Lasers1 Autocannon 101 LRM-10Crab Medium 'Mech50 tons86.4 kphNone1 Small Laser1 Medium Laser2 Large LasersHunchback Medium 'Mech50 tons64.8 kphNone1 Small Laser2 Medium Lasers1 Autocannon 20Trebuchet Medium 'Mech50 tons86.4 kphNone3 Medium Lasers2 LRM-15sGrim Reaper Medium 'Mech55 tons86.4 kphNone1 Medium Pulse Laser1 ER Large Laser1 SRM-61 LRM-20Dragon Heavy 'Mech60 tons86.4 kphNone2 Medium Lasers1 Autocannon 51 LRM-10Quickdraw Heavy 'Mech60 tons86.4 kphFive4 Medium Lasers1 SRM-41 LRM-10Bombardier Heavy 'Mech65 tons86.4 kphNone1 Machine Gun1 SRM-42 LRM-20sCatapult Heavy 'Mech65 tons64.8 kphFour4 Medium Lasers2 LRM-15sCauldron-Born Heavy 'Mech65 tons86 kphNone1 ER Medium Laser1 LB 5-X Autocannon1 Gauss Rifle1 SRM-21 LRM-10Jagermech Heavy 'Mech65 tons64.8 kphNone2 Medium Lasers2 Large Lasers2 LRM-15sFlashman Heavy 'Mech75 tons86.4 kphNone1 Flamer5 Medium Lasers2 Large LasersOrion Heavy 'Mech75 tons64.8 kphNone2 Medium Lasers1 Autocannon 101 SRM-41 LRM-15Rakshasa Heavy 'Mech75 tons86.4 kphNone2 Medium Lasers2 ER Large Lasers1 Medium Pulse Laser2 LRM-10sAwesome Assault 'Mech80 tons54 kphNone1 Small Laser3 PPCsHatamoto-Chi Assault 'Mech80 tons64.8 kphNone2 PPCs2 SRM-6sSalamander Assault 'Mech80 tons64.8 kphNone2 Medium Lasers3 LRM-20sThug Assault 'Mech80 tons64.8 kphNone2 PPCs2 SRM-4sVictor Assault 'Mech80 tons64.8 kphFour2 Medium Lasers1 Autocannon 201 SRM-4Zeus Assault 'Mech80 tons64.8 kphNone2 Medium Lasers1 Large Laser1 Autocannon 51 LRM-15Stalker Assault 'Mech85 tons54 kphNone4 Medium Lasers2 Large Lasers2 SRM-6s2 LRM-10sCyclops Assault 'Mech90 tons64.8 kphNone2 Medium Lasers1 Autocannon 201 SRM-41 LRM-10Highlander Assault 'Mech90 tons54 kphNone2 Medium Lasers1 Autocannon 201 SRM-41 LRM-10Mauler Assault 'Mech90 tons54 kphNone2 Large Lasers4 Autocannon 2s2 LRM-15sAnnihilator Assault 'Mech100 tons32.4 kphNone4 Medium Pulse Lasers4 LB 10-X AutocannonsAtlas Assault 'Mech100 tons54 kphNone4 Medium Lasers1 Autocannon 201 SRM-61 LRM-20</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1407">MechWarrior 2: 31st Century Combat</game><game id="5305">MechWarrior 4: Inner Sphere 'Mech Pak</game><game id="13931">MechWarrior</game><game id="18365">MechCommander 2</game><game id="17438">MechAssault</game><game id="17861">MechAssault 2: LoneWolf</game><game id="17059">MechAssault: Phantom War</game><game id="8805">BattleTech: The Crescent Hawks' Revenge</game><game id="16621">BattleTech: The Crescent Hawk's Inception</game><game id="19719">Chromehounds</game><game id="13461">Ultrabots</game><game id="17675">Armored Core 4</game><game id="12849">Heavy Gear</game><game id="9122">Front Mission Online</game><game id="13569">Heavy Gear II</game><game id="4602">10six Online</game><game id="25296">Lore: Aftermath</game><game id="25684">Murakumo: Renegade Mech Pursuit</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/11/118253/1751061-mw2mercenariesboxart.jpg</image></root>