<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17070</id><name>F.E.A.R. Combat</name><description>Overview F.E.A.R. Combat is the multiplayer component from F.E.A.R. - First Encounter Assault Recon. It is available for free to download. The multiplayer modes it has include Deathmatch, Team Deathmatch, Last Man Standing and Capture the Flag. F.E.A.R. Combat users can play together with owners of F.E.A.R. - First Encounter Assault Recon. Weapons and ItemsBang Bang AT-14 Pistol - The standard F.E.A.R operative side arm. The AT-14 Pistol is capable of firing a single shot and has a fairly fast rate of fire. Dual AT-14 Pistols - In F.E.A.R Combat the player is capable of equipping two AT-14 pistols at a time. This allows for twice as much firepower at the price of increased recoil. RPL Sub-Machinegun - Although it is not as powerful as the G2A2 Assault Rifle the Sub Machinegun makes up for its weakness with its impressive rate of fire (one of the highest in the game). This allows the player to effectively spray a room full of bullets and possibly hit an enemy or two in the process.  G2A2 Assault Rifle - Being one of the most versatile weapons in the game the G2A2 Assault Rifle is effective at both short and long range combative situations. The only exception to its perks is the lack of accuracy. VK-12 Combat Shotgun - The Combat Shotgun is the most effective close-range starting weapon in FEAR Combat. HV Penetrator - This weapon fires huge bullets which resemble nails. The HV Penetrator is one of the most powerful starting weapons in F.E.A.R Combat; in fact the Penetrator is so powerful that a victim may be nailed against a wall as a result of being hit by the nail like projectile. ASP Rifle - The ASP Rifle fires a short burst of 3 bullets and features a scope allowing the player to be unbelievably effective at a long range.  MOD-3 Multi-Rocket Launcher - This weapon fires three rocket projectiles and is almost guaranteed to kill your opponent in one hit. The only downside to this weapon its low ammo capacity. Type-7 Particle Weapon - The Particle Weapon is the most powerful weapon in the game. Anyone who comes into contact with the particle blast is instantly vaporized into a pile of bones.  P-50 Repeating Cannon - The P-50 Repeating Cannon fires explosive slugs and does extremely high amounts of damage. N6A3 Fragmentation Grenade - A typical frag grenade which explodes on impact whenever it comes into contact with a human body, however it has a small countdown before exploding whenever it does not land on another player. AT-S Proximity Grenade - A grenade that explodes whenever someone comes within its proximity. This is a great weapon to use as a trap.  M77 Remote Mine - Like the Proximity Grenade the Remote Mine is an amazing weapon when used for a trap. The grenade sticks to any surface, humans included, and explodes whenever the player presses the button on the detonator. Med Kits - Med Kits are used to restore the player's health.  Body Armor - Body Armor provides extra protection against bullets and sometimes explosives.  </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21388">Quake Live</game><game id="4745">Soldier of Fortune II: Double Helix</game><game id="3874">Quake III Arena</game><game id="20465">Condemned 2: Bloodshot</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1479/294542-fear_combat.jpg</image></root>