<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17134</id><name>Mega Man: Dr. Wily's Revenge</name><description>Overview:The Title ScreenMega Man: Dr. Wily’s Revenge is the first portable entry in the Mega Man series. Because of limited space on the Game Boy cartridge, the game only contained complete stages for four Robot Masters, plus Dr. Wily’s fortress and space station. The game uses a grid based password feature to allow the player to complete the game in multiple sittings, similar to what was found in other Mega Man games for the NES. Despite being on the original Gameboy, the game was noted for having the catchy music and strong controls that was characteristic of most early Mega Man games.Levels and Robot Masters:The First Four Robot MastersAt the start, the player can choose from four different stages, each containing a robot master taken from Mega Man for the NES (Elec Man, Fire Man, Ice Man, and Cut Man). After defeating the four Robot Masters, Mega Man heads to Dr. Wily’s Fortress stage. At the end of this stage you encounter four additional Robot Masters, taken from Mega Man II for the NES ( Bubble Man, Heat Man, Flash Man, and Quick Man). After defeating these four Robot Masters you take on an original Robot Boss called Enker. Finally, Mega Man travels to Dr. Wily’s space station stage to take on Dr. Wily himself.Weapons and Items:As in most Mega Man games, Mega Man acquires the ability to use the weapons of the Robot Masters that he defeats. This includes the original four Robot Masters, the four additional Robot Masters encountered in Dr. Wily’s Fortress, and the special boss Enker. The weapons are:The Carry ItemCut Man: Rolling Cutter – Shoots a powerful cutter that boomerangs out and then back. Very effective against Elec Man.Elec Man : Thunder Beam – Shoots a tall electric beam. Very effective against Ice Man.Ice Man : Ice Slasher – Shoots an icy blast that can freeze some enemies. Very effective against Fire Man.Fire Man : Fire Storm – Shoots a fire blast towards the enemy and creates a shield of fire that temporarily surrounds Mega Man. Somewhat effective against Cut Man.Bubble Man : Bubble Lead – Shoots a bubble which travels along the floor. Very effective against Heat Man.Heat Man : Atomic Fire – Shoots a heat blast that can be charged up. Somewhat effective against Quick Man and Flash Man.Quick Man : Quick Boomerang – Shoots several small boomerangs which travel out, and then back. Somewhat effective against Bubble Man and Heat Man.Flash Man : Time Stopper – Freezes time and damages the enemy. Very effective against Quick Man.Enker: Mirror Buster – Creates an energy shield that protects Mega Man and can even deflect some enemy attacks. Very effective against Dr. Wily’s final machine.In addition, Mega Man obtains a special item called the “Carry” after completing the first four Robot Master stages. This item allows Mega Man to create a temporary platform that can be used to traverse large pits or reach otherwise inaccessible areas.Cheats and Passwords:To access Dr. Wily's fortress stage, use the password: A2, A3, B4, C2, C3</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1806086-box_mmgb1.png</image></root>