<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17213</id><name>Jane's Combat Simulations: F-15</name><description>OverviewFlames on the title? SOLDJane's F-15 is a combat flight simulator developed by Origin Systems, which then became EA Baltimore, and published by EA. It was directed by Andy Hollis who was also a programmer for Microprose's F-15 Strike Eagle II and F-15 Strike Eagle III. As such, Jane's F-15 can be considered the spiritual successor to those games, with some people calling it F-15 Strike Eagle IV. Though it came out at the same year as Falcon 4.0, the flight sim that threatened to end all flight sims, Jane's F-15 sold reasonably well enough to warrant a sequel, Jane's F/A-18. The game's graphics engine was reused in the EA budget title: Fighter Pilot. Jane's F-15 remains one of the most realistic flight sims and is, for now, the most realistic at simulating the F-15E Strike Eagle.GameplayJane's f-15 cockpit upperJane's F-15 is the most realistic flight simulator for the F-15E. Every knob, switch, button and light in the cockpit works as it does on the real fighter jet. Jane's F-15 is not a perfect emulation of the Strike Eagle as there are still some classified materials regarding that aircraft. Though the aircraft in real life has been known to rarely go into a flat spin, in game it is very hard to perform such a feat. The player flies from the pilots seat of the aircraft and uses the mouse to press the buttons/ switches in the cockpit or uses a hotkey/ button on the keyboard/ joystick. The player can also switch to the Weapon's Systems Officer (WSO) seat and operate the aircraft from that position. The WSO typically guides the weapons to the target and manages the radar though in the game, its not especially important in the game as everything can be done from the pilot's seat.The game features many external camera views, typical in a Jane's Combat Flight Sim, though there is no HUD in these views. The player can command a flight of up to eight planes including the player's own. This allows flexibility during missions as some wingmen can be configured for air to air while others for air to ground. The player has a large extensive list of wingman orders at his disposal allowing the player to set the formation type and how the wingmen engage their targets. A computer generated voice, acting as the WSO, will constantly provide updates to the player.Training ScreenBecause this game is a flight sim, it has a steep learning curve of 10+ hours. To help the player, the game features a 20+ mission tutorial in addition to a thick manual to teach the player how to fly. Training missions are short and simple, teaching only one lesson such as firing the AIM-9 or dropping the GBU-15. Numerous options can also be turned on to allow the game to be slightly less realistic such as "no blackout" or "infinite ammo". The official strategy guide published by Prima has over 320 pages detailing procedures and what to do in specific situations.The game features two campaigns, one set during Desert Storm and the other in a fictional campaign with Iran. Unlike other Jane's Combat Sims, the campaign in Jane's F-15 is fully dynamic allowing for random events to happen. Numerous real world aircraft populate the game as NPC's and the player can call on allies for help. The game also features a single mission mode, where a random mission is played, as well as a mission editor to allow the player to create their own missions.The game features 4v4 air to air multiplayer via LAN or online. There are no co-op missions in this game.WeaponsArming ScreenBecause the F-15E is capable of fielding almost the entire US arsenal of bombs and missiles, a wide variety of ordnance is available for the player. Weapons behave and must be guided realistically unless the player turns on cheats. Players have the option to make their own loadouts and save them or use preset loadouts used by the US Air ForceM61A1 Vulcan 20mm Gatling GunM56A3 HEI (High Explosive Incendiary) ammoPGU-28A SAPHEI (Semi-Armor Piercing High Explosive Incendiary) ammoAir-to-Air MissilesAIM-9L/M/P SidewinderShort-Ranged Infrared Guided MissileThe L model is all-aspect capableThe M model is the L model with a reduced-smoke rocketThe P model is an improved B/E/J/N model originally for export but many exist in the US inventoryAIM-7F/M SparrowMedium Range SARH (Semi-Active Radar Homing)The F model has improved reliability compared to older SparrowsThe M model is the most common variant of the SparrowAIM-120A AMRAAMAdvanced Medium-Range Air-to-Air MissileActive Radar HomingAir-to-Ground MissilesAGM-65D/G MaverickThe D model is an electro-optically (TV) guided infrared air-to-ground missile with 125lb warheadThe G model is a D with a 300 lb warhead.Unguided BombsMk 82/84Mk 82 is a 500 lb bombMk 84 is a 2000 lb bombBSU-49/-50High drag bombs for low altitude droppingBSU-49 is a modified Mk 82BSU-50 is a modified Mk 84BLU-107 DurandalFrench made450 lb bomb330 lb warheadLow Altitude DroppedParachute provides dragAnti-RunwayLeaves 200m diameter craterCluster BombsCBU-52785 lbs220 bombletsAnti-PersonnelCBU-58/A800 lbs650 bombletsAnti-Personnel"A" model is IncendiaryCBU-71/ASimilar to CBU-58800 lbs650 bombletsBomblets are random time delayed"A" model is IncendiaryCBU-78 Gator500 lb45 Anti-Tank Mines15 Anti-Personnel MinesCBU-87 Combined Effects Munitions (CEM)950 lbs202 Combined Effects MunitionsAnti-Personnel/Light ArmorCBU-89 GatorA bigger CBU-781000 lbs72 Anti-Tank Mines22 Anti-Personnel MinesCBU-97 Sensor Fused Weapon (SFW)1000 lbs10 bombletsEach bomblet has 4 anti-tank munitionsInfrared detectionExplodes automatically if no tanks are detected after a period of timeMk-20 Rockeye II500 lbs247 bombletsAnti-TankGuided BombsGBU-10/-10E/-10G Paveway I/II/IIILaser Guided BombGBU-10 is a Mk 84 with a laser guidance kitGBU-10E is a Mk 84 with an improved laser guidance kitGBU-10G is a BLU-109, 2000 lb penetrator warhead, with improved laser guidance kitGBU-12/-12D Paveway I/IILaser Guided BombGBU-12 is a Mk 82 with laser guidance kitGBU-12D has an improved laser guidance kitGBU-15 v 1/2/31/32The F-15E's signature weaponGuided 2000 lb bombv1 uses a Mk 84 bomb and daylight only TV guidancev2 uses a Mk 84 bomb and imaging infrared guidancev31 uses a BLU-109 penetrator with TV guidancev32 uses a BLU-109 with imaging infrared guidanceRequires AN/AXQ-14 Data Link PodGBU-24/-24A Paveway IIILaser Guided 2000 lb bombGBU-24 uses a Mk 84 bombGBU-24A uses a BLU-109 penetratorGBU-28Laser Guided5000 lb bunker busterMiscellaneousAN/ALE-40 1/2/3Chaff and flare dispensers(1) has 120 chaff/ 60 flares(2) has 180 chaff/ 30 flares(3) has 60 chaff/ 90 flaresLANTIRN (Low Altitude Navigation and Targeting Infrared for Night)AN/AAQ-13 Navigation PodAN/AAQ-14 Targeting PodAN/AXQ-14 Data LinkExternal Fuel Tanks</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="24">Flight Simulator</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14628">Falcon 4.0</game><game id="12506">Flanker 2.0</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/86580/1516303-f15box.jpg</image></root>