<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17295</id><name>Mortal Kombat Mythologies: Sub-Zero</name><description> Overview  Sub-Zero, the titular protagonist     Mortal Kombat Mythologies: Sub-Zero is a 2D action-adventure platformer developed and published by  Midway for the                                  Sony PlayStation on October 1, 1997. Ported to the                                Nintendo 64 on December 8, 1997 by                               Avalanche, Mortal Kombat Mythologies: Sub-Zero is a                             spin-off title to the                              Mortal Kombat fighting game series, focusing on a narrow group of primary characters while serving as a prologue to the original                            Mortal Kombat (similar to                           Mortal Kombat: Special Forces, released three years later). The game blends fighting game mechanics of                          Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3 with a beat-em-up platformer, adding some elements of RPGs (such as an inventory system and                         experience point system, where the player learns new special moves as he defeats opponents). Mortal Kombat Mythologies: Sub-Zero is also the last Mortal Kombat game to feature                        digitized characters and the only Mortal Kombat game to have                     live-action cutscenes.In the game, players take the role of the              original      Sub-Zero (a ninja of the            Lin Kuei clan with the mastery of           frost-based attacks) who, after infiltrating the                 Shaolin Temple to steal the Sacred                Map of Elements (defeating, with the potential of killing,               Scorpion in the process), is sent by the mysterious sorceror        Quan Chi to retrieve a mysterious       amulet located in the Temple of Elements. It is revealed later, however, that Quan Chi is using this amulet to resurrect the dark fallen Elder God      Shinnok. After being confronted by     Raiden, god of thunder, the player must travel to the    Netherrealm, searching for the whereabouts of Quan Chi while fighting his three assassins (Kia, Jataaka, and   Sareena).GameplayLike Mortal Kombat 3, Mythologies consisted of 4 attack buttons, a block button, and a run button.  The game also used a "turn" button to deal with attackers on    either side of Sub-Zero, accompanied by an “action” button used for items. The gameplay took place on a 2D plane that consisted of a fighting system very similar to that of the Mortal Kombat fighting series. The "turn" button would alleviate the issue of Sub-Zero turning away from an opponent while performing a special move.  Platforming was also part of the 2D scrolling gameplay. Sub-Zero’s special abilities extinguished  an “Ice Meter” that was replenished by retrieving items.    Sub-Zero does not start the game with all his special abilities. The aforementioned "Ice Meter" does not appear until Sub-Zero learns abilities that use it. The system is very RPG-like in nature as it tracks experience points, ability upgrades, and inventory.</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9710">Batman Returns</game><game id="13568">Batman &amp; Robin</game><game id="29500">Streets of Fury</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1529068-mkmsz_box.png</image></root>