<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17357</id><name>Prince of Persia: Warrior Within</name><description>OverviewA very different tone from its predecessorPrince of Persia: Warrior Within is an action adventure game. Like Sands of Time, it has a strong emphasis on platforming and combat against numerous opponents. Both of these aspects of gameplay exemplify the Prince's reality-defying strength, agility, and acrobatic ability.One of the most obvious aspects of Prince of Persia: Warrior Within is its departure from the bright visuals of its predecessor. Inspired by the gritty aesthetics of games such as Silent Hill, it presents a much darker artistic style and story. An additional controversial change to the franchise is the Prince himself, having adopted a harsher, rougher tone and conduct.These stylistic changes are justified by the story progression of the game. For years, the Prince finds himself hunted by an unstoppable force, and the stress and strain have taken its toll on the Prince's charm and goodwill. What's left is a grim determination to survive.GameplayCombatPrince of Persia returns with a greater emphasis on combat. Throughout the game, the Prince will pit himself against groups of enemies and the occassional one-on-one boss. In order to dispose of these opponents, the player uses special input sequences to perform combos. He is now able to dual wield and throw weapons. Additionally, the Prince may utilize the environment to his advantage, attacking while running along walls or swinging around pillars.One of Ubisoft's primary concerns was to improve the combat system, which was often perceived as repetitive and simplistic in Sands of Time. New moves and abilities facilitate far greater variety in how players can deal with multiple enemies in more complex combat arenas. When the Prince ends an enemy is a particularly grizzly fashion, the game will slow down and the camera will adopt a more cinematic angle.PuzzlesWarrior Within's puzzle elements are not particularly difficult but do rely on a lot of movement within the environment (which involves tiresome repetition). Also like its predecessor, puzzles are usually relegated to the switch, lever, door variety: push a button to open a door then run to the door before it closes.The Dahaka ChasesAt certain moments in the game the Dahaka will find the Prince. When this happens the Prince will have to run for his life. Ubisoft added this new gameplay element to change up the flow of the game from a steady mix of combat and puzzles to add adrenaline fueled chase sequences where you have to think on your feet in order to figure out where to platform to stay a step ahead of the Dahaka. As the Prince, these will only occur in the present but as the Sand Wraith these will occasionally occur in the past. Either way these sequences will always end when you get to a time portal as the Dahaka can not pass the small water that passes through the doorway in the time portals. Whenever the Dahaka speaks it will be in reverse, but if you rewind time after he speaks then it will be played normally.Plot SynopsisSeven years after Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time, the Prince finds himself hunted by the invincible Dahaka, the Guardian of the Timeline. By manipulating the Sands, the Prince was able to cheat death and avoid his fate, something the Dahaka will not tolerate.The Prince's ship attackedAlways on the run and desperate to cease its pursuit, the Prince learns from an old man about the Island of Time, birthplace of the Sands of Time. The Prince sets sail; his mission: to prevent the Sands of Time from ever being created, altering the timeline and undoing all the Prince's mistakes so that the Dahaka will have no quarrel with him. Unfortunately, the Prince's ship is attacked by Shahdee and a small group of soldiers. When the Prince faces her in combat, he is thrown overboard. The Prince manages to drift ashore and follows the woman into the Palace of Time. During his pursuit, he discovers magical, time-manipulating portals.Using the portals to travel into the deep past, the Prince encounters Shahdee attempting to murder a mysterious woman in red, Kaileena. The Prince kills Shahdee, and the rescued Kaileena explains to him that she is a servant to the Empress of Time. She also explains to the Prince that to gain an audience with the Empress of Time he must activate two towers, which will open the doors to her throne room. Kaileena aids the Prince by giving him weapons which are used to activate the towers. Mysteriously during his quest, the Prince encounters a dark creature that vanishes into the shadows.The Prince and KaileenaAfter activating the towers, the Prince is attacked by the Dahaka and is almost killed, but the dark creature from before appears and is killed in his place. Immediately afterwards, the Dahaka inexplicably leaves.The Prince eventually succeeds in reaching the throne room only to discover that Kaileena is actually the Empress of Time. She has foreseen her death by the Prince's hands and has been trying to avoid her fate by killing him. They engage in mortal combat, and the Prince kills Kaileena. He returns to the present, satisfied that Kaileena will never be able to create the Sands of Time. To his horror, he discovers that Kaileena's body has spawned the Sands. The Prince in trying to change his fate became an intrument in the Sands of Time's creation.The sand wraithStill on the Island of Time, the Prince discovers the Mask of the Wraith, an ancient artifact that allows its wearer to coexists with his past self in the same timeline. Placing the mask on his face, he transforms into a sand wraith, the very creature the Prince witnessed die at the hands of the Dahaka. Travelling back into the past through the sand portals, the Prince returns to the moment when he witnessed the sand wraith's death. Instead of rescuing the Prince, however, he allows the Dahaka to kill his past self. The Dahaka appeased, it vanishes, and the Prince removes the mask, returning to human form.Still in the past, the Prince continues his quest to undo the creation of the Sands of Time. Instead of killing Kaileena, he forces her through a sand portal into the present. It is at this point the game diverges into two alternate endings:Without the Water SwordThe DahakaThe Prince kills Kaileena again. The Dahaka reappears and takes Kaileena's body since it is now she who is out of place in the timeline. It also claims the Prince's medallion, another relic of the Sands, and then fades into nonexistance. The Prince sets sail for Babylon. As the Prince sails he sees his kingdom aflame.You hear the Old Man saying "Your journey will not end well.You cannot change your fate,no man can."Before the credits roll you hear the Prince say "What have I done?"With the Water Sword (canon)The Prince spares Kaileena's life. The Dahaka reappears to claim her life since it is now she who is cheating fate. The Prince, however, defeats the Dahaka using the magic of the Water Sword. The Prince and Kaileena set sail for Babylon together. As they sail back the Prince and Kaileena embrace each other(it looks like sex but they're clothed)and Kaileena gets a vision of the future.Men fighting and dieing,a mysterious figure in a cloak picking up the crown which belongs to the Prince's father,Farah on a cross and Babylon in flames.The last thing you hear before the credits roll is the Old Man saying "Your journey will not end well.You cannot change your fate,no man can."Ubisoft used this cliffhanger ending foreshadow Prince Of Persia: The Two Thrones.ReceptionMany existing fans of the franchise, series creator Jordan Mechner included, have found the changes in tone and character unappealing. The Prince is often accused of excessive baditude and even alienating fans of preceding games. Many of these complaints were addressed in the game's sequel, The Two Thrones.Controversy over tone aside, the gameplay is generally held in high regard, though opinons differ on the game's stronger emphasis on combat.System RequirementsSupported OS: Windows 98SE/2000/XP (only)Processor: Pentium III 1 GHz or AMD Athlon 1 GHzRam: 256 MBVideo Card: DirectX 9-compliant graphics cardSupported Video Cards at Time of Release: Nvidia Geforce 3/4/FX series (including 4MX), ATI Radeon 7500/8500/9000 families or newerSound Card: DirectX 8-compliant sound cardCD-ROM: 16X CD-ROM or 4X DVD-ROMHard Drive Space: 2 GBSoundtrackThe soundtrack was composed by Stuart Chatwood with Inon Zur, and released in October 2005 by Team Entertainment/Sony Music Distribution in Japan. Some of the tracks from this game, along with Chatwood's music from Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time and Prince of Persia: The Two Thrones, were re-released by Ubisoft Music in December 2005 as part of Prince of Persia: The Official Trilogy Soundtrack.Prince of Persia: Warrior Within - Original Soundtrack (Stuart Chatwood, Inon Zur)No.Track TitleLength (62:24)1."Welcome Within"1:202."Attack at Sea"2:153."Conflict at the Entrance"2:104."Tower Encounter"2:125."Confrontation in the Mechanical Tower"2:286."Military Aggression"2:157."Clash in the Catacombs"2:168."Struggle in the Library"2:289."Rooftop Engagement"2:1510."An Unsafe Sanctuary"2:1611."The Mystic Caves"2:2512."Mystic Sanctuary"1:1313."Desolation of the Tower"1:3314."Avoid the Guards"1:2115."Explore the Catacombs"1:3116."Divine Sacrifice"1:3317."Dark Gardens"1:2618."Shadow of the Tower"1:4219."The Guard Tower Past"1:3020."Worried in the Catacombs"1:2721."The Mask Sanctuary"1:0922."The Chase of Time"3:2623."The Prophecy"2:1224."Escape in the Temple"0:3125."Despair and Hope"2:1426."The Mask"1:1627."Dahaka's Revenge"1:5228."Back to Babylon"2:4529."Escape the Dahaka"2:2130."At war with Kaileena"2:1331."Battle the Dahaka"2:2432."Conflict of the Griffins"2:25</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12710">Onimusha 3: Demon Siege</game><game id="7750">Tenchu: Return from Darkness</game><game id="4443">TMNT</game><game id="22928">Assassin's Creed II</game><game id="6959">God of War</game><game id="6681">Devil May Cry 4</game><game id="25551">Totems</game><game id="11314">God of War II</game><game id="13072">Devil May Cry</game><game id="31001">Assassin's Creed: Brotherhood</game><game id="21213">Mirror's Edge</game><game id="29284">Tron: Evolution</game><game id="30636">Garshasp: The Monster Slayer</game><game id="37494">Assassin's Creed III</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2280506-box_popww.png</image></root>