<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1753</id><name>Spyro: Year of the Dragon</name><description>OverviewSpyro: Year of the Dragon is the third installment of series, developed by Insomniac before they sold the rights of the franchise. The story follows the adventures of Spyro the Dragon, and his dragonfly companion Sparx. The big new feature of this game is the Spyro's friends are also available as playable characters in their own special areas, each with different and useful abilities.PlotSpyro stares at a dragon egg for no reason.Every twelve years, new dragon eggs are delivered into the realm of the dragons. This time around, an evil sorceress, her army of Rynocs, and apprentice, Bianca, have stolen the eggs. Spyro and his friends are the only ones who can retrieve the eggs, and stop the Sorceress' goals. As Spyro pursues the thieves responsible, he discovers a realm, called Avalon, which was once a home for dragons, but is now the place where the Sorceress resides. Spyro visits each forgotten realm to retrieve the eggs, with the help of different playable characters ( Sheila, Sgt. Byrd, Bentley, and Agent 9). It is later revealed that the Sorceress is planning to use the wings of the baby dragons to create an immortality potion. This new facet of information forces Bianca to change sides and aid Spyro in stopping her. Spyro is finally able to kill the sorceress, and deliver all the baby dragons to the Dragon Kingdom.Homeworld and LevelsThe game spans four homeworlds which act as stations to other portals. Each Homeworld contains eight portals to separate levels: four standard levels, a speedway, a freed character from Moneybags' level, a boss confrontation, and a Sparx level. The four homeworlds and levels are:Sunrise SpringsThe levels found in Sunrise Springs are as followed:Sunny VillaCloud SpiresMolten CraterSeashell ShoreMushroom SpeedwaySheila's AlpBuzz's DungeonCrawdad FarmMidday GardensThe levels found in Midday Garden are as followed:Icy PeakEnchanted TowersSpooky SwampBamboo TerraceCountry SpeedwaySgt. Byrd's BaseSpike's ArenaSpider TownEvening LakeThe levels found in Evening Lake are as followed:Frozen AltarsLost FleetFireworks FactoryCharmed RidgeHoney SpeedwayBentley's OutpostScorch's PitStarfish ReefMidnight MountainThe levels found in Midnight Mountain are as followed:Crystal IslandsDesert RuinsHaunted TombDino MinesHarbor SpeedwayAgent 9's LabSorceress' LairBugBot FactorySuper Bonus WorldPlayable CharactersIn a departure from the first two games, Insomniac introduced 4 more playable characters that can be unlocked as the player reaches each of the four worlds.Sheila The KangarooSheila allows the player to jump to new heights- she is able to double jump and even super jump in order to reach extremely high areas. Her attacks involve kicks and a move where she slams down after jumping up.Sgt. ByrdSgt. Byrd is a winged soldier able to fly and unleash rocket attacks from launchers attached to his sides.BentleyBentley the yeti is armed with a massive club that he can use to crush enemies that stand in his path.Agent 9Agent 9 is a space monkey who is equipped with a laser weapon that he names 'Mr Laser Blaster'.Cheat CodesAll cheat codes must be entered in the pause menu99 Lives - R2,L2,R2,L2,UP,UP,UP,UP,CIRCLEChange skateboard into squid - UP, UP, LEFT, LEFT, RIGHT, RIGHT, DOWN, DOWN, SQUARE, CIRCLE, SQUARE.2D Spyro - Left, Right, Left, Right, L1, R1, L1, R1, Square, CircleBig Headed Spyro - Up, R1, Up, R1, Up, R1, Circle, Circle, Circle, CircleBlue Spyro - Up, Left, Down, Right, Up, Square, R1, R2, L1, L2, Up, Right, Down, Left, Up, and X.Green Spyro - Up, Left, Down, Right, Up, Square, R1, R2, L1, L2, Up, Right, Down, Left, Up, TriangleRed Spyro - Up, Left, Down, Right, Up, Square, R1, R2, L1, L2, Up, Right, Down, Left, Up, and Circle.Yellow Spyro - Up, Left, Down, Right, Up, Square, R1, R2, L1, L2, Up, Right, Down, Left, Up, Up Crash Bash Demo - Hold L1, R2, and Square at the game menuSoundtrack"Title and Sparx Levels""Sunrise Spring Home""Sunny Villa""Sheila's Alp""Cloud Spires""Molten Crater""Seashell Shore""Mushroom Speedway""Buzz's Dungeon""Midday Garden Home""Icy Peak""Enchanted Towers and Sgt. Byrd Levels""Spooky Swamp""Bamboo Terrace""Country Speedway""Spike's Arena""Evening Lake Home""Frozen Alters""Lost Fleet""Fireworks Factory""Charmed Ridge""Honey Speedway""Bentley's Outpost""Scorch's Pit""Midnight Mountain Home""Crystal Islands""Desert Ruins""Haunted Tomb""Dino Mines""Harbor Speedway""Agent 9's Lab""Sorceress's Lair""Super Bonus Round""You Found an Egg!""Ending with Voices""Credits"ESRBThe ESRB rated the game Everyone for Comic Mischief.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14623">Jak and Daxter: The Precursor Legacy</game><game id="18309">Ratchet &amp; Clank</game><game id="3438">MediEvil II</game><game id="4228">Haven: Call of the King</game><game id="7804">Rocket: Robot on Wheels</game><game id="20330">Gex 3: Deep Cover Gecko</game><game id="15991">Chameleon Twist 2</game><game id="18376">Looney Tunes Back in Action</game><game id="7212">Klonoa 2: Lunatea's Veil</game><game id="5642">Jersey Devil</game><game id="24704">Frogger</game><game id="96">Kao the Kangaroo</game><game id="21460">Gurumin: A Monstrous Adventure</game><game id="8660">Crash Bandicoot 2: Cortex Strikes Back</game><game id="8698">Tail Concerto</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1803997-box_spyroyotd.png</image></root>