<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17547</id><name>Apollo Justice: Ace Attorney</name><description>7 years have passed... ...Since Phoenix Wright completed his last case... Now a new ace attorney rises to the challenge! Enter Apollo Justice and his chords of steel!Characters Apollo Justice - The title character, a 22 year old budding defense attorney working under Kristoph Gavin, an experienced defense attorney. He has the unique ability to tune into people's tells and reveal when they are lying.       Trucy Wright - The adopted daughter of former defense attorney Phoenix Wright. She is a magician in trading who has a similar ability to Apollo. Could there be a connection between the two?     Kristoph Gavin - Apollo's former mentor, and a friend of Phoenix Wright.    Klavier Gavin - The land's premiere prosecutor and the lead singer of rock band The Gavinners. He is the brother of defense attorney Kristoph Gavin.   Phoenix Wright - Trucy's father and a former defense attorney who lost his badge 7 years ago.  Ema Skye - Assisted Phoenix years ago in a trial to defend her sister, prominent prosecutor Lana Skye. She now uses science to investigate crimes.Case SummariesTurnabout TrumpSeven years after he was stripped of his attorney's badge, Phoenix Wright is charged in the murder of a traveler named Shadi Smith, and hires an old friend, Kristoph Gavin, to defend him, but insists that the defense attorney be a rookie attorney named Apollo Justice.Turnabout CornerIn his first case employed by the "Wright Anything Agency", Apollo is tasked to solve three simultaneous and seemingly unrelated incidents, which are eventually proven to be related to the killing of a doctor. Apollo is hired by the Kitaki family, a local gang, to defend their son in the murder. Klavier Gavin, Kristoph's brother, is introduced as the main prosecutor in this case, as well as Phoenix's adopted daughter, Trucy.Turnabout SerenadeIn the middle of a rock concert which Trucy and Apollo have been invited to by the band's frontman, Klavier Gavin himself, the manager of one of the guest performers is shot. Another of the guests, pianist Machi Tobaye, is accused of killing him, and Apollo is given his case.Turnabout SuccessionIn the test case of a new legal system, the Jurist System, Apollo takes on the case of a reclusive teenage girl, Vera Misham, charged with poisoning her father, Drew, in the middle of his first interview in seven years. During the investigation, the mysteries surrounding Phoenix Wright's last days as a defense attorney and the identity of the man pulling the strings since that incident come to light. 7 Year TrialTaking control of  Phoenix and Apollo, investigate crime scenes both past and present to prove Phoenix Wright's innocence, solving the mystery that caused him to lose his badge seven years ago.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1159">Hotel Dusk: Room 215</game><game id="20145">Sprung</game><game id="20522">Harvey Birdman: Attorney at Law</game><game id="12998">Sherlock Holmes: Consulting Detective</game><game id="18297">Where in Space is Carmen Sandiego? (Deluxe Edition)</game><game id="1182">Sherlock Holmes Consulting Detective: Volume II</game><game id="23075">Ikatan: Ikamono Tantei</game><game id="20529">Insecticide</game><game id="22330">Jake Hunter: Detective Chronicles</game><game id="21807">Unsolved Crimes</game><game id="24237">Again</game><game id="21845">Death Note: Kira Game</game><game id="25340">Tokyo Twilight Busters</game><game id="25446">Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kizuna: Daisankan Rasen</game><game id="25583">Yuzai x Muzai</game><game id="17544">Broken Sword: The Shadow of the Templars</game><game id="25156">Lux-Pain</game><game id="25654">Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kizuna: Daiichikan Tatari</game><game id="25655">Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kizuna: Dainikan Sou</game><game id="21411">Theresia</game><game id="25685">Miami Law</game><game id="26447">Hayarigami: Toshi Densetsu Kaii Jiken</game><game id="24071">So Blonde</game><game id="28435">Agatha Christie: The ABC Murders</game><game id="29344">Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kizuna: Daiyonkan Kizuna</game><game id="29533">Last Window: The Secret of Cape West</game><game id="30111">Disney Guilty Party</game><game id="40045">Devil's Attorney</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1836572-box_ajaa.png</image></root>