<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17595</id><name>Front Mission 3</name><description>Story Front Mission 3 grants a long story which plays out in a hard-future earth (around 2112) in which you, Japanese Kazuki Takemura is caught in a struggle between super alliances involving a weapon of mass destruction known as MIDAS. On board your (mecha) Wanzers, you and other characters find yourself engaging in combat fighting and uncovering a political conspiracy between the super nations of the game. The majority of the story takes place in south-east asia between the fictional OCU nation and China. Early on in the game it was possible to take one of two very different routes for the games story. While the fundamental core of the narrative was very similar, the progression, characters you encounter and enemies you fight changed drastically between both.  The main story was believed to be the one with Kazuki's sister being a playable character while the alternate was one involving a blonde haired woman named Emma.   Both these characters appear in both versions but play quite different roles. In order to chose which story you experience you must make a decision to your friends offer to go with him to a shopping mall early in the game.  If you say yes you get Story A, no, Story B.Gameplay Players of Front Mission 3 must progress through the games linear story by engaging in tactical turn based combat, selecting which areas to visit and characters to talk to and by checking emails and browsing information in the games fictional Internet known as Tenmou.Tactical Turn Based CombatCharacter Progression and Mech Customization  The character progression aspect of Front Mission 3 allows different tactics to be played out on the battle screens as different Wanzers can be built to play different roles such as an up close and personal attacker or a fast moving sniper. Pimp my mech  Like general RPGs, characters are able to level up and increase their various stats which in turn boost their abilities in battle. Character skills can range to increasing the rate of fire when firing the Wanzer's machine gun to doing a full body charge when attacking with a melee weapon. Wanzers can be built from different parts which range in abilities such as accuracy, speed and defence taking into account weight and energy levels. Additionally Wanzers can be given weapons ranging from knuckledusters, flame-throwers to shoulder-mounted missile launchers. Wanzers can also be given back packs which can hold extra ammo or repair items, some backpacks have the ability to hold stored energy to expand the limits of customizing you or a team mates Wanzer. Additionally aesthetic details can be given to the mech such as paint jobs or giving it a different name than the stock parts. Combat and Tactics Combat in Front Mission 3 is usually Wanzer vs Wanzer but occasionally you will find yourself fighting against military hardware such as tanks, attack hellicopters or gun emplacements with you and your team either in Wanzer or on foot with a handgun.Combat! Combat in the game is played on a square grid in which you must defeat an enemy usually by the win-condition of defeating all the foes. Ocasionally you may have to protect a certain character or entity whilst battling. On each turn you have the ability to move and attack with each of your characters on the field if your Ability Points permit it. When all your characters have ended their go then the turn order will switch to the enemy and they will proceed with moving and attacking. Wanzers can be customized in a variety of ways giving the player a multitude of options to complete the battle objective. Wanzers with fast mobility legs can move more squares than a Wanzer which is fitted with a heavy grenade launcher for example.  Not all combat is resolved by violence, occationally if you cause enough havok on the battlefield AI NPCs will peform a surrender check. If the player shoots them lightly without destroying them they will fully surrender leaving them out of play for the entire match. Front Mission 3 also gives you the option to leave your Wanzer during battle expanding the overall stategy by being able to hijack enemy Wanzers which have had their pilots ejected by a forceful attack. Hijacking enemy Wanzers is beneficial as you obtain their Wanzer at the end of the battle and keep your own. Not only does hijacking benefit profit but can prove to be a greater combat tactic as it sometimes faster to hijack than to destroy on occasions.  Character interactions and visiting locations When you are not battling on the field, you will be talking to characters and visiting locations such as bars or market places to advance the   story. Additionally talking to certain NPC characters can grant you bonuses such as an extra weapon. The same can be said for extensive navigation of  the fictional Internet Tenmou which has a variety of websites under password protection. These aspects of the gameplay are not 3D like the combat and are displayed from a list of options such as TALK, VISIT, CHECK MAIL etc. over a 2d sprite backdrop.Design Visuals Front Mission 3 sports two distinct game designs for each of their types of gameplay. When on the battle screen mechs can be seen on a fully rendered 3D backdrop and when attacking with a mech, the camera pans in at a stylized angle giving a more realistic impression of the combat, (bullets richochet of enemy armour for example.) When on the character interaction and location visiting aspect of the gameplay, different 2d backdrops are displayed with anime-esque character mug shots are shown when dialogue is initiated.Occasionally when an important story aspect needs to be shown, Full Motion Video is used to tell the story at optimum quality.Music and Sounds Sound effects in battles range from the clunking movement of a mech's feet hitting the ground, the sound of bullets penetrated metal to the woosh of an attack hellicopters missile flying OST Coverthrough the air. Music is also used to create the tense atmosphere of the tactical combat to the mellow moments of the investigative location visiting and character interaction.  The music in Front Mission 3 was also made available on an official sound track publication by DigiCube ranging two disks and totalling to 47 tracks.Reception Front Mission 3 was well recieved in Japan selling 298,000 copies in its first year. Like many other Squaresoft RPGs, merchandise such as a Official Sound Track was also made available for purchase. The success of Front Mission 3 spawned a number of re-releases such as Square's Millenium collection in which the package contained small collectables such as keychain and wallet. Another release in 2002 placed Front Mission 3 in Japan's The Best Range. The next year the game was repackaged with the two previous installments in the Front Mission Compilation. Finally the game was released once more in 2006 in Square Enix's Ultimate Hits line.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13073">Fire Emblem: Thracia 776</game><game id="12719">Advance Wars</game><game id="8352">Vandal Hearts II</game><game id="23083">Super Robot Wars D</game><game id="22607">Super Robot Wars Alpha 2</game><game id="21244">Super Robot Wars W</game><game id="25684">Murakumo: Renegade Mech Pursuit</game><game id="33567">Carnage Heart EXA</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2092590-box_fm3.png</image></root>