<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17639</id><name>Chasm: The Rift</name><description>Chasm: The Rift is a first-person shooter for the PC developed by Action Forms that was published in 1997 by WizardWorks Software, GT Interactive Software and MegaMedia Corp. In the game, you take control of an unnamed Marine whose mission is to stop the Time Strikers, mutant beings invading from different time epochs, from taking over the earth. On this quest to stop the evil forces, you visit places ranging from military bases in the present to tombs in ancient Egypt. One of the notable features of the game is the ability to remove limbs from your enemies. The bosses in the game have to be brought down by special tactics instead of raw firepower. There is an official addon to the game that adds three new levels along with new monsters and is available as a free download from the developer's website. Though the retail CD contains a level editor, no user-created levels are known to have been published on the internet, making it hard to find new content for the game. Chasm can also be edited using the Doom WAD editor XWE. The game received mixed reviews at the time of release. While many reviews gave points to the game for being a simple and fun shoot-em-up that, because it only supported software rendering, didn't need the biggest, baddest PC to run it, it got a lot of flak for being too simple and not being as good looking as the game it was trying to be, Quake. It also received flak for not being about to look up and down, like in Quake, so it feels like a chore and that it's multi-player was barely worth it, considering that Quake II was on the horizon. However, the game has lasted throughout the years and has gained a cult following. WeaponsRifle -The No-Ammo weapon accessed by pressing 1 is a low damage rifle. It has an unlimited amount of ammunition.Super Shotgun -The shell ammunition is readily available and is dropped by most enemies within the first level set. Boxes of shells (coming in sets of 10 or 20) are also very common throughout the game.Volcano -A chaingun type weapon with, initially, limited ammo.BladeGun -Shoots out blades.Laser Crossbow -A crossbow that shoots out laser fire.Grenader -The Grenader is a weapon that shoots out rocket propelled grenades. It is capable of harming the player's character.Land Mines -The Land Mines have more power than the Grenader, but the Land Mines can only be placed on the ground. It can harm the player along with the enemies.Mega Destroyer -The projectile is shot out like a long-ranged grenade throw. Each ammo pickup for this weapon is worth 2 points of ammo.Enemy'sThe enemies in Chasm are known as Time Strikers. They are monsters that travel through time rifts.Scorpion -They are golden monsters, about two feet long, with three stingers.Mong -Mongs are mutated soldiers wearing gas masks, and use rifles.Stratos -Stratos are flying soldiers which shoot projectiles from the bottom of their legs.Faust -Fausts are highly-armored soldiers that is armed with a bazooka.Turret -The Turrets were used by the Platoon, but now they have gone berserk and will shoot anything on sight.Gross -Gross' are monstrous-looking cavemen which attack with a spiked club and throw rocks at the player.Zombie -They are the walking undead, and must be decapitated.Punisher -The Punisher is a large beer-bellied and muscled man wearing a red hood over his head.Lionman -The Lionman is a humanoid with the body of a warrior and the head of a lion. They run pretty fast and wield a shield and a mace.Joker -Jokers are humanoid monsters wearing Jester attire. They attack using their unique Blade Guns.Viking -These Vikings are mutants armed with a shield and an axe, and will attack with either, and also with their spiked helmets on top of their heads.Werehog -Werehogs are mutated Warthogs that charge towards the player to gore him/her with their tusks.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21478">Cryostasis</game><game id="17386">Vivisector: Beast Within</game><game id="7175">Carnivores</game><game id="9452">Carnivores 2</game><game id="18836">Carnivores: Ice Age</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/20553/1153099-chasm___the_rift_coverart.png</image></root>