<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17631</id><name>Groove on Fight: Gouketsuji Ichizoku 3</name><description>OverviewGroove on Fight: Gouketsuji Ichizoku 3 (or just Groove on Fight) is a tag-team 2D fighter from Atlus. It was first released in Japanese Arcades in 1997 and later ported to the Saturn the same year. In order for the Saturn version to replicate the Arcade version, the game required a 1MB RAM cart which was included in certain copies of the game. Despite the added RAM and the Saturn being mostly identical to the Sega ST-V board the arcade version ran on, the game was rife with slowdown and load times due to the CD based media, as opposed to the cartridge-based arcade version. However, the Saturn version did receive additional features, such as unlockable characters and 4-player multiplayer through the use of a multitap as well as enhanced music. As an amusing extra, a large number of Shin Megami Tensei demons make cameos in Bristol-D's attacks.Groove on Fight takes place 20 years after the events of Gouketsuji Ichizoku 2. Like previous games in the series, the game features character designs from artist Range Murata.A doujin boxing game and soundtrack 'Glove On Fight' was released in 2002, an obvious play on the game's name. However, apart from being a fighting game, it bares no similarity to Groove on Fight.GameplayGameplay in Groove on FightGroove on Fight is a 6-button 2D fighter that plays like most other games in the genre, but features a tag-team system similar to that of other fighting games such as the Marvel vs. Capcom series. The player chooses two fighters for their team and at any time during the fight, the player can attempt to 'tag' their team-mate to bring them in. The opponent can break the tag by attacking the player, however. If tagged, the player's character will replace the substitute fighter and slowly regenerate health. An interesting feature in Groove on Fight is the ability to throw the body of any K.O'd fighters by pressing down and HP while standing over them, as they stay on the ground after being defeated. The game also features a "gottsui" (gutsy) attack button, which performs an overhead attack... even if the character performing it is crouching... crouching overheads being a rather unusual feature in any fighting game! The game also features the "mawa" button, which allows the player to evade an attack and counter by hopping behind the opponent.All characters have specific stats. For example, Otori Remi has the ability to jump higher than any other character in the game, by virtue of her being a witch. Damien moves and acts slowly due to his 'sissy' personality.UNIVERSAL COMMANDS: Abilities all characters can perform. It's also worth noting every character has a "rekka" style attack, although the inputs vary.Double jump: Tap up a second time while jumping.Stress Charge: Hold down LP and LK to charge meter!Parry: Press both heavy punch and heavy kick simultaneously to enter a parrying stance. If the opponent attacks their attack will be deflected and they will be vulnerable; however, if you whiff a parry you can be punished as it has recovery!Chou Gottsui attack: Press mawa and gottsui at the same time for a slow but powerful unblockable attack!Dual Attack: Down, down, P when tagging with a partner. This costs one bar of stress meter.Assist attack: Forward plus LP and LK. The player's partner will hop in for a second and attack the opponent in an effort to get some pressure off.Yujou power: This activates automatically when the player's partner is KO'd. The player receives a brief damage boost and gains some stress meter.CharactersCharacterInformationLarry LightLarry LightAge: 24Birthplace: Oregon, United StatesApparently following in his father's footsteps, Larry is an archaeologist from America who travels the world via motorcycle and is the game's main protagonist. He won't admit it, but he actually has a bit of bloodlust and loves to fight. His intended team mate is Chris.Movelist:Light Blast: QCF, PDriving Dribble: DP, PSlast Step: QCF, KAir Light Blast: QCF, P while in the airDash driving dribble: While dashing, DP, PImpact Connection: QCB LP, QCB HP, QCB GottsuiHistoric Moment: down, down, KChris WayneChris WayneAge: 18Birthplace: New York, United StatesThe son of Keith Wayne and Annie Hamilton, he's sick of his parents and their and efforts to make him "tough". He sets out with Larry just to have some good fights.Movelist:Lightning Slash: QCB,PRolling Cannon: Forward, down-forward, down, KSpiral Leg Bomber: QCF, KTaichi Rolling Cannon: Forward, down-forward, down, K in the airHead Slash: QCF, P while in the airOverdrive Kick: QCF LK, QCF HK, QCFGottsui Lightning Break: down, down, KTeniinbashi SujirokuTenjinbashi SujirokuAge: 32Birthplace: Osaka, JapanA huge and rowdy kansai-born man who loves matsuri more than anything else... except maybe fighting. He's ashamed of his face and wears a mask most of the time.Movelist:Haru: QCB, LPNatsu: QCB, HPAki: QCB, LKFuyu: QCB, HKShishigashira: LP and HP simultaneouslySan-nen goroshi: 360, KDash Shishigashira: LP and HP while dashingTenchi-jin: 360 LP, 360 HP, 360 gottsuiTsuutenroku Shakudama: down, down, KYukinoue HizumiYukinoue HizumiAge: 22Birthplace: Kanagawa Prefecture, JapanA smart geeky ninja... Who isn't actually of ninja origin at all, just a huge ninja fanboy and imitator who is entirely self-taught. He and Tenjinbashi are intended team-mates.Movelist:Kage shibari: QCF, PTsuchigumo no jutsu: LK and HK simultaneouslyHousenka no jutsu: QCF, KMakibishi: During a dash, LP and HPHyakuraijuu: QCF, P while airborneDash housenka: QCF, K while dashingRengeki tanjin no jutsu: QCB LP, QCB HP, QCB GottsuiJumonjika sumikuzushi: down, down, KMax Ax DaxMax Ax DaxAge: UnknownBirthplace: UnknownMore commonly known as "MAD", he's a top class mad scientist who lives in Hong Kong, although he isn't a native. He's also a wanted criminal; Solis has arrested him, but then ends up teaming with him. He is one of the characters capable of an air dash. He also is capable of controlling the opponent's actions through the use of his "megaphone" abilities, each strength having a different effect (I.E., no jumping, no attacking, etc.)!Movelist:Max Megaphone: QCF, P or KMax Servant: LK and HK simultaneouslyMax Sparkler: DP, PMax Net: LP and HP simultaneouslyMax Raygun: When getting up, mash PMax Drill: QCF, P while airborneDash Sparkler: DP, P while dashingMax Combo Originale: QCB LP, QCB MP, QCB GottsuiMaximum Service: down down, KSolis R8000Solis R8000Age: 20Birthplace: Eighth Moon ColonyA policewoman from 100 years into the future, who has come back in time to arrest MAD and Bristol and prevent history from being changed by ensuring the "correct outcome" of events. She is the main 'poster-girl' of the game, appearing on the game's cover and most promotional material.Movelist:Stun Bullet: QCF,PStun Platinum: DP, PGyrator: QCB, KTNT charge: Hold down P or K for two seconds then releaseSoar platinum: DP, P while airborneDash TNT charge: A TNT charge performed while dashingAbsolute beat: QCF LK, QCF HK, QCF MawaSolis Multiplier: down, down, KFalcoFalcoAge: 70Birthplace: London, EnglandAn old English gambler who lost his right eye in a bet. He suspiciously resembles Sean Connery. He is teamed with Oume and Otane, but for no particular reason other than casual events.Movelist:Bluff shuffle: QCF, P (repeatedly)Face or back: DP, P (repeatedly)Reversal slot: LP and HP simultaneouslyInsight dash: QCF, KDash face or back: while dashing, DP and P (repeatedly)Three characters: QCB LP, QCB HP, QCB GottsuiStormy Poker: down, down, KGouketsuji Oume  Gouketsuji OtaneGouketsuji Oume  Gouketsuji OtaneAge: 100, 100Birthplace: Kyoto PrefectureThe infamous Gouketsuji sisters of the series overall, they are fighting tied together as one character as a means of reconciliation. However, they still secretly harbor all of their dislike and suspicions of each other!Movelist:Ganzaiha: Charge back, forward PKoushiki ganzaiha: Charge forward, back PIkakugan: Charge down, up PBadou kourin: LP and HP simultaneouslySeiryuu ranbudan: Hld forward and press P rapidlyTenbukyaku: While airborne, up, down, KDash ikakugan: While dashing, up down P (no charge needed)Chibukyaku: Charge back forward, LK, back-forward HK, back-forward MawaIchizoku: down, down KRudolph GartheimerRudolph GartheimerAge: 45Birthplace: Berlin, GermanyA huge, mask wearing German. He was originally part of the Gouketsuji clan, but was expelled for past transgressions. He's a bit of a misanthrope, and is currently working for Bristol. Damien is his lover, and for some reason he will never tag in Damien during the sub-boss fight with him.Movelist:Iron Mine: LP and HP simultaneouslyHeavysault Kick: Charge down, up KGrind Rush: Charge back, forward KGrind Break: Hold forward and press LP rapidlyBody Smasher: Charge down, up PHeavy Tread: Up, down P while airborneDash Heavysault: Down, Up, K while dashingGain Control: Charge back, forward LK, back forward HK, back forward MawaIron Dust Bomber: down, down, KOtogiri RemiOtogiri RemiAge: 14Birthplace: Tokyo, JapanA descendant of music-using witches and a distant relative of the Gouketsuji. She teams with Popura to prove the power of music. Her quiet and reserved nature contrasts with Popura's. She is capable of air-dashing.Movelist:Il Filo: Charge back, forward PCapriola: Charge down, up PCorno refrain: LP and HP simultaneouslyPortamento: Up, down P while airborneLa Morte: LP and HP while airborneDash capriola: Down, up P while dashingTriangle: Charge back, forward LK, back forward HK, back forward MawaRequiem: down, down, KHananokouji PopuraHananokouji PopuraAge: 13Birthplace: Tokyo, JapanThe daughter of Clara from the other Gouketsuji games. Her (unknown) father is apparently always traveling around fighting, so she takes her mother's magic stick and goes on a journey to get some money to buy a fancy teddy bear (apparently her allowance is small...)Movelist:Shoujo commando: QCF, PKurukuru candy: LK and HK simultaneouslyKurkuru poi: QCF, KBikkuribako: LP and HP simultaneouslyCupid: LP and HP simultaneously while airborneDash Kurukuru poi: QCF, K while dashingPopura Special: QCB LP, QCB HP, QCB GottsuiTulip: down, down, KDamien ShadeDamien ShadeAge: 15Birthplace: Vancouver, CanadaGartheimer's gay lover. He was adopted by Gartheimer at an orphanage. He is not playable in the arcade version, but is a hidden character in the Saturn version. He is murdered by Bristol.Movelist:Haley Magic: QCB, PRose Flash: Charge back, forward PDamien Body Attack: Charge back, forward KDashing Haley Magic: QCB, P while dashingPoison Zone: QCB LK, QCB HK, QCB MawaPinch Crusher: down, down, KBristol WellerBristol WellerAge: 35Birthplace: Birmingham, EnglandThe boss of Groove on Fight. Although he pretends to be a philanthropist from England, he's actually a violent devil summoning criminal from the future who has come to the past to destroy the Gouketsuji clan for reasons unknown. He is not playable in the arcade version, but is a secret character in the Saturn version..Movelist:Single Shot: Charge back, forward KKiller Mantis: QCB, KHunting Mantis: DP, KWinners' Strike: QCB LP, QCB HP, QCB GottsuiDashing Hunting Mantis: DP, K while dashingBloody Execution: down, down, KBristol-DBristol-DAge: UnknownBirthplace: UnknownBristol's true, demon-summoning form. He summons many demons from the Shin Megami Tensei series, including some notables like Leonard and Beelzebub! He is not playable in the arcade version, but is a secret character in the Saturn version.Movelist:Pixy Rush: QCF, PGaap Upper: DP, PLeonard Wave: QCF, KAmon Flame: QCB, KHell's Gate: QCB LP, QCB HP, QcB GottsuiFlystorm Beelzebub: down, down, KSoundtrackThe soundtrack to Groove on Fight was composed by Toshikazu Tanaka under his alias Dencyu. It was originally released in Japan in 1997, then later reissued in 2005.GROOVE ON FIGHTGROOVE ON FIGHTReleased: June 18th, 1997Total Length: 55:42Periodically (Opening Demo)Start! (Press Start Screen)Soul Selecter (Player Select Screen)Red Bird (Steel Factory Stage)World Step (Ruins Stage)KAMIKAZE (Miyajima Stage)Time is Tango (Wall Clock Stage)M.A.D (Mad Machinery Stage)Fly Away (High-Speed Fighter Plane Stage)Incarnation (Noble Castle Stage)God Of Death (Destroyed Castle Stage)SOSHITE... (Ending Demo)Groove On Fight (Staff Roll)Ume  Tane (Leader's Deciding Match! Oume  Otane Appear)Who Are You? (The Goketsuji-Crusher Gartheimer Appears)I'm Gartheimer (Match! Gartheimer)Poor Thing Man (The True Enemy Bristol Appears)Bad Partner (Confrontation! Leader VS Partner)Revive (Resurrected Bristol)Absorption (Partner Absorption)Gate Of Time (Fated Solis towards the Other Side of Space-Time)Oh! Baby (Name Entry Screen)We Are Stronger (Winner Screen)GO! GO! GO! (Midway Participation ME)Larry LightChris WaynePopura HananokojiRemi OtogiriSolis R8000Max Ax Dax (M.A.D)Sujiroku TenjinbashiHizumi YukinoueOume Goketsuji  Otane GoketsujiFalcoRudolf GartheimerDamian ShadeBristol Weller Before TransformationBristol Weller After TransformationS.E. Collection</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2612">Marvel vs. Capcom 2: New Age of Heroes</game><game id="1541">Darkstalkers 3</game><game id="4124">The King of Fighters '97</game><game id="22629">Rage of the Dragons</game><game id="12312">SNK vs. Capcom: Match of the Millennium</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2906/187895-groove_on_fight.jpg</image></root>