<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17646</id><name>Unreal</name><description>OverviewUnreal is a first person shooter game jointly developed by Epic Games and Digital Extremes. It was published by GT Interactive for computers running Mac OS or Microsoft Windows.PlotThe protagonist, Prisoner 849, is a prisoner on a spacecraft called the Vortex Rikers. The ship is pulled into the orbit of the planet Na Pali, which is inhabited by a primitive civilization known as the Nali, and crashes on the planet's surface. After the ship crashes, it is attacked by a savage and technologically-advanced race of aliens called the Skaarj and 849 wakes up from unconsciousness to find everyone on the ship killed and most of the ship destroyed. Escaping the crashed spacecraft, 849 makes his way around Na Pali in search of surviving humans and a way off the planet. Prisoner 849 fights through mines, caves, Nali temples, Skaarj installations and the otherworldly Nali Haven as he looks for a way home. Along the way, he is hunted by the Skaarj, who have enslaved the native Nali in order to mine the precious mineral Tarydium. After fighting through the Skaarj and their alien minions and helping the oppressed Nali, Prisoner 849 finally finds a teleporter to the Skaarj Mothership and destroys its main reactor, killing its power. With the Mothership successfully sabotaged and about to explode, 849 faces the Skaarj Queen and, upon killing her, launches into orbit above Na Pali in an escape pod as the Mothership detonates. Players are left with the impression that he will be left floating in space for some time, with a small chance of rescue. Fortunately, this is not the case, and his adventures continue in the expansion pack, Return to Na Pali.CharactersPrisoner 849One of many avatars that can represent Prisoner 849The protagonist of the game. He or she was being transported aboard a prison ship when a Skaarj attack left them stranded on the alien world of Na Pali. The player has the option of changing to several different male and female skins for Prisoner 849, though in Return to Na Pali, the character has a male voice.SkaarjSkaarj WarriorInstinctive hunters capable of using numerous weapons and endowed with superhuman strength. They are equipped with huge retractable claws, and come in many varieties. Some are known to wear armor.SlithSlithAmphibious adaptations of the Skaarj, they are deadly on land and in the water. They have razor-sharp claws and produce a flesh-eating projectile saliva.MercenaryMercenaryHumanoid bio-engineered hunters. They're very aggressive and are equipped with forearm-mounted machine guns and missile launchers.KrallKrallHunting assistants employed by the Skaarj. Their intellect is quite limited, though they use their concussion staffs with considerable skill.BruteBruteProfoundly unintelligent creatures engineered by the Skaarj for the sole purpose of destruction. They are extremely aggressive but incredibly slow moving.TitanTitanAn extremely aggressive and gargantuan colossus, native to Na Pali. It hurls boulders with incredible accuracy and will smash and tear apart anybody who gets within reach of its long arms.NaliNaliThe former rulers of Na Pali, now enslaved by the Skaarj. They are timid and pacifistic but are quite willing to help those who help and protect them.The WeaponsDispersion PistolDispersion PistolThe default weapon in the game. It fires small plasma bolts with it's primary fire, while it's secondary charges up the weapon for a few second and fire a much larger shot, which also deals splash damage. It has regenerating ammo, giving you unlimited shots. This weapon can "evolve when we pick up dispersion pistol power ups, the primary fire will use more ammo and the ammo supply will be upgraded. however the secondary fire stay the same.This weapon will be remade in unreal 2, with no upgrade possibilities, it will be named as LEPEW-13 and will have only 8 shots and a faster energy recovery than this modelAutomagAutomagThis is a pretty basic weapon, and one you'll find yourself using quite a lot. It fires very accurate, but has a slow fire rate. Luckily, you can use its secondary fire and hold the gun sideways, giving a much faster firing rate but also less accurate.It is the gun that later became the Enforcer.StingerStingerThe Stinger is a Crystal firing minigun. It fires very fast. The secondary fire will unleash a volley of five shards instantly, much like a shotgun.ASMDASMDThe ASMD can fire railgun-like shock beam, which can be fired from large distances, making it a good alternative to the sniper rifle. It can also shoot a big slow-moving plasma ball. If both are used in a combination, it'll create a massive blast, which has been given the term "Shock-Combo", simply shoot the slow moving plasma ball with your shock beam. It is mostly skilled players that can pull this trick off perfectly, and when they do, they are deadly.Eightball LauncherEightball LauncherThis is not your typical rocket launcher, since it can load up to 6 rockets at the same time and fire them all in a deadly cone. With your secondary fire, you can even turn these rockets into jumping grenades, you can load up to 6 grenades as well. As a bonus, the rockets can also lock onto any threat, if the wielder keeps a steady aim over them for a short period of time. When loading up your rockets, you can hold the secondary fire, they will all fire in a tight circle.Flak CannonFlak CannonThe equivalent of a shotgun and a grenade launcher combined. The Flak Cannon can unleash a burst of molten shrapnel, making it ideal for cleaning out smaller rooms or tight corridors, since its shrapnel also bounces of walls. If you find yourself in a much bigger and more open environment, the Flak Cannon can fire a huge shell of metal, which will explode into molten shrapnel on impact.RazorjackRazor JackA Skaarj hunting weapon that is great for decapitation. It fires razor blades out in a straight line, which have the ability to bounce all surfaces. The secondary fire mode fires more rapidly and allows you to curve the blades, which also bounce off surfaces.GES BiorifleGES BiorifleThe Biorifle can disperse blobs of toxic sludge which can stick to any surface, including enemies. It can be charged to up create a bigger blob. Completely useless except as a novelty.RifleRifleThis weapon is a sniper rifle, even if we don't see any scope at the top, it fires high powered shells and can decapitate monsters.MinigunMinigunThis weapon is a twin rotative barrel minigun, it fires very fast. Each fire mode have a different firing speed, with primary firing at moderate speed and more accurate, while secondary fires very fast and inaccurate.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="65">Serious Sam</game><game id="9553">Powerslave</game><game id="21912">Planetside: Core Combat</game><game id="6183">Pariah</game><game id="14614">Turok: Dinosaur Hunter</game><game id="8015">Quake</game><game id="3207">Quake II</game><game id="10157">Clive Barker's Undying</game><game id="3719">Return to Castle Wolfenstein: Tides of War</game><game id="3061">Will Rock</game><game id="16372">Prey</game><game id="12699">Nerf Arena Blast</game><game id="2980">Half-Life</game><game id="38481">Gears of War: Judgment</game><game id="43106">Iron Soul</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15405/746709-unreal_coverart.png</image></root>