<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1764</id><name>LEGO Racers &amp; LEGO Racers 2</name><description>Lego Racers  LEGO Racers lets players make their own  LEGO vehicles and drivers and pits them against other LEGO racers to  become the greatest LEGO racing champion of all time.   Lego Racers 1  2     SummaryUpon release, Lego Racers was noted for its creation tools which allowed the player to create their own vehicle and driver. At  the time the concept was regarded as innovative, and is one which has  transcended through many other genres and is a staple in many new  releases today.  The player could then take their custom vehicle and driver for use in the game's adventure mode.  The  adventure mode consisted of numerous different worlds, each inhibiting  their own end of series boss aswell as track. Upon defeat of the boss,  their lego head, torso and legs, aswell as vehicle were them available  to the player for use in the creation modes.The game reaches a  climax as the player must defeat "Rocket Racer" the fastest racer in the  lego universe, in order to claim the final trophy and title the  ultimate lego racer. Characters  Circuit 1  4 Johnny Thunder (boss for C4)Captain Redbeard (boss for C1)Governor BroadsideRobin HoodAnn DroidPharaohs Mummy    Circuit 2  5 Baron Von Barron (boss for C5)King Kahuka (boss for C2)IslanderRoyal KingCommander ColdAchu    Circuit 3  6 Gypsy Moth (boss for C6)Basil The Batlord (boss for C3)Willa The WitchBlackjack HawkinsSam SinisterAlpha Dragonis    Circuit 7 Rocket Racer (final boss)Black KnightAdmiralGail StormNova Hunter    Bonus Veronica Voltage (time trial opponent)  CustomizationLego Racers  offers much in the way of customization. The player's car can be  customized, using the Lego builder,  by adding Lego Bricks and various  accessories onto a    Customization      variety of unchangable pre-built chassis. Characters  can also be customized in a way that , for the time, was quite  revolutionary and innovative. The player can customize his/her character  by changing headwear, heads, torsos, and legs. ModesCircuit     In Lego Racers, players race on one of seven circuits against upto  five opponents. The object of this mode is to gain the most points by  placing high on the race standings. A circuit lasts four races. Each  circuit has a racer who performs on a higher level than the other  opponents. This racer is called the "Circuit Champion" and are specific  to each course. The seventh circuit has one race against, the main  opponent throughout the game, Rocket Racer. Time Race     In the time racer mode, the player races against Veronic Voltage.  Veronic drives a ghost car that doesn't collide with any other cars. If  the player wins the race on all the tracks of the first three circuits,  Veronica's car set is given to the player. Multiplayer     Lego Racers offers a simple, 2 player split-screen mode in which 2  players on the same computer/console can play in a multiplayer free  mode. The second player is     Captain Redbeard     required to plug in either a gamepad or a  joystick     Lego Racers 2  Lego  Racers 2 is the sequel to Lego Racers published by Taito Corporation.  The game was developed by ATD and Pocket Studios. In Lego Racers 2 there  are five new worlds. You start at 'Sandy Bay' which is the hometown.  After completion of this world the player will move to another world  called 'Dino Island'. In the same matter the player will move to a  futher three worlds which are 'Mars', 'Arctic' and 'Xalax'. In the final  world 'Xalax' the player will race the ultimate boss 'Rocket Racer' in a  giant stadium where they will race for the title of 'greatest racer in  the lego galaxy'. A player will only move on from world to world if they  win five races and collect gold bricks.  Returning Racers  There are only three racers that are returning from the original Lego Racers and they are,   Rocket Racer  Rocket Racer.Sam Sanister (named Baron Von Barron in Lego Racers)Johnny Thunder. Worlds  There  are five different worlds in the Lego Racers 2 game which are based on  different themes. In addition to this each world is designed from some  original Lego sets. The five worlds are, Sandy Bay. This  world is based on Lego Town sets. This is an island that has a town,  construction sites and a lot of beaches. This world aswell as the other  worlds has portals to get to different worlds. This world has four  bosses that you have to race before challenging other worlds. Golden  bricks can also be located in and around this world.Dino  Island. This world is based on Lego Adventures sets. This world is  similar to the first as it is also an island. The difference is that  this world has got rivers, a volcano, a jungle, a tirbal village,  ancient ruins and only has a few beaches. On this world it has constant  rain and there are running lego dinosaurs. Golden bricks are also  located in this world.Mars. This world is based on Lego life on  mars sets. This world has a series of valleys that are inbetween the  mountains. It features a martian mine, martian base, abandoned martian  base, crashed space shuttle, caves and lava rivers. It is possible to  reach the top of the mountains in free roam but you need a lot of speed.  Golden bricks are found on this world.Arctic. This world is  based on the Lego arctic sets. This world is an island with a mountain, a  beached tanker, an ice maze, an iced lake and several bosses. In this  world it constantly snows. Golden bricks are found on this world.Xalax.  This world is the only world that doesn't resemble a lego set. This  world is a dome full of cheering fans an includes a volcano, lava lakes,  jumps, loops and a tunnel. Golden bricks are located in this world.Races Sandy Bay  Sandy Bay      Dig a Brick.Special Delivery.Hot Stuff. Bobby's beat.Dino Island  Tribal Trouble.Dino Dodgems.    Dino Island Cretacious Canyon.The lost race world.Sam sanisters slammer.Mars Mars attack.    Lava canyon.    Mars Logged out.Martian invasion.Arctic Snowy glaciers.    Arctic Icy mountains.Lake race.Maze of craze.Xalav Volcano rush.    Loop of luck.    Xalav Lava falls.Oval circuit. Bosses Sandy Bay Construction worker.Postman.Fireman.Policeman.Dino Island Sam Sinister. His car has a super engine.Mars Rigel. He is a martian.Arctic Berg. He is an ice monster that runs instead of driving.Xalav Rocket Racer. The former fastest driver.Other racers  In this game there are also normal lego racers that include, Pippen Reed.Sir Cunningham.Cassiopeia.Lightor.Warrior.Loopin'.Gears.Surfer.Shredder.Scratch.Spiky.Upgrades  A  player can recieve upgrades for their cars by winning mini games. Each  mini game are accessed by driving through a vortex whilst exploring  worlds. There is always one easy mini game per world and one difficult  mini game per world.  The upgrades come in three catagories which are, Grip. This improves how well the car turns and how it slides.Power. This can improve the cars speed and can determine how far the car can climb a mountain.Shield. This controls the amount of damage your car can take from an opponent.Powerups  There  are many different types of powerups on this game which can be used  whilst racing. When you drive through a glowing, spinning lego brick,  you will recieve this powerup. Whatever the brick lands on determines  the powerup you get. To use a powerup you press the fire button. The  powreups are, Weapons. This allows the racer to take bricks from another racers car. The symbol for this is a gray ninja.Stealth. This makes the racers car invisible to other racers. The symbol for this is a gray fox.Drill. This allows the racer to fire a missile into the front of another racers car. The symbol for this is a drill.Disk. This allows the racer to fire a flying disk into a racers car. The symbol for this is a disk with blades.Missile. This allows the racer to fire a missile into another racers car. The symbol for this is a bloodhound.Explosion. This allows the racer to put a bubble around thier car  to prevent attacks. The symbol for this is a storm cloud.Whirlwind.  This allows the racer to put a whirlwind around their car and makes  other racers move away. The symbol for this is a twister.Destructabrick.  This allows the racer to take three layers of bricks of every racers  car. The symbol for this is a flying lego brick.Comparison  Lego racers 2 has more freedom than lego racers because the player can free roam and can talk to other people.     Multiplayer  In  the lego racer you could only drive karts whereas in lego racers 2 you  can drive trucks, tank-like treads, lorry cars, hover cars and snow  vehicles with skis.  Lego racers 2 consists of more bricks bt  less characters than lego racers. However you cannot change your  character during story made but can change your car.  In lego racers 2 you can have up to eleven opponents but in lego racers you could only have five opponents.          </description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26848">ModNation Racers</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1379/277088-legoracers1_legoraces2.jpg</image></root>