<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17678</id><name>The Last Blade</name><description>StoryLong before humanity existed, in a far off time of myth, death was an unknown, equally distant concept, but when death first came to the world, the "Messenger from Afar" was born. With time, the Sealing Rite was held in order to seal Death behind Hell's Gate. At that time, two worlds, one near and one far, were born. Thus the history of life and death began.Half a year has passed since Suzaku's madness, and the underworld is still linked by a great portal. Kagami's great sin is still heard as if ringing from the heavens. Our world has been called upon. Legends of long ago told of the sealing of the boundary between the two worlds. The Sealing Rite would be necessary to hold back the spirits of that far away world.However, the Sealing Rite brings together the power of the Four Gods and Sealing Maiden, for the first time properly completing the ritual. To find the Sealing Maiden, Genbu began searching in the center of the world, from which all things begin. At the same time in the underworld, in the depths of darkness, many spirits conspired, plotting to hinder the Sealing Rite. They had but one wish, to be reborn into our world.CharactersPlayable charactersKaedeMoriya MinakataYukiKeiichiro WashizukaShikyohLee RekkaZantetsuAkari IchijouJuzohKanzakiOkina no GenbuShigen NaoePlaystation exclusive charactersKojiroh SanadaDeku no ShigenBossesMusashi AkatsukiShinnosuke KagamiAwakened KagamiGameplayThe game is a typical 2D fighting game with characters from the Edo period. Unlike many fighting games, you use weapons as your attacks. Each character is outfitted with their own type of weapon or fighting style. The characters must battle there way through each fighter and then confront a final boss and are awarded their own personal ending.The game consists of two fighting modes, Speed mode which allows players to chain several attacks that will build up your meter for a desperation attack or build a speed combo. Power mode allosw you to attack harder but the build up for your special takes longer. However, if you are able to fill the bar you can perform a desperation attack that does a great amount of damage to your opponentsThe button layout is weakest attack (A), stronger attack (B), kick (C), and deflect (D). Using the D button, players can interrupt otherwise damaging attacks by stunning their opponents, leaving them open for an attack. You may also perform "cancel" moves into your desperation moves.</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5692">Samurai Shodown</game><game id="21367">Sengoku Basara X</game><game id="800">Guilty Gear XX Λ Core</game><game id="13050">Ninja Master's</game><game id="22812">Battle Fantasia</game><game id="16407">Samurai Shodown II</game><game id="23535">Samurai Shodown VI</game><game id="21768">BlazBlue: Calamity Trigger</game><game id="5640">Capcom vs. SNK: Millennium Fight 2000 Pro</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4737/410138-lastblade.jpg</image></root>