<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17676</id><name>Monster Rancher</name><description>OverviewThe main crux of all Monster Rancher games revolve around the ability to aquire monsters by simply inserting any readible CD. Certain CDs would produce unique or "special" monsters which require the user to have a high grade in order to access the creature. The protagonist of the story is a nameless rookie breeder (you assign the name) who is determined to prove that they can be a legendary breeder of monsters.GameplayThe experience was a mix of RPG and turn based strategy to raise your monster. The Goal of the game was to advance through the ranks of breeders by fighting your monster in tournaments. Each tournament would have a reward(money, items.) When not fighting in a tournament, the main objective was to improve different statistics or learn skills by working or training. You could only do so much training in one week, however, or your monster would grow tired and disobedient. If worked to hard, monsters could even die.Monsters could also go on "adventures" in the game, which were a series of tracks with a "choose your path" style of gameplay.  CreaturesBelow is a list of the available monster types in the game. Monsters were a combination of primary and secondary types, with the first determining the shape and moves of the monster, while the second determines the characteristics. Ape - a gorilla monsterDino - a basic lizard-like monsterDisk - a monster shaped like the logoDoodle - a stickman drawing monsterDragon - a dragon-style monsterGali - a mask and cape monsterGhost - created from a dead monsterGolem - a humanoid rock monsterHare - a rabbit monsterHenger - a robot monsterJell - a liquid slime-like monsterMagic - a humanoid monsterMonol - a wall monsterNaga - a snake lizard humanoid monsterNya - a stuffed cat doll monsterPlant - a vine and flower monsterPixie - a winged fairy monsterSuezo - iconic monster with a giant eyeball and tailTiger - a lupine monsterWorm - a worm monster</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3899">Digimon World</game><game id="21502">Song Summoner: The Unsung Heroes</game><game id="18673">Pokémon Yellow: Special Pikachu Edition</game><game id="23375">Gangway Monsters</game><game id="9639">Dragon Seeds</game><game id="29461">How to Train Your Dragon</game><game id="40044">The Game Maker</game><game id="42177">Breeder</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2367499-box_mr.png</image></root>