<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17713</id><name>Zelda: The Wand of Gamelon</name><description>OverviewIn The Wand of Gamelon, player's control the character of Princess Zelda (as opposed to Link, who is the main character in most other games in the Zelda series) as she embarks on a quest to defeat the evil Ganon and save Link and King Harkinian.This is the first of two instances of Zelda being a playable character (the second being the third and final installment of the CD-i series, Zelda's adventure). Gameplay is identical to that of Link: The Faces of Evil.StoryThe story begins with Zelda's father, the King, going to Gamelon to aid Duke Onkled with his on going battle with the forces of Gannon. To protect himself, he takes the Triforce of Courage and tells Zelda to send Link if he's not heard from in a month. Impa foretells through the Triforce of Wisdom that the King will return safely. A month passes and no word has come back from her father, so Zelda worries. Impa and Link reassure her that he's fine, but Zelda sends Link to find the King anyway. Later still, Zelda awakens Impa and tells her to go to Gamelon with her. They take the Triforce of Wisdom and embark on their journey to find Zelda's father and Link. Zelda finds out that her father was betrayed by Duke Onkled, who was actually working for Gannon. Zelda gets the Wand of Gamelon, a weapon needed to defeat Gannon. At the final battle, Zelda throws the wand at Gannon, entrapping him in chains and sealing him in a book. Zelda reunites with her father, Duke Onkled is captured, Link is freed from a mirror, and a feast is had for all.GameplayTo grab items, rubies, and talk with villagers: attack.Major DifferencesOther than the CD-i games not being on a Nintendo console, there are several differences that make these games extremely different from the main series.The currency name change from Rupees to Rubies. Also, Rubie colors are different: red are 1, green are 5, and blue are 10 Rubies each.Zelda is the protagonist.With the exception of Zelda II, The Wand of Gamelon is not top down like the other 2D Zelda titles.The characters talk aloud to narrate the story and there is no written dialogue.Zelda must hit things in order to pick them up instead of walking over them.Link talks. Link may make exasperated noises in the other titles, but he never talks.</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15567">I.M. Meen</game><game id="5043">Link: The Faces of Evil</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2364919-cdi_zeldathewandofgamelon_front.jpg</image></root>