<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17743</id><name>Super Smash Bros. Melee</name><description>OverviewThis game was originally made just to insult other Nintendo characters you would love to get revenge on. It focuses on a range of attacks letting you to go all out offensive. Super Smash Bros. Melee is a fighting game published by Nintendo for the GameCube on November 21, 2001 and then a few weeks later on December 2, 2001. The game is the first of two sequels to the Nintendo 64's hit title, Super Smash Bros. Melee sports a cast of 25 total characters, all of which originated in Nintendo franchises.Super Smash Bros. Melee is the GameCube's top selling title by far, making it a huge success and one of the main games to boost the console's sale noticeably. Its main appeal derives from its large player base; being simple enough for many players to play, while having a fairly large competitive scene. In fact, Melee was competitive enough to be featured in many fighting game competitions, alongside the likes of "classic" fighters such as Street Fighter and King of Fighters.Super Smash Bros. Melee was developed by HAL Laboratory, with Masahiro Sakurai as the head of production. The game was one of the first games released on the Nintendo GameCube and highlighted the advancement in graphics from the Nintendo 64. The developers wanted to pay homage to the debut of the GameCube by making an opening FMV sequence that would attract people's attention to the graphics. HAL worked with three separate graphic houses in Tokyo to make the opening sequence. On their official website, the developers posted screen shots and information highlighting and explaining the attention to physics and detail in the game, with references to changes from its predecessor.The game's soundtrack was also extremely appreciated, being formed by a large series of remixes and remakes of classic Nintendo tunes and some new ones as well.GameplayRewarding TrophiesThe game plays in the same format of its predecessor. A big part of the fighting is items, objects that have direct or indirect effects in battle. The way a player approaches this game can greatly differ with some players opting for crazy 4-player item matches and others choosing to have one on one fights on the more standard stages. Most of these originated from a previous Nintendo franchise which may or may not be represented in the game by a character. The actual game unfolds exactly like the earlier title, with it's percentage based system and knock-out of stage concept.One of Melee's most acclaimed qualities is its large amount of playable modes. Default matches play out in Stock (a predetermined number of lives) or Time, where matches end when a certain time limit expires. Coin and Bonus battles are also available. In the former, players can earn coins by damaging other players, the one with the most coins prevails. In Bonus battles, players must try to gain bonuses, which grant points, by fighting with style or accomplishing different feats.A number of single player modes are also introduced. Classic mode derives directly from the original Smash Bros. The new Adventure mode, however, consists of a series of platform-style 2D stages, all of which represent multiple Nintendo franchises. For example, the first level is a basic sidescroller level designed to look like the classic Super Mario Bros. game with the same music and enemies.Changes from the originalCharacters can now preform a wall jumpCharacters now have four throws and can pummel the opponent while holding a character in the throwAll characters now have a left/right special attack in addition to their original threeCharacters can now spot dodge and air dodgeIt is possible for characters with a ranged grab attack (such as Samus and Link) to grab onto the side of the stage when recoveringAll characters can now move with a heavy item, whereas only Donkey Kong could do this in the originalSmash attacks can now be charged by holding the "A" button, as well as quickly executed with a respective flick the the "C" stickStock matches now have an optional time limitOn occasions when breaking container items a common enemy from Mario, Ice Climber or Zelda may pop outThe "C" stick can be used to change the camera angle while navigating the menu screensThe game moves at a much faster paceItems can now be caught in mid-air after they've been thrownItem ListNameDescriptionFranchise/GameParty BallA container item that explodes with confetti and items, though on occasion it will contain bob-ombs or enemies.Smash Bros.CapsuleA container that holds an item or an enemy, it can be thrown at your opponent to do damage.Smash Bros.CrateA heavy container item that the player will struggle to walk with while holding, there is a small chance of enemies emerging.Smash Bros.BarrelA heavy container item, if a barrel is thrown to the side it will roll along the floor until it breaks.Smash Bros.Beam SwordA powerful weapon with a long reach, it is similar in appearance to a lightsaber.Smash Bros.Home-run BatA baseball bat that almost always kills your opponent when used with a fully charged smash attack.Smash Bros.FanWhy is the fan awesome? Because it is. The fan attacks your opponent with weak rapid fire hits.Smash Bros.Star RodAn item from the Kirby series that can be used to shoot stars out the end.KirbyParasolAn umbrella weapon that can be used for attacks and to float peacefully back to the stage.KirbyLip's stickAn item from a Japan only game, when you hit someone with this item it will attach a flower to their head that continually drains their health.Panel de PonHammerAn item that constantly attacks when you pick it up until it runs out, it deals a lot of damage and knock back.Donkey KongRay GunA gun that shoots out long powerful green beams.Smash Bros.Fire FlowerA item from the Mario series, you can hold it and shoot a jet of flame out at your enemies.MarioSuper ScopeA Nintendo peripheral created for the SNES, you can shoot rapid fire shots or charge up for a more powerful blast.NintendoGreen ShellThe shell of a standard Koopa, it will slide along the ground if you throw or jump on it.MarioRed ShellA famous Mario Kart weapon, when it is activated it will go after the nearest player.MarioMr SaturnA useless item that walks back and forth from the Earthbound franchise. Mr Saturn is a chill bro.EarthboundFlipperAfter it is thrown it will stop in mid air and hitting it will cause it to spin, anyone who walks into a spinning flipper will be thrown back.Balloon FightFreezieAn item from the Ice Climbers universe that will freeze an opponent solid.Ice ClimberBob-ombA famous Mario enemy, if it is not thrown it will walk back and forth and eventually explode.MarioPokeballA spherical object that when thrown releases a random strange and exotic creature known as a pokémon.PokémonBarrel CannonA barrel that you can jump into, when inside it will begin to spin and you can press "A" to fire out of the cannon.Donkey KongMotion-Sensor BombAn explosive that attaches itself to the stage and detonates when a player comes within its proximity.Smash Bros.StarmanA famous Mario power up that turns you invincibleMarioWarp StarAn item from the Kirby franchise, when using this item you will fly into the sky and come smashing back into the stage doing some large damage, you can direct where you are going to land on the stage.KirbyPoison MushroomAn item from the Mario series that debuted in the Lost Levels, this mushroom looks slightly different to the Super Mushroom and shrinks whoever it comes into contact with for a limited time.MarioSuper MushroomPerhaps the most famous power up of all time, it makes the character become much larger and more powerful for a limited time.MarioScrew AttackA character holding this items regular jumps will become screw attacks ala Samus Aran.MetroidCloaking DeviceAn item that turns the player invisible for a limited time, though the outlines of the player can still be seen.Perfect DarkMetal BoxThis item turns the player completely metal, you will move a lot slower and be harder to knock long distances.MarioBunny HoodThis item allows the player to jump much higher and also move much faster.The Legend of ZeldaFoodNom nom nom. This item will lower your percent by a varied amount.Smash Bros.Maxim TomatoAn item from the Zelda franchise that heals a large amount of health.The Legend of ZeldaHeart ContainerAn item from the Zelda franchise that heals a large amount of health.The Legend of ZeldaPokeballsMuh Balls.Pokeballs are a staple of the Smash Bros franchise, having appeared in every game. When thrown, a random pokemon will be summoned. There are 29 individual pokemon that can appear in Melee and an extra one (Ditto) can be accessed through the use of an Action Replay. The previous game only had 13 pokemon. Unlike in Brawl, which limits the amount of pokeballs on screen at one time to three, there can be an infinite amount of pokeballs on the screen at any time in Melee. Other than Electrode, the moves of a pokemon that you summoned will not affect you. Mew will not appear in the game until all characters have been unlocked and Celebi will only appear when all stages and characters have been unlocked. After this, both have a 1-in-251 chance of appearing.Pokemon NameDescription of moveArticunoArticuno unleashes a blizzard that freezes your opponents and deals massive damage.BellossomBellossom sings a song that will send anyone within a close proximity to sleep.BlastoiseBlastoise uses a water attacks to push the opponent off the stage.CelebiIts appearance is very rare. It drops trophies onto the stage.ChanseyChansey throws out a number of eggs that can be thrown for damage and contain an item inside.CharizardCharizard shoots flames out either side of itself.ChikoritaChikorita will shoots multiple leafs straight forward damaging your enemies.ClefairyClefairy will do one of four random attacks:A wirlwind will trap your foe and deal heavy damage.An attack where fire will circle the ground around Clefairy.Projectiles rain from the sky and deals large knock-back.Clefairy will shake and then explode.CyndaquilCyndaquil will hop into the air and shoot flames down in front of itself.ElectrodeIt charges up and then explodes. On occasion it will be a dud and if you are brave enough there is a brief window before the explosion where you can pick up Electrode and throw it.EnteiA wheel of fire is shot directly upwards.GoldeenGoldeen will flop about uselessly on the stage.Ho-ohHo-oh will fly off the screen and then unleash a column of fire somewhere on the screen.LugiaLugia will shoot blasts of air out in front of itself that deal great damage.MarillMarill will run around and slap whoever it crosses doing a small amount of damage.MewMew will appear and then fly off doing nothing, you will get a notice to say you have seen mew if it is your first encounter.MoltresMoltres hovers in the middle of the screen and then flies off, anyone who touches Moltres will almost certainly be instantly killed.Porygon2Dashes forward horizontally does small damage to whoever it comes into contact with and then disappears.RaikouElectricity will surge around Raikou and anyone who touches it will be dealt massive damage.ScizorScizor will fly around the stage dealing large damage and knock-back to whomever it comes into contact with.SnorlaxSnorlax leaps into the air and then fall back down on the stage in a much larger form crushing those beneath him.StaryuStaryu will search for a target and then shoot projectiles at its targets rapid fire.SuicuneSuicune creates a mini-blizzard around itself which does damage to opponents and has a possibility of freezing opponents.TogepiTopepi will do one of five random attacks:Anyone that touches the glow of energy emitted will have a flower attached to their head that drains their healthIce is blasted out and anyone touched by it is frozen and damagedPowder is shot out and opponents in range are put to sleepThe ground around Topepi shakes and anyone caught in the attack will get stuck in the groundThe screen will go completely black for a few secondsUnownUnown will fly off the screen and then fly back across the screen with multiple other Unown's dealing damage.VenusaurVenusaur will stomp down on the ground hurting those within close proximity.WeezingWeezing shoots out poison gas in a low damage, short distance move.WobbuffetWobbuffet will rock back and forward when hit damages anyone who walks into it. If no-one attacks it then nothing will happen.ZapdosElectricity circles Zapdos and it holds whoever touches it in place while it deals a hefty amount of damage.TrophiesPart of Super Smash Bros. Melee's cinematic IntroA new feature in this game is the addition of Trophies and collecting them is one of the main features of the game. Trophies (known as "Figures" in the Japanese version) are small replicas of various Nintendo characters and objects throughout history that can be collected throughout the game. These trophies include figures of playable characters, accessories, and items associated with them as well as secondary characters and properties not otherwise included in the game. The trophies range from the well-known to the obscure, and even characters or elements that were only released in Japan. The trophies include a description of the particular subject and detail the year and the game in which the subject first appeared. Super Smash Bros. had a similar system of plush dolls (Biographies); however, it only included the 12 playable characters.There is 290 collectable trophies for the player to try and obtain in the American and European version of the game. There is a trophy menu that you can select; in this mode you can gamble to try and win new trophies, a mode where you can pose your trophies and a mode where you can look through all your collected trophies. You can access the gallery to view all the trophies you have collected so far, a "new" tag will show up besides the recently collected. The trophy lottery allows you to spend coins earned in game to try and win new trophies, the more coins you use the better chance you have. The collection mode allows you to pose the trophies you have earned and as a nice Easter egg when you zoom out you can see old Nintendo consoles in the background such as the N64. The Japanese version of the game has some additional trophies but three of these can be gained in the American version through using Action Replay codes.ModesSingle PlayerClassic - The successor to the 1 Player game in Super Smash Bros, players fight a string of battles with some random conditions (such as fighting Giant/Metal characters), interspersed with mini-games such as Target Test and Snag the Trophies. Your end battle is always the same: against Master HandAdventure Mode - Super Smash Bros. MeleeAdventure - A mode with equal parts platforming and battling. Certain stages/areas are only accessible in this mode. The player is tasked with making it to the end of character themed levels, such as the Hyrule dungeon crawl level, where you have the chance to beat up Like-Likes, Re-deads, and Octoroks. Players make it to different stages by completing the battles at the end of them. By meeting certain conditions, players may be allowed to participate in special battles (such as, against Giant Kirby or Giga Bowser).All-Star - Unlocked after acquirring every character. In this mode, the player must fight and defeat every character, with characters randomly teamed up to battle. Damage is not healed after each fight, it only heals when using one of the 3 heart containers in the lobby area. Trophies occasionally appear in the lobby after a fight.Event Matches - In these specialized matches, players must meet specific conditions (such as collect 200 coins during the battle) or defeat special opponents (such as the cast of Super Mario Bros. 2). Only the first 10 are available to start, but up to 51 are unlockable by completing events and meeting certain conditions. The majority of the matches let you select any character to attempt an event, though some do have a pre-determined character that you must use.Break the Targets - Super Smash Bros. MeleeStadium Games - Simple mini-games including the Home Run Contest (smack the sandbag), Target Test (break the targets), and Multi-Man Melee (defeat as many opponents as possible). There is also an Endless Melee mode which pits the player against an infinite number of foes until they are defeated, Cruel Melee which pits the player against some of the hardest CPU leveled characters in the game, and 100/50/15 man melee where the goal is to defeat said number of foes.Training - Standard training mode with adjustable conditions.MultiplayerReadying for the Melee! - Mario using the Super Scope itemVersus Mode - The standard Smash Bros. mode. This is where the majority of friendly and competitive matches take place. The player can determine which items are dropped, which stages appear, how many lives each player has, or the length of the match.Special Melee - Play matches under various conditions, such as slow-motion, and giant characters.Tournament Mode - Set up a standard tournament with various conditions, with up to 64 players participating. You can set the final match to be a two or four player match.Character ListPlayable CharatersAll of the characters posingMelee sports a total of 25 playable characters. The initial roster is composed by 14 characters, the remaining 11 are unlockable by multiple means. Characters found within the Melee Roster are composed of recurring characters (i.e. Mario and Luigi) and new found classics (i.e. Ice Climbers) from different popular Nintendo series. The methods for unlocking characters is quite varied, such as completing Classic mode a given amount of times, or reaching a certain number of Vs. matches. Some of the characters have very specific and unique methods for being unlocked. Whatever the method, before being unlocked and playable, each new character has to be defeated in a standard match. If the player fails to defeat the new character, he/she will simply be prompted to battle the next time the unlock conditions are fulfilled.Playable CharacterSeries OriginAttainedRecurringMario- Mario seriesIntial RosterOPikachu- Pokémon seriesInitial RosterOBowser- Mario seriesInitial RosterPeach- Mario seriesInitial RosterYoshi- Mario seriesInitial RosterODonkey Kong- Donkey Kong seriesInitial RosterOCaptain Falcon- F-ZeroInitial RosterOFox- Star Fox seriesInitial RosterONess- Mother seriesInitial RosterOIce Climbers- Ice Climber seriesInitial RosterKirby- Kirby seriesInitial RosterOSamus- Metroid seriesInitial RosterOZelda/ Sheik- Zelda seriesInitial RosterLink- Zelda seriesInitial RosterOJigglypuff- Pokémon seriesUnlockableOLuigi- Mario seriesUnlockableOMarth- Fire Emblem seriesUnlockableMewtwo- Pokémon seriesUnlockableMr. Game  Watch- Game  Watch seriesUnlockableDr. Mario- Dr. Mario seriesUnlockableFalco- Star Fox seriesUnlockableGanondorf- Zelda seriesUnlockablePichu- PokémonUnlockableRoy- Fire Emblem seriesUnlockableYoung Link- Zelda seriesUnlockableInitial RosterSuper Smash Bros. Melee starts with 14 characters that can be used when initially starting a new game. There is no need to use any methods to unlock these characters for play. When these characters are used throughout gameplay, they may help to unlock hidden characters within the game. They may also be able to collectively achieve certain trophies that were once found unattainable.Super Smash Bros. Melee - Princess PeachMario - (from the Mario series)Pikachu - (from the Pokémon series)Bowser - (from the Mario series)Peach - (from the Mario series)Yoshi - (from the Yoshi series)Donkey Kong - (from the Donkey Kong series)Captain Falcon - (from the F-Zero series)Fox - (from the Star Fox series)Ness - (from the Mother series)Ice Climbers - (from the game Ice Climbers)Kirby - (from the Kirby series)Samus - (from the Metroid series)Zelda/ Sheik - (from the Zelda series)Link - (from the Zelda series)Unlockable CharactersSuper Smash Bros. Melee - Dr. MarioSuper Smash Bros. Melee - PichuJigglypuff - (from the Pokémon series)Unlock: Complete Classic/Adventure Mode on any Difficulty/Stock, or play 100 battles in Vs. ModeLuigi - (from the Mario series)Unlock: Clear Adventure Mode with a "2" in the seconds clock. In the ensuing battle, Luigi must be defeated in 1 minute. Then he will appear as a challenger after the Mode is completed. Alternately, playing 800 battles in Vs. Mode will unlock him.Marth - (from the Fire Emblem series)Unlock: Clear Classic Mode with all default characters, or play as all default characters in Vs. Mode, or play 400 battles in Vs. ModeMewtwo - (from the Pokémon series)Unlock: Play 20 hours combined in all Vs. matches, or play 700 battles in Vs. ModeMr. Game  Watch - (from the Game  Watch series)Unlock: Clear Classic and Adventure Mode with all characters, or clear Target Test with all characters, or play 1000 battles in Vs. ModeDr. Mario - (from the Dr. Mario series)Unlock: Clear Classic Mode with Mario without using continues, or play 100 battles in Vs. ModeFalco - (from the Star Fox series)Unlock: Beat 100-Man Melee, or play 300 battles in Vs. ModeGanondorf - (from the Zelda series)Unlock: Beat Event Match 29, or play 600 battles in Vs. ModePichu - (from the Pokémon series)Unlock: Beat Event Match 37, or play 200 battles in Vs. ModeRoy - (from the Fire Emblem series)Unlock: Complete Classic or Adventure Mode with Marth, or play 900 battles in Vs. ModeYoung Link - (from the Zelda series)Unlock: Complete Classic or Adventure Mode with 10 characters (must include Link and Zelda), or play 500 battles in Vs. ModeClonesMultiple characters in this game are "clones" of one another. This means that they have essentially the same moves but handle differently and appeal to different players. This is a list of the clones in Super Smash Bros. Melee.Collision of emblem swords - Marth and Roy (left to right)Roy/ Marth: Roy handles like more of a heavy character with his main area of damage being the middle of his sword. Marth handles more like a light characters with a shorter recovery whose main damage box is at the edge of his sword. Marth's Down B "Counter" attack is slightly faster than Roy's and always does 7% damage. Roy's "Counter," on the other hand, takes a little more time to perform but does 1.5 times the damage of the opponents countered attack. Roy will take damage from his fully charged standard special move but has more of a potential for damage. Marth has much greater range than Roy due to his hit box being at the tip of his blade.Fox/ Falco: Falco is more of a heavy character and a fast faller after using an aerial move. Good at ground combos leading into air combos into a spike. A slower laser gun but, being a little bit more powerful, slightly stuns the enemy. Fox is a light character who is arguably the fastest character in the whole game. He is extremely good at doing combos in the air leading to a shine off of the edge. Has a much faster laser which can be spammed repeatedly to keep enemies at a distance, but there is no stun from his blasts. Falco has a worse recovery with his Up B and Side B (Falco Phantasm) having a less range than Fox's respective moves. Another notable difference lies in the characters' Down Aerial. Fox's Down Aerial functions as a combo attack, hitting six or seven times and having little-to-no knockback, whereas Falco's Down Aerial is a single hit spike.Link/Young Link: Link and Young Link don't have to many substantial differences; Young Link is lighter and thus faster than Link; Link is heavier and slower than Young Link. Given the difference in the size of their swords, Young Link has a slightly shorter range than Link in certain moves. Both have similar moves with slight aesthetic differences. Both have the ability to use their hookshot to grab onto ledges, but only Young Link has the ability to perform a wall jump technique and it is actually required in his target test stages. There main special move is different when activated on the ground in the Young Links version does less damage but does immediate knock-back, Link's version will trap his opponent in the spin before knocking them away. When Young Link taunts he will have a swig of tasty milk, where as Link will just summon Navi.Show me your moves!Captain Falcon/ Ganondorf: Captain Falcon is a fast light character and a fast faller. Falcon is fast enough to break into many combos and is an extremely good character for chain throws. Ganondorf is a heavy and slow moving character. Despite the fact that Ganondorf is slightly stronger than Falcon, Falcon is fast enough to gain the same damage from multiple moves as one of Ganondorfs powerful moves in about the same time. Ganondorf has an arguably better recovery due to the Down B trick. While recovering, both characters can use their mid-air jumps, followed by the Down B (Falcon Kick/Wizard's Foot) and recover their midair jump for further use. The difference in use lies in the great range of Falcon's Down B, causing him to lower his position a greater amount than Ganondorf's attack, making the trick more difficult to use than Ganondorf's.Mario/Dr. Mario: Both play extremely similarly with the only real differences being the after effect of each of their same moves. Both have the same exact speed and falling time, although Mario has slightly more range and slightly less power than the Doctor. Both have the same distance of recovery. Both of the characters can use their capes (Side B) to gain horizontal distance to the ledge and end with an up b recovery. Using the cape makes up for both characters' poor recovery. The two characters do have their differences, however subtle. For example: both characters have the same move set but Mario's ground A "jab" combo is faster than Dr. Mario's "jab" combo by about a quarter of a second and is only really noticeable when you have two controllers and are making both do the same moves at the same time. The first two attacks, punches, are perfectly timed but the third attack, a kick, sees Mario pulling ahead of the Doctor. This is a result of an extra few frames of Doctor putting his fist down after the second punch. Furthermore, Mario's and Dr. Mario's grounded Down B are the same attack with the same damage but, Mario's attack sends enemies launching straight up into the air while Dr. Mario's sends the enemies at an arc to either side of him. Mario's fireballs have a higher downward angle of trajectory from the hand than Dr. Mario's pills, the Doctor's pills deal random damage unlike Mario's fireballs. Bigger differences lie in the characters' aerial moves. Visually, Mario and Dr. Mario have the same Forward Aerial, but in practice, Mario's attack is a meteor smash whereas Dr. Mario's attack sends the opponent straight upward. Mario's Neutral Aerial reduces in damage and knock-back the longer it is out (which is the norm for similar ariel moves for other characters) while opposite is true for Dr. Mario's Neutral Aerial (unique to Dr. Mario). Both have similar cape attacks. These two are true clones with only mild differences and essentially a pallet swap to tell the two apart.Pikachu/ Pichu: Following the trend of the clone characters, Pikachu is the heavier, stronger version of the character type, whereas Pichu is the lighter, weaker version. The most notable difference between the two is that Pichu hurts itself when using an electric attack, taking 1-4% of damage depending on the attack. This difference basically makes Pichu an inferior version of Pikachu. Its light weight coupled with its self-damaging attacks make Pichu much easier to KO than its evolved counterpart. Although the two have essentially the same moveset, other minor differences exist. Most of Pichu's attacks seem to be designed more around multi-hit combos whereas Pikachu's attacks are mainly one strong hit. Pichu's Forward Smash, for example, hits several times in a row and ends with strong knockback. Pikachu on the other hand, hits just once for high damage and knockback. Also note that Pikachu's Up B "Quick Attack" does damage (although minimal) to the opponent if it is in the path of movement, whereas Pichu passes harmlessly through the opponent.Tier ListOver time, the tournament community for Super Smash Bros. Melee developed a "tier list" of the characters in the game, ranking them in overall ability from best to worst. In addition to being listed from best to worst, the list is broken down into different categories, or tiers (which is where the name of the list comes from), to indicate a particularly large gap in skill from one character to the next. For example: Below, Samus is at the the bottom of the "C Tier," and Pickachu is at the top of the "D Tier." Though they are only separated by one space, the difference in tournament viability between Mario and Link is much larger than the difference between Fox and Sheik. Tier lists are constantly changed and it is often hard to pin down an official list as many players work from different lists, the below tier list is the tier list that is used by the majority of the Smash community and is the 11th version that was updated on December 31, 2010.SFox McCloud1. Fox2. Falco3. Jigglypuff4. SheikA5. Marth6. PeachCaptain Falcon7. Captain FalconB8. Ice ClimbersC9. Dr. Mario10. Ganondorf11. SamusDSamus Aran12. Pikachu13. Mario14. Luigi15. Donkey KongE16. Link17. Young LinkFPikachu (centre) using Thunder (Down B) on Donkey Kong (left) and Samus (right)18. Zelda19. Roy20. Mewtwo21. Yoshi22. Game and WatchG23. Ness24. Bowser25. Kirby26. PichuStagesPrincess Peach's Castle - Mushroom Kingdom - Super Smash Bros. MeleeSuper Smash Bros. Melee has a total of 29 stages, 18 of which are available immediately. These stages run the gamut and each character typically has at least one stage that is representative of their homeworld and/or a stage from their series.Default StagesGreat Bay - Majora's Mask - Super Smash Bros.Hyrule Temple - Legend of Zelda - Super Smash Bros. MeleeYoshi's Story - Super Smash Bros. MeleeStar Warrior Kirby at the Fountain of Dreams - Super Smash Bros. MeleeRainbow Cruise - A colorful stage from Super Mario 64, the Rainbow Cruise is constantly moving. Players start out battling on the ship, then move on to some platforming of various kinds before finally dropping down to the ship once more.Princess Peach's Castle - A staple of the Mario series, you literally fight on the top of Princess Peach's Ca stle. Platforms appear and disappear on this stage and buttons can appear to trigger them. A word of caution: the Bullet Bills are especially large around these parts...Mushroom Kingdom - Styled after the original Super Mario Bro's, Mushroom Kingdom is divided into 3 parts, with 2 pits dividing them. In the middle of these pits are platforms that lower when stepped on. Breakable blocks are also a part of the stage.Fountain of Dreams - An elegant stage with flowing water and a fountain as the centerpiece. It is simple, with a large lower platform and three small upper ones. Is that a Star Rod in the center?Green Greens - A stage with three platforms, it is home to the Whispy Woods, a recognizable enemy from the Kirby series. There are blocks in between the platforms, with the occasional bomb block causing havoc. The Woods will also blow wind and drop apples on your noggin, however you can also pick these up and throw them at your opponents.Congo Jungle - This level has been redone a bit since Super Smash Bros, but the core remains intact. There are several platforms, along with a main one, with a waterfall background. There is also a barrel under the stage, to be used for easy recovery should you fall below.Jungle Japes - With a sultry feel and big band music playing in the background, Jungle Japes is a happenin' place to battle. There is a main platform, along with a few platforms to each side. Watch out though, as this shack is set on the river, and falling in may prove to be your doom.Corneria - An update of the classic Sector Z stage in Super Smash Bros., battle on this stage is fast and furious, just like the music. The battlefield is the ship, with Arwing's doing fly-bys every so often. You can also battle on the ships gun, but good luck getting down there.Venom - A different view of the famous Great Fox ship, the battle here takes place on the wings. You battle on the ships four wings while it travels through the sky.Yoshi's Island - A straight-forward stage, Yoshi's Island has a large hill at one end, a pipe at the other, and hittable blocks making up 2 platforms. The middle blocks can also be spun, but don't jump down, or you will die. Banjos accompany the fight at Yoshi's Island.Yoshi's Story - A storybook world, Yoshi's Story is another Battlefield-esque stage, with a main platform, and 3 raised ones. Shy Guys fly around, dropping food when hit. Pak E. Derm carries a sign in the background. Randall the Cloud also moves back and forth through the stage, providing a welcome safety net.Great Bay - Heroic music accompanies this stage built on the Great Bay in Termina. It is built around the main platform, with rocks lower on either sides. Tingle floats around on a balloon, being a general goofball. There is also a giant turtle to look out for...Temple - Set in the legendary land of Hyrule, this vast, expansive stage is built around a temple. There aren't many tricks to this stage, but there are lots of places to roam. A foreboding soundtrack joins your battle in Hyrule Temple. This is the largest stage in the game that doesn't scroll and matches can take an extremely long time on this stage.Pokemon Stadium - An ever-changing battlefield, it is the home of pokemon trainers everywhere. The stage changes shape entirely when a transformation occurs, making the battle an adventure. Watch yourself on the big screen, at Pokemon Stadium.Onett - From the Earthbound franchise, this city-based stage has some hazards. The ground isn't safe, because you'll get run over by mad motorists. The awnings collapse, and the stage is generally small. Still, this is Ness' home, the least you can do is duke it out on top of his house.Brinstar - A seemingly underground level, Brinstar is Samus territory. The stage is comprised of the central mass, with two raised side platforms attached to it. These attachments, as well as the bond holding the stage together, can be broken. Be careful not to fall into the lava below.Mute City - A large stage, but a small fighting area. It is comprised of a single platform while moving. When the platform stops, in disappears, and battle is done on the track. Watch out, as the F-Zero Grand Prix is going on, and the racers aren't hesitant to run you over.Icicle Mountain - Another moving stage in the vein of Rainbow Cruise, the action on Icicle Mountain is always moving. The stage will move up and down, with players having to jump and fall to different platforms while doing battle. The stage will scroll up most of the time so you need to make sure you don't get caught out and knocked off the screen when it changes direction. Topis and Polar Bears are local inhabitants, in Icicle Mountain.New Unlockable StagesMushroom Kingdom II - Super Smash Bros. MeleeNess EarthBound - Super Smash Bros. MeleeMushroom Kingdom II - Another stage that harks back to the early Mario games, it is basic, yet has the little stylistic touches that are appreciated. There is a lower middle platform, raised side platforms, and a waterfall. Birdo shoots eggs, and Pidgit flies by on his magic carpet.Unlock: Obtain the Birdo trophyBrinstar Depths - Even further underground, Brinstar Depths is centered around a revolving rock. Battle is done precariously above the lava. Kraid occasionally pops up from the depths to hit the rock and spin it around.Unlock: Play 50 battles in Vs. ModeFourside - Earthbound's second stage, Fourside is set on top of the high rise of a city. The buildings are average in size, and falling off results in a long fall to the bottom. Occasionally, a UFO will appear in one part of the stage, providing a slippery battlefield, in Fourside.Unlock: Play 100 battles in Vs. ModeBig Blue - A stage similar to Poke Floats, Big Blue puts the player on top of various cars during the F-Zero Grand Prix. Much like any race, the cars are speeding as fast as they can, and falling off of them results in near instant death by being sped off to the left side of the screen. Captain Falcon's ship provides the biggest platform, in Big Blue.Unlock: Play 150 battles in Vs. ModePoke Floats - A stage set in the sky, battle is done on large parade-like floats in the mold of various pokemon. Each has their own quirks, and staying on the screen may be a fight all of its own.Unlock: Play 200 battles in Vs. ModeFlat Zone - On this stage the battle is actually fought on a Game  Watch device, which makes it the homeworld of Mr Game  Watch himself. Lines make up the platforms, along with houses on the sides. Oil slicks and falling tools are the norm, in Flat Zone.Unlock: Beat one of the single-player modes with Mr. Game  WatchBattlefield - This is practically the template for a basic stage in Melee, it is made up of a base platform, along with smaller raised platforms on the left and right side of it, with one raised higher in the middle. Many stages are modeled after this.Unlock: Clear All-Star Mode with any characterFinal Destination - Perhaps the most recognizable and infamous stage in Melee, many competitive players prefer this stage due to its no frills nature which encourages technical play. Nightmares of Master Hand may greet you when you step onto this stage. But with just one big platform, it pits players in a test of skill.Unlock: Clear all of the 51 event matchesUnlockable N64 stagesTitle Screen - Super Smash Bros (N64)Kongo Jungle - A second stage themed around Donkey Kong Country, this one does not feature a waterfall, instead set in the dark jungle. There is a main platform, several upper ones, and one that moves around the stage. The barrel is also back, blasting players who land in it back to safety.Unlock: Beat 15-minute melee with any characterDream Land - A slightly larger battlefield-like stage that is also home to the Whispy Woods. The wind blows, yet not much else happens on this neutral stage.Unlock: Beat target test with all charactersYoshi's Island - The original Yoshi's Island stage, this one is even more storybook. The main stage actually is a book, with 3 platforms higher than it. There are also clouds on either side that you can land on. With a smiling heart and clouds in the background, as well as a happy soundtrack, it epitomizes Yoshi.Unlock: Hit sandbag 1,300 ft with any character.Trivia- Legend has it that Hideo Kojima begged the Smash Bros. team to include Solid Snake in Melee, only to be told that development was too far along for him to be included. Luckily, Snake made it into Brawl.Lucas's Upsmash - Super Smash Bros. Brawl (Wii)- The Smash Bros. team had development plans for Lucas, the star of the Game Boy Advance only release game Mother 3. As an inclusive part of Melee's character list, he would thus replace Ness from within the gameplay, but when Mother 3 was delayed until 2006 he was scratched from being a considerable replacement.- Rumor has it that Rayman and Sonic's name was also thrown around for possible inclusion, though this has not been substantiated. Sonic eventually made it into Brawl.- If you are playing as Fox or Falco on the Corneria or Venom stages you can activate a special taunt by pressing down on the d-pad for one frame of animation. You will then have a conversation with different members of the star fox crew such as Slippy and Peppy. The taunt takes a while to come out and will stop if you are hit so it is hard to do in a competitive match.- There is a glitch that can be performed on Hyrule Temple. It is a very specific glitch that causes the turnip's that Peach throws to spark, flame, swirl and suck characters in and quickly do 999% damage to them. The glitch causes massive slowdown to the game and has been known to crash the Gamecube.- There is a glitch in the game that allows you to play as the master hand, the glitch involves having the controller in the third port and utilizing some button presses on the name entry screen. What is amazing about this glitch is that it was not actually discovered until seven years after the original release of the game.- After completing the classic mode you were treated to a game where you are piloting an arwing in a first person perspective while you try to blast away at the credits. At the end of the credits the game will give you a score and award you a coins based on your performance.- There was a large tournament scene associated with this game. Supposedly at its peak it was the second largest, next to Halo 2. The Melee community has developed its own official set of rules originating from the popular smash boards forum.Official Tournament RulesFree for all - Not part of the Official Tournament RulesetGeneral RulesItems are off.The stock is set to 4.All sets are best of 3 matches.In the event of a dispute, controller ports will be selected by Rock-Paper-Scissors.No player may choose the stage they last won on.Ties will be broken by lives, then percentage. In the event of a percentage tie, one stock sudden death will be played.Wobbling is allowed except when used to excessively stall a match.The Ice Climber Freeze Glitch is banned.Jigglypuff's rising pound stall is banned.Peach's bomber stall beneath levels where she is unreachable is banned.Bowser V. Yoshi - A Fight for the FittestSet Format (in order of procedure)Opponents choose their characters for the first match *Each player may announce one stage to be banned for the entirety of the setThe first stage will be played at random from the Random Stage List **The loser of the previous match announces the next match's stage from either the Random Stage List or the Counter Stage ListThe winner of the previous match chooses their characterThe loser of the previous match chooses their characterRepeat steps 4-7 for all proceeding matches*Double blind character selection may be called for this match. In a double blind pick, a third party is brought over, and both players tell the third person their character choice, and then third person announces the picks.**Opponents may instead agree upon a random stageDream Land: Fountain of Dreams - Super Smash Bros. MeleeRandom Stage ListDream Land: Fountain of DreamsKanto: Pokemon StadiumMushroom Kingdom: Rainbow CruisePast Stages: Dream LandPast Stages: Kongo JungleSpecial Stages: Final DestinationSpecial Stages: BattlefieldYoshi's Island: Yoshi's StoryDK, Ice Climbers, Peach, Kirby on Lyat System: Corneria - Super Smash Bros Melee.Counter Stage ListDream Land: Green GreensDK Island: Jungle JapesF-Zero Grand Prix: Mute CityKanto Skies: Poke FloatsLylat System: CorneriaMushroom Kingdom: Princess Peach's CastleMushroom Kingdom IIPlanet Zebes: BrinstarCoin battle on Hyrule Temple - Super Smash Bros. MeleeBanned Stage ListDK Island: Kongo JungleEagleland: OnettEagleland: FoursideF-Zero Grand Prix: Big BlueHyrule TempleInfinite Glacier: Icicle MountainLylat System: VenomMushroom Kingdom IYoshi's Island: Yoshi's IslandPast Stages: Yoshi's IslandSuperflat World: Flat ZoneTermina: Great BayBowser's Down B laying wasteAdditional Rules for Double's PlayLife Stealing is allowedTeam Attack/Friendly Fire is ONAdd Termina: Great Bay to the Counter Stage ListAdd F-Zero Grand Prix: Mute City to the Banned Stage ListAdd Dream Land: Fountain of Dreams to the Banned Stage ListSoundtrackIn January of 2003, Nintendo Power sent a live orchestrated version of the soundtrack to subscribers as a bonus. The track listing is as follows:Song TitleSong LengthGame Song is FromPlanet Corneria02:05Star Fox ( SNES)Jungle Garden02:57Donkey Kong Country ( SNES)Great Bay Shrine04:14The Legend of Zelda and Zelda II: The Adventure of Link ( NES)Dr. Mario04:04Dr. Mario ( NES)Original Medley05:00Super Smash Bros. Melee ( GCN)Fountain of Dreams03:35Kirby Super Star ( SNES)Pokemon Medley05:00Various Pokemon Games ( Game Boy)Opening02:40Smash Bros. Melee ( GCN)Planet Venom02:19Star Fox 64 ( N64)Yoshi's Story02:43Yoshi's Story ( N64)Depth of Brinstar03:41Metroid ( NES)Smash Bros. Great Medley14:18Various Super Mario Bros. Games ( NES)Fire Emblem03:52Fire Emblem ( NES)Green Greens01:53Kirby's Dream Land ( Game Boy)Rainbow Cruise02:49Super Mario 64 ( N64)The songs were recorded on August 27, 2002, at Tokyo Bunka Kaikan, Tokyo.Conducted by: Taizo TakemotoPerformed by: New Japan Philharmonic.Sponsored by: Nintendo Co. Ltd./HAL Laboratory Inc.Produced by: AZA/HAL Laboratory, Inc.Supervised by: Masahiro Sakurai.ReceptionSuper Smash Bros. Melee received universal acclaim from critics and was praised for the numerous improvements it made to the formula of the original game as well as adding several brand new features. The visuals of the game got a great reception at the time of launch and it remains one of the best looking games on the Gamecube to this day. Melee's orchestrated soundtrack was also lauded for its nostalgic factor, incorporating the music of countless Nintendo classics. The game received an aggregate score 92 out of 100 on Metacritic and a 90.3 on GameRankings. Super Smash Bros. Melee is the best selling Gamecube game of all time with over 7 million copies sold, it was also the first Gamecube game to reach a million copies sold. It has also received numerous awards such as IGN's readers choice award for 2001, Gamespot's Gamecube game of the year and the Official Nintendo Magazine named it as 58th best Nintendo game of all time.Melee was well received by high level fighting game fans and has been featured in the MLG as well as represented at EVO in 2007. The game has remained an active tournament game for over nine years. The game has remained popular with competitive players even after the release of Brawl. Ken Hoang is generally considered to be the best high level player of all time and has won over $50,000 from competing in various tournaments. The game was successful enough to spawn an inevitable and much anticipated sequel that was launched in 2008.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3712">Power Stone 2</game><game id="18011">Power Stone Collection</game><game id="20100">Power Stone</game><game id="21788">Jump Ultimate Stars</game><game id="21241">Jump Super Stars</game><game id="18522">Onimusha: Blade Warriors</game><game id="547">Dream Mix TV World Fighters</game><game id="8605">Marvel vs. Capcom: Clash of Super Heroes</game><game id="12312">SNK vs. Capcom: Match of the Millennium</game><game id="20831">Castlevania Judgment</game><game id="4289">The King of Fighters 2006</game><game id="21519">The King of Fighters XII</game><game id="25158">Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Smash-Up</game><game id="2296">Custom Robo</game><game id="16794">Small Arms</game><game id="9533">Kung Fu Chaos</game><game id="28102">Kabuki Ittou Ryoudan</game><game id="21870">The Outfoxies</game><game id="34429">Cartoon Network: Punch Time Explosion</game><game id="22769">Neon Genesis Evangelion: Battle Orchestra</game><game id="25770">Tales of VS.</game><game id="38140">PlayStation All-Stars Battle Royale</game><game id="39954">Pen 1 Grand Prix: Penguin no Mondai Special</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1810970-box_ssbm.png</image></root>