<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17786</id><name>Growlanser Generations</name><description>OverviewGrowlanser Generations is Working Designs' PS2 collection of Growlanser II and III and was the last game published by the company before it closed its doors in 2005. This game also marked the first time a Growlanser title had been localized into English which was later followed by Growlanser: Heritage of War (Growlanser V in Japan) and Growlanser: Wayfarer of Time (Growlanser IV in Japan).Working Designs ExtrasThe US versions of Growlanser II and Growlanser II had many alterations that were added by Working Designs. These additions included a newly added Auto-Battle feature, the ability to switch voice acting on or off for specific characters, and Working Designs' trademark extras such as dub outtakes.The Deluxe PackageA deluxe version of Growlanser Generations was released that was packaged with several pieces of Growlanser merchandise created by Working Designs. This included a Growlanser analog watch, a ring/chain with storage pouch, a set of Growlanser playing cards, and a soundtrack featuring 20 arranged tracks. The deluxe edition with all its extras, and the copy of the game itself, coasted about $90 when it was initially released.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre><genre id="15">Compilation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21222">GrimGrimoire</game><game id="4834">Suikoden Tactics</game><game id="7522">La Pucelle: Tactics</game><game id="2652">Disgaea 2: Cursed Memories</game><game id="18540">Disgaea: Hour of Darkness</game><game id="3731">Phantom Brave</game><game id="22990">Blue Dragon Plus</game><game id="10751">Final Fantasy XII: Revenant Wings</game><game id="21626">Heroes of Mana</game><game id="19701">Stella Deus: The Gate of Eternity</game><game id="451">Makai Kingdom: Chronicles of the Sacred Tome</game><game id="20112">Sakura Wars: So Long, My Love</game><game id="17767">Lunar: Silver Star Story Complete</game><game id="4248">Lunar 2: Eternal Blue Complete</game><game id="1885">Summon Night 4</game><game id="3048">Summon Night 3</game><game id="22847">Eternal Poison</game><game id="31138">Global Defence Force Tactics</game><game id="25235">Under Siege</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2478657-box_gg.png</image></root>