<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17828</id><name>Battlefield 2142</name><description>OverviewBattlefield 2142 is primarily a multiplayer shooter that allows the player to battle on foot and in vehicles with up to 63 other gamers in two gameplay types: Titan and Conquest. The conquest mode is very similar to previous Battlefield games with players attempting to attack and defend various control nodes set on large scale maps. Titan mode, the new addition, asks you complete a series of objectives in order to down the other team's floating fortress ship.With 2142, developer DICE focused more heavily on the leveling and power-up system (where users exchange game experience for new weapons) then they had in the game's predecessor, Battlefield 2, which introduced the leveling concepts. Essentially, players choose one of the four classes: Recon, Assault, Engineer or Support, and gain experience in each class the more they play and destroy the opposing team. Experience can then be exchanged for special abilities for that class only. While giving people a reason to play the game for extended periods, the leveling system continued to annoy new players who were instantly at a disadvantage when loading up the game for the first time.Game ModesConquestIf you've ever played a Battlefield game on the PC or Mac before, you know what this is. Capture more control points on the map before the other team does to bleed them of resources (tickets). There are three variations on the style.AssaultHead-OnAssault Lines: The force that causes the opponents tickets to reach zero wins. The defending team's home base cannot be captured until the assaulting team have taken control of all other points on the map.TitanThe goal of Titan mode- Destroy the reactor core.Instead of capturing control points that are really just flags, you need to capture missile silos. These silos damage the enemy Titan's shields. The Titan is a flying fortress carrying air support vehicles and has several Titan guns for ground support. Once the shields are down, the opposing team can enter the Titan and destroy it. To do so, they need to blow up 4 consoles, then the 'Core' of the Titan. They then have about 30 seconds to escape the Titan as it blows up. The first half, the capture the silos half, plays a lot like traditional Conquest mode. A big part of strategy involves both defense of your own Titan and capturing silos to ensure the enemy Titan becomes vulnerable. An undefended Titan can be destroyed quickly by a good squad.MapsThere are 16 official maps in the game, including 3 that came with the Northern Strike Booster Pack and, and 2 that arrived for free in recent updates. All maps are spread across two theaters: Europe and Africa. The only exception is Wake Island 2142, a community developed map that takes place in the Pacific Theater that was included in an official update from DICE and is an update to a map that that was found in both Battlefield 1942 and Battlefield 2.European TheaterBelgradeConquest Mode: Head OnTitan Mode: UnavailableNo Vehicle Mode: YesCerbere LandingConquest Mode: AssaultTitan Mode: UnavailableNo Vehicle Mode: YesFall of BerlinConquest Mode: AssaultTitan Mode: UnavailableNo Vehicle Mode: YesMinskConquest Mode: AssaultTitan Mode: YesNo Vehicle Mode: YesVerdunPAC base in Verdun under attack.Conquest Mode: Head-OnTitan Mode: YesNo Vehicle Mode: YesBridge at Remagen (Only available with the Northern Strike Booster Pack)Conquest Mode: Assault LinesTitan Mode: YesNo Vehicle Mode: NoPort Bavaria (Only available with the Northern Strike Booster Pack)Conquest Mode: Assault LinesTitan Mode: YesNo Vehicle Mode: NoLiberation of Leipzig (Only available with the Northern Strike Booster Pack)Conquest Mode: Assault LinesTitan Mode: YesNo Vehicle Mode: NoAfrican TheaterThe African theatre; The sun rises of Tampa Highway.Northern Strike Camp GibraltarConquest Mode: AssaultTitan Mode: UnavailableNo Vehicle Mode: YesSuez CanalConquest Mode: AssaultTitan Mode: YesNo Vehicle Mode: YesShuhia TaibaConquest Mode: Head-OnTitan Mode: YesNo Vehicle Mode: YesSidi Power PlantConquest Mode: Head-OnTitan Mode: YesNo Vehicle Mode: YesTunis HarborConquest Mode: Head-OnTitan Mode: UnavailableNo Vehicle Mode: YesSteam ReleaseAccording to DICE associate producer Barrie "Bazajaytee" Tingle as of February 25th 2011 DICE has a Steam release in the " waiting" and should be release soon. Hopes for a Steam release were dashed when EA announced their own distribution service, Origin, and removed several of their games from Steam.System RequirementsMinimum System ConfigurationProcessor : 1.7 GHzRAM : 512 MBGPU :128 MB video card supporting 1.4 shaders (ATI Radeon 8500 / NVIDIA FX 5700 or above), DirectX CompliantInternet connection : 128kbit Cable/DSL connectionHard Drive : 1.8Gb of space is required to install the gameOS : Windows XP with latest service pack installed (does not work on Windows 2000/Me)Recommended System ConfigurationProcessor : 3.0 GHzRAM : 1.5 GBGPU : 256 MB video card supporting 1.4 shaders (ATI Radeon X700 / NVIDIA GeForce 6600GT or above)Internet connection : 512Mb Cable/DSL connectionHard Drive : 1.8Gb of space is required to install the gameOS : Windows XP with latest service pack installed (does not work on Windows 2000/Me)Latest PatchOn February 15, 2011 DICE release patch 1.51 which fixed some hit detection issues and included the previously separate booster pack Norther Strike for free.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19654">Frontlines: Fuel of War</game><game id="18883">Enemy Territory: Quake Wars</game><game id="7094">Star Wars: Battlefront II</game><game id="15481">Star Wars: Battlefront</game><game id="21116">MAG</game><game id="14436">PlanetSide</game><game id="7747">John Romero's Daikatana</game><game id="11339">Counter-Strike: Source</game><game id="21912">Planetside: Core Combat</game><game id="20614">Star Wars Battlefront: Renegade Squadron</game><game id="13683">Quake 4</game><game id="24949">Star Wars: Battlefront III</game><game id="2832">Tribes 2</game><game id="909">Tribes: Vengeance</game><game id="18758">Codename: Eagle</game><game id="17179">Starsiege: Tribes</game><game id="27863">Dust 514</game><game id="26549">Star Wars Battlefront: Elite Squadron</game><game id="18828">Unreal Tournament 2003</game><game id="32620">Section 8: Prejudice</game><game id="15048">Killzone</game><game id="11757">Crysis</game><game id="29601">Nuclear Dawn</game><game id="34424">Tribes Ascend</game><game id="38072">Ravaged</game><game id="38039">Call of Duty: Black Ops II</game><game id="42646">Battlefield Online</game><game id="42860">Titanfall</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1897518-box_bf2142.png</image></root>