<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17853</id><name>Sniper Elite</name><description>StoryThe story takes place in 1945 where Karl Fairburne is a US OSS (Office of Strategic Services) agent sent to the Battle of Berlin disguised as a German sniper. His Mission: Obtain secret documents about German nuclear technology before the Soviets get their hands on it.GameplayOffering a unique blend of third and first person tactical action with stealth. While all movement is made in third person (to include weapon switching), you switch to first person for all sniper shots. The stealth aspect is reinforced by a camouflage feature. As you navigate the terrain in Sniper Elite, you are given a percentage of how well you are camouflaged.Sniper Elite is a cross between simulation and arcade gameplay:Simulation - The game offers many difficulty modes of play. Most of which include options you can toggle on and off: gravity (bullet drop), wind strength, lung capacity, and overall AI strength. While it is arcade-like to be able to toggle these, the more options turned on, the more realistic this game is.Arcade - Uses the Gamespy account service (similarly seen in recent games like Borderlands) to track and record your score. The score is based on the number of times you save, the type of killshots you make, and time to complete the level. An overview of the statistics of the previous level are presented at each level's completion.One of the selling features of the game is including a slow-motion sniper cam. If you make a shot over 50m, the camera will fixate on the bullet leaving your gun and follow the trajectory in slow motion to it's intended target. Once it reaches that target, you get to see the gruesome results of your shot and are given a rating based on that shot that adds to your overall level score.CharactersKarl Fairburne - The protagonist and only character you play as. Not much is known about his background.MissionsKarlshorstMeet the informantAssassinate BormannSupply RaidReichstagBrandenburg GateExtract AgentMissing ContactMeet the CourierInfiltrate the SquareFrench CathedralExfiltrate the SquareKarlshorst RepriseDestroy Fuel DumpThe ScientistsU-Bahn StationPrevent EnforcementAnhalter StationNordsig HW PlantVia the U-barnApproach to NordsigEliminate GuardpostHW PlantAssist OSS TeamExfiltrate NordsigRecover V2 TechCut CommunicationsDestroy the Ammo DumpsDisable KatyushasHolzmarkt Train YardThe SchlossEscape From BerlinExtract the PilotJourney to TempelhofTempelhof AirportSecret MissionThe SafehouseWii VersionThe Wii version of Sniper Elite was ported by Raylight Studios and now includes motion controls and support for the Wii Zapper. This version also contains an extra bonus level upon completion of the game; beyond the bonus level and the addition of motion controls, the Wii version of Sniper Elite is near identical to the version released in 2005.PC System RequirementsMinimum System RequirementsWindows 98/2000/ME/XP1 GHz Pentium CPU or equivalentGeForce 2 32Mb256 Mb RAMDirectX 8 compatible sound card4 Gb free hard disk spaceDVD-ROM driveRecommended System RequirementsWindows 98/2000/ME/XP1.4 GHz Pentium CPU or equivalentGeForce 4 Ti or better512 Mb RAMDirectX 8 compatible sound card4 Gb free hard disk spaceDVD-ROM driveDigital DistributionThe PC version of Sniper Elite is available on Steam for $9.99 USD</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21616">The Saboteur</game><game id="30566">Sniper: Ghost Warrior</game><game id="32249">Sniper: Art Of Victory</game><game id="8835">Sniper: Path of Vengeance</game><game id="13970">World War II: Sniper - Call to Victory</game><game id="24772">The Sniper 2</game><game id="34715">Sniper Elite V2</game><game id="33002">Sniper: Ghost Warrior 2</game><game id="37516">Snipers</game><game id="41928">Sniper Elite 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2199371-box_selite.png</image></root>