<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17861</id><name>MechAssault 2: LoneWolf</name><description>OverviewMechassault 2 is a third person shooter developed by Day 1 Studios in conjunction with FASA Studios. The game follows the Mechwarrior, Lt. Foster and Maj. Natalia as they continue their fight against the Word of Blake. Though primarily focused on mech combat, Mechassault 2 allows players to exit the mech and pilot Power Armors, tanks and VTOLs.CampaignA Star Adder charging up its mighty Alpha StrikeThe campaign continues the story of the silent Mechwarrior, a Wolf's Dragoon mercenary mech pilot, and his unit as they continue to fight the radical World of Blake. The Word of Blake is attempting to find the lost data cores that contain lost technology in order to build the ultimate mech and it is up to the Mechwarrior to stop them. The player eventually collects all five data cores and uses them to fight the new leader of the Word of Blake: Nemesis. Completing the campaign unlocks the Nemesis avatar.GameplayCarry on. Don't mind me.Mechassault 2 features the same third person perspective mech gameplay as its predecessor. Players can choose to pilot light, medium, heavy or assault mechs. Like the previous Mechassault, the player cannot customize the mech and each chassis comes with a predetermined armor, heat capacity and weapon sets. LIke other Battletech games, weapons come in three categories: energy, ballistic and missile. Pilots can collect power ups for each of the three weapon categories that enhance the weapon for a set amount of shots. Many mechs also come with a defensive system such as cloaking or target jamming. New mechs, offensive and defensive weapons are introduced including the new Nova Cat and Star Adder Mechs as well as reactive and reflective armor abilities. Some of the chassis in the first game have been modified to include these new weapons. Assault Mechs now have the ability to perform an Alpha Strike, an attack available if all weapon systems on the mech are at level three. The Alpha Strike is capable of one hit killing many of the medium mechs and has a large blast radius. However the Alpha Strike has travels slowly towards its target and after firing, the mech not only overheats but all weapon systems return to level one.New to the series is the ability to exit the mech and continue the mission as a pilot on the ground. The player is extremely vulnerable as a pilot and can be run over or stepped on by vehicles and mechs. However, the pilot is capable of planting a powerful explosive that does significant damage to the lighter mechs. As a pilot, the player can choose to enter unoccupied mechs and vehicles strewn about the map.Mech Jacking in progressThe most touted addition is the Battle Armor, a Power Armor like the Elemental equipped with a pulse laser, a mortar and jump jets. The Battle Armor is capable of hijacking mechs by jump jetting and latching on to the mech. Pilots of the mech and the armor initiate a series of quick time button presses to fill up a bar. If the Battle Armor wins, the pilot in the mech is ejected from the mech giving access to the now empty mech. If the mech pilot wins, the Battle Armor is ejected form the the mech and takes half of his health bar away. The Battle Armor can also latch onto the legs of a friendly mech or underneath a VTOL for faster transport. It gains a more powerful pulse laser when latched.New controllable vehicles include the Rommel Mk II tank, the VTOL and a turret. Though they cannot stand up to a mech one on one, they offer valuable support. The tank controls much like the mechs and is equipped with machine guns, a cloaking system and a unique Gravity Cannon with optical zoom and the ability to knock down mechs. The VTOL can lift cargo such as power armor, tanks and in particular power ups. This makes the VTOL an invaluable support vehicle in multiplayer. The turret fires a player controllable missile and has a shield.MultiplayerMechassault 2 features many of the same game types found in the first Mechassault. Up to 12 players can compete in various game modes via Xbox Live or system link. However unlike its ancestor, players no longer have the ability to choose their mech chassis before the match. All players spawn in a Battle Armor and can exit and enter the mechs and vehicles on the map. The mechs and vehicles that appear depend on the game type. In the lobby, players are represented by character models. Models include the Mechwarrior, Foster, Natalia, Alera and Nemesis. Players can do gestures with their characters by pressing the X, Y, left and right triggers. Holding in the left thumbstick while pressing one of the four buttons allows an additional four gestures.Multiplayer MapsBogged DownDeliveranceGoing CommandoIll WindIn Your FaceKilling FieldsNew River CityNo Mans LandOn the RocksOver the FallsProving GroundRuch HourUnder CoverWitch CauldronLimited Edition/ Free DLCMountain HighTroubled WatersPaid DLCBarrier ReefBig DigField of DreamsKnee DeepNew VeniceTitansGame ModesGrinder: Wave based survival mode. Can be played Single Player or 2 player Co-opDestruction: Deathmatch/ Team DeathmatchCapture the FlagLast Man Standing: FFA or Team game where each player only has one life.Check It: Domination type game where teams fight for control of outposts scattered across the map. The team with the most outposts winSnatch It: Multi-flag CTF mode where two teams attempt to take as many data cores strewn about the mapNot It!: Free for all game mode where one player is "it". The only way to gain points is to get kills as "it". The player that killed "it" becomes "it"Base War: Both teams must defend a generator in their base while attempting to destroy the generator on the other team.Conquest: A new persistent multiplayer mode. The player initially joins one of the 5 Houses: Davion, Stiener, Kurita, Liao and Marik. The player participates in helping their house take over planets from the other houses for domination of the Inner Sphere.Mechs and VehiclesMechassault 2 features 30 Mechs. All the mechs from the first game, including the DLC mechs, return. Like the first game, many of the mechs share the same chassis but have different weapons load outs and paint jobs. In addition to the mechs, there are two PowerArmors, a tank, a VTOL and a turret.Light MechsMechTonnageWeaponsSpecial/ DefenseUller302 Lasers2 Javelin LRMsReflective ArmorJump JetsKitfox302 Pulse Lasers1 Warhammer MissileNull SignatureJump JetsRaven351 Laser2 Machine Guns1 Javelin LRMsNull SignatureCorvus352 Pulse Lasers1 AutocannonReflective ArmorOwens352 Machine Guns2 Crossbow SRMsReactive ArmorHackman351 Gauss Rifle2 Crossbow SRMsNull SigCougar352 Pulse Lasers1 Autocannon2 Javelin LRMsAnti-Missile SystemJump JetsPuma351 PPC2 Machine Guns2 Crossbow SRMsNull SignatureJump JetsMedium MechsMechTonnageWeaponsSpecial/ DefenseRaptor401 Pulse Laser2 Autocannons3 Crossbow SRMsNull SignatureJump JetsStiletto401 Flamethrower1 Gauss Rifle3 Crossbow SRMsReactive ArmorJump JetsUziel502 PPCs1 Machine Gun1 Crossbow SRMReflective ArmorJump JetsBelial502 Pulse Lasers2 Gauss Rifles1 Crossbow SRMTarget JammingJump JetsHeavy MechsMechTonnageWeaponsSpecial/ DefenseVulture602 Lasers1 Machine Gun4 Javelin LRMsReflective ArmorMad Dog602 Pulse Lasers2 Autocannons4 Crossbow SRMsTarget JammingCatapult654 Pulse Lasers4 Javelin LRMsReflective ArmorJump JetsBow Man652 Lasers2 Machine Guns2 Warhammer MissilesReactive ArmorJump JetsLoki652 Pulse Lasers2 Autocannons3 Crossbow SRMsNull SignatureHellbringer652 Flamers2 Autocannons1 Javelin LRMAnti-Missile SystemJump JetsThor702 Lasers4 Machine Guns2 Crossbow SRMsReactive ArmorJump JetsSummoner704 Pulse Lasers2 Autocannons1 Warhammer MissileAnti-Missile SystemJump JetsNova Cat705 Lasers1 Machine GunReflective ArmorWendigo701 PPC3 AutocannonsReactive ArmorMad Cat752 PPCs2 Machine Guns4 Javelin LRMsTarget JammingTimberwolf752 Pulse Lasers2 Gauss Rifles4 Crossbow SRMsAnti-Missile SystemAssault MechsMechTonnageWeaponsSpecial/ DefenseBlood Asp902 Plasma PPCs4 Machine Guns2 Javelin LRMsAlpha StrikeStar Adder902 Plasma PPCs1 Flamethrower4 AutocannonsAlpha StrikeAtlas1004 Pulse Lasers4 Autocannons2 Javelin LRMsAlpha StrikePrometheus1003 Lasers2 Gauss Rifles2 Warhammer MissliesAlpha StrikeRagnarok1001 Lava Gun2 Gauss Rifles4 Javelin LRMsShieldYmir1001 Lava Gun2 PPCs4 AutocannonsShieldOtherUnitClassificationWeaponsSpecial/ DefenseBattle ArmorPower Armor1 Pulse Laser1 MortarMech JackingJump JetsElementalPower Armor1 Laser1 Crossbow SRMJump JetsRommel Mk IITank1 Gravity Cannon1 Machine GunNull SignatureGoblin (DLC)APC2 Machine Guns2 Crossbow SRMsCargoVTOLPlane2 Crossbow SRMsCargoTurretEmplacement1 Pulse Laser1 POV MissileShieldLimited EditionThe Limited Edition contains the game disk, and a bonus disk containing 2 additional multiplayer maps and a making-of video.SoundtrackThe game features "Gettting Away With Murder" by Papa Roach and "Right Now" by Korn</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17302">War World: Tactical Combat</game><game id="17041">MechWarrior 2: Mercenaries</game><game id="11350">Zone of the Enders</game><game id="14084">TransFormers</game><game id="13461">Ultrabots</game><game id="4602">10six Online</game><game id="25296">Lore: Aftermath</game><game id="25684">Murakumo: Renegade Mech Pursuit</game><game id="772">Outwars</game><game id="34304">Iron Brigade</game><game id="34412">Hawken</game><game id="37541">Reign of Thunder</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2276012-box_mecha2lw.png</image></root>