<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17884</id><name>Secret Files: Tunguska</name><description>OverviewSecret Files: Tunguska is a classic 2D, third person point and click adventure game developed by German studio Fusionsphere. The game takes the real Siberian Tunguska event and weaves a fictional story around it. Known best for its high resolution graphics. The English version of the game features English voice over.The game has been released for both PC and Nintendo DS.StoryThe 1908 Tunguska event in Siberia unleashed over 1000 times the energy of the Hiroshima nuclear bomb and remains unexplained, having flattened over 6,000 square kilometers of trees and was heard from hundreds of miles away. Vladimir Kalenkov, a Russian scientist living in modern Berlin, Germany, and a leading researcher of the Tunguska event, mysteriously disappears from his office. His daughter Nina decides to investigate, which leads her around the world and uncovers a conspiracy related to the Tunguska event.GameplayA very traditional point and click adventure game, it features a highly streamlined user interface and highly detailed, high resolution graphics and 3D character models. It also features the Scoop key, which highlights all interactive elements on the screen when pressed. Puzzles are traditional and involve the usual mix of inventory combining and dialog trees.You play as both Nina and Max, but not at the same time. A diary records all important events and also provides optional hints for certain puzzles. It also allows double clicking on an exit to immediately leave the scene. The cursor in the game is a mouse in fact and visually indicates what action would occur for each mouse button when pressed.PC System RequirementsMinimumWindows 2000/XPIntel Pentium II 500MHz (Or equivilent)16MB DX9 Compatible graphics card2.0GB Disk SpaceDX9 Compatible Sound CardDVD-RomMouse</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="29490">Lost Horizon</game><game id="24312">Secret Files 2: Puritas Cordis</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3948/965293-44001.jpg</image></root>