<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17890</id><name>Tourist Trophy: The Real Riding Simulator</name><description>Tourist Trophy features a wide variety of motorcycles, scooters, sports bikes, endurers, naked bikes, and Motard ranging from 125cc to over 1500cc. Bikes are from 80's to modern day. Major real world race circuits are also featured, including the famous Nürburgring.GameplayTourist Trophy includes two main game modes:Arcade ModeThis mode is straight into the action. The player chooses a motorcycle, a track and applies changes to any settings that they want to change such as, riding style, gear, AI etc. The player is free to choose race settings.The race modes are "1 on 1", "Race" and "2 Player Battle". "1 on 1" is a one-player mode that allows you to play a head to head race using normal bikes. "Race" is a one-player mode that lets you choose a course and motorcycle, and then aim for the fastest possible lap time. "2 Player Battle" is a two-player split-screen mode where you can race against a friend.TT ModeTT Mode The license system from the Gran Turismo series remains the same, you complete challenges to receive licenses. There are four license types: "Novice", "Junior", "Expert" and "Super". The higher the level of your license the more bikes you can acquire in Challenge Mode and Race events you can enter. To acquire more motorcycles you enter Challenge Mode and select a bike and paint scheme, then complete a goal-specific challenge to acquire the bike you chose. In the Garage you can view the list of bikes you currently own. You can also manage bikes and change your riding form. In the Riding Gear menu the player can select the riding gear from the available set you've acquired. 186 different riding accessories including different helmets, gloves, boots, pants, one piece racing suits and jackets are available.These unlock as you win races and earn licenses, most major motorcycle brands are available, Arai, Shoei, AGV, Alpinestars and Dainese etc.The default difficulty setting is "Normal", this can be changed to "Professional" which adds separate control of the brakes and more realistic AI. Photo ModeThis a simplified version of the Photo Mode in Gran Turismo 4. This mode allows you to capture images of  the bike you are currently riding. You select the best bits from your run and capture pictures from there. These can be printed from a compatible USB printer or transferred as JPEG images to a USB memory stick. Images can also be saved in a format readable by the game itself on the memory card.TuningAnother trait that carries over from the Gran Turismo games is the tuning. Tyre pressure, gear timing, suspension etc. can all be changed to a players liking. Ridimg Syle can be changed to suit the players own needs. Players can choose from these riding forms, "Lean Body", "Neutral", "Lean Bike"  "Motard". "Neutral Form" is a comprehensive, easy riding style, "Lean Body" focuses on quick cornering and "Lean Bike" makes initial turn-in quicker and helps during slow cornering. "Motard" relates to the french style of off-road/road racing. In this riding style the rider puts their leg out during cornering. All of these have their own advantages and disadvantages. Riding form tuning is available in both Arcade and TT modes. You can also choose the settings you wish to modify and create your own custom riding style.Reception LaunchThe game was released first in China on January 26, 2006 and February 2 in Japan. The game was released in the US on April 4, 2006 with seven new motorcycles, new riding gear, seven bonus BGM tracks, in depth profiles of each motorcycle, a "Semi-Pro" difficulty and enhanced visual effects. The game was released in Europe on May 29 and Oceania on June 1. The European version contained new BGM tracks by European artists.General ReceptionThe game was praised for its realistic simulation of motorcycling, amount of motorcycles and in-depth tuning and customizing, but was criticised for having only three other AI racers in it's race modes and it's lack of online play. Some criticised the tracks receycled from the Gran Turismo series.Motorcycles12 Manufacturers. 132 Bikes.*RM*- The race modified version of a production motorcycle. ApriliaRSV1000 R (2005)RSV1000 R Factory (2005)    RSV1000 R Factory RM (2005)BMW MotorradK1200R (2005)K1200R RM (2005)K1200S (2005)K1200S RM (2005)R1200ST (2005)BuellFirebolt XB12R (2005)Firebolt XB12R RM (2005)Lightning XB9SX (2005)Ducati999R (2005)999R RM (2005)HondaCB1300 SUPER BOL D'OR (2005)CB1300 SUPER BOL D'OR RM (2005)CB1300 Super Four (2005)CB1300 Super Four RM (2005)CB400 (1974)CB400SS (2005)CB400SS RM (2005)CB750F (1979)CB750F (1981)CB750F RM (1981)CBR1000RR (2005)CBR1000RR RM (2005)CBR1000RRW Suzuka 8H R (2005)CBR1100XX (2001)CBR600RR (2005)CBR600RR RM (2005)CBR954 Fireblade (2002)Honda Forza S (2002)Honda Forza Z (2005)FTR (2005)NR750 (1992)NS250R (1984)NS250R RM (1984)NS400R (1985)NS400R RM (1985)NSR250R SE (1993)NSR250R SE RM (1993)RC162 (1961)VFR (2005)VFR400R (1989)VFR400R RM (1989)VT250F (1982)VT250F RM (1982)XR250 Motard (2005)KawasakiD-Tracker (2005)GPZ400R (1985)GPZ400R RM (1985)GPZ900R (1984)GPZ900R RM (1984)Ninja ZX-10R (2005)Ninja ZX-10R RM (2005)Ninja ZX-10R Suzuka 8H R (2005)Ninja ZX-12R (2000)Ninja ZX-12R RM (2000)Ninja ZX-6R (2005)Ninja ZX-6R RM (2005)Z1000 (2005)Z1000 RM (2005)Zephyr 1100 (2005)Zephyr 1100 RM (2005)ZRX1200R (2005)ZRX1200R RM (2005)MoriwakiCBR1000RR Suzuka 8H R (2005)Moriwaki CBR600RR-MORIWAKI (2005)MV AgustaF4-1000S (2005)F4-1000S RM (2005)Brutale 910 (2005)Brutale 910 RM (2005)SuzukiDR-Z400SM (2004)GSX 1100S Katana (2000)GSX 1100 Katana RM (2000)GSX 1300R Hayabusa (2005)GSX 1300R Hayabusa RM (2005)GSX 1300R Hayabusa Special Colour (2005)GSX 1400 (2004)GSX 1400 RM (2004)GSX-R 1000 (2005)GSX-R 1000 RM (2005)GSX-R 400 (1984)GSX-R 400 RM (1984)GSX-R 600 (2005)GSX-R 600 RM (2005)GSX-R 750 (2005)RG250 Gamma (1983)RG250 Gamma RM (1983)RG500 Gamma (1985)RG500 Gamma RM (1985)Sky Wave 250 SS (2005)Sky Wave 250 Type S (2005)Sky Wave 650 (2004)TriumphDaytona 650 (2005)Daytona 650 RM (2005)Speed Triple (2005)Speed Triple RM (2005)Sprint ST (2005)YamahaFJR1300 (2004FZR400 (1986)FZR400 RM (1986)Grand Majesty 250 (2005)MT-01 (2005)MT-01 RM (2005)RZ250 (1980)RZ250 RM (1980)RZV500R (1984)RZV500R RM (1984)SR400 (2005)SR400 RM (2005)TDM900 (2005)TMAX (2005)TMAX RM (2005)TW225E (2005)TZ125 R (2003)TZ250 R (2005)TZR250 (1985)TZR250 RM (1985)TZR250SPR (1995)TZR250SPR RM (1995)VMAX (2005)VMAX RM (2005)XJR 1300 (2005)XJR 1300 RM (2005)YZF-R1 (2005)YZF-R1 RM (2005)YZF-R1 Suzuka 8H R (2005)YZF-R6 (2005)YZF-R6 RM (2005)YoshimuraGSX-R 1000 Suzuka 8H R (2005)Katana 1135R (2001)HAYABUSA X-1 (2000)Race TracksReal TracksCircuit de ValenciaFuji Speedway 2005Fuji Speedway 80'sFuji Speedway 90'sInfineon RacewayLaguna Seca RacewayNürburgring NordschleifeSuzuka CircuitSuzuka Circuit East CourseSuzuka Circuit West Course    Tsukuba CircuitTwin Ring Motegi East Short CourseTwin Ring Motegi Road CourseTwin Ring Motegi Super SpeedwayTwin Ring Motegi West Short CourseFictional TracksApricot Hill RacewayAutumn RingAutumn Ring MiniBeginner CourseDeep Forest RacewayEl CapitanGrand Valley SpeedwayGrand Valley Speedway EastHigh-Speed RingMidfield RacewayMotorlandTest CourseTrial Mountain CircuitClubman Stage Route 5Special Stage Route 5City TracksCitta di AriaCosta di AmalfiCircuit de Monaco (Côte d'Azur)Hong KongNew YorkSeattle CircuitSeoul CentralTokyo Route 246</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17784">Gran Turismo 4</game><game id="17274">MotoGP '06</game><game id="17685">MotoGP: Ultimate Racing Technology 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2276105-box_ttrophy.png</image></root>