<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17905</id><name>PoPoLoCrois</name><description>Graphics The game uses anime type animation for CG movies and sprite based graphics for game play.GameplayThe game does not feature standard RPG random battles, but instead the enemies can be seen at all time, allowing you to avoid encounters if you so desire. The combat in the game is a cross between standard RPG turn-based combat (Final Fantasy) and Tactical RPG games (Ogre Battle).  On each turn a character can move on the grid a set number of spaces depending on stats and then attack targets within range, attacks can be made so that multiple enemies are hit, attacks from behind have a greater chance of being critical hits.  Many special attacks have an area of effect that the game highlights and may hit several enemies in a certain zone or pathway.StoryAfter some background with an Anime CG movie you come to present day to find the main character, Pietro, is celebrating the night of his 10th birthday, Pietro learns from his father that his mother, who Pietro thought was dead, is in a coma with.  Pietro of course sets out to cure his mother.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="15">Compilation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19938">The Legend of Heroes: A Tear of Vermillion</game><game id="5278">The Legend of Heroes III: Song of the Ocean</game><game id="6859">The Legend of Heroes II: Prophecy of the Moonlight Witch</game><game id="9532">Disgaea: Afternoon of Darkness</game><game id="11771">Brave Story: New Traveler</game><game id="7281">Astonishia Story</game><game id="21624">Mana Khemia: Alchemists of Al-Revis</game><game id="24102">Crimson Gem Saga</game><game id="26422">Lunar: Silver Star Harmony</game><game id="27372">Narisokonai Eiyuuden: Taiyou to Tsuki no Monogatari</game><game id="27501">Hexyz Force</game><game id="33382">Ni no Kuni: Wrath of the White Witch</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2199422-box_popo.png</image></root>