<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>17990</id><name>Trace Memory</name><description>Story Trace Memory stars    Ashley Mizuki Robbins, a 13 year old girl who for most of her life has  been raised by her aunt, Jessica, because her parents mysteriously  vanished when she was an infant. Both parents were believed to be  dead, but a couple of days before Ashley's fourteenth birthday, she  received a package that contained a letter from her missing father and  a small machine. The letter said that he would be waiting on Blood  Edward Island, an island located off the coast of Washington in the  United States. The next day, Jessica and Ashley ride over to the  Island, but Ashley's father isn't there to greet them. After realizing  that Ashley's father isn't around, Jessica goes to look for him When  Jessica fails to return also, Ashley decides to go out to find both of  them.GameplayAs an adventure game in the traditional point-and-click style, you'll be directing  Ashley to pick up and examine objects, as well as scrutinize written (often cryptic) clues  for use in puzzles scattered about the island. Simple examples include fitting broken pieces together to make a workable lever, valve or handle; more complex examples include thinking outside the box and actually using the Nintendo DS itself in clever ways to generate solutions.      One of the game's puzzles  Ashley can be controlled with both the stylus and the d-pad, offering varying degrees of precision with which to move her from location to location. To facilitate this, the polygonal environment is presented on the touch screen. The top screen shows any area of significance within Ashley's immediate viewpoint. For instance, having Ashley trot in front of a gate or a sign will bring up a more detailed illustration of that gate or sign. If the object(s) being looked at are interactive, the game will then let the player use the touch screen to manipulate the object.At the end of each chapter, Trace Memory asks a series of simple questions to test the player's memory with regards to the events that just transpired within that chapter. Worked into the game's theme surrounding "memories", this technique was also used by developer Cing in its follow-up point-and-click adventure,   Hotel Dusk: Room 215. This is ostensibly done to keep the player from not paying attention to the events s/he's supposed to be scrutinizing carefully.Trace Memory offers additional exposition in a second replay. Logs and diaries will contain slightly different text in the second run-through than they do in the first one, so the player will have to play through the game more than once to get ever detail regarding the plot. As these are small--though interesting--details, it's not necessary to play through the game twice to understand the main story.   Localized ChangesTrace Memory differs slightly depending on the region. The North American version portrayed Ashley as being more skeptical in comparison to the somewhat more accepting Ashley of the Japanese and European version. The American edition also contained more humor than the other regions' editions, possibly to lighten the game's generally dark story. Finally, the European and Japanese releases stated that Ashley is British-Japanese, while the American edition states that she is Japanese-American.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1159">Hotel Dusk: Room 215</game><game id="21807">Unsolved Crimes</game><game id="20145">Sprung</game><game id="19409">Phoenix Wright: Ace Attorney</game><game id="7894">Phoenix Wright: Ace Attorney - Trials and Tribulations</game><game id="13351">Phoenix Wright: Ace Attorney - Justice For All</game><game id="9365">Touch Detective</game><game id="8676">Touch Detective 2 1/2</game><game id="12998">Sherlock Holmes: Consulting Detective</game><game id="23075">Ikatan: Ikamono Tantei</game><game id="20529">Insecticide</game><game id="22532">Flower, Sun and Rain</game><game id="23145">Silver Jiken</game><game id="22330">Jake Hunter: Detective Chronicles</game><game id="21052">Time Hollow</game><game id="24237">Again</game><game id="17544">Broken Sword: The Shadow of the Templars</game><game id="25340">Tokyo Twilight Busters</game><game id="3970">Myst</game><game id="21411">Theresia</game><game id="21578">Ace Attorney Investigations: Miles Edgeworth</game><game id="24071">So Blonde</game><game id="28435">Agatha Christie: The ABC Murders</game><game id="29533">Last Window: The Secret of Cape West</game><game id="32606">Gyakuten Kenji 2</game><game id="28028">Ghost Trick: Phantom Detective</game><game id="35482">Mystery Quest: Curse of the Ancient Spirits</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2478707-box_tm.png</image></root>