<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18</id><name>Metal Slug X: Super Vehicle - 001</name><description>OverviewOne of the first bosses in the game.Metal Slug X is a revised version of Metal Slug 2, released in March, 1999 for the Neo Geo MVS. Metal Slug X was developed by SNK Playmore and Nazca Corporation, and published by SNK Playmore. Not only did it fix slowdown problems present in Metal Slug 2, but it increased the difficulty. New weapons and items were also added, such as the Iron Lizard and the Drop Shot. In addition to these changes, enemy placement and bosses were also changed. Metal Slug X was later ported to the Neo Geo AES (in 1999) and the PlayStation (in 2001).New WeaponsEnemy Chaser shoots rockets that track down enemiesIron Lizard shoots a bomb that travels on ground and explodes when it hits an enemyDrop Shot shoots iron balls that bounce on the ground until it hits an enemySuper Grenade fires a rocket that travels forward and causes a large explosion.Critical ReceptionGame Informer gave the review scores of 6 and 6 out of ten. Jay Fitzlof wrote, "Metal Slug X has plenty of action, with enemies jumping at you from all sides, plenty of weapons and vehicles to try out, and lots of hidden items to discover. The only problem is, assumming you use the unlimited continues, you''ll finish the game in about half and hour... it feels like Metal Slug X would work better on a handheld. In fact I know it would since I thoroughly enjoyed the two Metal Slugs on the Neo Geo Pocket Color only a year ago".</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2190">Gunstar Heroes</game><game id="17452">Alien Hominid</game><game id="692">Contra Advance: The Alien Wars EX</game><game id="4350">Contra</game><game id="4237">Contra 4</game><game id="7227">Abuse</game><game id="7475">Liero Xtreme</game><game id="17008">Alien Soldier</game><game id="3016">Contra III: The Alien Wars</game><game id="11684">Contra: Shattered Soldier</game><game id="11973">Gunstar Super Heroes</game><game id="1421">Ranger X</game><game id="10077">Super C</game><game id="17939">Konami Collector's Series: Castlevania &amp; Contra</game><game id="21340">Time Slip</game><game id="24997">Eduardo the Samurai Toaster</game><game id="29479">GunForce II</game><game id="13388">Shock Troopers</game><game id="840">Metal Slug 2: Super Vehicle - 001/II</game><game id="39627">Intrusion 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1614/969857-metal_slug_x_ng_us.jpg</image></root>