<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18026</id><name>Rock 'n Roll Racing</name><description>OverviewA screenshot of the Super Nintendo version of the gameRock 'N Roll Racing came out in the US on June 4th, 1993 for the Super NES and was developed by Silicon  Synapse (now known as Blizzard). The game puts four racers up against each other racing around tracks on various planets. Up to two players can play together while the rest is AI controlled. The game is viewed from an isometric view.Although the title indicates that this is mainly a racing game, the emphasis on attacking the competitors is huge. There are many different weapons in the game (such as rockets and mines). Although players re-spawn rather quickly, the cash bonus that is being handed out to an attacker is always a good reason to fire that last rocket. From the start, the tracks are littered with various things such as oil slicks, mines, and health  money packs. Sometimes, depending on the planet the race is being hosted on, various obstacles like lava or snow, can appear.Commentary is given by Loudmouth Larry (Voiced by Larry "Supermouth" Huffman) who makes various comments throughout the race on the appropriate moments such as:The stage is set, the green flag drops!Let the carnage begin!Rip is about to blow!Hawk should avoid mines!Olaf lights him up!Holy Toledo!Olaf Unleashes Hot Fury!Between the races, players can spend their hard earned money on outfitting their cars with more weapon charges, better parts (like improved bumpers or tires), or just buy a new car. The races always last for four laps and a nice cash and point reward is split between first, second, and third place. Players need to win a certain amount of points to be allowed to enter the next division on that planet, which features tougher opponents and a higher point requirement to advance. Completing the second division will allow players to proceed to a new planet.RacersCyberhawkIvanzypherJake BadlandsKatarina LyonsSnake SandersTarquinnOlaf the Stout from The Lost Vikings is a secret character with great stats and is accessible either through entering a secret code on the character select screen or through password manipulation. Another (possibly unfinished) secret character with higher than normal stats is also available through password manipulation, but there is no sound files or name attached to the character. Some people have nicknamed the character "The Phantom" due to his/her pure black character portrait.MusicThere are five rock and roll classics that play in all their MIDI-no-vocals glory. They are:"Paranoid" by Black Sabbath"The Peter Gunn Theme" by Henry Mancini"Highway Star" by Deep Purple"Born to Be Wild" by Steppenwolf"Bad to the Bone" by George Thorogood and the DestroyersA sixth track was added to the Genesis port and is exclusive to that version:"Radar Love" by Golden EarringCritical ReceptionWhen the SNES version was released Electronic Gaming Monthly's Mike Weigand gave the review score of 8 out of ten writing, "...Music makes all the difference with this smash-and-destroy racing game. The two-player mode is a real blast to play! The several tracks and alien planets on which you can race add the variety the game needed to stand out".</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1374">R.C. Pro-Am</game><game id="9842">Biker Mice From Mars</game><game id="20608">PixelJunk Racers</game><game id="11631">Galaxy 5000</game><game id="6017">Super Cars</game><game id="9017">Mad Max</game><game id="22786">BS Excitebike Bun Bun Mario Stadium</game><game id="8251">Road Rash</game><game id="22883">Red Asphalt</game><game id="786">Destruction Derby</game><game id="11718">Skunny Kart</game><game id="12544">Wacky Wheels</game><game id="18044">Death Rally</game><game id="15242">F-Zero</game><game id="4969">Big Red Racing</game><game id="1166">Badlands</game><game id="28127">Scrap Metal</game><game id="7458">Racing Destruction Set</game><game id="33354">Harms Way</game><game id="28073">Rush Rush Rally Racing</game><game id="28346">Mini Yonku Let's &amp; Go!!: Power WGP 2</game><game id="15610">High Way Star</game><game id="21285">Rollcage Stage II</game><game id="3125">Mickey's Racing Adventure</game><game id="1659">Jupiter's Masterdrive</game><game id="4481">Antz Racing</game><game id="12364">Battle Cars</game><game id="36378">Armada F/X Racers</game><game id="37579">Zen-Nippon GT Senshuken</game><game id="28272">The King of Rally</game><game id="16228">Uniracers</game><game id="2140">Micro Machines</game><game id="42604">Mini Motor Racing EVO</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2371401-genesis_rocknrollracing.jpg</image></root>