<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1804</id><name>Gothic II</name><description>Plot  NPC Interaction      Gothic 2 is the second game in the                    Gothic series, in which you take control of the same                    Nameless Hero from the first game. You wake up in    Xardas' tower after the events of the first game; the necromancer has saved you from near certain death after battling the   Sleeper. He tells you about the army of evil that is  threatening  the island of  Khorinis and that you must obtain the Eye of Inos, an artifact that the paladins posses, that has the power to put an end to that threat. As the Nameless Hero you have to find a way into the city , where he has to work his way into the ranks of one of the three factions (The Militia based in the city of Khorinis, The Fire Mages in a nearby monastery or the Mercenaries) by completing quests for them in order to earn the right to speak with Lord Hagen , the commander of the paladins in Khorinis, to inform him about the dragons that are threatening the city.   Although to get the Eye of Inos from the paladins you are tasked to bring proof of the existence of an army led by dragons.To do that you have to travel to the castle in the mining colony that is under siege by orcs and obtain a letter from the paladin commander there that proves the existance of dragons. After that Lord Hagen will grand you permission to take the Eye but you will discover that it has been stolen from the monatery by an agent of the evil god and it has been damaged to a point that it has lost its powers, so you must find a way to repair it. After it is restored you must go back to the mining colony and kill the four dragons that are leading the army.  But that is does not end the threat to the island of Khorinis as you have to put an end to the one behind the dragons leading the army of evil. To do that you have to gather a crew of trusted friends and sail with  the paladin ship, that is anchored in the city harbor, to the lair of powerfull undead dragon that was controling all other dragons and kill you putting an end to the threat. The game ends with a cut scene showing your ship sailing the sea to the mainland where Gothic 3 takes place.GameplayAttributes  Stats!     The gameplay in Gothic centers around the ability to choose your path, both in skills and character development, and                    who you side with in the story. The game is open-ended with many sidequests and things to do to gain favor with different people and groups. Depending on which side of the story you join, you get different equipment, weapons, and locations to call home. The combat is controlled with the mouse and keyboard. You lock onto an enemy, and by pressing directions in certain orders you unleash combos on your enemy with your melee weapon. As in the first game in the series, melee combat is centered on the player's skill, which frustrated many players and delighted others. Only the mastering of both attack and defence techniques would yield truly strong fighting characters.  Spells are chosen from a menu and cast with a mouse click. Ranged weapons work in a similar way to magic. All dialogue in the game is                    spoken, with the option to have subtitles or not. Each character has a unique voice, and most characters can be engaged in conversation, with conversation trees.                    Unimportant characters will have one or several lines to say to you if you try to talk to them.  Original System requirements Windows 98/ME/2000/XPPentium III 700MHz Processor (with Video Hardware TL)Pentium III 1.2GHz Processor (without Video Hardware TL)256MB RAM (512MB Recommended)2.2GB Hard Disk Space4X CD-ROM Drive32MB DirectX compatible Video Card (64MB Recommended)DirectX compatible Sound CardDirectX 8.1b Digital DistributionGothic 2 - Gold Edition was re-released by  Good Old Games for $4.99 (at normal non/sales price) with compatability  support for Windows XP, Vista, and 7 for both 32 and 64-bit. The "Gold Edition" contains the Gothic 2 main game and its expansion Night of the Raven. It can also be purchased on Steam for $10 (normal non/sales price). </description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14759">Two Worlds</game><game id="17367">The Elder Scrolls III: Morrowind</game><game id="21473">Blade of Darkness</game><game id="7870">Dark Earth</game><game id="10473">The Witcher</game><game id="14565">Dungeon Lords</game><game id="23081">Risen</game><game id="19907">Heretic II</game><game id="4254">Crusaders of Might and Magic</game><game id="20504">Fallout 3</game><game id="10784">Arx Fatalis</game><game id="642">The Elder Scrolls Adventures: Redguard</game><game id="1567">Die by the Sword</game><game id="23139">Divinity II: Ego Draconis</game><game id="20238">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion</game><game id="28178">The Witcher 2: Assassins of Kings</game><game id="33149">Risen 2: Dark Waters</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15693/618097-561413_front_1_.jpg</image></root>