<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18086</id><name>Rumble Roses</name><description>OverviewRumble Roses is a wrestling game produced by Yukes, developer of the popular WWE Smackdown series, and released for the Playstation 2 in 2004. The game features a roster of fictional female combatants and has faced criticism over perceived misogyny concerning its portrayal of women, drawing comparisons with the Dead or Alive and Soul Calibur series.The game is notable for its use of the Vow System whereby each of the ten characters can appear under two guises: Face (Good) or Heel (Bad). By selecting challenges before matches you can earn points that adjust a slider allowing you to unlock each character's alternate persona. However only one persona is selectable at one time leaving the character count at 10, plus one unlockable.The game was given a sequel in the form of Rumble Roses XX, released for the Xbox 360 in 2006.GamplayWrestling in Rumble Roses works like old school Aki wrestling games. While grappling you have to press a direction and the grapple button again to preform a specific moves. Some moves are just regular damage dealers but others will put your opponent in another position, so straight into a pin, or whip your opponent into the ropes. These rules also apply to when an opponent is on the ground or on the turnbuckle. Punching is a simple press of the square button, you can chain punches into combos as well. To reverse a strike you must press R1 and Square at the same time as the punch is about to land.Every opponent has separate meters for their legs, arms, head, and body. When you are putting your opponent into a submission these bars will decrease depending on what move you are putting pressure on. Once that body parts meter reaches 0 your opponent will tap out. To get out of a submission quickly you must mash the face buttons as fast as you can.Special MovesHumiliation MovesHumiliation Moves are special attacks that will put your opponent in a humiliating position. These are in the forms of submissions and you must have at least 1 special bar saved up in order to use it. Throughout the match certain moves that you do to your opponent will fill up your heart meter. Once you have a full heart meter and 1 special stock saved you will be able to preform a humiliation move. Humiliation moves can be reversed by pressing R1 and L2 at the same time before the attack hits, and you must have a special stock saved.Lethal/Killer MovesLethal moves are specials that you can preform on standing opponents while you have 1 special stock. These are devastating attack the will greatly injure your opponent. On the other hand Killer Moves and specials that can be preformed while a character is in a certain state. The Killer Move for each character is their signature move. These moves are more powerful and flash than Lethal Moves.Match TypesExhibition ModeThis mode is just your regular match mode. Pick a character and get to fighting. You may also set special rules for the match to make it as brutal or tame as you wish.Mud MatchA mud match.Mud Match is the exact same as exhibition mode but you are fighting in a ring of mud. As you fight the characters will become covered in mud. Sometimes when you do a submission move it will look like you're drowning the other person but that doesn't affect the game in any way. Also the ring is located by the beach so all the characters are limited to their swimsuit outfits.Title MatchTo partake in a title match you must first have a title eligible character. You will either be fighting for of defending the Rose of Roses championship belt. You do not get to pick the title holder to beat.Story ModeEach character has a story mode to do through, each with their own unique story. After some cut scenes and matches you will eventually meet up with the final boss, Lady X. Her first form is just a regular person but then she turns into a robot. Do you think you can beat a robot in a wrestling match?CharactersReiko Hinomoto / Rowdy ReikoReiko making a cameo in MGS3Default Type: FaceCountry: JapanAge: 19Height:5'7" Weight: Top SecretMeasurements: Bust: 34" Waist: 26" Hips: 33"Specialty: Angel Dive, Sunrise SuplexVoiced By: Bianca AllenDixie Clemets / Sgt. ClemetsDefault Type: FaceCountry: U.S.A.Age: 26Height: 5'11" Weight: 143 lbsMeasurements: Bust: 36" Waist: 28" Hips: 35"Specialty: Dixie Buster, Double Bridge HoldVoiced By: Lilia SilvaBloody Shadow / JudgmentDefault Type: HeelCountry: JapanAge: UnknownHeight: 5'6" Weight: 103 lbsMeasurements: UnknownSpecialty: Hades Drop, 6 RealmsVoiced By: Lenne HarditMiss Spencer / Mistress SpencerFan art of "Mistress" SpencerDefault Type: FaceCountry: CanadaAge: 28Height: 5'9" Weight: 103 lbsMeasurements: Bust: 37" Waist: 26" Hips: 36"Specialty: Tricolour Suplex, Teacher's PetVoiced By: Rachel WalzerAisha / ShowbizDefault Type: FaceCountry: U.S.A.Age: 24Height: 5'11" Weight: 138 lbsMeasurements: Bust: 36" Waist: 28" Hips: 35"Specialty: NHB Combo, ShowdownVoiced By: Pari BanyanCandy Cane / BeckyDefault Type: HeelCountry: CanadaAge: 18Height: 5'7" Weight: 119 lbsMeasurements: Bust: 36" Waist: 26" Hips: 35"Specialty: Astro Scissors, School DriverVoiced By: Peggy WooMakoto Aihara / The BBDFan art of Candy CaneDefault Type: FaceCountry: JapanAge: 18Height: 5'5" Weight: 114 lbsMeasurements: UnknownSpecialty: Tornado Form, Knee FlexorVoiced By: Lisle WilkersonAigle / Killer KhanDefault Type: FaceCountry: MongoliaAge: 18Height: 5'5" Weight: 119 lbsMeasurements: UnknownSpecialty: White Doe, Lobster LockVoiced By: Terry OsadaEvil Rose / Noble RoseHand drawn version of Evil Rose.Default Type: HeelCountry: UnknownAge: UnknownHeight: 5'10" Weight: 149 lbsMeasurements: UnknownSpecialty: Bloody Rose, VampiressaVoiced By: Xanthe SmithAnesthesia / Dr. CutterDefault Type: FaceCountry: UnknownAge: UnknownHeight: 5'9" Weight: UnknownMeasurements: Bust: 36" Waist: 27" Hips: 35"Specialty: Morgue, Flying StretcherVoiced By: Donna Burke</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="10">Wrestling</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21479">Dead or Alive Xtreme Beach Volleyball</game><game id="7792">Dead or Alive 4</game><game id="16202">Dead or Alive: Xtreme 2</game><game id="12592">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2008</game><game id="20678">Soulcalibur IV</game><game id="10158">M.U.S.C.L.E.</game><game id="6319">Strip Fighter II</game><game id="30637">Lucha Libre AAA Heroes del Ring</game><game id="31212">Fighting Angels</game><game id="37482">Girl Fight</game><game id="39930">Wrestling Universe: Fire Pro Joshi Dome Choujo Taisen: Zenjo vs JWP</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2525237-box_rr.png</image></root>