<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18110</id><name>Guild Wars: Eye of the North</name><description>OverviewGuild Wars: Eye of the North (referred to as "GWEN") is the first true expansion to the Guild Wars franchise, requiring any of the three previous campaigns (  Prophecies,   Factions or   Nightfall) to play. For information on core  Guild Wars gameplay and character classes, go   here. Story The New EnemyPlayers return to Tyria, the continent where the original Guild Wars took place, to find that a new and destructive enemy has awoken and begun traversing the surface.  To defeat this new menacing enemy, the Player must venture throughout the new previously unexplored areas of Tyria to find the aid of other races.  The army-of-one Norn, the intelligent Asura, the soliders of Vanguard and even the rival forces of the Charr will have to be considered.  Victory or Defeat, these actions will ultimately determine the fate of the future... Features Hall of Monuments  40 new Armor sets and stand-alone Armor pieces   100 new Skills  50 new PvE-only Skills  10 new Heroes  The "Hall of Monuments" where you will be able to obtain exclusive content in the upcoming Guild Wars 2 based on your achievements in the previous Guild Wars games  4 new Regions: Charr Homeland, Depths of Tyria, Far Shiverpeaks and the Tarnished Coast   Notes  There is no Collectors Edition   This game bridges content from previous Guild Wars games to Guild Wars 2  GW:EN could be an allusion to Gwen, a girl from Guild Wars: Prophecies.  A Pre-Release Pack was available, offering 3 exclusive weapons: Glacial Blade, Hourglass Staff and Darksteel Bow along with a 10-hour/14-day trial key to the previous Guild Wars games.     This game does not feature: new Professions, new Guild Halls nor any additional Character Slots.  A rule used to be that you had to be level 20 to access this expansion because of the high leveled monsters. But at the holidays they took that cap away.     SoundtrackThe music from Guild Wars Eye of the North was composed by   Jeremy Soule.The Guild Wars: Eye of the North Soundtrack1. Beyond the Northern Wall 2:562. Overture from Eye of the North 2:203. Ballad of Ice and Snow 4:394. Gwen's Theme 1:135. The Scrying Pool 1:046. Under the Dark Span (Asura Theme) 1:257. Through the Asura Gates 3:098. The Doomlore Flame 4:499. March Through Norrhart 2:0110. Livia's Heart 1:3111. Kathandrax 2:0012. Memories of Ascalon 1:0513. Claiming Balthazar's Favor    1:0714. Horns of Gunnar's Hold 5:0115. Tome of Rubicon (Dwarf Theme) 1:3416. Darkness Beneath 3:1717. Lyssa's Dance 1:0218. The Shattering of the World (Destroyer Theme) 1:5619. Ogden Stonehealer 1:0320. Darkrime Delves 2:0221. Iron Footfalls 2:3722. Victory Banners 1:2423. A Storm Is Coming - Battle Depths 2:4024. Song of the Shiverpeaks (Norn Theme) 2:0725. Central Transfer Chamber 1:0526. The Primordial 1:5227. Live by the Sword (Svanir's Saga) 1:5928. The Great Bear's Roar 2:1629. Rise of the Destroyers 3:1030. Vanguard's Stand     1:1831. All Hail King Jalis 1:0832. The Sun Beyond the Peaks 1:0833. Legacy of the Gods 1:28System RequirementsMinimum:Microsoft Windows Vista/XP/2000/ME/98Intel Pentium III 1 Ghz or equivalent512 MB RAMDVD-ROM Drive3 GB Available HDD SpaceATI Radeon 8500 or NVIDIA GeForce 3 Series Video Card with 64 MB of RAM16-bit Sound CardInternet ConnectionKeyboard and mouseDirectX 8Recommended:Microsoft Windows Vista/XP/2000Intel Pentium 4 2.0 Ghz or equivalent1 GB of RAMDVD-ROM Drive4 GB Available HDD SpaceATI Radeon 9600 or NVIDIA GeForce FX 5700 Series Video Card or above16-bit Sound CardInternet ConnectionKeyboard and mouseDirectX 9</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21223">Guild Wars 2</game><game id="22063">Perfect World</game><game id="22997">The Lord of the Rings Online: Mines of Moria</game><game id="23411">Runescape Classic</game><game id="9705">Lineage II: The Chaotic Chronicle</game><game id="23193">Perfect World International</game><game id="6204">EverQuest: The Shadows of Luclin</game><game id="545">Asheron's Call</game><game id="29355">Tera</game><game id="26847">Final Fantasy XIV Online: A Realm Reborn</game><game id="27896">World of Warcraft: Cataclysm</game><game id="33394">The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8169/1248930-11806.jpg</image></root>