<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18394</id><name>Carmageddon</name><description>OverviewCarmageddon is the first in a series of graphically violent driving-oriented video games produced by Stainless Games and published by Interplay and SCI. It was inspired by the 1975 cult classic movie Death Race 2000.Carmageddon's Front cover art workCarmageddon started out as "3D Destruction Derby", a banger-racing (stock-car) sim prototyped by Stainless. This was signed by SCi in 1995, but the banger-racing angle was quickly dropped and for a while the game was going to use the Mad Max license. This also fell through, and was replaced by the Death Race 2020 license, as a sequel to the original film that was being planned at that time. This is what introduced the running-over of pedestrians into the game.When this license also fell through, SCi and Stainless took the decision to carry on with the game anyway without a license. The name "Carmageddon" was thought up, and development carried with the designers allowed unusually free rein with the content of the game, this could be why the game became so bloody.CarsCarmageddon (PC)NamePhotoDriverInformationAnnihilator"For Vlad, it's not the winning, it's the taking apart that counts. This car's speed is unbeatable...Just don't try to corner it."VladOpponent number 29Short name VladRace number 20Top speed 420 mphKerb weight 1.0 tons0 - 60 mph in 2.2 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 1Stealworthy YesNetwork availability AllThe Bear"With a Ukraine-manufactured monster truck and vodka-manufactured hangover, Ivan's black mood makes him a dangerous competitor."Ivan the BastardOpponent number 15Short name IvanRace number 28Top speed 150 mphKerb weight 1.4 tons0 - 60 mph in 9.4 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 3Stealworthy YesNetwork availability AllCleaver"She's the self-crowned queen of the race scene, and her chariot is aptly equipped with wheel mounted blades."Val HellaOpponent number 28Short name ValRace number 21Top speed 220 mphKerb weight 1.3 tons0 - 60 mph in 5.5 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 2Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverMerciless Cullwing"She's mean, lean and she's got a killing machine. Wanda's lust is primarily for blood - yours."Wanda LustOpponent number 17Short name WandaRace number 69Top speed 210 mphKerb weight 1.1 tons0 - 60 mph in 6.7 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 2Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverCaddy Fat Cat"King of cool, the laidback lord of lowriders is, however, inclined to turn into a slavering lunatic if the cat gets it's paintwork scratched."Otis P JivefunkOpponent number 19Short name OtisRace number 9Top speed 180 mphKerb weight 1.8 tons0 - 60 mph in 7.7 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 4Stealworthy YesNetwork availability AllCountslash"He takes great pleasure in causing pain, and seems curiously keen to receive punishment in return. Who are you to argue?"KutterOpponent number 16Short name KutterRace number 7Top speed 280 mphKerb weight 1.1 tons0 - 60 mph in 4.1 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 1Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverElectric Blue"Stella’s got herself wired to the battery of her super sleek racer, she says it gives her an extra buzz... enough said."Stella StunnaOpponent number 24Short name StellaRace number 17Top speed 230 mphKerb weight 1.0 tons0 - 60 mph in 4.5 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 4Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverFearari F666"She's behind the wheel of one of the fastest cars on the circuit, And she'll take your breath away... for good."Madam ScarlettOpponent number 26Short name ScarlettRace number 11Top speed 270 mphKerb weight 1.1 tons0 - 60 mph in 4.1 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 1Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverFraud Broko"He seems a friendly kind of guy, but appearances can deceive, and the way he guns that 4x4 along you’d think he was on the run!"OK StimpsonOpponent number 18Short name OKRace number 8Top speed 170 mphKerb weight 1.9 tons0 - 60 mph in 8.9 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 3Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverGrunge Buster"He’s a hi-tech hi-spec speed freak who knows no fear. The Grungebuster is super-quick but super-twitchy, so Mech needs nerves of steel."Mech ManiacOpponent number 6Short name MechRace number 16Top speed 220 mphKerb weight 0.4 tons0 - 60 mph in 3.3 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 3Stealworthy YesNetwork availability AllHevy Impaler"Survivalist Ed wants to rid the world of Commies. But to him, everyone’s a pinko. His armoured station wagon’s a moving roadblock."Ed HunterOpponent number 9Short name HunterRace number 25Top speed 160 mphKerb weight 2.3 tons0 - 60 mph in 9.6 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 4Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverKing Merc"Teutonic terror Heinz has a supercharged superheavy sport coupe with go anywhere tank tracks... Don’t get caught in his path!"Heinz FaustOpponent number 10Short name HeinzRace number 4Top speed 160 mphKerb weight 3.0 tons0 - 60 mph in 7.6 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 5Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverLumberer"Harry will try to win at any cost, so he can lavish the winnings on his pet pig, Squealer. Best stay out of his way if you can."Halfwit HarryOpponent number 14Short name HarryRace number 26Top speed 170 mphKerb weight 1.9 tons0 - 60 mph in 9.4 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 5Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverLeadpumper"The mad ex-FBI agent will hunt you down with extreme prejudice if you dare to hit his heavyweight sedan."Agent OrangeOpponent number 2Short name OrangeRace number 12Top speed 150 mphKerb weight 1.7 tons0 - 60 mph in 7.6 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 4Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverRazorbill"Road-going gang of psychos, muggers  murderers who drive a variety of armored off-roaders."Auto ScumOpponent number 21Short name ScumRace number Skull / Piranha symbol (-3)Top speed 210 mphKerb weight 0.6 tons0 - 60 mph in 4.5 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 3Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverRed Eagle"Mad maximum impact fruitcake with a hydraulic neck and no crumple zones in his brain. Drives the Eagle, a car designed for rammin’ and slammin’."Max DamageOpponent number 0Short name MaxRace number ♂ (100)Top speed 200 mphKerb weight 1.1 tons0 - 60 mph in 4.01 secondsStrength (1 - 5) -1Stealworthy YesNetwork availability eagleRoad Bratt"Road-going gang of psychos, muggers  murderers who drive a variety of armored off-roaders."Auto ScumOpponent number 5Short name ScumRace number Skull / (-1)Top speed 220 mphKerb weight 0.6 tons0 - 60 mph in 3.6 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 2Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverPinkpulveriser"Halfwit Harry’s sister is as devoted to Squealer the pet pig as he is (and has the same single figure IQ)."Burly ShirleyOpponent number 23Short name ShirleyRace number 27Top speed 170 mphKerb weight 2.0 tons0 - 60 mph in 9.9 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 5Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverThe Plow"Big truck, big guy...no heart. Don’s a disgruntled municipal worker and he drives a customized earthmover; hard, fast  heavy."Don DumpsterOpponent number 7Short name DumpyRace number 24Top speed 100 mphKerb weight 2.6 tons0 - 60 mph in 14.8 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 5Stealworthy YesNetwork availability AllProject X"Hammy thinks he’s a superhero, but actually he’s just another nut. He drives his own twisted creation with demented zeal."HammerheadOpponent number 13Short name HammerRace number 6Top speed 210 mphKerb weight 2.0 tons0 - 60 mph in 6.6 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 5Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverSquad CarThe CopsOpponent number 3Short name CopRace number 500Top speed UnknownKerb weight Unknown0 - 60 mph in UnknownStrength (1 - 5) -1Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverStreet Eater"Road-going gang of psychos, muggers  murderers who drive a variety of armored off-roaders."Auto ScumOpponent number 8Short name ScumRace number Skull / (-2)Top speed 180 mphKerb weight 0.9 tons0 - 60 mph in 4.5 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 3Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverStiffshifter"The funeral funsters will deliver you straight to hell in style with their nitrous snorting hot-rod hearse."Brothers GrimmOpponent number 12Short name GrimmRace number 5Top speed 230 mphKerb weight 1.2 tons0 - 60 mph in 4.2 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 2Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverSuppressorThe Cops Special ForcesOpponent number 4Short name CopRace number 501Top speed UnknownKerb weight Unknown0 - 60 mph in UnknownStrength (1 - 5) -1Stealworthy YesNetwork availability NeverTanka"Crazed chem. worker Firestorm stole a company tanker and took to racing. The rig is big and the driver is brutal."FirestormOpponent number 11Short name FireRace number 99Top speed 100 mphKerb weight 2.1 tons0 - 60 mph in 8.9 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 4Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverTashita Coupe"Ed blew a fuse and went psycho. The crazed android stole a prototype prized racing coupe in order to cause high-speed carnage."Ed 101Opponent number 27Short name Ed 101Race number 10Top speed 280 mphKerb weight 0.9 tons0 - 60 mph in 4.2 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 1Stealworthy YesNetwork availability AllThe Twister"This wacky guy favours the ‘supercar/monster truck/light aircraft/mole machine’ mode of transport. He’s about as insane as they come."Screwie LewieOpponent number 22Short name ScrewieRace number 12Top speed 220 mphKerb weight 1.7 tons0 - 60 mph in 6.4 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 3Stealworthy YesNetwork availability AllTowmeister"Like a rabid scrapyard dog, he’ll come baying for your blood and your engine oil. If he catches you... it’s hamburger time."Psycho PitbullOpponent number 20Short name PitbullRace number 22Top speed 160 mphKerb weight 2.0 tons0 - 60 mph in 9.1 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 4Stealworthy YesNetwork availability allVolkswerker"Stig knows that what his car lacks in speed, it more than makes up for in strength and durability. And he thinks it’s beautiful."Stig O'SoreOpponent number 25Short name StigRace number 33Top speed 150 mphKerb weight 1.0 tons0 - 60 mph in 11.6 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 2Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverYellow Hawk"Psychopathic stunner. Born in a body bag and raised in a morgue. Drives the Hawk - faster than Max’s Eagle but not as strong. Best suited to impacts with flesh rather than steel."Die AnnaOpponent number 1Short name AnnaRace number ♀ (101)Top speed 250 mphKerb weight 0.8 tons0 - 60 mph in 3.15 secondsStrength (1 - 5) -1Stealworthy YesNetwork availability hawkCarmageddon Splat Pack (Only added cars)NamePhotoDriverInformationAnnihilator II"For Vlad, it's not the winning, it's the taking apart that counts. This car's speed is unbeatable... Just don't try to corner it."VladOpponent number 29Short name VladRace number 20Top speed 420 mphKerb weight 1.0 tons0 - 60 mph in 2.2 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 1Stealworthy NoNetwork availability AllBlood Mobile"Psycho surgeon Sawbones is almost always the first to arrive on the scene of an accident. Usually he caused it."SawbonesOpponent number 13Short name SawbonesRace number 911Top speed 100 mphKerb weight 2.0 tons0 - 60 mph in 9.6 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 5Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverBugutti"Lady Bug-Smyth-Gery looks rather too sophisticated to be involved in this madness. You won't think that when she steams up your rear!"Lady BugOpponent number 21Short name Lady BRace number 88Top speed 170 mphKerb weight 1.5 tons0 - 60 mph in 4.5 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 3Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverCarrerasaur"Stig traded up from his old Volkswerker, to the latest model from the Porky Mo.Co. The Carrerasaurus is hard, fast and drop dead gorgeous..."Stig O'SoreOpponent number 25Short name StigRace number 91Top speed 180 mphKerb weight 1.3 tons0 - 60 mph in 3.6 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 2Stealworthy YesNetwork availability NeverDe Gory'Un"Since major brain surgery Mikey hasn't been himself. That's because he was given a murdering lunatic's brain due to an administrative error."Metal MikeyOpponent number 9Short name MikeyRace number 89Top speed 150 mphKerb weight 1.6 tons0 - 60 mph in 6.6 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 4Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverDoozer"Techno-crazy Su split from the Auto-Scumto indulge in some solo road-rampage. The Doozer packs a helluva punch, so watch out!"Su BorgOpponent number 8Short name Su BorgRace number 72Top speed 120 mphKerb weight 1.9 tons0 - 60 mph in 4.5 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 3Stealworthy YesNetwork availability AllEagle IIMax DamageOpponent number 0Short name MaxRace number ♂ (100)Top speed UnknownKerb weight Unknown0 - 60 mph in UnknownStrength (1 - 5) -1Stealworthy YesNetwork availability eagleFearari F999"He's behind the wheel of one of the fastest cars on the circuit... and one of the softest. Catch him in a head-on and send him into orbit!"AshteroidOpponent number 26Short name AshRace number 51Top speed 270 mphKerb weight 1.1 tons0 - 60 mph in 2.1 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 1Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverHawk IIDie AnnaOpponent number 1Short name AnnaRace number ♀ (101)Top speed UnknownKerb weight Unknown0 - 60 mph in UnknownStrength (1 - 5) -1Stealworthy YesNetwork availability hawkKiller Coop"It's chirpy Cockney Mike O′Kane, in the Killer Coop. Keep yer ′Mince Pies′ peeled, unless you want him to take that lance and ′Elephant and Castle′."Mike O'KaneOpponent number 16Short name KaneRace number 64Top speed 100 mphKerb weight 0.7 tons0 - 60 mph in 7.2 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 1Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverKiller Kitty"She's mean, lean and she's got a killing machine. This pussy has a lust for blood - yours."Pussy LaGoreOpponent number 17Short name PussyRace number 83Top speed 220 mphKerb weight 1.2 tons0 - 60 mph in 5.7 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 2Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverMonster Masher"Herman likes to have a good view of the road ahead, and hates getting caught in a traffic jam. Lucky for him he drives the Masher!"Herman MonsterOpponent number 18Short name HermanRace number 155Top speed 130 mphKerb weight 2.9 tons0 - 60 mph in 5.9 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 3Stealworthy YesNetwork availability NeverPiecemaker"Hippy nightmare chick Moon Child was raised in a Vegan-Pagan commune. A strict diet of pulses and free love sent her mad, and she Rebelled. Big time."Moon ChildOpponent number 5Short name MoonRace number 80Top speed 100 mphKerb weight 0.6 tons0 - 60 mph in 7.0 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 2Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverRamraider"The big man with the face paint is keen to introduce you to his pet ram. It's attached to a big stick and heading for ya at speed now!"Big DaddyOpponent number 11Short name Big D.Race number 8Top speed 100 mphKerb weight 1.9 tons0 - 60 mph in 8.9 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 4Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverRig O'Mortis"The mother of all truckers, this little old lady has more than a zimmer frame to defend herself with. It's pensioner payback time..."Mother TruckerOpponent number 210Short name Ma TruckRace number 74Top speed 160 mphKerb weight 5.0 tons0 - 60 mph in 7.6 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 5Stealworthy YesNetwork availability AllRoadhog"Distant cousin of Halfwit Harry and Burly Shirley, Helga has a pet Warthog - the love of her life."Helga ShweinOpponent number 23Short name HelgaRace number 436Top speed 130 mphKerb weight 3.0 tons0 - 60 mph in 3.9 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 5Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverThe Sled"Ex-squeeze of Agent Orange, Synthea's taken to the streets in order to avenge the agent's untimely demise."SintheaOpponent number 2Short name SintheaRace number 73Top speed 150 mphKerb weight 1.7 tons0 - 60 mph in 7.6 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 4Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverStiletto"Super slippery race ace Alfonso likes to look good, and his likes his car to look good too. Scratch that bright yellow paint at your peril!"Alfonso SpaghettiOpponent number 28Short name AlfonsoRace number 71Top speed 170 mphKerb weight 1.3 tons0 - 60 mph in 5.5 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 2Stealworthy NoNetwork availability NeverStodge Barger"This dynamic duo look like they're trapped in a timewarp. Flares, afros and a muscle car... it's the 'In-a-state '76' pair!"Carkey  ClutchOpponent number 14Short name CCRace number 76Top speed 180 mphKerb weight 1.7 tons0 - 60 mph in 4.4 secondsStrength (1 - 5) 5Stealworthy YesNetwork availability NeverGameplayAt the start the player must choose between two drivers: Max Damage and Die Anna. Each has their own cars which are essentially the same, but with minor differences. Die Anna's is yellow and is slightly faster, while the red one is Max's, which is slightly tougher than that of the yellow version.In Carmageddon, the player races a vehicle against a number of other computer controlled competitors in various settings, including cities, mines and industrial areas. The player has a certain amount of time to complete each race, but more time may be gained by collecting bonuses, damaging the competitors' cars or by running over pedestrians.The player running over a pedestrianRaces are completed by either completing the course as one would in a normal racing game, "wasting" (wrecking) all other race cars, or running over all pedestrians on the level before anyone else.The game was notable for its realistic and ground-breaking physics and for its in-game movie making features. It was also one of the earliest examples of a sandbox 3D driving games, and may have influenced later games including Driver and the GTA series.Each of the games levels had a pun in the title. For instance, "I Scream in the Sun".Game Boy Color VersionSplattered a zombieThe Game Boy Color version of the game is played from a top down perspective rather than the traditional style. Instead of pedestrians, Carmageddon for the Game Boy Color has the player instead running down zombies. When the player runs over a zombie they explode leaving behind a green mark on the road.ControversyIn many countries including Germany and, for a short time the United Kingdom, the game contained zombies or robots with green blood instead of people, as running over the undead was considered more acceptable by their respective ratings boards. In the UK, SCi wanted to gain publicity for the game by submitting it to the BBFC to get an 18 rating, even though this was not necessary as the game contained no video footage. This backfired when the BBFC refused to certify the game unless all blood and gore was removed. After 10 months of appealing, the BBFC certified the original version.TechnologyCarmageddon was developed using the Blazing Renderer (BRender) from Argonaut software. BRender was a 3D graphics engine that could be used to develop games for the Windows, MS-DOS and the Sony PlayStation.Notable features of the BRender engineZ-buffer and scanline rendererHierarchical, linked objectsGoraud shadingMultiple cameras and light sourcesCollision detectionSprite scaling and deformation effects32-bit libraries for Watcom and MS Visual CSupport for hardware accelerators such as GLiNTSoundtrackThe game's soundtrack was a mix of 3 instrumental tracks from Fear Factory and 4 from Lee Groves. Fear Factory provided heavy metal while the Lee Groves songs were ambient tracks.The CD-ROM on the game had Track 1 as the game data, while Tracks 2-8 provided the game's soundtrack while playing randomly through the game or playing in a CD player:Track Listing:1) Data Track2) Fear Factory - Demanufacture (instrumental)3) Lee Groves - Industrial4) Lee Groves - Coastal5) Fear Factory - Zero Signal (instrumental) [intro cutscene song]6) Lee Groves - Desert7) Lee Groves - Winter Wonderland8) Fear Factory - Body Hammer (instrumental)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18864">Road Rash 64</game><game id="786">Destruction Derby</game><game id="13177">FlatOut</game><game id="9017">Mad Max</game><game id="12364">Battle Cars</game><game id="23527">Hardware 2</game><game id="16728">Powerslide</game><game id="12283">Quarantine</game><game id="25512">Clutch</game><game id="29265">Zombie Driver</game><game id="18044">Death Rally</game><game id="25641">D.I.P.R.I.P. Warm Up</game><game id="12359">Midtown Madness 3</game><game id="32627">Blood Drive</game><game id="5279">Interstate '76</game><game id="37415">Roadkill</game><game id="37266">Smash 'n' Survive</game><game id="4543">Quarantine II: Road Warrior</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/15/155745/2250492-1281953641_00.jpg</image></root>