<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18457</id><name>Advance Wars: Days of Ruin</name><description>OverviewAdvance Wars: Days of Ruin is the second Advance Wars game for the Nintendo DS. Developed by Intelligent Systems, it is a turn-based strategy game that takes place in a fictional world separate from previous Nintendo Wars titles and features a darker storyline in which the countries of Rubinelle and Lazuria are fighting for control over what is left of their world after meteor strikes decimate the global population. Captain Brenner's 12th Batallion, or 'Brenner's Wolves,' are caught in the middle of a corrupt tug-of-war for power. The main character, Will, who is only a young cadet, must make sense of this chaos and figure out what kind of person he really is.The game features a different art style and a brand new, darker story with new factions:Rubinelle 12th Battalion (Red)Lazurian Army (Blue)New Rubinelle Army (Yellow)Intelligent Defense Systems (Black)As with the previous versions, Advance Wars: Days of Ruin comes packed with multiplayer features. You can play with up to 4 people on only one Nintendo DS console, or you can use the wireless connection to play with others around you. You have full control over the rules of war and how battle will take place. The game also comes with a map editor; this dramatically increases the lasting appeal of this game with the multiplayer experience. The game also features full online play through the Nintendo Wi-Fi Connection service.Release HistoryAdvance Wars: Days of Ruin, while developed by Intelligent Systems like previous installments in the franchise, was first released in North America and Europe in 2008. While a Japanese release was also intended, complications pushed the release back until it was eventually cancelled. However, in 2013, Nintendo announced that Days of Ruin will be a special Club Nintendo reward for Japanese 3DS owners. Available as a digital download, it will mark both the first time that Days of Ruin will be available for the Japanese market and also be the first Nintendo DS game made available for the 3DS in a digital capacity.StoryMuch of humanity has been wiped out after a meteor strike destroys most of the cities on earth. To make things worse, the dust from the meteors' impact is also blocking the sun, making life for the survivors even more difficult. It is in this backdrop that the story begins.The game starts with a young survivor named Will escaping his destroyed academy only to be attacked by a group of rogue soldiers lead by a man called The Beast. Things look bleak for Will when the 12th Battalion of the Rubinelle army, led by Captain Brenner and Lin, show up and rescue him. Will learns that they are called Brenner's Wolves, a group that is still loyal to Rubinelle and is looking for as many survivors as they can. Will is inspired by the ideals and bravery of Captain Brenner and looks up to him as a mentor. As they are looking for survivors while fighting off The Beast's army of ex-soldiers they discover a young girl in the rubble who has forgotten everything about her past. She instantly bonds with Will, who names her Isabella, and joins the group where they learn that there is more to her than they had realized. This is because she somehow has detailed knowledge about military secrets and information even though she doesn't know how or where it is comes from. The first part of the story ends with the defeat The Beast and relief for the villages that he was terrorizing.A year goes by when Brenner's Wolves meet up with a new faction called the New Rubinelle Army lead by General Greyfield. They learn that they are currently fighting the Lazurian aermy, who were enemies of Rubinelle before the meteor strike occurred. Brenner is suprised that they are still fighting given the conditions but is told that the Lazurians attacked them first and so they are defending themselves. Thus, being the dutiful soldier that he is, Brenner helps the New Rubinelle Army by helping them defeat the the Lazurian Leader, Forysthe. Brenner had made a deal with Forysthe that if he surrendered, his soldiers would not be harmed but Greyfield would have none of this. He shot Forysthe even after he had surrendered and ordered all the Lazurians to be executed. Brenner was disgusted by the lack of honour that Greyfield possessed, and in wanting to keep his world to Forysthe he decides to help the Lazurian captives escape. He stays behind to buy them time while they escape. Greyfield, angry at Brenner's betrayal and wanting to make an example of him, uses a weapon that was given to him by a mysterious man named Caulder. Caulder claimed that the weapon would vapourize everything in a certain range and in his anger Greyfield orders it used on the area in which they think Brenner is hiding. The weapons causes the not only the death of Brenner but even Greyfield's own soldiers that were ordered to go after Brenner and kill him. With Brenner's death, Will is made the commander and they decide to flee from Greyfield's army since they cannot match them. It is at this time there is word of a virus that is spreading across the land called the Creeper, which turns people into plants and kills them. After a series of many battles, they finally face off against Greyfield. The Rubinelle Army under Lin's command defeats Greyfield and she executes him in cold blood to avenge Brenner's death.MultiplayerAdvance Wars: Days of Ruin comes packed with multiplayer features. You can play with up to 4 people on just one Nintendo DS console, or you can use the wireless connection to play with others around you. This is also the first Advance Wars game to make use of Wi-Fi, and you can play games or download other users' maps over the internet through the Nintendo Wi-Fi Connection service. You can play either with random opponents close to your rank, or take part in a friend match via the use of friend codes. During random matches the maps are chosen randomly but with a friend all the options are available, including voice chat, through the DS integrated microphone. There is a map editor that allows full multiplayer maps to be made and can hold up to 50 custom maps.Medals and RecordsThe game keeps records of almost everything the player does, from the number of direct attacks, indirect attacks, moves, how many of each unit are made or destroyed; the list goes on. For achieving certain milestones in these categories of stats, the game will award you medals. They have no value except that they show up on your records section.Changes From Previous GamesDays of Ruin is a large step away from other Advance Wars games. Previous games all had the same characters that were very cartoony and light spirited. DoR gets rid of the whole previous universe and instead creates a dark, post-apocalyptic world. It adds several new units, but also gets rid of several units from the old games. The biggest change gameplay-wise is that CO's are no longer just bonuses and have super powers. They now have to be placed inside units and only give bonuses to units within a specific range. This makes them much less overpowering than in the previous games. The whole idea behind these changes was that the previous universe and gameplay were getting too out of hand, and they wanted to take a step back and make the gameplay more balanced.A considerable amount of features from Dual Strike have been removed:Dual screen matchesPurchasing new maps and optionsCO tag powers and super powersSurvival and Combat modesA hard difficulty setting for the campaign once the main game has been completedCO's no longer gain experience points to level upThe new units introduced into the battlefield are:Bike: Infantry units with high movement range. The purpose of these is to capture properties around the map faster in open terrain than any other infantry unit.Duster: Air units that can fire on both ground and air units with a machine gun. These are more economic Fighters.Gunboat: Ships that can fire on other naval units. They can also carry one infantry or mech unit at a time. After each successful attack or counter attack, they have to resupply since these units only carry one ammo at a time.Flare: In a fog of war match, these units can fire flares to uncover some of the hidden terrain. These are also good attackers against infantry units while having decent armor.Anti-Tank: These units are powerful against tanks and are the only indirect attackers that can counter-attack if the opposing enemy is within close range.Seaplane: Air units that can attack every type of unit on the battlefield. These have to be produced on carriers.These classic units have been changed from previous games:Infantry: The cost of Infantry was increased to 1500 funds, from 1000. This was to lessen the effectiveness of "infantry spamming," an unbalanced tactic in earlier games.Mech: The cost of Mechs was reduced to 2500 funds, from 3000. This change was to make Mechs easier to deploy, to make them a more effective counter to mechanical units.Bomber: The cost of Bombers was reduced to 20000 funds, from 22000. This was to make Bombers more affordable and attractive, as they were underused units in earlier games.Battleship: The most exciting changes to old units was to the Battleship. Not only was its cost reduced to 25000 funds, from 28000 (although all naval units had reduced costs too), but it also gained the ability to move and fire in the same turn; it is the only long-rage unit in the game with this ability.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21244">Super Robot Wars W</game><game id="1520">Fire Emblem</game><game id="14285">Age of Empires: The Age of Kings</game><game id="9659">Panzer Tactics DS</game><game id="22722">Disgaea DS</game><game id="24220">Fire Emblem: Shadow Dragon</game><game id="23547">Anno 1701: Dawn of Discovery</game><game id="21428">Warlords DS</game><game id="25514">Mecho Wars</game><game id="5239">Battles of Prince of Persia</game><game id="17276">Rebelstar: Tactical Command</game><game id="26476">Dragon Quest Wars</game><game id="19532">Zone of the Enders: The Fist of Mars</game><game id="24252">Hero's Saga Laevatein Tactics</game><game id="27680">Luminous Arc 3</game><game id="27921">Mage Knight: Destiny's Soldier</game><game id="3368">Summon Night 2</game><game id="18876">Summon Night</game><game id="22933">Bleach: The 3rd Phantom</game><game id="28180">Dawn of Heroes</game><game id="27338">Spectral Force Genesis</game><game id="20557">Operation Darkness</game><game id="35846">Memoir '44 Online</game><game id="35865">Battle Dex</game><game id="39483">Great Little War Game</game><game id="31495">Uniwar</game><game id="36394">Fire Emblem: Awakening</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1841699-box_awarsdor.png</image></root>