<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18461</id><name>Gangsters: Organized Crime</name><description>OverviewIn the game Gangsters you are in control of a growing crime syndicate. The objective of the game is maintaining and expanding your territories, influence, economy and manpower, in order to either go straight, be elected as mayor of Chicago or be the last man standing – by either outliving or eradicating all the other crime organizations. These objectives are reached through extorting business owners, moonshining, illegal gambling, creative lawyers and accountants, and other activities generally frowned upon by the 1930’s police officials.Your gangsters have different skills suiting them for different missions, and several aids can be purchased for them to carry out their missions, ranging from knives to tommyguns and vehicles to ease their daily illegal shenanigans.All this while the police and the FBI is hot on your tail. Luckily, that can be solved by bribery and threats, and carrying out the aforementioned threats. To ease the public’s opinion of you, you can always donate some money to your local church, or just bribe it, take your pick.GameplayThe game switches between being turn-based and real time. In the turn-based part of the game you select your gangsters actions, which is at the beginning of the week. After you have planned your actions, your actions are carried out in the following week in real time.In the working week, you have the option to change orders and actions if it does not play out the way intended, or if your men suddenly have too much time on their hands.PC RequirementsWindows 95/98 or Me;Pentium 133 (Min.);4x CD-ROM drive;16MB RAM (Min.);2MB DirectX 6 compatible SVGA Graphics card;DirectX 6 compatible sound card;350MB free hard drive space;Mouse  Keyboard.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14101">Republic: The Revolution</game><game id="306">Gangsters 2</game><game id="6315">Constructor</game><game id="13710">Chaos Overlords</game><game id="37676">Omerta: City of Gangsters</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/16944/772084-gangsters_game.jpg</image></root>