<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18484</id><name>Killer Instinct</name><description>OverviewKiller Instinct is a fighting game developed by Rare. It was published by Midway on the arcade, and by Nintendo for the Super Nintendo Entertainment System and Game Boy. The game is well-known for the large amount of combos that a player can dole out.Nintendo originally planned Killer Instinct for early release on the Nintendo 64. Killer Instinct and Cruis'n USA were actually among the first Nintendo 64 games announced. When manufacturing issues delayed the system's release, Nintendo debuted Killer Instinct on the SNES instead in late 1995.GameplayFulgore vs. OrchidKiller Instinct uses a basic 2D fighting layout, where players face each other from opposite sides of an arena and move primarily left and right, attacking from standing, jumping, or crouching positions. Its gameplay expanded on other 1990s fighters in important ways, including match format, multi-part combo system, and through the introduction of "breakers."Prior to Killer Instinct, most fighting games (including Street Fighter and Mortal Kombat) used a strict "best of three" round system. Both players started with the same amount of energy, fought until one side ran out, and restarted the fight. Killer Instinct replaced this with a 2-stage life bar where matches reset when a player loses half their life, but the "leader" keeps their current amount. (This makes "perfect" rounds more challenging, as victors must drain both bars without taking damage.)Killer Instinct's basic joystick and button controls closely resemble Street Fighter. Its six attacks use three strengths of punches and kicks, weak, medium, and strong. Players block by holding the stick away from their opponent (and not attacking). Most special moves use quarter-circle, half-circle, or back-forward joystick movements followed by an attack. Character-specific special moves also serve as openers to a combo chain.Combo Attack SystemKiller Instinct features a multi-stage attack system whose structure encouraged mastery of both basic attacks (as openers) and "continuers," moves that build into long, visually impressive combos.Combo opener: special move or jumping attack that leaves opponent "open" to combo (each character has several openers)Continuer: performed after successful opener and adds 2-4 hits; joystick + button move that's typically one "up" from the opener (weak to medium, medium to strong, strong to weak)Linker: joystick + button move that adds 2-3 hits (exact move is character-specific)Finisher: joystick + button move after linker and adds 3-4 hits (knocks opponent to ground and ends combo)An unbroken, 4-part combo scores about a dozen hits, depending on the characters and moves used. (Note that the player only performs 4 distinct button presses.) Killer Instinct's combo system created longer attacks with fewer actions than most other fighting games, a system designers created to encourage deeper knowledge of each character and limit the success of "button mashing."On defense, players can break attacker combos with a character-specific stick + button move at the start of any continuer, linker, or finisher (see Combo Breakers). Breakers end the combo's "flow" and knock the attacker back. (The match announcer says one of this game's distinctive lines, "C-C-C-COMBO BREAKER," on successful breakers.) Players must have energy in their life bar to break a combo; attackers who drain the final amount with an opener can continue their combo uninterrupted.Finishing OpponentsOnce attackers deplete an opponent's life bar, they can finish opponents a la Mortal Kombat with a violent "No Mercy" move or Humiliation, which forces the opponent to dance. (Humiliations require the victor to still be on their first life bar.)Attackers can also trigger an "Ultra Combo" (a knockout sequence consisting of 20+ hits) by inputting a character-specific move during their combo chain when an opponent's life bar flashes red (under 10% left). The game automates ultra finishing sequences, requiring no further button pressing; arcade players often removed their hands from the machine to accentuate their win and watch the combo play out.SoundtrackKiller Cuts was a soundtrack album that was released and packaged with the video game Killer Instinct on the Super Nintendo in 1995. Many of the tracks were arranged and included the character's theme songs in addition to the songs featured in the fighting stages. Although exclusive to the pack-in with the game, it could be bought via the Nintendo Power magazine catalog.Killer Cuts front coverK.I. Feeling ( B. Orchid) - 3:45The Way U Move - 3:58Controlling Transmission ( Glacius) - 3:56Oh Yeah ( Chief Thunder) - 3:23It's a Jungle - 3:04Do It Now! ( Jago) - 3:55Full-bore ( Fulgore) - 3:16The Instinct (Theme) - 4:53Yo Check This Out! ( T.J. Combo) - 1:36Freeze - 2:11Trailblazer ( Cinder) - 1:50Tooth  Claw ( Sabrewulf) - 3:09Ya Ha Haa ( Spinal) - 3:00Rumble ( Riptor) - 2:11The Extreme ( Eyedol) - 2:33Track 16 through 29 are blank and are only a few seconds in length. Track 30 is the song used in the Humiliation finishers/dances.AnnouncerThe game was also famous for the announcer, who announced the combos after their completion as well as the iconic Combo Breaker. There were 11 types of combos, each with a distinctive name and delivery.3 hits: Triple combo4 hits: Super combo5 hits: Hyper combo6 hits: Brutal combo7 hits: Master combo8 hits: Awesome combo9 hits: Blaster combo10 hits: Monster combo11 hits: King combo12 hits: Killer comboFinishing combo: Ultra combo (20+ hits)StoryA mega-corporation (mega-corporations have completely replaced governments in this future) named Ultratech organizes a tournament consisting of fights to the death. Ultratech has entered some of their experimental prototypes in the contest, as well as other entrants. Most of the other entrants have some sort of motivation to joining the contest, usually due to something that Ultratech has promised them (for example, in Sabrewulf's case, Ultratech promises to heal him of his lycantrophy) Ultratech discovers a way to unleash an ancient warrior named Eyedol and enters him into the tournament.CharactersCharacter DescriptionImageFulgoreFulgore is a cyborg who is the result of a cybernetic project at Ultratech. He, like other Ultratech experiments, was entered into the tournament as a test. If it was able to win, it would be produced in mass quantities. However, it was defeated by Jago.CinderCinder is a criminal who was promised a release from jail if he was tested on with chemical weapons. As a result, his body has been turned into fire. If he is able to defeat Glacius in the tournament, then he will return to his original form.GlaciusAn alien who was captured by Ultratech, Glacius was promised freedom if he wins the tournament. His body is composed of ice and water, making him able to shapeshift.JagoJago is a Tibetan monk who follows the Tiger Spirit (who later ends up to be Gargos). Jago is on the search for enlightenment, and wants to defeat Ultratech (he believes it is his destiny).RiptorA velociraptor that has been genetically engineered by Ultratech. It is a prototype; it is a test to determine its abilities.SabrewulfA normal human who has been transformed into a werewolf, and is promised the cure if he wins the tournament. He is likely a reference to Rare's game Sabre Wulf.SpinalSpinal is a skeleton who, through cell regeneration, is made living. He is the remains of an ancient warrior, and unlike many others participating in the tournament, fights for enjoyment. His brain could not regenerate in the process, so this is probably the reason why.TJ ComboTJ Combo is a boxer who was kicked out of his position of champion after it was discovered that his arms had cybernetic implants that improved his boxing ability. Ultratech promises him back his championship if he wins the contest.Chief ThunderChief Thunder is a Native American who enters the tournament to find out what happened to his long lost brother Eagle. It is later revealed that his long lost brother is actually Spinal.B. OrchidA spy for an unknown entity, she is a secretary for Ultratech. Jago and B. Orchid are essentially the protagonists of the game.EyedolThe final boss of the game, Eyedol is a two-headed, ancient mystical warlord who was trapped in a dimensional prison in the distant past. Ultratech released him to be the final combatant in the tournament. It is shown in Killer Instinct 2 that the person Eyedol was trapped in combat with was Gargos, the final boss of that game.</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="243">Street Fighter II: The World Warrior</game><game id="1434">Mortal Kombat 3</game><game id="2178">Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3</game><game id="16349">Justice League Task Force</game><game id="21941">Dragon Ball Z: Super Butoden</game><game id="21943">Dragon Ball Z: Super Butoden 2</game><game id="21944">Dragon Ball Z: Super Butoden 3</game><game id="15743">Mortal Kombat</game><game id="8161">Street Fighter II Turbo: Hyper Fighting</game><game id="1328">Street Fighter Alpha 3</game><game id="11156">X-Men vs. Street Fighter</game><game id="8680">Street Fighter Alpha 3 MAX</game><game id="1251">Super Street Fighter II Turbo</game><game id="2612">Marvel vs. Capcom 2: New Age of Heroes</game><game id="12125">Capcom Fighting Evolution</game><game id="9369">Namco x Capcom</game><game id="5640">Capcom vs. SNK: Millennium Fight 2000 Pro</game><game id="8492">Capcom vs. SNK 2: Mark of the Millennium</game><game id="9309">Marvel Super Heroes Vs. Street Fighter</game><game id="14078">Primal Rage</game><game id="21997">Dragon Ball Z: Shin Butoden</game><game id="7751">Art of Fighting Anthology</game><game id="1940">Pray for Death</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="11065">Shaman King: Power of Spirit</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="489">ClayFighter</game><game id="16199">ClayFighter: Tournament Edition</game><game id="3185">ClayFighter 63 1/3</game><game id="18019">ClayFighter: Sculptor's Cut</game><game id="22362">Street Fighter II': Hyper Fighting</game><game id="21699">The King of Fighters '98 Ultimate Match</game><game id="21519">The King of Fighters XII</game><game id="2374">The King of Fighters Collection: The Orochi Saga</game><game id="20463">SNK Arcade Classics V.1</game><game id="5030">The King of Fighters XI</game><game id="4289">The King of Fighters 2006</game><game id="16200">The King of Fighters: Neowave</game><game id="18037">The King of Fighters '94 Re-bout</game><game id="19799">The King of Fighters EX2: Howling Blood</game><game id="18240">The King of Fighters 2003</game><game id="449">The King of Fighters 2001</game><game id="7581">The King of Fighters 2002: Challenge to Ultimate Battle</game><game id="11976">The King of Fighters EX: Neo Blood</game><game id="15728">The King of Fighters 2000</game><game id="13352">The King of Fighters: Evolution</game><game id="6452">The King of Fighters: Dream Match 1999</game><game id="6872">King of Fighters R-2</game><game id="17540">King of Fighters R-1</game><game id="10621">The King of Fighters '98: The Slugfest</game><game id="4124">The King of Fighters '97</game><game id="8146">The King of Fighters '96</game><game id="18568">The King of Fighters '95</game><game id="4249">The King of Fighters '94</game><game id="13875">Plasma Sword: Nightmare of Bilstein</game><game id="16444">Eternal Champions</game><game id="10476">War Gods</game><game id="18423">ClayFighter 2: Judgement Clay</game><game id="21277">Ultimate Mortal Kombat</game><game id="4896">Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Tournament Fighters</game><game id="14880">Tuff E Nuff</game><game id="42896">Killer Instinct</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2363896-snes_killerinstinct_3.jpg</image></root>