<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1849</id><name>Barbie's Ocean Discovery</name><description>Barbie takes the role a a marine biologist seeking to rescue the ocean life and its creatures. During her humanitarian expedition, Barbie will uncover buried treasure, (Barbie does not work for free). As the story goes along, the player will be acquainted with Sandy the dolphin. Gameplay consists of Barbie swimming alongside her dolphin friend Sandy and finding doorways. In order to access these doorways the player will need to complete certain quests and activities. Once completed, the player can explore a city of crystals, the corral reef, and a sunken ship. Various mini-games are present in the these areas as well.Production Credits Company: Mattel InteractiveVP of Development: Amy BoylanDirector of Operations: Timothy WatersExecutive Producer: Jesyca DurchinProducer: Erica BobrowTechnical Producer: Keith KirbyAssociate Producer: Vance HuskinsBusiness  Legal Affairs Senior Manager: Cynthia Berry MeyerSenior Contract Analyst: Karen KellyLocalization Coordinator: David GordonPC Product Producer: Isabel WoodwardPC Developer: Gorilla SystemsSenior Executive Assistant: Toni DeBerryAdministrative Assistant: Dawn GottulaVice President: Pamela Kelly BoogarSr. Product Manager: Lauren BerzinsAssistant Product Manager: Shaun Rowan, Michelle MachroneInternational Director: Cathy TischeInternational Coordinator: Pat MooreLegal and Business Affairs Director: Nicole Van DamVendor Operations Project Manager: Cheryl HagerPackaging Manager: Heino MoellerMedia Planning: Kimberly CurrySenior Technician: Dom DeLuciaLead Tester: Craig ForrestTester: John Bloodworth III, Roger Hu, Oscar Lopez, Brett Rommel, Terri Sieker, Ray YamauchiCompany 2: Realtime AssociatesProgrammers: Stephen Cuong Nguyen, Steve Ettinger, Doug Schilling, Michael DorganArt  Animation: Connie Goldman, Laura Raines Smith, Phil KnowlesAudio: Greg TurnerProducer: Steve EttingerJapanese Localization: Shippy Ohka ~ Scott Alan Marriott, All Game Guide</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="445">Endless Ocean</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/10/103881/1891019-od.jpg</image></root>