<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18509</id><name>King's Field: The Ancient City</name><description>StorySynopsis:An ancient idol bearing a curse, responsible for the utter destruction of a civilization of ages past, has resurfaced once again and is threatening the kingdom of man. Someone has to deliver the idol to the Ancient City to break the curse, but it is a dangerous and perilous journey. The city is full of monsters, but even they are afraid of the unspeakable evil that has returned.In more detail*:"At the west of the barren land, at the foot of the high peaks within the Morraddi mountains, lies a land found in the shadows of a dark and misty forest.Once, this land was referred to as the Holy Land and it was blessed by the grace of fertile soil and a giving Sun.There came a time long ago when the skies in this area became perpetually obscured by a shroud of dark clouds. The Holy Land was deserted. The people of this Land, known as the Forest Folk, built an underground city and they have lived there ever since.Knowledge of this once great land has faded amongst the remaining kingdoms. Even now, only a few of the wise men remember tales of the Holy Land. The place is now referred to as simply "The Land of Disaster."One day, a ceremonial idol representing the highest ideal of peace was presented to the King of the small country Heladin. Moved by the gesture of the gift, the King, Lucien IV, decreed that the idol would have a permanent home in his throne room.At once, the kingdom of Heladin began a quickening spiral of decay. The King's sages were asked if they could discover the source of the curse that had befallen the kingdom.The sages uncovered the legend of an "Idol of Sorrow" that was said to originate from the mysterious Forest Folk from the Land of Disaster. The sages attributed the fall of the Land of Disaster to the cursed Idol of Sorrow and believe that the idol received by King Lucien was indeed this item. The people of Heladin organized an expedition to return the wretched idol to the Land of Disaster in the hopes of breaking its curse. With the highest hopes, the team of adventurers, led by the famous Sword Master, set out on their expedition and, tragically, were never seen again.On a storm-swept night, Prince Devian of Azalin was visited by a strange wanderer. The person presented the Prince with an idol and informed him to, "Return this idol to the Land of Disaster so that other kingdoms do not succumb to its wicked curse."Because of his friendship with the Sword Master, Prince Devian knew of the expedition sent from Heladin to return a cursed idol but had not heard the outcome. Feeling the burden of the quest to rid the land of the wicked idol, the prince set out for the Land of Disaster and the Ancient City that lies within its dark forest. Prince Devian was also aware of the dangers inherent in traveling to a realm that has been reclaimed by nature's fury."*Taken off of the game's official homepageGameplayThe game is played in a first-person perspective, and you use melee attacks and spells to repel the evil lurking about. You find new items to use along the journey, but equipment deteriorates over time and lose effectivity, therefore one has to seek out someone who can repair them from time to time. To be able to use magic, you have to find Magic Crystals spread across the game, and via them you get access to different spells across different elemental forces (Earth, Wind, Water, Fire, Dark, and Light). Also scattered across the map are different obstructions, blocking off areas, that you only can get past once your character has had an increase in power. Therefore there is some open-ended backtracking of sorts taking place over the game. Something new to the King's Field series was introduced in this fourth installment; the ability to swin underwater, to explore underwater caves and such. You've got an air-gauge to keep track of underwater, once that is depleted - you drown.The King's Field series of games are famous for their steep difficulty level. You have to tread very carefully and use tactics to be able to prevail.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="28444">King's Field II</game><game id="619">King's Field</game><game id="34919">Shadow Tower Abyss</game><game id="18651">Eternal Ring</game><game id="32697">Dark Souls</game><game id="24057">Demon's Souls</game><game id="22892">Shadow Tower</game><game id="40798">Dark Souls II</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2243855-box_kftac.png</image></root>