<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18522</id><name>Onimusha: Blade Warriors</name><description>Overview Melee multipayer battles set in the Onimusha universe.  The game focuses  in fights which include more than two characters and  can support up to  4 characters. in vs. mode players may choose from  characters and fight  in levels which have random item drops at times.  Players may also use  orbs to unleash powers to bring in new abilities to  the fight. Players  may also customize their characters and use  different weapons and can  disarm opponents mid-battle. The story mode  follows loosely the events  in the Onimusha series and has some boss  battles and levels where you  simply kill a bunch of enemies to go from cutschene to cutscene. Gameplay The  is like Nintendo's Super Smash Bros. series - two to four  characters  fight on a 2D plane. But the game does have a bit of depth  to the  fighting, such as "Critical Attack/Counterattack," combos, melee  items,  and "Charged Attacks."  Critical attack/critical counterattack is a  technique that's use in the   core Onimusha games. Critical attack is  when a enemy  about to strike   the player, the player has to strike back  at the last possible moment  -  thus triggering the critical attack  feature - a very powerful  attack  will occur and will perform heavy  damage on the opponent. And  critical  counterattack is similar to critical  attack but done  differently, when  the enemy is about to attack the  player must block  the attack at the  last possible moment and fellow it  up with an attack  of his or her own.   The game also has charged  attacks. Three different levels of power and   three different versions of  the charged attack is available to the   player. The charged attack is done  by holding the square button, the   longer the button is hold, the more  powerful the attack will be -the   maximum of the charged is three. After  the charged is good and ready   for the player, he or she can perform one  of three attacks - one being a   projectile attack that's done by pressing  left or right on the D-pad,   the second if a multi-hit attack that's  done by keeping the D-pad in   neutral position and then releasing the  square button, and the third  is  a powerful stab that's done by holding  the R1 button after  releasing  the square button.     There is also a deep customizable weapon system in which you equip  different weapons to different warriors. Characters  Kotaro       Nobunaga KojiroJujudormah-RahSamanosuke  JubeiMarcellusMusashiKeijiroEkeiGogandantessJujudormahOyuGargant   KaedeGruntThree Eyes/Musaid/GramusaidZombie   Warrior/JaidMagoichi      MegaMan.EXE      Zero (Mega Man)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12411">Soulcalibur</game><game id="7750">Tenchu: Return from Darkness</game><game id="19998">Tenchu: Dark Secret</game><game id="17743">Super Smash Bros. Melee</game><game id="20588">Super Smash Bros. Brawl</game><game id="20500">Dragon Ball Z: Burst Limit</game><game id="21195">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai Tenkaichi 3</game><game id="21520">Viewtiful Joe: Red Hot Rumble</game><game id="547">Dream Mix TV World Fighters</game><game id="21870">The Outfoxies</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2115770-box_onimushabw.png</image></root>