<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18547</id><name>EverQuest II</name><description>OverviewEverQuest II returns to the land of Norrath after one of the two moons, Luclin, that circles the planet explodes causing mass destruction for the world's cities and civilizations. The events within this game, which take place in the Age of Destiny, are roughly 500 years after the Age of Turmoil (EverQuest).EverQuest II makes many improvements from the original EverQuest game. EverQuest II has a much more elaborate implementation of adventuring and tradeskill. Whereas before, characters would have no set path for adventuring, EverQuest II includes a tiered system of leveling. Starting players can choose one of four cities (only two were available at launch) to start their adventure. After following sets of quests, they are pushed towards other areas of the world which are more suited for the character's level.Originally, EverQuest II was designed to have you choose your archetype which would lead to a choice of class and from there a choice of subclass. This was later done away with for choosing the subclass at the start of character creation. Although, that was changed the class chart still remains the same with showing which subclass can do what in a common group. The levels you gain from killing creatures and finishing classes would be known as the adventuring level.EverQuest II has nineteen races to choose from including humans, elves, and more unique ones such as frogloks and sarnaks. Each race has their own traits that allow them to specialize in classes that match the lore of the race.The trading classes are also divided like the adventuring classes where you go from one archetype to a class to a subclass. The difference is that you can only gain levels by making tradeskill items or doing tradeskill related quests.ClassesThere are 4 main "archetypes" in EQ2: fighter, scout, priest, and mage. Within each archetype, players can choose their "class" and "sub-class." Following the initial launch of the game, the structure was simplified such that when creating a character in EQ2 today, a player immediately chooses their "sub-class." While any race can be any class they must be aligned with a certain city to be able to use a certain class. In Game Update 52, many classes that were formerly restricted to good or evil cities had this restriction removed. Only four classes currently have good or evil only subclasses.FighterFighter ClassesThe primary task for the Fighter archetype in most groups is tanking. Each member of this group gets a taunt skill which receives upgrades based on their class.Guardian - Can be used by characters of either alignment.Berserker - Can be used by characters of either alignment.Paladin - A holy warrior that goes into battle with magic and melee skills at its disposal. The Paladin can be seen casting healing spells and magic based spells against it's enemy. The Paladin wears heavy armor and can carrier swords, hammers, axes, spears, maces and shields into battle. Only accessible to good aligned characters.Shadowknight - The Shadowknight is a hybrid class that uses both magic and melee skills in battle. The Shadowknight is able to utilize debuffs, life taps and summon undead pets when in battle. The Shadowknight commonly wears heavy armor and is seen going to battle carrying swords, hammers, maces, axes, spears, and shields. At higher levels the Shadowknight is able to receive special abilities such as Feign Death and Harm Touch. The Shadowknights spells usually have a disease effect to them. Only accessible to evil aligned characters.Monk: The Monk is a hand to hand combatant that wears light armor. While the Monk does not have mitigation as well as other fighters it's avoidance is higher than most. The Monk uses few weapons.Bruiser: The Bruiser is a hand to hand combatant that wears light armor. While the Bruiser does not have mitigation as well as other fighters it's avoidance is higher than most.ScoutScout ClassesThe primary task for the Scout archetype in most groups is causing damage per second. Every member of this group gets a stealth ability and a run speed buff.Troubador: The Troubador is a hybrid class that sings songs that buff its group and has attacks that can weaken its foe.Dirge: The Dirge is a hybrid class that is able to sing songs and use melee attacks to weaken it's enemy.Ranger: The Ranger is a master of bows and arrows. Most of the Ranger's abilities center around his ability to use stealth, melee weapons and bows.Assassin: The Assassin uses attacks based on stealth and position to it's enemy. This class is similar to the Rogue class.Swashbuckler: The Swashbuckler attacks are based on his position to the enemy. The Swashbuckler also has many stun effects that it can use on it's enemy. This class is similar to the Rogue class. Only accessible to goodly aligned characters.Brigand: The Brigand's attacks are based on position, trickery and stealth. While the majority of high damage attacks are based on where the Brigand is in relation to his target, there are several attacks that allow the Brigand to also debuff his enemy. Some of the debuffs the Brigand can use weaken the enemies defense and ability to do damage. Some iconic abilities the Brigand has over other classes at this time are Ruse which will make the Brigand appear to be dead but in turn cause massive damage to the enemy, as well the Brigand has an ability called Band of Thieves that creates 3 pets to assist the Brigand in fighting. This class is similar to the Rogue class. Only accessible to evil aligned characters.Beastlord: The Beastlord was introduced in Age of Discovery, and is the pet-using Scout class. Beastlords can tame pets, called warders, and use them in combat. Warders come in offensive, defensive, and exotic categories, and level up with the Beastlord. They also gain special AA points which may be spent to improve the warder.PriestPriest ClassesThe primary task for the Priest archetype in most groups is healing. Each member of this group receives a resurrection spell that they can use on an ally.Fury: The Fury is a healing class in EverQuest 2 that uses health regeneration spells on their allies. The Fury can only wear leather or cloth armor, and wield maces, staves, shields or scimitars. The Fury can also cast many direct damage spells. The Fury can also use teleportation spells to quickly move around the world.Warden: The Warden is a healing class in EverQuest 2 that uses health regeneration spells on their allies. The Warden can only wear leather or cloth armor, and wield maces, staves, shields, or scimitars. The Warden can also cast many direct damage spells. The Warden can also use teleportation spells to quickly move around the world.Templar:Inquisitor:Mystic: The Mystic is a healing class in EverQuest 2 that uses health wards to protect their allies. The health ward system works by the Mystic casting a ward on it's ally and the ward absorbs a set amount of damage from the enemy. The Mystic can wear chainmail, leather and cloth and can use maces, staves, spears and shields. Only accessible to good aligned characters.Defiler: The Defiler is a healing class in EverQuest 2 that uses health wards to protect their allies. The health ward system works by the Defiler casting a ward on it's ally and the ward absorbs a set amount of damage from the enemy. The Defiler can wear chainmail, leather and cloth and can use maces, staves, spears and shields. The Defiler is also known to cast many debuffs and DoTs in combat. The Defiler can also summon feathers which allow his allies to resurrect the Defiler if it dies in combat. Only accessible to evil aligned characters.MageThe primary task for the Mage archetype in most groups is causing Damage per Second. Each member of this group uses spells to attack enemies.Wizard: The Wizard is considered a master of Ice and Fire magics. They are most known for casting direct damage spells. These casters specialize in single target damage.Warlock: The Warlock is considered a master of Disease and Poison magics. They are most known for their focus on area of effect damage, which focuses on damaging multiple enemies at once.Illusionist: Illusionists are one of the two enchanter classes which specialize in crowd control via stuns and mesmerizing foes while also having a bevy of support buffs which enhance group members' capabilities. Illusionists specialize further in buffing mage classes.Coercer: Coercers are one of the two enchanter classes which specialize in crowd control via stuns and mesmerizing foes while also having a bevy of support buffs which enhance group members' capabilities. Coercers further specialize in buffing melee based classes such as fighters and scouts.Conjurer: Conjurers are pet based casters which summon elemental-type pets to assist them in battle. Only accessible to good aligned characters.Necromancer: The Necromancer is a pet class that normally creates a dead spirit to assist in fighting. Only accessible to evil aligned characters.RacesArasaiThe malicious children of hate and dark magic, Arasai honor their goddess through defiling and torturing the inferior races across Norrath, taking pure pleasure in their cruelty. The Arasai are blindingly loyal to the Teir'Dal Queen Cristanos, whom they worship as a goddess, and are powerful allies to the dark elves.Best suited as scouts and mages.Arasai are an evil race, they can start in Neriak or Gorowyn.BarbariansBarbarians are the very tall and muscular cousin to the human. Although they share many of the physical traits with humans, they far outpower them in sheer strength. Rising nearly 7 feet in height, barbarians traditionally wear their hair long due to the cold climate of the far north that their tribes are accustomed to. This served the purpose of assisting them in surviving the harsh winters of Halas within the frozen tundra of Everfrost.Barbarians are best suited as either fighters or priests.Barbarians can start in any city due to their alignment.Dark ElvesDark Elves are one of the oldest of the ancient elven races. They are one of three in Norrath. To the other two races of elves they are known as the Teir'Dal which translates to, "The elves of the Abyss", in the common tongue. They were created by Innoruuk, the Prince of Hate, and are considered his children. Dark Elves look down on all other races and consider them lessor creations. They only ally and work with other races as a means to manipulate them into fulfilling their will.Dark Elves are best as either mages or scouts.Dark Elves can start only in the evil cities Neriak and Gorowyn due to their alignment.DwarvesDwarves of Norrath are stout and mighty, and have long been one of Norrath's strongest races. They average 4 feet in height, but their weight can often be greater than it appears. They have large noses and ears. Dwarves take great pride in their hair, often adopting ancient styles worn by their ancestors. Their beards are typically bushy and full; even the females sometimes wear light beards. Dwarves often view a beard's fullness as a sign of prestige.Traditionally Dwarves have been either fighters or priests.Dwarves can start in only the good cities of New Halas and Kelethin because of their alignment.EruditesErudites are related to humans and share many similar features. They have devoted their lives to the pursuit of knowledge and intellect. Having chosen this path, the Erudites are usually slight in build compared to humans - a characteristic stemming from their distaste for conventional labor. The Erudites have shifted further from their human origins in their quest for mastery of the arcane arts. Their bodies have become even thinner, but still maintain a defined musculature. Their eyes glow with mystical power and their skin tone has changed to shades of grey.Erudites are best suited as either mages or priests.Erudites can start in any city because of their neutral alignment.FaeFae are the vivacious heart of the Greater Faydark. Friendly and light-hearted, they enjoy playing tricks on the unwary. Child-like in their superstitions and beliefs as well as highly adept at magical skills. This gives them a sense of humor that is often described as “tricksy.”Fae are best suited to be either scouts or priests.Fae are a good race, they can start in Kelethin or New Halas..FreebloodA race of vampires who arose out of the Loping Plains. Unlike other vampire races in Norrath, they do not fear the sun, and can walk about in full daylight. They have the ability to drain a foe's life force, to transform into a cloud of bats, as well as to shift between their elven and demonic forms.Freeblood are best suited as either scouts or mages.Freeblood can start in any city because of their neutral alignment.FrogloksFrogloks of Norrath were touched by the hand of the god of valor, Mithaniel Marr. They rapidly evolved from short, flimsy amphibians into a race that is both wise of spirit and formidable in battle. Visible muscles and tendons create an imposing upper body cinched to a narrow waist. Their most notable feature is a long, sticky tongue that can be extended up to three feet, perfect for snatching passing insects or pulling up a stein of ale.Frogloks are best suited to be either fighters or priests.Because of their alignment Frogloks can only start in the good cities of New Halas and Kelethin.GnomesGnomes make up for their small stature with tenacity and ingenuity. Known for their inquisitive nature, they are constantly tinkering with devices both mystical and technological. This poking around has gotten them into trouble in the past, but their craftiness and intellect has allowed them to survive and prosper despite whatever mischief they might unleash.Gnomes are best suited to scout and mage classes.Gnomes are a neutral race and may start in any city.HalflingsThe courageous Halflings are good-natured and friendly, amiable to anyone willing to share a warm meal and a grand tale. Known for their humor, they enjoy mischief and shenanigans. Some view them as objects of physical abuse and ridicule, but Halflings are far from being easy targets. They are quite nimble, a fact belied by their typical appearance.Hafings are best suited to scout and priest classes.Halflings are a good race, they start in either New Halas or Kelethin.Half ElvesCaught between the cultures of the Elves and Humans, Half Elves have struggled to establish their own society. They are known for their fierce determination and independent spirit. The Half Elves are rebellious which seems to show through in their hair styles and garb. They have grown somewhat rebellious as a result of exile and refer to themselves as Ayr'Dal, a term derived from the old elven word for "misfit."Half Elves are well rounded and good at a variety of classes.Half Elves are a neutral race and may start in any city.High ElvesThe fair-skinned high elves embody nobility and wisdom. They are benevolent people who strive for order and discipline, though some consider their stoic nature a sign of arrogance. Their Wood Elf cousins exist chiefly to do their bidding and most other good races are merely tolerated. Evil races, especially their mortal enemies the dark elves, are worthy only of a quick and efficient death.High Elves are best suited as priests or mages.High Elves are a good race, they start in either New Halas or Kelethin.HumansSometimes wise and sometimes foolish, humans are capable of both remarkable ingenuity and startling brutality. Humans are diverse in nearly every aspect of their abilities and culture. They possess a wide range of physical features, and their values and principles are equally varied. Capable of both amazing deeds of kindness and thoughtless acts of cruelty, they have risen to prominence among many of the older races.Humans are well rounded and good at a variety of classes.Humans are a neutral race and may start in any city.IksarCalculating and cold, the Iksar are a powerful reptilian race whose history is defined by conflict. They are a harsh but disciplined people who delight in cruelty and conquest. The Iksar are a very strong race, well-suited for the physical combat styles of the fighter classes. Their keen intellect allows them to be powerful mages, with a definite emphasis on dark forms of magic.Iksar are best suited to either fighter or mage classes.Iksar are an evil race, they may start in either Gorowyn or Neriak.KerraKerra worship the spirits of the land and those of their ancestors. Their often docile demeanor masks the fearsome and powerful predators that they are. Kerra are a large humanoid feline race, their bodies covered in fur with colors and patterns denoting their lineage. They are tall and powerful with great agility, their tails able to perform menial tasks almost with minds of their own.Kerrans are well rounded and good at a variety of classes.Kerra are a neutral race and may start in any city.OgresOgres are aggressive brutes who show their opponents neither sympathy nor mercy. Strong and intelligent, their physical might is matched only by their hunger for power. Built for warfare, these hulks long-ago ruled an empire that encompassed most of Norrath. No other race is more physically imposing than the Ogres. Their fat-layered, muscular bodies are covered in thick battle-scarred skin: coarse, bumpy and hideous to most.Ogres are best suited as either fighters or priests.Ogres are an evil race, they may start in either Gorowyn or Neriak.RatongasThe Ratonga are agile, crafty, and surprisingly charismatic. Little is known of their past. They have a keen perspective and are highly intelligent, but tend to be selfish and manipulative. They prefer to lurk in the shadows and remain unseen; whatever they do is intended to be silent and blend in with the darkness. Though lacking strength, the excellent agility of Ratonga often makes them perfect scouts.Ratongas excel as either scouts or mages.Ratonga are an evil race, they may start in either Gorowyn or Neriak.SarnakBred and magically altered to be the fiercest militia, the Sarnak of Gorowyn can be practical and approachable, but when placed in a combat situation, they are unflinchingly dedicated and vicious. Exiled from their homeland and banished from Norrath’s history, the Sarnak emerge to uncover artifacts long thought lost.Sarnak are well rounded and good at a variety of classes.Sarnak are an evil race, they start in Gorowyn or Neriak.TrollsTrolls care only about satisfying their hunger for food and lust for battle. Their unpredictable behavior and formidable strength make them fearsome and deadly opponents. Despite their limitations, trolls are not to be underestimated. A particularly savage clan filled with hate, Trolls have daunting strength and stamina, which make them good fighters of any type.Trolls are best suited to fighter and priest classes.Trolls are an evil race, they may start in either Gorowyn or Neriak.Wood ElvesWood Elves are pleasant and friendly. Fierce protectors of the woodlands, they will do battle with any who dare to taint the purity of nature. Wood Elves love celebration and song, dedicating their lives to the praise of their creator, Tunare. Their welcoming and accepting nature has led to close ties with other races, especially humans. This particular closeness has, in turn, sired the vast majority of the Half Elf race.Wood Elves excel in scout and priest classes.Wood Elves are a good race, they start in either New Halas or Kelethin.HousingEverquest 2 features fully customizable player housing and guild halls. Players can craft, buy or quest for housing items from beds, books, tables and even pets. There are a set amount of houses to choose from per city and are separated by the good and evil cities. For each house, rent must be paid per week and is either a monetary and/or status cost.Guild Halls were released in Game Update 49 and gives guilds the chance to create a base of operations and a fully customized miniature city with vendors and menders.Free-To-PlayOn December 6th, 2011, Sony Online Entertainment made all of EQ2 free to play by merging its free to play Everquest II Extended service with its subscription-based Everquest Live service. EQ2 retains the Bronze, Silver, and Gold memberships from EQ2X, but now gives out 500 Station Cash a month to recurring Gold subscribers. Players who had both EQ2 and EQ2X accounts would gain an increase in character slots to compensate for the two different services being merged.Many classes and races much be purchased in the in-game store using SOE's premium currency, Station Cash. Station Cash may also purchase cosmetic items, potions, and premium mounts. Everquest II: Extended includes all expansions except for the latest one, which can be purchased in the Station Cash Marketplace using Station Cash.There are three subscription levels:Bronze: The default and most restricted level. Completely free.Silver: One-time 500 SC purchase. Allows the player to create guilds, also lifting multiple restrictions of Bronze.Gold: Subscription program that removes many restrictions, but costs monthly.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="13">Card Game</genre><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9705">Lineage II: The Chaotic Chronicle</game><game id="12149">Dark Age of Camelot</game><game id="12376">The Lord of the Rings Online: Shadows of Angmar</game><game id="19796">City of Heroes</game><game id="11142">Final Fantasy XI Online</game><game id="4791">Vanguard: Saga of Heroes</game><game id="9641">Age of Conan: Hyborian Adventures</game><game id="20666">Warhammer Online: Age of Reckoning</game><game id="20701">World of Warcraft: Wrath of the Lich King</game><game id="18603">World of Warcraft: The Burning Crusade</game><game id="20238">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion</game><game id="21707">Fury</game><game id="9437">Star Wars: Galaxies - An Empire Divided</game><game id="22063">Perfect World</game><game id="22488">Mortal Online</game><game id="21545">Tibia</game><game id="21308">Aion: Ascension</game><game id="22431">Ultima Online: Kingdom Reborn</game><game id="22997">The Lord of the Rings Online: Mines of Moria</game><game id="13682">Asheron's Call 2: Fallen Kings</game><game id="13479">Anarchy Online</game><game id="4326">RF Online</game><game id="6867">Richard Garriott's Tabula Rasa</game><game id="16614">Ragnarok Online</game><game id="21426">The Chronicles of Spellborn</game><game id="23559">Priston Tale</game><game id="23433">Shin Megami Tensei: Imagine</game><game id="24766">Cartoon Network Universe: FusionFall</game><game id="21958">MapleStory</game><game id="24243">Grandia Online</game><game id="23193">Perfect World International</game><game id="22187">Flyff - Fly For Fun</game><game id="24416">Free Realms</game><game id="26847">Final Fantasy XIV Online: A Realm Reborn</game><game id="21337">Final Fantasy XI Online: Wings of the Goddess</game><game id="28082">Earth Eternal</game><game id="24336">Fiesta</game><game id="28125">Legend of Mir 2</game><game id="13869">Istaria: Chronicles of the Gifted</game><game id="3634">Redmoon</game><game id="33226">The Lord of the Rings Online: Rise of Isengard</game><game id="38774">Final Fantasy XI: Seekers of Adoulin</game><game id="38488">Rift: Storm Legion</game><game id="21223">Guild Wars 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/7930/389357-everquest_ii_uk_box_art.jpg</image></root>