<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18568</id><name>The King of Fighters '95</name><description>OverviewThe King of Fighters '95 is a 2D 3-on-3 fighting game developed and published by SNK for the Neo Geo. It is the second installment in the King of Fighters series and introduces the concept of team customization. The American Sports Team is also replaced by the Rivals Team, featuring Fatal Fury rival Billy Kane, Art of Fighting rival Eiji Kisaragi, and the popular Iori Yagami, rival to Kyo Kusanagi. The story is similar to the previous game, as Rugal Bernstein hosts a tournament featuring the strongest warriors.GameplayThe gameplay was still the same as its previous title but a few alterations and additions were made to this game. Unlike The King of Fighters 94 where a fixed team of 3 is chosen to each fight, the concept of "Team Edit" was added where the player can choose any 3 characters from any of the teams.CharactersJapan TeamKyo KusanagiBenimaru NikaidoGoro DaimonFatal Fury TeamTerry BogardAndy BogardJoe HigashiArt of Fighting TeamRyo SakazakiRobert GarciaTakuma SakazakiIkari Warriors TeamHeidernRalf JonesClark SteelPsycho Soldier TeamAthena AsamiyaSie KensouChin GentsaiWomen Fighters TeamYuri SakazakiMai ShiranuiKingKorea TeamKim KaphwanChang KoehanChoi BoungeRivals TeamIori Yagami (new character)Eiji Kisaragi (new character)Billy Kane (new character)OtherSaisyu Kusanagi (sub-boss) (new character)Rugal Bernstein (boss)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11156">X-Men vs. Street Fighter</game><game id="7751">Art of Fighting Anthology</game><game id="18484">Killer Instinct</game><game id="21952">Killer Instinct 2</game><game id="10614">Killer Instinct Gold</game><game id="21277">Ultimate Mortal Kombat</game><game id="12151">Street Fighter Collection 2</game><game id="39238">Battle High 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1614/840835-kof95_ng_jp.jpg</image></root>