<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18645</id><name>Dragon Ball GT: Final Bout</name><description>OverviewDragon Ball GT: Final Bout is a 2.5D fighting game developed by TOSE and published by Bandai for the PlayStation on October 1, 1997. The sequel to Dragon Ball Z: Ultimate Battle 22 and Dragon Ball Z: Shin Butōden, Dragon Ball GT: Final Bout is the first Dragon Ball game released in North America (without being heavily localized), the first game in the franchise to feature 3D character graphics, and the first game to use assets from Dragon Ball GT. Despite the game's name, most of the characters are from various points in the Dragon Ball Z series.The game would see a reprint in both North America and Europe (due to the increased popularity of the Dragon Ball franchise) in August 24, 2004 by Atari. The only difference is new box art.Game ModesBattle ModeThe standard mode, here players can either face their friends or the computer in random battles.Tournament ModeLike other Dragon Ball titles, this mode allows players to fight their friends or the computer in Budokai tournament. This mode can allow up to eight players to join in. Players can also play as their build up character.Build Up ModeCarried over from Ultimate Battle 22, this feature gives player the chance to train a character of their choosing and save them via a memory card. Unlike Ultimate Battle 22, this version of the mode allows to build their characters strength to triple digit levels, and comes with experience chart in their character profile. Like Ultimate Battle 22, players have the opportunity to battle their friends with their character in the option called Build Up Battle.CharactersThe character selection screen, showing all 17 playable characters.The game includes ten playable fighters (with seven different variations of other characters, totalling the total playable character amount to 17). Ten characters are playable from the start, with the other seven being unlockable with cheat codes.Despite the name of the game, the only characters to resemble their Dragon Ball GT appearances are Goku (in all but his "DBZ gear" version), Trunks (in all but the "alternate future" version), Pan, and Vegeta (after being infected by Baby and transformed into his Great Ape form). The other characters resemble their Dragon Ball Z versions.Goku (regular, kid form, unlockable Super Saiyan, unlockable Super Saiyan w/ DBZ gear, unlockable kid form w/ Super Saiyan, and unlockable Super Saiyan 4)Trunks (regular, unlockable Super Saiyan, and unlockable alt. future w/ Super Saiyan)PanVegeta (Super Saiyan, and Great Ape form after infected by Baby as the unplayable final boss)Gohan ("unlocked full potential" version)Cell (perfect form)Majin Buu (kid form)Frieza (final form)PiccoloVegito (Super Saiyan, unlockable)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6153">Soul Blade</game><game id="12411">Soulcalibur</game><game id="10081">Tekken</game><game id="4249">The King of Fighters '94</game><game id="5394">Transformers: Beast Wars Transmetals</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1814859-box_dbgtfb.png</image></root>