<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18734</id><name>Birth of America</name><description> OverviewBirth of America tells the story of the wars that took place in North America during the late 18th century. You can relive the American War of Independence (1775-1783), and also the long fight between France and England for the control of the Ohio valley and Canada, known as the French  Indian war (1755-1763).  BoA is a strategy game, with a map divided into regions. It is a turn-based game, so the player has as much time as he/she wishes to think about his orders. Turns are solved simultaneously by the game engine,therefore a two-player game takes the same amount of time as a single-player one. The player can control leaders, armies and fleets, each represented by colorful sprites. You assume the role of on the Commanders in Chief on the North American theater and must fight your way to victory - defeating your opponent in the field and taking key objectives and strategic cities.   Gameplay Birth of America's gameplay is primarily a region based tactical strategy game.  Your units moves are dictated  by how far they can march within a month, and, the leadership abilities of the units leaders.  Your battle victory depends on each units defensive abilities, current stance and the location of the fight.   Battles, unit movement and unit attrition is greatly affected by the weather.  Units also require constant supplies, either through foraging or supply lines.  The game also utilizes fog of war.  This will prevent you from seeing deeply into enemy territory.   Most of the game focuses around scenarios where there are objectives of importance to capture and a restricted amount of turns to do so.  There are ten campaigns over all spanning the course of history in north america from 1755-1783.  These campaigns include the American war for independence and the French and Indian war.  The game also provides a grand campaign spanning the entire course of history from 1755-1873.   System Requirements  Minimum system requirements :Processor: Intel Pentium III or AMD Athlon, 1200 MHzRAM: 512 MBGraphic Card: 64 MB vRAM, DirectX 8.1 compatibleSound Card: 16-bits, DirectX 8.1 compatibleCD Rom: x 8Peripherals: Microsoft compatible keyboard and mouseOperating System: Windows 2000 or XPHard Disk: 1 GB free disk spaceDirectX : Version 8.1  Recommended system requirements :Processor: Intel Pentium IV or AMD Athlon, 1800 MHzRAM: 1024 MBGraphic Card: 128 MB vRAM, DirectX 8.1 compatibleSound Card: 16-bits, DirectX 8.1 compatibleCD Rom: x 8Peripherals: Microsoft compatible keyboard and mouseOperating System: Windows XPHard Disk: 2 GB free disk spaceDirectX: Version 8.1</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9909">Shattered Union</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2748/295486-10.jpg</image></root>