<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18775</id><name>Space Rangers</name><description>GameplayPlayers assume the role of one of these heroic Rangers on their quest to save the galaxy from slavery. The Ranger begins with a small spaceship and the freedom to act as he pleases. There are no certain ways to win the game and each of the rangers decides on his own what to do to stop Klissans' invasion and to prove that it is him who is the Hero whose destiny is to save the galaxy.Alien RacesThere are 6 different alien races in the game and 5 of them are playable characters.Maloq - the maloq are very big character in stature that have great strength, but weak mental constitution. Their race eats the most and they have the cheapest equipment, but the equipment is easiest to break.Peleng - pelengs are four fingered that are most known as criminals. Their specialty is their intelligence and their equipment is 2nd most cheapest and delicate.Human - humans are the most average of the races and run most of the economy of the universe. Human equipment is also as average and in the middle of the spectrum as their abilities.Faeyan - faeyans are the scientists and technicians of the universe, but are also made fun of as hermaphrodites. Their equipment is 2nd only to the Gaal in expensiveness and durability.Gaal - the gaal are 3-eyed creatures who are very philosophic and also scientists, even if not as talented scientists compared to the faeyan. They are the wisest of the races and and their equipment is the most durable and most expensive equipment in the game.Klissans - the klissans are the only race in the game that are not playable because they are the enemy in the game. This race is very mysterious in nature and not much is known about them.PC System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Windows 95/98/ME/NT/2000/XPProcessor: Pentium 233 GHzMemory: 64 MBHard Drive: 300 MBGraphics: Video card that supports 800x600 and 16-Bit High ColorRecommended:OS: Windows 2000/XPProcessor: Pentium III 733 GHzMemory: 256 MBHard Drive: 700 MBGraphics: Video card that support 1024x768 and 16-Bit High Color</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16484">Space Rangers 2: Rise of the Dominators</game><game id="31010">DarkStar One: Broken Alliance</game><game id="35942">Space Pirates and Zombies</game><game id="2112">SunDog: Frozen Legacy</game><game id="37043">X3: Albion Prelude</game><game id="22771">X3: Terran Conflict</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1403/397250-506_space_rangers.jpg</image></root>