<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>18801</id><name>WWF War Zone</name><description>GameplayPlayers choose a wrestler to compete in various types of matches, including: one-on-one, tag team, tornado tag, cage match, weapons match, and war. The Nintendo 64 version of the game also included Royal Rumble and gauntlet matches. Much like modern wrestling games, the player uses a combination of buttons to punch, kick, and grapple their opponents. Also, during some of the matches, you can set the mode to hardcore and use weapons which are available.Career ModeThe single player "WWF Challenge" mode consists of a pyramid of television sets that the player starts at the bottom of. In each set is a different wrestler in the WWE, and as the pyramid goes higher, so does the difficulty of the matches. After the player has defeated his opponent, often that same opponent would issue a "grudge match." These "grudge match" challenges were not optional and were prefaced by a full-motion video of the challenger. After you win the WWF championship, you defend the title and, if you suffer a loss, you need to win the title again.The Game Boy version of the game features a password save system. Playable RostersNintendo 64 and Playstation VersionsAhmed Johnson Bret Hart British Bulldog Faarooq GoldustHeadbanger MoshHeadbanger Thrasher Kane Ken Shamrock Mankind Owen Hart The Rock Shawn Michaels Stone Cold Steve Austin Triple H The Undertaker Cactus Jack (Secret Character) Dude Love (Secret Character)Pamela (Secret Character)Rattlesnake (Secret Character)Sue (Secret Character)Trainer (Secret Character)Turok (Secret Character; can only be unlocked using a GameShark)Commentators Vince McMahon Jim RossGameboy Version The Gameboy version of the game featured a smaller roster than the console counterparts.Shawn MichaelsKaneKen Shamrock"Stone Cold" Steve AustinFaarooqGoldustTriple HMankindOwen HartThe RockThe British BulldogAhmed JohnsonThe Undertaker </description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="10">Wrestling</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8647">ECW Hardcore Revolution</game><game id="6945">ECW Anarchy Rulz</game><game id="16435">WWF Attitude</game><game id="22390">Monday Night Raw</game><game id="20680">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2009</game><game id="20469">TNA iMPACT!</game><game id="18320">WCW/nWo Revenge</game><game id="7908">WCW Nitro</game><game id="14786">WCW vs. nWo: World Tour</game><game id="1873">WCW/nWo Thunder</game><game id="557">WCW vs. the World</game><game id="30637">Lucha Libre AAA Heroes del Ring</game><game id="28430">WWF Royal Rumble</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2139915-box_wwfwz.png</image></root>