<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1880</id><name>Ridge Racer 64</name><description>FeaturesRidge Racer 64 contains 3 environments, each having 3 variations, making for a total of nine tracks. Reverse versions of each track are available. 25 fictional cars are included, 4 of which are unlocked from the beginning. Additional cars may be unlocked by playing in the car attack mode, where the player faces off against the car they would like to unlock in a 1 vs 1 duel.CarsGrading Scale (The # is approximately how far the performance bar is in game, 100 would mean the ability is maxed out):Very low: 0-20%Low: 20-40%Medium: 40-60%High: 60-80%Very High: 80-99%Max: 100%F/A RacingF/A RacingSpeed: MediumAcceleration: MediumHandling: MediumGrip: MediumA decent car, but there isn't much reason why you should use it compared to the other 3 starter cars.RT RyukyuRT RyukyuSpeed: MediumAcceleration: MediumHandling: HighGrip: HighBetter than F/A Racing, great for turning corners, but just isn't fast enough to catch up to the other cars in the later races.Pac RacingPac RacingSpeed: MediumAcceleration: Very HighHandling: LowGrip: Very LowA good car, but is even slower than the Ryukyu, and handles worse to boot, you shouldn't really use this car.RT SolvalouRT SolvalouSpeed: HighAcceleration: LowHandling: MediumGrip: Very LowThe car you should be using for the early races, the speed allows you to catch up to the pack quickly, and the low acceleration is not as important during these races.RT Pink MappyRT Pink MappySpeed: MediumAcceleration: MediumHandling: Low / MediumGrip: MediumThis car shouldn't even be in the game, it's the same as F/A Racing but handles even worse, don't use this car.RT Blue MappyRT Blue MappySpeed: MediumAcceleration: MediumHandling: MediumGrip: MediumExactly the same as the Pink Mappy, but with slightly better handling. These two cars serve no real purpose in the game.Galaga RT Prid'sGalaga RT Prid'sSpeed: Medium/HighAcceleration: MediumHandling: Medium/HighGrip: LowDecent car, but you unlock the RT Xevious Red before you get this car, and the Xevious is a far superior car, so don't bother with this car.Galaga RT CarrotGalaga RT CarrotSpeed: HighAcceleration: MediumHandling: HighGrip: LowThe RT Prid's but with improved speed and handling.RT BosconianRT BosconianSpeed: MediumAcceleration: MediumHandling: MediumGrip: Medium/LowFairly mediocre car, only slightly better than F/A Racing.RT NebulasrayRT NebulasraySpeed: MediumAcceleration: MediumHandling: MediumGrip: Medium/LowJust a blue Bosconian, but with worse handling.RT Xevious RedRT Xevious RedSpeed: MediumAcceleration: High/Very HighHandling: Low/MediumGrip: LowFantastic car, the handling may be a bit low, making it feel a bit heavy around the corners,but whenever you crash, this cars massive acceleration will let you regain your speed in no time,this should be the first car you use after the starter cars.RT Xevious GreenRT Xevious GreenSpeed: HighAcceleration: MediumHandling: MediumGrip: Low/MediumTrades away the Xevious Red's acceleration for a boost to Speed, handling, and grip.Unfortunately, the only noticeable increase is in speed. Due to it's low acceleration, ittakes quite a long time to regain your speed. By the time you get this car, there are much more balanced cars available.DIG Racing TeamDIG Racing TeamSpeed: HighAcceleration: MediumHandling: HighGrip: LowAnother great car, It's amazing handling will insure you can get around corners much more easily than in other cars.However, it's low grip makes exiting drifts a bit difficult sometimes.If you do crash, this cars acceleration will take you up to a pretty high top speed. An overall great car.Micro Mouse MappyMicro Mouse MappySpeed: HighAcceleration: MediumHandling: MediumGrip: LowSimilar to the Xevious Green, a lot of speed, but not enough acceleration or handling to back that up. If you crash, it will take you awhile to get back to your high top speed.13th Racing Kid13th Racing KidSpeed: HighAcceleration: Very HighHandling: LowGrip: Low/MediumThis car is VERY fast. It has a great top speed and the extremely high acceleration insuring that you reach it quickly. It is however, not very agile and you may wreck a few times, but you won't be down for long, because your acceleration will eliminate any speed loss quickly, a good car, but unfortunately overshadowed by a far better car.White AngelWhite AngelSpeed: High/Very HighAcceleration: Very HighHandling: Very HighGrip: High/Very HighThis car is good, very good, one of the best cars in the game, use it, and win.Digipen RacingDigipen RacingSpeed: HighAcceleration: MaxHandling: MediumGrip: MediumAfter White Angel, don't even bother...it's got great acceleration, but you'll have trouble in the corners due to mediocre handling.Assoluto InfinitoAssoluto InfinitoSpeed: HighAcceleration: Very HighHandling: Very HighGrip: MediumShould be called the White Angel 2.0. It has a higher speed and handles much better than the White Angel, but at the expense of grip, which isn't a huge deal. It also does away with the White Angel's excessive width.Age Solo SupernovaAge Solo SupernovaSpeed: Very HighAcceleration: MediumHandling: MediumGrip: LowIt has a great top speed, but has a bit of a problem getting there. It is also a bit heavy through the corner, but if your a skilled racer, and can control a heavy car well, this car is tough to beat.Atomic PurpleAtomic PurpleSpeed: Very HighAcceleration: HighHandling: Very HighGrip: MediumLike an improved Age Solo Supernova, it has a slightly lower top speed, but makes up for it in significantly increased acceleration and handling capabilities. The grip isn't too lacking either. A great car overall.Extreme GreenExtreme Green FrontSpeed: High/Very HighAcceleration: MaxHandling: HighGrip: NoneAmazing acceleration, but has absolutely no grip. The handling and speed are worse than on Atomic Purple, but it sure does look cool, overall, Atomic Purple is a better choice though.Terrazi TerrificTerrazi TerrificSpeed: Very HighAcceleration: MediumHandling: MediumGrip: LowBuilt for one, and only one reason, to beat Lizard Nightmare. The fastest car you have when you race against Lizard Nightmare, it is a perfect choice for the race, that is, if you can keep yourself from crashing due to it's heavy handling.Lizard NightmareLizard NightmareSpeed: Very HighAcceleration: MaxHandling: MaxGrip: HighThe White Angel, reborn, and it's even better than before. A nearly perfect car, you will have a hard time crashing with it's fantastic handling. Even if you do, it won't matter, because the massive acceleration will rocket you back to this lizard's insanely high top speed.Screamin' EagleScreamin' Eagle FrontSpeed: Very HighAcceleration: Very HighHandling: MaxGrip: MaxYou sure will be screamin' along in the United States themed race car. Almost unbeatable, only one car can top it.Ultra 64Ultra 64Speed: MaxAcceleration: MaxHandling: MaxGrip: MaxPerfect. Everything good about a car is here. It's fast, and almost too fast, On Z class, the car will often crash into the walls during drifts due to it's quick movement, however crashing isn't a concern, as your already lapping the competition.Nintendo DS PortIn 2004, an updated port titled Ridge Racer DS was released for the Nintendo DS. Along with Super Mario 64 and Rayman 2, RRDS followed an early trend of publishers porting N64 titles to the DS with varyling levels of results. Improving on the series with 4-player simultaneous gameplay, new tracks, improved graphics, and new cars.The Nintendo DS port suffered from lower resolution (making it hard to make out what's ahead, especially at the high speeds later in the game), inadequate framerate (also hindering player reaction time) and lack of a control stick, making precise control more problematic, considering the game's demanding difficulty and narrow roads in some of the courses, an issue made worse by invisible walls drawn near the edge of the road. (Meaning you can hit an invisible wall simply from being too close to the edge of the road.)</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12064">WipEout 64</game><game id="10791">Beetle Adventure Racing!</game><game id="22135">Daytona USA</game><game id="24513">DiRT 2</game><game id="42324">Ridge Racer Driftopia</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1839035-box_rracer64.png</image></root>