<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19032</id><name>ATV Offroad Fury</name><description>OverviewATV Offroad Fury is a racing game featuring 12 ATVs, 18 tracks, and 5 wide open environments. Gameplay is straight forward, with five event types and three race modes. Riders can also perform stunts while in the air.Event TypesMAXXIS NationalsThese tracks are outdoor races full of hills, bumps, jumps, drops, and hairpin turns.Presido ParkChateau HalifaxYucatan DunesLexington TrailThe BadlandsManitoba MillsKodiak PipelineSalem's BacklotRed RocksSomers RacewayTaramac RanchStadium SupercrossThese races take place in dirt-filled arenas complete with cheering and booing fans.ChesapeakeWilkes-BarreSyracuseLatrobeTupeloSanta FeMenifee Freestyle CompetitionThese massive environments offer plenty of spots to pull stunts and rack up huge points, or you can just cruise around and see the sights.Canyon CountryHarp ValleyYardley StationFort RobertsCrater ParkCross Country EnduroThese are point-to-point races through the same environments as the Freestyle competition. Each of the five environments has three separate races: short, medium, and long.Pro CareerSelect an ATV and race on all the Maxxis Nationals and Supercross tracks in tournament style.Race TypesSingle RaceRace against the AI or up to three friends on any track for up to 20 laps.Lap AttackRace against the clock and your own ghost ATV to get the best possible lap time.PracticeYou have unlimited laps to learn the race tracks or unlimited time to explore the freestyle environments.ATVs Ravage TalonRavage EagleRavage HawkRavage DCXRavage 1000Havoc ProformerHavoc MilanHavoc RazorHavoc SiegeHonda 300EXHonda 400EXKawasaki MojaveYamaha BansheeYamaha BlasterYamaha LaredoYamaha WarriorPolaris 400Polaris 500 StuntsHeel Clicker Superman Air Walk Nac Nac Bar Kneel Split X Scissors Cordova Heart Attack Lazy Boy Double Can Can Tail Grab Bar Hop Saran Wrap Cliff Hanger Seat GrabSoundtrack"Atlanta" by Strawhorse"Click" by Ultraspank"Crumble" by Ultraspank"Crush" by Anthrax"Denial" by Sevendust"Fishbowl" by Strawhorse"Isolate" by Bender"Jerry Was a Race Car Driver" by Primus"Mephisto" by Strung Out"Scarecrow" by Strung Out"Spoonman" by Soundgarden"Stop and Panic" by Cirrus"Superfly" by Bender"Them Bones" by Alice in Chains"Yo! Future" by Apollo 440</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20957">Pure</game><game id="20933">Baja: Edge of Control</game><game id="23921">MotorM4X</game><game id="15429">Excitebike 64</game><game id="4026">MX Unleashed</game><game id="23461">FUEL</game><game id="26452">MX vs. ATV: Reflex</game><game id="34155">ATV Wild Ride</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2275967-box_atvof.png</image></root>