<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19125</id><name>Super Smash Bros.</name><description>OverviewThe game's title screen (English Version).Super Smash Bros. (known in Japan as "Nintendo All Star! Dairantō Smash Brothers", translated to "Nintendo All-Star! Great Melee Smash Brothers") is a 2.5D fighting game developed by HAL and published by Nintendo for the Nintendo 64 in April 26, 1999.The game features characters from popular Nintendo franchises (such as Mario, The Legend of Zelda, and Pokémon) in arena battles (for up to four players) using a unique open-movement fighting game system (in which depleting player vitality is replaced by knocking players out of the arena, weakening their knock-back resistance by attacking them).The game received sequels for each Nintendo console: Super Smash Bros. Melee (for the GameCube), Super Smash Bros. Brawl (for the Wii), and Super Smash Bros. Universe (for the Wii U and Nintendo 3DS). The game's concept and unique fighting system was used by other game franchise crossovers, such as Jump Super Stars (using Shonen Jump assets) and PlayStation All-Stars Battle Royale (using Sony assets).GameplayThe game introduced the fighting system that would later become stable for the entire series, with newer variants increasing the speed and versatility of combat rather than adjusting the underlying gameplay.Physics-Oriented Health SystemRather than ensuing the usual method and dynamics of fighting games, Super Smash Bros. involves a player trying to knock theLink vs. Linkother players off a stage. Each stage has boundaries, which vary from one another in length and height, that allow players to eliminate others by sending them off the stage in one of 4 different directions in most cases. In order to increase the likelihood of a player sending another off the stage, that player can perform a variety of attacks on the other which will inflict damage as represented by a percentile level at the bottom of the screen. As the percentage goes up, each attack you perform will send the opponent further than before, thus making it easier to knock them off the stage. The attacking moves available differ from character to character, much like other fighting games, as each character will have their own unique move set. However, unlike most other fighting games, there are no combos involved and most of the moves are easy to pull off. In addition to the standard attacking moves, each character will also have their own distinctive grappling move which will throw your opponent far distances if their damage percentage is relatively high, as well as the name-sake "smash" attack which can be done by tapping the joystick while preforming a move.Freedom of MotionTo complement the combat objective of knocking opponents off the stage to win, Super Smash Bros. maps have a significant degree of verticality built into their layouts (the notable exception being Final Destination, a flat and uneventful battlefield popular on tournament scene for its lack of environmental hazards). Platforms can be located above and below the main ground, they can move around, and they can potentially injure the player. These extra obstacles and paths lend themselves to a combination of ground and aerial combat, both of which the game encourages. The game also gives each player 2 jumps--a ground jump and a mid-air jump--in addition to a final up B recovery move for most characters to increase the viability of air combat as well as improve the chance of off screen recovery by characters not knocked far enough away from the stage to fall to their death.Ground vs. Air CombatGo! Fight! Win!Air attacks tend to be faster and have less knock back than ground attacks, making the earlier game about racking up damage quickly with lighter, faster aerial strikes. Once the opponent is sufficiently damaged, the smash attacks available to characters on the ground will serve as a final blow to send their targets flying off the side of the stage. Combatants on the ground also get the ability to grab opponents and either punch them while they are helpless or throw them in the hopes of flinging far enough to finish them off. Like all other moves, the throws vary in animation and strength by character and certain throws are more powerful than others depending entirely on which character is used.Mid-Battle ItemsAssisting a player during battles are items that were primarily made famous by previous Nintendo titles. During a battle, items will randomly be placed in various locations inside the stage, with each item being different than another in terms of its effects which range from healing health to helping inflict damage and, at times, even deliver a knock-out blow to an opponent. Items can be delivered in numerous forms, as they can either appear by itself, within a capsule, or within a box or a barrel, with boxes and barrels carrying multiple items the majority of the time when opened. However, capsules, boxes, and barrels are best to be thrown at an opponent or on the ground first to open them as some of them self-destruct upon contact.Modes of PlaySuper Smash Bros. consists of two game play modes, a one player progressional mode with a number of stages a player must complete, and a multi-player mode which supports up to 4 players either fighting individually or as teams.1P ModeStage 2 in 1P Mode1P Mode features 14 stages (3 of which are mini-games, and the last one being a boss battle), with each stage ultimately getting harder as you near the final stage. A player will have the ability to choose the difficulty of the opponents from one of five settings, set how many lives the selected character will have, and indicate whether or not the stages should be timed. As each stage is completed, the character will receive a score which is calculated by how much time is remaining and how much damage the opponent inflicted, and additionally any bonuses the character may have achieved during the stage, such as throwing the opponent off the stage or performing a taunt at the very last moment before the stage is over.VS ModeVersus Mode is where the multi-player component of the game is kept. This mode supports between two and four players battling, either individually or as teams, on either a stage selected by a player or a random stage. There are two different mAn engaging battle at Hyrule Castleethods to choose from in regards to how to determine a winner, having a timed battle or a battle with a fixed set of lives. Timed battles count down from a set time and whoever has the greater kill-to-death ratio (how many players you've knocked off the stage vs. how many times you have been sent off the stage) wins. Stock battles are not timed as every player enters a battle with an equal set of lives, and the last person standing wins (each time a player gets knocked off the stage, they lose a live).Bonus ModesThe Bonus Modes within the game are more intended to act as mini-games and are categorized into 2 games, Break the Targets and Board the Platforms. The Break the Targets mini-game involves a character to maneuver around a stage and hitting 10 targets without falling out of the stage in order to complete the mini-game. The Board the Platforms mini-game is fairly similar, characters must maneuver around a stage and land on 10 platforms without falling out of the stage. Each of the characters within the game have their own unique stage for both of the mini-games, and each of them are timed. If a player doesn't complete the stage, the highest number of targets or platforms a player successfully makes will appear at the character selection screen, but if they complete it, the quickest time it took to complete it will be shown instead.Training ModeTraining Mode is available to those primarily who are new to the game or to some players who want to experiment or refine their play with a character. Training Mode has a large set of options available to a player during play, including changing the game speed, spawning any item, and setting the playing style of the optional computer player.CharactersSelect a characterSuper Smash Bros. features a total of 12 playable characters, 4 of which must be unlocked. Among the roster is a series of what, at the time, would be quite a surprise, for example, Ness was one of the unlockable characters, even if he was almost completely unknown in the West and his games were not yet prominent among the other Nintendo franchises. Many other characters, however, are some of the most famous faces in gaming. Biographies of each character are available where each character was described in a couple of paragraphs, and at the end of the game, characters were represented by inactive dolls, falling to the floor of a child's bedroom. The doll archetype would later transform into the Trophy scheme, the main collectible objective of the following games in the series.MarioMARIO!Symbol: Super MushroomHome Stage: Peach's CastleCharacteristics: Great jumping ability, slow ground movement, excellent backthrowB Special Move: Red Fireball. Affected by gravity.Taunt: Grows to Super Mario and shrinks back to normalDonkey KongDK!Symbol: DKHome Stage: Congo JungleCharacteristics: Powerful attacks, carrying grappling move, very slow movementB Special Move: Mega Punch. Pressing B the first time charges the move and a second press throws it.Taunt: Shrugs his shouldersLinkLINK!Symbol: TriforceHome Stage: Hyrule CastleCharacteristics: Fast attacks, damaging aerial attacks, limited jumping abilityB Special Move: Throws a boomerang. Depending on how much Link moves it may not return back to him.Taunt: Poses with a shining swordSamus AranSAMUS!Symbol: Samus' S logoHome Stage: Planet ZebesCharacteristics: Ranged combatant, great jumping capability, powerful moves, missed grapple can leave a player exposedB Special Move: Charge Shot. Pressing B charges an energy ball and pressing it again launches it.Taunt: Poses with blaster cannonYoshiYOSHI!Symbol: EggHome Stage: Yoshi's IslandCharacteristics: Very large mid-air jump, powerful grapple move, up B doesn't help offstage recovery, slow movementB Special Move: Eats enemies and then turns them into eggs. Enemies are helpless while in the egg.Taunt: Waves arms and says "Yoshi"KirbyKIRBY!Symbol: StarHome Stage: DreamlandCharacteristics: Ample move set, quick attacks, great jumping ability, fairly light and thus prone to being knocked aroundB Special Move: Sucks up enemies. Can be spit back out with A or eaten to give Kirby the sucked up enemy's B move and a costume similar to the enemy.Taunt: Waves arms and says "Hi"Fox McCloudFOX!Symbol: Winged FoxHome Stage: Sector ZCharacteristics: Down-B reflects projectiles back at enemy, very fast movement, good aerials, weak attacksB Special Move: Lasers.Taunt: Crosses his armsPikachuPIKACHU!Symbol: PokeballHome Stage: Saffron CityCharacteristics: Good speed, good jump ability, weak attacksB Special Move: Sends an electric arc along the ground that will adhere to a platform regardless of direction.Taunt: Waves arms and says "Pika Pika"LuigiCharacter must be unlocked (beat Break the Targets with all eight original characters)Symbol: MushroomHome Stage: Peach's Castle/ Mushroom KingdomCharacteristics: Great jumping ability, more powerful than Mario, slow ground movementB Special Move: Green Fireball. Unaffected by gravity.Taunt: Kicks the ground. Luigi's taunt is unique in the fact that it is the only taunt in the game which causes damage. If an opponent is hit by his kick, the opponent will gain 1% of damage.Captain FalconCharacter must be unlocked (beat 1P Mode in less than 20 minutes)Symbol: FalconHome Stage: None (when battling him to unlock him, the battle takes place on Planet Zebes stage)Characteristics: Powerful attacks, good jumping ability, fast movement, long recovery windowB Special Move: Falcon Punch. Takes a second to actually happen, but does huge damage.Taunt: Poses and says "Show me your moves"NessCharacter must be unlocked (beat 1P Mode on Normal difficulty and lives set to 3)Symbol: EarthHome Stage: None (when battling him to unlock him, the battle takes place on Dreamland stage)Characteristics: Ability to regenerate health, great jumping ability, slow jump and movement, awkward recovery requires him to hit himself with a guided thunderboltB Special Move: PK Fire. Throws a bolt that lights enemies on fire and stuns them for a moment.Taunt: BowsJigglypuffCharacter must be unlocked (beat 1P Mode on any setting)Symbol: PokeballHome Stage: Saffron CityCharacteristics: Strong attack when used properly, five jumps instead of two, up B doesn't give up or sideways motion, other attacks are weakB Special Move: Pound. A short-range, high-damage punch.Taunt: Rolls around and says "Jigglypuff"StagesSelect a stageStages are the playing fields for the one-player mode and multi-player modes, and although the stages are rendered in three dimensions, players can only move on a two-dimensional plane. There are a total of 9 stages and a random stage selector, with each of the stages being unique in their own way as most of the characters playable within the game have a stage that characteristically and historically relates to them. Much like characters,not all stages are available immediately, as one of the stages must be unlocked.Peach's CastlePeach's CastleStage Size: SmallHazards: A bumper floats above a platform that can inflict damageCharacteristics: Small island with shifting block at the bottom of the islandCongo JungleCongo JungleStage Size: Very SmallHazards: A moving and rotating barrel at the bottom of the stage can send a player off the stage if they aren't carefulCharacteristics: Small stage with small revolving platforms in the centerHyrule CastleHyrule CastleStage Size: LargeHazards: A tornado that spawns in random locations on the mapCharacteristics: Large stage with lots of different platformsPlanet ZebesPlanet ZebesStage Size: AverageHazards: Acid beneath the stage that will rise to various heightsCharacteristics: Average sized stage with elevator and rising acidYoshi's IslandYoshi's IslandStage Size: LargeHazards: Clouds to the sides of the stage dissolve if a player stands on them too longCharacteristics: Large stage with relatively small island and clouds in distanceDreamlandDreamlandStage Size: Very SmallHazards: Whispy Woods will try to blow you off the platformCharacteristics: Very small stage with very few obstacles or hazardsSector ZSector ZStage Size: Very LargeHazards: Arwings will come in at random and shoot if a player is in their sightsCharacteristics: Very large stage with two different battle areas of different heightsSaffron CitySaffron CityStage Size: AverageHazards: Pokemon that may inflict damage will appear at random outside an area within the stageCharacteristics: Average sized stage with one main battle area and two small landing areasMushroom KingdomStage must be unlocked (beat 1P Mode on Normal with lives set to 3 with all eight original characters)Stage Size: LargeHazards: Piranha Plants that randomly appear out of pipes can inflict damage, POW block can send a player off the stage if they are on the ground when struckCharacteristics: Large stage, only stage to be predominatly flat, contain pipes that can warp a player to another location on the stageItemsBarrelItem Type: ContainerCharacteristics: Can contain up to 3 items, can also self-destruct after thrown or hitBeam SwordItem Type: Close CombatCharacteristics: Powerful swordBob-ombItem Type: ThrowCharacteristics: Explodes after thrown or hit, if left unattended it will start movingBumperItem Type: ThrowCharacteristics: Lays on the ground when thrown, if hit by a player they will have damage inflicted and the bumper will moveCapsuleItem Type: ContainerCharacteristics: Contains an item, can also self-destruct after thrown or hitChansey EggItem Type: ContainerCharacteristics: Contains an item, can also self-destruct after thrown or hitCrateItem Type: ContainerCharacteristics: Contains up to 3 items, can also self-destruct after thrown or hitFanItem Type: Close CombatCharacteristics: Weak though quick weapon, more useful if thrown at opponentFire FlowerItem Type: CombatCharacteristics: Unleashes a fiery blast, wears out over timeGreen ShellItem Type: ThrowCharacteristics: Powerful if hits an opponent in mid-air, will roll across the stage aswellHammerItem Type: Close CombatCharacteristics: Very powerful weapon, players will be unable to double or triple jump if carrying this weaponHeartItem Type: RecoveryCharacteristics: Will recover all of your healthHome Run BatItem Type: Close CombatCharacteristics: If a smash attack is used with this, it can instantly send an opponent off the stageMaxim TomatoItem Type: RecoveryCharacteristics: Will recover 100% of your health if a player had over 100% damageMotion Sensor BombItem Type: ThrowCharacteristics: Powerful, will detonate when any character touches itPokeballItem Type: ThrowCharacteristics: Will unleash a random Pokemon, with each Pokemon having a different attack or effectRay GunItem Type: CombatCharacteristics: Will send a laser shot that is useful for long range combat, will wear out over timeRed ShellItem Type: ThrowCharacteristics: Powerful if hits an opponent in mid-air, will move toward nearest player aswell if thrown onto stage, will disappear over timeStarItem Type: SpecialCharacteristics: Will temporarily give a player invincibilityStar RodItem Type: Combat/Close CombatCharacteristics: Can be used for close combat and if used as a smash attack, semi-long rangePokéballsThere are 13 different Pokemon that may randomly appear out when a Pokeball is thrown in Super Smash Bros. Pokemon will not harm the player who summoned it.NameDescriptionBeedrillBeedrill will use Poison Sting attack. It will fly off the screen and then a flock of Beedrill will fly across the screen attacking your enemies.BlastoiseBlastoise uses Hydro Pump attack. It fires several blasts of water out of its cannons and pushes back anyone it hits doing decent damage.ChanseyChansey uses Softboiled attack. It throws eggs out on the stage with items inside them.CharizardCharizard uses Flamethrower attack. It will turn its head left and right and breathe fire out either side.ClefairyClefairy uses Metronome attack. This attack will use the random attack of one of the games 12 other pokemon.GoldeenGoldeen will use Splash attack. Goldeen will flop around on the stage and will do no damage to any of the players.HitmonleeHitmonlee uses Hi-Jump Attack. Hitmonlee will choose a random target and attack it with a jumping kick, this attack does heavy damage and knock-back.KoffingKoffing uses Poison Gas attack. Gas shoots out and traps whoever it touches doing light damage.MeowthMeowth uses Pay Day attack. Meowth will jump in the air and shoot coins in all directions, it is possible to get caught in the barrage.MewMew is the only Pokemon that does not attack, it has a 1-in-151 chance of appearing. The first time Mew appears the character will unlock Mew Catcher and get 10,000 points.OnixOnix uses Rock Throw attack. Onix will jump in the air and drop rocks down on your opponents within a certain area.SnorlaxSnorlax uses Body Slam attack. Snorlax will jump up in the air, inflate in size and slam down on the screen dealing heavy damage to those below them.StarmieStarmie uses Swift attack. Starmie will fly around the screen until it finds a random target, it will then freeze in position and shoot multiple stars at its target.</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="44061">Rumble Academy</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1810969-box_ssb.png</image></root>