<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1914</id><name>Shin Megami Tensei: Digital Devil Saga 2</name><description>Plot  Note: Significant plot points  As a precursor to the events of the game, the player is told that the world is made from data at a quantum level, which is found out in the original Digital Devil Saga. The members of the  Embryon tribe, the players team, are in the Junkyard having been saved by the intervention of God and given bodies to be able to exist in the real world. Waking, they see that the sun has been turned dark, similar to an eclipse, and turns those without the Demon Virus to stone. Only three of the members of the Embryon tribe are in the Junkyard (Serph, Argilla and Gale) as Cielo had been kidnapped by the Lokapala resistance group. After fighting through the Junkyard the player meets the Leader of the Lokapala, Roland, and convinces him that they can help defeat the Karma Society.  Managing to get into the Karma Society's City, the Embryon trys to rescue a former member, Sera from the Medical Ward in the Detention Facility. Their plans are abated by former member Heat, how is been controlled by Madame Cuvier. A second attempt to rescue Sera is made at the E.G.G. facility, made to try to communicate with God, but are once again affronted by Heat trying to stop the rescue. After a heated battle Heat injures Serph and as a result both are dragged into the E.G.G. reactor just as God is trying to envelop and consume the planet. Jenna Angel, the main antagonist from the last game, kills Madame Cuvier and the rest of the Embryon tribe attempts and fails to stop the reactor.   As a result of a failure to stop E.G.G. Jenna Angel releases Meganada into the residence of the Junkyard hoping to spread it to the entire human race, but Roland and Cielo sacrifice themselves to stop this from happening. After this, the tribe enters the new E.G.G. structure and finds Heat's new form caused by the the E.G.G. and seeing that Seph is still alive, saved by the E.G.G. The tribe then learns about the past events that caused the events in the game. It is explained that Sera was a project of the Karma Society had scientists working on a project to create a subject that could communicate with God. Most of the subjects were destroyed by extreme mental pressure, the soul survivor was Sera. A man named Heat O'Brien opposed the project and the way another man Serph Sheffield's treatment of the children. The two fought and Sera was subject to this and saw the real personality of Serph. Due to the project causing a strong link between Sera and God, God "saved" most of those who were killed by Serph as data and recreated into a the Junkyard, which was supposed to be a paradise but when the military found it they wanted it to be used for training thus destroying the tranquillity of the paradise, as AI to deal with the trauma. Serph was confronted by two pieces of data Serph Sheffield and an AI Serph. Then the data of Heat O'Brien appeared to guild Serph and tells him that he must defeat these two to be free from his past and requesting that he release the AI Heat. After defeating the data, who turned into Varuna (Serph's Atma Avatar) both Serph and Heat escape and Serph meets up with the rest of the tribe after Heat tells him to go and see them and promptly dies due to a wound Serph gave him. Sera remembers another facility that they could use to reach God, called HAARP. The only way to get to the facility was through an abandoned airport where the tribe is confronted by Karma soldiers that were sent by Jenna Angel. There was a need to sacrifice many of the tribe but Serph and Sera were able to escape to HAARP facility. Once at the facility the two attempt to reach God and to support Sera, Serph holds her hand. There is a massive surge in data causes explosions throughout the facility, killing both Sera and Serph. There data is merged together when they are sent to the sun and they form Seraph. When they reach the sun they are united with the data of the rest of the tribe. After passing through all of the levels of the sun and defeating Brahman, Embryon is able to calm God and send the sun back to its original state. Seraph, as the only one to reach enlightenment, through realising that it was one with God, was able to retain its original body and travel to Nirvana while those of the Embryon who couldn't reach enlightenment were sent back to the world, reincarnated as children on the new formed planet.        OverviewCan we party with him? No wait, where are you going?Digital Devil Saga 2 is an RPG released by        Atlus for the       PlayStation 2 and is a direct sequel to the first game,         Digital Devil Saga. It shares most of the gameplay of the original while adding in some new concepts like equippable rings that boast various effects and frenzies that depend on the phase of the sun. It also adds in new characters to tie up the storyline.        Mantras In Digital Devil Saga the player can buy and equip special objects to the characters called Mantras. These allow the characters to learn different skills depending on what they have equipped. The mantras are set up in a hexagonal format so the player has to work their was through low level mantras to get at their stronger counterparts. There are twelve distinct types of mantras with  sub divisions for a few of these. The mantras are levelled up by gaining atama points (AP) which an be increased by ingesting opponents. Physical These mantras will teach your character abilities that consume health but can preform attacks that are much stronger than those of the attack function. Scattered throughout the physical skills are ability to cause status ailments as well as damage. The physical skills are separated into two kinds, normal and auto. List of physical mantras:         Mantras skills:Shura:            Body Rush, Mad RushSramana:           Venom Claw, Double Slash, HP BonusBhikkhuni:           Raving Slash, Critical, Quick Cure,ResolutionVanquisher:           Mute Blow, Chi BlastHoly Beast:            Hell FangViolent God:           Skull Cleve, Death Blow, RetaliateCruel Leader:          Power Wave, Life GainDemon Soldier:           Mind Scream, Power Charge, Void Phys, VengeanceOverlord:           Executioner, Resist PhysWarrior King:           Bloodbath, Demon RageAmatsukami:          Gate of Hell, Life Surge Destroyer:           God Slayer, Ragnarok, Null Phys Priestess:           Death Spray, Counter, Quick Escape Maiden:            Stun Needle, Comatose, First Strike, Null Critical Princess:           Charm Slash, Counterstrike, Null Risks Queen:             Sakura Rage, Attack All, Close CallGodess:           Revelation, High Counter, Deploy, Double Repel  HuntThese mantras will allow your character to gain more atama points from battle by ingesting an opponent. These are similar to to physical skill in that they require a portion of the character's health to preform and require physical contact on the opponent. There are two kind of hunt skills, fatal and non-fatal.  List of hunt mantras:         Mantra skills: Devourer:           Devour, Ingest Mana Demon Beast:          Feed Frenzy, Rend Asunder, Atama bonus, Iron Stomach Holy Beast:           Consume, AP Divide Godly Beast:          Insatiable, Atma Premium, Devour Mana Demon:           Vile Blade, Devil Feast, Taunt, Horror  Battle Demon:          Venom Fang, Ingest, Paralyze Demon Lord:          Genocide, Great Feast, Phys Repel, Petrify Demon God:          Last Meal, Phys Drain  SupportThese mantras give the characters spells that give improved stats or lower the opponents. They also encompass the status aliments and  List of support mantras:        Mantra spells: Spirit:            Tarukaji, Makajam, Void Mute Karma:            Sukukaja, HP Thief, Mana Bonus Twilight:           Makakaja, Makajamon, MP Thief Curse:            Rakukaja, Enervale, Silent Howl Arcane:            Dark Mirage, Null Mute, Mana Gain Illusion:            Spell Gloom, Dekunda Evil God:           Deliberate, Mana Surge Adamant:           Pulinpa, Stun Sphere, Void Panic, Void Nerve Kichijyo:           Marin Karin, Foul Breath, Void Charm, Void Poison Vidya Raja:           Allure, Neural Shock, Poison Mist, Null Nerve Holy Leader:          Tentarafoo, Stun Wave, Null Panic, Null Poison Mukti:            Fatal Charm, Poison Rain, Void Ailment, Null Charm Formless:           Vanity, Null Ailment  Fire These mantras give your characters the ability to cast the Agi spells as well as the fire resistant and boost abilities.  List of fire mantras:         Mantra spells: First Spirit:           Agi, Void Fire Fire Demon:           Maragi, Fire Boost Fire Leader:           Agilao, Flame Breath, Fire RepelFire Lord:           Maragion, Fire Drain Fire Emperor:          Agidyne, Explode, Fire Amp Fire God:           Maragidyne, Fire Resist Sublime Fire:          Trisagion  Ice These mantras give your characters the ability to cast Bufu spells as well as the ice resistance and boost abilities.  List of ice mantras:        Mantra spells: Ice Spirit:            Bufu, Void IceIce Demon:            Mabufu, Ice BoostIce Leader:            Bufula, Frost Breath, Ice RepelIce Wolf:            Mabufula, Ice Drain Ice Master:           Bufudyne, Cold Wave, Ice AmpIce God:            Mabufudyne, Ice ResistSublime Ice:           Niflheim  Force These mantras give your character the ability to cast Zan spells as well as the force resistance and boost abilities.  List of force mantras:         Mantra spells: Dragon:            Zan, Void ForceDragon Lord:           Mazan, Force BoostHiten:             Zanma, Shock Wave, Force RepelSky Dragon:           Mazanma, Force DrainSky Wizard:            Zandyne, Tempest, Force AmpWind God:            Mazandyne, Force ResistSublime Wind:          Vayaviya  Earth These mantras give your character the ability to cast Tera spells as well as the earth resistance and boost abilities.  List of earth mantras:         Mantra spells: Earth Spirit:            Tera, Void EarthEarth Shrine:           Matera, Earth BoostEarth Temple:           Terazi, Avalanche, Earth RepelEarth Lord:            Materazi, Earth DrainEarth Emperor:           Teradyne, Heavy Rock, Earth AmpMother Earth:           Materadyne, Earth ResistSublime Earth:          Titanomachia  Electric These mantras give your character the ability to cast Zio spells as well as the electric resistance and boost abilities.  List of electric mantras:        Mantra spells: Bolt Wizard:            Zio, Void ElecBolt Lord:            Mazio, Elec BoostLightning:            Zionga, Bolt Flare, Elec RepelBolt Emperor:           Mazionga, Elec DrainBolt Master:            Ziodyne, Jupiter's Fury, Elec AmpBolt God:            Maziodyne, Elec ResistSublime Bolt:          Narukami  Expel These mantras give your character the ability to cast Hama spells as well as resisting the opponents Hama spells.  List of expel mantras:        Mantra spells: Angel:            Hama, Taruda, Void ExpelArchangel:           Mahama, Sukunda, Expel ResistThrones:           Hamaon, Makanda, Makatora, Expel RepelCherubim:           Mahamon, Rakunda, Null ExpelSeraphim:           Xanadu, Dekaja  Death These mantras give your character the ability to cast Mudo spells as well as resisting the opponents Mudo spells.  List of death mantras:        Mantra spells: Yaksa:            Mudo, Curse, Void Death Evil Spirit:           Mamudo, Blood Curse, Stone Gaze, Death ResistDark Spirit:           Mudoon, Wicked Curse, Death RepelDeath:            Mamudoon, Petrifier, Null Death  Almighty These mantras give your character the ability to cast Megido spells, the strongest strongest spells in the game, as well as the strongest resistance spells.  List of almighty mantras:        Mantra spells:Dark Leader:            Megido, Mind ChargeDark Lord:           Megidola, Last WordDark King:            Megidolaon, Magic RepelDark Lord:           Null Element  Heal These mantras give your character the ability to cast Dia spells and revive party members with Recarm.  List of heal mantras:         Mantra spells: Protection:           Dia, Parta, AnalyseFallen Hero:           Media, Posumudi, Achedi, Dream HazeFierce Spirit:           Diarama, Paraladi, Me PatraCalm Spirit:           Mediarama, Closdi, Cursedi, DorminaProgenitor:           Dairahan, PetradiDeath Spirit:           MediarahanVicious God:          Salvation, Auto Soma Hades:            RecarmSix Realms:           SamarecarmWorld:            Recarmdra, Calm Death  Esoteric These mantras are a collection of different types of skills and spells that range from reducing money loss to gaining chakra back from moving.  List of esoteric mantras:        Mantra spells: Esoteric 1:           Mutual KarmaEsoteric 2:           Miser's Spirti Esoteric 3:           Item Find Esoteric 4:           Level GiftEsoteric  5:           Full Banquet, Chakra Walk, MAX CriticalEsoteric 6:           New Banquet, Leech, MIN CriticalEsoteric  7:           Cocytus, Auto-ChakraEsoteric 8:           Null Sleep, Mana Walk  Boss These mantras are obtained by by defeating a specific boss and deliver some of the most powerful abilities.  List of boss mantras:         Mantra spells:          Boss to defeat: Root of Evil:           Spiteful Force, Death Flies       Seth Aksara:            Third Eye, Phys Absorb        Shiva Dragonslayer:          Divine Light, Fire of Sinai        Michael God of Light:          Chaturbhuja, Celestial Ray       Vishnu     Soundtrack   Digital Devil Saga: Avatar Tuner 2 Soundtrack Cover     Digital Devil Saga: Avatar Tuner 2 Soundtrack Song List:  01.     Battle For Survival    02.     Om Mani Padme Hm     03.     Epic Battle     04.     Occupied Sector     05.     Underground City     06.     Coercion    07.     Heroic Battle     08.     Backtracking     09.     Internment Facility     10.     Prison Break     11.    Karma City     12.     Karma Society Tower     13.     Heat's Theme     14.     Madness     15.     EGG Facility     16.     Infiltration     17.     Power Plant     18.     Karma     19.     Inherent Will    20.    EGG Facility Revisited     21.     Hunting - Betrayal     22.     The Bell Tolls     23.     Regret     24.     Airport     25.     The Sun     26.     Enemies Reborn     27.     Divine Identity    28.     One Word     29.     The Rising Sun    30.     Om Mani Padme Hm - Rearrangement</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4822">Wild Arms 3</game><game id="20128">Wild Arms Alter Code: F</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1845420-box_smtdds2.png</image></root>