<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19288</id><name>Mortimer and the Riddles of the Medallion</name><description>Story The player takes control of either SId or Sally, two suburban kids who discover one day that their pets have been turned to stone. Dr. Lazlow, a local mad scientist tells them that the evil Lodius, his ex-apprentice had stolen a magic medallion and used it to steal the powers of animals and turn them into statues. After being used by Lodius to incapacitate many animals, the medallion burst into pieces which were scattered all over the world. Laslow then enlists the help of a giant snail with a high-tech shell and a wacky attitude named Mortimer, and the player's chosen character accompanies Mortimer in his quest to retrieve the medallion pieces, unfreeze the animals, and defeat Lodius one and for all.   Gameplay The game is divided up into four levels: Savanna, Forest, Arctic and Castle. Each zone involves the player piloting Mortimer, "sliming" any enemies that get in his way, restoring animals, and solving riddles about the various real-life creatures native to each climate. The final zone pits the player in a heated battle against Lodius himself, and features a high concentration of riddles to answer.  Theme Song Lyrics Mortimer and the riddles of the medallion  Mortimer and the riddles of the medallion   Mortimer, he is cool. He's a super snail with a hi-tech shell Lodius he is cruel. He is super ugly with a booger breath smell Morimer, he was crushed in a plot by Lodius the evil one Lodius he did fail - Lazlow had Mortimer completely redone  Fly the slimy skies - Mortimer and the riddles of the Medallion  Fly the slimy skies - Mortimer and the riddles of the Medallion       Lazlow has lots of power from an ancient medallion If it's used just for good it protects the world and everyone Lodius wished to rule and so he stole the medallion Animals turned to stone; it looked like Lodius had won  Fly the slimy skies - Mortimer and the riddles of the Medallion     Fly the slimy skies - Mortimer and the riddles of the Medallion    [Bridge] To save the animals you need Mortimer - he's your slimy hot - rod Take a piece of the medallion on your muck - chuckin' super gastropod  Medallion broke in seven - five pieces landed in five different lands Lodius has one piece - but they are all beyond his command If you're smart you will reach his evil castle in the sky You have got just one day - not much time so you'd better fly  Fly the slimy skies - Mortimer and the riddles of the Medallion      Fly the slimy skies - Mortimer and the riddles of the Medallion...     </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="8">Educational</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/4/48594/1278255-mortimerandtheriddlesofthemedallionmac2.jpeg</image></root>