<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>1932</id><name>SSX</name><description>OverviewThe first installment in the popular  SSX franchise and the first game by the now well-known        EA Sports Big. SSX took the success of other snowboarding games such as  Cool Boarders and released it in a new and refreshing approach that, combined with its release on              PS2 launch and superb use of the new system's graphical capabilities, helped it sell incredibly well. SSX put a new spin on extreme sports game by making an already extreme sport even more...extreme. Hundred-foot drops and tricks that require the boarder to take his feet out of the clamps on the board are instant crowd pleasers. Not for the faint of heart.  Gameplay          SSX is an exaggerated take on the snowboarding genre. Players can choose one of eight characters, all with their own boarding styles and statistics. Players can also choose a variety of tracks packed with        ramps, jumps, and rails. These objects, as well as the games' exaggerated tricks, help the player gain boost. Boost can be used to increase speed drastically for a short time, similar to racing games. The tricks the player can pull off range from realistic to ridiculous.   Completing events earns medals, which are used to unlock new characters, boards, courses, and improved abilities for the characters. Characters also have a "trick book" which lists several specific tricks to do while playing. Completing these trick books unlock character costumes. Boarders can opt to choose one of three types of snowboards, all with their own specialties.. They include the all-around "BX" board, trick oriented "Freestyle" board, and the racing board "Alpine." Along with race and competition, SSX includes practice and freeride modes. Characters Mac Fraser Jurgen Angermann JP Arsenault           Mac Fraser  Moby Jones Hiro Karamatsu             Kaori Nishidake        Zoe Payne            Elise Riggs CoursesThe many courses of SSX take place across the world.       Snowdream     ElysiumMerqury City MeltdownMesablanca    Tokyo Megaplex   Aloha Ice JamPipedreamUntracked</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="33">Snowboarding/Skiing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="834">Jonny Moseley Mad Trix</game><game id="20954">Shaun White Snowboarding</game><game id="7128">Cool Boarders 2001</game><game id="9806">EyeToy: AntiGrav</game><game id="5022">Freekstyle</game><game id="21938">ESPN Winter X-Games Snowboarding</game><game id="15277">TransWorld Snowboarding</game><game id="20957">Pure</game><game id="14367">Sled Storm</game><game id="9279">Kelly Slater's Pro Surfer</game><game id="23479">Stoked</game><game id="24305">Snowboard Heaven</game><game id="25097">Shaun Palmer's Pro Snowboarder</game><game id="24449">We Ski &amp; Snowboard</game><game id="5510">X-Games: Pro Boarder</game><game id="20880">We Ski</game><game id="16647">Amped 3</game><game id="15510">Amped 2</game><game id="1509">Amped: Freestyle Snowboarding</game><game id="35516">Winter Stars</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2139874-box_ssx.png</image></root>