<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19371</id><name>Urban Terror</name><description>Overview The enemy stalks to rooftops in 'Kingdom'Usually abbreviated as UrT or UR, Urban Terror is a total conversion mod which stems from id Software's Quake III Arena. Developed by FrozenSand, LLC, (formerly Silicon Ice Development) Urban Terror was originally intended as a map pack for Quake III Arena, but quickly expanded to become a total conversion, introducing team-based and tactical shooter elements as well as realistic environments and maps. Urban Terror Beta 1 was released on August 5th, 2000 at QuakeCon. Its focus on realism and team-driven gameplay inspired a great deal of interest, allowing the development team to quickly expand while including community mappers into the staff. The development team released updates to the game with relative frequency, Beta 2 being released June, 2001. Urban Terror's development ended with version 3.7 in the summer of 2004. While the Silicon Ice Development planned to release a completely new version of Urban Terror, with the aim to raise the game to commercial levels, this project was eventually ceased. Finally, with the availability of the Quake 3 engine as open-source software, Urban Terror version 4 was released in spring 2007, winning the "Mod of the Year" award from game modifications site Mod DB. Urban Terror 4.1 is free of charge, having previously required Quake III Arena in order to install and play. Understanding that the game is free, FrozenSand nonetheless retains the rights to the game making modification and selling of Urban Terror unauthorized. An active Urban Terror community still exists, with competitive leagues and clans operating today. Part of this community consists of different custom maps. Some maps, like icy jumps or woot jumps, are maps that test your jumping skills rather than your shooting skills. They consist of the following skills: jumping, circling, powersliding, and grabbing ledges. You can play in the game modes of Free for All (FFA, DM), Team Deathmatch (TDM), Team Survivor (TS), Capture the Flag (CTF), Capture and Hold (CAH, CH), Follow the Leader (FTL), and Bomb Mode (BM).  Look out for clans as well because if you are good you could join a pro team.Gameplay FeaturesMan downBleedingWhen players take damage there is a chance that the player will begin to bleed. Players must take the time to heal, or be healed by another player so that they do not die from blood loss. Depending on what part of the body is bleeding, they player maybe be penalized with slower movement. If the player is equipped with a med-kit, they can heal teammates back to 80% of full health. Without a med-kit, only 40% of a teammates health can be restored. Players can choose the color of their bandages.Wall JumpingPlayers can press jump while touching a vertical surface to perform a wall jump.  Medics When you are hurt you can heal yourself by pressing q (or the button you set as heal) You can also choose to have a health pac as one of your items, which will allow you to heal other people on your team to full health.Power SlidingAfter gaining speed via sprinting or strafe jumping, the player can hold the crouch key as he touches the ground to perform a 'Power Slide'.Grabbing LedgesIf a ledge is in reach after the player has jumped, the player can hold the forward key to pull themselves up.CirclingCircling is used only when playing on the icy jumps maps. This technique requires you to make an arch so that you can go faster Downloading new Maps When you try to join a map that you have never been to it will ask you to download the map then press enter. After you tell it to download then you will have to wait but it will be worth it. Icy Jumps Icy Jumps 5These are servers that you play at for jumping skill not for shooting.  You have to get as far as possible on these levels.  You will use some of the techniques that you learned previously in this review such as circling and power sliding. There are three Icy Jump servers out at this moment put out by the clan |KSA| Guns This game consists of a total of 13 guns and a knife.1. HK G36 2. Kalashnikov AK103 3. ZM LR300 ML 4. HK 69 5. HK PSG-1 6. Remington SR8 7. IMI Negev 8. M4A1 9. Franchi Spas-12 10. HK Mp5K 11. HK Ump45 12. Beretta 92G 13. .50 Desert Eagle 14. FN-P90 (due out in 4.2)15. Benelli M4 Tactical (due out in 4.2)  Original Maps The game Urban Terror comes with a list of 28 official maps. This is a list of all of the maps that come with the downloaded game.1. Abbey 2. Abbey CTF 3. Algiers 4. Austria 5. Casa 6. Crossing 7. Dressing Room 8. Eagle 9. Elgin - Industrial Terror 10. Firing Range 11. Kingdom 12. Mandolin 13. Mayan Standoff 14. Oildepot 15. Prague 16. Ramelle 17. Riyadh 18. Sanctuary 19. Snoppis 20. Terror in the Suburbs 21. The Bath 22. Thingley 23. Tombs 24. Toxic 25. Tunis 26. Turnpike Terror 27. Uptown 28. Ambush</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3874">Quake III Arena</game><game id="11339">Counter-Strike: Source</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/7900/299112-urban_terror.png</image></root>