<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19596</id><name>Tomb Raider III: Adventures of Lara Croft</name><description>OverviewTomb Raider 3 tells the story of Lara trying to find four meteorite stones, all four of which are in very different parts of the world.FeaturesOne new feature that was introduced in Tomb Raider 3 was having the choice of the order you wished to play some of the levels. After completing the first set of levels set in India, the player was given the choice of traveling to Nevada, the South Pacific, or London before taking on the games last set of levels in Antarctica.It brought new weapons, vehicles and it also had new movements for Lara, such as the monkey bar swing, duck, and dash maneuvers. It also included some new graphical effects like blood visible in water when you got damaged, ripple effects in water caused by shell casings, and smoke emitting from fired guns. The new vehicles include snowmobiles and quad bikes. In Lara's mansion, there is an unlockable quad bike course.WeaponsPistolsShotgunDesert EagleUzisMP5Rocket LauncherGrenade LauncherHarpoonLocationsIndiaThe first levels set in India introduced new enemies like Snakes, Piranhas, and Monkeys, which would sometimes pick up items like health packs if they were left alone. These levels are very much in the style of the original Tomb Raider, while the rest of the game is urban.NevadaLara travels around the deserts of Nevada. She eventually ends up in Area 51, in which the game takes on a science-fiction tone where Lara battles Area 51 security guards and frees prisoners.South Pacific IslandThese levels were inhabited by dinosaurs continuing the theme from previous games, it had the return of Velocoraptors not seen since the original Tomb Raider.LondonLara travels through the streets, rooftops and subways of London. These levels are very vertically oriented.AntarcticaPC RequirementsOS: Windows 95/98/Me/XPProcessor: Pentium 166 (Min.), Pentium 200 (Rec.)4x CD-ROM (Min.)Memory: 16MB RAM (Min.), 32MB (Rec.)Graphics: Direct3D compliant 3D accelerator cardSound: DirectX 6 compatible sound cardMouse  Keyboard.</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7284">Indiana Jones and the Infernal Machine</game><game id="16589">The Mummy Returns</game><game id="13288">Barbie Explorer</game><game id="39082">Tomb Raider: The Golden Mask</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1810972-box_traider3.png</image></root>