<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19621</id><name>Ys: The Ark of Napishtim</name><description>OverviewYs: The Ark of Napishtim was originally developed for the PC in 2003, and was later ported to the PlayStation 2 and PSP systems in 2005 and 2006, respectively. Ys protagonist Adol Christin is stranded on a mysterious island and begins his adventure by journeying into the Great Vortex of Canaan.CharactersAdol Christin: A red-hair adventurer, not surprisingly known as Adol the Red. He's traveling with his close friend Dogi when he finds himself on a pirate ship, heading towards the Great Vortex of Canaan, which is found on the edge of the great ocean.Olha: A Rehdan priestess with long ears and an animal-like furry tail. She is responsible for guiding her tribe, and ends up healing Adol after he is swallowed up by the Great Vortex.Isha: Olha's younger sister. Extremely shy, especially around Adol.Terra: Member of a pirate gang from Xandia, as well as the daughter of the pirate Ladoc.Geis: A mercenary that wields a huge halberd. Adol and him cross paths many times during Ys: The Ark of Napishtim.Ernst: A young, cool-headed war commander serving under Admiral Agares. He pursues Adol and the pirate ship he's on--the Tres Mares--into the Great Vortex.WeaponsThe only weapons in this Ys game (other than the starting sword...which breaks) are three Emelas swords, all of which are important to the game's story:Livart: a single-edged sword with the power of wind. Average strength, speed, and has tornado magic.Blirante: a double-edged sword with the power of fire. The strongest of the three Emelas swords, but slow and has firewall-like magic.Ericcil: a rapier with the power of lightning. The weakest, but fastest sword, with homing lightning bolt magic.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21108">Star Ocean: First Departure</game><game id="620">Star Ocean: The Second Story</game><game id="21464">Star Ocean:  Second Evolution</game><game id="21237">Tales of Symphonia</game><game id="1335">Tales of Destiny</game><game id="11703">Tales of Rebirth</game><game id="2889">Valkyrie Profile 2: Silmeria</game><game id="11602">Valkyrie Profile</game><game id="21460">Gurumin: A Monstrous Adventure</game><game id="21848">Final Fantasy Type-0</game><game id="7916">Willow</game><game id="10983">Kingdom Hearts</game><game id="5056">Phantasy Star Universe</game><game id="2361">Crisis Core: Final Fantasy VII</game><game id="28142">Chantelise</game><game id="12945">Lagoon</game><game id="29104">Mimana Iyar Chronicle</game><game id="3247">Untold Legends: Brotherhood of the Blade</game><game id="2603">Untold Legends: The Warrior's Code</game><game id="21636">Dungeon Explorer: Warriors of Ancient Art</game><game id="30419">Tales of Phantasia: Narikiri Dungeon X</game><game id="14694">Threads of Fate</game><game id="31372">Jikandia: The Timeless Land</game><game id="32155">Recettear: An Item Shop's Tale</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2100009-box_ys6.png</image></root>