<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19709</id><name>Realms of Arkania: Blade of Destiny</name><description>OverviewRealms of Arkania: Blade of Destiny is a role-playing game developed by      Attic Entertainment Software, and it is based off of the German Pen  Paper RPG system "Das Schwarze Auge", developed by     Fantasy Productions. The original version of the game was out in stores in 1992, but given its commercial success, it was later translated to English and given an international release in 1993.Story Realms of Arkania: Blade of Destiny takes place in a typical fantasy world.Humankind is suddenly in danger as an Orc chieftain manages to unite all Orc tribes and is planning to attack the Human territories. The player's character is then hired by the leader of the Thorwalians to find the Grimring, also known as the Blade of Destiny, which would ultimately help prevent the Orc invasion on the land of Thorwal. However, this powerful magical sword has of course been missing for an what seems to be an eternity and in order to recover it, the player must go out into the world and find all the pieces of a lost treasure map showing its location. However, if the player fails to succeed in finding the Blade in two (in-game) years, the Orcs will attack the Humans and its game over.But should the player succeed in finally finding the sword, they then needs to defeat the Orc chieftain and his minions in a final battle for survival.GameplayRealms of Arkania: Blade of Destiny has the player going through towns and dungeons in a 3D first-person perspective. However, whenever the player engages in combat with any of the enemies he may find throughout the game world, the game automatically switches the camera to an   isometric viewpoint and the game gives way to a    tactical turn-based combat setting.PC System requirementsOperating System: DOS 4.0Processor: Intel 80286RAM Memory: 640 KBHard Drive Space: 9 MBVideo Card: VGA AvailabilityRealms of Arkania: Blade of Destiny is available for purchase at        gog.com.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/11/117587/1659633-rak1.jpg</image></root>