<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19801</id><name>Mega Man X2</name><description>OverviewThe Maverick war continues as X is once again faced with the relentless threat of Sigma. The game begins with X and Zero exploring an old reploid factory that was previously thought abandoned only to find that it is busily working away at creating an army of Mavericks. Released in 1995, this game uses the same graphics engine as Mega Man X, but the developers included an in-cartridge Cx4 chip, which allowed for some primitive 3D visuals. Known in Japan as Rockman X2: Versus Counter-Hunters, this game was produced by Tokuro Fujiwara, with character designs by Keiji Inafune, and a soundtrack by Yuki Iwai.GameplayThe gameplay isn't too different from the previous game, with the notable exception of X having the dash ability from the start. The basic Mega Man gameplay is here, relying on fast reflexes and some pattern memorization to best your Maverick foes. Every level consists of one boss and sometimes a mini-boss around half-way through the level. The game is very linear like its namesake, with plenty of death traps in each unique environment. The difficulty, however, is slightly more balanced to suit newcomers than the first game.Boss Robots (Mavericks)These are the Maverick bosses X faces throughout his second adventure, listed in order with weapons and weaknesses.Boss selectionBoss - Wire Sponge Weapon - Strike ChainPower - 6400rpSpeed - 4800rpWeakness - Sonic SlicerLocation - Weather controlBoss - Wheel GatorWeapon - Spin WheelPower - 9800rpSpeed - 1800rpWeakness - Strike ChainLocation - Dinosaur TankBoss - Bubble CrabWeapon - Bubble SplashPower - 6000rpSpeed - 4800rpWeakness - Spin WheelLocation - Deep-Sea BaseBoss - Flame StagWeapon - Speed BurnerPower - 3600rpSpeed - 7000rpWeakness - Splash BubbleLocation - Volcanic ZoneBoss - Morph MothWeapon - Silk ShotPower - 3200rpSpeed - 8800rpWeakness - Speed BurnerLocation - Robot JunkyardBoss - Magna CentipedeWeapon-Magnet MinePower-2900rpSpeed-8880rpWeakness-Silk ShotLocation - Central ComputerBoss - Crystal SnailWeapon - Crystal HunterPower - 6800rpSpeed - 500rpWeakness - Magnet MineLocation - Energen CrystalBoss - Overdrive OstrichWeapon - Sonic SlicerPower - 3800rpSpeed - 9900rpWeakness - Crystal HunterLocation - Desert BaseUpgradesHelmet CapsuleStrewn throughout the various stages are blue upgrade capsules, placed by X's creator, Dr. Light. In each, there is an upgrade to X's armor, most of which are nearly essential in the defeat of Sigma. Listed here are the upgrades, their locations, and the requirements to reach them.Helmet(No item required)- Gives X the ability to see which tiles hold secrets (uses weapon energy).Location - Crystal Snail stageArmor(S.Wheel required)- Gives X the series' first ultra attack, which decimates all enemies on screen, and takes time to recharge.Location - Morph Moth stageBoots(S.Wheel required)- Gives X the ability to dash in the air.Location - Overdrive Ostrich stageGun(Boots upgrade required)- Gives X the ability to charge his buster in both arms, allowing him to fire one and store another for instant use.Location - Wheel Gator stageHidden MoveIn addition to the four base upgrades, X can receive the Street Fighter series' iconic Shoryuken uppercut move, which takes out most bosses in an instant.Location - Sigma's Fortress (via a long-winded method, all items/powerups must be collected beforehand)To execute Shoryuken: right, down, down-right, buster up (at full HP)SoundtrackCover ArtIn 2005 Capcom released a 5-disc box set called Capcom Music Generation Rockman X1~6. It contains the original music of Mega Man X through Mega Man X6 as well as some unused tracks. Mega Man X2 tracks span the second half of disc 1 and the tracks are as followed:Track #TitleLength36.CAPCOM LOGO0:0637.OPENING1:0038.TITLE0:1939.PASS WORD0:2340.OPENING STAGE1:2541.ANOTHER BOSS 10:1742.ANOTHER BOSS 20:3843.DEMO0:3144.STAGE SELECT 10:2545.STAGE START0:0846.WIRE HETIMARL STAGE2:0147.METAMOR MOTHMEANOS STAGE1:5048.FLAME STAGGER STAGE1:3449.MAGNE HYAKULEGGER STAGE1:3650.SONIC OSTREAGUE STAGE1:3451.BUBBLY CRABLOS STAGE1:5252.WHEEL ALLIGATES STAGE1:0753.CRISTAR MYMINE STAGE1:3954.BOSS 10:1755.BOSS 21:0256.STAGE CLEAR0:0757.STAGE SELECT 21:0558.COUNTER HUNTER STAGE 11:0659.COUNTER HUNTER STAGE 21:0360.ZERO0:3861.SIGMA 1st0:3462.SIGMA 2nd0:5063.DR.RIGHT0:2764.ENDING1:5365.STAFF ROLL1:15</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8292">Super Metroid</game><game id="21761">Metroid</game><game id="5708">Metroid II: Return of Samus</game><game id="10323">Metroid Fusion</game><game id="17356">Metroid: Zero Mission</game><game id="15473">Metroid Prime</game><game id="4725">Metroid Prime 3: Corruption</game><game id="6215">Metroid Prime: Hunters</game><game id="3228">Spider-Man</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2363968-snes_megamanx2.jpg</image></root>