<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19809</id><name>Project Gotham Racing 3</name><description>OverviewProject Gotham Racing 3 or PGR3 was one of the launch titles on the  Xbox 360. As the name suggests it's the third in the series. PGR3 is an arcade-style racing game and features over 90 licensed cars from 30 different manufacturers. Manufacturers include, Dodge, Ford, McLaren, Ferrari and Lamborghini and many many more. As the cars are licensed it gives the game a look and feel of the real thing. The tracks of PGR3 improve on that of it's predecessors whereby they give a stream less horizon so drivers can see the road ahead without having to wait for graphics to load as they drive.  PGR3  Las Vegas,  London,  New York,  Tokyo, and the ever popular  Nürburgring in  Germany. Unlike other racing games, PGR3 is about pure racing and damage to cars is only visual and basic at that. PGR3 uses genuine engine sounds which were recorded in studios, which makes the game sound as realistic as it looks.CareerThe career modes in PGR3 are two way, there is an offline mode which pits players against AI drivers and an online career against other players from around the world over Xbox Live. Both careers earn players Kudos and credits for winning races and various events. In the offline career mode there are various difficulty levels from Easy to Platinum with the latter earning drivers more credits.Gotham TVPart of the Online career or online multiplayer, Gotham TV is a unique system which allows players not racing to view players race around. The Gotham Heroes TV channel features some of the best racers on the game and can be viewed by anyone. Gotham TV also allows you to save replays of races and view them which you can then take screenshots in.Screenshot taken in-game ScreenshotsDuring offline play or after an online race players can take screen shots of the race action rotating the Camera,Zooming, Panning, Spinning and adding simple effects to images that one takes. This feature can then allow screenshots to be downloaded from the PGR3 screenshot website, although the amount at any one time is limited. KudosAkin to it's prequels PGR3 sticks with the Kudos points system. This system allows players to gain credits by preforming stunts in-race such as drifting or drafting (tailing another car). These credits however are not which allow players to buy cars which is seen in the previous PGR games. However race wins earn players valuable credits which and be put towards the many cars up for sale in the PGR catalogue. Each car in PGR3 is allocated to a specific class depending on it's performance ability. There are five classes, A through E, the high performance cars being Class A, and the low performance cars in Class E.MultiplayerOnline play in PRG3 features a variety of race modes apart from the normal street race. Street race can be preformed in lap form or in a stretched version which involves racing from point A to point B. Other modes include Cat and Mouse which sees two teams attempting to prevent the "Mouse" which is in a slower car to the "Cat" from crossing the line before their own Mouse does. Eliminator is good old fashioned racing where the last to cross the line after each lap is eliminated. Cone Capture pits players against each other in seeing who can capture the most cones on a course in a certain time. Capture the track in another mode in which teams must produce the fastest times in a sector of a track to "Capture" that section, the most sections wins. Most of these modes are seen throughout the single career.TournamentsPGR3 allows players to qualify for tournaments by racing on a certain track and attempting to have the quickest time. Players with the quickest time will then enter into the tournaments. Sponsored tournaments feature cash prizes.  Track ListLas VegasBig Apple LoopFlamingo Straits Buccaneer Loop Tropicana Tour Spring Mountain TurnsSouth Strip Loop Las Vegas BLVD Tour Boulevard Straits Short RunNorth Vegas Run South Vegas Run The Grand Run      LondonWorth  Walker Street  The Birdcage Embankment Rush Whitehall Straits The Bulldog The Old City Loop Westminster Tour Trafalgar TourDown the Mall Thornbury CornerOld City EastSt James ParkNew YorkWorth  Walker StreetBroadway Run City Hall Park The Outskirts Park Row Brooklyn Bridge StraitThe Bridge Tour Park to Tillary Center  Broadway Foley Square LoopWhite Street Bends Chapel Street Corner NürburgringHalf F1 CircuitFull F1 Circuit Nordschleife Nordschleife Long The BehemothSchwedenkreuz WippermannFuchsröhreSchwalbenschwanzKlostertalMetzgesfeldAntoniousbuche Pflanzgarten LongTokyoShinjuku Kabukicho Loop Tochomae LoopThe Good Tomorrow Ekimae LoopBark to the SunNishiguchi SpeedwayShinjuku SpeedwayShinjuku SkyscraperOdeo Chase The Triangle Building Shinjuku Tour Crazy Turns Car List *(style) denotes this car was released in the 'style' content pack.*(speed) denotes this car was released in the 'speed' content pack. *(caddy) denotes this car was released in the 'caddy' content pack. ArielAriel Atom 2 Supercharged Aston MartinAston Martin DB9 Aston Martin DBR9 Aston Martin V8 Vantage *(speed)    Audi   Audi RS 4 *(speed)  BentleyBentley Continental GT   BMW  BMW M6 *(style)BMW Z8 *(style)BMW M3 CSL *(style)BMW Mini Cooper S *(style)CadillacCadillac Sixteen Cadillac CTS-V *(caddy)Cadillac XLR-V *(caddy)Cadillac STS-V *(caddy)CallawayCallaway C7 Sledgehammer Twin Turbo ChevroletChevrolet Corvette C6 Chevrolet Corvette ZR-1 Chevrolet Corvette Z06 *(speed)  Chrysler   2005 Chrysler Firepower Concept *(style)DodgeDodge Viper GTS ACR Dodge Viper SRT-10 Dodge Viper SRT-10 Carbon Dodge Viper SRT-10 Coupe *(speed)ElfinMS8 Streamliner FarboudGTS FerrariFerrari 360 Challenge Stradale Ferrari 575M Maranello Ferrari Enzo Ferrari F355 GTS Ferrari F355 F1 BerlinettaFerrari F40 Ferrari F430 Ferrari F50 Ferrari F50 GT Ferrari GTO Evoluzione Ferrari Testarosssa Ferrari 612 Scaglietti *(speed)Ferrari 365 GTB4 "Daytona" *(style)Ferrari 430 Challenge *(style)FordFord SVT Mustang Cobra R Ford GT Ford GT40 MK-II   Gumpert  Gumpert Apollo Coupe 4.2 V8 *(style)JaguarJaguar XJ220 Jaguar XKR JossJoss Supercar HondaHonda NSX GT1 Turbo(street Version) KoenigseggKoenigsegg CCV8S Koenigsegg CCRLamborghiniLamborghini Countach 25th AnniversaryLamborghini Diablo VT 6.0 Lamborghini Diablo GT Lamborghini Gallardo Lamborghini Gallardo SE *(speed)Lamborghini Miura P400 S Lamborghini Murcielago Lamborghini Murcielago R-GTLamborghini Countach LP500 QV LotusLotus Elise GT1 Lotus Esprit MaseratiMaserati GranSport Maserati MC12 McLarenMcLaren F1 LM Mercedes-BenzMercedes-Benz CLK-GTR Mercedes-Benz SLR Mclaren Mercedes-Benz CLK DTM AMG *(style)MGMG XPower SR-V   Mitsubishi      Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution VIII FQ-400 *(speed)NissanNissan Skyline GT-R34 Nissan R390 GT1 Nissan NISMO R34GT-R Z-Tune *(speed)NobleNoble M400 Noble M14 Palmer SportJP1 PaganiPagani Zonda C12-S 7.3 Roadster Pagani Zonda F *(style)PanozPanoz Esperante GTLM Esperante GTR1 (street version)   Pontiac   Pontiac GTORadicalRadical SR3 Turbo  Radical SR8 *(speed)RUFRUF CTR RUF CTR Yellow Bird RUF CTR 2 RUF R Turbo RUF RT12 Turbo RUF RT12 *(speed)RUF R.K. Spyder *(style)SaleenSaleen S281 Saleen S7 Saleen S7 Twin Turbo *(speed)SpykerSpyker C8 Double 12 S ShelbyFord Shelby Cobra GT500 ToyotaToyota GT-One TVRTVR Sagaris TVR Typhon TVR Cerbera Speed 12 TVR T350T TVR Tuscan MK 2 Targa  UltimaUltima GTR Unique PerformanceShelby Mustang GT-500E   Vanwall   Vanwall GPR V12 *(style)   VolkswagenVolkswagen W12 Coupe (Nardo) WiesmannWiesmann GT     Downloadable ContentBizarre Creations supported Project Gotham 3 with quite a bit of downloadable content, both free and paid. 3 official content packs were released within a four month span. Dubbed the (in order of release) 'speed', 'caddy' and 'style' packs, all contained new cars for use in single player and multiplayer and in the case of both the speed and style packs -- game updates and modes. The caddy content pack was released for free (to Xbox Live Gold subscribers) and included 3 Cadillac 'V-Series' cars and a chance to win a gamer picture if the player is able to set a top 100 time using one of the 3 cars included in the pack.SoundtrackBloc Party - Helicopter  Death Cab for Cutie - Photobooth Death from above 1979 - Black History Month Gratitude - Drive Away Hot Hot Heat - Island of the Honest Man Less than Jake - Bridge And Tunnel Authority Louis XIV - God Killed the Queen Morrissey - I Like You The Futureheads - Trying not to think about time The Kills - The Good Ones The Presidents of the United States of America - Poke and Destroy Ammoncontact - My People Chops - Git That Muther C-mone - Stan Bac Def Tex - What the? DPF -Yadda Yadda Hexstatic - Distorted Minds Kool Keith - G.A.M.E. Lordikim - Sleep Pest - Dr Umz Styly Cee feat The Anthroplogist - One under the Sun The Numbs - The Art The Streets - Could well be in Wordsmith - Nomad (Caruana Remix)  Alpinestars  - Carbon Kid Atlas Plug - The Ace, The Only Audio Bullys - Real Life Crush - Consciousness Dirty Vegas - A Million Ways LCD Soundsystem - Tribulations Lunatex - Crawl New Order - Krafty Phontaine - One more day Radio 4 - Party Crashers Robert Miles - Improvisations P.2. The Chemical Brothers - The Big Jump Crazy Anglos - Fade Dark New Day - Brother Head Automatica - Beating Heart Baby Mastodon - Blood and Thunder Queens of the Stone Age - Little Sister Secret Machines - Better Bring Your Friends Skindred - Pressure Staind - Right Here The Used - I Caught Fire Thornley - Come again Unwritten Law - Get Up 2Backka - Sky Daichi Miura - No Limit DALLAX - Bring Down Your Hope DALLAX - Twenty Junk Rock IngaLand - IngaLand is Dead IngaLand - Rotten Works NORA - Seaside Walk NORA - Zig Zing The Local Art - Klaxon The Local Art - No Reason 30Hz - No Mans land Aphex Twin - Come to Daddy (Pappy Mix) Auto Aggression - Das Nyquist Theorem Faetal - Phosphor Sky Micronaut - Perdition Mind.in.a.box - Walking Mindless Faith - Singular Orbital - Tunnel Vision Squarepusher - Menelec Stromkern - Stand Up (extended mix) Trash Palace - Animal Magic  Celldweller - Switchback  Covenant - 20Hz Deadstar Assembly - All You Ever Wanted Deathboy - Black Morning Firewerk - Without a Sound Flesh Field - Haven Freak XXI - Zero Goteki - Shinjuku Lullaby Psychophile - All in the Mind Skinny Puppy - Past Present Static X - Start a War  Achanak - Lak Noo Hala De  Achanak - Maar Sutia Dhamaal Soundsystem - Bol Breaker Echotwist - Frankies Next Move Jasbir Jassi - Hauli Hauli Jasbir Jassi - Putt Jattaan Daa Karsh Kale - One Step Beyond MIDIval PunditZ - Bhanga Fever (Heavy Nitro Remix) MIDIval PunditZ - Kesariya Tigerstyle - Akh mastani Tigerstyle - Boliyan Tigerstyle - Maan doabe da Beethoven - Allegro con brio - Symphony No. 7 in A major Brahms - Allegro Giocoso - Poco meno Presto from Symphony No. 4 in E minor Rimsky Korsakov - Danse des bouffons (Dance of the Clowns) - Snow Maiden Suite Tchaikovsky - Finale: Allegro con fuoco - Symphony No. 4 in F minor Liszt - Hungarian Attack March Bach - III. Allegro - Brandenburg Concerto No. 3 in G major Mozart - Molto allegro - Symphony No. 40 in G minor Mussorgsky - Night on the Bare Mountain Verdi - Requiem - Dies Irae Tchaikovsky - Mazeppa: The Battle at PoltavaXbox 360 Game Installation/DownloadsProject Gotham Racing 3 requires 6.2GB of space to install on an Xbox 360  HDD. PGR3 features car downloads ranging from 50mb to 150mb for single cars or packs. </description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20729">GRID</game><game id="5881">Forza Motorsport 2</game><game id="17599">Forza Motorsport</game><game id="18095">Need for Speed: ProStreet</game><game id="8844">Need for Speed: Carbon</game><game id="20597">Gran Turismo 5 Prologue</game><game id="788">The Fast and the Furious</game><game id="11055">NASCAR 08</game><game id="20038">NASCAR: Dirt to Daytona</game><game id="589">R:Racing Evolution</game><game id="2416">Gran Turismo</game><game id="17784">Gran Turismo 4</game><game id="12950">Gran Turismo 3 A-Spec</game><game id="8100">Gran Turismo 2</game><game id="21297">Gran Turismo HD</game><game id="7482">Gran Turismo Concept: 2001 Tokyo</game><game id="21390">Gran Turismo Concept: 2002 Tokyo-Seoul</game><game id="7313">Gran Turismo Concept: 2002 Tokyo-Geneva</game><game id="13895">Gran Turismo 4: Prologue</game><game id="12976">Need for Speed: Most Wanted</game><game id="20741">Need for Speed: Undercover</game><game id="9651">Need for Speed Underground 2</game><game id="12254">Need for Speed Underground</game><game id="8831">Need for Speed: Porsche Unleashed</game><game id="12395">Need for Speed: Hot Pursuit 2</game><game id="5977">Need for Speed III: Hot Pursuit</game><game id="453">Need for Speed: High Stakes</game><game id="18021">Need for Speed: Carbon - Own the City</game><game id="367">Need for Speed II</game><game id="9927">SRS: Street Racing Syndicate</game><game id="10124">Midnight Club: Street Racing</game><game id="20927">Midnight Club: Los Angeles</game><game id="21114">Midnight Club: Los Angeles Remix</game><game id="20418">Midnight Club II</game><game id="5875">Midnight Club 3: DUB Edition</game><game id="6499">RalliSport Challenge 2</game><game id="8437">TOCA 2: Touring Car Challenge</game><game id="7019">Ridge Racer V</game><game id="8779">Sega GT 2002</game><game id="14428">Sega GT Online</game><game id="15965">Sega GT</game><game id="16276">Ford Bold Moves Street Racing</game><game id="20919">Ford Racing: Off Road</game><game id="7431">Ford Racing</game><game id="7777">Juiced</game><game id="284">NASCAR 2005: Chase for the Cup</game><game id="17872">TOCA Race Driver 3 Challenge</game><game id="18777">The Club</game><game id="16882">Running Wild</game><game id="24866">OutRun Online Arcade</game><game id="22693">RACE Pro</game><game id="25254">Roadsters</game><game id="24995">Forza Motorsport 3</game><game id="25225">Need for Speed: SHIFT</game><game id="25961">Blur</game><game id="11445">Need for Speed: Most Wanted 5-1-0</game><game id="24513">DiRT 2</game><game id="2453">R4 Ridge Racer Type 4</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2213167-box_pgr3.png</image></root>