<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19845</id><name>Crusader Kings</name><description>Gameplay  The Gameplay Map     Broadly, Crusader Kings resembles the other games in the        EU series. It's a real time empire management game, set on a parceled out boardgame map showing political and geographical detail. The first major difference is that this game is limited entirely to       Europe, Northern      Africa, and the near     Middle East. The second difference is the game's focus on dynasty type gameplay.  Dynasties   Family Tree    Unlike other games in the series, where you control a nation, in Crusader Kings you control the patriarch of a family, and the basest level of management is managing your family. You have to arrange strategic marriages for your children, appoint capable and loyal members of your family to key positions in your empire, and manage the education of the children to expand your family's control and influence over Europe.   Feudalism A unique aspect of this game's empire management is that you can only directly control a handful of provinces, the number of which is tied to the skills of your patriarch. The rest of your territory has to be administered by vassals. You can also play as a vassal to another empire. Your current rank dictates what kind of vassals you can appoint. The chain of command is as follows: KingDukeBishopCount Religion As you might guess from the title, much of the conflict in Crusader Kings revolves around the push and pull of Muslim and Christian empires in the Middle Ages. In this game, the pope has far reaching powers, including the power to call crusades which you must answer at the risk of your prestige, and the ability to excommunicate rulers. In un-modded Crusader Kings, you can only play as a Christian family, although the AI islamic factions operate in much the same way.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16084">Europa Universalis III</game><game id="2875">Knights of Honor</game><game id="21645">Europa Universalis: Rome</game><game id="8349">Hearts of Iron</game><game id="4866">Hearts of Iron II</game><game id="23460">Hearts of Iron III</game><game id="18049">Victoria: An Empire Under the Sun</game><game id="32847">Europa Universalis III: Divine Wind</game><game id="36365">Sengoku</game><game id="15601">Svea Rike</game><game id="39594">March of the Eagles</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/5/58746/1217221-crusader_kings_coverart.png</image></root>