<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19887</id><name>Rome: Total War</name><description>OverviewRome: Total War is the first in the series to feature fully polygonal real-time battlesRome: Total War is a critically-acclaimed historical strategy game by British developers The Creative Assembly. It was originally released for PC on September 22nd, 2004. Although initially published by Activision, later versions of the game have been released by Sega, who acquired The Creative Assembly after Rome's release. A version was released for Mac OS X by Feral Interactive in 2010.Like its predecessors Shogun: Total War and Medieval: Total War, Rome: Total War features a unique combination of turn-based empire management and real-time battles. It is the first game in the series to use a fully polygonal engine, replacing the 2D sprites of Shogun and Medieval with fully animated 3D models.The main campaign sees the player take charge of one of three great Roman houses — the Julii, the Scipii and the Brutii — with the goal of siezing the Republic and forging an Empire. After completing the campaign, other factions are unlocked for use. Factions can also be unlocked by destroying them in the campaign.GameplaySiege warfare has been greatly expanded in Rome: Total WarAs with previous Total War games, the primary objective is to raise large armies to conquer provinces and cities which will grant you income from taxes and allows you to expand your empire. The ultimate objective is to capture 50 provinces and control Rome itself, though this can be reduced through the option of a shorter campaign. The player begins the campaign by choosing one of three Roman factions — the Julii, the Scipii or the Brutii. It is also possible to unlock more factions by defeating them campaign, allowing for a greater variety of gameplay.Rome Total War's multiplayer has been the subject of some criticism. Some players consider many of the units to be overpowered, meaning that even the faction you pick before the game even begins may determine the outcome of the fight.CampaignRome introduces the free movement of armies within territories, adding a further layer of strategy to the campaign mapThe main element of the single player experience, the campaign allows the player to have complete control over the political, social, economic, and military elements of one of the 19 (not include the rebels) factions in the game. Each of the factions represent a different empire or political bloc from the ancient world.There are two types of campaign. The short campaign requires the player to capture 15 cities and destroy a designated faction. The longer campaign requires the player to take over Rome and occupying a total of 50 cities.For the first play through of the campaign, players must choose to be one of the three Roman factions. However, over time other factions will be unlocked as the player conquers the other groups with the Roman factions and all playable factions will be unlock when the player finishes the campaign. Certain factions can never be unlocked, but simple modification of game files have allow them to be playable.Family MembersEvery faction in the game owns family members that rule your settlements and your army in battle. You start the game with some family members and during the game-play you get more by birth or marriage your daughters to other noble men.The family members along with diplomats, spies and assassin's die in time but you recruit or you get more during the game.Male family members have 3 major statistics:Influence: Important to keep the public order in your settlements . If your family member does not have influence then there is a chance for the people to revolt.Management: Management take care of the settlement's economy. The more management your family members have, the more profit you gain.Command: Command is based on how good your family member is in case of combat and how good is he to command your troops especially when you decide to automatically resolve the battle.Each faction has a faction leader and an heir, and those are the one that rule your faction. In case of combat you lose both the faction leader and faction heir then you automatically lose the game. Also the faction leader and faction heir gain more stats that of a common family member.The family members gain traits from academies, temples and from events that happens during the gameplay .Some traits are giving positive stats to your family members and some of them negative which sometimes it turns dangerous for your settlement's stability.DiplomatsThe diplomats are very important units in the game.They are the ones that arrange your trade with other factions alliances or even enemies.You can obtain map information if the other faction agrees.Also you can bribe an enemy army or family member and if you have the money and they are the same units with your faction army , they can join you.SpiesAnother important non-combat unit is the spy. The spies inflitrate to enemy settlements or armies. That way you can see what buildings or units the enemy settlement have so you can prepare your attack or defence. You can also see the population of the enemy settlement the currency or even the family members traits and stats.You can also use the spies to find armies that are ready to ambush and also to find enemy assassins.If you send to many spies into one settlement then the public order of that settlement is reducing and in many cases they rioting.Also if you keep to many spies in your settlement then you make it hard for enemy spies to enter your city and get information.AssassinsThe assassin's duty is simple but important.You either send him to sabotage the enemy buildings and in that case you delay the enemy to train more units or even lose public order and money from trade. Otherwise you can use the assassin to kill family members, diplomats, other assassins or if his rank is high, spies.Naval CombatPorts can be build in regions with a coastline. Building a port allows the region to make use of naval trade routes, which are one of the most lucrative sources of income, and allows the recruitment of Warships. More developed ports can recruit better Warships and support more trade routes.Warships serve many roles. They can be used to protect a port, or besiege an enemy's. They can raid enemy trade routes, cutting off a vital supply of income. Troops and agents can be transported by sea using a fleet. Warships can also engage in combat with enemy warships, although naval battles can only be resolved automatically by the AI. Like infantry units, warships gain experience as they engage in combat.Quick BattleThe player has the ability to jump right into a quick and random battle with this mode. Unlike the Custom Battle where the player can choose their faction and units, in this mode the player can be evenly matched, have an advantage, or be at a disadvantage. The battlefield can also range from cities and towns to open fields and mountains.Custom BattleIf the player wishes to jump right into the tactical combat element of the game they can do so by playing a Custom Battle. In this mode the player has the ability to join a custom battle in which they select an available faction and particular units for themselves as well as their computer opponent.Historical BattlePlayers also have the ability to participate in some of the greatest battles in the ancient world such as the Battle of Lake Trasimene and The Battle of Carrhae. Unlike the custom battle, players do not have control of choosing their units as the scenarios maintain some historical accuracy.FactionsHouse of JuliiCultureRomanStarting LocationNorthern Italy (Ariminium and Arretium)PlayableYesThe Julii faction is based on the family of Roman general and statesman Gaius Julius Ceasar who led the conquest of Gaul. Upon his return, Ceasar dragged Rome into a civil war, paving the way for the transition from Roman Republic to Roman Empire. The Julii are positioned to the north of Italy, making Gaul a ripe target for expansion. Their unique units include the Urban Cohort, the most powerful infantry unit in the game, and the Samnite Gladiators.The backbone of the Roman army are the legionnaires, incredibly versatile heavy infantry. Romans can also make use of advanced siege weaponry. The Roman factions are unique in that after the construction of an imperial palace their unit roster completely changes — this is justified as the Marian reforms being implemented. Each Roman faction has a unique gladiator unit available to them.InfantryPeasants, Town Watch, Auxilia, Triarii, Hastati, Principes, Early Legionary Cohort, Legionary Cohort, Praetorian Cohort, Urban Cohort, Samnite Gladiators, ArcaniCavalryEquites, Roman Cavalry, Legionary Cavalry, Praetorian Cavalry, General's Bodyguard, Cavalry AuxiliaSupportRoman Archers, Archer Auxilia, Velites, Light AuxiliaSiegeBallistas, Repeating Ballistas, Scorpions, Onagers, Heavy OnagersOtherIncendiary Pigs, WardogsHouse of ScipiiCultureRomanStarting LocationCentral Italy (Capua) and Sicily (Messana)PlayableYesThe Scipii faction is based on a Roman family which included the general Scipio Africanus who defeated Hannibal at the final battle of the third and final Punic War and the senator and general Scipio Aemilianus who led the destruction of Carthage.The Scipii have a very similar army structure to the Houses of Julii and Brutii.InfantryPeasants, Town Watch, Auxilia, Triarii, Hastati, Principes, Early Legionary Cohort, Legionary Cohort, Praetorian Cohort, Urban Cohort, Murmillo Gladiators, ArcaniCavalryEquites, Roman Cavalry, Legionary Cavalry, Praetorian Cavalry, General's Bodyguard, Cavalry AuxiliaSupportRoman Archers, Archer Auxilia, Velites, Light AuxiliaSiegeBallistas, Repeating Ballistas, Scorpions, Onagers, Heavy OnagersOtherIncendiary Pigs, WardogsBrutiiCultureRomanStarting LocationSoutheastern Italy (Tarentum and Croton)PlayableYesThe Brutii were a family in ancient Rome that included a number of famous figures including the Roman politician Brutus, most famous for his prominent part of the assassination of Julius Caesar.The Brutii also have a very similar army structure to the Houses of Julii and Scipii.InfantryPeasants, Town Watch, Auxilia, Triarii, Hastati, Principes, Early Legionary Cohort, Legionary Cohort, Praetorian Cohort, Urban Cohort, Velite Gladiators, ArcaniCavalryEquites, Roman Cavalry, Legionary Cavalry, Praetorian Cavalry, General's Bodyguard, Cavalry AuxiliaSupportRoman Archers, Archer Auxilia, Velites, Light AuxiliaSiegeBallistas, Repeating Ballistas, Scorpions, Onagers, Heavy OnagersOtherIncendiary Pigs, WardogsSPQRCultureRomanStarting LocationCentral Italy (Rome)PlayableNoS.P.Q.R. stands for the senate and the people and Rome (Senatus populus que Romanus). It was the capital of Rome, the house of the senates and their Caesars. From there the Roman Empire was controlled.InfantryPeasants, Town Watch, Auxilia, Triarii, Hastati, Principes, Early Legionary Cohort, Legionary Cohort, Praetorian Cohort, Urban CohortCavalryEquites, Roman Cavalry, Legionary Cavalry, Praetorian Cavalry, General's Bodyguard, Cavalry AuxiliaSupportRoman Archers, Archer Auxilia, Velites, Light AuxiliaSiegeBallistas, Repeating Ballistas, Scorpions, Onagers, Heavy OnagersOtherIncendiary Pigs, WardogsGermaniaCultureBarbarianStarting LocationDamme, Mogontiacum, Trier (Capital), Batavordum and Vicus MarcomanniPlayableYes (unlockable)Germania is actually the Latin word for the area of land on the east bank of the Rhine. However this region historically was occupied by many different tribes, not all of which were Germanic, so there was no single cohesive faction that existed in the days of Ancient Rome.InfantryPeasents, Screeching Women, Berserkers, Naked Fanatics, Axemen, Night Raiders, Spear Warband, Chosen AxemenCavalryBarbarian Cavalry, Barbarian Noble Cavalry, Gothic Cavalry, Barbarian WarlordSupportChosen Archer Warband, Skirmisher WarbandSiegeN/AOtherWardogsGaulCultureBarbarianStarting LocationAlesia (Capital) , Condate Rodonum, Lemonum , Narbo Maritus, Medolanium , Patavium and NumanthiaPlayableYes (unlockable)Gauls are a warlike barbarian tribe from northeast Europe.InfantryPeasants, Warband, Naked Fanatics, Swordsmen, Chosen Swordsmen, DruidsCavalryBarbarian Cavalry, Barbarian Noble Cavalry, Barbarian WarlordSupportSkirmisher Warband, Forester WarbandSiegeN/AOtherWardogsBritanniaCultureBarbarianStarting LocationLondinium (Capital) , Eburacum , Deva and SamarobrivaPlayableYes (unlockable)The Briton faction were similar to the Gauls in many ways. They are also Celts and they had trading links to the whole world.InfantryPeasants, Warband, Woad Warriors, Swordsmen, Chosen Swordsmen, DruidsCavalryMerc. Barbarian Cavalry, Briton Light Chariots, Briton Heavy Chariots, Briton WarlordSupportSlingers, Head HurlersSiegeN/AOtherWarhoundsDaciaCultureBarbarianStarting LocationCampus Lazyges (Capital) and PorrolissumPlayableNoInfantryPeasants, Warband, Naked Fanatics, Falxmen, Chosen SwordsmenCavalryBarbarian Cavalry, Barbarian Noble Cavalry, Scythian Horse Archer, Barbarian WarlordSupportArcher Warband, Chosen Archer WarbandSiegeBallistas, OnagersOtherWarhoundsScythiaCultureBarbarianStarting LocationCampus Scithii (Capital) , Campus Sarmatae and Campus AlaniPlayableNo InfantryPeasants, AxemenCavalryBarbarian Cavalry, Head Hunting Maidens, Scythian Nobles, Barbarian Warlord, Scythian Horse Archers, Scythian Noble Women, Scythian Noble Horse ArchersSupportArcher Warband, Chosen Archer WarbandSiegeOnagersOtherN/ASpainCultureBarbarianStarting LocationAsturica (capital) Carthago Nova, Scallabis and OscaPlayableNoAlso known as the Celtiberian Confederacy, Spain was a Carthago-Barbaric faction that resided in the Atlantic and Mediterranean coasts. Many North African and Germanic peoples migrated to Spain by 1000 B.C. and soon the different immigrants merged into being the Caltiberians, who were the first to rule over the Spanish peninsula. Soon when the Romans began to expand, they introduced the Celtiberians to the latin language. Spain was seen as a colonizing opportunity of many Mediterranean powers and while the Carthaginians lived with the Celtiberians in harmony, Rome captured it by force taking 200 years to fully secure Spain in the Punic Wars.InfantryPeasants, Town Watch, Iberian Infantry, Scutarii, Naked Fanatics, Bull WarriorsCavalryRoundshield Cavalry, Longshield Cavalry, General's BodyguardSupportSkirmishers, Slingers, Balearic SlingersSiegeOnagersOtherN/AGreek CitiesCultureGreekStarting LocationSparta (Capital), Rhodes, Thermon, Pergamum and SyracusePlayableYes (unlockable)The Greeks had a great impact on all civilizations of the known world and were the founders of philosophy, mathematics and science. Their explorations and colonization reached from Spain to Russia.The Greeks were the first to defeat the Persian Empire. They had the most powerful military unit, the Spartan hoplites.Only in Sparta and Syracuse you can train the Spartan phalanx unit.InfantryPeasants, Hoplite Militia, Hoplites, Armoured Hoplites, Spartan HoplitesCavalryGreek Cavalry, Militia Cavalry, General's BodyguardSupportPeltast, Archer, Heavy Peltast, Merc. Rhodian Slingers, Merc. Cretan ArchersSiegeBallistas, Onagers, Heavy OnagersOtherIncendiary PigsSeleucid EmpireCultureGreekStarting LocationSardis, Tarsus, Antioch (Capital), Harta, Damascus and SeleuciaPlayableYes (unlockable)The Seleucid Empire are the heirs of Alexander the Great and they are those who inheritance the fallen Persian empire. But the heirs of Alexander the great were too greedy and they wanted more power and land thus their fall over the time. Their units range from long speared phalanxes to chariots, cataphracts and war elephants. They have even adopted the roman legionnaire units. They begin in what is now the Middle East fighting against Egypt, and Pontus for supremacy.InfantryPeasants, Hoplite Militia, Levy Pikemen, Phalanx Pikemen, Silver Shield Pikemen, Silver Shield LegionariesCavalryGreek Cavalry, Companiion Cavalry, Cataphracts, Scythed Chariots, Militia Cavalry, General's BodyguardSupportPeltast, ArchersSiegeOnagersOtherIncendiary Pigs, Elephants, War Elephants, Armoured War ElephantsMacedonCultureGreekStarting LocationThesalonica (Capital), Larissa, Corinth, BylazoraPlayableNoMacedonia is the kingdom that actually united the city states of Greece. With Alexander the Great as a leader, the Macedonians conquered the known world! They were the ones that crushed the Persian empire, conquered the Egyptians and even built the Pharos of Alexandria. After Alexander's death the conquered kingdoms were under rule by Alexander's generals and they formed the Seleucid empire.InfantryPeasants, Hoplite Militia, Levy Pikemen, Phalanx Pikemen, Royal PikemenCavalryGreek Cavalry, Companion Cavalry, General's Bodyguard, Light Lancers, Macedonian CavalrySupportPeltasts, Archers, Mercenary Illyrian Heavy Peltasts, Mercenary Cretan ArchersSiegeBallistas, Onagers, Heavy OnagersOtherN/AThraceCultureGreekStarting LocationTylis (Capital) and Campus SakePlayableNoInfantryPeasants, Falxmen, Bastarnae, Militia Hoplites, Phalanx PikemenCavalryGreek Cavalry, Militia Cavalry, General's BodyguardsSupportPeltasts, Archers, Mercenary Illyrian Heavy PeltastsSiegeOnagersOtherN/AParthiaCultureEasternStarting LocationMiddle East (Arsakia and Susa) and Eastern Europe (Campus Sakae)PlayableYes (unlockable)The Parthians were historically raised after the fall of the Seleucid empire. They control an interesting portion of units like their powerfull horses and elephants. In the game, they face the Scythians, the Seleucid Empire and the Armenians for supremacy. In history the Parthians were one of the few factions that acctualy defeated the Romans invaders while defending their lands.InfantryPeasants, Hillmen, Eastern InfantryCavalryCataphracts, Cataphract Camels, Eastern General, Horse Archers, Persian Cavalry, Mercenary Bedouin Warriors, Arabian Cavalry, Bedouin Camel ArchersSupportArchers, SlingersSiegeOnagersOtherWar ElephantsArmeniaCultureEasternStarting LocationArtaxarta (Capital) and KotaisPlayableNoInfantryPeasants, Hillmen, Eastern Infantry, Heavy Spearmen, Armenian LegionariesCavalryCataphracts, Cataphract Camels, Eastern General, Horse Archers, Cataphract Archers, Mercenary Bedouin Warriors, Arabian Cavalry, Bedouin Camel ArchersSupportArchers, PeltastsSiegeOnagersOtherN/APontusCultureEasternStarting LocationMazaka, Sinope (Capital)PlayableNo InfantryPeasants, Hillmen, Eastern Infantry, Phalanx Pikemen, Bronze Shield Pikemen, Mercenary Thracian Bastarnae, Mercenary Cilician PiratesCavalryPontic Heavy Cavalry, Cappadocian Cavalry, Scythed Chariots, Eastern General, Pontic Light Cavalry, Chariot ArchersSupportArchers, PeltastsSiegeOnagersOtherN/ACarthageCultureCarthaginianStarting LocationTunisia (Carthage and Thapsus), Sicily (Lilybaeum), Corsica (Caralis), Balaeric Islands (Palma) and Southern Spain (Corduba)PlayableYes (unlockable)A remnant of a Phoenician colony, The Carthaginians were at one point Rome's mortal enemy, facing off in a series of conflicts known as the Punic Wars.A naval power, their navy was envied even by the Romans and it even inspired the Spanish to create powerful ships against their Roman foes. Hannibal, a particularly talented military commander, almost destroyed the Roman Empire having made a difficult journey across the Alps in northern Italy. He even reached the outer wall of Rome its self. It was the wars with Carthage, with Hannibal that ultimately leads Rome to extends its power into what is today Spain and norther Africa.InfantryPeasants, Town Militia, Iberian Infantry, Libyan Spearmen, Poeni Infantry, Sacred Band Infantry, Mercenary Spanish PeltastsCavalryRound Shield Cavalry, Long Shield Cavalry, Sacred Band Cavalry, General's Bodyguard, Mercenary Light CavalrySupportSlingers, Mercenary Balearic Slingers, SkirmishersSiegeOnagers, Heavy OnagersOtherElephants, War Elephants, Armoured War ElephantsNumidiaCultureCarthaginianStarting LocationCirta (Capital), Dimmidi, Tingi and SiwaPlayableNo InfantryPeasants, Desert Infantry, Numidian LegionariesCavalryNumidian Cavalry, Long Shield Cavalry, Numidian Cavalry RidersSupportArchers, Numidian Javelinmen, SlingersSiegeOnagersOtherMercenary War ElephantsEgyptCultureEgyptianStarting LocationEgypt (Alexandria, Memphis and Thebes), Israel (Jerusalem), Cyprus (Salamis) and Lebanon (Sidon)PlayableYes (unlockable)The Egyptians in their early history were able to establish one of the most advanced kingdoms in human history. Experts in astrology, mathematics and trade the Egyptian civilization lasted for hundreds of years. Equipped with powerful chariots and spearmen in conjunction with order and faith to their pharaohs, the Egyptians rivaled the Romans in discipline and loyalty. In the game they are settled in Egypt, Jerusalem and Palestine and they even have in their control the island of Cyprus. They come in conflict with the Seleucid empire for supremacy.InfantryPeasants, Nubian Spearmen, Nile Spearmen, Desert Axemen, Pharaoh's GuardsCavalryNubian Cavalry, Desert Cavalry, Nile Cavalry, Egyptian Chariots, General's Bodyguard, Camel Archers, Egyptian Chariot ArchersSupportBowmen, Pharaoh's Bowmen, Skirmishers, SlingersSiegeOnagers, Heavy OnagersOtherN/A SoundtrackLike most games in the series, Rome: Total War is scored by Jeff Van Dyck.Journey to Rome Part ICarthage introMayhemBarbarian VictoryRome HQEastern IntroCaesar's NightmareEnemy is nearImperial ConflictLost SoulsEgyptian IntroDeath ApproachesDivinitusConteplationDrums of DoomRoman IntroArmy of DrumsMelee CafeArabic VictoryAutumnMobilizeRomantic BattleBarbarian DominationArabic WinterRome total warGreek IntroArabic SummerSoldiers ChantJourney to Rome Part IIRoman CelebrationEpicWarrior MarchForeverSystem RequirementsMinimum System SpecificationsRecommended System SpecificationsProcessor: 1.0GHz Pentium III or equivalentProcessor: 2.0GHz Pentium IV or equivalentRAM: 256MBRAM: 512MBVideo Memory: 64MBVideo Memory: 128MBHard Drive Space: 2.9GBHard Drive Space: 3.4GBOS: Windows 98SE/ME/2000/XPOS: Windows 98SE/ME/2000/XPDirectX: Version 9.0bDirectX: Version 9.0b</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16457">Sid Meier's Civilization IV</game><game id="4867">The Lord of the Rings: The Battle for Middle-earth II</game><game id="13076">Age of Mythology</game><game id="8407">Shogun: Total War</game><game id="5209">Shogun: Total War - The Mongol Invasion</game><game id="4685">Medieval II: Total War</game><game id="13453">Medieval II: Total War - Kingdoms</game><game id="21645">Europa Universalis: Rome</game><game id="5488">Warhammer: Dark Omen</game><game id="18510">Warhammer: Mark of Chaos</game><game id="8897">Stronghold 2</game><game id="16130">Imperial Glory</game><game id="17037">Codename: Panzers - Phase One</game><game id="19857">Empire Earth</game><game id="1565">Empire Earth II</game><game id="22846">Stronghold Crusader Extreme</game><game id="233">Harpoon</game><game id="582">Colosseum: Road to Freedom</game><game id="17982">Command &amp; Conquer: Generals - Zero Hour</game><game id="8876">Sid Meier's Colonization</game><game id="24420">Europa Universalis: Rome Vae Victis</game><game id="18752">Carthage</game><game id="20674">StarCraft II: Wings of Liberty</game><game id="29283">King Arthur: The Role-Playing Wargame</game><game id="29207">Europa Universalis: For the Glory</game><game id="8349">Hearts of Iron</game><game id="30376">SPARTAN</game><game id="20509">Empire: Total War</game><game id="27879">Napoleon: Total War</game><game id="9264">Rome: Total War - Barbarian Invasion</game><game id="24980">Grand Ages: Rome</game><game id="341">Rome: Total War - Alexander</game><game id="11993">Rise of Nations</game><game id="10485">Age of Empires</game><game id="20580">Sid Meier's Civilization Revolution</game><game id="32487">Hegemony: Philip of Macedon</game><game id="30057">Sid Meier's Civilization V</game><game id="31531">Total War: Shogun 2</game><game id="39889">Hegemony Gold: Wars of Ancient Greece</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/864/676163-589390_front.jpg</image></root>