<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>19936</id><name>Fatal Fury 3: Road to the Final Victory!</name><description>Overview Fatal Fury 3: Road to the Final Victory! (known in Japan as Garou Densetsu 3: Harukanaru Tatakai, translated to Legend of the Hungry Wolf 3: The Distant Battle) is a fighting game developed and published by                            SNK for the                           Neo Geo. The only returning characters from previous                          Fatal Fury games are                         Terry Bogard,                        Andy Bogard,                       Joe Higashi,                      Mai Shiranui, and                     Geese Howard. This game marks the debut of                    Blue Mary and                   Ryuji Yamazaki, who both appeared in the                  King of Fighters series. The game focuses on the Scrolls of Immortality, in which the Jin brothers (                Chonshu and                Chonrei) and Ryuji Yamazaki are trying to find in order to be world rulers.  Unlike previous installments of the Fatal Fury franchise, the console ports were done by SNK themselves. It was ported to the              Neo Geo CD,             Sega Saturn, and the            PC (Windows 95 based). The original Neo Geo version was also included in the           Fatal Fury Battle Archives Volume 1 compilation for the          PlayStation 2 and was released on the         Wii Virtual Console in Japan on April 20, 2010. Gameplay The format and controls of Fatal Fury 3 are directly from        Fatal Fury Special, with some subtle differences. Players can now control the height of their character's jump and can block in the air. Fatal Fury 3 also features a new kind of combo system, where players execute a specific series of regular attacks (varying by character) from one to the other.  In addition to normal "desperation moves", which can only be executed when the life gauge flashes red, players now have a rare ability to do a "hidden desperation move" once per round. This is unlocked by pressing all the buttons simultaneously as soon as the word "GO!" flashes on the beginning of the round. If this is done right, the player's name on the life gauge will turn green. Then, when the life gauge flashes red, you must set up correctly (either by moving to a set distance away from the opponent or executing a specific attack), where the name will flash. Only then could you execute this devestating super move.  The two-line system from the previous Fatal Fury games have been replaced by a three-plane format known as the Oversway system, where the players mainly fight in the middle plane, but can switch between the background and foreground planes temporarily to avoid attacks and projectiles completely.  Fatal Fury 3 also features a fighting grade system which grades your performance from E to A, then S, SS, and SSS. How far you can progress through the boss battles is determined on your average fighting grade when battling the computer players. Characters Fatal Fury 3 contains ten playable characters and three CPU-only boss characters, which can only be played with a special cheat code in the PC version.                                       Terry Bogard                                    Andy Bogard                                   Joe Higashi                                  Mai Shiranui                                 Geese Howard                                Blue Mary     Sokaku Mochizuki                               Bob Wilson    Hon-Fu   Franco Bash                              Ryuji Yamazaki (boss)                             Jin Chonshu (boss)                            Jin Chonrei (boss)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14669">Virtua Fighter Animation</game><game id="16064">World Heroes 2 JET</game><game id="3744">Def Jam: Fight for NY</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1445910-ff3_box.png</image></root>