<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20112</id><name>Sakura Wars: So Long, My Love</name><description>OverviewSakura Wars: So Long, My Love is the fifth game in Sega's Sakura Wars series. Originally published in Japan as "Sakura Taisen V: Saraba, Itoshiki Hito yo," the game is the first in the series to be localized in North America, by NIS America. Like its predecessors, Sakura Wars 5 mixes tactical RPG gameplay with the dating simulation, or "visual novel," genre peculiar to the Japanese video game market, featuring a large female cast of stage actresses/combat pilots.NIS America published the North American PS2 release as a two disc premium edition that includes the English and original Japanese audio tracks as well as a collector’s item art cover. The Wii version is a single disc release with only the English voice track included.GameplayGameplay in Sakura Wars is divided into two main segments - Adventure Mode and Battle Mode.Adventure ModeAw Yeah! Samurai TrainingIn Adventure Mode, Shinjiro Taiga, the main protagonist, is controlled from a third-person perspective and can move throughout various locales of New York and interact with other characters. Sakura Wars: So Long, My Love features the series' traditional Live  Interactive Picture System, or LIPS, which requires the player to participate in quick-time events that decide that outcome and consequences of interactions with other characters. During a conversation, various responses or actions may appear on screen for the player to choose or perform within a time limit. Failure to choose an option within the time limit is also considered a valid response. Furthermore, the player's actions over the course of the game not only determine the narrative direction/ending of the plot, but also the effectiveness of the party in combat.Character progression in Sakura Wars does not occur in the traditional role-playing sense of earning points from combat towards higher experience levels; rather, the protagonist and his party members become more powerful over time depending on the strength of their respective relationships - therefore, Adventure Mode is the primary avenue through which the player bonds with the other party members in order to become more effective in Battle Mode.Battle ModeFighting on the StreetsBattle Mode consists of turn-based combat on a gridless field. Each party member's STAR (steam-powered mecha) is assigned a certain number of movement points based on his or her speed, which can be spent on actions such as movement or attacks. Additionally, when controlling the protagonist's command unit, the player can also issue special commands to the rest of the squad in order to activate special attacks or change tactical modes befitting the sitaution. Over the course of the game, more tactical options will become available as the player builds up his/her relationship with the other party members.Main CharactersOgami's ReplacementTaiga ShinjiroAge: 19Birthday: 8/20/1908Hieght: 5'5Weight: 130lbPlace of Origin: Tochigi, JapanThe nineteen-year-old nephew of Ogami Ichiro - the protagonist of the previous Sakura Wars games - Second Lieutenant Taiga Shinjiro is summoned to the Imperial Assault Team's headquarters in the opening cutscene, only to be reassigned to the Star Division squadron of the newly established New York Combat Revue, an American sister organization of the Imperial Assault Team. Following the Star Division's first combat sortie in which Ratchet Altair, the current leader, is wounded, Shinjiro is appointed acting field commander of the Star Division. Born and bred into the Taiga samurai family, Shinjiro's personality is straightforward and reflects the traditional Japanese samurai ethic in a rapidly changing world, impressing and occasionally baffling those around him.Two in OneGemini SunriseAge: 16Birthday: 6/21/1911Hieght: 5'2Weight: 106lbPlace of Origin: TexasThe protagonist of the prequel Sakura Wars V Episode 0, Gemini Sunrise is a self-styled cowgirl samurai from Texas that speaks with a Texan drawl and claims to find the bustle of New York disconcerting. When Shinjiro first transfers into the NYCR, Gemini is working as a cleaning girl in the Littlelip Theater, a front for the Combat Revue's headquarters.Objection!Cheiron Archer (Sagitta Weinberg)Age: 21Birthday: 12/6/1906Hieght: 5'11Weight: 150lbPlace of Origin: Harlem, New YorkPilot, attorney, biker gang leader, and star actress, Cheiron is a strong-willed woman of many talents and a member of the Star Division. Long before she became a lawyer, Cheiron was a gang member in Harlem. The discrimination she and her friends experienced compelled her to become a lawyer to fight for their rights; unfortunately, Cheiron's work affected her sense of morality and she is frequently conflicted between compassion and her desire for justice. Originally named Sagitta Weinberg, her name was changed to Cheiron in the English voice track disc.He, She, It?Subaru KujouAge: UnknownBirthday: 5/9/????Hieght: 4'9Weight: 80lbPlace of Origin: Kyoto, JapanOne of the two original members of the Star Division, Subaru is the most enigmatic member of the Revue. Her history, age, and actual gender are unknown to the whole team, but there is no denying that Subaru is by far the most talented actress and pilot on the Revue at the time during which Shinjiro joins. Idolized by all, Subaru's ego is nonetheless far from arrogant, though she has little tolerance for those she sees as useless to the team.The Birds!Diana CapriceAge: 19Birthday: 1/12/1909Hieght: 5'4Weight- 99lbPlace of Origin: MassachusettsA kind but frail doctor that spends much of her time in Central Park, Diana first meets Shinjiro in the park not longer after his arrival in New York.Gold or SilverRosarita Aries (Rikaritta Aries)Age: 11Birthday: 4/2/1917Hieght: 4'00Weight: 50lbPlace of Origin: MexicoRosarita is a prodigious young gunslinger and bounty hunter from the frontier. With nothing but her revolvers, pet weasel, and ravenous appetite, Rosarita arrives in New York searching for her next job/meal, but is recruited to the team early on for both her childish appeal and incredible marksmanship. Originally named Rikaritta, she has her name changed to Rosarita in the English voice disc, presumably to more clearly reflect a Mexican background.SoundtrackDisc 1:No.Track NameLength1Surface Warrior (Opening Vers.)1:492Surface Warrior (Title Background Vers.)2:583Little Lip Theater3:394Coffee Break3:235Neon Lit Town4:256Welcome to Broadway2:437Excited3:208Closed Heat3:319Whoa!3:0510Thoughts, Overflowing3:1811Warmth4:2912Another Clear Day in Manhattan3:3413Sword Flash3:2914State of Emergency2:4615Prelude to Battle3:2216Ahab, Take Off!2:2717New York Floral Assault Group, Ready Go!!4:2418Assault4:5619Those Fighting on the Flight Deck3:3020Gang of Destruction3:58Disc 2:No.Track NameLength1The Destroyed and Undestroyed2:452Strategy2:223Orchids2:124Sixth Heaven2:055It's Showtime!3:456The Whole World Under Conquest3:337Victory Is in My Hands1:208Surface Warrior (Final Battle Vers.)2:349Loving New York4:1710Kiss Me Sweet4:1611My Dream1:2912Downtown Heart2:0713Bounty Hunter Rika1:3314One Day I Looked Up at the Blue Sky1:5915Shining Constellation1:3216Silver Wind0:4617Here Is Paradise2:1318Movie - Cherry Blossoms Fluttering about the Imperial Capital0:4119Movie - Hopeful New World1:0220Movie - New York Is in Tumult!0:5121Movie - Musical (Cleopatra)0:5122Movie - Trash Chute0:3923Movie - Star, Sortie!0:5924Movie - Ahab, Take Off!1:3625Movie - Change! Flight Form!!0:3426Movie - Sagitta, Special Attack!0:3527Movie - Rika Is Bounty Hunting!0:4728Movie - To a Shining Future0:3629Movie - Bonds0:5130Movie - Shoot-out on the Brooklyn Bridge0:4931Movie - Nobunaga, Departure for the Front1:1332Movie - Sixth Sky1:0133Movie - Mainland Anti-aircraft Machine [C.A.R.P.]1:2334Movie - Together with My Hopes1:0935Movie - The Skyscraper is the Color of Cherry Blossoms1:1836Over the Rainbow Sunshine6:21</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2652">Disgaea 2: Cursed Memories</game><game id="21355">Soul Nomad &amp; the World Eaters</game><game id="3731">Phantom Brave</game><game id="451">Makai Kingdom: Chronicles of the Sacred Tome</game><game id="21541">Ar tonelico II: Melody of Metafalica</game><game id="19701">Stella Deus: The Gate of Eternity</game><game id="771">Front Mission 4</game><game id="17786">Growlanser Generations</game><game id="21373">Shin Megami Tensei: Persona 4</game><game id="4473">Shin Megami Tensei: Persona 3</game><game id="20971">Valkyria Chronicles</game><game id="21222">GrimGrimoire</game><game id="25354">Phantom Brave: We Meet Again</game><game id="31138">Global Defence Force Tactics</game><game id="32689">Senjo no Valkyria 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1988895-box_swslml.png</image></root>