<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20121</id><name>Star Trek: Klingon Academy</name><description>GameplayWith similar gameplay to   14° East's previous Star Trek space flight simulator    Star Trek: Starfleet Academy the player controls Klingon warships and completes missions that are broken up by full motion live action videos of Christopher Plummer and David Warner reprising their roles as Chang and Gorkon from the TV series and films. The difficulty of the game is determined by what class of space ship the player chooses at the mission briefing. The more advanced the ship the harder the mission is to accomplish. Weapons Primary WeaponsPhaserDisruptorHeavy DisruptorImpulse Velocity Projectile (IVP)Assault Phaser: a super-sized Phaser nominally equiped only on starbases.Secondary WeaponsPhoton TorpedoHeavy Photon TorpedoPlasma TorpedoGorn Plasma TorpedoSpecial Weapons Antimatter Field Projector (AFP)Cohesive Fused Deuterium Irradiation Cannon (CFDIC)Frequency-Modulated Meson Particle Accelerator (FMPA)Gravitic Harmonic Resonator Cannon (GHRC)Graviton Density Distortion Sphere (GDDS)Quantum Carrier-Wave Beam (QCB)Tholian Web CannonStarship Classes Starship classes from six different species may be encountered during the game. The ships range from small shuttlecraft to massive battleships.  Fans of the  Star Trek TOS movies may recognize a few of the ship models. Fans of Interplay's  Starfleet Command-series may recognize some ships as reworked and restoried  Starfleet Command models. However,  Klingon Academy features more than twelve new starship designs.The Klingon Empire Escort: the Bird-of-PreyFrigate: Suspicious-classDestroyer: Insurrection-classLight Cruiser: Relentless-classCruiser: K'tinga-classCommand Cruiser: Warrior's Anger-classBattlecruiser: Emperor-classDreadnought: Accuser-classBattleship: the Sword of Kahless-classThe United Federation of Planets Scout: Oberth-classFrigate: Okinawa-classDestroyer: Akula-classLight Cruiser: Miranda-classCruiser: refitted Constitution-classCommand Cruiser: Lexington-class Battlecruiser: Excelsior-classDreadnought: Ulysses-classBattleship: Missouri-classExperimental Battleship: Yamato-class The Romulan Star Empire Escort: Praex-classFrigate: Gladius-classDestroyer: Warbird-classLight Cruiser: Legion-classCruiser: Centurion-classCruiser: D7-classCommand Cruiser: Senator-class Battlecruiser: Imperium-classDreadnought: War Eagle-classBattleship: Imperial Hawk-class  The Gorn Confederacy Frigate: King Snake-classDestroyer: Anaconda-classCruiser: Euromastyx-classBattleship: Grendel-classThe Tholian Assembly Escort: Feldspar-classDestroyer: Quartz-classLight Cruiser: Garnet-classCruiser: Ruby-classBattlecruiser: Amethyst-classBattleship: Sapphire-class The Sha'Kurian Ducal TerritoriesLight Carrier: Hunter-classFleet Carrier: Long Fang-classSuper Carrier: Alpha-class SoundtrackThe Klingon Academy soundtrack was composed by       Inon Zur.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17383">Star Trek: Starfleet Academy</game><game id="12943">Star Trek: Starfleet Academy - Chekov's Lost Missions</game><game id="37043">X3: Albion Prelude</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/34651/2231613-klingonacademy.jpg</image></root>