<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20124</id><name>Cave Story</name><description>OverviewCave Story is a freeware side-scrolling action-adventure game for Windows, Mac, and Linux developed solely by Daisuke Amaya, better known as Pixel. Created over a period of five years, Cave Story was released on December 20th, 2004 to widespread acclaim. Described as a "Metroidvania"-style shooter/platformer, the game was created in style reminiscent of early 1990's SNES releases like Super Metroid. Cave Story was translated to English by Aeon Genesis and has been emulated for the Xbox, PSP, and Amiga platforms. A Game Boy Advance port, later turning into a Nintendo DS port, was partially developed, but never finished. However, a port of the original game to DSiWare with some of the features from the WiiWare version was released on November 29th 2010. In 2008, development studio Nicalis announced that a new version of Cave Story, complete with enhanced music, enhanced graphics and exclusive features was being prepared for release on Nintendo's WiiWare download service. The game was released through WiiWare on March 22, 2010 in North America. The European WiiWare-version of the game was eventually released on December 10, 2010. There was an updated re-release by Nicalias (for PC, Mac, and Linux) called Cave Story + on November 22, 2011 which included the extra content added to the WiiWare version, as well as additional content including new areas to explore. A 3DS version titled Cave Story 3D was released on November 8, 2011. This version used 3D graphics instead of 2D sprites, includes new areas and extended versions of existing areas, and is a retail release published by NIS America.PlotThe first room of Cave StoryThe story follows Quote, a "soldier from the surface" who awakens in a cave with no prior memories. He moves through a network of caves and discovers a village of Mimiga, rabbit-like humanoids terrorized by abductions at the hands of "The Doctor". As the game progresses, Quote learns that he is on a floating island, naturally inhabited only by Mimiga. The Doctor, having arrived on the island with a human research team, has hatched a plan to conquer the surface world, using the island's magical "Demon Crown" and the Mimiga's susceptibility to rage-inducing "red flowers". Quote, his own identity still uncertain, is enlisted by the remaining researchers and Mimiga to stop the Doctor and restore order to the island.Though the game does not place a heavy emphasis on player choices or branching storylines, both are present to some degree. For example, the player can easily choose to bypass the first fight with Balrog. Such minor decisions often have no impact on the larger story, but others can be hugely important to the progression of the plot. For instance, at a certain point, the player can choose to end the game early and earn the "bad" ending. Alternatively, if the player succeeds in following a specific sequence of sidequests and decisions, an extra area and the "good" ending will be unlocked near the end of the game. Otherwise, the player will earn the standard "normal" ending.GameplayQuote fights enemies in Grasstown.Cave Story controls very similarly to early SNES action titles. The player uses the arrow keys to move, the Z key to jump, and the X key to shoot. Throughout the game, the player can collect a number of necessary and optional weapons, which can be linearly auto-upgraded by collecting experience points from fallen enemies. Each weapon in the game can be upgraded to a third level. The player loses experience, which can result in a weapon downgrade, by losing health. The A and S keys are used to cycle through weapons. The Q key is used to open the inventory, from which the player can view and use items. The W key is used to view the map (once it has been acquired). The game also has native game-pad support. All of the key functions can be modified in a separate application, which also handles graphical settings.The game world is split into a number of areas, connected by teleportation devices and/or direct passages. Progression often requires backtracking into previously traversed areas. Through close exploration, the player can collect optional weapons, items, health-expanding Life Capsules,and missile capacity-expanding Missile Expansions. Due to the game's lengthy and nonlinear nature, save points and health-restoration machines are found at certain points. The story is advanced at certain junctures by dialogue and simple in-game animations.CharactersQuoteQuote, as seen in the PC Version (left) and the enhanced WiiWare version (right).The amnesiac silent protagonist, one of the robotic soldiers originally sent to eradicate the Mimiga.Curly BraceA female robot soldier who, similarly to Quote, found herself on the island with no memory; she is Quote's closest ally.The DoctorThe main antagonist, a power hungry man bent on using the Mimiga to conquer Earth; his power stems from the Demon Crown, an evil artifact he found on the island.MiseryA powerful witch and one of the Doctor's minions, a regular antagonist throughout the game; long ago, she convinced Ballos (her uncle) to create the Demon Crown, and is therefore cursed to obey its holder's commands.BalrogAnother of the Doctor's minions (also cursed by the Crown), Misery's sidekick and "punching bag"; he often serves as comic relief.Sue SakamotoSue, as seen in the PC version (left) and the enhanced WiiWare version (right).Daughter of Momorin Sakamoto; she was transformed into a Mimiga by Misery before escaping to the Mimiga Village.Kazuma SakamotoSon of Momorin Sakamoto and brother of Sue; he escaped from the Doctor with the research team and now hopes to escape the island with Sue by hatching a flying Sky Dragon.Momorin SakamotoA member of the human research team, mother of Sue and Kazuma; she has been hiding in the Plantation since her escape from the Doctor.Professor BoosterThe research team's elderly leader, who has escaped with the other members; he is a close friend of the Sakamoto family and often assists Quote on his journey.ItohThe research team's cowardly engineer; he was transformed into a Mimiga by Misery before escaping from the Doctor's captivityTorokoA young Mimiga who befriended Sue; mistaken for Sue, she is kidnapped by Misery early in the game.KingThe brave leader of the Mimiga Village; he is very protective of Toroko and very mistrustful of Sue.JackKing's direct subordinate.ArthurA legendary Mimiga hero, killed by the Doctor before Quote's awakening; he was Toroko's older brother.BallosA powerful sorcerer, creator of the Demon Crown; he accidentally obliterated his own homeland, driving him to insanity, long before the events of the game.JenkaAn elderly witch living alone in the Sand Zone, guardian of the dangerous red flowers and Misery's mother; she imprisoned Ballos (her brother) on the island after his descent into madness.System RequirementsPCMinimumOS:Windows XPProcessor:Intel Core SoloMemory:128 MB RAMGraphics:64MB RAMHard Drive:64 MB HD spaceRecommendedOS:Windows 7Processor:Intel Core Duo 2.0 Ghz and aboveMemory:512 MB RAMGraphics:256MB RAM, non-integratedHard Drive:64 MB HD spaceMacMinimumOS:OS X version Leopard 10.5.8, Snow Leopard 10.6.3, or later.Processor:Intel only, Power PC not supportedMemory:128 MB RAMGraphics:64MB RAM</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14216">Castlevania: Symphony of the Night</game><game id="8292">Super Metroid</game><game id="14026">Mega Man 2</game><game id="9463">Mega Man X</game><game id="6630">Aquaria</game><game id="24999">Spelunky</game><game id="1257">Blaster Master</game><game id="23727">Iji</game><game id="33566">Bunny Must Die</game><game id="34940">Terraria</game><game id="36869">UnEpic</game><game id="24768">Fez</game><game id="38695">The Iconoclasts</game><game id="27691">Dust: An Elysian Tail</game><game id="40031">Ikachan</game><game id="40262">Sealark</game><game id="33120">Melolune</game><game id="30380">Limbo</game><game id="42526">Helen - Castle In Wonderland</game><game id="40860">Bleed</game><game id="42721">Super Puzzle Platformer Deluxe</game><game id="42593">Rex Rocket</game><game id="43448">Ghost Song: A Journey of Hope</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5353/483734-doukutsu.jpg</image></root>