<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20135</id><name>POD SpeedZone</name><description>There are six cars to choose from:   Viper   Cougar   Scarab Wasp Bulldog (unlocked from creating an online account) Crab (unlocked from creating an online account) All of these cars/PODs have slightly different handling/statistical differences, but they do not pose much of a difference in racing feel while playing the game.  Although this is not meant to be anywhere close to a "racing simulator" I found that the cars handled very well, much better than any "arcade" type of racing.There are also six different tracks to choose from:  K Zone            This race is placed in an ancient city type of environment, lots of old structures and buildings  Volcano            A race that takes place around/in a big volcano, its just a big volcano.  Canyon            This is a race that takes place in a big canyon, lots of sand and tall canyon walls.  Mines Web            This race weaves in and out of lots of tunnels/mines.  Bridge Ride            Bridge Ride is a race that takes place around a futuristic factory.  OddRock            (unlocked by creating an online account)  I believe that it is a figure-8 track that takes place on a giant rock. While racing, you will find coloured spheres, these pick ups/power ups can help you in completing the race, by either helping you, or negating one of the other cars. There are 5 different kind of coloured orbs to pick up, each with its own special ability.  Yellow            Gives you full boost for a short period of time.  Orange            Gives you a land mine that you can place on the ground behind you.  Blue           This gives your boost gauge a slight fill up.  Red           This gives your shield a slight repair.  Purple           Gives you a electric shock that will slow anyone that is in front of you down for a split second.  Every vehicle is equipped with a shield wich degrades as you crash into walls or are hit by enemy weapons. If your shield is fully depleted during a race, your car will overheat and stop working, making you fail the current race. </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19115">Dethkarz</game><game id="16728">Powerslide</game><game id="15636">Forsaken</game><game id="20645">Mario Kart Wii</game><game id="10084">Mario Kart 64</game><game id="6539">Mario Kart DS</game><game id="20610">WipEout HD</game><game id="20596">WipEout Pulse</game><game id="9707">WipEout</game><game id="8949">S.T.U.N. Runner</game><game id="11573">POD: Planet of Death</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2402/841892-new_picture.png</image></root>