<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20258</id><name>Spider-Man: Friend or Foe</name><description>OverviewThis time they play as a team.Spider-Man: Friend or Foe is a beat 'em up where Spider-Man has to team up with his enemies in order to stop an unknown nemesis. You travel to typical locations such as: Tokyo, Transylvania and Nepal. You fight through each level, taking down ever phantom in your way, and then defeat one of your brainwashed foes, which will add them to your team. You gain tech coins during each level, which can then be used to upgrade each character's abilities. The combat looks good and is rather simple, thus making the game very accessible. Friend or Foe features full 2-player co-op, but disappointingly is offline only. The game is also rather easy, which can be good for casual gamers, but will inevitably leave most gamers wanting more of a challenge.PlotThe Green Goblin.The basic plot of Friend or Foe is that the meteor which brought Venom's symbiote broke up in the Earth's atmosphere and five pieces were scattered across the world. Nick Fury sends Spider-Man on a mission to collect these five pieces, but finds the task more difficult because his foes have all been put under some form of mind control. As Spider-Man fights all of his foes and releases them from the mind control, they agree to help Spider-Man on this particular mission. Eventually you find out who is behind it all and of course, you stop them and save the day.LocationsTokyo, JapanIndustial PlantSecret LabThe RooftopsOscorp JapanTangaroa IslandBeachsideSea CavesThe CliffsAncient RuinsCairo, EgyptSun-Drenched CityThe OasisUnearthed CatacombsExcavation SiteTransylvaniaOldworld VillageThe Manor HouseGraveyard PathAncient ChurchNepalLower VillageDark CavernsUpper VillageTemplePlayable charactersPlayable cast.Spider-ManSpider-Man (black suit)Silver SableProwlerBlack CatDoc OckGreen GoblinScorpionIron FistRhinoLizardSandmanBladeVenomNew GoblinElectro (PSP only)Carnage (PSP only)CheatsFor PSPNew Goblin:Hold L R and press Circle, Down, X, Right, Square, Up, Triangle, Left at the "Stage Completed" screen. The New Goblin will be available for purchase for 4,000 tokens. He has the same stats and specials as the Green Goblin, but does it with style.For PS2, Wii, XBOX 360 / LIVE and PC5,000 upgrade points:Press Up(2), Down(2), Left, Right while standing on the Helicarrier. Note: This code can only be enabled one time.New Goblin:Press Left, Down, Right(2), Down, Left while standing on the Helicarrier.Sandman:Press Right(3), Up, Down, Left while standing on the Helicarrier.Venom:Press Left(2), Right, Up, Down(2) while standing on the Helicarrier.UnlockablesFor PSPHero Concepts:Successfully complete the game. Continue on the cleared saved game file and complete Tokyo area 1.Villain Concepts:Play a game in Memorable Battle mode.Carnage:Unlocked during Co-op mode.For PS2, Wii, XBOX 360 / LIVE and PCBonus characters:Complete the indicated task to unlock the corresponding character.Black Suit Spider-Man:Proceed through the game up to when you first meet Bubble-Man. After this point you can activate the Black Suit Spider-Man at the Helicarrier .For NINTENDO DSPartners:Complete the indicated task to unlock the corresponding character.Other characters can be purchased at the shop for the indicated number of tokens.Xbox 360 Game InstallationSpider-Man: Friend or Foe requires 3.6GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD.System requirements (PC)Processor Speed: 1.6GHzOperating System: Windows XP, Windows VistaSystem Memory: 256MB RAMHard Drive Space: 5GBVideo: 128MB 3D DirectX 9.0c-compatible video cardSound Card: DirectX 9.0c-compatible 16-bit sound cardDVD-ROM 4x</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17844">Batman: Rise of Sin Tzu</game><game id="22441">Avatar: The Last Airbender - The Burning Earth</game><game id="7184">Trauma Center: Second Opinion</game><game id="21847">Watchmen: The End is Nigh</game><game id="26913">Watchmen: The End is Nigh Part 2</game><game id="7527">Marvel Ultimate Alliance</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1817080-box_smanfof.png</image></root>