<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20256</id><name>Mega Man X4</name><description>OverviewThe title screen.Released in 1997, Mega Man X4 is the second Mega Man game to be released on the PlayStation  Saturn (The first being a port of Mega Man X3 from the Super Nintendo with some new additions). Unlike Mega Man X3, Mega Man X4 is not a port of a game from an older console. Mega Man X4 features a brand new redrawn look, anime cut-scenes, new soundtrack, and the ability to play the entire game as Zero.StoryThe story starts off with Sigma (in disguise) having a meeting with the General of the RepliForce. Sigma tells the General that the RepliForce have been often accused of being Mavericks by the humans and to go at war with them, but the General refuses and tells Sigma to leave.Later on, a city populated by humans is attacked and destroyed by the Mavericks. X or Zero find the Colonel of the RepliForce; X or Zero tells the Colonel to disarm himself and come with, to headquarters, but the Colonel refuses and leaves; that's when the Repliforce were put under the suspicion that the RepliForce might become Mavericks.The General soon announces that the RepliForce should start their own utopia by building a space station. But something didn't seem right for X  Zero, they thought the plan was foolish and then they later find out that the Repliforce were actually buliting a weapon that was going to destroy the planet Earth. So it was up to X  Zero to put a stop to the RepliForce's plan.Story X VersionOne of the cut-scene in X's story.The story for Mega Man X4 are similar for both X  Zero.The differences for X is he teams up with a rookie Maverick Hunter named Double--Whom X later finds out is a undercover agent of the Mavericks.Story Zero VersionDr. Wily making his first appearance in the X series.The differences with Zero is he teams up with the Colonel of the Repliforce's sister, Iris. Zero also has a few more anime cut-scenes than X. One of them reveals that Zero's creator is Dr. Wily--the main villain of the original Mega Man series.Gameplay"Get Ready!"The gameplay for X is similar to the previous games in the series; X has his X-buster that can be charged up to shoot out a powerful projectile, he can climb on walls, and has a dash move. When bosses are defeated, X can inherit their powers in the form of a weapon with limited ammunition. X also has armor upgrades - Helmet, legs, body armor, and X-Buster - that are found in four of the eight levels; they can upgrade X's power for the X-buster, and others can give him special abilities that he never had.Zero is similar to X in terms of basic mechanics (Dash and climb), but differs greatly in terms of combat. Zero is more up close melee style, he also has no projectile attacks (With the exception one that is earned by Storm Owl). Zero has no armor upgrades - it's partly due to the fact the armor upgrades are not compatible to Zero (It was explained in Mega Man X5). When a boss is defeated, Zero learns a new technique instead of a new weapon - he also has no limit to how many times he could use his newly learned techniques.Other upgrades can be found in each of the stages. Such as heart containers, that can increase the health bar; and energy capsules that's use to store extra health. In the previous games, the player can hold up to four energy capsules, but in Mega Man X4, only two are found for the health bar and a third one is use to refill a weapon's ammo.UpgradesThe Fourth Armor.Helmet: The helmet upgrade allows infinite energy for all of X's weapons.Legs: The leg upgrade allows X to hover in the air for a short amount of time.Body Armor: The armor upgrade gives X a new ability known as Nova Strike - it's a powerful air-dash move. The way the Nova Strike is done is by filling up a meter by taking enough damage - it's similar to the G-Crush armor from Mega Man X2.X-Buster: For the first time in the X series, Mega Man X4 allows the player to give a choice of two X-Buster upgrades. One of them lets X charge up his X-Buster up to four times. The other version gives the X-Buster a fourth level when charged up.StagesJungleThe most well drawn level in the game, the jungle level has X or Zero going through streaming water while battling javelin wielding mavericks that can shoot spears from their backs in eight different directions. Other areas contains large gaps with a waterfall raining down in between with falling logs that are used as platforms for X or Zero to get through. Mechanical bee hives are also present - they can generate robotic killer bees. Robotic snakes are also found - they can sneak up on X or Zero while crossing through trees.Snow BaseA snowy level that's filled with mechanical polar bears that have the ability throw out sharp ice blocks. Other sections have X or Zero going through spiked floors with sliding platforms that will disintegrate in a short period of time; on the platforms, are mavericks with skiing gear on. The other section of the stage is filled with frozen blocks that have bombs or the little helmet mavericks frozen inside. And the last sections of the stage has a bird that can change the scenery by freezing everything.Marine BaseAll of this level is done via "land chaser" - a hover bike that can shoot out projectiles. It's a fast moving stage that has pipe bombs planted on the ground and other mavericks on land chasers as well; Jet Stingray will appear in the middle of the stage to shoot out some ground hunters to try to stop X or Zero. The land chaser has the ability to dash on the ground or in mid-air.Military TrainNot much platforming in this stage, but there's lots of shooting involved. X or Zero are on top of a train going through waves and waves of mavericks - some of them are equipped with hand guns and can throw grenades. At one point one in the stage, X or Zero will be in control of a mech suit that's equip with a laser sword that can do some heavy damage.Cyber SpaceProbably the most creative stage, Cyber Space contains yellow spheres moving along slowly across the stage; if unable to avoid it, the sphere will suck X or Zero to the center of it and do some damage. Portals will also appear with mavericks coming out of them. While X or Zero is going through the stage, they will be timed, if they make it through a section of the stage quick enough, they will be ranked. If they get the highest ranking (S rank), they will go through a short area that contains a heart container, energy capsule, or an armor upgrade.Bio LaboratoryAt the beginning of the stage, X or Zero will go through a flight of stairs that will actually rotate 360 degrees while moving along (kind of giving you the sense that it looks like in 3D). Other areas have X or Zero going through short tunnels with mavericks with powerful drills on top of the tunnels ready to destroy the place as soon X or Zero crosses through. Another part has X or Zero moving upwards through a small corridor filled with hovering mavericks that shoot out projectiles.Air ForceIn this stage X or Zero will be on top of an aircraft going through laser shooting canons, giant mavericks that shoot out missiles, and even more gigantic canons that can shoot out devastating lasers. Another mech suit will be present for X or Zero to take control, but this one is different than the one that was found in the Slash Beast stage. This mech suit can hover in mid air and can shoot out charged up projectiles.VolcanoA lava filled stage that contains sections that has X or Zero going through falling rocks, giant fireballs coming out of the ground, and platforming sections that has fireballs falling through in between the gaps. But some of the platforms are not safe to be on, some of the fireballs will shoot out from the ground and will go right through one of the platforms that X or Zero is on.BossesName: Frost WalrusDescription: He protects the weapon which lies deep within the snow base.Level: Snow BaseWeapon: Frost Tower (X). Hyouretsuzan (Zero).Objective: "We've discovered a hidden base. Halt production of their new weapon."  Name: Jet StingrayDescrption: He destroyed the city and escaped to the Sea.Level: Marine BaseWeapon: Ground Hunter (X) Hienkaru (Zero)Objective: "Repliforce decimated the city and left. Pursue them aboard a land chaser."Name: Slash BeastDescription: He defends the Military train to protect the supply of goods.Level: Military TrainWeapon: Twin Slasher (X) Shippuuga (Zero)Objective: "A military train is moving supplies. Cut off Repliforce's supply route.     Name: Web SpiderDescription: He protects the secret weapon of the jungle.Level: JungleWeapon: Lighting Web (X) Raijingeki (Zero)Objective: "Infiltrate enemy-occupied jungle and destroy the weapon under construction. Name: Spilt MushroomDescription: He occupies the laboratory and attacks anyone who visits there.Level: Bio LaboratoryWeapon: Soul Body (X) Ruuenbu (Zero)Objective: "The abandoned lab is now operational. Investigate and destroy the lab.     Name: Cyber PeacockDescription: He lives in cyber space and he wants to destroy the Network System.Level: Cyber SpaceWeapon: Aiming Laser (X) Rakuhouha (Zero)Objective: "A bug has corrupted the network. Dive into Cyber Space and exterminate it."       Name: Storm Owl Description: He left with a space fortress to conquer the air.Level: Air ForceWeapon: Double Cyclone (X) Tenkuuha (Zero)Objective: "The Repliforce ship has taken off. Pursue and blast it out of the air."  Name: Magma DragoonDescription: He betrayed the irregular hunters and hid himself in a volcano.Level: VolcanoWeapon: Rising Fire (X) Ryuenjin (Zero)Objective: "Dragoon of the 14th unit is a traitor. Locate and bring him back to hunter HQ."SoundtrackCover ArtIn 2005 Capcom released a 5-disc box set called Capcom Music Generation Rockman X1~6. It contains the original music of Mega Man X through Mega Man X6 as well as some unused tracks. Mega Man X4 tracks span the entire third disc and the track listing is as follows:Track #TitleLength1.TITLE0:152.PLAYER SELECT0:243.STAGE SELECT1:074.OPENING STAGE X2:025.OPENING STAGE ZERO1:396.EREGION1:147.STAGE START0:168.WEB SPIDUS STAGE2:499.CYBER KUJACKER STAGE2:3310.STORM FUKUROUL STAGE2:2111.MAGMARD DRAGOON STAGE1:5812.JET STINGREN STAGE1:5413.SPRIT MUSHROOM STAGE2:4414.SLASH BEASTLEO STAGE2:4715.FROST KIBATODOS STAGE 12:1416.FROST KIBATODOS STAGE 22:3517.BOSS1:1618.STAGE CLEAR X0:1119.STAGE CLEAR ZERO0:1120.GET A WEAPON0:3921.STAGE SELECT 20:4522.FINAL WEAPON STAGE 11:3323.COLONELGENERAL1:1124.FINAL WEAPON STAGE 22:5025.DOUBLE1:4726.IRIS1:5227.SIGMA 1st2:0728.SIGMA 2nd1:3629.DR. RIGHT0:4630.DEMO 10:4831.DEMO 20:3332.SIGMA DEMO0:4433.INDEPENDENCE0:3434.BETRAYAL OF DOUBLE0:3135.ENDING X0:2436.MEMORY OF PAST 10:3937.MEMORY OF PAST 20:2238.COLONEL VS ZERO0:2439.PAST OF ZERO1:4240.ENDING ZERO0:30</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4350">Contra</game><game id="1257">Blaster Master</game><game id="4237">Contra 4</game><game id="6673">Castlevania</game><game id="3016">Contra III: The Alien Wars</game><game id="11684">Contra: Shattered Soldier</game><game id="847">Metal Slug</game><game id="1638">Mega Man X6</game><game id="26410">Strider</game><game id="8583">Metal Slug Advance</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1806100-box_mmx4.png</image></root>