<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20439</id><name>Shin Megami Tensei: Devil Summoner - Raidou Kuzunoha vs. the Soulless Army</name><description>OverviewShin Megami Tensei: Devil Summoner Raidou Kuzunoha vs The Soulless Army is not only a long title, but also the first foray into the action RPG genre for the Megami Tensei franchise. Taking place in Japan in the 1920s Japan, players take the control of an unnamed protagonist as he gains the title of Raidou Kuzunoha the 14th. The Raidou name is bestowed to the person who shall become the next in a line of devil summoners and can not only converse with demons, but travel into the dark side of areas to prevent demonic influences. In order to take up this task, Raidou is employed at Narumi detective agency. From there all kinds of claims and mysteries wait to be solved.The main story revolves around a family curse and an evil army sent to do the bidding of their dark master. When the Narumi detective agency gets a strange phone call from a young girl asking them to meet her on the bridge on the city outskirts, it was clear something strange was up. When she asks them to kill her, it was obvious. Before anything can happen however, a strange soldier in red grabs her, thus putting into motion the events that will take place throughout the game.As mentioned above this is an action RPG. Though it wouldn't be a MegaTen game without the demons. Sadly however, the conversation system is gone and all demons will be caught in battle by weakening them and mashing the circle button. Raidou does still have the fusion ability at his disposal allowing him to create some powerful demons to aid him in his task. The demons also play a larger investigative role as well. A Pixie for instance can read peoples minds and get the facts that they are keeping from Raidou. This creates a great feel for the game in which investigation and some small puzzle elements are required to advance the story as opposed to the franchises typical dungeon crawling.While it isn't your typical MegaTen game, Devil Summoner has its own charm and is a great game for anyone looking for a lighter, more humorous take on the MegaTen world while still having the great stories and characters you've come to love.CharactersRaidou Kuzunoha the XIVThe protagonist and player-character of the game. He's in his late teens and used to go to Yumizuki High School until he became a Devil Summoner. Afterward, he becomes an apprentice at the Narumi Detective Agency. Not much is known about him, however, since (like many other heroes in the Shin Megami Tensei series) he remains silent throughout most of the game. As a Devil Summoner he can capture demons in small tubes and use them to his advantage in battle, to help with his detective work, and fuse them to create more powerful demons. He uses a sword and pistol in battle, and various rounds of ammunition for that pistol. His partner throughout the game is a black cat named Gotou.GotouA black cat that accompanies Raidou throughout the game and acts as his partner. He claims to have worked with all the previous Devil Summoners named Raidou and that it is his mission to watch over them.Shohei NarumiThe owner of the Narumi Detective Agency, and Raidou's boss. He's somewhat lazy and mostly let's Raidou do all the detective work. He is in his early to mid twenties.Tae AsakuraNarumi's client. She's a reporter for the "Capital Daily" news who hires Narumi and Raidou to investigate the strange happenings in the Capital. She's a strong advocate for women's rights.Kaya DaidojiA local high school student who calls the Narumi Detective Agency and asks Narumi and Raidou to kill her, thus becoming a major focus for the two in their following case. Soon after the call she is kidnapped by a Red Guard. It is later revealed that she is the only heiress left to the wealthy Daidoji family name.RasputinThe infamous mad monk of Russia during the early 1900s. Eventually murdered after being shot four times, badly beaten, poisoned, and finally drowned. Somehow, he returns to life; palying a critical role in the strange happenings in the Capital, and also acts as the antagonist of the game. It is revealed that he is a skilled Devil Summoner himself, using small Russian dolls (instead of tubes) to capture and hold his demons.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9228">Parasite Eve</game><game id="22985">Linda³</game><game id="4001">Shadow Hearts: Covenant</game><game id="12788">Rule of Rose</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1845421-box_smtds.png</image></root>