<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20452</id><name>Fight Night Round 4</name><description>Overview EA's Fight Night series continues with Fight Night Round 4, which was  released on the Xbox 360 and PlayStation 3 on June 30th 2009. Fight  Night Round 4 was developed by EA Canada following the dissolution of  the previous FIght Night game developers, EA Chicago. This game focuses  more on inside fighting with a new physics-based style of gameplay. Gameplay  The gameplay is similar to previous FIght Night games. The left and  right analogue sticks controls your fighter's movement. Each kind of  punch is based on the movement of the analogue sticks. Punching is  controlled by your right analogue stick and movement with the left  analogue stick with an option to switch to button controls included via a downloadable patch.One  of the improvements over previous entries is the greater distinction  between the fighter's height and reach from each other. This has more  impact on the gameplay than in previous entries, leading to a clearer  distinction between fighters that are stronger in close range and those  who are better at a distance.  Improved damage model     Additional enhancements  were made to the damage model with fighters having more hitzones.  Blocking now has a meter, this meter decays over time, your overall risk  increases as the meter decreases. Punches can break through your guard  and your arms can be knocked out of the way more easily as your opponent  wears down your defence. The treatment of cuts between  rounds has been changed from previous entries as well. In Round 4, cut  work and the like is based on a points system. You will accumulate  points as fight and then choose to apply them to damaged areas in  between rounds. Legacy Mode   In Legacy Mode, players start their boxing career using a created boxer  or an existing one. This mode lets the player work their way up the  rankings. Fights are scheduled using the game's calendar. Depending on  the date, the player may get the chance to have one or more training sessions before their next bout.   The training sessions  raise different attributes and decrease others. These sessions can be  manually performed or can be set to auto. However, using the auto  setting will decrease the amount of points gained. The manual system  awards points based on how well the player performed while exercising.  The number of points gained will slow down if the fighter becomes older  or has reached his peak for a particular section. The in-game  calendar tells you when your next fight is scheduled and how long your  fighter will take to recover after each fight. The game simulates the  matches of other boxers when your fighter is not involved. At the end of  each year, awards are given out in categories such as Fighter of the  Year, Round of the Year, and Prospect of the Year.   Throughout a  fighter's career, the player is sent messages from their trainer  informing them whenever a belt changes hands, making the player aware of  up and coming fighters, and letting the player know when they have been  nominated for an award.  When you complete Legacy mode you are  given a ranking, this will depend on what you did during your career.  RosterThe roster contains a total of 50 fighters from the past and present of boxing. The weight classes include, Heavyweight, Light Heavy, Middleweight, Welterweight, Lightweight, Featherweight, Bantamweight and Flyweight. Amin Asikainen Anthony Mundine    Mike Tyson Arementa Arthur Abraham Arturo Gatti Billy Dib Carlos Monzon Corey Spinks Diego Corrales Eddie Chambers Edwim Valero Emanuel Agustus Erik Morales   Manny Pacquiao Fernando Montiel George Foreman Jake Lamotta James Toney Jermaine Taylor Joe Calzaghe Joe Frazier Jorge Armando Arce Julio Caesar Chavez Kelly Pavlik Kermit Cinteron Lennox Lewis Manny Pacquiao Marco Antonio Barrera   Muhammed Ali Marvin Hagler Miguel Cotto Mike Tyson Muhammad Ali Nate Campbell Nonito Donair Paulie Malignaggi Pernell Whittaker Ray Leonard Ray Robinson Ricky Hatton Roberto Duran Roberto Guerrero Ronald "Winky" Wright Roy Jones Jr. Sergio Mora Shane Mosely Thomas Hearns Tommy Morrison Victor Ortiz Vinny Paz Vivian Harris Yuriorkis GamboaXbox 360 Hard Drive InstallInstalling Fight Night Round 4 takes up about 4.4 GB of space on your hard drive.Post-Release UpdatesOn July 28, 2009, EA released a free of charge pack which included a new training gym, new gameplay sliders, and new equipment to outfit boxers.Another update that added a face button control scheme in place of the default layout which is based on using the right analog stick for punches was released. Downloadable Content A new batch of boxers are available for download for 400MS points or $4.99. This boxer pack includes Oscar De La Hoya, Vitali Klitschko, Wladimir Klitschko, and different versions of George Foreman and James Toney.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="20">Boxing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21455">Black &amp; Bruised</game><game id="19836">Ready 2 Rumble Boxing</game><game id="13997">George Foreman's KO Boxing</game><game id="26611">Tournament of Legends</game><game id="23965">Punch-Out!!</game><game id="20675">Don King Presents: Prizefighter</game><game id="25648">Don King Boxing</game><game id="1031">Muhammad Ali Heavyweight Boxing</game><game id="14022">Rocky Super Action Boxing</game><game id="32371">Fighters Uncaged</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1894708-box_fnr4.png</image></root>