<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20469</id><name>TNA iMPACT!</name><description>OverviewTNA iMPACT! is a pro-wresting game based on the Total Nonstop Acton promotion. Developed and published by Midway, the game brings to fans many of their favorite wrestlers in both likeness and voice, and allows them to duke it out in fast-paced matches with less emphasis on the submission maneuvers found in many pro-wrestling games and more on combative wrestling moves. AJ Styles, Samoa Joe, Christopher Daniels, Senshi, Sonjay Dutt, and Jeff Jarrett were brought in to provide the motion capture animations for the game. Every real life TNA wrestler had their bodies scanned in for an authentic look and an original character was made specifically for the game, Suicide, who jumped into reality on TNA programming shortly after the game's release. StoryThe story revolves around the wrestler Suicide who fights his way back to the top of TNA after receiving a severe beating and left for dead in Mexico. After his vicious attack, Suicide has a plastic surgery procedure done introducing his new look (the player's created wrestler) and has no recollection as to who he is or what happened to him. Players then participate in matches  in the middle of nowhere leading to a tryout and eventually a spot on the TNA roster. Once with TNA you will fight your way through all 3 tiers (tag, X-Division  World Heavyweight) regaining memories along the way until you finally remember who you are and what happened to you. WrestlersTNA iMPACT! features 25 of TNA's finest wrestlers and 5 bonus characters but excludes the TNA Knockouts. Roster:                              AJ Styles                            Samoa Joe                           Booker T                          Christian Cage                         Christopher Daniels                        Hernandez                       Homicide                      Jay Lethal                     Kurt Angle                    Sting                    Rhino                   Tomko                 Jeff Jarrett                Abyss               Senshi              Scott Steiner             Chris Sabin            Alex Shelley           Eric Young          Shark Boy         Kevin Nash        Robert Roode       James Storm      Sonjay Dutt     Brother Ray    Brother Devon DLC Characters:    Petey Williams  Curry Man Mike Tenay  Matches  Standard Tag Team  Free For All Ultimate X  Ultimate X Free For All  Submission  Falls Count Anywhere  Falls Count Anywhere Tag  Handicap  OnlineThe Xbox 360 and Playstation 3 versions of the game enable players to battle online with up to two players. Players cannot take created wrestlers online. Style PointsTNA iMPACT! has a points system known as Style Points, you earn style points by performing moves during matches. The points can be used to unlock new Wrestlers, Arenas and CAW Moves. Unlockables  Unlockable Wrestlers   Abyss: Defeat Abyss during Story Mode  Brother Ray: Defeat Team 3D during Story Mode  Eric Young: Win the tag match with Eric Young during Story Mode  Jay Lethal: Defeat Jay Lethal during Story Mode  Kevin Nash: Defeat Kevin Nash during Story Mode  Sonjay Dutt: Defeat Sonjay Dutt during Story Mode  Tomko: Defeat Tomko  AJ Styles in the Tag Team match during Story Mode  Jeff Jarrett: Complete Story mode.  Suicide: Complete Story mode.  Don West: Accumulate 250,000 Style Points.  Senshi: Accumulate 200,000 Style Points.  Benny: Accumulate 350,000 Style Points.  Lenny: Accumulate 400,000 Style Points.  Afro Thunder: Accumulate 750,000 Style Points in the PlayStation3, Xbox 360 or Wii version.   Unlockable Arenas   Armory: Win all your matches in the Armory Arena during Story Mode  Freedom Center: Win all your matches in the Freedom Center Arena during Story Mode  Japan: Win all of your matches in Japan during Story Mode  Mexico: Win the Gauntlet Match in Mexico during Story Mode  Vegas: Win your match in the Vegas Arena during Story Mode  England: Accumulate 420,000 Style Points. Unlockable CAW Moves   Wheelbarrow Neckbreaker: 120,000 Style Points  Full Nelson Suplex: 130,000 Style Points  Basement Dropkick: 140,000 Style Points  Crotch Punch: 156,000 Style Points  Twisting Crossbody: 184,000 Style Points  Tornado DDT: 192,000 Style Points  The Book End: 200,000 Style Points  Eye Rake: 208,000 Style Points  Neckbreaker: 216,000 Style Points  Tailbreaker: 232,000 Style Points  The Cradle Shock: 240,000 Style Points  Jawbreaker: 240,000 Style Points  Leg Sweep: 252,000 Style Points  German Suplex: 268,000 Style Points  Dragon Suplex: 280,000 Style Points  The Border Toss: 290,000 Style Points  Atomic Drop: 312,000 Style Points  The Gore: 320,000 Style Points  Hurricanrana: 332,000 Style Points  Running Neckbrkr: 340,000 Style Points  The Gringo Killer: 360,000 Style Points  Mexican Head Scissors: 376,000 Style Points  Cutter: 388,000 Style Points  Hangman's Neckbreaker: 400,000 Style Points  Sonjay Cutter: 615,600 Style Points  The Steiner Recliner: 648,000 Style Points  The Styles Clash: 680,400 Style Points  The Stroke: 712,800 Style Points  The Unprettier: 745,200 Style Points  The Black Hole Slam: 777,600 Style Points  The Angle Slam: 842,400 Style Points  Canadian Destroyer: 972,000 Style Points</description><genres><genre id="10">Wrestling</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20680">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2009</game><game id="11394">WWF No Mercy</game><game id="12592">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2008</game><game id="6">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2007</game><game id="6945">ECW Anarchy Rulz</game><game id="22464">Wrestling Encore</game><game id="1204">WCW Mayhem</game><game id="3826">WWF Super Wrestlemania</game><game id="18801">WWF War Zone</game><game id="20723">WWE Legends of WrestleMania</game><game id="21620">WWE Day of Reckoning 2</game><game id="26888">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2010</game><game id="30637">Lucha Libre AAA Heroes del Ring</game><game id="13440">Backyard Wrestling: Don't Try This at Home</game><game id="18333">Backyard Wrestling 2: There Goes the Neighborhood</game><game id="31640">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2011</game><game id="28430">WWF Royal Rumble</game><game id="31641">WWE All Stars</game><game id="35483">WWE '12</game><game id="38395">WWE '13</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14036/824181-tna_cover.jpg</image></root>