<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20465</id><name>Condemned 2: Bloodshot</name><description>PlotEthan Thomas11 months after the original Condemned: Criminal Origins, Bloodshot features a Ethan Thomas. Consumed by alcohol and living on the streets, the now grief-bearded Thomas is recruited back into the SCU in order to deal with a city-wide phenomenon wreaking havoc and leaving mass delirium in its wake. Dealing with inner demons, Thomas will find the answers that he seeks, uncovering the dark truth hidden behind all of the problems plaguing not only the city, and himself.Single PlayerEthan using forensic equipment to solve the crime.Bloodshot brings back that same blunt and bloody combat as its predecessor, now in an even grittier environment. A first person action game, Bloodshot offers new ways of pummeling enemies not seen in the original, including hand-to-hand combat. The player can also chain attacks together, creating combos from simple little jabs and hooks to much more complex tactics. The game also offers environmental kills, which are dependent on the level. Investigation and problem solving also return from the original.Bloodshot offers a wide array of melee weapons and firearms, now with a durability element. Most melee weapons will degrade, forcing the player to look for other implements of destruction. Ammo is restricted to what is in the firearm at the moment the player gets a hold of the weapon. Due to his alcoholism, Ethan is incapable of steady aim when sober, and requires frequent doses of alcohol in order to fix his shaking hands and blurred vision. Additional special abilities are unlocked later in the game. The investigation aspects are enhanced. In addition to forensic photography, blood spatter patterns can be analyzed to identify bullet wounds, stabs wounds, blunt force trauma, so on.An alternate game mode unlocked after beating the game called FPS mode, wherein the player is allowed to start each level or mission with one firearm and unlimited ammo. Any guns procured in the level also have unlimited ammo after you pick them up. Completing this mode unlocks an achievement.LevelsRock BottomPreston HotelCommuter TracksDoll FactorySCU BuildingCity MuseumBlack Lake LodgeTrenton DistrictMagic TheaterJunk BargeThe PeninsulaMultiplayerStraight up DeathmatchCondemned 2: Bloodshot is first in the series to offer multiplayer, which includes four modes:Deathmatch - First player to reach the kill limit or to have the most kills by the end of the round wins.Team Deathmatch - Same as regular Deathmatch, only with teams.Bum Rush - SCU against the bums. The SCU can one shot kill the bums, have guns, and more health, but cannot respawn.Crime Scene - Bums must hide two pieces of evidence while the SCU must attempt to find it before time runs out.When beginning a match, the player chooses between SCU or bums. There are numerous character models. Bums usually wear masks such as a pig's face, hockey masks, and clown masks. Weapon selection is tied to faction. SCU players can choose from the shotgun, rifle, or pistol. Bums choose from a brick, Molotov cocktail, or 2x4. There are nine multiplayer maps, however several curb stomp finishers and environment specific kills are not present in it.Xbox 360 Game InstallationCondemned 2: Bloodshot requires 6.8GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4800">F.E.A.R.: First Encounter Assault Recon</game><game id="20663">F.E.A.R. 2: Project Origin</game><game id="6108">Manhunt</game><game id="21173">MadWorld</game><game id="11085">The Chronicles of Riddick: Escape from Butcher Bay</game><game id="20987">The Chronicles of Riddick: Assault on Dark Athena</game><game id="11787">F.E.A.R.: Extraction Point</game><game id="15596">F.E.A.R.: Perseus Mandate</game><game id="22860">The Hunt</game><game id="3748">Urban Chaos: Riot Response</game><game id="17070">F.E.A.R. Combat</game><game id="13385">Breakdown</game><game id="17280">BioShock</game><game id="21478">Cryostasis</game><game id="9201">The Darkness</game><game id="23217">SAW</game><game id="23254">Shellshock 2: Blood Trails</game><game id="30629">SAW II: Flesh &amp; Blood</game><game id="20827">BioShock 2</game><game id="3841">The Suffering</game><game id="11870">The Suffering:  Ties That Bind</game><game id="36028">Black Death</game><game id="38078">The Dead Linger</game><game id="40089">Outlast</game><game id="41535">Daylight</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14036/824167-condemned2_cover.jpg</image></root>