<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20474</id><name>Aliens vs. Predator: Requiem</name><description>Alien vs Predator: Requiem is based on the movie of the same name that was developed by Rebellion Developments and was published by Sierra Entertainment. Rebellion Developments had previous experience with Alien vs Predator, developing and releasing Alien vs Predator on the Atari Jaguar. It is exclusively for the PSP (PlayStation Portable) and was released November 23, 2007, a month in advance to hype the movie. The game was also released on November 30th in Europe and December 6th in Australia. With the development of Alien vs Predator: Requiem, Rebellion was given materials from the film's production, including footage and the full script, in order to recreate the feel of the film and lend authenticity to the game.  The plot of the game is loosely based on the plot of the film. In the game, players take the role of the "Wolf" Predator in the film. The game is a third person action-adventure game with the single player part of the game being around 15 missions. The goal of the game is is to hunt the aliens that have gotten lose in the small American town and wipe out any trace of them and to avoid detection from the humans. While playing the missions, you can choose between three different paths throughout the game, with optional objectives to disassemble pieces of the Predators Technology. The player has the ability to stealth camouflage and has several vision modes, such as infrared. The player earns "Honor Points" during these missions, which allow the player to obtain extra weapons, such as the disk blade, dual sholder cannons, the plasma cannon and the predator spear. Health is represented by a segmented life bar that regenerates after a successful kill and and an energy bar is also available to provide power for the Predator's weapons.Nearly all of the reviews for the game were negative, describing the game as not "bad", just not "good", saying that it was just another entry in a long line of poorly-developed movie tie-ins. Reviewers enjoyed the opportunity to play as a Predator, but complained that the game was way too easy and not rewarding, complaining that the A.I. of the enemy's was way too simple and that it came to just "furiously mashing buttons" to get through the game. The critics talk about how poor the game's visuals and audio are, even on the PSP. The critics also compare it to Miami Vice: The Game, a previous Rebellion PSP title, stating that "[Miami Vice: The Game is] one of those games that's not bad, but nor is it ever that good."</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8142">Alien vs Predator</game><game id="21299">Alien vs. Predator</game><game id="16068">Aliens Versus Predator 2: Primal Hunt</game><game id="1297">Alien Vs. Predator</game><game id="9498">Alien vs Predator: The Last of His Clan</game><game id="13125">Aliens Versus Predator: Extinction</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2285626-box_avpr.png</image></root>