<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20481</id><name>Battlestations: Pacific</name><description>OverviewBattlestations: Pacific is an action-RTS set during World War II in the Pacific Theater. It is a blend of the action and real-time strategy genres, with players able to order an entire fleet around the map and also take control of individual units. It offers two campaigns - one each for the United States and Japan. The US campaign is a direct sequel to Battlestations Midway, whereas the Japanese campaign is based on an alternate version of history in which Japan wins the Battle of Midway and carries out its historical war plan successfully.PlotAmerican CampaignThe American Campaigns kicks off from the end of the battle of Midway and you continue fighting historically accurate battles at Guadalcanal, Leyte, and Okinawa and more.Japanese CampaignThe Japanese Campaign starts at the Battle of Pear Harbor, and continues in a fictional world where the Japanese could have won, you fight through 14 missions through Australia, Guadalcanal, fighting the Americans, the Australians, and the British.MultiplayerThe Multiplayer consists of 5 modes of which are:Island CaptureThis mode consists of 2-8 players in teams of two fighting over control of chains of islands. Usually consisting of many tiny islands, and one central island.DuelA free for all game mode, where the teams play as one unit, such as multiple battleships and pit it out against one another.EscortSimilar to a VIP game type, where one team protects an objective, such as a ship convoy, while another team attacks.SiegeThis is similar to an attack and defend game type. Where one team tries to capture an island, while the other team defends.CompetitiveYour standard team deathmatch mode.System RequirementsMinimumOS: Microsoft Windows XP (admin rights required)/Microsoft Windows Vista (admin rights required)Processor: Intel Pentium 4 3 GHz or AMD Athlon 2.5 GHzMemory: 1GB (Windows XP) / 2GB (Windows Vista) system memoryGraphics: NVIDIA GeForce 6 series 6800GT (or better) / ATI 1800XT (or better)Hard Drive: 8 GB Free SpaceSound: Direct X 9.0c compatible sound card and driversRecommendedOS: Microsoft Windows XP (admin rights required)/Microsoft Windows Vista (admin rights required)Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo 2.2 GHz or Athlon 64 X2 4400Memory: 2 GB system memoryGraphics: nVidia GeForce 9800 GTX or ATI HD4800Hard Drive: 8 GB Free SpaceSound: Direct X 9.0c compatible sound card and driversInput Devices: Keyboard and mouse / Xbox 360 Controller for Windows</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20952">World in Conflict: Soviet Assault</game><game id="22827">Naval Ops: Commander</game><game id="18377">Heroes of the Pacific</game><game id="20968">Heroes Over Europe</game><game id="12047">IL-2 Sturmovik</game><game id="1179">IL-2 Sturmovik: 1946</game><game id="9926">Rowan's Battle of Britain</game><game id="12098">Turning Point: Fall of Liberty</game><game id="30639">Naval Assault: The Killing Tide</game><game id="36235">World of Warships</game><game id="23071">Navy Field</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1906702-box_bsp.png</image></root>