<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20482</id><name>Beowulf: The Game</name><description>OverviewBeowulf shows no mercy.Beowulf: The Game is a third-person action game based on Robert Zemeckis' movie released in 2007. The game features numerous quick time events (looking especially well during the boss battles) and limited character development. Beowulf can fight with different weapons with 2 attack buttons (as he can collect new ones during his quest), grapple the enemies (what may be followed by disarming, throwing or beating them up in several ways). Some of the most bloody moves can be performed when the protagonist enters the carnal power mode, which gives him a temporary damage boost. Beowulf has a group of Thanes under his command and he can give them simple orders such as: open, follow, boost. The game also features several rhythm game segments (e.g. completing a song succesfully speeds up opening the door or is necessary in order to lure Grendel). The hero is pitted against regular-sized enemies, as well as bigger creatures (trolls) and large boss characters - each enemy type can be finished in various bloody ways.StoryHey, it's almost Angie!The story is divided into three parts. In the first one players play as young Beowulf from racing Brecca (what was mentioned in the movie as well) to the point where Beowulf becomes a king after defeating Grendel and meeting his mother. The second part enables players to live through the period that was not covered in the movie and features several missions as a young king. The final act is the ultimate showdown between old king Beowulf and the Dragon.Bossesvs. GrendelSea SerpentGrendelThe WolfBreccaHelaThe DragonGrendel's Mother (not exactly a boss with a health bar)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20621">Viking: Battle for Asgard</game><game id="21210">Conan</game><game id="6959">God of War</game><game id="20461">God of War III</game><game id="11314">God of War II</game><game id="20592">God of War: Chains of Olympus</game><game id="20928">Golden Axe: Beast Rider</game><game id="31180">God of War: Ghost of Sparta</game><game id="32687">Ninja Gaiden 3</game><game id="39754">Wild Blood</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2243841-box_beowulf.png</image></root>