<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20497</id><name>Dark Sector</name><description>OverviewDark Sector was developed by Digital Extremes for the Xbox 360 and PlayStation 3 and was released on March 25, 2008 through D3 Publisher. It was released on the PC a year later, published by Aspyr Media. Originally planned to feature a sci-fi setting with the main character being a man in an advanced armored suit, it was later changed to a more realistic setting in military bases, abandoned towns, and other grittier environments . The developers stated that this was because of other developers and publishers shifting their attention to more realistic settings. Gameplay revolves around cover, third-person shooting, and the use of a bladed projectile weapon called the glaive.GameplayThe glaive can be used at the same time as one-handed guns. Throwing the glaive can stun enemies, setting them up for melee finishing moves; with enough accumulated damage, the glaive can also dismember foes, killing them immediately even if only a limb is severed. Hayden's disease mutates over time, resulting in new abilities as the story progresses. One of these new powers is the ability to perform charged up "power throws". These power throws will decapitate most minor enemies in one hit. Soon after learning power throws, Hayden obtains "aftertouch", allowing him to directly control the path of the glaive in mid-flight. The glaive can also absorb the "elements" such as fire, ice, and electricity for improved combat abilities as well as involvement in the game's puzzle-solving. It also serves as a boomerang, capable of collecting items that are too far for Hayden to reach.There is also a heavy amount of gunplay. The shooting is reminiscent of Gears of War, with a similar over-the-shoulder perspective and cover system. However, there is no blind fire, increasing the importance of the glaive because it is capable of killing enemies while Hayden is still taking cover. There are also collectible upgrades throughout the game's chapters, which can be added to the guns during visits to the black market. Upgrades are permanent and take up limited slots on each gun.PlotThe story begins with Hayden Tenno, an operative from an unnamed United States agency (the game's multiplayer simply refers to it as "The Agency"), on a mission in the fictional Eastern European nation of Lasria. He possesses a disease called congenital analgia which mostly nullifies his ability to feel pain. Hayden kills a captured U.S. agent named Viktor, because he is believed to be infected by the Technocyte Virus, a disease that transforms its victims into powerful abominations, and then pursues a man named Mezner. Mezner is the man responsible for unleashing the virus in the first place. The mutation process is so painful that it usually drives the infected insane. As Hayden tracks down Mezner, he meets the Nemesis, an imposing, gladiator-esque creature in an armoured suit. After a brief fight Hayden is defeated and infected, but due to his disease, he does not feel the agonizing pain to the extent that others do, and so he is not driven into madness. He remains mostly in control of himself and his thoughts, able to use the disease to his advantage. Hayden sets out to find Mezner and stop the spread of the virus.LevelsPrologueExposureBaggage ClaimMoths to the FlameThe ShipmentThe BaitIndustrial EvolutionUnnatural HistoryThreshold GuardianThe Dark SectorCharactersHayden Tenno:Dark Sector's protagonist who is infected with the Technocyte virus, giving him his unique in game abilities, is out to stop the spread of the virus across the worldRobert Mezner:Dark Sector's antagonist is also infected with the Technocyte virus. Hoping to create a new race, Mezner attempts to release the Technocyte virus across the planet.Yargo Menshik:Also known as a "sleeper agent", Yargo is an expert on the Technocyte virus and Hayden's main provider of intel and advice throughout the game.Nadia Sudek:A female agent working under Mezner. She and Hayden were once romantically involved, but the story does not elaborate upon it.Viktor:An agent similar to Hayden also working for the agency. Hayden's initial mission is to find Viktor, who is believed to be infected, and murder him. His relevance to the story is extremely minor.The Black Market Dealer:The game's dealer sets up shop in sewers accessible through various manholes; he allows the player to buy, sell and upgrade weapons. The character shares similarities to The Merchant, a character from Resident Evil 4.Weapons and UpgradesThroughout Dark Sector the player is able to purchase new weapons and find new upgrades.Sidearms1: Tekna 9mmAmmo: PistolRound Capacity: 12Price: 9000 RublesFirst Available: Chapter One2: Tekna BurstAmmo: PistolRound Capacity: 26Price: 10500 RublesFirst Available: Chapter Four3. Vekesk MicroAmmo: Machine GunRound Capacity: 30Price: 21000 RublesFirst Available: Chapter Four4. SpectreAmmo: ShotgunRound Capacity: 2Price: 28000 RublesFirst Available: Chapter Six5. Hammer 1895Ammo: MagnumRound Capacity: 6Price: 32000 RublesFirst Available: Chapter SixAssault Weapons1: AKS-74Ammo: Machine GunRound Capacity: 30Price: 20000 RublesFirst Available: Chapter Four2: StrikerAmmo: ShotgunRound Capacity: 6Price: 26000 RublesFirst Available: Chapter Four3: ProtectaAmmo: ShotgunRound Capacity: 12Price: 39000 RublesFirst Available: Chapter Five4: VX CarbineAmmo: MagnumRound Capacity: 6Price: 30000 RublesFirst Available: Chapter Five5: Korbov TK6Ammo: Machine GunRound Capacity: 30Price: 40000First Available: Chapter SevenSpecial Weapons1: RPGAmmo: RPGsRound Capacity: 4Price: This item cannot be purchased. Found throughout levels and carried by some enemies.First Available: Chapter One2: Gatling GunAmmo: Machine Gun / RPGRound Capacity: UnlimitedSecondary Capacity: 10Price: This item cannot be purchased. Dropped by soldiers in exo-suits.First Available: Unknown3: Frag GrenadeAmmo: NullRound Capacity: NullPrice: Item cannot be purchased. Dropped by enemies.First Available: Chapter OneWeapon UpgradesUpgrades can be found hidden throughout the game in aluminum suitcases.1: AccuracyAvailable to: EverythingThis upgrade decreases the size of your guns accuracy circle. Although it does not shrink it past the guns normal maximum accuracy point. Using your glaive with after touch completely removes the necessity of this upgrade.2: Double ShotAvailable to: EverythingThe Double Shot upgrade makes each gun fire twice in one shot. This upgrade can be deadly when used with a shotgun or magnum weapon.3: Fire RateAvailable to: EverythingThis upgrade does exactly what is sounds like it would do. It increases the firing speed of a weapon. It helps on slower pistols and shotguns, but generally is not necessarily needed.4: Reload SpeedAvailable to: EverythingReload Speed allows you to reload your weapon faster then normal. Except for the fact that Hayden already reloads all of his guns at a fast pace, it would be a better idea to just sell this upgrade for money.5: PunctureAvailable to: MagnumThis allows bullets to pass through an enemy and into one directly behind him. This upgrade is generally pointless when you have your glaive that can do the same thing for free. It would again be a better idea to sell this upgrade instead of using it.6: Stopping PowerAvailable to: Shotgun, MagnumThis upgrade allows your shots to knock enemies over allowing you to shoot them more. This upgrade does not cause any more damage to the enemy.7: Enferon ShellsAvailable to: EverythingEnferon Shells are a rare upgrade in the game and should be used carefully. The upgrade coats your ammunition in Enferon and is highly affective on the infected. A few shots will cause them to swell up and die of convulsions (after around 10 seconds).8: Clip ExtenderAvailable to: EverythingThis upgrade will extend your ammo capacity by 25%. On longarms it is stackable up to 100% (using four upgrades) and on sidearms only to 75%. The only exception to this rule as pointed out by others is the Spectre which only gets one extra shell.9: FirepowerAvailable to: EverythingFirepower is an extremley rare upgrade with only four scattered through the game. They will increase the firepower strength of your weapon.10: Upgrade SlotAvailable to: EverythingThe rarest upgrade in the game which can only be found in timed levels of the game. It allows you to add one more upgrade slot to your weapon of choice (if that weapon is not already maxed out in upgrade slots).Technocyte Powers (Special Abilities)1: Steal / GrabAchieved in: Chapter TwoAllows Hayden to use the glaive to grab items from a distance by throwing it at them.2: Power ThrowAchieved in: Chapter ThreeAllows the glaive to break special chains and locks. It also kills most enemies in one hit.3: After TouchAchieved in: Chapter ThreeLets the player control the movement of the glaive in slow motion.4: ShieldAchieved in: Chapter FourGenerates a shield in front of Hayden which blocks most all attacks and deflects projectiles back in his facing direction.5: Energy PulseAchieved in: Chapter FiveAllows Hayden to create an energy explosion with the glaive when it is thrown and charged with any elemental power (fire, electricity, and ice).6: Shift / InvisibilityAchieved in: Chapter SevenTurns Hayden invisible for a short period of time, allowing for stealth kills and bypassing some security systems. Invisibility automatically ends when the player attacks.Reclassification In AustraliaOn Feburary 18th, 2008, Dark Sector was refused classification by the Office of Film  Literature Classification board (OFLC), due to the games high-impact level of violence, and deemed unsuitable for audiences under the age of 18 years old. The OFLC stated:"The finishing moves and most violent game play includes decapitation, dismemberment of limbs accompanied by large blood spurts, neck breaking spurts, neck breaking twists and exploded bodies with post-action twitching body parts. These moves are relatively easy to accomplish and once the player has mastered the moves and is able to get close to his foes, these violent moves can be executed... Successfully shooting an opponent results in the depiction of blood spray. When Hayden cuts off his opponent's limb with the glaive, large amounts of blood spray forth from the stump and the injured person screams in agony which increases the impact."Dark Sector was later reclassified with MA15+ classification and released in Australia on October 9th 2008. Featuring no decapitations and toned down dismemberment on human opponents. This heavily censored version was based on the Japanese version, which was also slightly sanitised before its release. HDD InstallationDark Sector requires 1.3 GB of installation space for the Playstation 3 version and an optional 1.3GB of space to install for the Xbox 360 version.PC System RequirementsOperating System Windows XP SP3, Vista SP1CPU Intel Dual Core 2.0 Ghz or AMD Athlon 4000Memory XP- 1 GB, Vista 2 GBHard Drive Space 6.1 GB; 1 GB swap fileSound Card Directx 9.0 compatibleVideo Card ATI Radeon X1600, Nvidia Geforce 7600Media Required 6x DVD-ROM drive</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12231">Gears of War</game><game id="1152">kill.switch</game><game id="20662">Gears of War 2</game><game id="20703">Dark Void</game><game id="20537">Lost Planet: Extreme Condition - Colonies Edition</game><game id="20479">Army of Two</game><game id="18596">Power Blade II</game><game id="15774">WinBack: Covert Operations</game><game id="21621">Wanted: Weapons of Fate</game><game id="25413">Lost Planet 2</game><game id="20454">50 Cent: Blood on the Sand</game><game id="27951">Twin Sector</game><game id="13552">Krull</game><game id="24041">Quantum Theory</game><game id="20800">Dead Space</game><game id="12354">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Chaos Theory</game><game id="22864">MorphX</game><game id="11725">S.T.A.L.K.E.R.: Shadow of Chernobyl</game><game id="4209">Prototype</game><game id="31555">Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows: Part 1</game><game id="35514">Star Trek: The Video Game</game><game id="22425">The Darkness II</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14036/824169-dark_sector_cover.jpg</image></root>