<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>205</id><name>Pursuit Force</name><description>OverviewIn Pursuit Force, the player is hired as the only agent working for this organization. Single-handedly, the player must destroy all six gangs; "The Capelli Family", "The Warlords", "The Convicts", "The Vixens", and "The Killer 66". Each gang has six missions, with the last one always fighting the boss or the leader of one of the gangs. Each gang has unique style. For example, the convicts are escaped criminals and their weapons and vehicles reflect this, they are crude and poorly made.To defeat the gangs the player has to destroy vehicles, people, jump from car to car and escort and protect people. In Pursuit Force there are a variety of vehicles such as cars, trucks, motorbikes, boats, helicopters, buses and trucks. After winning a certain number of missions, the player's rank increases and there are unlockables and more missions available.You can also do races in Pursuit Force. These will put you in he boots of members of the different crime families and give you a number of different scenarios to do. While the premise is still the same, win the race, you can ride in a number of different cars.Lack of Sleep ModePursuit Force is one of the only PSP titles (if not the only PSP titles) in which sleep mode is evidently disabled. (This applies to both the UMD and PSN versions.) The player cannot put to sleep or even power off the PSP while the game is running. The only way to stop playing is to use the Home button and exit the game. This in turn also means that the player must sit through the bootup sequences for the game each time they decide to play it.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9259">Twisted Metal: Head-On</game><game id="23527">Hardware 2</game><game id="13281">Chase H.Q.</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2154880-box_pforce.png</image></root>