<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20500</id><name>Dragon Ball Z: Burst Limit</name><description>The game has a story mode, a versus mode, a trial challenge mode, and a tutorial. The story mode is divided into certain sagas and ends before the Majin Buu saga.Story Mode SagasSaiyan SagaThe saiyan saga focuses on the events at the beginning of the series, culminating with the fight of Goku VS. Vegeta.Goku in his final effort against Frieza Frieza SagaThe Frieza Saga focuses on the events which take place on the planet Namek. It encompasses the series of fights that Gohan, Krillin, and Vegeta take on before Goku's arrival. It then focuses on Goku's efforts against the Ginyu Force and ultimately culminates with a duel between Goku and Frieza.Cell SagaThe Cell saga encompasses both the android saga and the cell games events. It culminates with the fight of Teen Gohan and Perfect Cell.Bardock SagaThe Bardock Saga is an out of continuity saga which focuses on Bardock. Players take control of Bardock as he faces off with Frieza, Krillin, Vegeta and culminates with a fight against Goku.Broly charging his ultimate attack Broly Saga The Broly saga is an out of continuity saga which puts the player in control of Broly. Players fight against Krillin, Teen Gohan, Piccolo, Trunks, Vegeta, and end the arc with a fight against Goku.GameplayDragon Ball Z: Burst Limit is set apart from previous games with the introduction of Drama Pieces. Drama pieces are short cutscenes that play out during a battle once certain conditions are met. They often have effects on the status of characters, such as the increase or decrease of a character's health, defense, or ki. Versus In the versus mode players choose a partner before each fight who sometimes jump in and deliver an attack to their opponent just before leaving. Trial ChalengesTrial challenges ask players to win 100 matches without dying or finish ten matches within a time limit. Story modeZ Chronicles, the game's story mode differs from past games in that players don't choose the character they play as. Instead, players are commonly placed in the shoes of whatever character wins the major fights throughout the series.Some of the more general gameplay changes include not being able to charge up ki energy. Rather, it fills up automatically during fights. Once full players can use aura spark, use ultimate attacks, and if available complete transformations.Ultimate attacks are the game's equivalent of special moves. Each character has one or more, and chooses before each match in versus mode. It's not uncommon for a single ultimate attack to take away en entire bar of an opponent's health. Aura Spark lasts only a short while. It makes players stronger and allows them to knock their opponents into the air, initiating a short minigame. Both players must mash the face buttons to get their color (red or blue) to fill a bar on the bottom of the screen. The bar is divided into three sections. The players that starts the game has to get their color from the left to the right; the player on the receiving end must get their color from the right to the left. If both colors are in the middle then the minigame ends in a draw. If the players that starts it gets their color to the far end then they win and do quite a bit of damage to their opponent. However, the player that gets hit with this move can reverse it if they are fast enough.CreditsJapanese Voice :                                                      Goku -                                                       Masako Nozawa Japanese Voice : Kid/Teen                                                     Gohan - Masako Nozawa Japanese Voice :                                                   Vegeta -                                                    Ryo Horikawa Japanese Voice :                                                 Trunks -                                                  Takeshi Kusao Japanese Voice :                                                Yamcha -                                               Toru Furuya Japanese Voice :                                              Krillin -                                             Mayumi Tanaka Japanese Voice :                                            Tien -                                           Hirotaka Suzuoki Japanese Voice :                                          Piccolo -                                         Toshio Furukawa Japanese Voice :                                        Frieza -                                       Ryusei Nakao Japanese Voice :                                      Cell -                                     Norio Wakamoto Japanese Voice :                                   Broly -                                    Bin Shimada Japanese Voice :                                  Bardock - Masako Nozawa Japanese Voice :                                 Nappa - Shozo Iizuka Japanese Voice :                                Raditz -                               Shigeru Chiba Japanese Voice :                              Ginyu -                             Hideyuki Hori Japanese Voice :                            Recoome -                           Kenji Utsumi Japanese Voice :                          Android 16 -                         Hikaru Midorikawa Japanese Voice :                        Android 17 -                       Shigeru Nakahara Japanese Voice :                      Android 18 -                     Miki Itou Original Author -                    Akira Toriyama English Voice of Captain Ginyu -                   Brice Armstrong English Voice of Piccolo, Yamcha, Vegeta, and Recoome -                  Christopher Sabat English Voice of Android 17 -                 Chuck Huber English Voice of Cell -                Dameon Clarke English Voice of Trunks -               Eric Vale English Voice of Android 16 -              Jeremy Inman English Voice of Tien and Saibamen -             John Burgmeier English Voice of Raditz -            Justin Cook English Voice of Frieza -           Linda Young English Voice of Android 18 -          Meredith McCoy English Voice of Nappa -         Phil Parsons English Voice of Goku -        Sean Schemmel English Voice of Krillin and Bardock - Sonny Strait English Voice of Kid Gohan and Teen Gohan -       Stephanie Nadolny English Voice of Broly -      Vic Mignogna Roundcall Voice -     Mike McFarland Voice of Super Buu - Justin Cook Voice of Majin Buu -    Josh Martin  Common CriticismsThe game is commonly criticized for not doing a good job of explaining the story beyond brief dialogue before fights. Many others have felt that the game offers much less than those prior. It has less characters and moves available, all of which are unlocked after one playthrough. Something that was impossible in most of the previous games.Xbox 360 Game InstallationDragon Ball Z: Burst Limit requires 3.4GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20486">Bleach: Shattered Blade</game><game id="707">Virtua Fighter 5</game><game id="20903">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja Storm</game><game id="20678">Soulcalibur IV</game><game id="22231">Bleach: Blade Battlers 2nd</game><game id="18522">Onimusha: Blade Warriors</game><game id="7792">Dead or Alive 4</game><game id="22723">YuYu Hakusho: Dark Tournament</game><game id="11065">Shaman King: Power of Spirit</game><game id="22974">Bleach: Heat the Soul 3</game><game id="25280">Naruto Gekitou Ninja Taisen Ex</game><game id="25297">Naruto Gekitou Ninja Taisen 4</game><game id="20456">Street Fighter IV</game><game id="27582">Saint Seiya: The Hades</game><game id="27495">Naruto Shippuden: Ultimate Ninja 5</game><game id="30539">Naruto Shippuden: Ultimate Ninja Storm 2</game><game id="30786">Naruto Shippuden Ultimate Ninja Heroes 3</game><game id="31236">Dragon Ball Z: Tenkaichi Tag Team</game><game id="33356">Bid For Power</game><game id="35032">Kinnikuman Muscle Grand Prix Max 2: Tokumori</game><game id="32688">Asura's Wrath</game><game id="42977">Dragon Ball Z: Battle of Z</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14036/824165-burstlimit_cover.jpg</image></root>