<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20534</id><name>LEGO Indiana Jones: The Original Adventures</name><description>OverviewReleased on June 3, 2008 for   PC,   PS2,   PS3,   PSP,   Xbox 360,   DS, and   Wii, Lego Indiana Jones lets players get into   Indy's Lego shoes and experience breathtaking events from the films Raiders of the Lost Ark, Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom, and Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade.GameplayArtifacts from each level come togetherMuch like in the previous   Lego Star Wars games, Lego Indy offers a number of levels based on each of the three films, and you're free to play through each movie's storyline in any order you want. You'll proceed through each level and collect various items, including 10   treasure chests per level. Finding all of these will unlock a secret at Barnett College, the hub level in the game.You'll work through various   environmental puzzles to move through the levels, from opening   trap doors to crossing   pits, and flee from the occasional Lego   boulder. Like Lego Star Wars, Indy realizes what kind of game it is and has fun with its theme. For instance, remember in Raiders when   Indiana shoots the swordsman in the market after he shows off his moves? Well, in Legoland, Indy's gunshot causes the guy to fall into pieces.Intense Stud-collecting gameplay!In addition to Indiana and his trusty   whip, other characters have special abilities, such as   Henry Jones Sr. and his ability to decipher puzzles, or   Willie, who can break glass by screaming. Also, every woman character can jump higher. Careful, though, as the characters also have their faults; Indy freezes when snakes are around, and his father can't stand rats.Two friends can join up and work together in co-op mode, but if you decide to go it alone you'll still get   A.I. support to fulfill the puzzles you're dealt. You can also play free mode, which will allow you to roam around each level in search of hidden items like the treasure chests, for those who'd like to unlock secret characters like   Han Solo or others and pursue 100 percent completion of the game.In tune with the light-hearted nature of the game, there isn't any direct reference to   Nazism in Lego Indiana Jones. Instead, the enemies are simply "Germans" and their swastikas are nowhere to be found.Bundle with Kung Fu Panda for the Xbox 360As part of the Xbox 360's attempt to reach families with younger children, the   Xbox 360 Pro model was bundled with Lego Indiana Jones and   Kung Fu Panda during the 2008 holiday season at no additional cost.List of Playable CharactersLego to English dictionary: Nazis = "Enemy"  BanditBandit (swordsman)BarrancaBazooka trooper (Crusade)Bazzoka trooper (Raiders)  Belloq (Desert)Belloq (Jungle)Belloq (Priest)Boy scoutBritish officerBritish soldierBritish commander  BrodyCaptain KatangaChatter lalChatter lal (Thuggee)ChenColonel DietrichColonel VogelDancing girlDonovanElsaElsa (Desert)Elsa (Officer)Enemy boxerEnemy butlerEnemy Radio operatorEnemy guardEnemy guard (Mountains)Enemy officerEnemy officer (Desert)Enemy pilotEnemy soldierFedoraFirst mateGrail knight  Henry JonesHovitos tribesman  Indiana JonesIndiana Jones (Army Disguise)Indiana Jones (Desert)Indiana Jones (Desert Disguise)Indiana Jones (Dinner suit)Indiana Jones (Kali)Indiana Jones (Officer)Indiana Jones (Professor)JockJungle guideKao KanKazimKazim (Desert)Lao CheMaharajaMajor Toht  MarionMarion (Cairo)Marion (Evening Dress)Marion (Nightgown)Masked Bandit  Mola RamMonkey manPankot assassinPankot Guard  Sallah (Desert)Sallah (Fez)SatipoSherpa BrawlerSherpa Gunner  Short roundSlave childThuggeeThuggee AcolyteThuggee Slave driverVillage dignitaryVillage elder  WillieWillie (Ceremony)Willie (Dinner Suit)Willie (Evening Dress)Will PyjamasWu HanYoung Indy Han Solo (available once all other characters have been unlocked)Xbox 360 Game InstallationLego Indiana Jones: The Original Adventures requires 3.6 GB of space to be installed on an Xbox 360 HDD.PC System RequirementsMinimum RequirementsProcessor: Intel P3 1.0 Ghz or AMD Athlon XPVideo Card: 64MB 3D Graphics card with Vertex and Pixel Shader (VS/PS) CapabilityMemory: 256MB / 512MB with VistaHard Drive: 1 GB FreeOS: Windows Windows XP SP2Recommended RequirementsProcessor: Intel P4 3.0 Ghz or AMD Athlon 64Video Card: 256MB 3D Graphics card with Vertex and Pixel Shader (VS/PS) CapabilityMemory: 512MB / 1GB with VistaHard Drive: 2 GB free</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20330">Gex 3: Deep Cover Gecko</game><game id="15991">Chameleon Twist 2</game><game id="32196">Marvel Super Hero Squad: The Infinity Gauntlet</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2284685-box_legoij.png</image></root>