<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20546</id><name>Naruto: Ninja Council 3</name><description>OverviewNaruto Ninja council 3 is actually the 4th installment in the series. It is know in Japan as Naruto saikyo ninja daikesshu 4. The real third installment (naruto saikyo ninja daikesshu 3) never made it to the US. It had the same gameplay style as the 2 prior games in the series that came out on Gameboy advanced, wich was a sidescrolling beat'em up style.Naruto saikyo ninja daikesshu 4, the game that Naruto ninja council 3 is based on, has 35 characters to choose from. As for ninja council 3, you only get 27 total. A cut in the cast of characters availble had to be made to keep the game from advancing / revealing too much of the story that had not yet been revealed on the Tv show at the time.The gameplay of ninja council 3 requires the playrer to choose from ever 60 misions available. You have to beat the mission keeping to the conditions that are set for you at the begining of the mission it self. The conditions can include surviving with a health bar cut down in half, having to protect a cpu controlled  partner, killing a certain number of enemies, and so on.NARUTO: Ninja Council 3 is based on episodes from VIZ Media's anime series SHONEN JUMP NARUTO and will feature mission-based gameplay for up to four players. The ninja action game utilizes an interchangeable attack system allowing players to combine attack techniques from all available characters in the mission to increase their chance of success. Using the new interchangeable attack system, players select a main character to complete the mission and then customize their attack scheme by selecting special techniques from other available characters -- increasing their chance of success by combining the best techniques for the mission. Players can activate special attacks using the Nintendo DS stylus on the touch screen or by blowing into the microphone. Just like a true ninja, in NARUTO: Ninja Council 3, players will have to protect, defend or defeat as they train hard to perfect their skills in order to progress through the ranks in over 60 missions ranging in difficulty from moderate to challenging. Up to four players (wireless) can choose from over 20 different characters with four different playing modes including Timed Mode, Scroll Collection Mode and Head-to-Head Versus Mode.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9872">Dragon Ball: Advanced Adventure</game><game id="14300">Dragon Ball Z: Sagas</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2215061-box_narutonc3.png</image></root>