<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20605</id><name>High Velocity Bowling</name><description>Gameplay and ControlsHVB has two game modes, Let's Bowl and Challenge Mode:Let's Bowl  A quick-bowl type game that supports up to 4 players all using the one controller. This is good for     PlayStation 3 owners who only have one controller and wish to play multiplayer with their friends and family.Challenge modeA single player mode where you compete to unlock more players, clothes and balls. There are three different types of challenges: Head 2 Head, Tournament and Trick Shots.   In Head 2 Head you compete against another bowler and unlock the competitor if you win.   Tournament is a bowling tournament against AI opponents, if you win you can unlock items.   Trick Shots is the final challenge mode where you have to participate in objective type bowling games; such as bowling around items and over ramps.  In HVB you utilize the     SIXAXIS/    DualShock 3's motion sensing abilities to control your character much like the bowling game in       Wii Sports. You grip the SIXAXIS/DS3 upside down and perform a bowling motion with your arm to emulate real life bowling. This works rather well and is good use of the SIXAXIS and DS3.HVB also supports in-game music through the game itself for players wanting to listen to whatever music they may have on the HDD of their PS3.Downloadable content is available for HVB through the      PSN Store.   Move support is ONLY  available for PlayStation Plus members, otherwise move support will be  available in the near future.  </description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="29">Bowling</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13328">Wii Sports</game><game id="278">Brunswick Circuit Pro Bowling</game><game id="3405">Milo's Astro Lanes</game><game id="19789">Nester's Funky Bowling</game><game id="19119">PBA Bowling 2</game><game id="5847">Super Bowling</game><game id="20236">AMF Xtreme Bowling</game><game id="705">Black Market Bowling</game><game id="15259">PBA Tour Bowling 2001</game><game id="13673">Kingpin: Arcade Sports Bowling</game><game id="19679">Championship Bowling</game><game id="10521">The Flintstones: Bedrock Bowling</game><game id="20955">Ten Pin Alley 2</game><game id="14746">Animaniacs: Ten Pin Alley</game><game id="16781">Ten Pin Alley</game><game id="2402">Fast Lanes Bowling</game><game id="21583">AMF Bowling Pinbusters</game><game id="23739">AMF Pro Bowl 3D</game><game id="23405">Elf Bowling 1 &amp; 2</game><game id="4937">Elf Bowling</game><game id="25052">Bowling</game><game id="28101">Alien Monster Bowling League</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4759/196552-highvelocitybowling_logo_black.jpg</image></root>