<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20614</id><name>Star Wars Battlefront: Renegade Squadron</name><description>Star Wars Battlefront: Renegade Squadron is PSP exclusive game and is the third game in the Star Wars Battlefront series. GameplayThe gameplay is similar to the other battlefront games as the basic goal is to reduce the enemy tickets to zero by either killing them or more likely to capture command posts. The game has a story mode which you are a member of Han Solo's renegade squadron called Commander Col Serra (or any name that you give him), the game starts off with him describing the forming of the squadron. Then you start a series of missions ranging different objectives while including Metal Gear Solid portable ops style cut scenes in between each mission.    New featuresThe main new feature in this game is the fact that you can customize your character anyway you want with your favorite appearance, weapons and skills. You are given 100 credits to spend on these upgrades. The weapons in the game include primary, secondary and explosives. Before the game’s release, LucasArts had stated that over one million different customizable options would be present. Another new feature is there are new heroes and vehicles such as you can fly in the the Millennium Falcon and new in some space maps you can enter asteroid bases. MultiplayerRenegade Squadron allows up to 16 players to compete via Infrastructure mode and eight person support for ad hoc. The infrastructure mode is very robust and does not lag often.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21109">Resistance: Retribution</game><game id="2726">Star Wars: Episode I - Jedi Power Battles</game><game id="16866">Battlefield 2</game><game id="17828">Battlefield 2142</game><game id="12716">Battlefield 1942</game><game id="7094">Star Wars: Battlefront II</game><game id="8837">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Size Matters</game><game id="5556">Killzone: Liberation</game><game id="1995">Bounty Hounds</game><game id="9084">Syphon Filter: Logan's Shadow</game><game id="5910">SOCOM: U.S. Navy SEALs - Fireteam Bravo 2</game><game id="7023">SOCOM: U.S. Navy SEALs - Tactical Strike</game><game id="3641">007: From Russia with Love</game><game id="24499">Eragon</game><game id="2992">Syphon Filter: Combat Ops</game><game id="7827">Call of Duty: Roads to Victory</game><game id="26549">Star Wars Battlefront: Elite Squadron</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1784840-box_swbfrs.png</image></root>