<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20616</id><name>Super Street Fighter II Turbo HD Remix</name><description>OverviewAkuma, now in High Definition!Super Street Fighter II Turbo HD Remix is a 2D fighting game developed by Backbone and published by Capcom for the Xbox 360 (via Xbox Live Arcade) and PlayStation 3 (via PlayStation Network) on November 26, 2008. The seventh official iteration of Street Fighter II, the game further rebalances the gameplay of Super Street Fighter II Turbo while adding brand new high-definition graphics (courtesy of UDON), remixed music (from OverClocked ReMix), optional widescreen resolution, enhanced training mode (including the option of displaying the fighters' hitboxes), and online multiplayer (including ranked matches, eight-player tournaments, and online round-robin lobbies). The rebalances, new graphics, and new music are optional and can be disabled. A complete list of the game's new features is found here.A limited version of the game was released on June 25, 2008 as a timed open beta for those who bought Wolf of the Battlefield: Commando 3. The beta (designed to test the netcode) only included online match play, two characters (Ken and Ryu), and one stage. The beta lasted until November 25, 2008.CharactersPlayer Select ScreenRyuKenFei LongChun LiSagatM. BisonVegaBalrogE. HondaDhalsimBlankaDee JayT. HawkCammyGuileZangiefAkuma (Hidden character: In single player character select screen go to Guile and push up, in multiplayer go to E. Honda and push up</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21519">The King of Fighters XII</game><game id="16793">Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="9542">Night Warriors: Darkstalkers' Revenge</game><game id="22820">Red Earth</game><game id="12125">Capcom Fighting Evolution</game><game id="10574">X-Men: Children of the Atom</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="22953">Ultimate Fighter</game><game id="16165">InuYasha: A Feudal Fairy Tale</game><game id="13875">Plasma Sword: Nightmare of Bilstein</game><game id="14918">Hyper Street Fighter II: The Anniversary Edition</game><game id="16200">The King of Fighters: Neowave</game><game id="5964">The King of Fighters '99</game><game id="28437">Super Street Fighter IV</game><game id="29779">BlazBlue Calamity Trigger Portable</game><game id="13463">Real Bout Fatal Fury Special</game><game id="35506">Fighting For One Piece</game><game id="36181">Writer Rumble</game><game id="36274">Persona 4 Arena</game><game id="34082">Skullgirls</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1099/900269-826903_sfhdp30f_large.jpg</image></root>