<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20638</id><name>This Is Vegas</name><description>This Is Vegas was an open-world game that was being developed by Surreal Software, the same team that created The Suffering and the Drakan games. It was to be published by Warner Bros. Interactive for the Xbox 360, PlayStation 3, and PC. It has, since summer 2010, been cancelled.PARTY!This Is Vegas was a rags-to-riches story of one man -- your playable character -- who hops off the bus in the city of sin with only a handful of dollars to his name. It's up to you to create your own empire in Vegas by getting to know all the famous people at the best night clubs, gambling and growing your bankroll, engaging in street races to get more respect, and of course fighting people, whether it's with guns or your own two fists.The game was to be relying on four pillars: fighting, driving, gambling, and partying. The game contains numerous gambling minigames, such as poker, blackjack, and roulette, and you'll be able to cheat at them to increase your odds -- provided you don't get caught. You can also hit various nightclubs and pick up extra cash by tending bar or laying down moves on the dance floor.The citizens of Vegas were to be categorized as suits in a deck of cards:The Diamonds are the high rollers; the Hearts, classic Vegas old-timers; the Clubs, naturally the people into the club scenes; and the Spades, the rockers in Vegas. Each of these factions will give you different missions to complete, unlocking new options in the game.Rumored CancellationOn August 24th, 2010, it was reported that "This is Vegas" was been canceled, leaving Midway and Warner Bros $50 million dollars in the hole."Apparently the entire This Is Vegas project has been totally canned," said CVG's source. "Midway spent in the region of $43 million up to the point when it was being sold to WB. Alan Patmore, who was studio boss, either left or was let go - but considering the resources and art created this is a lot of work down the drain."It was moving along to a point where the title was on the schedule for release late last year - but still needed another eight months to a year to finish with a studio burn rate of $250,000 per month."</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9966">Scarface: The World is Yours</game><game id="11153">True Crime: Streets of LA</game><game id="20698">Wheelman</game><game id="5618">Saints Row</game><game id="4065">Crackdown</game><game id="20679">Saints Row 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4086/268750-9.jpg</image></root>