<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20635</id><name>Rock Revolution</name><description>Overview Rock Revolution is a three-player rhythm and music game coming from               Konami,              Zoe Mode, and             HB Studios. Much like the            Japan-only           DrumMania games before it, or          MTV's         Rock Band without a vocalist, Rock Revolution allows a drummer and two guitarists to wield plastic instruments and play along to a variety of rock tunes on the       Xbox 360 and      PlayStation 3.  Unlike Rock Band's four pad drum kit and        Guitar Hero: World Tour's five pad drum kit, Rock Revolution uses an all new drum controller with six pads and a foot pedal. The pads on the kit aren't arranged in the order they appear on screen and have different shapes. It has been revealed that all the peripherals for     Rock Band 2 and Guitar Hero: World Tour on the PlayStation 3 and Xbox 360 will be compatible with Rock Revolution. The game shrinks the amount of note lanes for the drum tracks depending on which drum peripheral you have attached when you start the game. The    Wii version of Rock Revolution allows custom instruments in favor of standard   Wii Remote and Nunchuk support. A                separate DS version contains a karaoke mode that employs the  DS microphone.  Soundtrack* master recordings Song - Artist All The Small Things - Blink 182Chop Suey! - System Of A DownCum on Feel the Noize - Quiet RiotDance, Dance - Fall Out BoyDetroit Rock City - CityDr.Feelgood - Motley CrueHoly Wars... The Punishment Due - MegadethPull Me Under - Dream TheaterSomebody Told Me - The KillersSpoonman - SoundgardenStone Cold Crazy - QueenThe Joker And The Thief - WolfmotherSpirit Of Radio - RushWe're Not Gonna Take It - Twisted SisterWhite Room - CreamYouth Gone Wild - Skid RowDirty Little Secret - All American RejectsLast Resort - Papa RoachRound and Round - RattStill Of The Night - WhitesnakeAre You Gonna Be My Girl - JetNo One Like You - ScorpionsDiary Of Jane - Breaking BenjaminBlitzkrieg Bop - The RamonesFalling Away From Me - KornThe End Of Heartache - Killswitch EngageRun To The Hills - Iron Maiden Walk- PanteraHeading Out To The Highway - Judas PriestWon't Get Fooled Again - The WhoPain - Three Days GraceAll My Life - Foo FightersAm I Evil? - Diamond Head / MetallicaOur Truth - Lacuna CoilSk8er Boi - Avril Lavigne Kiss Me Deadly - Lita FordMagic Man - HeartParalyzer - Finger Eleven*Given Up - Linkin Park*</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9860">Rock Band</game><game id="20673">Guitar Hero World Tour</game><game id="14916">Guitar Hero II</game><game id="11281">Shredz64</game><game id="20808">Rock Band Track Pack Volume 1</game><game id="4031">Guitar Hero III: Legends of Rock</game><game id="20714">Rock Band 2</game><game id="6311">Guitar Hero</game><game id="22167">Synthesia</game><game id="17021">DJMAX Portable</game><game id="20639">Guitar Hero: On Tour</game><game id="23613">Guitar Praise: Solid Rock</game><game id="23849">JamLegend</game><game id="21099">Wii Music</game><game id="12241">Guitar Hero Encore: Rocks the 80s</game><game id="23219">Guitar Rising</game><game id="24637">BCFX: The Doug Williams Edition</game><game id="1420">Amplitude</game><game id="5825">Frequency</game><game id="10051">PaRappa the Rapper 2</game><game id="25521">Guitar Hero: Smash Hits</game><game id="25642">Rock Band Track Pack: Classic Rock</game><game id="25871">Tap Tap Revenge: Coldplay Edition</game><game id="25421">Rock Band Unplugged</game><game id="21102">Guitar Hero On Tour: Decades</game><game id="25765">LEGO Rock Band</game><game id="23939">AC/DC Live: Rock Band</game><game id="21171">Lips</game><game id="26367">Band Hero</game><game id="24711">Guitar Hero 5</game><game id="30014">Guitar Hero: Warriors of Rock</game><game id="9436">Audiosurf</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15405/746995-revolution.png</image></root>