<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20654</id><name>Doom 4</name><description>HistoryThere is very little information known about Doom 4 currently, although it has been stated by id developers that it will be an action game, like the original Doom and Doom II were, as opposed to continuing down the path of the horror genre as Doom 3 did. Perhaps one of the most confusing things about the game is the fact that id Software chose to announce it with a small day announcement, instead of waiting for their own event QuakeCon. At QuakeCon 2008, id announced that Doom 4 will not be available through digital distribution like many of the company's previous titles. At the press conference, id Software co-founder John Carmack announced that Doom 4 would have "three times as much horsepower as RAGE". The game will run at only 30 frames a second, but despite this, Carmack promises to raise the bar on video game graphics to a level "no one has ever seen before." Later in the event, id CEO Todd Hollenshead contradicted Carmack in a way when he announced id is "not even sure if Doom 4 will be Doom 4". Hollenshead admitted that the game is so early in development that id hasn't even decided if this new Doom will be a true sequel or even be called "Doom 4". John Carmack has theorized, however that the PC version of the game will look significantly better than the console versions, due to the superior power of high-end PCs.GameplayIn interviews John Carmack has implied that the gameplay will be more action-oriented than the previous title, and acknowledged the negative aspects of 2003's Doom 3. Namely, the excessive darkness and survival-horror gameplay, e.g. monsters 'hiding in closets' and limited ammo.Early interviews suggest this move away from survival horror to Doom's more traditional focus on action:You get to punctuate a lot more with triumphs and successes, and you just don't get to do that very much in survival horror. You know, you want to say, 'I'm victorious,' not, 'I'm not dead.' It's just a fundamentally more rewarding genre to be in.ReleaseDoom 4 is 'targeted' for a simultaneous release on PC, Xbox 360, and Playstation 3.MoviePersonnel within id software have expressed interest in making a new Doom movie that actually follows the Doom storyline, unlike the original Doom movie starring The Rock. Todd Hollenshead has openly aired his interest in a possible Doom movie following the storyline of Doom 4 itself, whatever that may be. He hopes that the hype for Doom 4 will encourage Universal Studios into talks about the project's possibility.</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26445">Serious Sam 3: BFE</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/16132/789193-doom4releaselogo.png</image></root>