<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20653</id><name>NFL Blitz '99</name><description> The second game in the NFL Blitz franchise was released exclusively in arcades in 1998 and features NFL rosters for the 1999 season. Though conversion kits allowed for two-player configurations based on upgrading an original NFL Blitz cabinet, Blitz '99 is the first game in the series to allow up to four players to play simultaneously. New plays, as well as the ability to create plays and assign them to a personal player profile are additional new features.Operators can also opt to install a Nintendo 64 controller pak reader on the side of a Blitz '99 cabinet. Plays created on the N64 version of the original Blitz home release can be transferred into the game in this fashion. A small metal door opens when the pak reading process is triggered, keeping the contacts covered and, ideally, free from gum and other foreign substances that arcade attending miscreants may attempt to force into the slot.Like the original game, Blitz '99 is a fast-moving, arcade-style football game that takes numerous liberties with the rules of football, such as lengthening the distance required for a first down and allowing "late hits," which appear in the form of various post-play tackles and wrestling maneuvers. As in many of Midway's other arcade sports titles, the action is commentated by Tim Kitzrow.</description><genres><genre id="21">Football</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="98">John Elway's Quarterback</game><game id="8073">NFL Sports Talk Football '93 Starring Joe Montana</game><game id="22877">NFL Xtreme 2</game><game id="20030">NFL Street 3</game><game id="2632">Mutant League Football</game><game id="11229">Tecmo Bowl</game><game id="1243">Super High Impact</game><game id="25082">CFL Football '99</game><game id="26930">Madden NFL Football</game><game id="26931">Madden Season 2</game><game id="2849">NFL Blitz 2000</game><game id="29744">Madden NFL 11</game><game id="20920">Blitz: The League II</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1940/240779-blitz99f.jpg</image></root>