<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20670</id><name>Sneak King</name><description>OverviewSneak King is a promotional game that was released by Burger King alongside two other games, Big Bumpin'and Pocketbike Racer, on Nov. 19th 2006 up until December 24. Each of these games was $4.00 with the purchase of any combo. However, the price was later reduced to free if you asked your local Burger King manager politely.Note that all of the BK games only had achievements worth 200 points.Cross-Compatibility The three promotional games were notable for being the first three games to have cross-compatibility between the original Xbox and the Xbox 360. The same disc could be used on either system. Obviously if you played the game on the original Xbox the graphics were inferior to those found on the Xbox 360. Playing on the original Xbox resulted in lower texture resolution and lower polygon count. Despite this, the graphics were quite notable for a $4.00 to free title, thanks to cell phone developer extraordinaire Blitz Games.Gameplay The game has you play as The Burger King himself as you attempt to sneak up on unsuspecting victims and force-feed them Burger King products. The products range from the almighty Whopper to Burger King-branded fries and coffee.Stealth is the primary focus of the game. In order to feed the various construction workers and citizens that inhabit Sneak King's world, you must sneak up on them. Each character that you are able to feed has a blue shadow that appears around their vicinity and if you happen to tip-toe into it, they'll turn around and spot you. To succeed, you must avoid the blue shadow and get close enough to them that you are able to tap the 'A' button to surprise them. Once you surprise them, you then can attempt to perform a flourish maneuver by hitting 'A' again at the appropriate time. There are three levels of flourish, one being the worst and three being the best; the better flourish you perform, the more points you get. Another way to obtain more points is by racking up chain surprises. To do this, one must simply surprise multiple targets without getting spotted. Also, surprising from a hiding spot, such as a dumpster or a bush, will snag you a points bonus as well.LocationsThere are various levels in which you can enact your stealthy food delivery fantasies. They include:SawmillCul-De-SacConstruction SiteDowntownXbox 360 Game InstallationInstallation to the Xbox 360 HDD is not supported at this time.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1045">Big Bumpin'</game><game id="4622">Pocketbike Racer</game><game id="2549">Yaris</game><game id="12655">Cap'n Crunch's Crunchling Adventure</game><game id="24825">Dash of Destruction</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1803981-box_sking.png</image></root>