<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20672</id><name>Rage</name><description>OverviewJ.K. Stiles, the producer of Mutant Bash TV.Rage is id Software's new game franchise, built entirely on the company's latest proprietary engine, id Tech 5. The title, as with the title's of id's previous first-person shooters Doom and Quake, is entirely meaningless, using a short, dangerous-sounding word to try to get across the violent atmosphere of the game.Rage takes place on an Earth recovering from impact with an asteroid named Apophis, with its landscape ravaged into a wasteland.Shoot to kill.This environment, inspired by popular games such as Fallout 3, S.T.A.L.K.E.R. and Metro 2033, is perfectly suited to the rough-and-tumble dune buggy racing seen in games like MotorStorm, and players have the ability to acquire their very own car at some point early on in the game. Players can augment their cars with various items and upgrades acquired by doing races and side missions for non-player characters. The game is far more than a racing title - many trailers and demonstration videos of the game have showcased first-person shooting as an equally significant portion of the game. The player has access to a wide variety of weapons and tools - such as placeable turrets and exploding RC buggies - available for use. Several weapons allow multiple ammo types and a crafting system is available for making these tools. All items are managed via an inventory system and corpses can be examined for loot. Beyond paid upgrades in the game world, other RPG elements such as level progression and skill trees are absent from Rage. The protagonist has no name, adding him to the list of similar characters in the Fallout series, Gothic and Fable.Though the game is very large (21GB at release), it is not characterized by id Software as an open-world game. Creative Director Tim Willits and Lead Designer Matt Hooper prefer the expression "open but directed" - "You know that you have to go [to an objective], but if you see something that's interesting you're free to go and explore," Hooper said in an interview.PlotThe player takes the role of a surviving member of one of the Arks: a series of underground shelters, constructed as a worldwide, collaborative effort to ensure humanity's survival after the impact. Each Ark contains several specially-selected people, each with some trait or unique skillset that would contribute towards the re-emergence of humanity. Upon beginning the game, the player discovers that his Ark failed at its job - the player is the only surviving member of his own unit.LevelsWaking UpQuell the Bandit ThreatMedical SuppliesFind the Buggy PartsDestroy the BarricadeDan's MessageWellspringFeltrite CraterFeltrite SampleDefibrillator UpgradeCuprino NeededMutant Bash TVResupply the TowerDestroy the Bomb CachesHijacked WellDeadly DeliveryLiberate Captain MarshallRecover ID DriveLost Research DataSubway TownGaining InfluenceMutant ExpansionGearhead VaultThe Price of PowerAbandoned DistilleryArk EquipmentAssault the Authority BridgeAssault Capital PrimeDLC - Wasteland Sewer MissionsA DLC package is available on the Xbox 360 called 'Wasteland Sewer Missions'. It add 9 additional sewers to the game. The DLC unlocks the already present sewers in the game. Anyone with the Anarchy edition already had them unlocked.DLC - The ScorchersA second DLC package known as The Scorchers was released on December 18th, 2012 for Xbox360, PlayStation3, and PC for $5. It includes a short mission based campaign against The Scorchers, new weapons, new environments, and the ability to continue playing the game after completing the main story. Also included in the DLC update was a new "Ultra Nightmare" difficulty level.The id Tech 5 EngineVehicles will play an important role throughout the game.The Id Tech 5 Engine marks the first engine designed around "visualizing texture data", whatever that means. The idea is to allow artistic freedom by improving the engine's handling of textures - they can be any size or resolution, and it will have no impact on engine performance. The only limitations remaining are storage on the disc/hard drive, and the artist's imagination. This takes away the struggle between realism and performance'.While this is one major selling point to developers, the engine is also being designed with cross-platform capabilities in mind, at least as far as the platforms it's being released on. This means that a developer could compile their game for PS3, and then immediately compile another version for the Xbox 360, and then another for Windows, without ever needing to change any of the assets, code, etc. This also works for Mac OS X and Linux - and because the engine is OpenGL 2 and DirectX 9 compliant, it will work on versions of Windows before Vista as well.id Software has traditionally focused on providing a solid, stable, and highly scalable engine, while all content creation tools were designed from a technical standpoint, and with less focus on the artist's job. id Tech 4 (the engine used for Doom 3) had all of its development tools built in the game executable to allow for real time editing, but it still possessed the beauty-to-performance tradeoff that made beauty passes such a headache. However, for id Tech 5, id will introduce "id Studio", a real-time collaborative editing platform (thus far only planned for release on Windows). While it resembles CryTek's Sandbox Editor in function, the premise of id Studio is that more than one editor can work on the same level collaboratively. Given the engine's texturing capabilities, it can be best described as bringing a few friends over to work on a Lego set together, except replacing Lego with clay and paint.Version differencesAt QuakeCon 2008, id Software announced that they would shy away from the traditional digital distribution method that the studio usually use for their games. Also, the Xbox 360 version of Rage may have to be divided into 2 discs or suffer from serious compression compared to the other versions. The final release would in fact see three discs in the Xbox 360 version.John Carmack went on to note that the game was originally going to feature several wastelands, but the limitations of the 360's DVDs required the developer to cut them down to two. These changes were made for all versions of the game. Carmack also stated that the game might be a " little blurry" in parts for the Xbox 360, due to compression. This is necessitated by storage issues, because even with multiple discs, the Xbox 360 version will have to downgrade its graphics slightly to fit onto the DVDs. This is of course compared to the PC version, which does not have that limitation when the right hardware is available.However, it was also announced that Rage would take full advantage of current generation consoles and run at 60 frames per second on both the Playstation 3 and Xbox 360.The mentioned iPad and iPhone versions of the game were published in 2010. The game is totally different from the final game for PC, XBOX360 and PS3 as it is an on-rails shooting experience within the Rage environment using several Rage monsters. The Rage app was also a prototyping project of ID to show the world what mobile devices were capable of.EngineeringThe player has the ability to build items out of the various scraps you find around the wasteland. Some of these items can be purchased from the various vendors in the game, but some can only be found in certain areas of the game. The majority of the schematics can be purchased while a select few have to be acquired though completing missions or exploration of the wasteland. Below is a list of all the items that can be built in Rage, the advanced builds replacing the standard ones.ItemsRequiredAuthority AugmenterNanotrite Conduit(2), Electrical Wire Kit, Feltrite Coupler, Feltrite Power PackRegenerative InfusionBandages, Comet Bloom(2), Vial of BlueshineAdvanced Sentry TurretOrdnance Pack, Turret Barrel, Nanotrite Conduit, Small Battery Pack, Electrical Wire KitAdvance Sentry BotOrdnance Pack, Nanotrite Conduit, Small Battery Pack, Electrical Wire Kit, Hardware PacketAdvanced WingsticksSteel Blades, Hardware Packet, Electrical Wire KitEMP GrenadeElectrical Wire Kit, Feltrite Power Pack, HE Grenades(3)Dynamite Bolts – Crossbow AmmoSteel Bolts(6), Explosive PackMind Control Bolts – Crossbow AmmoSteel Bolts(12), Explosive Pack, Ghost Toxin, Mutant Adrenal Gland(2)Advanced RC Bomb CarExplosive Pack, Nanotrite Conduit, Small Battery Pack, RC Car KitPop Rockets – Shotgun AmmoBuckshot(16), Explosive PackFat Mamas – Pistol AmmoFatboys(12), Explosive PackApophis InfusionDesert Spore(2), Bandages, Night Blossom(2)Lock GrinderElectrical Wire Kit, Hardware Packet, Small GearsAdrenaline OverdriveBandages, Night Blossom, Mutant Adrenal GlandBandagesCloth Rags, Antiseptic FormulaRacingDriving is the main way the player will traverse the wastelands in Rage, and said wastelands are hostile places. Filled with bloodthirsty bandits and the vicious Authority, the cars in Rage are heavily weapon-ised, equipped with guns, rocket launchers and have strong defensive capabilities too, such as shields, friendly turrets and mines. Apart from the ATV, the cars can be customised in regards to the tires, engines, armour and how much boost they can store. Below is a list of the class types for the vehicles and the weapons and defences that are in the game.Car nameDescriptionJetter - ATVThis will be the first vehicle you acquire, a simple ATV that cannot be customised in any way. The player can’t use the defence items while driving this either.Dune Buster - BuggyThis is gained by completing an early story mission and be equipped with one weapon at a time, which has to be switched out at the garage.Cuprino - TruckThis is also gained by completing a story mission, has far more durability than the buggy and can be equipped with two weapons simultaneously. You can also fit custom bumpers to the front, that deal heavy damage when driving at high speed.Monarch – APCThis is the only vehicle that isn’t obtained through a story mission, when talking to Redstone in Subway town, he advises you to get a stronger vehicle to fight the authority. You must go and speak to the racer on the bottom floor of the town, beat him in the race and the Monarch is yours. The main difference this vehicle has is the addition of the pulse cannon, which is a devastating energy weapon that deals massive damage to vehicles. Like the Cuprino, you can equip armour and a rammer on the front.WeaponsWeaponDescriptionMinigunsStandard dual mounted miniguns that can store a very large amount of ammo. They are not effective for taking down armoured vehicles, such as the Cuprino and Monarch.Rocket LaunchersThese fire homing rockets that take down most un-armoured vehicles in one shot. There is a short delay for lock-on targeting, but line of sight firing is possible.Pulse CannonA single shot weapon that has a significant cool down between each shot. Especially effective at taking down armoured vehicles. This can be only fitted to the Monarch.Defence ItemsItemDescriptionShieldProvides complete protection from all damage taken by your vehicle. Has a limited time of use.Armour RestoreCompletely repairs all damage that your vehicle has taken.Drop MineStationary mine that will detonate upon contact with any vehicle, even your own.AftershockerSends out a powerful shockwave that will blast away all vehicles around you.Hover TurretA small friendly turret will hover above your vehicle and automatically target hostile targets.Escort BombDeploys an RC bomb car that will follow you and detonate near hostile targets such as cars and turrets.Easter EggsRage has quite a few Easter Eggs in it many of which reference other id Software games. Many of the id references come in the form of special items around the world that can be sold for large amounts of money.In one of the levels there is a reference to "Rage 2" and "Doom 5". Perhaps regarding future releases.At the beginning of the game there is a Doomguy bobble-head on the dashboard of Dan Hagar's buggy.You find a Vault Boy bobble-head on the desk of the mayor in Wellspring. The game even describes it as being Vault-Tec paraphernalia leading Brad Shoemaker and Vinny Caravella to debate whether or not RAGE takes place in the same world as Fallout or that the game simply takes place in a world that Fallout existed in as a game.There are "Quayola" crayons that bare the Quake logo on them.In the game there are several boxs of "Pinkies" that bears resemblance to a box of twinkies but makes the roaring sound that a Pinky makes in Doom when you pick it up.In the Wasteland Garage there are three hidden buttons, when pressed they make a noise from Quake and when you press all three of the buttons you can go up some stairs that were previously un-passable. The stairs are located where a Quake Logo is on the wall leading you into a Quake style portal at the top of the stairs. The portal takes you to an original Quake level where you would originally chose your difficulty level. On the ground you find an item called a "Shambler Plush" to pick up.In the Distillery in the Eastern Wasteland the stills have logos on them that look very much like the "No. 7" that can be found on Jack Daniel's bottles.In the Abandoned Distillery there is a hidden developer room with all the developer signatures and an "ID" logo. It also unlocks the Achievement "Dev Graffiti" after you enter the room.In the Gearhead Vault there are a bunch of computers with keyboards by them. Press the interact key on a keyboard and you will hear a sound from Doom. When you interact with all the keyboards you will hear a growl, that means you have unlocked a door. If you go through the door which is at the start of the vault by a flaming barrel then you will enter a room which a portal on the ground. If you go through the portal you end up in the original level from the shareware game Doom. In the level is an item you can pickup called "Doom Marine Bobblehead" it is the same one that is on Dan Hagar's dashboard.When you first enter the Gearhead base there is a bandit sweeping the floor and whistling a tune that is just shy of being "Whistle While You Work".In one of the first quests you can access a room that resembles a cell block from the old Wolfstein 3D computer game. The room contains a trophy that 'has a german design to it'.You can paint your cars with the ID logo.AwardsRage won the "Best Console Game" award at E3 2010 from the Game Critics, as well as "Best Action Game" and "Special Commendation for Graphics".Xbox 360 installDisc 1- 7.7GBDisc 2- 7.4GBDisc 3- 6.7GBLaunch TroublesThe launch of the PC version of Rage was met with strong backlash that were not entirely the fault of the game's developer or publisher. Rather video card drivers produced by nVidia and particularly ATI/AMD resulted in excessive graphics and compatibility issues that for some rendered the game unplayable. John Carmac implemented features that were not yet fully supported by the video card drivers, and that resulted in major problems with texture popping and blinking character models. ATI/AMD released an updated driver the same day in order to improve performance and compatibility. Bethesda released within a week a patch to set display settings like texture size and vsync to cope with the problems. Both efforts resulted in solving most of the problems reported for the PC.Inaccurate Product PlacementOn August 28th, 2011 AMC's Breaking Bad inexplicably featured a two minute scene with a character playing the then-unreleased Rage as a rail shooter (which it is not).PC System RequirementsBelow are the official pc system specifications that Bethesda announced on their blog in september 2011.MinimumOS: Windows XP SP3, Windows Vista, Windows 7Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo or AMD EquivalentMemory: 2 GBHDD Space: 25 GBVideo Card: Geforce 8800, Radeon HD 4200RecommendedOS: Windows XP SP3, Windows Vista, Windows 7Processor: Intel Core 2 Quad or AMD EquivalentMemory: 4 GBHDD Space: 25 GBVideo Card: Gefore 9800 GTX, Radeon HD 5550Rage also uses Steamworks and feature Steam Achievements, VOIP (Voice over Internet Protocol), and Friends Support.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20504">Fallout 3</game><game id="20665">Far Cry 2</game><game id="12134">Wasteland</game><game id="23275">Fallen Earth</game><game id="32327">S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2</game><game id="25933">Fallout: New Vegas</game><game id="20964">Metro 2033</game><game id="8015">Quake</game><game id="7326">Doom</game><game id="621">Doom II: Hell on Earth</game><game id="3207">Quake II</game><game id="13683">Quake 4</game><game id="36055">Borderlands 2</game><game id="3407">Duke Nukem 3D</game><game id="38389">Nuclear Union</game><game id="38072">Ravaged</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2080541-box_rage.png</image></root>