<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20679</id><name>Saints Row 2</name><description>OverviewPlayers can cause large amounts of chaos throughout Stilwater. Saints Row 2 is a crime-themed, mission-based, open world game that looks to continue evolving the over-the-top gameplay formula of its predecessor. With many comparisons to the  GTA series, it is no surprise that Volition have chosen to take the game in this direction to individualize it and perhaps gain an identity outside of all those comparisons. Saint's Row 2 has the player work his way through a vastly improved  Stilwater, a 150% larger version of the city with new areas including a prison island, a power plant, suburbs, and some underground sections, dispensing of rival gang members and otherwise unruly denizens to reclaim the turf and respect his once lofty gang has lost.A wide variety of vehicles can be used, including biplanes. Saint's Row 2 boasts many of the same features of the first game such as diversions (known as 'Activities'), as well as a host of new features such as varying degrees of customization including complete character customization, vehicle customization, and crib customization, a revamped respect system, new vehicles including jets, speedboats, jet skis,  helicopters, and  monster trucks, new weapons including  rocket launchers, shock paddles, stun guns, and  satchel charges,  co-op gameplay, and online multiplayer.StoryThe Third Street Saints. Saints Row 2 picks up several years after the events of the first game.  The Boss, the player's character who was thought to be dead at the end of the first game after being betrayed by his own gang members, awakes from a coma induced by a bombed yacht but is horribly disfigured. The game opens with a reconstructive surgical procedure, allowing players to freely customize the look of the player character. Upon returning to  Stilwater, the lead character notices that much has changed, from building renovations that have added more high-rise buildings and apartments, to the situations that his old friends and gang members have gotten into. The player character must now deal with all of these changes and somehow restore the Row to its former glory.GangsThere are four gangs in Stilwater: 3rd Street Saints - The player character's gang. The Saints were broken up after the events of the first game, and it's time to bring them back, stronger than ever. Their flag color is purple. Brotherhood of Stilwater - A gang that largely deals with violent crimes and extortion. Led by Maero. Their flag color is red. Ronin - A Japanese gang that deals with gambling and prostitution. Led by Shogo Akuji, though his father seems to really have most of the power. Their flag color is yellow. Sons of Samedi - A gang that deals with heavy drug trafficking. Led by "The General". Their flag color is green.GameplayThe combat of Saints Row 2 is slightly different from that of other games in the genre. For starters, there is no  lock on-targeting system, with the player having to free aim. This can be accomplished by either pressing the fire button when pointed at an enemy, or the player can click in the left stick for a more accurate, "zoomed-in" aiming mode. If the player has a gun equipped, the right trigger will fire, while the left trigger will melee attack. If the player has an inventory  melee weapon available, it can be swung with both the left and right triggers. If unarmed, the player's melee has a sort of "combo" system; if the player successfully lands three hits on an opponent, the third hit will spin the camera around and cinematically show the character performing a special attack that ground his enemy. By holding either trigger, the player can also charge up his attack, making it extra deadly. A couple of interesting features of SR2's combat are the use of environmental objects and the  human shield mechanic. There are certain objects in the game that can be picked up and wielded like melee weapons, like cinder blocks or  chairs. These items can be dropped however, if the player is knocked down, and are not held in the inventory like normal weapons. Also, by holding the left bumper the player can take a nearby enemy hostage as a "human shield". While having a shield, the player is virtually invincible from the front, but moves slower in return. Also, by pressing the left trigger, the player will "execute" his shield in a way specific to the weapon he is holding. There are numerous weapons that appear in Saints Row Two, which include:Melee Pepper Spray Chainsaw Shock paddles Machete Baseball Bat Butterfly Knife Knife Taser Pimp Slap (Slaps enemy and sends them flying) Nightstick Sledgehammer Crowbar Samurai Sword Pistols (can be dual wielded) 44 Shepard GDHC .50 Vice 9 NR4 Kobra (Auto with  Laser Sight) SMGs (can be dual wielded) GAL-43 SKR-9 Threat TK3 Urban Shotguns Tombstone12 Gauge (Double barrel) AS14 Hammer Pimp Cane (Also makes your character pimp-walk) XS-2 Ultimax Assault Rifles AR-40 Xtnd (  M-16) AR-50 XMAC AR-50 XMAC w/  Grenade Launcher AR200 SAW K6 Krukov (  AK-47)SpecialsUnlocking the Flamethrower. RPG Launcher Annihilator RPG (Heat seeking) Flamethrower Fire Extinguisher McManus 2010 (  Sniper Rifle) Mini GunThrown Flashbang (Flare) Hand Grenade Molotov Cocktail Pipe Bomb Satchel Charge (Remote Detonate)ActivitiesSaints Row 2 boasts quite a few activities for the player to complete, in order to get respect for missions and have fun.The activities are:Crowd ControlIn Crowd Control, you play as a bodyguard for VIPs. The activity requires you to meet a score by killing crazy fans that attack the celebrity. Special kills earn you more money, for instance, beating an attacker down with a baseball bat gets you $250, but throwing them into spinning helicopter blades earns you $1000!Rewards: Clothing Store Discount, Pepper Spray, Chainsaw.Trail Blazin'Race around Stillwater on a flaming quad bike, setting fire to everything and everyone.Rewards: Explosion Damage -5%, Fire Fighter Suit, Explosion Damage -15%.Demo DerbyDrive around in a car and attempt to take out other rides, any way you see fit.Rewards: Demo Derby Cars, Mechanic Discount.Drug TraffickingYou ride shotgun to protect a drug dealer as he makes his rounds.Rewards: Infinite shotgun ammo, reduced Ronin notoriety.EscortIn Escort, you drive around with prostitutes as they do their job in the backseat. However, the customers don't like media attention or a private detective, so you must avoid them at all costs. Sometimes, the client will order you to do something, like go buy some food at Freckle Bitch's or drive around at a high speed. Play this game in co-op mode, and one of you gets to be the prostitute!Rewards: Vehicle Delivery, reduced Sons of Samedi notoriety.Fight ClubFace off against other fighters in a fighting ring or prison block. You can't use firearms, but anything thrown into the ring by onlookers can be used to bash and break your opponents.Rewards: Legal Lee, Troy, Increased Melee Damage, Pumped Up.FuzzDress up as a cop and take out criminals and college students for Stilwater's hot new police reality show, Fuzz! The variety of violent ways you use to "enforce" the law in Stilwater is limited only by your imagination. Rev up those chainsaws boys!Rewards: Kobra Pistol, Unlimited Pistol Ammo, Police notoriety reduced.Heli AssaultFly around in an attack helicopter with heat-seeking missiles and protect your crew members down below. Learning how to properly use the missiles can cause you to rain death and destruction from the sky.Rewards: Reduced Bullet damage.Insurance FraudJust like in the original game, you throw yourself in front of vehicles in an attempt to rack up as much insurance money as you possibly can.Rewards: Sprint increased, Reduced Vehicle damage.MayhemInfinite RPG rockets at the ready, blow up anything and everything in an attempt to cause as many dollars of damage as possible.Rewards: Crib Customization Discount, Flamethrower, Annihilator RPG.Septic AvengerLower the value of real-estate by spraying everything in sight with fecal matter. Unfortunately for the cops though, they have to attempt to stop you by driving up to you and shooting at your truck. A mouth full of diarrhea is what they get in return!Rewards: Improved Weapon Accuracy, Food and Liquor Discount, Septic Truck.SnatchIn Snatch, you take out pimps and steal their prostitutes. Be careful of the shotguns those pimps wield though.Rewards: GAL 43, Infinite SMG ammo, Health Regeneration.HitmanIn Hitman, you receive a list of targets. These targets appear as crosshairs on your map when you get in range, however, unlike in the first Saints Row, you can kill them with any weapon, which makes this one quite a bit easier.Rewards: Infinite Assault Rifle ammo, Hand Grenades, Satchel Charges.Chop ShopIn Chop Shop, you need to collect the cars that the garage wants and bring them back there.Rewards: Buggy, Mechanic Discount.DiversionsThe game also has Diversions, these are random things for you to do to get some rewards and just have fun.TaggingTagging has been redesigned since the last game, now you need to fill a part of the wall with paint, but you can't spray too much outside of the lines.General CollectingThere are a few thing to collect in Saints Row 2, like CDs and other things.Basejumping and SkydivingJump out of a plane or helicopter and deploy your parachute to start the Basejumping diversion. Land on top of the Saints' car in the middle of the bullseye to receive invincibility from falling damage, no matter the distance!Civil ServicesTaxi driving, firefighting, vigilante and towing vehicles. You saw 'em all before on GTA, and they're pretty much the same here.StreakingSimply go to any of the clothing stores in Stillwater, or one of your cribs, hit the X button to go into your own wardrobe, then go to the very last menu option and choose to remove all your clothes. Then go out in public and a Diversion will start that will give you a time limit to offend as many people as possible. As the levels go up, the more people you're required to offend with your nakedness.Ho'ingOnly located in one or two spots around the city, generally at public toilet stops, strip clubs, or adult bookstores in the Red Light District. You and a prostitute occupy a toilet cubicle for sex. Pleasure your lady for up to 10 levels to unlock a pimp outfit!MuggingMeet and greet the friendly citizens of Stilwater with some cold hard steel. Who knows, you might make a buck or two.SoundtrackSaints Row 2 features a large selection of music from a diverse background. The music is organized into radio stations by genre.K12We Are Rockstars - Does It Offend You, Yeah?Death Of A Moralist - Daniel MansuryDon and Sherri - Matthew DearGive Me Every Little Thing - Juan MacleanNorth American Scum - LCD SoundsystemSexy Results - Death From AboveSpecial Effect - TRS-80Street Justice - MSTRKRFTOver and Over - Hot ChipThrough The Hosiery - Crystal CastlesCrossover Appeal - Guns N BombsFunkLove Fades - AmnestyTrespasser - Bad MedicineGotta Get Your Love - Chocolate StarKeep Running - Cliff NyrenDrugs Ain't Cool - Ebony Rhythm BandStreet Scene - Leon MitchisonYou Can Be A Star - Luther Davis GroupWake Up Pt. 1  2 - Pure EssenceLook What You've Done To Me - Sheila SkipworthFunky In Here - Dayton SidewindersPut A Smile On Time - The Rhythm MachineThe Cissy's Thang - The Soul SevenDon't Get Discouraged - UPC AllstarsKrunchAnthem - TriviumBat Country - Avenged SevenfoldColony of Birchmen - MastodonMilk Lizard - Dillinger Escape PlanNothing Left - As I Lay DyingGhost of Perdition - OpethStars - HumResurrection - ChimairaUnsung - HelmetWhat A Horrible Night To Have A Curse - The Black Dahlia MurderRedneck - Lamb Of GodDeadly Sinners - 3 Inches of BloodBarnburner - The Agony SceneWoman - WolfmotherUndergroundAnd She Would Darken… - The Twilight SadCheer It On - Tokyo Police ClubDead Friends = The SapsDon't Call It A Ghetto… - ArchitectsEvery Single Line Means Something - Marnie SternFor Real - Okkervil RiverHazel Street - DeerhunterHere's Your Future - The ThermalsShoot The Runner - KasabianWestern Biographic - Bound StemsCall In The Debts - South StreetTerror - The RakesHouse Of Cards - ShipwreckThird Gear Scratch - ShinerGenXAll That I've Got - The UsedLying Is the Most Fun A Girl Can Have Without Taking Her Clothes Off - Panic At The DiscoRock And Roll Queen - The SubwaysTeenagers - My Chemical RomanceHate ( I Really Don't Like You) - Plain White T'sHole In the Earth - DeftonesPut Your Money Where Your Mouth Is - JetKnights - Minus The BearLet Me In - Hot Hot HeatMakedamnsure - Taking Back SundayFace Down - Red Jump Suit ApparatusCoat of Arms - The Life and TimesWhat You Need - GalacticMisery Business - ParamoreKrhymeTrick Me - KelisOne Thing aka 1 Thing - Amerie Featuring EveTell Me Bout It - Joss StoneFandango - DJ Quik Feat. B-RealSo Sick - Ne YoMe  You - CassieHands Up - Lloyd BanksNew York State of Mind - NasGangsta Bitch - ApacheSucker MCs - Run DMCRidin In That - WaleTwinz - Big Pun Feat. Fat JoeWhat A Thug About - Beanie SigelGood Girl - Chrisette MichelleI Luv It - Young JeezyThe MixDown Under - Men At WorkKarma Chameleon - Culture ClubPretty In Pink - Psychedelic FursTake On Me - A-HaThe Reflex - Duran DuranDon't You (Forget About Me) - Simple MindsOut of Touch - Hall  OatesSister Christian - Night RangerEverybody Wants To Rule The World - Tears For FearsEverybody's Working For The Weekend - LoverboyThe Final Countdown - Europe420Hey Boy - Buju BantonStop the Fussing and Fighting - Dennis BrownBoom Shaka Tak - Born JamaicansWho Am I? - Beenie ManGanja Smuggling - Eek-A-MouseGuns Out - NinjamanHeads High - Mr. VegasHere I Come - Barrington LevyKrazy - Elephant ManPicture This - Vybz CartelMurder She - Chaka Demus  PliersThe WorldOver The Moor To Maggie - Greg Knowles and Mike TaylorEl Viento En La Isla - Liza Carbe and Jean Pierre DurandBangara Dance - Ravi ShaniZahrat El Sahra - Roger AbajiThe Drunkard's Song - Viktor MastoridisSchenkt's Ma Mal Was Boarisch - Karl BarthelMountain Hut Landler - Martin BeelerMandilatos - Robin JeffreyMambo De Fito - Liza Carbe and Jean Pierre DurandHungarian Sundance - Friedrich SehlHumours of Glen Dart - Greg Knowles and Mike TaylorHot Nights - John LeachGypsy Dance - Laszlo BorteriGood Morning Polka - Jan SchneebergFriss A Rozsa - Niko RadicEmerald Jig - Ian Clarke and Simon PainterDrumjig - Greg Knowles and Mike TaylorConnaught Chase - Greg Knowles and Mike TaylorCigany - Niko RadicBarasilian Fiesta - Claudia Figueroa, Forbes Henderson, Tony Hinnigan, and Martin TaylorBaidoushka - Robin JeffreyKlassicCoppelia Ballet Suite, Act 1, No. 1 - Leo DelibesWater Music Suite No. 1 in F Major - HandelSleeping Beauty Waltz - TchaikovskyNutcracker Suite - TchaikovskyHungarian Dance No. 5 - BrahmsArrival Of The Queen Of Sheba - HandelBrandenburg Concerto No. 3 - BachConcerto No. 4 in A - BachEine Cleine Nachtmusik - MozartFour Seasons No. 1 - The Spring - VivaldiFour Seasons No. 2 - The Summer - VivaldiHaffner Serenade No. 7 in D Major - MozartMoonlight Sonata (First Movement) - BeethovenMusic for the Royal Fireworks - HandelPeer Gynt Suite No. 1 - Anitra's Dance - GriegRide of the Valkyries - WagnerString Quartet in G Major - 2nd Movement - MozartSymphony no. 40 - 1st Movement - MozartSymphony no. 5 in C Minor - Allegro Con Brio - BeethovenSymphony no. 5 in C Minor - Allegro - BeethovenToccata and Fugue in D Minor - BachWater Music Suite No. 1 in F Major - Overture - HandelMarriage of Figaro - Overture - MozartPeer Gynt Suite No. 1 - In The Hall of the Mountain King - GriegEzzzyNaughty But Nice - Walt RockmanMarvellous Singers Remix - Marc Durst and Laurent LombardLove For Life - Sammy Burdson and John Charles FiddyKalamazoo Style - Olivier Andres and Christian SeguretJust Strolling Along - Sammy Burdson and John Charles FiddyCoconuts - Gerhard NarholzDancing On The Avenue - John CacavasDolce Vita - Bruno BertoliFace To Face - Sammy BurdsonA Girl Like You - Norman CandlerJarabe Tapatio - Carlos PeriguezTooba Boogie - Otto SiebenWalkie Talkie - Gerhard NarholzWhistle Happy - Colin Baldry and Tom KaneTchoupa Twist - Nicolas FolmerA Sunny Day In Heidelberb - Horst JankowskiSwing Paname - Angel DebarreStereo Cha Cha - Umberto PagniniColonie Celeste - Jean-Jacques PerreyA Cielito Lindo - Carlos PeriguezChanson Pour Toi - Alfred JackBossa Cubana - Gerhard NarholzBerg Und Tal - Gerhard NarholzBachelor Samba - Marc DurstIt's also possible to buy individual tracks (with in-game money), and put them together to make custom radio stations.DLCPack 1Ultor Exposed - Matches you up with Tera Patrick, a disgruntled Ultor employee, trying to get rid of the corporation by exposing its seedy operations to the citizens of Stillwater. It also contains three all new co-op enabled missions. Also new air and ground vehicles, new customizations, and new Strong Arm multiplayer maps. This is priced as 800MS points ($10)Pack 2Corporate Warfare - A new civil has brewed in the Ultor corporation as Dex, a former partner from the first game, is appointed Ultor's head of security and is running a black market nuclear weapons operation. Meanwhile, an Ultor executive offers the Saints a chance to take down the corporation. It features new vehicles, customizations, multiplayer maps, and an all new Co-Op competitive mode. It is priced at 560MS points.Pack 3The Unkut Pack - It features over 60 customizations from clothing to tattoos. It is free content.PC System RequirementsMinimumSupported OS:Windows XP or Vista.Processor: 2.0 GHz Intel Dual-Core Pentium IV or equivalent or AMD Dual-Core Athlon XP or equivalentMemory: 1 GB system RAMGraphics: 128MB 3D graphics card with Shader Model 3.0 support (i.e. 7600 NVidia card or better, ATI X1300 card or better)DirectX Version: DirectX 9.0cSound: DirectX 9.0c compatible 16-bit sound cardHard Drive: 15 GB of Hard Drive SpaceDisplay: DirectX compatible display capable of 640x480 in 16-bit colorMultiplay: Internet play requires broadband connection and latest drivers; LAN play requires network interface card and latest driversRecommendedSupported OS:Windows XP or Vista.Processor: 3.2 GHz Intel Dual-Core Pentium IV or equivalent or AMD Dual-Core Athlon XP or equivalentMemory: 2 GB system RAMGraphics: 256MB 3D graphics card with Shader Model 3.0 support (i.e. 8800 NVidia card or better, ATI HD3850 card or better)DirectX Version: DirectX 9.0cSound: DirectX 9.0c compatible 16-bit sound cardHard Drive: 15 GB of Hard Drive SpaceDisplay: DirectX compatible display capable of 640x480 in 16-bit colorMultiplay: Internet play requires broadband connection and latest drivers; LAN play requires network interface card and latest driversXbox 360 Game InstallationSaints Row 2 requires 6.8GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD.Censored Version in GermanySaints Row 2 could only be released as a heavily censored version in Germany, since the USK determined that the game might be harmful to minors and likened it to criminal activity, despite it being rated too high for minors to play in the first place. The game has been so heavily censored that on Xbox Live, gamer scores for the game appear separate for the International version and the German version (which appears as "Saints Row 2 BRD"). Despite these efforts, the game is easily available in Germany from surrounding countries.A thorough list of differences to the uncensored version (in German) can be found at  schnittberichte.com. The save games of the censored German version are not compatible with the uncensored version.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20457">Grand Theft Auto IV</game><game id="10281">Bully</game><game id="17036">Grand Theft Auto: Vice City</game><game id="15879">Mafia</game><game id="5092">Bully: Scholarship Edition</game><game id="9966">Scarface: The World is Yours</game><game id="20697">Mercenaries 2: World in Flames</game><game id="4065">Crackdown</game><game id="13567">Grand Theft Auto</game><game id="10781">The Godfather: Blackhand Edition</game><game id="7180">Yakuza</game><game id="21100">Grand Theft Auto: Chinatown Wars</game><game id="3345">True Crime: New York City</game><game id="11153">True Crime: Streets of LA</game><game id="22353">The Godfather: The Don's Edition</game><game id="23346">The Godfather II</game><game id="1470">The Getaway</game><game id="14785">The Getaway: Black Monday</game><game id="18163">Just Cause</game><game id="457">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Double Agent</game><game id="10593">Grand Theft Auto 2</game><game id="20599">inFamous</game><game id="26568">Revolution</game><game id="20669">Metal Gear Solid 4: Guns of the Patriots</game><game id="20742">Just Cause 2</game><game id="27257">Gangstar: West Coast Hustle</game><game id="26790">Crackdown 2</game><game id="20638">This Is Vegas</game><game id="14491">Driv3r</game><game id="4241">Total Overdose</game><game id="21616">The Saboteur</game><game id="3157">The Simpsons: Hit &amp; Run</game><game id="5618">Saints Row</game><game id="16255">50 Cent: Bulletproof</game><game id="38237">Gangstar Rio: City of Saints</game><game id="36765">Grand Theft Auto V</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1967525-box_sr2.png</image></root>