<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20678</id><name>Soulcalibur IV</name><description>Overview    Namco's  Soul series returns with  Soulcalibur IV, which was released on July 29, 2008 in North America, and July 31, 2008 in Japan, Europe and Australia. This is the first game in the series to feature online play. It features all the familiar modes: Versus, Special Versus, Story, Arcade, Training, Create a Soul, and newly featured Tower of Lost Souls. The game also introduces several new concepts to the series, such as Critical Finishers and Soul Gauge. It has been confirmed that players are now able to play online with their created characters.Gameplay    Combat in Soulcalibur IV.     Soulcalibur IV doesn't deviate much from the core gameplay of the series;  Soulcalibur's claim to fame in the fighting game genre is the characters' usage of melee weapons (as opposed to the martial arts-based hand-to-hand combat seen in most other fighting games). Players have access to three different kinds of attacks: a horizontal slash, a vertical slash, and a kick. Each of these attacks can be performed at three different levels: high, medium, or low. Mixing up the height and type of attack to get around an opponent's guards/dodges is the key to winning. This gameplay style could be seen as similar to Tecmo's                   Dead or Alive franchise. Players also have a block button. Pressing the analog stick in different directions will let the player block either high and medium attacks or medium and low attacks.Blocking player's attacks has a little more complexity than other fighters such as                   Mortal Kombat. If players block for too long, an icon (which can be seen next to the player's life bar) will slowly change from blue to green to red to flashing red. If a player's icon is flashing red, one more strong attack will send the player into a state of "Soul Crush", stunning them for a few seconds. Once in a state of Soul Crush, the opponent can press all four face buttons on the controller (block, horizontal attack, vertical attack, and kick) to engage a critical finish, instantly killing the player. This system encourages players to not play a totally defensive game, as too much defense could lead to a Soul Crush and defeat.Players have a number of tactical options, however, to turn a well timed block into a powerful offensive assault. By pressing the analog stick or D-pad towards the opponent while hitting the block button, the player can engage a "guard impact" which will deflect the incoming attack and leave the opponent open for a split second-plenty of time to lay down a few powerful, uninterrupted attacks. Players can also "repel" a weapon attack and thrust it away from the player. This manoeuvre gives the defensive player even more time to hit an opposing player while they try to reorient themselves in combat. Every character in Soulcalibur IV has high, medium, and low  armor. A powerful attack to one of these areas could cause the armor to break, increasing damage caused to that area of the body. Broken armor will shatter in the middle of battle, changing the appearance of the character without stopping the flow of battle.Character Creation       The character creation system.       The character creation system promises to be similar to that found in  Soulcalibur III, though in Soulcalibur IV the types of clothes and armor the player equips will have an effect on his or her performance in battle. Players choose from a "style" used by one of the main Soulcalibur fighters, which effectively means that the player chooses a move set of one of the regular characters in the series. Once a style and character sex has been chosen, players can automatically generate a character based on a few specific stats (whether the character has regular, heavy or light armor, a focus on attack, defense, HP or skills, and whether the character is good or evil. Players can also choose to create their fighter from the ground up in the edit mode. Edit mode lets players choose from a number of different facial, hair, and body types, as well as different voices for their character (which can be modulated in pitch to sound higher or lower). Most importantly, players can choose from a number of different armors and accessories to equip onto their character. These accessories will increase or decrease the amount of attack, defense, or HP a character has, adapting the character for any number of single player or online challenges. Returning Characters A number of characters installments in the series return in Soulcalibur IV. The game also features several newcomers and bonus characters.Returning:                    Amy                   Astaroth                    Cassandra                    Cervantes                   Hilde                   Ivy                    Kilik                    Lizardman                    Maxi                    Mitsurugi                    Nightmare                    Raphael                     Rock                     Seong Mi-na                   Setsuka                    Siegfried                    Sophitia                    Taki                    Talim                    Tira                    Voldo                    Xianghua                    Yoshimitsu                     Yun-seong                   Zasalamel Bonus                   Angol Fear                     Ashlotte                    Kamikirimusi                     Scheherazade                    Shura                   Darth Vader (PS3)                   Yoda (360)                   Starkiller (referred to as "The Apprentice")  Unlockable Characters                    Rock: Purchase in character creation                   Zasalamel: Purchase in character creation                   Talim: Purchase in character creation                   Lizardman: Purchase in character creation                   The Apprentice: Defeat in Arcade mode with either  Yoda or Darth Vader                   Algol: Defeat in Story mode                   Angol Fear: Defeat in Story mode                   Ashlotte: Defeat in Story mode                   Kamikirimusi: Defeat in Story mode                   Scheherazade: Defeat in Story mode                   Shura: Defeat in Story mode                   Amy: Purchase in character creation                   Cervantes: Purchase in character creation                   Hong Yun-Seong: Purchase in character creation                   Sophitia: Purchase in character creation                   Setsuka: Purchase in character creation                   Seong Mi-Na: Purchase in character creation                   Yoshimitsu: Purchase in character creation Limited Premium EditionA Premium Edition of Soulcalibur IV for the Xbox 360 and Playstation 3 was alongside the Standard Edition. The Premium Edition includes: an art/comic book, a white T-shirt for the 360 version or a black T-shirt for the PlayStation 3 version, a Tournament Kit that will give people the chance to keep a record of their battles against their friends, and exclusive access to extra Create a Soul content.Downloadable ContentMany videos have leaked onto the internet, showing Yoda fighting Darth Vader. Also, in both versions of the game, there is an empty character slot that is impossible to unlock. This has led many to speculate that Darth Vader and Yoda are eventually going to be up for download on the opposing consoles. That wish came true when Namco Bandai announced Yoda being downloadable on PS3 along with Darth Vader on 360 for 400 Microsoft Points (five dollars on PSN) on October 23, 2008. The fact that the opposing characters are on-disc DLC makes Soulcalibur IV one of the more infamous examples of developers nickel-and-diming their customers through DLC.At the end of July, almost immediately after its release, Soulcalibur IV saw a host of                   DLC, though only one pack which could be applied to gameplay. The Customization Equipment pack was made available for 100  Microsoft Points or $1.49 on                   PSN, and included goodies for returning characters Sophitia (who was given an armor pack) Astaroth, Yoshimitsu and Voldo (whose old head models were made available. Also released were 17 tracks from the original game's OST, which were also made available for individual sale. They were made available for 1200 Microsoft Points for the pack, or 80 Microsoft Points per track and $14.99/$.99 each on the PlayStation Network.August saw the next DLC costume pack dubbed the 'Maid Pack'. Costing 200MS on the Xbox Market place, you unlock perverted French Maid items for your female custom character. These items include 2 types of aprons, another French maid top, a maid headdress and a maid skirt.PS3 Japanese VersionThe Japanese version is almost completely identical to the US release. If your PS3's language settings are set to English, all text and menus in the game will appear in English as well. No need to import a US copy if you are living overseas.  SoundtrackDisc One  1. "DISTANT THUNDER"   遠雷 0:35 2. "SEIZE YOUR DESTINY"   運命をつかむために 3:04 3. "REVELATION"   太古の黙示 1:31 4. "THE UNCOVERED HISTORY"   見いだされた歴史の舞台 1:37 5. "SEARCHING FOR THE TRUTH"   歴史の真実を求めて 2:43 6. "IMMACULATE PLEDGE"   その誓いに一点の穢れなし 3:08 7. "TO THE WIND"   風の生まれるところへ 1:52 8. "PHANTASMAGORIA"   一夜の夢のごとく 3:05 9. "VALIANT HEART"   勇気を内に秘め 2:16 10. "TEMPERED SOUL"   己が魂を鍛えよ 2:23 11. "REIGN OF DOOM"   破滅の座 2:57 12. "GLACIAL COLOSSEUM"   氷冠の決闘場 3:02 13. "INFERNAL OFFERING"   贄は捧げられた 2:32 14. "INDOMITABLE WARRIOR"   不撓不屈の心 2:49 15. "TWILIGHT DWELLERS"   宵闇に生きる者たち 3:12 16. "INNOCENT VISION"   ただ一時、純白の幻 4:06 17. "HALCYON HARBOR"   波路尽き、空は青 2:48 18. "LOST IN THE MIRAGE"   惑いの回廊 2:27 19. "GIGANTESQUE"   そびえ立つ巨塔 2:56 20. "BREAKTHROUGH"   切り開かざれば道はなし 2:28 21. "DESTINY WILL TELL"   宿命は争えず 2:25 22. "THE SUPREME SWORD"   頂に立つ者 2:51 23. "RAGING BLOOD"   激しい血潮のたかぶり 1:09 24. "CONFESSION"   明かされた歴史の断片 0:51 25. "FATIDIC SHADOW"   塔の暗示 1:10 26. "SPARK OF FATE"   咲くは火花、散るは命 4:28 27. "THANATOS"   死は平等なり 3:52 28. "SURVIVOR'S WORDS"   勝ち残りし者の語り 1:06 Disc Two  1. "PORTRAIT OF A WARRIOR"   ある戦士の肖像 3:21 2. "INFINITE IMAGES"   無限の想像力 3:02 3. "FATEFUL ENCOUNTER"   来るべき戦いの時 1:43 4. "THE VALIANT ORDER"   勇あるもの…… 1:14 5. "THE PERFECT WORLD"   完全なる世界］ 1:05 6. "DIES METI"   恐怖の日 0:38 7. "THE SUCCESSOR"   邪剣を継ぐもの 1:44 8. "FATE ATTESTED BY THE SWORD"   剣の示した運命 1:10 9. "BOTTOMLESS THIRST"   あくなき欲望 1:14 10. "THE SWORD KEEPER"   不死の番人 1:12 11. "SHOWDOWN"   決着の時 1:06 12. "HER DECISION"   彼女の結論 0:58 13. "A FIRM RESOLUTION"   揺るがぬ決意 1:10 14. "THE AVENGER"   復讐を成す者 1:01 15. "UNFLINCHING CHOICE"   迷いなき選択 1:29 16. "KEEPER OF THE BALANCE"   永劫の平衡を保つ者 0:34 17. "THE UNLEASHED DESPAIR"   解き放たれた絶望 1:05 18. "HER MASTER'S WAY"   師の流儀 0:59 19. "DERANGED MASTER"   狂気の主 1:24 20. "CHIMERIC FEAST"   異形たちの宴 1:11 21. "THE LAST LESSON"   最後の稽古 1:09 22. "REALIZATION"   目覚め 1:21 23. "RESTFUL WIND"   安息の風 1:08 24. "RIGHTEOUS BLADE"   義を知る者 1:01 25. "END OF A JOURNEY"   旅の終わりに 1:10 26. "LIGHT OF SALVATION"   救いの光 1:51 27. "THE ETERNAL OBSERVER"   永久の観察者 1:21 28. "THE KING'S SORROW"   王者の哀しみ 1:32 29. "THE DEED IS DONE"   偉業は成し遂げられた 1:05 30. "STORY TELLER'S BRAVERY"   語り部の勇姿 1:12 31. "THE IRON MAIDEN"   鋼鉄の淑女 1:08 32. "FIERCE WAY OF LIFE"   その荒々しき生き様 1:08 33. "SEARCHING FOR HER CLAN"   仲間を求めて 1:05 34. "APOCALYPSE"   審判の時 0:57 35. "WINDS AND MEMORIES"   追憶は風に舞い 3:50 36. "ENTWINED DESTINY"   綾なす運命の絆 2:39 37. "PATH OF DESTINY"   運命は己が胸の内に 6:40 </description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="707">Virtua Fighter 5</game><game id="20456">Street Fighter IV</game><game id="20689">Tekken 6</game><game id="7792">Dead or Alive 4</game><game id="23220">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja</game><game id="6226">Bushido Blade 2</game><game id="11876">Bloody Roar II</game><game id="21023">Star Wars: The Clone Wars - Lightsaber Duels</game><game id="1235">Street Fighter</game><game id="10476">War Gods</game><game id="22305">Street Fighter III: 2nd Impact</game><game id="21948">Street Fighter III: New Generation</game><game id="19273">Ace Combat 6: Fires of Liberation</game><game id="25990">Samurai Shodown SEN</game><game id="31127">Swords</game><game id="31233">Dragon Ball: Raging Blast 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1810170-box_sc4.png</image></root>