<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20685</id><name>NBA Ballers: Chosen One</name><description>NBA Ballers puts the user in the shoes of an amateur basketball player who gets a shot at the big time with an entry to the NBA Ballers tournament. Along the way, the created player will face off real-world NBA stars like Dwight Howard and Kobe Bryant in a variety of basketball challenges.  The foundation of NBA Ballers is its trick system, which allows players to combo together ball handling moves to baffle opponents and clear the way to the basket. As moves are accomplished, a meter fills that allows for even more outlandish moves, including a level three "shut 'em down" move that ends the game if performed.  Chosen One has a sense of hip-hop style to it, with all of the instrumental background music being provided by well-known producer Just Blaze, and full-motion video sequences that feature Public Enemy frontman, Chuck D.  Roster    Al Horford Chuck D (from Public Enemy) Carmelo Anthony Chris Paul Dirk Nowitzki Dwyane Wade Gilbert Arenas Kevin Garnett Kobe Bryant Lamar Odom LeBron James Nate Robinson Paul Pierce Stephon Marbury Steve Nash Tim Duncan Tracy Mcgrady Vince Carter Adam Morrison Al Jefferson Amare Stoudemire Andre Iguodala Andre Miller Andrea Bargnani Andrei Kirilenko Andrew Bogut Antawn Jamison Baron Davis  Brandon Roy Carlos Boozer  Chauncey Billups Chris Bosh Dwight Howard Danny Granger Elton Brand Gerald Wallace  Greg Oden Jameer Nelson Jason Richardson Jason Terry Jermaine O'Neal Joe Johnson Josh Smith Kevin Durant Kirk Hinrich Luke Ridnour Marcus Camby Michael Redd Mike Miller Peja Stojakovic Rashard Lewis Rasheed Wallace Ray Allen Ricky Davis Ron Artest Sam Cassell Sebastian Telfair Stephen Jackson Tony Parker Yao Ming Zach Randolph Moses Malone Bill Russell Clyde Drexler Darryl Dawkins Dominique Wilkins George Gervin Jame Worthy Julius Erving Larry Bird Magic Johnson Oscar Robertson Pete Maravich Walt Frazier Wilt Chamberlain Jason Kidd Shaquille O'Neal Ben Wallace Larry Hughes Mike Bibby Pau Gasol Allen Iverson The Soundtrack  Just Blaze - "Sky High" Just Blaze - "Hard Road" Just Blaze - "Hart to Hart" Just Blaze - "Head Crack" Just Blaze - "Winning Run" Just Blaze - "Squilla" Just Blaze - "Harry R" Just Blaze - "Thunder Head" Just Blaze - "Zone F" Just Blaze - "Slow Victory" Just Blaze - "Kneel Before Zeed" Just Blaze - "Canei Live" Just Blaze - "No. 1 Stunna" Just Blaze - "Wilderys Wish"</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="22">Basketball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13770">Dr. J and Larry Bird Go One on One</game><game id="16685">Jordan vs. Bird: One-on-One</game><game id="10302">NBA Street Homecourt</game><game id="21470">NBA 2K8</game><game id="9866">NBA Street Vol. 2</game><game id="7982">NBA Street</game><game id="61">NBA Street V3</game><game id="20920">Blitz: The League II</game><game id="29664">NBA Jam</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14036/824162-ballers_cover.jpg</image></root>