<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20689</id><name>Tekken 6</name><description>OverviewIn development since 2005 and originally listed as an exclusive for the arcades and the PlayStation 3, Tekken 6 is the eighth game in the 13-year-old Tekken franchise of 3D fighting games. It was first released exclusively in Japan on November 26, 2007 while released worldwide during January of 2008. It is no longer set to be released on any home consoles as it has been replaced by an updated version: Tekken 6: Bloodline Rebellion, which has been released on both the PlayStation 3 and Xbox 360.Gameplay in Tekken traditionally consists of levels comprised of infinite, circular or square arenas, where two characters duke it out using various combos, holds, special attacks and counters until one of them runs out of health. Tekken 6 contains multi-tiered, interactive, destructible stages such as the breakable floor in Fallen Colony and the destructible wall in Temple Grounds. The standard, combo-based Tekken gameplay returns, with new features such as item moves (for example, Bryan can now use a shotgun), a new "bound" system (during an air combo, certain moves knock the opponent down and make them bounce off the floor, allowing the player to continue their combo), a new "rage" system (when a player's health goes below a certain point, their attacks do much more damage).Additionally, the graphic engine in the game has been significantly redone since the original arcade release and now features full-time variable motion blur for the first time in a fighting game. Every move in the game has been reanimated, character customization options have been significantly improved, and an increased health bar has been implemented due to the new rage and bound systems allowing players to deplete greater amounts of health. The ID card system from Tekken 5 also returns. This feature enables players to record their win-loss records, achieve higher ranks through victories and earn money through matches to be able to buy items for character customization.StoryJin saluting his army during Tekken 6's CG introAt the conclusion of The King of Iron Fist Tournament 5 (Tekken 5), Jin Kazama defeated his great grandfather and tournament sponsor Jinpachi Mishima and won the tournament, as well its its grand prize - the Mishima Zaibatsu. Jin immediately changed the direction of the company, beginning various programs within the company and converted the Tekken Force into a spy project. People began suspecting darkness in the president of the Mishima Zaibatsu, which lead to increased tension, fighting and eventually a full-scale war, with the entire world drawn in. With nations beginning to lose power, war became a profitable option for the Mishima Zaibatsu, which lead to Jin announcing the Zaibatsu as an independent nation, declaring war on the entire world.Initially, the Mishima Zaibatsu proved to be a formidable enemy, but then G Corporation, lead by Jin's father Kazuya, rose to become the Zaibatsu's main opposition. The world saw G Corporation as its savior, and endorsed them completely in their attempt to suppress the Zaibatsu. G Corporation claimed that the president of the Mishima Zaibatsu was the root cause of the war, and announced that they will pay an immense amount of money to anyone who can capture Jin Kazama dead or alive. G Corporation's current CEO and chairman, Kazuya Mishima, took over the company after killing those within it who betrayed him just after The King of Iron Fist Tournament 4. As if the Mishima Zaibatsu anticipated this move, the Mishima Zaibatsu announced the opening of The King of Iron Fist Tournament 6.New CharactersBobBobBob is a Karate expert from the United States. A celebrated fighting genius with an excellent physique Bob had many fans, however his inability to defeat larger opponents drove him to build up his body size. He returned to the public eye after several years of seclusion and his new image garnered many shocked glances and more than a few sniggers. Believing he had now achieved his optimum build Bob decided to enter the King of Iron Fist Tournament 6 to test his new body.LeoLeoAn orphan from a young age, Leo is shocked when the police inconclusively end her parent's murder investigation. Taking matters into her own hands she links the death of her parents to a man by the name of Kazuya Mishima, head of the mysterious G Corporation. Although intent on tracking him down she finds it impossible to get anywhere near Kazuya. However Leo learns that the King of Iron Fist Tournament 6 is being organized by the Mishima Financial Group. Hoping for just one chance to avenge her dead parents she enters and begins training.Miguel Caballero RojoA rebel and a wanderer Miguel Caballero Rojo left home aged 15. Miguel trusted no one except his kind-hearted sister who would visit him in secret without their parents knowledge. Miguel was later outraged to learn that his sister planned to get married, he even plotted to kill his sister's fiancee. He watched the wedding from afar, disgruntled and aware that his parents would be there. All of a sudden the church became a fiery inferno and when Miguel searched the smoking ruins he found his sister in her blood soaked wedding dress. He later discovered that the air raid was ordered by the Mishima Zaibatsu, filled with hatred he vowed to kill the Zaibatsu's leader Jin Kazama.ZafinaZafinaBorn to an ancient tribe and tasked with protecting a tomb that has lay dormant for centuries, Zafina reputedly took down an army single-handedly and so was appointed the tribe's solo assassin. A keen follower of astrology she receives a bad omen, something bad is going to happen, something that could lead to the end of the world. These premonitions continually haunt her and after seeking the advice of her guru she ventures East to where this evil is apparently gathering.Returning CharactersAnna WilliamsArmor KingAsuka KazamaBaek Doo SanBruce IrvinBryan FuryCraig MardukChristie MonteiroDevil JinEddy GordoFeng WeiGanryuHeihachi MishimaHwoarangJack-6Jin KazamaJulia ChangKazuya MishimaKingKumaLee ChaolanLei WulongLiliLing XiaoyuMarshall LawMokujinNina WilliamsPandaPaul PheonixRavenRoger Jr.Sergei DragunovSteve FoxWang JinreiYoshimitsuStagesFallen ColonyAzazel's ChamberCemetery (multi-tier)City After DarkGargoyles PerchFallen Colony (multi-tier)High Roller's ClubManji ValleyMystical ForestNoh TheaterRustic AsiaTemple GroundsUrban War Zone</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="707">Virtua Fighter 5</game><game id="20678">Soulcalibur IV</game><game id="7792">Dead or Alive 4</game><game id="10651">Mortal Kombat: Unchained</game><game id="3839">Dead or Alive</game><game id="2045">Dead or Alive 2</game><game id="15584">Virtua Fighter</game><game id="22292">Dead or Alive 2: Hardcore</game><game id="11065">Shaman King: Power of Spirit</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="16842">Street Fighter: Anniversary Collection</game><game id="13753">Dead or Alive Ultimate</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="23220">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja</game><game id="9855">Soulcalibur III</game><game id="13875">Plasma Sword: Nightmare of Bilstein</game><game id="22305">Street Fighter III: 2nd Impact</game><game id="21948">Street Fighter III: New Generation</game><game id="28437">Super Street Fighter IV</game><game id="30064">Virtua Fighter 5 Final Showdown</game><game id="31233">Dragon Ball: Raging Blast 2</game><game id="35161">Soulcalibur V</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3699/374227-tekken_6_poster_v2.jpg</image></root>