<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20714</id><name>Rock Band 2</name><description>OverviewFollowing the huge success of the first Rock Band, Harmonix began work on Rock Band 2, along with publisher MTV Games and distributor EA. It was released as a stand-alone game (i.e. not bundled with instruments) on September 14th, 2008 for the Xbox 360 in North America. The PlayStation 3 version was released as both a stand-alone game as well as bundled with the new instruments on October 19th, 2008, as well as the Xbox 360 bundle, containing the game disc, guitar, drum kit and microphone. The PlayStation 2 and Wii versions were released at later dates.Naturally, Rock Band 2 features full band gameplay similar to that of its predecessor, allowing up to four players of different instruments to play together as a band. Rock Band 2 shipped with the largest on-disc setlist for a Rock Band or Guitar Hero game yet, featuring 84 songs, all of which were master recordings. Some notable inclusions on the set list include AC/DC's first song in a rhythm game with "Let There Be Rock" and Guns N' Roses "Shackler's Revenge," off their newest album Chinese Democracy. Purchasing the disc also grants buyers a voucher that allows them to download twenty free songs, with no additional charge.GameplayBasic gameplay remains the same as the original Rock Band title; players play solo or as a band in order to complete songs and get high scores by hitting notes and singing in pitch to the tune of rock songs of all years and genres. Rock Band 2, however, features many tweaks to the gameplay modes.QuickplayEither as solo or a group, Quickplay allows players to play songs with ease by simply selecting songs to play off of the list of all songs that have been unlocked. Rock Band 2, however, features a way of creating a setlist of many songs to play in order without having to stop to select a new song after completing another, which allows for a quick transition from song to song. Quickplay can be played with players locally on the same console, online with players across the console's mutliplayer service, or a combination of both.Band World TourContrary to Rock Band, the Band World Tour mode acts as both the single and mutliplayer career-like mode. Rock Band 2 no longer offers a single player mode that simply progresses the player through each difficulty of songs down the list. Instead, Band World TourCreate a band and rock the world.can now be played with any combination of instruments, including a single person. The need for a band leader has also been eliminated, so any player can jump in at any time and play. The core of Band World Tour has remained in tact: players form their own fictional rock band, name it, choose a hometown from a small selection, and progress from city to city around the world as they unlock new venues. Setlists start with simpler songs, but eventually grow into long, difficult sets as the band reaches its final stages of success. Setlists also feature downloadble content, as opposed to only on-disc songs. Throughout their career, players will unlock new cities by earning new methods of transportation, staff members that help them earn more money and fans, and new instruments, clothing, and accessories for their characters that they buy with the money. Band World Tour mode is also able to be played online now, allowing for the creation of online bands, and players are also able to assign the premade characters or their own to fill in the empty spots in a band if there are not four people playing.Tour ChallengesAnother new feature of Band World Tour mode are Tour Challenges, premade setlists that have an underlying theme, such as songs from a specific decade, that players can complete to earn achievements, songs, or other unlocks for their characters.Battle of the BandsThe last new sub-mode of Band World Tour is the Battle of the Bands, which lets players compete in weekly challenges that compare their scores to others'. The challenges range from a variety of goals, such as obtaining a long streak to simply getting the highest score on the board, and also have certain requirements, like being required to have a vocalist or play on a certain difficulty. Each battle has a leaderboard that compares your score to other player's. Battles can include downloadable content, and are often ideas contributed by the players of the Rock Band community.New FeaturesDrum TrainerRock Band 2 offers a mode in which players can attempt to teach those having trouble keeping time on the drums with a new drum trainer. It has a series of different drum beats ranging from basic patterns to more challenging rhythms, of which players can choose to play on different speeds to increase their skills, as well as a variety of common drum fill patterns. It also contains a freeplay mode, in which players can simply play whatever they want, or even play along with songs from an MP3 player or on their system's harddrive. To get the full effect of playing on a real kit, the cymbal expansions are ideal. All three modes also allow players to choose between a small variety of drum kits to "play on", including the standard Rock Band (1 or 2) kits, electronic, etc.No Fail ModeTo help make the game more accessible to everyone, No Fail Mode can be turned on so that players cannot fail out of a song if they are performing poorly. This can make the experience more enjoyable for inexperienced players, or for anyone who just wants to play through a tough song without having to be limited to playing it in practice mode.Breakneck SpeedThe Hyperspeed Mode from the Guitar Hero games is back. You can double the scrollspeed of the fretboard for all the instruments, excluding vocals. This makes the notes more spaced out as they come at you, however as a result you cannot see as many notes at a time as you could without Breakneck turned on; it's all a matter of preference.InstrumentsGuitarLet there be guitar...there was guitar.Like its predecessor, Rock Band 2 will be available in a bundle featuring all new instrument peripherals. The new Fender Stratocaster guitar, while functioning nearly the same, has a number of improvements from the last and features a new sunburst finish. This new Strat improves on the original Rock Band guitar by having a more reliable strum bar, quieter and more responsive buttons, and a new calibration system that allows you to calibrate the audio/visual lag directly from the guitar. The guitar once again features an effects switch with five effects and the high neck solo buttons. All versions of the guitar are wireless.DrumsLet there be drums....there was drums!The new drum kit is improved in terms of functionality by offering more responsive pads with better rebound. The pads are also quieter and velocity sensitive, meaning the volume of the notes will be determined by how hard you hit the pads. The kit also includes a new kick pedal that will be reinforced with metal plating, offering a far more reliable and longer lasting pedal. Additionally, the kick pedal can now be attached to the bottom of the drum set so that it doesn't drop when the set is lifted. Expansion plugs are also located on the back of the kit which allow you to plug in optional cymbal additions (sold separately). These cymbals can be used to play yellow, blue, and green notes, allowing up to three cymbals on a drum kit. While there is no visual indication of when a cymbal is being played as opposed to a tom or snare, players can enhance their musical experience by using their own judgment to correctly play both on the cymbals and pads. With all three colored cymbals plugged in, the yellow, blue, and green pads will act as toms during freestyle fills, and the cymbals will all act as cymbals (yellow high hat, blue ride, and green crash - players, however, can still use the green pad to hit the fill-ending crash cymbal to activate overdrive). Like the guitar, the drum kit wirelessly connects to the console.Ion DrumsIon Drum SetIon Audio has also developed a premium drum kit that can function both as a Rock Band peripheral and an actual electronic drum kit by purchase of a electronic drum module, or "drum brain." The Ion kit, like Rock Band's sports four pads and a bass pedal, as well as two cymbals, with the option of a third.MicrophoneThe mic offered for Rock Band 2 is the same as its predecessor aesthetically wise, however included an upgraded phoneme detector that increases the accuracy of the atonal "talkie" bits of a song's vocal part. Additionally, any microphone can be used.CompatibilityAll Rock Band instruments are compatible with Rock Band 2, and vice versa. Additionally, for the Xbox 360 and PS3, all other instrument peripherals from games such as Guitar Hero World Tour and Rock Revolution are compatible as well. This is not the case on the Wii due to technical differences. The Lips and Sing Star microphones are compatible on the Xbox 360 via a title update released on September 25, 2009.SetlistAll 84 on-disc songs in Rock Band 2 are master recordings. Additionally, 55 songs may be imported from the original Rock Band setlist after downloading a $5 export key from either the PlayStation Store or the Xbox Live Marketplace. You may also export the 45 songs from Lego Rock Band to Rock Band 2 for $10. The exporting feature does not work for the Wii.Let there be rock!AC/DC “Let There Be Rock” - 1970sAFI “Girl’s Not Grey” - 2000’sAlanis Morissette “You Oughta Know” - 1990’sAlice in Chains “Man in the Box” - 1990’sAllman Brothers “Ramblin’ Man" - 1970’sAvenged Sevenfold “Almost Easy” - 2000’sBad Company “Shooting Star” - 1970’sBeastie Boys "So Whatcha Want” - 1990’sBeck “E-Pro” - 2000’sBikini Kill “Rebel Girl” - 1990’sBilly Idol “White Wedding Pt. I” - 1980’sBlondie “One Way or Another” - 1970’sBob Dylan “Tangled Up in Blue” - 1970’sBon Jovi “Livin’ on a Prayer” - 1980’sCheap Trick “Hello There” - 1970’sDevo “Uncontrollable Urge” - 1980’sDinosaur Jr. “Feel the Pain” - 1990’sDisturbed “Down with the Sickness” - 2000’sThe Donnas “New Kid in School” - 2000’sDream Theater “Panic Attack” - 2000’sDuran Duran “Hungry Like the Wolf” - 1980’sElvis Costello “Pump It Up” - 1970’sFleetwood Mac “Go Your Own Way” - 1970’sFoo Fighters “Everlong” - 1990’sThe Go-Go’s “We Got the Beat” - 1980’sThe Guess Who “American Woman” - 1970’sGuns N’ Roses “Shackler’s Revenge” - 2000’sThe Grateful Dead “Alabama Getaway” - 1980’sInterpol “PDA” - 2000’sJane’s Addiction “Mountain Song” - 1980’sJethro Tull “Aqualung” - 1970’sJimmy Eat World “The Middle” - 2000’sJoan Jett “Bad Reputation” - 1980’sJourney “Anyway You Want It” - 1970’sJudas Priest “Painkiller” - 1990’sKansas “Carry On Wayward Son” - 1970’sL7 “Pretend We’re Dead” - 1990’sLacuna Coil “Our Truth” - 2000’sLinkin Park “One Step Closer” - 2000’sLit “My Own Worst Enemy” - 1990’sLush “De-Luxe” - 1990’sMastodon “Colony of Birchmen” - 2000’sMegadeth “Peace Sells” - 1980’sMetallica “Battery” - 1980’sMighty Mighty Bosstones “Where’d You Go” - 1990’sModest Mouse “Float On” - 2000’sMotorhead “Ace of Spades” - 1980’sThe Muffs “Kids in America” - 1990’sNirvana “Drain You” - 1990’sNorman Greenbaum “Spirit in the Sky” - 1960’sThe Offspring “Come Out  Play (Keep ‘em Separated)” - 1990’sPanic at the Disco “Nine in the Afternoon” - 2000’sParamore “That’s What You Get” - 2000’sPearl Jam “Alive” - 1990’sPresidents of the USA “Lump” - 1990’sRage Against the Machine “Testify” - 1990’sRatt “Round  Round” - 1980’sRed Hot Chili Peppers “Give it Away” - 1990’sThe Replacements “Alex Chilton” - 1980’sRise Against “Give it All” - 2000’sRush “The Trees” - 1970’sSilversun Pickups “Lazy Eye” - 2000’sSmashing Pumpkins “Today” - 1990’sSocial Distortion “I Was Wrong” - 1990’sSonic Youth “Teenage Riot” - 1980’sSoundgarden “Spoonman” - 1990’sSqueeze “Cool for Cats” - 1970’sSteely Dan “Bodhitsattva” - 1970’sSteve Miller Band “Rock’n Me” - 1970’sSurvivor “Eye of the Tiger” - 1980’sSystem of a Down “Chop Suey” - 2000’sTalking Heads “Psycho Killer” - 1970’sTenacious D “Master Exploder” - 2000’sTestament “Souls of Black” - 1990’sThe Who “Pinball Wizard” - 1960’sBonus Artist "Bonus Song Title" - DecadeAbnormality “Visions” - 2000’sAnarchy Club “Get Clean” - 2000’sBang Camaro “Night Lies” - 2000’sBreaking Wheel “Shoulder to the Plow” - 2000’sThe Libyans “Neighborhood” - 2000’sThe Main Drag “A Jagged Gorgeous Winter” - 2000’sSpeck “Conventional Lover” - 2000’sThe Sterns “Supreme Girl” - 2000’sThat Handsome Devil “Rob the Prez-O-Dent” - 2000’sDownloadable ContentThe Rock Band 2 DLC Page shows songs currently available. The official Rock Band website also contains an up-to-date, sortable list of all available songs, as well as an embeddable widget so that fans can search for specific songs. All DLC is cross-compatible between Rock Band and Rock Band 2.New copies of Rock Band 2 come with a key that can be redeemed for 20 free downloadable tracks. They are as follows:The 88 "Sons and Daughters"Authority Zero "No Regrets"Between the Buried and Me "Prequel To The Sequel"The Cab "Bounce"The Chevelles "Get It On"The Cocktail Slippers "Give It To Me"Dealership "Database Corrupted"Endeverafter "I Wanna Be Your Man"The Ghost Hounds "Ashes To Fire"Hollywood Undead "Young"Kutless "The Feeling"The Len Price 3 "If I Ain't Got You"Lesley Roy "I'm Gone, I'm Going"Opiate for the Masses "Burn You Down"Semi-Precious Weapons "Magnetic Baby"Shaimus "Like a Fool"Thenewno2 "Crazy Tuesday"Tickle Me Pink "The Time Is Wrong"Underoath "Desperate Times, Desperate Measures"X Japan "I.V."ReceptionRock Band 2 received universal acclaim, much like its predecessor. Much of the praise was focused on the improvements in the World Tour Mode, the excellent setlist, and the ability to create a band online. A major criticism was that the game was a little too similar to the original Rock Band, and that some of the songs were not fun to play on certain instruments.Rock Band NetworkThe Rock Band Network functions as a means of players posting user-generated content to Rock Band. Although from a glance it appears to be a response to the song creation tools found in some of the latest Guitar Hero titles, RBN is an incredibly robust service. At its core, the Network allows for any music owners (be they the artists themselves or legal owners of the intellectual property) to add their song to the Rock Band store. Subscribers to the service can submit a song and create a note chart and background performance using a combination of some of Harmonix's tools, as well as an XNA development kit.At present, the service only exists for Xbox 360 Rock Band 2 owners with a membership to the XNA Creators Club. Songs published via the Rock Band Network will be sold in the Xbox Live Marketplace as well as the PlayStation Store with a portion of the proceeds going to the music's creator. RBN has enormous potential for essentially everyone involved: Independent artists will have a way to gain exposure and profit from their music, while established, mainstream artists who somehow aren't yet featured in the game will have another method of submitting their creations.Several artists have already announced plans to post music for Rock Band Network including Evanescence, Creed, and Jonathan Coulton. Additionally many of Harmonix's in-house bands (Bang Camaro, etc.) have gone on record saying they will be making contributions.Gamers can only download songs released on Rock Band Network, if they have access to XNA in their country. As a result, locations such as Australia are unable to partake in the Rock Band Network at this time.Xbox 360 Game InstallationRock Band 2 requires 6.3 GB of space to be installed on an Xbox 360 HDD.Star System PatchDue to feedback and demand from Rock Band players, a star system was implemented into Rock Band 2 by a patch. It allows you to sort the songs by how many stars you have received in a song. Note that it clears the songs you have already played, so you won't see your star progress unless you play the songs again. The sorting is similar to how you sort by genre, band, etc. The patch was released for the Xbox 360 in summer of 2009 and released on PS3 early 2010.Rock Band NetworkRock Band 2 has patched in access to Harmonix's third party content system, Rock Band Network. This was the first Rock Band title to have this feature, although it was patched in. It allows for third parties to create their own music tracks without going through a Harmonix approval process. The system has over 1300 songs available to download.</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20673">Guitar Hero World Tour</game><game id="8631">GuitarFreaks 3rdMIX &amp; DrumMania 2ndMIX</game><game id="5825">Frequency</game><game id="14916">Guitar Hero II</game><game id="4031">Guitar Hero III: Legends of Rock</game><game id="20635">Rock Revolution</game><game id="6311">Guitar Hero</game><game id="12241">Guitar Hero Encore: Rocks the 80s</game><game id="23011">DrumMania</game><game id="23849">JamLegend</game><game id="23882">DJ Hero</game><game id="1420">Amplitude</game><game id="21290">Tap Tap Revenge</game><game id="1872">Frets on Fire</game><game id="23219">Guitar Rising</game><game id="24637">BCFX: The Doug Williams Edition</game><game id="24711">Guitar Hero 5</game><game id="20872">Battle of the Bands</game><game id="18157">Um Jammer Lammy</game><game id="10051">PaRappa the Rapper 2</game><game id="25385">Tap Tap Dance</game><game id="25400">SingStar Pop Edition</game><game id="25521">Guitar Hero: Smash Hits</game><game id="20462">SingStar</game><game id="21360">SingStar Rock Ballads</game><game id="21357">SingStar Rocks!</game><game id="23524">SingStar: Queen</game><game id="20639">Guitar Hero: On Tour</game><game id="21102">Guitar Hero On Tour: Decades</game><game id="25536">Guitar Hero: Van Halen</game><game id="26367">Band Hero</game><game id="25559">Rolling Stone: Drum King</game><game id="26558">SingStar Svenska Hits Schlager</game><game id="20403">Dance Factory</game><game id="30014">Guitar Hero: Warriors of Rock</game><game id="9436">Audiosurf</game><game id="28051">SingStar Motown</game><game id="27546">SingStar: Take That</game><game id="31427">DJMAX Portable 3</game><game id="11982">Elite Beat Agents</game><game id="32141">Rhythm Zone</game><game id="32905">Singstar Guitar</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8169/963183-rb2_box.jpg</image></root>