<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20733</id><name>Castle Crashers</name><description>OverviewCastle Crashers is a 2D side-scrolling beat-em-up developed and published by  The Behemoth for the  Xbox 360 (via Xbox Live Arcade on August 27, 2008),  PlayStation 3 (via PlayStation Network on August 31, 2010), and PC/Mac (via Steam on September 26, 2012).The game features an adventure mode for up to four players (either locally, online, or a mixture of both), numerous playable characters and weapons, and light RPG elements (allowing players to gain experience and upgrade character stats and abilities).The game's main inspiration comes from retro co-operative four-player beat-em-up titles like  Guardian Heroes and  Dungeons  Dragons: Shadow Over Mystara. Because of The Behemoth's relation to the  Newgrounds community, almost all of the game's soundtrack is created by the community members (and is available to download for free). The game not only has references to Behemoth's earlier game  Alien Hominid, but also Newgrounds and other internet memes.Originally released for the Xbox 360 as part of Microsoft's Summer of Arcade 2008 promotion, the game had technical problems that made online multiplayer almost impossible on certain network settings (as well as game crashes and unwanted save game deletion). After resolving those problems in a patch four months later, the game received some paid DLC adding new characters, weapons, and gear. The game was later released with new game modes and content for the PlayStation 3 and PC.GameplayCastle Crashers plays like a traditional arcade side-scrolling beat-em-up. Each player has a Light Attack button (X on the 360), a Heavy Attack button (Y on the 360), a Jump button (A on the 360), an Item button (B on the 360), a Block button (LT on the 360), a Magic button (RT on the 360), and two Item Select buttons (LB and RB on the 360). The Magic button does not perform any abilities right away, and must be held while pressing another button to perform magic attacks and abilities.Players earn experience for their characters by causing damage to enemies. (Instead of most beat-em-ups with experience where players can only earn experience by actually defeating enemies) Multiple players can simultaneously earn experience by striking the same enemy. Each time a character levels up (up to level 99), they are granted attribute points (one point, with a bonus point at levels less than 21) that can be added to one of the four character attributes:Strength - Increases the damage of physical attacks. Certain levels grant the use of special combos.Magic - Increases the damage of magical attacks and decreases the time required to recharge the magic bar. Certain levels grant the use of special magical attacks.Defense - Increases health and decreases the amount of damage you take.Agility - Increases running speed and damage/speed with the bow.Story ModeStory Mode is the default mode in the game and can be played with up to four players at a time. Players must travel from stage to stage, defeating bosses and gaining special items, in order to rescue the four princesses and reclaim the magic crystal from the Evil Wizard. There are 36 main levels (that can be later revisited in the Overworld map) split into eight sections. There are also arena stages, where players are pit in a battle royale against waves of enemies of varying types (unlocking new characters when each stage is completed). There are also stores, allowing players to buy healing potions, sandwiches, weapons, and various other items to aid them during gameplay. The Blacksmith is a special location on the Overworld map that allows players to switch between different found weapons and animal orbs.Insane ModeBy beating Story Mode once with any character, a new path should be open in the Overworld, where taking the path will start the game over in Insane Mode. (Exiting Insane Mode uses the same path, though you must defeat the first boss of the game to be able to return to Normal mode) Insane Mode is extremely difficult, and can even leave a single maxed-out character begging for mercy. A group of four maxed-out players is advised for beating this mode. Completing Insane Mode earns your character a golden skull that shows up in the character selection screen and a special  trophy for the PlayStation 3 version. The PlayStation 3 version also includes a special store for Insane Mode.Arena ModeUp to four players (online and offline) pick their best character and compete in a battle royale to the death. If a single player competes locally, they will just face waves of A.I. opponents. Characters are re-balanced to level 99 so everyone is on the same playing field. Players can be split into multiple teams in the PlayStation 3 version. There are five arenas (using the same stages as the Story Mode arenas) and four different game modes:Melee - Standard match.Quickdraw - Every attack button is mapped to the Bow  Arrows.Treasure - Every attack button is mapped to the Shovel. The only way to do damage is by either doing the digging animation near other players, or collecting treasure (which must be dug up).Beefy - Players are stripped of their weapons. Chickens (representing the Behemoth mascot) are scattered around the level and moving constantly. Players must grab these chickens in order to beef-up (like the Sandwich item) and beat up their opponents."All You Can Quaff" ModeAvailable in the Xbox 360 and Steam version, "All You Can Quaff" is a simple button masher mini-game for up to four players (online, offline, and A.I.). Players alternate between the Light Attack and Heavy Attack buttons to eat various pieces of fruit. When they finish that piece of fruit, they have to hit the Jump button in order to call the next piece of fruit. The winner is declared when they eat their final piece of fruit, which is depicted by a flag slowly raising next to them. In rare instances, it's possible for multiple players to finish at the same time (in which there are multiple winners).Volleyball ModeExclusive to the PlayStation 3 version, Volleyball mode pits up to eight players (up to 4 players online and offline, the rest can be A.I.) in a volleyball match. Players can use magic attacks to place effects on the ball.Playable CharactersThe game features 28 playable characters. However, only four are available from the start. The rest needs to be unlocked by either completing various in-game tasks or downloading DLC packs. Each character has unique magic blasts, jumps, and projectiles. (Though most of the magic blasts for non-elemental characters is the same volley of arrows)Default Characters Green Knight - Performs poison-based magic attacks. Starts out with the Thin Sword. Orange Knight - Performs fire-based magic attacks. Starts out with the Broad Ax.Red Knight - Performs lightning-based magic attacks. Starts out with the Mace. Blue Knight - Performs ice-based magic attacks. Starts out with the Sheathed SwordUnlockable CharactersGray Knight - Throws bomb projectiles in an arc. Starts out with the Skinny Sword. Unlocked by defeating the first boss.Barbarian - Throws axe projectiles in a straight line. Starts out with the Barbarian Ax. Unlocked by completing the King's Arena.Thief - Throws sword projectiles in a straight line. Starts out with the Thief Sword. Unlocked by completing the Thieves' Arena. Peasant - Throws dagger projectiles in a straight line. Starts out with the Wooden Spoon. Unlocked by completing the Peasants' Arena.Iceskimo - Performs ice-based magic attacks similar to the Blue Knight (but with higher Magic consumption). Starts out with the Fishing Spear. Unlocked by completing the Ice Arena.Periwinkle Knight - Throws bomb projectiles in an arc. Starts out with the Light Sabre. Unlocked by completing the Volcano Arena. Royal Guard - Throws bomb projectiles in an arc. Starts out with the Saracen Sword. Unlocked by completing the game with the Green Knight. Saracen - Performs sand-based magic attacks. Starts out with the Saracen Sword. Unlocked by completing the game with the Royal Guard.Fire Demon - Performs fire-based magic attacks. Starts out with the Round Mace. Unlocked by completing the game with the Orange Knight. Ninjer - Throws shuriken projectiles and emits purple smoke. Starts out with the Sai. Unlocked by completing the game with the Fire Demon. Skeleton - Performs dark-based magic attacks. Starts out with the Skeletor Mace. Unlocked by completing the game with the Red Knight. Bear - Performs wind-based magic attacks. Starts out with the Club. Unlocked by completing the game with the Skeleton.Industrialist - Attacks with buzzsaws. Starts out with the Ugly Mace. Unlocked by completing the game with the Blue Knight.Fencer - Attacks with buzzsaws. Starts out with the Fencer's Foil. Unlocked by completing the game with the Industrialist.Black Knight - Throws knife projectiles in a straight line. Starts out with the Gladiator Sword. Unlocked by completing the game with the Gray Knight. Killer Beekeeper - Attacks with  bees. Starts out with the Rat Beating Bat. Unlocked by completing the game with the Barbarian.Snakey - Throws dagger projectiles in a straight line and performs earth-based magic attacks. Starts out with the Snakey Mace. Unlocked by completing the game with the Thief.Civilian - Throws knife projectiles in a straight line. Starts out with the Pitchfork. Unlocked by completing the game with the Peasant.Brute - Performs earth-based magic attacks. Starts out with the Dual Prong Sword. Unlocked by competing the game with the Iceskimo. Alien Hominid - Fires beams from his plasma gun. Starts out (and can only equip) the Alien Gun. Unlocked in the Xbox 360 version by getting an achievement in  Alien Hominid HD. Unlocked in the PlayStation 3, PC, and Mac versions by completing the Alien Ship level.Open-faced Gray Knight - Throws knife projectiles in a straight line. Starts out with the Thin Sword. Unlocked in the Xbox 360 version by purchasing the King Pack DLC. Unlocked in the PlayStation 3, PC, and Mac versions by completing Catfish on Insane Mode.King - Throws knife projectiles in a straight line and performs healing-based magic. Starts out with the King's Mace. Unlocked in the Xbox 360 version by purchasing the King Pack DLC. Unlocked in the PlayStation 3, PC, and Mac versions by completing Pipistrello's Cave on Insane Mode.Necromancer - Attacks with skeletons. Starts out with the Evil Sword. Unlocked in the Xbox 360 version by purchasing the Necromantic Pack DLC. Unlocked in the PlayStation 3, PC, and Mac versions by completing Industrial Castle on Insane Mode.Cult Minion - Attacks with dark-based magic attacks. Starts out with the Glowstick. Unlocked in the Xbox 360 version by purchasing the Necromantic Pack DLC. Unlocked in the PlayStation 3, PC, and Mac versions by completing Ice Castle on Insane Mode. Pink Knight - Unlocked by purchasing the Pink Knight Pack DLC. Starts out with the NG Lollipop. Performs rainbow magic attacks, as well as using stuffed fluffy weasels and penguins as projectiles.Blacksmith - Unlocked by purchasing the Blacksmith Pack DLC. Starts out with the Hammer. Originally shown helmet-less in theHatty Hattington - Unlocked in the Xbox 360 version by getting an achievement in BattleBlock Theater. Starts out with the Gem Sword. Uses money-based magic attacks, as well as gems as projectiles.WeaponsThroughout Castle Crashers, players will often find new weapons that can be equipped. Players can only carry a single weapon that is either equal in level or less (with the exception of the character's starting weapons), picking up new weapons will cause you to drop your previous weapon and will unlock that weapon in the Blacksmith's Weapon Frog, where it can later be used. Each weapon has attributes that can increase/decrease your character's attributes. Some weapons can perform elemental side-effects and some weapons have a chance of performing a  critical hit attack.Level 1 WeaponsSkinny Sword - Found in Castle Keep. Starting weapon for the Gray Knight. 1 to Agility, -1 to Strength.Thin Sword - Starting weapon for the Green Knight and the Open-faced Gray Knight.Barbarian Ax - Found in Castle Keep. Starting weapon for the Barbarian. -1 to Magic, -1 to Defense. Adds critical hit chance.Pitchfork - Found in Home Castle. Starting weapon for the Civilian. 1 to Strength, -1 to Agility.Mace - Starting weapon for the Red Knight.Wrapped Sword - Found in Thieves' Forest. -1 to Strength, 1 to Magic, 1 to Defense.Meat Tenderizer - Found in Thieves' Forest. 2 to Strength, -1 to Agility.Sheathed Sword - Starting weapon for the Blue Knight.Twig - Found in Thieves' Store. -1 to Strength, 2 to Magic, -1 to Defense.Leafy Twig - Found in Thieves' Forest. -1 to Strength, -1 to Defense, 2 to Agility.Wooden Spoon - Starting weapon for the Peasant. -1 to Magic, 2 to Agility.Alien Gun - Starting weapon for the Alien Hominid.Broad Ax - Starting weapon for the Orange Knight.Fishing Rod - Found in Marsh. -1 to Strength, -1 to Magic, -1 to Defense.NG Lollipop - Unlocked in the Xbox 360 version by purchasing the King Pack DLC or the Pink Knight Pack DLC. Unlocked in the PlayStation 3, PC, and Mac versions by purchasing the Pink Knight Pack DLC. 5 to Agility.NG Gold Skull Mace - Unlocked in the Xbox 360 version by purchasing the Necromantic Pack DLC. Found in the PlayStation 3, PC, and Mac versions in the Insane Store. Adds critical hit chance.NG Gold Sword - Unlocked in the Xbox 360 version by purchasing the King Pack DLC. (6 to Strength, 1 to Magic, 1 to Defense) Found in the PlayStation 3, PC, and Mac versions in the Insane Store.Chainsaw - Unlocked in the Xbox 360 version by purchasing the Necromantic Pack DLC. Found in the PlayStation 3, PC, and Mac versions in the Insane Store. 4 to Defense. Adds critical hit chance.Hammer - Unlocked by purchasing the Blacksmith Pack DLC. 3 to Strength, -1 to Agility.Gem Sword - Unlocked in the Xbox 360 version by getting an achievement in BattleBlock Theater.Level 5 WeaponsHalf Sword - Found in Industrial Castle. -1 to Magic, 2 to Defense.Carrot - Found in Home Castle. -1 to Strength, -2 to Magic, 3 to Defense.Thief Sword - Found in Forest Entrance. Starting weapon for the Thief. -1 to Strength, 2 to Agility.Fish - Found in Tall Grass Field. 2 to Strength, -1 to Magic.Leaf - Found in Forest Entrance. -1 to Strength, 3 to Magic, -1 to Defense.Lobster - Found in Tall Grass Field. -1 to Strength, 1 to Agility. Adds critical hit chance.Umbrella - Found in Tall Grass Field. -2 to Strength, 3 to Defense.Wrench - Found in Tall Grass Field. 1 to Strength, -1 to Magic. Adds critical hit chance.Chicken Stick - Found in Snow World. 2 to Magic, -1 to Defense, -1 to Agility.Level 10 WeaponsPumpkin Peeler - Found in Desert Chase. 3 to Strength, -2 to Magic, 2 to Defense.Zigzag - Found in Industrial Castle. 3 to Magic, 1 to Defense, -1 to Agility.Saracen Sword - Found in Desert. Starting weapon for the Royal Guard and the Saracen. 1 to Strength, 3 to Defense.Fencer's Foil - Found in Industrial Castle. Starting weapon for the Fencer. 1 to Strength, 1 to Magic, 1 to Agility.Apple Peeler - Found in Wedding Crash. -1 to Strength, 1 to Magic, 3 to Defense.Rubber-Handle Sword - Mysterious weapon that can only be obtained by someone who already has it. 2 to Strength, -2 to Magic, 3 to Agility.Refined Mace - Found in Flowery Field. 1 to Strength, 1 to Defense, 1 to Agility.Clunky Mace - Found in Volcano Store. 5 to Strength, -2 to Agility.Rat Beating Bat - Found in Flowery Field. Starting weapon for the Killer Beekeeper. 2 to Strength, 1 to Defense.Practice Foil - Found in Church Store. 1 to Magic, -1 to Defense, 3 to Agility.Light Sabre - Found in Wedding Crash. Starting weapon for the Periwinkle Knight. 1 to Agility. Adds lightning damage chance.Staff - Found in Church Store. 4 to Magic, -1 to Defense.Killbasa - Found in Desert Chase. 1 to Strength, 1 to Magic.Level 15 WeaponsThick Sword - Found in Swamp Village Store. 2 to Strength, -1 to Magic, 5 to Defense.Gladiator Sword - Found in Full Moon. Starting weapon for the Black Knight. 1 to Strength, -1 to Magic, 3 to Defense. Adds critical hit chance.Butcher Knife - Found in Snow Store. 5 to Strength, -2 to Magic, 2 to Agility.Gold Sword - Found in Marsh. 4 to Magic, 1 to Defense.Playdo Pasta Maker - Found in Medusa's Lair. 3 to Magic, 3 to Defense, -1 to Agility.Pointy Sword - Found in Industrial Castle. 1 to Magic, 2 to Defense, 2 to Agility.Chewd Up Sword - Found in Medusa's Lair. -1 to Magic, 4 to Defense, 2 to Agility.Curved Sword - Found in Sand Castle Roof. 2 to Strength, 3 to Magic, -1 to Defense.Key Sword - Found in Full Moon. Needed for getting the Beholder animal orb. -1 to Strength, 3 to Magic, 3 to Agility.Bone Leg - Found in Snow Store. -2 to Strength, 5 to Agility. Adds critical hit chance.Fishing Spear - Found in Snow World. Starting weapon for the Iceskimo. 5 to Strength, 2 to Magic, -3 to Agility.Lance - Found in Snow Store. 4 to Strength, 2 to Defense, -2 to Agility.Unicorn Horn - Found in Wizard Castle Interior. -3 to Strength, 6 to Magic, 1 to Defense.Candlestick - Found in Marsh. -1 to Strength, 1 to Magic. Adds fire damage chance.Panic Mallet - Found in Marsh. 1 to Strength. Adds critical hit chance.Broad Spear - Found in Medusa's Lair. -2 to Strength, 4 to Agility. Adds critical hit chance.Level 20 WeaponsDual Prong Sword - Found in Industrial Castle. Starting weapon for the Brute. 3 to Strength, 3 to Defense. Adds critical hit chance.Club - Found in Tall Grass Field. Starting weapon for the Bear. 5 to Strength, 5 to Defense, -5 to Agility. Adds critical hit chance.Ugly Mace - Found in Industrial Castle. Starting weapon for the Industrialist. -2 to Magic, 6 to Defense. Adds critical hit chance.Skeletor Mace - Found in Marsh. Starting weapon for the Skeleton. -2 to Strength, 3 to Defense, 6 to Agility.Snakey Mace - Found in Marsh. Starting weapon for the Snakey. 5 to Magic, -2 to Defense, 3 to Agility. Adds critical hit chance.Round Mace - Found in Lava World. Starting weapon for the Fire Demon. -3 to Strength, 6 to Magic, 1 to Defense. Adds critical hit chance.King's Mace - Dropped by the King if he is killed by Killer Beekeepers on Insane Mode. Starting weapon for the King. 3 to Strength, 2 to Magic, 3 to Defense.Sai - Found in Pirate Ship. Starting weapon for the Ninjer. -2 to Defense, 6 to Agility. Adds critical hit chance.Ribeye - Found in Ice Castle. 4 to Strength, -2 to Magic, 4 to Agility.Evil Sword - Found in Wizard Castle Interior. Starting weapon for the Necromancer. 2 to Magic, 7 to Defense.Ice Sword - Found in Ice Castle. Adds ice damage chance.Glowstick - Found in Wizard Castle Interior. Starting weapon for the Cult Minion. -4 to Strength, 5 to Magic, 5 to Defense.Demon Sword - Found in Final Battle. 2 to Strength, 2 to Magic, 2 to Agility. Adds fire damage chance.ItemsThroughout the game, players can pick up various items that will aid them on their quest. Some of them are alternate weapons, some give you health or special abilities, and some are required to progress through the game.Alternate WeaponsBow  Arrows - Allows the player to fire an arrow projectile at enemies in their direct plane. Increasing the Agility attribute increases the damage and speed at which arrows travel. These are dropped by enemies that use the bow as a weapon and have infinite ammo.Boomerang - Allows the player to throw a boomerang at enemies, which travels back to that player (causing more damage). Used primarily to break through obstacles. Found with the Cardinal animal orb in Thieves' Forest.Bomb - Can be used to damage and knock down groups of enemies, as well as open certain hidden areas throughout the game. Each bomb must be bought from certain stores.Shovel - Used primarily to dig up buried items and secret weapons, but can also damage enemies from the digging animation. Found in Desert.Horn - Given to players after completing Corn Boss, the Horn lets off a loud sound that damages enemies and activates secret areas and events.Health and Other EffectsHealth Potion - Fully restores a player's health. Found in all stores.Sandwich - Using one allows the player to become beefed up for ten seconds, giving them increased power and damage resistance. Found in certain stores.Required for Game ProgressionCompassSteering WheelTelescopeMapAnimal OrbsAnimal Orbs are little creatures that can be either found hidden within a level, acquired after defeating certain enemies, or bought from shops. They are passive characters that follow your character around, providing their own unique ability to aid you in battle. Running into another Orb in a level replaces your current one and adds that Orb to the Blacksmith's Animal Ark, where it can be replaced later. There are 28 Animal Orbs, two of them are included as DLC for the Xbox 360 version.Chicken - Found in Medusa's Lair. Adds 1 to Strength, 1 to Defense, and 1 to Agility. Cardinal - Found in Industrial Castle. Retrieves secret items. Owlet - Found in Forest Entrance. Retrieves food hidden in trees. Mr. Buddy - Found in Home Castle. Allows you to dig faster. Giraffey - Found in Desert. Increases multiplier for gaining experience by 10%. Snoot - Found in Cyclops's Fortress. Adds 2 to Strength. Piggy - Found in Swamp Village Store. Increases potency of food. Zebra - Found in Desert Chase. Retrieves food hidden in grass. Rammy - Found in Tall Grass Field. Randomly knocks down enemies. Spiny - Found in Volcano Store. Adds 2 to Defense. Bitey Bat - Found in Pipistrello's Cave. Flies around the heads of enemies, preventing them from moving and doing little damage. Troll - Found in Thieves' Forest. Slowly regenerates your health. Frogglet - Found in Marsh. Retrieves nearby items with its tongue. Seahorse - Found in Thieves' Forest. Allows you to move through water faster. Snailburt - Found in Marsh. Adds 5 to Defense, -5 to Agility. Scratchpaw - Found in Sandcastle Interior. Adds 1 to Strength, 2 to Agility. Yeti - Found in Snow World. Protects you from being frozen. Monkeyface - Found in Church Store. Increases chance of finding items. Pazzo - Found in Snow Store. Hovers over buried items. Sherbert - Found in Animal Ark. Allows you to jump higher. Meowburt - Found in Parade. Adds 3 to Agility. Hawkster - Found in Tall Grass Field. Attacks downed enemies and retrieves extra food from defeated enemies. Burly Bear - Found in Tall Grass Field. Adds 2 to Strength. BiPolar Bear - Found in Snow World. Attacks any characters (including allies and even the owner) with low health. Beholder - Found in Animal Ark. Adds 2 to Magic. Install Ball - Found in Alien Ship. Shoots lasers at enemies.Pelter - Unlocked in the Xbox 360 version by purchasing the King Pack DLC. Found in the PlayStation 3, PC, and Mac versions in the Insane Store. Randomly throws ice at enemies.Dragonhead - Unlocked in the Xbox 360 version by purchasing the Necromantic Pack DLC. Found in the PlayStation 3, PC, and Mac versions in the Insane Store. Randomly throws fire at enemies.Golden Whale - Unlocked in the Xbox 360 version by getting an achievement in BattleBlock Theater. Randomly drops gold.Downloadable ContentWhat you gain from both the King Pack and the Necromantic Pack. (The three on the bottom-right are components of one weapon: the Chainsaw)The Xbox 360 version of Castle Crashers features two downloadable content packs released in 2009 for 160 msp ($2) each, featuring new playable characters, weapons, animal orbs, and abilities. The PlayStation 3 version contains all of this content within the game, which must be unlocked by either completing certain levels on Insane Mode or buying them from the Insane Store.On February 8, 2011, Behemoth released the Pink Knight Pack (featuring new weapons and a new character) on the PlayStation 3 version for $1.99. Revenue earned by purchasing the pack is being donated to charities dedicated to breast cancer research.King PackReleased on January 14, 2009 for the Xbox 360 version.New Playable Characters:Open-faced Gray KnightKingNew Weapons:King's MaceNG LollipopNG Gold SwordNew Animal Orb:PelterNecromantic PackReleased on August 26, 2009 for the Xbox 360 version.New Playable Characters:NecromancerCult MinionNew Weapons:ChainsawNG Gold Skull MaceNew Animal Orbs:DragonheadPink Knight PackReleased on February 8, 2011 for the PlayStation 3 version, on August 26, 2011 for the Xbox 360 version, and on September 26, 2011 for the PC and Mac versions.New Playable Character:Pink KnightNew Weapons:NG LollipopBlack MaceBroccoliElectric EelScissorsBlacksmith PackNew Playable Character:BlacksmithNew Weapons:HammerMan CatcherDinner ForkCattle Prod2x4 SwordPC System RequirementsMinimum:OS:Microsoft® Windows® XP / Vista / 7Processor:Intel Core 2 Duo 2GHz+ or betterMemory:1 GB RAMGraphics:Graphics Card that supports Pixel Shader 2.0 and Vertex Shader 2.0DirectX®:9.0cHard Drive:250 MB HD spaceSound:DirectX compatibleOther Requirements:Broadband Internet connectionAdditional:Supports Microsoft® Xbox 360 controller or Direct Input compatible controllerRecommended:OS:Microsoft® Windows® XP / Vista / 7Processor:Intel Core 2 Duo 2GHz+ or betterMemory:2 GB RAMGraphics:Graphics Card that supports Pixel Shader 2.0 and Vertex Shader 2.0DirectX®:9.0cHard Drive:250 MB HD spaceSound:DirectX compatibleOther Requirements:Broadband Internet connectionAdditional:Supports Microsoft® Xbox 360 controller or Direct Input compatible controllerMac System RequirementsMinimum:OS:Mac OS X 10.5 - LeopardProcessor:Intel Core 2 Duo 2GHz+ or betterMemory:2 GB RAMGraphics:Graphics Card that supports Pixel Shader 2.0 and Vertex Shader 2.0Hard Drive:300 MB HD spaceSound:Mac compatible sound cardOther Requirements:Broadband Internet connectionAdditional:With the right drivers the game supports Microsoft® Xbox 360, Sony PS3, and Logitech controllersRecommended:OS:Mac OS X 10.7 - LionProcessor:Intel Core 2 Duo 2GHz+ or betterMemory:4 GB RAMGraphics:Graphics Card that supports Pixel Shader 2.0 and Vertex Shader 2.0Hard Drive:300 MB HD spaceSound:Mac compatible sound cardOther Requirements:Broadband Internet connectionAdditional:With the right drivers the game supports Microsoft® Xbox 360, Sony PS3, and Logitech controllers</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17452">Alien Hominid</game><game id="6722">Final Fight</game><game id="20436">Streets of Rage</game><game id="6608">River City Ransom</game><game id="2536">Altered Beast</game><game id="15143">Knights of the Round</game><game id="20752">Double Dragon</game><game id="9663">Captain Commando</game><game id="14351">Golden Axe</game><game id="5901">Guardian Heroes</game><game id="21228">Battletoads</game><game id="22870">Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Tower of Doom</game><game id="22872">Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Shadow Over Mystara</game><game id="290">Vampire Killer</game><game id="25714">Explodemon!</game><game id="21184">Fat Princess</game><game id="24997">Eduardo the Samurai Toaster</game><game id="27063">Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Turtles in Time Re-Shelled</game><game id="24397">Fairytale Fights</game><game id="27973">Penalty of Heroes</game><game id="28126">Dungeon Fighter Online</game><game id="30494">Charlie Murder</game><game id="29491">Scott Pilgrim vs. The World: The Game</game><game id="31280">Protect Me Knight</game><game id="25637">Shank</game><game id="32612">Platformance: Castle Pain</game><game id="28897">Samurai Deeper Kyo</game><game id="31659">Moon Diver</game><game id="3705">Dragon Valor</game><game id="15148">Splatterhouse</game><game id="17393">The Tick</game><game id="21870">The Outfoxies</game><game id="20588">Super Smash Bros. Brawl</game><game id="7950">The Peace Keepers</game><game id="23408">Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles</game><game id="36721">Code of Princess</game><game id="39520">Crisis Heart Brawlers: Clash at Otakon</game><game id="39901">Picotto Knights</game><game id="39269">Sacred Citadel</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1331136-ccrasher_box.png</image></root>