<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20755</id><name>19XX: The War Against Destiny</name><description>StoryThe story takes place during a fictional war following a lone pilot trying to save the world from an evil corporation trying to start a third world war. The player must take control of the pilot and battle his way through six stages of mayhem and climactic boss battles.   BasicsThe piloting player selects one of three different planes, each with a unique statistic in three different category's of speed, homing and power. In addition, each of the planes will get a damage boost to one the existing three weapons. During game-play the pilot will face a horde of enemies and find multiple ways to defeat them. Holding down the firing button will charge up a homing missile that will lock on to the target and give a massive damage boost. In tight situations the pilot can also use an evasive loop or drop a smart bomb to evade/destroy incoming fire. Power-ups and medals for extra bonus score will also drop from various enemies as the game progress.  PlanesThere's three different planes to pilot each with a set of unique statistics and a special weapon. The special weapon skill set determines which weapon in the game the player can power-up on more step.    Mosquito:  Strong in power but rather slow moving with a weak Homing stat.    Special weapon: Missiles, the forward-firing missile becomes much stronger when powered-up Sinden: Represents speed for fast and evasive maneuvers, very weak in Power and medium-weak stat in Homing.   Special weapon: Laser, will produce a twin-laser shot for better spread when powered up. Lightning: The most balanced plane in the game with a strong Homing attack.   Special weapon: Vulcan, will produce three shots when powered up.  WeaponsThere's three unique weapons featured in the game each comes with it own strength and weakness.     Missiles: Shoots out three missiles in the classic spread pattern. Stronger in close range but over all a weaker weapon compared.   Vulcan: Your basic machine-gun styled weapon, the default starting weapon for every plane. A very balanced weapon with a medium spread and medium-strong firepower.   Laser: Strongest in firepower but the weakest in spread, will penetrate through anything making it very effective for boss-battles. Music19XX: The war against destiny features a classic Capcom style of soundtrack.    Track list:Mission 1 - A Bit of Blue Sky Between the Clouds Mission 2 - The Red Naval Port Mission 3 - Dance of the Green Gnome Mission 4 - Silver Ice Sheet Mission 5 - City Lights in the Black Strait Final Mission P1 - Grayish Tornado Final Mission P2 - The Last-Ditch Fight  Track list copy-pasted from Arcade-history.com    Music composed by    Syun Nishigaki , Tatsuro Zukuki</description><genres><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2032">Aero Fighters</game><game id="19210">Aero Fighters 2</game><game id="9871">Aero Fighters 3</game><game id="16693">Raiden</game><game id="5962">Raiden II</game><game id="413">Raiden III</game><game id="11379">Ghost Pilots</game><game id="22712">Giga Wing</game><game id="385">Giga Wing 2</game><game id="24002">Raiden IV</game><game id="25243">Shooting Love, 200X</game><game id="22550">DonPachi</game><game id="21705">DoDonPachi</game><game id="216">Dodonpachi Dai-Ou-Jou</game><game id="1487">Xevious</game><game id="597">Super Xevious</game><game id="16952">Radiant Silvergun</game><game id="21861">Twinbee</game><game id="7455">TwinBee 3: Poko Poko Daimaou</game><game id="1506">Twinbee da!</game><game id="1190">Pop'n Twinbee</game><game id="15361">Gun.Smoke</game><game id="12864">Nanostray</game><game id="21385">Nanostray 2</game><game id="5564">Dragon Saber: After Story of Dragon Spirit</game><game id="5015">Psyvariar: Complete Edition</game><game id="956">Steam Hearts</game><game id="10744">OverKill</game><game id="75">Castle Shikigami 2</game><game id="7928">M.U.S.H.A.</game><game id="10870">Solar Striker</game><game id="25828">Ray Crisis</game><game id="28233">Progear</game><game id="6869">Bomber Raid</game><game id="14734">Power Strike II</game><game id="2551">D-Force</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/172/350522-19xx_game_flyer.jpg</image></root>