<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20785</id><name>FIFA Street 3</name><description>Fifa Street 3 is the third game in EA BIG's street franchise based on football (soccer). Street soccer is very flashy, and Fifa Street 3 features a ton of unbelievable football tricks that only the best freestylers in the world can do easily. It's the first game for the new generation of consoles, the Xbox 360 and PS3, along with some other platforms, like the Nintendo DS. EA has redesigned the gameplay a bit in Fifa Street 3.GameplayInstead of a keeper and 10 field players, Fifa Street 3 will allow you to take control of only one keeper and 4 field players. You play in small arenas that have walls that you can use to beat players or There are some gravity-defying tricks in the gamepass along to outpass an opponent more indirectly. The Y button (on Xbox 360) or the Triangle button (on PS3) can be used to launch the ball into the air. If you are standing still, the player will start to juggle, but if you are running, he'll knock the ball in front of him to set himself up for a volley or beat a player. You can also use the stick to do ground tricks, both in beating players or using various flashylooking drags. Finally, you can trap the ball with the left trigger or L2 for additional tricks. A player can also do some extremely unrealistic tricks such as running along a wall with the ball at his feet, then flipping off it and beating a player before knocking the ball over another defender and ramming the ball into the net (or any other object that serves as a goal). Situations such as these are very common in the Fifa Street games.Cover AthletesFeatured on the game's cover are Brazilian superstar Ronaldinho, England's star Peter Crouch, and Italian star Gennaro Gattuso.In Game SoundtrackHexstatic  - Red Laser Beam Hexstatic  - Tokyo Traffic Hexstatic  - Bust Tim Deluxe - Let The Beats Roll Tim Deluxe - Let The Beats Roll (Rennie Pilgrim Mix) Asian Dub Foundation - Stop Start Bassnectar (feat. Ms. Persia) - Kick It Complex Bassnectar (feat. Ms. Persia) - Kick It Complex (Bassnectar Remix) Bassnectar (feat. Ms. Persia) -  Bomb The Blocks Bassnectar (feat. Ms. Persia)  - Bomb The Blocks (Ghislain Poirier Mix) Montreal / Canada Bassnectar (feat. Kristinamaria) - Yo Bassnectar (feat. Kristinamaria) - Yo (Speaker Junk’s Jackin’ Mix) Buraka Som Sistema - Yah! feat. Petty Chromeo - Fancy Footwork (Zdar Dub, Pee Thug Edit) Chromeo - Fancy Footwork (DIM Mix) Coburn (feat. Solidstate) -  We Interrupt This Programme Coburn  - We Interrupt This Programme (Jean Claude Ades Mix) Datarock - I Used To Dance With My Daddy (M.O.M. Mix) Datarock - I Used To Dance With My Daddy (Subsource Mix) Does It Offend You, Yeah? - We Are Rock Stars Does It Offend You, Yeah? - Battle Royale Forro In The Dark - Suor de Futbol Fina (Mawglee Mix) Innerpartysystem - Don’t Stop Junkie XL (feat. Lauren Rocket) -  Booming Right At You M.I.A. - Bird Flu M.I.A. - Boyz MC Amilcka - Humildade da Favela No Bizzi (feat. J2K) - Yeah Yeah Sasha  Paul Rogers - Black Powder The Go! Team - Grip Like A Vice The Planet People (feat. Afrika Bambaataa) -  Make It Break (La Resistance and Deemus Mix) The Tigerpicks - Disco Punk Electro Funk Underworld - Crocodile Underworld - Crocodile (Huntemann Mix) Walter Meego - Wanna Be A Star Walter Meego - Wanna Be A Star (Walter Sees Stars Mix) Wax Poetic - Bombeiro  Playable Area's in the Game:Street Balcony near Charles Bridge in Prague, Czech Republic Parking lot in Little Havana in Miami, Florida (US) Street Underpass in Sao Paulo, Brazil an Oil Rig near Campeche, Mexico Shipyard near Liverpool, England Rooftop of Shanghai, China Coastal neighborhood of Naples, Italy </description><genres><genre id="40">Soccer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20798">UEFA Euro 2008</game><game id="13754">This is Football</game><game id="2433">Kunio-kun no Nekketsu Soccer League</game><game id="4551">Pro Evolution Soccer 2</game><game id="21612">90 Minutes: European Prime Goal</game><game id="21030">FIFA Soccer 09</game><game id="37">FIFA Soccer 07</game><game id="19644">RedCard 20-03</game><game id="1586">Total Club Manager 2003</game><game id="31024">SFG Soccer</game><game id="30203">Pure Futbol</game><game id="27038">FIFA 06: Road To FIFA World Cup</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2266517-box_fifastr3.png</image></root>