<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20794</id><name>Wall-E</name><description>OverviewWall-E is a video game based of the 2008 hit Pixar film of the same name. In the game, the player takes control of either Wall-E or EVE (and sometimes, both at the same time) as they adventure through 9 levels that follow the same plot as the movie and allow the player to play scenes taken directly from the film. The Wall-E gameplay consists of platforming segments that use his ability to crush cubes and throw them, while the EVE gameplay segments play out similarly to a flying game. Additionally, the Wii version of the game included multiple mini-games, including two on-rail light gun levels , and a cooperative mode.  The PS2 and PC version was developed seperately from the Wii/XBox 360/PS3 version and features 26 chapters, shorter EVE flight sequences, and increased gameplay diversity.  Arabic VersionTHQ partnered up with Emirati company Pluto Games to release a localized version of the game in the Middle East, marking Wall-E as the first Western game to be officially translated and produced into Arabic for seventh generation video game consoles. THQ's Export Sales  Marketing Manager, Luke Keighran said in a press release that "there are only few games that would suit the Middle East's morals more than WALL-E. The game depicts family virtues through a fun and adventurous story line", following up that  THQ "do hope it will be the first of a long line up for Arabic titles in the future". However, the Arabic translated version is only available on the PS3, PSP and 360, despite the original version of the game also being available for the PS2, DS, Wii and PC. Xbox 360 Installation The amount of memory it takes to install this game is 4.7 GB.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7804">Rocket: Robot on Wheels</game><game id="24646">The Tale of Despereaux</game><game id="759">The Incredibles</game><game id="26059">Finding Nemo</game><game id="26074">The Incredibles</game><game id="20640">Kung Fu Panda</game><game id="30877">Shrek Forever After</game><game id="23648">Machinarium</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2284725-box_walle.png</image></root>