<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20792</id><name>Warriors Orochi 2</name><description>Story   Warriors Orochi 2 is a direct continuation of the previous game which sees the combatants of China's Three Kingdoms era and Japan's Sengoku period try to restore calm to a world ravaged by the slain Serpent King Orochi. While scattered clans reform and regroup, officers who served under Orochi in the previous war form break-away factions in an attempt to claim the land as their own as Da Ji seeks to resurrect the Serpent King, prompting the intervention of various mystics and renowned warriors from other time periods. Gameplay The story is divided between five different story modes for each of the prominent factions (Wei, Wu, Shu and Sengoku), with a new Orochi path that tells of the Serpent King's rise to power leading up to the events of the first game. It also features the entire cast from the first title (which itself was comprised of all the playable characters from Dynasty Warriors 5 and Samurai Warriors 2), as well as 13 additional characters including Fu Xi and Nu Wa from Dynasty Warriors 3, Motochika Chosokabe, Gracia, Toshiie Maeda, Katsuie Shibata, Kojirou Sasaki from Samurai Warriors 2: Xtreme Legends and Sun Wukong, Taigong Wang, Himiko, Kiyomori Taira, Yoshitsune Minamoto, and Shin Orochi, bringing the total roster of playable characters to 92.  In addition to the new characters, there are also 20 new stages (14 from Dynasty Warriors 5: Xtreme Legends, 2 from Samurai Warriors 2: Xtreme Legends and 4 original stages) as well as several new gameplay features such as support attacks, character-specific strategies which are implemented when the player fulfills a set requirement, and an extended weapon combination system with new elements to enhance each character. The Versus mode from Dynasty Warriors 4 also makes a comeback, as does the traditional one-on-one fighting system from the original Dynasty Warriors in the Tag Team and Elimination modes. Also new to the franchise is the Dream mode, which has the player control one of several groups of three characters that have to carry out a mission in a special scenario tailored to that specific team.Xbox 360 Installation The amount of memory it takes to install this game is 6.7 GB.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20816">Dynasty Warriors 6</game><game id="6597">Dynasty Warriors 4</game><game id="3757">Dynasty Warriors 5</game><game id="1224">Dynasty Warriors 3</game><game id="20871">Samurai Warriors 2: Xtreme Legends</game><game id="10139">Samurai Warriors</game><game id="21424">Dynasty Warriors: Gundam</game><game id="21972">Samurai Warriors 2: Empires</game><game id="21742">Dynasty Warriors 4: Xtreme Legends</game><game id="6513">Bladestorm: The Hundred Years' War</game><game id="21743">Dynasty Warriors</game><game id="23748">Dynasty Warriors Online: Dance of the Divine General</game><game id="23198">Samurai Warriors 2</game><game id="26881">Warriors: Legends of Troy</game><game id="26379">Witches</game><game id="26889">Undead Knights</game><game id="15413">Dynasty Warriors 2</game><game id="35701">Sengoku Basara Chronicle Heroes</game><game id="37103">Sengoku Basara 3 Utage</game><game id="38478">Sengoku Basara HD Collection</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2126459-box_worochi2.png</image></root>