<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20811</id><name>We Love Golf!</name><description>OverviewWe Love Golf! is a golf title for the Wii developed by Camelot Software Planning, the same developer behind the Mario Golf series, and published by Capcom. The game shares many elements with its Nintendo-branded cousins, including colorful, sometimes fantastically-themed courses, numerous gameplay modes, and easy-to-learn gameplay mechanics. Releases outside of Japan also include an online play mode that allows for head-to-head competitions between random opponents or friends through the use of Friend Codes.GameplayStandard ModesThe games standard modes include Tournament, Character Match, Stroke Play, and Match Play. Tournament is an 18-hole round against CPU oppoents, and Character Match is a 1-on-1 match against a CPU character. New playable characters can be unlocked if the player beats them in this mode. Stroke Play and Match Play are basic variations on Tournament and Character Match, respectively.Other ModesRing Shot: The player must successfully shoot the ball through a large colored ring and complete the hole on Par or less.Target Golf: The player is tasked with hitting the ball onto a target. Points are given based on how close to the center the ball stops.Near Pin Contest: The player must hit the ball as close to the pin as possible on a single stroke. A score penalty is given if the ball does not come to a stop on the green.Training: A basic practice mode.Swing ControlsFore!As in other golf games on the Wii, the Wii Remote is meant to be held and swung in a manner similar to a golf club. By holding down the A Button and raising the remote into a backswing, a Wii Remote cursor on the swing gauge will also rise. A separate club head cursor will then follow the Wii Remote cursor. When the two cursors overlap, the club head cursor will move back in the opposite direction. The player must then take the swing, timing it so that the Wii Remote cursor overlaps the club head cursor in the impact zone of the gauge. The closer the player is in matching the ideal back swing point and impact point, the better the shot will be.A more powerful Power Shot can be used by pulling the Wii Remote all the way to the back of the shot gauge during the backswing. This can potentially send the ball longer distances, but requires more precise timing to pull off successfully.The player can take as many practice swings as desired by holding the B Button during the swing instead of A. Top spin and back spin can be added to shots by holding the 1 or 2 Button during the shot, and holding the Wii Remote at an angle will affect the level of the shot's draw or fade.Online PlayThere are two online modes in We Love Golf!:World PlayA basic mode that matches the player against a random opponent in a one-on-one match. The match is limited to nine holes in length using randomly selected holes from the game's various courses. There are two rules variants, Beginner and Master. The differences between the two modes are the positioning of the tees, and the Master rules hide some elements of the HUD.Friend PlayA mode that allows players that have shared Friend Codes to play together. The rules are more adjustable, giving the players the option of playing an 18-hole round and changing other basic elements.If the connection with an opponent is severed, the CPU will take over the opponent character's actions for the remainder of the match. Winning a disconnected match does not prevent the user from unlocking the character costumes for Morrigan and Ken, which can only be acquired by winning a World Play and Friend Play match, respectively.Mii SupportIn multiplayer, players have the option of using their Miis in place of the standard character roster. Use of Miis in single-player is not available from the start and must be unlocked.Character CostumesWe Love Golf! includes special unlockable Capcom character costumes for the standard characters.Morrigan hitting the links.Yuki dressed as Jill Valentine. Zombies not included.Jack - Apollo Justice (Ace Attorney Series)Meg - Sakura Kasugano (Street Fighter Alpha series)Tony - Ryu (Street Fighter series)Carlos - Arthur (Ghosts n' Goblins)Lisa - Chun-Li (Street Fighter series)Mark - Ken Masters (Street Fighter series)*Yuki - Jill Valentine (Resident Evil 3: Nemesis appearance)Brian - Guile (Street Fighter series)Annie - Pearl Fey (Ace Attorney series)Leo - Zack (Zack  Wiki: Quest for Barbaros' Treasure)Marissa - Rose (Street Fighter Alpha series)Stephanie - Morrigan (Darkstalkers series)** Denotes costumes that are exclusive to releases outside of Japan. These costumes are unlocked by fulfilling requirements during online play.</description><genres><genre id="28">Golf</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20598">Hot Shots Golf: Out of Bounds</game><game id="6300">Hot Shots Golf Fore!</game><game id="13462">Hot Shots Golf</game><game id="11691">Hot Shots Golf 2</game><game id="1547">Hot Shots Golf: Open Tee</game><game id="1598">Mario Golf: Toadstool Tour</game><game id="20058">Mario Golf: Advance Tour</game><game id="19716">Mario Golf</game><game id="22203">Super Swing Golf</game><game id="9316">Kirby's Dream Course</game><game id="21262">Disney Golf</game><game id="24256">Super Swing Golf Season 2</game><game id="25442">Tiger Woods PGA Tour 10</game><game id="35579">Hot Shots Golf: World Invitational</game><game id="25607">Pangya: Fantasy Golf</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/26/11716-wiilovegolf-box.jpg</image></root>