<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20818</id><name>Infinite Undiscovery</name><description>Overview  Infinite Undiscovery is a Japanese Action-RPG, developed by  tri-Ace (Star Ocean, Valkyrie Profile) and published by both  Square-Enix and  Microsoft Games Studio. Infinite Undiscovery follows Capell, a minstrel who was mistaken as Sigmund the Liberator, that has been imprisoned by the Order of the Chains. He is rescued by Aya, a member of the Liberation Force, who also mistakes him for Sigmund, and joins the fight against the sinister Dreadknight and his Order of the Chains. Spanning over two DVDs,  Infinite Undiscovery claimed to move the genre forward, boasting a vast real-time world with seamless transitions to monster battles  and even menus, in hopes of keeping the players on their toes. The game introduces a new element to the genre which tri-Ace dubs as “situation battles.” These situation battles will have the player experience certain situations that will affect  the battle and the environment, uncovering unknown discoveries in the process.  Story  Summary (no spoilers)caption The Dreadknight and his Order of the Chains have claimed the divine power of the moon. As massive chains bind this only source of life, the land begins to die and evil creatures spawn throughout the world. The task falls upon Sigmund the Liberator and the support of the Liberator Force to rise up against the Order of the Chains and free the moon from its bounds. Meanwhile, a minstrel by the name of Capell is imprisoned by the Order of the Chains, mistaken as the Liberator.. Blessed by the moon, lunaglyphs are bestowed upon men and women from birth as a symbol of divine power to guide the people of the world. It is through this blessing that glyph bearers are given unique abilities, which in turn are influenced by the phase of the moon itself. Full Plot (spoiler alert)Capell finds himself trapped in Graad Prison. Eventually, a girl breaks in and tries to break Capell out. The girl, Aya, has mistaken Capell for Lord Sigmund, the Liberator. As Aya tries to break him out, she eventually discovers that he is not Lord Sigmund. With no other choice, Aya helps Capell break out of the prison anyways. However, the two run into an ogre called Vembert and just decide to flee. Eventually Aya and Capell reach the exit into Graad Woods, and the two are forced to sneak past the guards. They would be saved by Sigmund and his Liberation Force. Capell would meet for the first time, Sigmund, Balbagan, Eugene, Edward and Genma. Everyone was surprised at how similar Capell looked to Sigmund, but their looks is all they would have in common. The party would make camp a safe area. At the camp, while Capell talked to Aya, she would fall to the ground in pain. It turns out she recieved a wound while rescuing Capell. Capell would agree to take Aya to Nolaan to get her wounds treated. Sigmund gives Capell the Emblazoned Sword, which has a special cresant on it that will allow him access to more places. Sigmund and his party would help escort Capell as he carries Aya to Nolaan. However, Sigmund and company has to go their seperate ways at Luce Plains since Sigmund was still on his journey to destroy the chains. Capell is forced to carry Aya through a field with a dragon, but he is able to safely bring Aya to Nolaan.  (INCOMPLETE)Gameplay caption Infinite Undiscovery’s world is completely seamless, having no transitions into battle sequences or  into any portions of the map.  In their journeyacross this world   of secrets, the player  will come across special situation battles.  Situation battles are battles that tie in with a specific scenario, both in the story and field encounters. If a scenario has been triggered  by your actions, the game will cut to a cutscene to present the situation, and then the situation battle will commence up  until the objective has been complete.  caption The game’s combat mechanics are straightforward.  The player will first need to draw his sword using the Right Trigger (RT), which can conveniently be drawn even in motion.The player can execute combos both in the air and on the ground using Light attacks (A),   Heavy attacks (B), Connect Actions   (X, Y), and spells.  To compensate for the lack of a block button, the player  has the ability to freeze the enemy with a timed parry by using the "Deflect Drive" action   (LT), creating a large opening for the player to take advantage of. caption The player will only control Capell, and the artificial intelligence willtake control of the other party members. However, the player can briefly control another party member’s actions using the “Connect Action” function. The “Connect Action” function is activated by pressing the Right Bumper (RB), at which point the player can choose which party member he’d like to connect with by pressing either X, B, or A. When connected, the party member’s actions  will be mapped onto the X and Y buttons, replacing Capell’s Battle Skills, allowing the player to control the chosen member’s actions at the press of a button.  Players will also want to take advantage of Force Points and the Action Point Bar. If air combos have been successfully performed, Red Force Points that give extra experience points will be distributed to the team. If ground-smashing combos have been successfully performed, monsters will give out Green Force Points, which replenished HP and MP for the team. For regular successful combos, monsters will give out Yellow Force Points, which replenish the Action Point Bar. The Action Point Bar will receive a mark with the word “Target” to indicate the level of the monster. If the “Target” mark has been reached or surpassed, special attacks will be given an extra edge. caption The game will have a number of eighteen playable characters throughout the story, allowing only up to four characters per party. There will be s ome missions where three other teams of four will accompany the player's party in their journey.Party members are unique in which they  not onlyhave  their own areas of expertise in the field of battle, but alsounique skills in  music,alchemy, forging, writing, cooking, enchanting , and other skills that  may come in handy inside and outside of battle. There is also an affection feature in the game that allows the player to bond with his party.  Requests on the field of battle made by certain party members that go fulfilled or unfulfilled will affect what said member will think of you. The player can converse with his party members in the Camping Menu, and get to know them better. It’s through these conversations that the player can find ways to please his party member. The player should not ignore his members, as their thoughts on you will alter their movements in battle. Another way that the player can bond with his party is initiating “Private Events”. As Capell and his party reach a town, they will often split up for the time being. “Private Events” occur whenever the player meets up with a certain party member as he is traversing around town alone.  Enemies respond to the character’s presence by using their senses; such as seeing, hearing, and smelling. The player can give hunting dogs food to use as bait, however, there is a chance that the guard might hear this action and become alert of your presence. With this new detection system, the player can ambush his enemies, as well as be ambushed on. Worth noting is that menus do not pause the game, and leave the player vulnerable for any enemy encounters. The time of day also affects how sensitive both the player and his enemies are with their senses. If it’s nighttime, your vision and your HUD will be limited in detection,and the player will not be able to lock onto targets. If it’s daytime, you’ll be able to see far across the map with the HUD at full capacity.    </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11497">Final Fantasy XII</game><game id="259">Grandia III</game><game id="10129">Grandia II</game><game id="12099">Star Ocean: Till the End of Time</game><game id="21094">Star Ocean: The Last Hope</game><game id="620">Star Ocean: The Second Story</game><game id="10401">Radiata Stories</game><game id="10518">Eternal Sonata</game><game id="14210">Tales of the Abyss</game><game id="20664">Final Fantasy XIII</game><game id="21073">Tales of Symphonia: Dawn of the New World</game><game id="21406">Fragile Dreams:  Farewell Ruins of the Moon</game><game id="19152">Suikoden V</game><game id="18991">Suikoden IV</game><game id="11252">Suikoden III</game><game id="7527">Marvel Ultimate Alliance</game><game id="6336">Final Fantasy VI</game><game id="7447">Blue Dragon</game><game id="25787">Resonance of Fate</game><game id="25942">Magna Carta 2</game><game id="7958">Baten Kaitos: Eternal Wings and the Lost Ocean</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1817647-box_iu.png</image></root>