<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20835</id><name>MLB 08: The Show</name><description>OverviewMLB 08: The Show is the latest in a popular franchise of baseball titles produced by Sony Studios (These games were formerly developed by 989 sports until they were reabsorbed into Sony Studios after MLB 06: The Show). The 2008 entry of the series features several notable changes and additions:Deeper "Road to the Show" mode.Vastly improved online gameplay.Dualshock 3 SupportIncreased realism and statistical trackingAll new animationsA more cinematic and lifelike gameplay experienceRyan Howard is the 2008 iteration's cover athlete and the game features a bevy of interesting modes. Those of note are:Road to the Show-Create a Player and lead him from the Minors to the Big Leagues by completing goals and improving your skills.Franchise-Lead a team from the bottom or take a perennial contender and send them over the top. The Franchise mode allows you to assume the role of Owner, General Manager, Coach, and Player of your favorite ball club.Online-Ranked matches, Player matches, Leagues, and Tournaments are all options here. The mode really shines with the regularly updated rosters and SCOUT (SportsConnect Online User Tracking) that records all of the players statistics.Create-a-Player-The great graphics make this mode a joy to fool around with. The feature lacks the facial customization depth of a Tiger Woods, however.There is also a PSP version of this game, both are produced by Sony StudiosSoundtrackA Tribe Called Quest -- Award TourThe Blood Arm -- Suspicious CharacterFranz Ferdinand -- The Fallen (Ruined by Justice)Hot Hot Heat -- My Best FriendKenna -- Out of Control (State of Emotion) - XXXChange RemixNo More Kings -- Sweep the Leg (Remix)Queens of the Stone Age -- In the FadeThe Ramones -- Blitzkrieg BopThin Lizzy -- JailbreakWar -- Low RiderZZ Top -- I'm Bad, I'm Nationwide</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="34">Baseball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9978">MVP Baseball 2005</game><game id="16036">High Heat Major League Baseball 2003</game><game id="5811">Baseball Stars</game><game id="20942">Little League World Series</game><game id="20687">MLB Power Pros 2008</game><game id="20876">Major League Baseball 2K8</game><game id="15449">Backyard Baseball 2001</game><game id="21255">Major League Baseball 2K7</game><game id="21254">Major League Baseball 2K5</game><game id="5295">MVP Baseball 2004</game><game id="4908">MVP Baseball 2003</game><game id="21259">MVP 06 NCAA Baseball</game><game id="21260">MVP 07 NCAA Baseball</game><game id="5984">High Heat Major League Baseball 2002</game><game id="11415">High Heat Major League Baseball 2004</game><game id="11859">Sammy Sosa High Heat Baseball 2001</game><game id="3894">Ken Griffey Jr.'s Winning Run</game><game id="11803">Ken Griffey Jr.'s Slugfest</game><game id="7266">Ken Griffey Jr Presents Major League Baseball</game><game id="14051">Major League Baseball Featuring Ken Griffey Jr</game><game id="6423">MLB Slugfest Loaded</game><game id="6304">MLB SlugFest 20-04</game><game id="18355">MLB SlugFest 20-03</game><game id="20893">Backyard Baseball 2009</game><game id="21806">Backyard Baseball</game><game id="11158">Backyard Baseball</game><game id="22546">Major League Baseball 2K6</game><game id="22776">Out of the Park Baseball 9</game><game id="17271">Triple Play 2002</game><game id="7000">Triple Play 2001</game><game id="9670">Triple Play Baseball</game><game id="14025">Triple Play 2000</game><game id="8283">Bases Loaded</game><game id="6736">Frank Thomas Big Hurt Baseball</game><game id="5259">Super Baseball 2020</game><game id="24440">Major League Baseball 2K9</game><game id="25511">The BIGS 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1832149-box_mlb08.png</image></root>