<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2088</id><name>Seven Samurai 20XX</name><description>OverviewSeven Samurai 20XX is a hack and slash, action adventure game that is loosely based on Akira Kurosawa's "Seven Samurai". Developed by Dimps and published by Sammy for the Playstaion 2 Seven Samurai 20XX was released in 2004.   Story  The story having been Inspired by Akira Kurosawa's "Seven Samurai" does have some passing similarity's to the classic film. They have a main character, a village that is being attacked and... swords. Set in a Japan in the far flung future you follow the story of Natoe the Hunter as he brings together a group of seven fighters in order to protect "THE VILLAGE" from an army of Humanoids.   Humanoids are a race that exits in the darkness of the "CITY". Shrouded in mystery no one knows when these mechanical life forms came into existence or who created them. Some Humanoids are made to look exactly like humans but posses physical and mental capabilities far beyond that of any human.    As you gather fighters to your side you are attacked by Humanoids that are searching for the "CHILD OF HEAVEN" who has disappeared from the "STEEPLE OF LIGHT".       Gameplay    The name suggests that you may at some point play as some one other than Natoe but you don't. When a fight starts, some reason is made in order for you to be on your own. It ranges from Natoe saying "I will handle this" to another warrior running  away .   Fighting is arena based keeping you in the immediate area while enemies funnel in. To kill your enemies you must combo your moves together in order to build up your gauge. The gauge allows you to pull out your second sword and bring the pain Nitoh-Ryu style. This second sword is the main way of fighting in the game as you will not do much damage without it. Timing an attack, guard or step move just right will build up your meter much faster.     </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2193304-box_ss20xx.png</image></root>