<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20896</id><name>Siren: Blood Curse</name><description>OverviewAn American crew of documentary filmmakers travel to Japan to investigate a 'disappeared' village, only to find that its residents have become bloodthirsty abominations. Siren: Blood Curse is a re-imagination of the original Forbidden Siren released on the PlayStation 2 in 2003.GameplayDark, gritty environments are typical in Siren: Blood Curse.Siren: Blood Curse is an action-adventure game with survival horror elements. While controlling seven different characters in short snippets (as if they were episodes in a TV series-- very much like Alan Wake did in early 2010), you move around town, avoiding and hiding from the Shibito villagers who have turned ravenous. You can 'sightjack' these villagers with some characters by using the L2 button, allowing you to see -- via split-screen -- what they see. You can also swing melee weapons and shoot firearms via a targeting system.CharactersSam MonroeMelissa GaleAmanaMiyakoHoward WrightBella MonroeSeigo SaigaSol JacksonDistributionBlood Curse is available in North America only through the PlayStation Store. There are twelve episodes of the game, and you can opt to buy all twelve for $39.99, or in four-episode chunks (1-4, 5-8, 9-12) for $14.99. A disc version is was scheduled to be released this fall but was eventually scrapped. Hard disc copies of the game have been obtained in North America through online outlets in order to obtain the Japanese version or Asian version. The Asian version is usually preferred in North America because it features English voice audio and subtitles.Unlocking Hidden Mini GamesOn Episode 8, Melissa Gale's stage, before reaching the Waiting Room or after reuniting with Bella, go down into the basement and hide Bella in the incinerator using the "Hide" command. A cut scene will play and Bella will find a portable gaming hand held. This is archive item #32: JOYLiNK - Ultra Network King.Now on the main menu, select "ARCHIVES" and view item #32. When you check out this archive, you will unlock the " MINI GAMES" option on the main menu. Note that in order to be able to play these mini-games, you must be logged onto the PlayStation Network.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4312">Silent Hill</game><game id="5842">Resident Evil</game><game id="2842">Haunting Ground</game><game id="17962">Clock Tower 3</game><game id="20982">Alan Wake</game><game id="34731">Amy</game><game id="18070">Fatal Frame</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2314076-box_sbc.png</image></root>