<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20917</id><name>NBA 2K9</name><description>SoundtrackNBA 2K9 features a heavily licensed soundtrack, leaning on hip-hop and pop to fill out the roster. NBA 2K9 uses the 2k beats functionality, which mainly is used to control the playlist of songs while browsing from menu to menu. The 2k Beats section of the 2k Sports website goes into further detail regarding 2k Beats and 2k artists. The entire soundtrack is as follows.Blackwizard — Dem Nah Ready fe WeBlockhead — Duke Of HazzardBloody Beetroots — Mac MacDangerdoom — Sofa KingDawn Penn — You Don’t Love Me (Extended Mix)DJ Rasta Root — RootZilla BeezDJ UNK — In Yo Face (Exclusive Track)Gnarls Barkley — Going OnJamalski — That Undaground (Remix) Blackwizard — Dem Nah Ready fe WeMochipet — SharpdrestMommy and Daddy — Pretty LoserMoney Mark — Silly PuttyN.E.R.D. — SpazNickodemus — Funky In The MiddleSantogold feat. Switch  Freq Nasty – CreatorSkeewiff — Light the FuseSpank Rock  Benny Blanco — Loose (inst.)The Brand New Heavies — Jump ‘N’ MoveThe Cool Kids — 2K Pennies (Exclusive track)The Heavy — ColeenThe Limp Twins — Moving Closer to The SofaThe Meters — Cissy StrutThe Pharcyde — Passing Me ByUrsula 1000 — Step Back (Deekline  Ed Solo Remix)What's New?NBA 2K9 features several new editions to its "Signature Style", which emulates mannerisms of over 300 players, including their shot style as well as their free throw preparations.In the gameplay front, NBA 2K9 added "Living Rosters", which were updated at the beginning of every week. For example, if a player was on a hot streak that week, the player's ratings would go up, and the opposite would occur if they were struggling. The updates also accounted for trades in-season, as well as injuries that happened during the season. These rosters were also implemented online, so players couldn't abuse a certain player who was injured during the year.Along with improved menus and fixes to glitches the previous year, NBA 2K9 featured "Team Up" where up to 10 players could face against each other online at the same time. The FIFA series also included this feature in the previous two iterations. Players could grade their teammates on their sportsmanship, if they hogged the ball too much, or were simply not very good.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="22">Basketball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20819">NBA Live 09</game><game id="7437">NBA Live 07</game><game id="7206">NBA Live 06</game><game id="15029">NBA Live 2005</game><game id="9237">NBA Live 2004</game><game id="13378">NBA Live 2003</game><game id="11411">NBA Live 2002</game><game id="8383">NBA Live 2001</game><game id="3771">NBA Live 2000</game><game id="2861">NBA Live 99</game><game id="15170">NBA Live 98</game><game id="1356">NBA Live 97</game><game id="20257">NBA Live 96</game><game id="3091">NBA Live 95</game><game id="21762">NBA ShootOut 2000</game><game id="61">NBA Street V3</game><game id="7982">NBA Street</game><game id="18984">NBA Courtside 2: Featuring Kobe Bryant</game><game id="6199">NCAA College Basketball 2K3</game><game id="21363">NBA 2K6</game><game id="9829">NBA 2K7</game><game id="23188">ESPN NBA 2Night</game><game id="22695">NBA 09: The Inside</game><game id="21470">NBA 2K8</game><game id="1395">ESPN NBA 2K5</game><game id="16937">ESPN NBA Basketball 2004</game><game id="10319">NBA 2K3</game><game id="16896">NBA 2K1</game><game id="21687">NBA Live 08</game><game id="23864">NBA '08</game><game id="9866">NBA Street Vol. 2</game><game id="10302">NBA Street Homecourt</game><game id="25545">NCAA Basketball 09</game><game id="3557">NBA 07</game><game id="20242">NBA Showdown</game><game id="31439">NBA 2K11</game><game id="31438">NBA Elite 11</game><game id="2860">Fronte del Basket 2007/2008</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2222528-box_nba2k9.png</image></root>