<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>20927</id><name>Midnight Club: Los Angeles</name><description>Midnight Club: Los Angeles is an extremely fast-paced arcade racer being developed by Rockstar San Diego. In the game you participate in illegal street racing in a recreated version of Los Angeles in order build up a racing reputation and earn money, which you can then use to buy new vehicles or "pimp out" your existing ones using the game's extremely deep customization system. It runs on the RAGE engine, the same engine that powers Rockstar Games presents Table Tennis and Grand Theft Auto IV.The special abilities featured in Midnight Club 3 are back. These features include EMP (short-cut nearby cars), Aggro (makes traffic bump off you), Roar (sends a sonic wave that pushes vehicles away), and Zone (slow-mo driving for better handling).WorldThe gameworld is littered with recognizable landmarksWhile it will feature many recognizable landmarks, MC:LA's version of Los Angeles will not be an exact replica of the real city. Instead, Rockstar San Diego is taking the most interesting parts of the city and putting them together to make a compressed version of Los Angeles specially designed for street racing. This does not mean the world will be small, however. It has been said that the drivable area in the game will be bigger than all three cities in Midnight Club 3: Dub Edition combined. The entire city will be open from the start. Traffic in the game will also change based on where you are and what time of day it is. Traffic will obviously be much higher during rush hour than it would be at midnight. Other new additions to the game world include a 24-hour day/night cycle a dynamic weather system. Weather will have effects like reducing your vison and making the streets slicker, which means corners are easier to slide around but its much easier to lose tire traction. A map at the bottom left at the screen will display your immediate surroundings and can be enlarged to either a full-screen illustrated or 3D-rendered satellite version.MultiplayerMidnight Club: Los Angeles has an online multiplayer component that supports up to 16 players. The game does not feature any split-screen play. When players select Online from the main menu they can either choose to join an existing match or host one of their own. Players can participate in either player or ranked matches. Player matches allow you to customize game modes and rules, while ranked matches have a default setup that cannot be changed. When players join a match lobby, they can choose their car and signal that they are ready to begin the game. After the game ends, the players are brought back to the lobby where the host can change game modes and settings and start another game.Race TypesOrdered Races: Races where players must drive through multiple checkpoints in a certain order. The first racer to reach the final checkpoint wins.Circuit Races: Similar to ordered races, the difference being that players must complete several laps around a track before reaching the final checkpoint. There is a Last-Man-Out variation of this race type, in which the last place car at the end of every lap is eliminated.Unordered Races: Multi-checkpoint races where players can collect all the checkpoints in any order before proceeding to the final checkpoint.Landmark Races: Races with only one checkpoint. Whoever reaches said checkpoint first wins.Battle TypesFree-for-all CTF: Players must capture a flag on the map and return it to a certain drop-off point on the map while other racers try to steal the flag for themselves. Whoever reaches the score limit first or has the highest score when the time runs out wins.Basewar CTF: A team-based version of capture the flag. Each team has a flag that spawns inside their base. It is the each team's job to steal the opposing team's flag and bring it back to their base.Splitbase CTF: Another team-based capture the flag mode, in which each team has a base and one neutral flag spawns in between the bases. It is each team's job to take that flag and return it to their own base.Stockpile: A cluster of flags spawn across the city. Players must capture as many flags as they can and take them to a stockpile point. When all the flags have been captured a new cluster of flags spawns. Be careful, however, because one flag in each cluster may be a bomb. You do not know which flag is the bomb until you pick it up. If you do accidentally pick up the bomb, you must transfer it to another player by bumping it into their car before the time runs out. Whoever has the bomb flag when the time runs out will have their score docked. Whoever reaches the score limit or has the highest score when the time runs out wins.Splitbase Stockpile: A team-based stockpile mode, where a cluster of flags spawns between each team's base. It is each team's job to collect as many flags as they can and return them to their base.Keepaway: A mode in which one flag spawns at a random place on the map. Whoever captures the flag will accumulate points the longer they hold the flag. They must dodge and evade other players to keep them from stealing the flag. Whoever reaches the score limit or has the highest score when the time runs out wins.Online CruiseA mode where players can freely cruise around the entire city. If a player wants to play a game they make one up and request it. If there is more than one race requested it will be added to a queue. If players wish to join the race they can accept the request, or they can choose to ignore it and keep cruising around the city at their leisure.Race EditorThe game features a race editor which can be accessed from online cruise mode. Players can make their own races by setting down checkpoints whereever they want to. When they are done editing their race, they can either add it to the queue of races in online cruise, or save it and share it with other players.Car/Bike ListMidnight Club: Los Angeles features 46 different vehicles that fit into five categories: tuner, muscle, luxury, exotic, and bike.TunerAudi RS4Chevrolet Cobalt SS1975 Datsun 280ZFord SVT Focus1995 Mazda RX7Mazda RX8 Shinka1999 Mitsubishi 3000 GT VR-41999 Mitsubishi Eclipse GSXMitsubishi Lancer Evolution IX MR1998 Nissan 240SXNissan 350Z Roadster1999 Nissan Skyline GT-R V-SpecPontiac SolsticeVolkswagen R321983 Volkswagen Golf GTI1988 Volkswagen SciroccoMuscle1987 Buick Grand National GNX1969 Chevrolet Camaro RS SSChevrolet Camaro ConceptChevrolet Camaro Concept DUB EditionChevrolet Corvette Z061996 Chevrolet Impala SS1970 Dodge Challenger R/TDodge Challenger ConceptDodge Challenger Concept DUB EditionDodge Charger SRT-81969 Ford Mustang Boss 302Ford Mustang GT Convertible1979 Pontiac FirebirdSaleen S302 ExtremeLuxuryChrysler 300C SRT-8Mercedes-Benz S600Mercedes-Benz S600 DUB EditionMercedes-Benz SL65 AMGExoticAston Martin V8 Vantage RoadsterAudi R8Ford GTFord Shelby Cobra ConceptLamborghini Gallardo Spyder1971 Lamborghini Miura SVLamborghini Murcielago RoadsterLamborghini Murcielago Roadster DUB EditionSaleen S7BikeDucati 999RDucati Monster S4RSKawasaki Ninja ZX-14All cars and bikes can be customized with many aftermarket parts. Parts are purchased at a garage in LA called Hollywood Auto. Aftermarket parts do things like increase grip, speed, acceleration, and overall handling. A livery editor and paintshop can also be purchased on a car-by-car basis at Hollywood Auto for $1000 each. The paintshop lets you paint specific parts of the car and choose a finish type like mettalic and other paint finishes. The livery editor allows you to place decals on your cars to make them look more race worthy. Aftermarket parts brands include:5 Zigen USAACTAmerican RacingApex'iAPCAPR PerformanceAsantiBBSBF GoodrichBomex USABoriaBremboCarbontrixC-WESTDavinDC SportsDropsterFlowtechHolleyIforgedKaminariKonigLexaniMomoPirelliPM PerformanceProject MuRacetechRC ComponentsRK SportsSeibonSparkoT.I.S.T.I.S.M.Tenzo RacingVis RacingVolks RacingWings WestWork Super WheelsZEXDLCIn December 2008 Rockstar announced DLC to be released for Midnight Club: Los Angeles for “early 2009” .The content pack was mistakenly released on Xbox Live on January 14, 2009 and was subsequently removed; anyone who downloaded the pack was informed to delete it as it may "cause unforeseen problems with achievements and save data" as stated by an Xbox Live Marketplace staff member.It was announced that the South Central Update would be release on March 12th, 2009 on the PlayStation Network and Xbox Live in two parts. The first is a free "South Central Map Expansion" which will be “1/3 of the current map” and contains four new neighborhoods: Baldwin, Crenshaw, Exposition and Huntington. Landmarks such as Exposition Park, the USC campus, Shrine Auditorium, Crenshaw Plaza, and the L.A. Memorial Coliseum will be included, and it also "stretches south to the 105 Freeway". The second update is the South Central Premium Upgrade which adds 9 new vehicles, 26 races, 12 battle maps, 10 delivery missions, 100 red light races, new rims, new body kits for the nine new vehicles, new vinyl pre-sets, hydraulics/airbags unlocked on all the new vehicles, and new music (including original tracks). The South Central Premium Upgrade costs $9.99, or 800 Microsoft points. On March 11th, it was announced that the DLC will be delayed one week, making its new relese date March 19th, 2009.The South Central Premium Upgrade full vehicle list includes:Luxury2008 Mercedes-Benz CLK63 AMG "Black"SUV2008 Range Rover Supercharged2008 Range Rover Sport SuperchargedLowrider1964 Chevy Impala1955 Chevy Bel Air1963 Buick Riviera1964 Chevy Impala1965 Chevy MalibuMuscle1970 Chevy Chevelle1966 Pontiac GTOMidnight Club: Los Angeles Complete EditionThe Complete Edition (Xbox 360 Version)On September 28, 2009 Rockstar released an updated version of Midnight Cub Los Angeles called the Complete Edition on both the Xbox 360 as Platinum Hits and the Playstation 3 as a Greatest Hits. Midnight Club: LA CE features all the DLC released for the original game as well as any tweaks and patches.Unlike some re-released games, MC:LA CE is compatible with the original for online play. Everything that is included in the complete edition is available for the original as DLC.SoundtrackMidnight Club's 67 song soundtrack spans multiple genres, from rock to hip-hop to electronica.33 HZ - "I Feel Alive! (Ming Mix)"Agent Elf - "Lost in Control"Akwid - "No Hay Manera (Jason Roberts Remix)"Antiform - "Boombox (Screwface Remix)"As I Lay Dying - "Nothing Left"Beck - "Timebomb"Bishop Lamont Feat. The New Royales - "City Lights"Black Kids - "Partie Traumatic"Bloc Party - "Mercury"Busy P Feat. Murs - "To Protect And Entertain"The Chemical Brothers - "Midnight Madness"The Cool Kids - "What It Is"CSS - "Rat Is Dead (Rage)"Danny Byrd - "Red Mist"Darker My Love - "Waves"Deadmau5 - "The Oshawa Connection"Digitalism - "Idealistic"Diplo Feat. Rye Rye - "Wassup (Crookers Remix)"Disturbed - "Indestructible"DJ Felli Fel Feat. Akon, Lil’ Jon, Ludacris  Diddy - "Get Buck In Here"Doap Nixon Feat. Reef the Lost Cauze  Vinnie Paz - "The Wait Is Over"Dukes Of Windsor - "In The Wild"Eagles of Death Metal - "Wannabe in L.A."The Equalizers - "Wide Awake"Evidence - "Let Yourself Go"Evil Nine Feat. Aesop Rock - "Crooked"Evil Nine Feat. Beans - "Set it Off"Evil Nine Feat. Emily Breeze - "Twist the Knife"Feeder - "Miss You"The Fever - "Eyes on the Road"Foals - "Mathletics"The Game - "Big Dreams"Get Cool - "Go"Gliss - "Blue Sky"G-Unit - "Straight Outta Southside"Holy Fuck - "Royal Gregory"Hyper - "Replica"Ice Cube - "Gangsta Rap Made Me Do It"J Mill - "Like Dat"Kid Cudi - "Day ‘N’ Nite (Crookers Remix)"Kidz In The Hall Feat. Masta Ace - "Drivin Down The Block (Low End Theory)"K.I.M. - "Wet  Wild"Kudu - "Let’s Finish (Sinden Remix)"Maino - "Hi Hater"Markus Kienzl Feat. Paul St Hilaire - "Dundy Lion"Matt Herdman - "Wasted Intellect"MGMT - "Electric Feel (Justice Remix)"Murs Feat. Will.i.am - "Lookin’ Fly"Nas - "Sly Fox"Nas Feat. Keri Hilson - "Hero"Nine Inch Nails - "1,000,000"Nine Inch Nails - "Discipline"No Age - "Sleeper Hold"Ozomatli - "City of Angels"Plump DJs - "Snake Eyes"The Presets - "Kicking and Screaming"Primal Scream - "Suicide Bomb"The Qemists - "Stompbox"Randam Luck - "1, 2 Hit ‘Em"Reks - "All In One"Santogold - "L.E.S. Artistes (Switch Remix)"SebastiAn - "Momy"Sensi Allstars v Ctrl-Z - "Big Riddim"Shinedown - "Cry For Help"Shodan  Offkey - "Boogie Down"Slim Blue Feat. Ken Mac vs Polkadot - "Flick It"Snoop Dogg Feat. Kurupt - "Press Play"Social Distortion - "Reach for the Sky"South Rakkas Crew - "Mad Again (Boy 8 Bit Remix)"The Subways - "Kalifornia"Tech N9ne - "Everybody Move"Tilly and the Wall - "Pot Kettle Black"Too $hort Feat. Snoop Dogg  Will.I.Am - "Keep Bouncin"Tricky - "Baligaga"The Vines - "Get Out"WC Feat. The Game - "West Coast Voodoo"We Are Wolves - "Psychic Kids"The Whip - "Trash"Wolf  Cub - "Targets (Minotaur Shock Remix)"Wolfgang Gartner - "Montezuma"Wolfgang Gartner - "Squares"Young Jeezy Feat. Kanye West - "Put On"Young Maylay - "You Ain’t Uh"Young  Restless - "Police Police"Rockstar has grouped all the songs into their different genres and you can easily select a group of songs for a custom playlist while you cruise the streets of LA.Xbox 360 Game InstallationMidnight Club: Los Angeles requires 6.0GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12976">Need for Speed: Most Wanted</game><game id="20741">Need for Speed: Undercover</game><game id="18095">Need for Speed: ProStreet</game><game id="8844">Need for Speed: Carbon</game><game id="1101">Ridge Racer 7</game><game id="2279">Project Gotham Racing 2</game><game id="19809">Project Gotham Racing 3</game><game id="8437">TOCA 2: Touring Car Challenge</game><game id="20729">GRID</game><game id="7019">Ridge Racer V</game><game id="16276">Ford Bold Moves Street Racing</game><game id="20919">Ford Racing: Off Road</game><game id="5977">Need for Speed III: Hot Pursuit</game><game id="7431">Ford Racing</game><game id="12950">Gran Turismo 3 A-Spec</game><game id="7777">Juiced</game><game id="17872">TOCA Race Driver 3 Challenge</game><game id="8438">NASCAR 06: Total Team Control</game><game id="21657">Initial D: Extreme Stage</game><game id="1321">L. A. Rush</game><game id="23461">FUEL</game><game id="21689">Wangan Midnight</game><game id="5648">Burnout Paradise</game><game id="5881">Forza Motorsport 2</game><game id="25225">Need for Speed: SHIFT</game><game id="6582">Test Drive Unlimited</game><game id="21297">Gran Turismo HD</game><game id="25226">Need for Speed World</game><game id="17599">Forza Motorsport</game><game id="20858">NASCAR 09</game><game id="20597">Gran Turismo 5 Prologue</game><game id="24866">OutRun Online Arcade</game><game id="20957">Pure</game><game id="20132">Sega Rally Revo</game><game id="14975">Import Tuner Challenge</game><game id="9651">Need for Speed Underground 2</game><game id="21653">Asphalt: Urban GT</game><game id="1591">Need for Speed Underground: Rivals</game><game id="22693">RACE Pro</game><game id="23526">GTR: Evolution</game><game id="26011">Volvo: The Game</game><game id="16492">Burnout Revenge</game><game id="4703">Road &amp; Track presents The Need for Speed</game><game id="12395">Need for Speed: Hot Pursuit 2</game><game id="4970">Burnout Legends</game><game id="12254">Need for Speed Underground</game><game id="13895">Gran Turismo 4: Prologue</game><game id="9927">SRS: Street Racing Syndicate</game><game id="367">Need for Speed II</game><game id="19522">Live for Speed</game><game id="8100">Gran Turismo 2</game><game id="25523">Split/Second</game><game id="8459">Burnout Dominator</game><game id="4890">Muscle Car 3: Illegal Street</game><game id="31698">Need for Speed: Hot Pursuit</game><game id="32301">Cargasm</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2428402-box_mcla.png</image></root>