<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2092</id><name>Fable: The Lost Chapters</name><description>OverviewFable: The Lost Chapters is an expansion of the classic Xbox game Fable, which features all of the content of the original Fable, plus extra content such as new areas, monsters and items, and is the continuation of the story from where the original Fable ends. There are a few other small technical changes in game as well, such as a different voice actor for Jack of Blades, and a few glitches from Fable have been fixed.The Lost Chapters was released for the Xbox and for PC. The Xbox version of Fable on the Xbox Originals section of Xbox Live Marketplace does not feature Lost Chapters.The Northern WastesThe Lost Chapters introduces the Northern Wastes, which is a new frozen area available to players once the main story of Fable is completed, opening the way to a new story and more content. The Northern Wastes consists of:The Lost BayThe Northern WastesThe Lost Bay is the first area that you will enter upon your arrival in the Northern Wastes, and sets the tone for the snowy wastelands that you will be exploring. Here you will find new enemies, the Summoners, that are tougher than any other enemy you will have faced.SnowspireSnowspire is the only village of the Northern Wastes, home to the Oracle. It is a beautiful snowy village similar to Hook Coast, with new items to find and a house you can buy. Within Snowspire is the Charity Shop. By donating items of worth to the Charity Shop, rare items will appear for you to purchase.The OracleThe Oracle is located within Snowspire village and is an important source of information. The Oracle can also give you information on past heroes and the whereabouts of your old friends.The NecropolisArchon's ShrineThe Necropolis was once a town, but now is a haunted graveyard full with ghosts and the undead.Archon's ShrineArchon's Shrine is massive structure outside of Snowspire, and somehow linked to the Bronze Gate.The Bronze GateThe Bronze Gate is a huge door within the Northern Wastes. It is said that when the gate opens, the end of the world will come. Truly, a great evil lies trapped on the other side, and you will be faced with a tempting choice that could threaten your own alignment.Extra QuestsThere are quite a few new additions to Fable, most of which utilize the alignment system of Fable and offers good and evil choices to be made, some that play an important part of the Lost Chapters story. A few of these quests are available at the start and throughout the game of 'Fable' before the new areas of the Northern Wastes is reached. Some of these quests include:The Darkwood BordelloA safe haven for the men of Albion lies within Darkwood. Here you can meet some very friendly girls and have a fun time, or if you are feeling heroic, save them from their miserable fate.The Sick Child and Blue MushroomsA child has fallen unconscious due to a certain 'intoxicant' and requires the remedy. It seems a lot of the citizens of Albion have become involved with this new craze and may need your help in one way or another.The Bowerstone Book CollectionThe school in Bowerstone South has received budget cuts of late and are desperately short of books. You can help out the schoolmaster by finding him books to read out to his pupils, although not all books are suitable for the little ones.Fishing and Chicken Kicking CompetitionIf you enjoy fishing, then by entering the Fishing Competition you could win a legendary fishing pole and hat! Or, if you really like kicking chickens, perhaps the Chicken Kicking competition would be more to your taste. You may even learn how to wow the ladies with a chicken calling expression.The Mayor of BowerstoneThe original Fable gave you the choice of marrying the Mayor of Bowerstone, but she is not as sweet as she first seems. Will you uncover the truth of her murky past and save an innocent man? Or is the lure of power just too much?There are many more quests, some decidedly more evil than others. Most new quests give you both good and evil alignment choices.Other New ContentLost Chapters introduces new armor and weapons, including new hats, some of which are accessed through new Demon Doors. There are also new expressions for you to use, including 'dance' type expressions.System RequirementsMicrosoft速 Windows速 XP, Windows速 Vista, Windows速 7PC with 1.4 GHz equivalent or higher processor256 MB of system RAM3 GB available hard disk space32x speed or faster CD-ROM drive64 MB shader capable video card requiredDirectX 9.0c or later required (installed by Fable: The Lost Chapters)Sound card, speakers or headphones required for audio</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9061">Neverwinter Nights 2</game><game id="10740">The Elder Scrolls IV: Shivering Isles</game><game id="8580">Jade Empire</game><game id="17949">The Elder Scrolls III: Tribunal</game><game id="14759">Two Worlds</game><game id="10473">The Witcher</game><game id="19467">The Legend of Zelda: Twilight Princess</game><game id="24818">Orient: A Hero's Heritage</game><game id="12482">Sudeki</game><game id="21864">Overlord</game><game id="32416">DeathSpank: Thongs of Virtue</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1803629-box_fabletlc.png</image></root>