<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2101</id><name>Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 4</name><description>OverviewTony Hawk's Pro Skater 4 is a skateboarding game developed by Neversoft and published by Activision (under their Activision o2 label) for the PlayStation 2, Xbox, and GameCube on October 23, 2002. The fourth installment of the long-running Tony Hawk franchise and the sequel to Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3, Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 4 is the last main game in the franchise to bear the "Pro Skater" name, adding new levels, skaters, and tricks (such as Flatland Tricks, Grind and Lip Trick Extensions, skitching vehicles, and Spine Transfers, which allow players to switch between connecting quarter-pipes or self-right themselves to exit quarter-pipes without bailing), as well as a new Career Mode system (where players skate around levels similar to Free Skate mode, and are given objectives and mini-games by talking with NPCs). A limited version of Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 2's currency system returns (by completing objectives and special mini-games, as well as collecting cash pickups, players can buy clothes for the Create-A-Skater mode, decks, movies, cheats, secret skaters, and hidden levels).The game was ported to the PlayStation alongside the original release (by Vicarious Visions), and the PC in August 27, 2003 (by Beenox, published by Aspyr). The PlayStation version runs on a slightly-modified Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3 engine, changing the level structure of most levels while replacing the Zoo, Carnival, and Chicago levels with two new levels: Sewers and Little Big World (the counter-tops of a giant kitchen).Handheld versions were released on both the Game Boy Advance on October 28, 2002 (developed by Vicarious Visions) and the Zodiac in 2004 (developed by Semi Logic and published by Tapwave). Both games are played in a 2D isometric viewpoint, and feature many elements from the console versions.Similar to previous two entries in the series, this game features crossover characters from different franchises as hidden playable skaters: Jango Fett (a bounty hunter from the Star Wars franchise) and Eddie the Head (the mascot of the heavy metal band Iron Maiden).GameplayThe core skating mechanics are mainly unchanged, but adds a spine transfer maneuver, where you can press a button to either switch to a ramp on the other side of a vert, level off of launched away from a ramp, or land correctly into a ramp if entering from a flat area.Pogo tricks were also introduced. These tricks are performed during manuals by tapping one of the face buttons. Depending on the trick, the skater will perform a handstand on his board or stand on the side of his board. Exstensive use of the pogo system is effective during combos.The way you receive goals is greatly changed, adopting a sandbox-style system where goals are given to you by people placed in the current area. Completing a goal results in receiving stat points that you can assign, and sometimes special trick slots which can be customized. The game also reintroduces the concept of money, which was present in the second game but not in the third game. Small amounts of money can be found throughout the level, usually by going up a ramp or grinding rails.Each skater, including the custom skater, has a unique "end" goal, which is often very elaborate. Completion of the goal nets a highlight video of the chosen skater, if using a pro skater.CharactersInitial CharactersTony HawkBob BurnquistKareem CampbellSteve CaballeroRune GlifbergEric KostonBucky LasekBam MargeraRodney MullenChad MuskaAndrew ReynoldsGeoff RowleyElissa SteamerJamie ThomasHidden CharactersEddie (Iron Maiden Mascot)Jango FettMike VallelyDaisy (Jenna Jameson)Little Person (resembles an Oompa Loompa - PS1 version only)Frycook (GBA version only)Mindy (GBA version only)Momo (GBA version only)Roger (GBA version only)In the game's Create-a-Skater mode, apparel can be unlocked to create Officer Dick and Ollie the Magic Bum from Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3.LevelsCollegeSan FranciscoAlcatrazKonaShipyardLondonZooCarnivalChicago (A level from Mat Hoffman's Pro BMX 2)SoundtrackSongArtistT.N.TAC/DCLaborAesop RockBloodstains (Darkness Version)Agent OrangeSimple SongAvailManthemThe Bouncing SoulsBad DreamCity StarsBad FunThe CultOodles of O'sDe La SoulHouse of the Rising DrumDelinquent HabitsSeneca FallsThe DistillersBig ShotsEyedea  AbilitiesSkate and DestroyThe FactionDrunken LullabiesFlogging MollyMass AppealGang StarrSpokesmanGoldfingerNon Compos MentisHaiku D'EtatFreightlinerHot Water MusicThe Number of the BeastIron MaidenBeach Blanket BongoutJFAAll My Best Friends Are MetalheadsLess Than JakeWhenimondamicLootpackBodyrockMuskabeatz  Biz MarkieVersus of DoomMuskabeatz  Jeru the DamajaI'm a StarMuskabeatz  Melle MelExpress YourselfN.W.AGiantNebulaBlackballThe OffspringBy the Time I Get to ArizonaPublic EnemySavoir FaireRocket from the CryptMy AdidasRun D.M.CAnarchy in the U.K.Sex PistolsShimmySystem of a DownDig That Groove BabyToy DollsYer CountryU.S. BombsDeath AlleyZeke</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="23">Skateboarding</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5464">Grind Session</game><game id="14487">MTV Sports: Skateboarding</game><game id="20661">Skate 2</game><game id="2570">Aggressive Inline</game><game id="21495">Skate It</game><game id="6759">Disney's Extreme Skate Adventure</game><game id="25647">Transworld Surf: Next Wave</game><game id="25743">Sunny Garcia Surfing</game><game id="28135">Skate 3</game><game id="30195">Shaun White Skateboarding</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2106409-box_thps4.png</image></root>