<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21051</id><name>Naruto: Clash of Ninja Revolution 2</name><description>The Naruto: Clash of Ninja series (known in Japan as Naruto: Gekitou Ninja Taisen) is a series of 3D cel-shaded fighting games based on the popular manga and anime series Naruto by Masashi Kishimoto.The player controls one of many characters directly based upon their counterparts in the Naruto anime and manga. As in practically all fighting games, the player then pits their character against another character controlled by the game's AI or by another player, depending on the mode that the player is in. The objective of each game is to reduce the opponent's health to zero using basic attacks and special techniques unique to each character that are derived from techniques they use in the source material. For instance, Naruto Uzumaki is able to use his signature Shadow Clone Technique, and Rock Lee utilizes many of his Strong Fist style techniques. To use these techniques, characters have available a chakra bar, which depletes upon the execution of a special technique. Each game in the series also possesses numerous modes that offer different styles of play. The game's story mode generally follows the plot from the anime and manga, with a versus mode pitting two players against each other also included. This game in the series adds new modes not included in the original, as well as incorporating new features into the game. The player is able to unlock several characters by using the Shop and obtaining money in fights. Like other Naruto games there is a feature called 'Omake', a bonus section which contains music, sound effects and character models.The game has 2 characters from the American story line Kagura (Tsunasde's rival) and Bando (Kaguras hechmen)There are 2 multiplayer modes where you actually fight each other's two man squad where you choose two players to be on your team and some have specials. In the single match you compete with your opponent in a traditional 1 on 1 match up.ControlsSwing the Wii Remote to attack and use the stick on the Nunchuck to move.Press and hold C and Z button while moving the wii remote Up, down, left, or right in a three direction sequence to have effects like restore chakra or add strength</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20486">Bleach: Shattered Blade</game><game id="5206">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai</game><game id="15234">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai 2</game><game id="22285">Dragon Ball Z: Shin Budokai</game><game id="22723">YuYu Hakusho: Dark Tournament</game><game id="21378">Bleach: Heat the Soul 4</game><game id="2154">One Piece: Grand Battle</game><game id="22307">Battle Stadium D.O.N</game><game id="29071">Soul Eater: Battle Resonance</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2215053-box_narutoconr2.png</image></root>