<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21084</id><name>Kirby: Super Star Ultra</name><description>OverviewKirby Super Star Ultra is an enhanced remake of the 1996 Super Nintendo game  Kirby Super Star. It was developed by HAL Laboratory and published by Nintendo. Released on September 29, 2008, it features new minigames, challenges, graphics, and all-new cutscenes. Gameplay  One of the new cutscenesAs with the original game, Kirby Super Star Ultra will feature a variety of different games. In addition to new challenges and minigames, there is local wireless co-op play. When  Kirby swallows an enemy, he can create an ally out of the enemy that can either be computer controlled or by a friend of local wireless mode. The game features a variety of different challenges from platforming games to quick minigames. As with all of the previous Kirby games, the player can swallow enemies and take their powers. Games  Original Games  Spring Breeze Dyna Blade Gourmet Race The Great Cave Offensive Revenge of  Meta Knight Milky Way Wishes The Arena  Original Minigames    Samurai Kirby Megaton Punch  New Games The Revenge of the King  Meta Knightmare Ultra Helper to Hero The True Arena New Touch-Based Minigames  Card Swipe Kirby on the Draw Snack Tracks</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18376">Looney Tunes Back in Action</game><game id="2866">Super Mario World 2: Yoshi's Island</game><game id="14433">Sonic CD</game><game id="10299">Super Mario Bros. 3</game><game id="15544">Super Mario Bros.</game><game id="8224">New Super Mario Bros.</game><game id="7314">Super Mario Bros. Deluxe</game><game id="7406">Super Mario Bros. 2</game><game id="20974">Super Mario Bros.: The Lost Levels</game><game id="20748">Super Mario Bros. 3: Super Mario Advance 4</game><game id="4300">Wario Land 4</game><game id="25412">Chou Gekijoban Keroro Gunsou: Gekishin Dragon Warriors de Arimasu!</game><game id="23692">Prinny: Can I Really Be the Hero?</game><game id="4237">Contra 4</game><game id="25757">Giana Sisters DS</game><game id="25552">Mighty Flip Champs</game><game id="21016">The Legendary Starfy</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14741/1131531-ksu.jpg</image></root>