<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21099</id><name>Wii Music</name><description>Overview First demoed at E3 2006, Wii Music is a rhythm game which utilizes the  Wiimote to simulate over 60 instruments. As part of the "Wii" series and " Touch Generations", the game is designed for accessibility and its particularly geared toward younger players. The game includes songs ranging from Nintendo's signature tunes, such as the  Super Mario Bros. theme, to orchestral classics and cultural favorites such as "Yankee Doodle."  Gameplay A night serenade in Wii MusicPlaying the virtual instruments is based on the timing of button presses with the Wiimote and Nunchuk, and not the motion sensing capability of the controller. For instance, a saxophone demo shown at E3 by the game's executive producer  Shigeru Miyamoto requires alternating between the 1 and 2 buttons, with actions not impacting gameplay but meant to add to the experience. Using these instruments, players control a band with up to six  Mii musicians in a number of locales, such as a grassy field or a music classroom. Pressing buttons in time with the music will make the music sound better, and this is the only reward the game offers: there is no way to fail a song, no onscreen indication of whether a song is being played correctly or not, hence relying on both the player's knowledge of the music and personal preference. Players are, however, ranked at the end of a song by their score as a conductor.  The  Wii Balance Board is compatible with the game, and can be used as part of a virtual drum kit. The drum kit and orchestra modes are two extended "minigames", with more depth to them than other instruments. For instance, the drum mode has lessons programmed in for players to learn, and possibly apply their skills to a real drum kit.  Multiplayer One Wii console supports four players simultaneously, and was used at the E3 2008 Nintendo Media Briefing as a finale. It also uses the  Nintendo Wi-Fi Connection for recorded video sharing. It is unclear, but likely, that the game will use the friend code setup. It does not feature online play. Songs There are 50 songs in the game, with 4 different categories. All Popular songs are instrumental covers, with the original artist for each song listed in parentheses. Classical Ode to Joy Bridal Chorus Swan Lake From the New World Minuet in G Major A Little Night Music The Blue Danube Carmen  TraditionalAmerican Patrol The Entertainer Twinkle, Twinkle, Little Star Do-Re-Mi My Grandfather's Clock Happy Birthday to You Yankee Doodle Frère Jacques Sur le pont d'Avignon The Flea Waltz Turkey in the Straw Oh, My Darling Clementine Scarborough Fair Long, Long Ago Little Hans O Christmas Tree From Santurtzi to Bilbao Sakura Sakura Troika La Bamba Over the Waves La Cucaracha  PopularDaydream Believer (The Monkees) Sukiyaki (Kyu Sakamoto) Jingle Bell Rock (Bobby Helms) Please Mr. Postman (The Marvelettes) The Loco-Motion (Little Eva) Woman (John Lennon) Every Breath You Take (The Police) September (Earth, Wind  Fire) Material Girl (Madonna) Wake Me Up Before You Go-Go (Wham!) I'll Be There (Jackson 5) I've Never Been to Me (Charlene) Chariots of Fire (Vangelis)  Game The Legend of Zelda  F-Zero --  Mute City Theme Super Mario Bros.  Animal Crossing Animal Crossing --  K.K. Blues  Wii Sports  Wii Music  InstrumentsThere are 66 instruments.Piano Galactic Piano Toy Piano Harpsichord Harp Dulcimer Marimba Vibraphone Steel Drums Handbells Dog Suit Cat Suit Timpani Rapper Acoustic Guitar Ukulele Electric Guitar Galactic Guitar Banjo Sitar Shamisen Jaw Harp Electric Bass Upright Bass Galactic Bass Trumpet Galactic Horn Saxophone Clarinet Recorder Accordion Bagpipe  NES Horn Singer Tuba Flute Harmonica Violin Cello Basic Drums Rock Drums Jazz Drums Latin Drums Reggae Drums Ballad Drums Galactic Drums Marching Snare Bass Drum Taiko Drum Congas Galactic Congas Djembe Drum Timbales Maracas Tambourine Bells Castanets Cowbell Hand Clap Beatboxer Black Belt Cheerleader Güiro Cuica Whistle DJ Turntables  ReceptionThe game has received mixed and negative pre-release impressions from gaming outlets. Critics main concern is the gameplay's simplicity, basing itself on button-presses for a concept that is more suited to motion control. There is also negative feedback about the MIDI audio quality for instruments, the track selection being uninspired, and the visual presentation basic. However, the game is predicted to perform very well in retail, and is a pillar of Nintendo's Q4 lineup.</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9860">Rock Band</game><game id="9439">Wii Play</game><game id="13328">Wii Sports</game><game id="20808">Rock Band Track Pack Volume 1</game><game id="20635">Rock Revolution</game><game id="20872">Battle of the Bands</game><game id="21617">Rayman: Raving Rabbids</game><game id="2520">Donkey Konga</game><game id="19832">Donkey Konga 2</game><game id="7907">Donkey Konga 3: Tabe-houdai! Haru Mogitate 50 Kyoku</game><game id="18157">Um Jammer Lammy</game><game id="10051">PaRappa the Rapper 2</game><game id="7466">Space Channel 5</game><game id="113">Space Channel 5: Part 2</game><game id="492">Electroplankton</game><game id="36822">C.P.U. Bach</game><game id="18360">PaRappa the Rapper</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2119739-box_wiim.png</image></root>