<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21117</id><name>Buzz! Master Quiz</name><description>OverviewBuzz! for PSP packs over 5000 questions – on topics including music, celebrities, TV, sport, science, nature, movies and general knowledge – alongside 1000 pictures and videos, into a handheld PSP game ready to test your knowledge at home or on the move. The title features six new round types specifically designed for PSP including the speed-is-of-the-essence ‘Quickfire Challenge’, the picture-puzzler ‘Picture This’ and the mind-boggling ‘Virus Challenge’.  The focus of Buzz! has always been on social play and the PSP version is no different, with three exciting multiplayer modes to test your quiz skills to the limit. Pass Around is a mode that you only need one PSP for, as you pass the system from player to player. As well as the fun of traditional quizzing, some rounds will let you prey on your opponents’ general knowledge weaknesses: you can choose who to pass PSP to according to the question’s subject matter. Other rounds will let you select the section of a photo you want to reveal to the next player, as you try to make it as difficult as possible for them to guess what it is. It’s perfect for stitching up your pals and adds an exciting new tactical edge to game play - as well as a new social gaming element to PSP.  Game sharing is also supported – up to 4 friends can connect multiple PSPs and share just one copy of the game to see who’s quickest off the mark in frenzied ‘Fastest Finger’ play. Then there’s Quiz Host Mode which is where one of the (two to six) players takes control of the game to select and ask the other players questions. The Quiz Host runs the whole game, with the power to award (or even deduct!) points however they see fit.  Not only does Buzz! for PSP offer great multiplayer quiz action; it also has a bigger and more exciting single player mode than previous Buzz! games. This mode presents players with a series of 15 different quiz challenges designed to test all aspects of your general knowledge. In each round, players can earn medals for their performance according to how many points they collect from correct answers. Each quiz has bronze, silver and gold medal criteria, so be sure to brush up on your general knowledge skills if you want to earn those elusive golds! There is also a variety of special trophies to collect according to how many correct questions the players has answered in a row, or how fast the players react.  Features: Three new multiplayer modes, all requiring either just one PSP or one copy of the game to enjoy: Pass Around, Game    Share and Quiz Host  Bigger and better single player mode than ever before, with 15 quiz challenges to test your knowledge to its limits  Six all-new single and multiplayer round types specially created for PSP  Over 5000 unique questions alongside over 1000 licensed picture and video assets  Eight question categories: Music, TV, Science, Celebrities, Nature, Sport, Movies and General Knowledge </description><genres><genre id="14">Trivia/Board Game</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4698">You Don't Know Jack</game><game id="5778">You Don't Know Jack: Volume 3</game><game id="18646">Quiz Show</game><game id="988">Jeopardy!</game><game id="23407">Wits and Wagers</game><game id="25031">1 vs 100</game><game id="27877">Football Genius - The Ultimate Quiz</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9253/1089417-buzz_master_quiz_us_psp_front.jpg</image></root>