<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21141</id><name>Elefunk</name><description>SummaryElefunk is a physics-based puzzle where the goal is to add or remove platforms and their supports to allow one or more elephants to reach a goal. Once the structure has been completed the player presses a button which causes the elephant(s) to start walking A Bridge Being Madeacross the map; if the building cannot support the weight of the elephant then the structure collapses underneath it, causing the mission to be restarted.The game takes place over 20 missions in 4 stages, each with its own visual and gameplay style.ModesSingle PlayerPuzzle mode - In puzzle mode, you have a set amount of points that continuously count down from 100,000.  During this long period of time, you need to build a successful supporting structure to allow the elephant(s) to move to the objective. The faster the level is cleared, more of the 100,000 points are earned. However, if the points get to zero you still are allowed to finish the level. Time attack mode - Time attack is the same as puzzle mode except for the fact that you're trying to build the structure as fast as you possibly can. These times are uploaded to the Playstation Network and ranked against other players globally. MultiplayerPlayers remove one girder at a time from one of five pre-built structures  Elefunk's multiplayer mode is similar to Jenga. On one of 5 levels, players take turns removing beams from a pre-built structure upon which elephants are standing. The loser is the player who removes a beam which causes   the structure to collapse; the more beams have been removed, the longer the structure must remain structurally sound before the other player may take a move.Multiplayer supports both local and online gameplay. The gameplay in this mode is simple, allowing children and adults of all ages to play - and no communication is necessary.Puzzle Mode LevelsPuzzle mode is made up of a total of 20 levels over 4 stages and with a bonus stage on the end of each stage. The 4 stages are called "The Mystic Mountain", "The Eastern Promise", "The Swamp Lands" and the "Circus".The levels in each:The Mystic Mountain                                      Simply LoveUp and DownSupport MeLong and Winding RoadCould Be TrickyBonus Level 1The Eastern PromiseRolling, Rolling, RollingCross the CartoucheIts a Pharaoh WayTrunks Across The NileHerd It Thru The GrapevineBonus Level 2The Swamp LandsSmile For The SnappersAcross The SwampElevate or Be EatenHitch A RopeUps And DownsBonus Level 3The CircusRoll Up, Roll UpHigh Wire HeightsThe Main AttractionBig Top DipperThe Rungmasters DemiseBonus Level 4</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1446">Lemmings</game><game id="15499">Armadillo Run</game><game id="20647">World of Goo</game><game id="10437">Pontifex 2</game><game id="18688">Pontifex</game><game id="24960">Tiki Towers</game><game id="15212">Ratchet &amp; Clank Future: Tools of Destruction</game><game id="34621">GooseGogs</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/28/175957-elefunk.png</image></root>