<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21156</id><name>Mushroom Men: Rise of the Fungi</name><description>Overview A meteor crashes down on Earth, causes the aftershock to rain down a strange green dust to the atmosphere. This dust is harmless to humans but has a big effect on flora, fauna and fungi. This causes them to mutate into living creatures with sentience. The living breathing mushrooms, cacti and fungi can now eat, talk and make judgements of their own. These Mushroom Men are divided into four tribes: Bolete, Morel, Amanita and Lepiota. The Bolete and Morel are isolated tribes and wished nothing but peace and quiet throughout the land. The Amanita nation however consider themselves superior to the other mushrooms and would want nothing more than total domination. In Mushroom Men, you play as a member of the Bolete tribe who is chosen to end this war once and for all. You can play as either the Heavy, the Sage or the Scout fungus. The Heavy fungus specializes on melee attacks who can take a lot of damage but is slow and lumbering. The Sage fungus is the Master of Spore Powers who is well-balanced between speed and strength. And the Scout fungus is the fastest with great ranged weapons but has low stamina and is very vulnerable to damage. Regardless of which classes you choose, they all play relatively the same just some minor dialogue changes and abilities. A  meteor crashes down on Earth, causing the aftershock to rain down a strange green dust to the atmosphere.   Gameplay Mushroom Men for the DS is a side-scrolling action-platformer with light RPG elements. Players move to and fro along large levels solving quest objectives, fighting enemies, and collecting items and equipment. Items and scraps can be put together into weapons and there are tons of them. Players can also be upgraded with having special abilities to run faster or shoot poisonous projectiles, depending on the classes you choose.   Reception Mushroom Men: Rise of The Fungi received mediocre to negative reviews. Common complaints include hard difficulty, cheap deaths and uninspired controls. The enemies are quite difficult to beat and the main character can't jump very far, making it a frustrating game to beat. Mushroom Men: The Spore Wars (the sequel) received more favorable reviews than the DS counterpart.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8942">Super Mario 64 DS</game><game id="609">Rayman 2: The Great Escape</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2452899-box_mmrotf.png</image></root>