<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21161</id><name>Are You Smarter Than A 5th Grader? Make the Grade!</name><description>Jeff Foxworthy's blue collar trivia game show made its video game debut On October 29th 2008 on the Xbox Live Arcade costing 1200 Microsoft Points. This simple trivia game will test the player's intellectual abilities with various elementary-based questions.In Are You Smarter Than A 5th Grader?: Make the Grade, contestants of all ages have the chance to prove their smarts in a game where every question is based on grade school curriculum and the answers are “elementary.” Contestants will choose their partner from five all new brainy 5th graders and test their skills in over 23 subjects while earning coveted gold stars on the way to the virtual Million Dollar Question. Throughout the game, just as on the television show, Jeff Foxworthy encourages and teases the contestants with his trademark brand of humor.Contestants playing the Nintendo Wii, PlayStation 2, Windows PC and PC downloadable version of the game will be challenged by over 6,000 questions in 23 subjects including Animal Science, Cultural Studies, Grammar, Music, Reading, US Geography, Vocabulary, Health and Astronomy. Four exciting game modes will put contestants’ skills to the test: contestants can go head-to-head against friends in the Academic Academy Mode or see who can answer questions the quickest in the fast-paced Flashcards Mode. Spelling Bee Mode challenges contestants to quickly identify misspelled words, while the Homeroom Mode gives contestants the opportunity to play just like they do on the actual show. The Nintendo DS version of the game boasts 3,000 new questions and gives players the opportunity to partner with 5 unlockable bonus classmates. A brand new multi-player mode allows contestants to play head to head against their friends, or pass and play to see who’s the smartest.Are You Smarter Than A 5th Grader?: Make the Grade for Xbox Live Arcade allows players to challenge themselves with over 6,000 questions through three unique game modes—Single Player, Local and Xbox LIVE Multiplayer. Players can earn Gold Stars as they answer grade school questions on their way to the virtual Million Dollar Question.PC System RequirementsWindows Vista/XPPentium IV 1.2GHz Processor256MB RAM120MB Hard Disk SpaceDirectX 9.064MB ATI 8500/Nvidia 5200 FX Video CardDirectX Compliant Sound CardCD-ROM Drive</description><genres><genre id="14">Trivia/Board Game</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21950">Scene It? Box Office Smash</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93538/1555784-954032_113386_front.jpg</image></root>