<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21172</id><name>UNO Rush</name><description>Overview Uno Rush is a four-player, social party XBOX LIVE arcade game.  Arrange your cards so you can play them  successively when it is your turn. The first player to get rid of all their cards wins the round, and scores points based on the remaining cards in opponents' hands. It was originally meant to be released alongside the  New Xbox Experience however was delayed to March 25th 2009; it costs 800 Microsoft Points on the Xbox Live Marketplace.\GameplayEach player in Uno Rush is dealt seven cards with a number on it between 0-9, in one of four colours. The objective is to play all your cards, which is done by playing a card of the same colour or number as the one in the middle. There are also special cards that can hinder your opponents, causing them to miss a turn, get extra cards or having all their cards shuffled around. Your turn only lasts a few seconds, hence the "Rush" part of the name. In addition to the standard game mode, there is also Elimination mode, wherein you have to play a card on your turn or you get a strike, three strikes and you are eliminated from the round. You can also play Pairs, which is a two-on-two mode. The player can greatly customize the rules, from the speed of the game to the amount of cards dealt at the start and the amount of points required to win th game.FeaturesAvatar Support4 players matches (singleplayer and multiplayer)Xbox Live Vision Camera supportBig Button Pad supportNew UNO gameplay</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="13">Card Game</genre><genre id="14">Trivia/Board Game</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23813">Domino Master</game><game id="22973">Gin Rummy</game><game id="20764">Lost Cities</game><game id="10489">Pokémon Trading Card Game</game><game id="23407">Wits and Wagers</game><game id="24835">Classicard</game><game id="25038">Uno</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1841457-box_unorush.png</image></root>