<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21181</id><name>PixelJunk Eden</name><description>OverviewPixelJunk Eden, developed by Q-Games in with collaboration Baiyon, marks the third PixelJunk title to be released on the PSN. In PixelJunk Eden, the player takes control of a Grimp (grip jump), a small insect-like creature that travels through the game's various levels (gardens) by launching and swinging itself from plants situated throughout each stage. The player progresses through a level by striking pollen buds that pollinate the plant seeds located throughout the garden. A garden is completed by collecting special items known as spectra, generally located far above the player's starting location. This is companied by simple but striking 1080p visuals at 60 frames per second and a techno sound track to create an immersive experience.GameplayGrimpsGrimps can be controlled by jumping or by launching silk off a plant and rotating around it. The length of silk can als o be drawn in. While jumping, the grimp can be made to spin which will prevent it from attaching to plants or rocks, and can be used to destroy certain enemies. Spinning also pulls in pollen from small area around the grimp. Pollen is produced by destroying Pollen Prowlers, which can be done by either hitting them with the body of the grimp or by the silk for the Type A variety. Once they release the pollen, the grimp must collect it by touching it with their body or silk. Collecting pollen causes it to drift toward the closest unpollinated seed or be absorbed if there is not one within a sufficient distance. Once a seed is fully pollinated/charged, it starts glowing, which indicates that it is ready to be opened. When the player makes contact with the seed, it will grow into a plant. The SIXAXIS motion controls can also be used to suddenly project the grimp downward, which results in a greater amount of pollen released from any Pollen Prowlers destroyed on the way down.There are also two sizes of crystals scattered throughout a garden that refill/tune the player's oscillator bar depending on its size. This bar depletes over time, so gathering these crystals is very important. If it goes out of tune, the level is failed. However, with the first patch you may choose to continue from the last spectra collected, though you forfeit trophies by doing this. Collecting at least five Pollen Prowlers in a single swing will also generate a circle of small crystals which remain for a limited amount of time. The oscillator bar is completely refilled when a spectra is collected.There are several tougher enemies in the game. Their abilities vary from breaking the silk to bumping the grimp off its path and causing it to spin. Later enemies have advanced abilities such as removing a certain amount from the oscillator bar or causing a plant to simply disappear for a short amount of time.When a player collects a new spectra it is added to the player's own Eden, which helps to reach gardens that are placed higher up. There are ten gardens with five spectra each, making a total of 50 spectra to collect. Upon the each play through of a garden, only one additional spectra is required to complete it until all five are collected.YouTubeIt is also possible to record in-game footage up to 10 minutes long and upload it directly to YouTube or save it to the PlayStation 3 hard drive.MusicThe soundtrack to PixelJunk Eden was published by ANIPLEX Records and released on September 24th, 2008. The game features very ambient and funky music. Most songs are very soothing and relaxing while others provide a simple beat as to not distract from the gameplay. The album is available online at certain retailers but can also be purchased for $1.99 from the PSN store. Once the player has attained all 50 spectra, the ability to create custom soundtracks for the game is unlocked.Track ListingBecome Part of This637 VolpeBoard De LacThey SaidSummer in WinterFlat FrogSwept The RainWheel WindowHand-WashDruck Der FarbenReturn3 Across 4CriticismAn open letter lamenting the difficulty of the game (particularly the enemies and the timer) was responded to by the developer of the game, Dylan Cuthbert. He thinks that the game would be too easy in co-op mode if any changes were made. Nevertheless, Q-games has many ideas for an upcoming expansion pack dubbed PixelJunk Eden Encore. Cuthbert states that "the controls are too much fun to waste on just one set of game rules" and that he is "sure we will try and add a more namby pamby mode for the “lighter” people out there." This expansion was later released, bearing the the same name as previously stated by Cuthbert, PixelJunk Eden Encore . The timer was never addressed and the add-on does not "fix" anything, per se, but simply adds more mechanics.System RequirementsOS:Windows XP, Vista, 7Processor:Performance equivalent to Core™2 Duo. SS3 required.Memory:512 MB RAMGraphics:5 years or younger. Integrated graphics and very low budget cards may not work. OpenGL 2.1.DirectX®:dx90cHard Drive: 446 MB HD space</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15849">flOw</game><game id="20320">Synaesthete</game><game id="5057">Lumines: Puzzle Fusion</game><game id="20290">Wik &amp; The Fable of Souls</game><game id="7860">Bionic Commando</game><game id="21120">Flower</game><game id="16676">Globdule</game><game id="15212">Ratchet &amp; Clank Future: Tools of Destruction</game><game id="31650">TerRover</game><game id="35697">Solar 2</game><game id="35657">Rotastic</game><game id="37741">Chasing Aurora</game><game id="40464">Fly'N</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/172/177075-pixeljunk_eden_logo.jpg</image></root>