<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21195</id><name>Dragon Ball Z: Budokai Tenkaichi 3</name><description>OverviewDragon Ball Z: Budokai Tenkaichi 3 delivers an extreme 3D fighting experience, reaching new heights of Dragon Ball Z thrills and excitement with over 150 playable characters, enhanced fighting techniques, beautifully refined effects and shading techniques, making each character's effects more realistic, and over 20 battle stages. Amongst the wealth of brand new features are more than ten types of AI balancing for opponents, a new Dragon History mode that lets fans select favourite battle scenes, and a new Battle Replay mode that lets players save and replay their greatest battles.  In the Wii version, an improved control system lets players mimic signature moves even more easily to execute devastating energy attacks straight from the Dragon Ball Z animated series. The two player mode on both platforms lets friends engage in fierce head-to-head battling.   In addition to the unprecedented number of characters and improved gameplay, the environments have also been enhanced to feature day and night stages. The power of the moon in the night stages gives players additional ways to transform their characters and letting fans recreate some of their favorite memories from the show.  Features:  Over 40 hours of gameplay through 10 different game modes recreating the complete Dragon Ball world! 90 unique characters with over 150 forms, including many new ones from DB, DBZ, DB GT and DB movies! Over 20 unique battle stages, each with their own particular specificities affecting battles! Follow the original anime flow through seamless battles with impressive scenes thanks to the [Dramatic Z Engine]!  Dragonball Z Budokai: Tenkaichi 3 is a fighting game released for Nintendo's Wii and Sony's PlayStation 2. It features 161 playable characters. Also a Battle Replay, night and day cycle, the Wii's online function, and Disc Fusion have been added to the game. Battle Replay allows players to capture their favorite fights and save them to the hard drive to view later on. Night and day cycle allows for more accurate battles in Dragon History, as well as the ability to transform into an Oozaru (Great Ape) by using the moon. There are also several other time differences, such as dawn and afternoon. Not all stages provide different times. You can also change the aura of your character. The Wii version will feature online multiplayer capability, the first game in the series to have such a feature. Players can fight against anyone from around the globe with a ranking system showing the player's current standing compared to anyone else who has played online. As compensation for the lack of an online feature, Spike has added a new "Disc Fusion System" to the PlayStation 2 version. Inserting a Budokai Tenkaichi or Budokai Tenkaichi 2 disc during play unlocks Ultimate Battle or Ultimate Battle Z modes featured in the respective games needed to unlock them. Characters Goku (early, mid, Super Saiyan 1,2,3 Vegito, Super Vegito, Super Gogeta) Kid Goku (Giant Ape) Goku GT (Super Saiyan, 3,4, Super Saiyan 4 Gogeta) Gohan (kid, teen, Super Saiyan, 2, Great Saiyaman) Ultimate Gohan Future Gohan (Super Saiyan) Piccolo Vegeta (Scouter, Great Ape, Super Saiyan, 2, Vegito, Super Vegito, Super Gogeta, Super Saiyan 4, Super Saiyan 4 Gogeta, Majin) Krillin Yamcha Trunks (Sword, Super Saiyan, Ultra Super Saiyan) Kid Trunks (Super Saiyan, Gotenks, Super Saiyan Gotenks,3) Goten (Super Saiyan, Gotenks, Super Saiyan Gotenks,3) Tien  Chiaotzu Videl (Great Saiyaman 2) Hercule Uub (Majuub) Pan Master Roshi (Max Power) Yajirobe Nail Super Kai (Kibitokai) Raditz (Great Ape) Nappa (Great Ape) Saibaman Recoome Burter Jeice Guldo Zarbon (Post-Transformation) Dodoria Frieza (1st, 2nd, 3rd, 4th, final, full power form, Mecha) Appule Cui Frieza Soldier King Cold King Vegeta (Great Ape) Cell (1st, 2nd, 3rd form) Cell Jr Dr. Gero Android #19 Android #18 Android #17 Android #16 Majin Buu Majin Buu (Evil) Super Buu (Gotenks absorbed, Gohan absorbed) Kid Buu Babidi Spopovich Demon King Dabura Bardock (Great Ape) Fasha (Great Ape) Garlic Jr (Super Garlic Jr) Dr. Wheelo Turles (Great Ape) Slug (Giant) Salza Cooler (Final form, Meta) Android  13 (fusion) Broly (Super Saiyan, Legendary Super Saiyan) Zangya Bojack (full power) Janemba (Super Janemba) Pikkon Tapion Hirudegarn Baby Vegeta (Super Baby 1,2, Golden Great Ape Baby) Super 17 Nova Shenron Syn Shenron (Omega Shenron) Demon King Piccolo Tamourine Pilaf Machine (Fusion) Devilman General Blue General Tao (Cyborg Tao) Chi-Chi Grandpa Gohan Nam Android #18 Arale</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20903">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja Storm</game><game id="20486">Bleach: Shattered Blade</game><game id="18522">Onimusha: Blade Warriors</game><game id="7792">Dead or Alive 4</game><game id="22723">YuYu Hakusho: Dark Tournament</game><game id="12411">Soulcalibur</game><game id="11065">Shaman King: Power of Spirit</game><game id="18753">Tekken 5</game><game id="21375">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja 3</game><game id="9855">Soulcalibur III</game><game id="18303">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja 2</game><game id="23220">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja</game><game id="10162">Tekken Tag Tournament</game><game id="10989">Street Fighter EX3</game><game id="5336">Marvel Nemesis: Rise of the Imperfects</game><game id="14684">Tekken 4</game><game id="4289">The King of Fighters 2006</game><game id="5465">Destrega</game><game id="27571">Saint Seiya: The Sanctuary</game><game id="27582">Saint Seiya: The Hades</game><game id="28105">Evangelion: Jo</game><game id="30539">Naruto Shippuden: Ultimate Ninja Storm 2</game><game id="33356">Bid For Power</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2352256-box_dbzbt3.png</image></root>