<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21191</id><name>Call of Juarez</name><description>OverviewCall of Juarez (formerly known as the Lawman ) is a first person shooter/adventure game from Techland Sp. First, it was released in Europe for PC on September 15th 2006. Then a year later on June 5th, the ported Xbox 360 version was released alongside the PC version in North America. The PC version was one of the first games to use DirectX 10. Its prequel, Call of Juarez: Bound in Blood was released in 2009 and its unfortunate sequel, Call of Juarez: The Cartel in 2011.CharactersBilly CandleA young Native American. Billy has been forced to grow up fast in the unforgiving Old West. His father is unknown, he is named after a mysterious medallion he carries, which was given to him by his mother. Billy is good at heart, but is constantly blamed for the wrongdoings of others. He can sneak past enemies and use stealth to his advantage. Billy is also very agile - he can climb over objects and use items to get on top of buildings. He also has a handy whip which allows him to swing across gaps and onto ledges or just climb up or down the side of a building/canyon.Reverend RayRay McCall is a man of God who has lived a rough life. Rumor has it that he was once an infamous gunfighter, feared by all who crossed his path. He is now a man of the cloth who has devoted his life to saving the souls of the damned and bringing light into the lives of those who live in sin. When push comes to shove, Reverend Ray is an imposing man with great physical strength and a crack shot.Juan MendozaMendoza ( with the nickname of Juarez ) is the real father of Billy and a ruthless Mexican warlord. His ultimate goal is to find the gold of Juarez and that's why he desperately looks for the medallion which his son carries. He has a headquarters near the town of Juarez.. Juarez is also the one responsible for the death of Thomas and Marisa.Calm WaterCalm Water is an old native who lives alone in the wilderness and tries to convince Billy to stop running and face his fears with some methods that Billy finds strange at first. Nothing is known about his past in CoJ, but in BiB, we understand that Calm Water was the leader of a tribe with the name " Running River " who leads his tribe and son to doom because of his hunger for war with the white skins. After that, he changed his name to Calm Water and settled down.StoryThe game places you in the shoes of two very unique and vastly different characters. The first of which is a young native American man named Billy Candle and the other is his Uncle Ray or Reverend Ray as the towns people call him. Billy has returned home after a long and unsuccessful journey of looking for the Lost Gold of Juarez. "The Legend of the Lost Gold of Juarez has been passed from one generation to the next since the time of Hernando Cortez. It was said to be the ransom for Montezuma, held hostage by the Spanish in the great Aztec capital of Tenochtitlan. The treasure disappeared soon after the sacking of the city and some believe it's buried near the borderUsing a bowtown of Juarez. According to the Legend, the Aztec Sun God, Huitzilopochtli, put a curse on the treasure and all who seek it will find only insanity and perdition. This avaricious madness has come to be known as the "Call of Juarez". Billy comes home to find his mom and dad dead. Reverend Ray thinks Billy did it and so begins the chase between family. Billy wants to clear his name and Ray wants revenge on Billy for killing his brother. Along the way Ray has to fight off bandits and outlaws as Billy runs for his life and also tries to reach his love interest Molly Ferguson, the daughter of a Ranch owner he once worked for. But then got fired by him and threatened to death if he ever returns after he found out that Billy is in love with his daughter.Billy meets an old Native American ( Calm Water ) who teaches him the ways of their culture. By the end, Billy finally finds his Gold and Reverend Ray learns that Juarez is the real murderer and goes on a vengeful rampage in his fortress, saving Billy and Molly in the process.Unique GameplayThe game contains several unique gameplay elements including Billy's avid use of his whip which allows him to scale things and swing. This brings a certain platforming to the game all in first person. Reverand Ray even has the special ability to slow time and target all his enemies with a red reticule and unload one single shot kill for each bullet in each of his two six-shooters. Ray also has one of the most unique and inspiring melee weapons in all of video games, The Bible. Ray can call out verse from the bible in real time, and if close enough to the enemies, they will in some cases put down their weapons and surrender or just stop to listen to the touching words, giving you a couple of seconds to lay waste to them. Inspiring Indeed.PC System RequirementsMinimumOperating System: Windows® 2000/XP (only)Processor: 2.2 GHz Pentium® 4, AMD Athlon™ 2400 , or 2.4 GHz CeleronRAM Memory: 512 MBVideo Card: nVidia: GF6600, ATI: Radeon 9800 or better video cardSound Card: DirectX 9-compliant sound deviceDirectX: DirectX 9.0c or higherHard Drive Space: 2 GBPeripherals: Windows-compliant mouse and keyboardRecommendedProcessor: 3 GHz Pentium 4, AMD Athlon 3000 , or 3 GHz Celeron or betterRAM Memory: 1 GBXbox 360 Game InstallationCall of Juarez requires 6.2GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8873">GUN</game><game id="21524">Warhound</game><game id="21912">Planetside: Core Combat</game><game id="1803">Dead Man's Hand</game><game id="25249">Red Dead Redemption</game><game id="1673">Outlaws</game><game id="39682">Call of Juarez: Gunslinger</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1881062-box_coj.png</image></root>