<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21217</id><name>TimeSplitters 4</name><description>DevelopmentTimesplitters 4 was confirmed to be in development in some way or another since 2005, but focus had been given to Haze. The game would still focus on multiplayer as with the rest of the series. Continuing in the vein of Timesplitters: Future Perfect, Timesplitters 4 would also contain a fully-featured single player campaign. Rumors stated that Simon Pegg, star of the movies Shaun of the Dead and Hot Fuzz, would have creative input, and possibly record voice acting. The series tradition of including monkeys as characters had been confirmed, and the protagonist of the previous games, Cortez would also be returning. Concept art released later suggested that the game would also feature zombies, as well as fan-favorite Jo-Beth Casey, this time in nun attire.On December 18th 2008, Free Radical Design, the long time developers of the Timesplitters saga shut it's doors. The English studio met for a final meeting, and for a time, the status of Timesplitters 4 was unknown. The main reason behind Free Radical's closure seemed to be the poor performance of HAZE which sold under 500,000 units, and was in development for 4 years, costing the company millions of dollars. Free Radical Design has since been acquired by Crytek, changing its name to Crytek UK. Following this, the game was placed on hold, its future uncertain.On January 28th 2011, during an interview with CVG, Crytek CEO Cevat Yerli revealed the fact that his team had been discussing completion of the game, but that nothing more was likely to happen until Crysis 2 was complete, as the former Free Radical team was responsible for the game's multiplayer portion.</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10955">Unreal Tournament 3</game><game id="20455">Haze</game><game id="21256">Perfect Dark</game><game id="21912">Planetside: Core Combat</game><game id="25251">Onslaught</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4527/1192592-timesplitters4.png</image></root>