<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21229</id><name>Mythos</name><description>OverviewMythos is a fast paced Action MMORPG by             Flagship Studios Seattle,  comprised of the creators of FATE.  Initially created to test network code for             Hellgate: London, it was quickly decided that it was fun enough to be developed into a full-fledged game itself.  Many beta testers actually considered the game to be better than             Hellgate: London.The game was in beta phase, but due to financial and legal issues faced by Flagship Studios (involving a dispute with their Korean partner Hanbitsoftt) the game and its website have been shut down.   After the closure of Flagship Studios, the Seattle team reformed and started            Runic Games, and has been developing the Action RPG,          Torchlight. Mythos' development has since been continued by  San Mateo based developer, Redbana, a subsidiary of T3 Entertainment, under the Korean MMO Publisher, Hanbitsoft. European version of the game is being published by Frogster alongside Hanbitsoft. European Closed beta was launched on the 27th. of January 2011.  Gameplay The standard gameplay is very "diabloesque" and hack n' slash players should feel right at home within minutes.   Following features have been announced so far: - Quest system - Crafting system. - In game achievement system  It currently features the following classes and races:Gameplay of Mythos ClassesBloodletter: Melee based fighter which also can also exploit corpses similarly to necromancers in other games. Gadgeteer: Uses grenades and turret pets against enemies.  Also has skills which improve the use of guns. Pyromancer: Attacks with powerful magic flames.  Has various other utility abilities.  In an interview before development of the game went on hiatus, one of the developers stated that a fourth class was being worked on.  As they were still in the process of deciding what skills it would have, no further details were given. Races Satyr: Ancient race adept at magic - Racial bonus: 20% poison resistance  3 mana  Human: Young race with no particular strengths or weaknesses - Racial bonus: 20% fire resistance  3 health  Gremlin: Eccentric halflings with that live fast and loud - Racial bonus: 20% electric resistance  11 hit bonus  Cyclops: Hulking one-eyed creatures with great strength and size - Racial bonus: 20% ice resistance  4 defence   However the game may have changed due to a new development team.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5985">Diablo</game><game id="8638">Titan Quest</game><game id="2268">RuneScape</game><game id="23411">Runescape Classic</game><game id="25983">Torchlight</game><game id="19703">Darkstone</game><game id="1119">Diablo II</game><game id="20803">Diablo III</game><game id="15589">Diablo II: Lord of Destruction</game><game id="33494">Dungeons &amp; Dragons Daggerdale</game><game id="29827">Battle of the Immortals</game><game id="5776">Legend of the North: Konung</game><game id="12">Blade &amp; Sword</game><game id="36093">Legends of Yore</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2759/181413-mythos_030408_art_01_0.jpg</image></root>