<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21237</id><name>Tales of Symphonia</name><description>OverviewTales of Symphonia is another release from Namco's Tales Studios, and has been released on both the Gamecube and the Playstation 2, however the PlayStation 2 version is only availabe inside Japan. Players who have played this game will experience its lengthy storyline, cel-shaded animated graphics (complete with voice overs in cutscenes), and its Linear Motion Battle System. Symphonia expands upon this battle system in this 80 hour (or so the back of the box claims) adventure. More emphasis is placed on the protagonist's relationships with his party members by the decisions he makes than previous installments in the series. Symphonia is also a distant prequel to the Tales series first entry, Tales of Phantasia. Tales of Symphonia sold fairly well and was highly regarded by most publications.PlotThe game is based in the world called Sylvarant which lives off of mana. At this time the world is in a form of depression and losing mana, so the Chosen one must travel the world going to ancient shrines where there they must summon spirits to break something called seals allowing the mana to flow back into Sylvarant. There are five seals in the world altogether. You start off playing Lloyd Irving, a boy who decides to protect and help his friend Colette Brunel the chosen one.Two of Lloyd's fellow townsfolk join him on his quest; his best friend Genis Sage, and Genis' older sister and their teacher Raine Sage. Shortly after they set off for their quest they meet a mysterious man named Kratos Aurion who volunteers to help and protect Colette on her journey of regeneration. Later on a female assassin who attempts to stop you, but fails several times, joins your party named Sheena Fujibayashi. Sheena is sent from another world called Tethe'alla to assassinate Colette.As Colette gets closer to reaching her goal of world regeneration they stumble upon several twists to complicate their situation. They learn that the angels are manipulating them for their personal reasons and that Kratos is an angel.They then learn of the other world called Tethe'alla that shares mana with Sylvarant and that one prospers with mana while the other falls into a a state of disrepair. The remaing members (excluding Kratos) journey to the other world to find answers to their dilemma. While there they decide to restore mana to both worlds for both of them to prosper.While in Tethe’alla they meet new people who join their cause. One is a small girl named Presea Combatir who seems rather strong for a girl and shows little emotion. They then meet up with Zelos Wilder, the man who is the chosen for Tethe’alla. Zelos is somewhat arrogant, a ladies man, and rather carefree.The last member to join their party is Regal Bryant, a man who is a convict. Regal fights with his feet instead of his hands since they remain bound for what he believes is an unforgivable crime. They then set out to open the seals in Tethe’alla so as to sever the bonds of both worlds. Through this quest they end up reviving an ancient tree of mana and with something called the Eternal Sword they are able to connect the worlds and restore mana to both.Links to Tales of PhantasiaThe Yggdrasil Tree in Phantasia is named after the main villian in Symphonia.Many locations are the sameThe two world maps are very similiarSheena and Suzu both have the same last nameCharactersLloyd IrvingThe main character of Tales of Symphonia, Lloyd is a young and energetic man who makes it his goal to protect the female Chosen, Colette. He uses two swords in battle, and is a fast and powerful attacker.Colette BrunelThe female lead of the game, Colette is a clumsy and slightly air-headed young girl who has been deemed the Chosen of Sylvarant, and would do anything to protect the people of her world. She fights with chakra, bladed rings, and can use some magic.Genis SageA young and reluctant "sidekick" of the story, Genis is usually levelheaded and can overthink situations. He fights using his powerful magic.Raine SageOriginally Lloyd, Genis, and Colette's teacher, she decides to accompany the younger group so that she can study the world and protect her young brother, Genis. She is primarily a healer, and can cast powerful light-based magic.Kratos AurionAn older man who shows up in Lloyd's home town claiming to be a mercenary, and offers his services in protection of the chosen. He is later revealed to have a closer connection to the characters than thought at first. He fights with a single sword, and can also be made into a powerful spellcaster.Sheena FujibayashiA girl who is not much older than Lloyd or Colette, but who is somewhat stereotypically insecure about her abilities. She comes from a hidden village of ninjas, and is charged with following the Chosen, for different reasons at different points in time. She fights using magic cards and summon spirits.Regal BryantAn older man whose hands are constantly shackled because of his past crimes. He thus fights with his feet, and has a very troubled view of his own past and future.Presea CombatirA woman who has been trapped in the body of a very young girl due to horrible experiments done to her. She wields an enourmous axe, and is the heaviest hitter in the game.Zelos WilderA womanizer and a jokester, Zelos is a comedic character that actually has some skeletons in his closet. He joins the party shortly after a pivotal moment in the story.Skits/AffectionOne of the game's numerous skitsThroughout the game you will come across a button popping up at the bottom of the screen that will indicate a skit. It will also have a sentence about the skit next to it. In these skits, it shows the characters talking about something that just happened or something totally random. There are also some skits on the overworld that will trigger when you go to a certain area or into a glowing circle of light. These affect Lloyd's relationship with the people in his party. Some things you do in the skits where you answer questions can change a major event in the game; others might change something small, but they can all add up. There is only one major game changing event based on the relationship of characters, otherwise, it just helps you get more scenes.Battle SystemFighting in Tales of Symphonia is not like a traditional RPG. Just like other Tales games, it uses a modified version of the Linear Motion Battle System, which features real-time fights. The player can only directly control one character, while the rest of the party is controlled by A.I. However, if there are more controllers installed in the game, other people can control the other three characters whilst in battle.Characters no longer have to share the same horizontal pathwayThe newest addition to the battle system is a 3D plane. Players and enemies no longer are crowded up on a horizontal line. The player can still only move exclu s ively left and right, but can switch directions by pushing the right trigger button and switching the target. Also new to Symphonia is Overlimit. As the players , or occasionaly the enemy, reach a certain amount of tension points, they will go into Overlimit mode. Overlimit mode briefly reduces the character's reci eved damage, stops staggering, and decreases spell casting time. Sheena can only make Summons while in Overlimit mode. Unison Attacks are a lso a feature unique to Symphonia. When the Unison Attack Gauge fills up, characters can unleash a Unison attack, which allows all 4 battle members to unleash an attack at the system. Sometimes if the right attacks are combined, an additional special attack will be unleashed.After battles, GRADE can be earned or lossed depending on the quality of the player's performance during battle. GRADE can be used to purchase materials for customizing weapons or for buying new features for the next playthrough in the GRADE shop after beating the game.Allies can have their AI customized in order to fit with the players style. For example, Kratos can be commanded to take an all out offensive approach, or told to stay back and concentrate on spells and healing.In addition, ally magics can be mapped to directions on the C-stick, making combos and strategic attacks a snapSummonsSheena Fujibayashi has the ability to summon spirits to help her in battle. While these summons are often time consuming and leave her vulnerable, the effects can be devastating to enemies.CorrineCorrine doesn't make much of a difference in battle, but is always around to give Sheena a hand.EfreetEfreet is the first summon obtained, based in the element of fire.UndineUndine is a water summon located on the island of ThodaSylphSylph is a bird-like summon that harnesses the properties of windLunaLuna partners with Aska and is in charge of lightAskaAska is the last summon obtained in Sylvarant and co-ops the lightCelciusCelcius' powers are based in the cold and Ice, and is found up north in the Tethealla reigonVoltVolt is found at the top of the Temple of Lightning and reigns over lightningGnomeGnome is an Earth based summon and a bit of a goofShadowShadow has the ability to cure a party's status effects, and is the spirit of DarknessOriginOrigin is the king of the summon spirits and forger of the Eternal SwordMaxwellMaxwell works to keep the city of Exire afloatVeriusVerius is the rebirth of Corrine, and the guardian of emotionMusicThe soundtrack containing all the tracks found in the original GameCube release was released in October 1st, 2003, it contained 4 CDs; while a little more than a year later, on 27 October in 2004 a revised version was released due to the Playstation 2 release of the game, containing the remaining Playstation 2 exclusive tracks.The opening theme was performed by Day After Tomorrow.The complete set of tracks is the following:Disc One01 - Tales of Symphonia02 - A Prologue03 - Old Familiar Scent of Iselia04 - Lloyd05 - Colette06 - Genis07 - Raine08 - Kratos09 - Unsatisfied Desire10 - Standing the Pain11 - Overcome12 - Dad, I'm Home13 - Talk About Sylvarant14 - The Land of Sylvarant15 - Full Force16 - Victory17 - Rest of the Heart18 - Desert Flower19 - The Struggle to Survive20 - Rovers21 - Along the Beach22 - Harbor Town23 - Town of Wind and Ruins24 - Untold Despair25 - Water Symphony26 - Water Symphony ~Despair~27 - Sweet DreamsDisc Two01 - Nova's Caravan02 - Venturers' Colony03 - Search for the Seal ~Sylvarant~04 - Escape From Enemy Base05 - Lloyd ~ Ocarina Version~06 - Collet ~Sad~07 - Raine -Ruin Mode-08 - The Tower09 - Confusion10 - An Appearance11 - Delightful Day12 - Behind Us13 - In the Ashes14 - Deep Fear15 - On the Very Edge!16 - Off-Key17 - Moonlight18 - Wood Carving Star19 - Shining Dew20 - The Grudge21 - Fatalize22 - On the Tight Rope23 - New One World24 - On the Hill at Night25 - Floating in the Air26 - Nobody KnowsDisc Three01 - Far From Our World02 - The Kingdom City of Meltokio03 - Darkside of Meltokio04 - A Selfish Want05 - Tethe'Alla Castle06 - Presea07 - Zelos08 - Walking on Tethe'Alla09 - Like a Glint of Light10 - Academic City11 - Secret From the Blue Sky12 - Regal13 - Trip on the Ship14 - Sheena15 - Shinobi Life16 - Anchor17 - Underground Passage18 - Dry Trail19 - In a Shadowy Woods20 - Deepest Woods21 - Dance in the Sunshine22 - A Snow Light23 - Aviators ~Rheards~24 - Rest of the Heart ~Sanctuary~25 - Serenade of Elves26 - Torent Forest27 - Firing28 - A Break Down29 - Zelos ~Serious~30 - Mithos31 - Encount with the Renegade32 - Eternal OathDisc Four01 - Judgment of Mana02 - Spirits Whispers03 - Fun with Idol04 - Fighting the Spirit05 - Search a Seal ~Tethe'Alla~06 - The Law of the Battle07 - The End of a Thought08 - Keep Your Guard Up!09 - Defeat the Angel10 - Edge of Nowhere11 - A Sign12 - Be Invoked13 - Derris Kharlan ~Appear~14 - Derris Kharlan ~Fear~15 - Derris Kharlan ~Shine~16 - Derris Kharlan ~Requiem~17 - Keen-Edged Blade18 - Last Battle ~Will~19 - Last Battle ~Decision~20 - Hidden Sorrow21 - It Can Waver and Fight22 - Final Destination23 - Harmony24 - Revival25 - Ending ~Staff Rolling~26 - Thank You AllReceptionTales of Symphonia is the most popular game in the Tales franchise. The GameCube version in Japan sold below expectations, which is why Namco threw out the exclusive title and released the game on the PlayStation 2, which it sold fairly well on. Many publications gave it nominations for 2004 GameCube Game of the Year and 2004 RPG of the Year. It also prompted Namco to create a spin-off sequel to the game on the Wii, "Tales of Symphonia: Dawn of a New World", a first in the Tales franchise. It's main protagonist, Lloyd Irving, has made cameo appearances in other games like Soul Calibur Legends for the Wii.LocalizationNamco originally had no intentions of bringing Tales of Symphonia to the US. However, Nintendo later asked for Namco to bring Symphonia to the US and offered to publish the localized version. Nintendo funded the translations, voice acting, and also helped promote the game by giving it a front cover on Nintendo Power. The game went on to sell fairly well in the US. Seeing as it was published by Nintendo outside of Japan, it is highly unlikely that the PlayStation 2 version will ever be released outside of Japan.Other Info1 player2-4 players simultaneousMemory blocks needed: 3</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7958">Baten Kaitos: Eternal Wings and the Lost Ocean</game><game id="21464">Star Ocean:  Second Evolution</game><game id="15050">Atelier Iris: Eternal Mana</game><game id="1959">Atelier Iris 2: The Azoth of Destiny</game><game id="21442">Atelier Iris 3: Grand Phantasm</game><game id="19621">Ys: The Ark of Napishtim</game><game id="7447">Blue Dragon</game><game id="4763">Kingdom Hearts II</game><game id="10983">Kingdom Hearts</game><game id="29300">Summon Night Granthese: Horobi no Tsurugi to Yakusoku no Kishi</game><game id="4338">Final Fantasy Anthology</game><game id="24076">Arc Rise Fantasia</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1837515-box_tos.png</image></root>