<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21259</id><name>MVP 06 NCAA Baseball</name><description>Overview After 2K acquired the exclusive rights to publish 3rd party MLB games, EA decided to keep its MVP namesake, but create a College Baseball version of their game. MVP 06 NCAA Baseball was the first College Baseball game ever created, and was well received among critics and fans of the series. This was also the last MVP Baseball game to be developed for the Xbox (however, MVP 06 was made backwards compatible with the Xbox 360).Gameplay ImprovementsMVP06 added new right analog hitting and fielding mechanics. At the plate, players would pull back on the right stick to go into the batting action, then push the stick forward to perform the swing motion. In the field, players would use the right analog stick to throw to the various bases.SoundtrackMVP06's soundtrack consisted soley of artists from Chicago based independent label Victory Records.Action Action - "Paper Cliche"Bayside - "Devotion and Desire"Hawthorne Heights - "This is Who We Are"The Forecast - "These Lights"Silverstein - "Smile in your Sleep"The Audition - "Approach the Bench"The Black Maria - "Organs"The Junior Varsity - "Get Comfortable"Waterdown - "Repeater"  NCAA StadiumsRosenblatt StadiumKindall Field Packard Stadium Baum Stadium Baylor Ballpark Goodwin Field Doug Kingsmore Stadium Dick Howser Stadium Russ Chandler Stadium Alex Box Stadium Mark Light Field Swayze Field Dudy Noble Field Hawks Field Frank Eck Stadium Reckling Park Sunken Diamond Dedeaux Field The Ballpark at St. Johns Lindsey Nelson Stadium Disch-Falk Field    </description><genres><genre id="34">Baseball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20687">MLB Power Pros 2008</game><game id="20876">Major League Baseball 2K8</game><game id="15449">Backyard Baseball 2001</game><game id="20835">MLB 08: The Show</game><game id="2250">Triple Play 98</game><game id="1202">Triple Play 97</game><game id="17271">Triple Play 2002</game><game id="7000">Triple Play 2001</game><game id="9670">Triple Play Baseball</game><game id="14025">Triple Play 2000</game><game id="22848">MLB '98</game><game id="29485">MLB 10: The Show</game><game id="24901">MLB 09: The Show</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2261137-box_mvpncaab06.png</image></root>