<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21286</id><name>Final Fantasy Tactics A2: Grimoire of the Rift</name><description>PlotVandalism doesn't pay. I mean, look at this outfit!As school lets out for summer break, Luso Clemens finds himself cleaning his school's library instead of enjoying fun in the sun. His fate, constructed only by recklessness, sees him absorbed in a dusty old book after he writes his name in it. A portal to the magical land of Ivalice thrusts him right into the heart of battle, and Luso has no choice but to join the ranks of Clan Gully. With a mysterious revgaji named Cid leading the clan, Luso quickly gets wrapped around twists and turns beyond his grasp. The quest to return home is strewn with conflicting feelings and tough decisions; turbulent times are aplenty. Familiar characters and familiar worlds may line the setting, but only Luso's fate may line the pages of the Grimoire.GameplayTurn-Based TacticsGrids and Bangaas? I know what this game is going to be!Like previous releases, Final Fantasy Tactics A2 (FFTA2) utilizes a turn-based tactics mechanic outlined on a grid. Based on their speed statistic, units will take turns moving and attacking from fastest to slowest. If a unit does not move or attack, their next turn will come quicker. Each unit has limitations involving their move space, attack range and overall stat growth; most of which depends on the job and the base level. Battles take the form of quests issued at pubs located throughout the world. Examples include escort missions, item finding quests, field-clearing battles, etc. Most battles and quests usually involve depleting the enemy's HP down to zero. In addition to accepting quests, certain ones may have a time limit attached to them; plot-based quests exclude the limit.Job System/AbilitiesMoogles are awesome and cute. Mostly awesome though.Holding true to previous FFT games, FFTA2 uses a job system to supplement unit growth and abilities. With fifty-six jobs, from Warriors to Summoners, FFTA2 sports the biggest job tree in all the tactical spinoffs thus far. Mastering a job involves equipping a job-specific weapon and gaining enough ability points to learn attached abilities. When enough abilities are learned, new jobs will open up. Certain advanced jobs will require the completion of a sidequest; certain jobs are also exclusive to certain races as well.Judge SystemLike FFTA before it, FFTA2 has a judge overlooking the battle and prohibiting certain actions such as the use of a magic type or use of a weapon type. New to the FFT series, are clan privileges. These allow specific stat boosts as long as the law is upheld, if any friendly unit breaks a law, the privilege is revoked and units with zero HP cannot be revived. Instead, KO'd units are sent to a temporary jail where they'll be released as soon as the battle ends.FACTAs part of the Ivalice Alliance, The re-release of Final Fantasy tactics on the PSP saw, added connections to other games. One being a cameo by Luso Clemens. After Ramza bumps into him and helps him out, He joins claiming that he's looking for his friends.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1520">Fire Emblem</game><game id="12869">Tactics Ogre: The Knight of Lodis</game><game id="11215">Shining Force: Resurrection of the Dark Dragon</game><game id="22933">Bleach: The 3rd Phantom</game><game id="21244">Super Robot Wars W</game><game id="23481">Front Mission 2089: Border of Madness</game><game id="22722">Disgaea DS</game><game id="22990">Blue Dragon Plus</game><game id="21400">Valkyrie Profile: Covenant of the Plume</game><game id="24220">Fire Emblem: Shadow Dragon</game><game id="21642">Knights in the Nightmare</game><game id="5239">Battles of Prince of Persia</game><game id="20300">Super Robot Taisen Original Generation</game><game id="11145">Super Robot Taisen Original Generation 2</game><game id="5534">Luminous Arc</game><game id="21163">Luminous Arc 2</game><game id="11939">Advance Wars: Dual Strike</game><game id="21626">Heroes of Mana</game><game id="14011">Hoshigami: Ruining Blue Earth</game><game id="14285">Age of Empires: The Age of Kings</game><game id="24380">Age of Empires: Mythologies</game><game id="17276">Rebelstar: Tactical Command</game><game id="21502">Song Summoner: The Unsung Heroes</game><game id="6483">Onimusha Tactics</game><game id="24252">Hero's Saga Laevatein Tactics</game><game id="27680">Luminous Arc 3</game><game id="27921">Mage Knight: Destiny's Soldier</game><game id="3368">Summon Night 2</game><game id="18876">Summon Night</game><game id="28180">Dawn of Heroes</game><game id="27338">Spectral Force Genesis</game><game id="9532">Disgaea: Afternoon of Darkness</game><game id="21640">Yggdra Union: We'll Never Fight Alone</game><game id="31423">Fire Emblem: Shin Monshou no Nazo - Hikari to Kage no Eiyuu</game><game id="27994">Final Fantasy Tactics: The War of the Lions</game><game id="32143">Tactics Ogre: Let Us Cling Together</game><game id="37054">Pokémon Conquest</game><game id="35687">Rainbow Moon</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1814648-box_ffta2.png</image></root>