<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2128</id><name>John Deere: American Farmer</name><description>Gameplay John Deere American Farmer is a sim game Where you purchase equipment and move them to a field you want to till seed or Harvest the plants from. You must purchase all the seed or animals and hope to get a return on your investments. You must know the right season to plant your crops or they will not grow and you would have wasted all that time and money. You must keep your workers happy or they will quit, you do this by buying better farm homes and entertainment ex: Trampolines, Swimming pools. When you save up enough money you can buy more land or buy better equipment to make money faster and require less workers, and there is an option to hire airplanes to come and cropdust your plants or you can invest in a tractor that spreads pesticide to save money in the long run Equipment In the game all the equipment available to purchase is from John Deere except for 1 Truck you start off with. There Is a Truck. Gator, small tractor, large tractor Pesticide Tractor, and many attachments for harvesting certain plants and tilling certain fields.   Recommended System RequirementsCPU: Pentium III 1GHz  RAM: 256MB  GPU: 32MB 32-bit Video Card compatible with DirectX 9.  OS: Windows XP</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10137">John Deere: American Builder Deluxe</game><game id="4768">Farmer's Daughter</game><game id="14186">Harvest Moon</game><game id="21055">Harvest Moon: Island of Happiness</game><game id="20929">Harvest Moon: Tree of Tranquility</game><game id="21486">Rune Factory: A Fantasy Harvest Moon</game><game id="2067">Harvest Moon: More Friends of Mineral Town</game><game id="12573">Harvest Moon DS</game><game id="6913">Harvest Moon: Back to Nature</game><game id="12010">Harvest Moon 64</game><game id="23920">Harvest Moon: Welcome to the Wind Bazaar</game><game id="28041">Farming Simulator 2009</game><game id="28050">Farming Simulator 2008</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/11/112064/1619891-john_deere___american_farmer_coverart.png</image></root>