<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21290</id><name>Tap Tap Revenge</name><description>Tap Tap Revenge is a free arcade-style musical-rhythm game for the iPhone and iPod touch that draws from various aspects of it's console predecessors.HistoryTap Tap Revenge was originally introduced to jail-broken iPhones/iPod Touches in Summer on 2007. Acquired and further developed by the Palo Alto-based Tapulous Inc, Tap Tap Revenge is the officially Apple-approved version of the game. It was originally titled "Tap Tap Revolution" as an obvious nod towards the oh-so-famous "Dance Dance Revolution" games.Currently, TTR is free on the iTunes Applications Store, and has remained at the top of the charts since it's July 11th 2008 release.GameplayTTR plays a lot like other famous rhythm games. There is a note "highway" consisting of three "beams" of light that start at the top of the screen. Little bubbles float down these beams to the bottom of the screen in rhythm with the included songs. The object of the game is to tap the bubbles when they hit the bottom area of the screen. There also is a second aspect of gameplay that requires you to shake the device left, right, or forward in rhythm, making use of the iPhone's accelerometer.There is also a local multiplayer mode in TTR. This involves one person sitting on each end of the device, with a separate 3-beam highway decending from the side opposite the player. Both players play the exact same notes head to head, and compete for the highest score.Extra ContentTTR features extra content in the form of free downloadable songs for the 4 difficulty levels. Many times there are new songs released every week. Each song is specific to the difficulty level it belongs, and most songs cannot be played on more than one difficulty.The developer, Tapulous, also has regular TTR tournaments, with the announcement and information automatically updating directly to the game if the user is online. These contests feature iTunes gift cards as prizes.Soundtrack (Including Downloadable Songs)Easy Tracksfa fa fa-Data RockFeel Good Drag-AnberlinLiquid Smog-BeccaTechnologic-Daft PunkMarimbini-DJ 4MileOxygenio-Electric FunkyLosin' It-FallbrookeShowtime-Florent LelongNever Miss a Beat-Kaiser ChefsDark Liquor-KewShe's a Killer- Lunar FictionHeartbreaker-MusicshakeTurn Yourself Around-Nick GallantDiscipline-Nine Inch Nails18 Days-Saving AbelFour Years-Senses FailThe One-Stroke 9I Wanna Know-Synthetic SinergyMedium TracksSad But True-BeccaWest Coast-Coconut RecordsTap Tap Tap-DJ TapulousLove Hertz-ElectroSynthesisMadrid-ErmoStone in My Hand-EverlastGrease Walk-GeCBetter Days-Jimmy KaneDirect Inuendo-Kai CherryGood Days Bad Days-Kaiser ChefsLookin' For a Good Time-Lady AntebellumFire-Lee PerryTap It Up-MatechaGoodbye Railroad-Nick GallantTurn Yourself Around-Nick GallantDay Like This-OnceWolves At the Door-Senses FailFull Moon-The Black GhostsIt's Good-The HumansGoldrush-TiestoTroublemaker-WeezerWe Wish You a Merry Christmas-WeezerInside Out-WexinHard TracksDon't Trust Me-3OH!3One Night Stand-Big City KidsThe Bomb-Bitter: SweetIn My Arms-BunkoheadBirthright-CelldwellerTechnologic-Daft PunkTap Tap Tap-DJ TapulousBlondie-Electric FunkyLosin' It-FallbrookeNever Miss a Beat-Kaiser ChefsHot N' Cold-Katy PerrySweet Thing-Keith UrbanSay Hey (I Love You)-Michael Franti  SpearheadDownload-MusicshakeRound the Bend-Nick GallantDiscipline-Nine Inch NailsGettin' Up-Q-Tip Featuring EveYou Better Pray-Red Jump Suit ApparatusLight it Up-Rev Theory18 Days-Saving AbelFamily Tradition-Senses FailThe One-Stroke 9Pure Dream-Synthetic SinergyYou're Gonna Go Far, Kid-The OffspringFlitchen-The Passive ResistanceGoldrush-TiestoRestless-TruroTroublemaker-WeezerExtreme TracksCliche-A Social PathThe Ice Dance-Bachelors of ScienceSwitchback-CelldwellerBlo-Hok-Claymation Horror ShowCannonfire-DJ 4MileSololuna-DJ 4MileOur Phoenix-DjadGood Days Bad Days-Kaiser ChefsSupernova-Q.N.D.Garden State-Senses FailLungs Like Gallows-Senses FailDisoriented-Wexin</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7477">Phase</game><game id="20673">Guitar Hero World Tour</game><game id="23613">Guitar Praise: Solid Rock</game><game id="9860">Rock Band</game><game id="20714">Rock Band 2</game><game id="14916">Guitar Hero II</game><game id="6311">Guitar Hero</game><game id="24594">Tap Tap Revenge: NIN Edition</game><game id="29073">Rock Band</game><game id="29945">Rhyme Player</game><game id="31632">Guitar Hero</game><game id="34039">Tap Tap Revenge 4</game><game id="35994">Tap Sonic</game><game id="36025">Groove Coaster</game><game id="40029">DJMAX Ray</game><game id="37671">Cytus</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/296/185977-2664640305_f8a4041b35.jpg</image></root>