<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21336</id><name>Dead Rising: Chop Till You Drop</name><description>DescriptionDead Rising: Chop Till You Drop is a Wii remake of the original Xbox 360 game. Capcom decided to port the game due to the critical success of Resident Evil 4: Wii Edition. Players take control of Frank West, a journalist who was dropped off at the Willamette Mall in Colorado to try and uncover the mystery behind a zombie outbreak. Frank can use almost anything in the environment to defend himself; such as chainsaws, lawn mowers, katanas, guitars, teddy bears and water guns. Largely the game is built off of the Wii Edition of Resident Evil 4. Most of the guns as well as the perspective and control style are borrowed. The game also features a new weapon upgrade system, also largely consisting of the same exact weapons from Resident Evil 4. Cletus now serves as the trader, allowing the player to buy and sell weapons and ammunition.Differences in the Wii VersionThe Wii version is mostly a direct port but there are some significant differences:Graphics and PerspectiveSince the Wii can not support the level of graphics and the number of zombies on screen of the Xbox 360 version, Capcom scaled back the number of zombies that could attack at once, but stated a hope to fit up to a hundred zombies on screen at once. The gameplay perspective has also shifted and enters an over-the-shoulder viewpoint similar to Resident Evil 4 when brandishing and using weapons.Story StructureThe story of Dead Rising: Chop Till You Drop is structured in a much different fashion from its original form. Instead of Otis contacting Frank and interrupting gameplay via the transceiver, the game takes on a more traditional approach. Otis presents the player with a few sub-missions, and once those are completed, the main story progresses, and a new series of missions are offered. The story is also no longer kept on a timer and will only progress as missions are completed, and Overtime Mode is now a part of the main story.ControlsFirearms controls function in a similar manner to Resident Evil 4: Wii Edition. The player can also ward off zombies with a shake of the Wii Remote. The Wii Remote can also be shook to swing melee weapons for more power than the standard button-press attack, but these attacks are slower and leave Frank vulnerable.Other ChangesThe photography element present in the original Dead Rising is absent, though Frank still carries his camera with him.Chop Til' You Drop features multiple save slots for the player to use, rather than the single save slot in the Xbox 360 version.The game features an adjustable difficulty setting.After the story is completed, the player can unlock some zombie-themed mini games.Bonus CharactersRad Spencer, the lead character of Bionic Commando, is available in the game as an unlockable character skin for Frank.</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13632">State of Emergency</game><game id="31992">Yakuza: Dead Souls</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2179474-box_drctyd.png</image></root>