<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21348</id><name>X-Blades</name><description>OverviewX-Blades is an action-adventure game for the PlayStation 3, Xbox 360 and Microsoft Windows PC's. The game was developed by Russian developer Gaijin Entertainment and published by SouthPeak Interactive in the US and TopWare Interactive in Europe. It was already released in December, 2007 by 1C Company in the Russian language only for Microsoft Windows PC's under the title Oniblade. The game gives you control of a scantily clad female heroine by the name of Ayumi, and she is a proficient gunblade user.The Japanese box art for the Playstation 3 and Xbox 360 only differs in the coverage provided by Ayumi's underwear. In the 360 version of the game, more exposed flesh is shown. Sony requested Gaijin to change the image a bit and Gaijin obliged.StoryAyumi is an adventurous relic hunter in search of an artifact believed to hold the fate of the world in its grasp. Hidden ages ago by a fearful king, the magical orb is the object of curiosity, ambition, and fear from those few who know of its existence. But there are those, like Ayumi, that would stop at nothing to harness the power of this orb and use it to gain fame, power, and fortune. Relying only on her fighting skill, pistol blades, and magical abilities, Ayumi must endure countless battles against creatures and other fortune-seekers determined to prevent her from escaping with the relic alive.GameplayWhen Ayumi isn't using her effective combat spells, she faces up to the enemy hordes with naked blades and explosive projectiles. Since the unique Gunblades are a combination of sword and pistol, the heroine can change her combat style lightning-fast. Surrounded by countless opponents, Ayumi uses both blades with deadly accuracy in hand-to-hand combat. She's well versed in various combat techniques - and she makes full use of them to cut her way through the ranks of the monsters. The player is rewarded with special finishing moves for carrying out particularly successful combos. However, Ayumi must first learn powerful attacking techniques by collecting hidden coin fragments throughout the levels. One three-piece set of these silver, gold or ruby artifacts releases a long-range or close combat upgrade.EndingsThere are two different endings in the video game X-blades. Depending on the player's actions during the game, the player will receive either a "good" or "evil" ending. There is not a separate ending for players who try to to go down a neutral path.Xbox 360 InstallationThe amount of memory it takes to install this game is 2.0 GB.PC System RequirementsOS: Windows XP SP 2/VistaProcessor: Pentium 4 @ 1.5 GHz or EquivalentMemory: 256 MB RAMGraphics: 128 MB (ATI Radeon/nVidia GeForce 6600)DirectX:9.0cHard Drive: 5 GB Free</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7876">Heavenly Sword</game><game id="6959">God of War</game><game id="11314">God of War II</game><game id="20694">Tomb Raider: Underworld</game><game id="8554">Lara Croft Tomb Raider: Legend</game><game id="21604">Onechanbara: Bikini Zombie Slayers</game><game id="6681">Devil May Cry 4</game><game id="890">Devil May Cry 3: Dante's Awakening</game><game id="20928">Golden Axe: Beast Rider</game><game id="39749">Ninja Gaiden 3: Razor's Edge</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2151667-box_xb.png</image></root>