<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21342</id><name>Wacky Races</name><description>StoryWacky Races follows the concept of the TV show of the same name in a    Mario Kart style racing game (closed tracks and power ups available) with the entire cast of the TV series. Wacky races allow players to play in both single player and cooperative mode through all the races and challenges as well as support for 3-4 players.    When starting a new story, players pick one of the following vehicles and use that for the duration of the game, i.e. switching vehicles is not allowed throughout the story.     Dick Dastardly and  Muttley in the Mean Machine (Race Car # 00) Lazy Luke and Blubber Bear in the Arkansas Chuggabug (Race Car # 8) The Gruesome Twosome with  Rufus Ruffcut  vying for 2nd place  Penelope Pitstop in the Compact Pussycat (Race Car # 5) Peter Perfect in the Turbo Terrific (Race Car # 9) Professor Pat Pending in the Convert a Car (Race Car # 3)  Red Max in the Crimson Haybailer (Race Car # 4)  Rufus Ruffcut and Sawtooth in the Buzzwagon (Race Car # 10)           Sergeant Blast and Private Meekly in the Army Surplus Special (Race Car # 6) The Ant Hill Mob in the Bulletproof Bomb (Race Car # 7) The Gruesome Twosome in the Creepy Coupe (Race Car #2) The Slag Brothers in the Bouldermobile (Race Car # 1)    Wacky races takes place in a hub world where all races can be entered by driving to a small, themed section within the hub world similar to Diddy Kong Racing. Players must complete challenges and races in order to unlock stars which lead to races against the “boss’s” within the game Namely Pat Pending, Red Max and Dick Dastardly.    Successfully winning against a boss character unlocks that vehicle for use in the single player or cooperative story but cannot be switched to when through a portion of the game as with the rest of the cars.  Race LocationsAll race tracks within Wacky Races take place in the 4 following locations within the hub world, each a parody of a real life location.  Wild FrontierWild Frontier is a desert packed with stereotypical locations for driving around in such as an oil mine and the Wild West towns that surround it.    Oil be Back  Tombstone      Pass Los      Angle Tease Square  Railway      Canyon   Manic Mines    Snowfall PeaksIn contrast to Wild Frontier, Snowfall Peaks is the wintry location within Wacky Races with races usually taking place in and around snowy mountains and caverns.  Snow      La Costa Snow      Hope Village Gruesome      Towers  Glacier      Lake  Ice Caverns   Redwood ValleyRedwood Valley is the balance between the two locations above taking place in a lush forest as with races taking place around a lumberjack mill and sprawling fields for example.  Lumberjack      Lake  Scarecrow      Creek  Wood      Stockade Redwood      Springs Rush      More Rapids   The Big ApricotA deliberate pun on New York City, The Big Apricot is another contrast to the nature of Redwood Valley, taking place in key locations within a bustling modern day city such as a shipyard, an airport terminal and on rooftops of tall skyscrapers.    Fish      'n' Ships Subway      Shenanigans Alone      in the Park  Terminal      Turmoil  Rooftop      RunaroundGameplay Throughout the game the player will participate in a variety of race types including:   Track challengesStandard time based races where players must compete against other drivers and achieve first place within the time limit for that track.   Wacky Cup ChallengesTournament style challenges in which points are awarded based on the place the player finishes in e.g. 10 points for 1 place, 6 points for 2 place etc.   Golden Mutley ChallengesThese challenges operate in a similar manner to normal time based races with the one exception that the player must also collect 10 golden Mutley statuettes scattered around the race track in addition to finishing in first place.   Battle ChallengesBattle royal style challenges in which each driver is given 3 “lives” and must drive around in a closed area, attacking other players to reduce the number of lives they have whilst trying to retain their own.   Team 00 Tag ChallengesElimination style challenges that operate like normal races except the driver in last place on each lap is eliminated until only one driver is left.   Throughout the game each wacky racer also has access to their own uniquely styled gadgets which operate around the following themes.   Boost – Gives the driver a temporary acceleration boost   Flying – Allows the driver to float above the ground for a short period of time.   Missles – When fired, lock on to the nearest driver in front and cause them to spin 360 degrees.  Mine – Deploys a mine that detonates if a competing player drives over it   Shields – Prevents any damage from being taken when used.   Sticky Traps – Causes any driver that runs over the trap to be temporarily immobilised. </description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26848">ModNation Racers</game><game id="20622">Wacky Races: Crash &amp; Dash</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2154890-box_wraces.png</image></root>