<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2136</id><name>Onimusha: Dawn of Dreams</name><description>Overview Onimusha: Dawn of Dreams is the 4th main installment to the                Onimusha series. However the main character this time around will be "  Sōki" based on real life person Yūki Hideyasu who was Tokugawa Ieyasu's second son.  One of the main changes from its predecessor was the full use of the camera, however in a few areas the camera is locked. Again just like in                Onimusha 3: Demon Seige the game uses full 3D rendered backgrounds as apposed to pre-rendered backgrounds used in the first two games. The game includes Japanese voice overs if the player wishes to change that, this feature was only included in the original               Onimusha before the release of Dawn of Dreams. Even in the Japanese Onimusha: Dawn of Dreams the option for both text and voice in English are available.You are also able to change things from              Subtitles to having  green blood.Take control of multiple Characters  Gameplay A big change to the series is that another character can be controlled during gameplay, you can easily switch between which character you want to control. The AI will control the other character and does a fairly decent job but they can also follow certain commands which can be issued through the D-pad. A shop system is also available where players can buy new weapons as well as upgrade them, you can buy accessories which gives the player certain advantages depending on what they use and they can also purchase other items like medicine. You can even gain new skills and improve them throughout the game. The game has quite a lot of RPG elements in it you will be able to increase, your characters level,             HP,            MP, OP to improve your character. When you kill an enemy you can absorb their soul you can later use these souls to upgrade your weapons.  Story  Onimusha: Dawn of Dreams takes place about fifteen years after the defeat of                Nobunaga Oda from the end of                Onimusha 3: Demon Seige.           Hideyoshi Toyotomi who is Nobunaga's vassal takes over the country,  unifying it under one banner and basically ending the wars that had torn the land apart under his former lord's banner. But this piece doesn't last very long when natural disasters keep occurring acting as an omen of things to come which includes an "Omen Star" appearing in the sky.A lot of rumors started spreading across the country that the  Genma are going to return and that Hideyoshi  has something to do with it.    Characters                Sōki - Hideyasu Yuki A powerful samurai who has the power of the Dark Oni.  Standard SōkiThrough the game he is called many different things from Sōki, Hideyasu Yuki, Blue Demon, God of Darkness and the Oni of the Ash. Once he learns what Hideyoshi is doing he sets off on a journey to burn the Genma trees and kill the Genma that are running wild across the country. While on his travels a creature by the name of Minokichi helps Sōki on his quest.He gives Sōki information on different creaturesSōki with Street Fighter "Ryu" costumeand places they traverse and talk about your allies who you will eventually meet, he is also able to use instant teleport travel. Sōki's voice was done by                David Berón for the English version and Toshiyuki Kusuda for the Japanese version of the game.                Jubei - Akane Yagyu A young woman who carries on the name of the famous Yagyu clan. Standard JubeiJubei has amazing skills and she even has the Eye of the Oni.Jubei or also known as Akane is assigned to kill former clan member and relative Munenori Yagyu as he has betrayed and killed members of the Yagyu clan.She is known for using a  shikomizue. A weapon famously used by the fictional swordmaster  Zatoichi. Jubei with Street Fighter "Cammy White" costumeJubei's voice was done by         B.J. Ward for the English version and Yukana Nogami for the Japanese version of the game.                Ohatsu Younger sister to Lady Yodo who is the royal concubine to Hideyoshi Toyotomi. Standard OhatsuOhatsu is a fantastic marksman, she can use techniques similar to those of her mentors, Magoichi Saika who is in                Onimusha 2. She is the daugter of Oyu who is also from Onimusha 2. Ohatsu can use different kind of firearms, explosives and even a grapple hook. Ohatsu's voice was done by                Nika Futterman for the English version and Sanae Kobayashi for theOhatsu with Street Fighter "Chun-Li" costume Japanese version of the game.                Roberto Frois His mother is Japanese his father is Spanish, he is a Christian missionary. Standard RobertoHe was betrayed by his adopted and demonically possessed father, Luís Fróis. Roberto is a magnificent fighter he uses his enchanced arms and fists and is able to do various boxing style techniques. His theme tune also contains a small guitar sample from the first mission of                Devil May Cry 3 and in missions 13-15. Roberto's gaunlets are based on the Christian archangel's, Raphael, Uriel and Michael.Roberto with Street Fighter "Guile" costumeAlthough he appears to have a tough exterior, deep inside he's a romantic as you will discover the book he was reading was "Romeo and Juliet". Roberto and Ohatsu have their moments in the game. Roberto's voice was done by Juan Monsalvez for the English version and Wataru Hatano for the Japanese version of the game.  Tenkai Nankobo A mysterious monk who makes his home high upon Mt. Hiei. Original TenkaiHe has sensed the stirrings of evil and has started on a quest. Eventually he discovers Hideyoshi's intentions. During the games end credits it is revealed that Tenkai is actually                Samanosuke Akechi. Tenkai's voice was done by                Josh Keaton for the English version and Hideo Ishikawa for the Japanese version of the game. Tenkai with Street Fighter "Ken" costume Enemies Neo Fortinbras        Hideyoshi Toyotomi Hideyoshi ToyotomiHideyoshi's voice was done by Tôru Ôkawa for the Japanese version of the game. Claudius - Mitsunari Ishida Mitsunari IshidaMitsurari's voice was done by       Alastair Duncan for the English version and      Norio Wakamoto for the Japanese version of the game. Ophelia - Lady Yodo Yodo's voice was done by Mari Yokô for the Japanese version of the game. Rosencrantz - Luis Frois Luis' voice was done by     Masaharu Satō for the Japanese version of the game. Munenori Yagyu Munenori YagyuMunenori's voice was done by    Josh Keaton for the English version and Keiji Fujiwara for the Japanese version of the game. Sakon Shima Sakon's voice was done by Kenta Miyake for the Japanese version of the game. Ban Danemon Ban's voice was done by Shōzō Iizuka for the Japanese version of the game. Armored Soldier Armored Soldier Genma Warrior Genma Warrior Controls Click Image to view ControlsTriangle - Oni Magic Circle - Examine X - Absorb SoulsSquare - AttackStart - Pause / Sub ScreenSelect - Map D-Pad - Issue Command R3 - Click to Reset CameraL1 - GuardL2 - Character ChangeR1 - Ready / Focus on EnemyR2 - Secret Technique R1 Circle : KickL3 R3 : Oni AwakeningHold Triangle to charge to Level 3 followed by L2 for a co-op attack Partner Commands D-Pad Up - All out AttackD-Pad Down - Wait and RecoverD-Pad Right - Follow and AttackD-Pad Left - Special Order (Different for each character) Skills  Soki's SkillsStandardHold R1 while performing each skillWhirlwind - Back, Forward Square Sōki will step forward with a spinning horizontal attack that will lead into an overhead strike. Thrust - Forward Square Sōki will stab in front of him. Blade Jab - Forward Square during "Thrust" Sōki moves closer to the enemy and pulls off a multiple hitting stab. Lift - Back Square Sōki uppercuts the enemy. Slam - Forward Square during "Lift" Sōki will do a shoulder slam, you can do this up to 3 times for each lift. Finisher - Square near a downed enemySōki stabs the enemy with his sword while they are laid out, press Square to push the sword deeper into the enemy.H.Splitter - Square X Sōki will put his sword in the air and attack with a overhead strike. Kick - Circle Sōki will kick the enemy it can also knock them to the ground. Phoenix - Forward, Back SquareSōki will jump and attack horitontally to the ground. Secret Technique - Sword of Purification Coil - R2 Sōki's purifying sword will spin around him and hit any nearby enemies. Stab - Forward R2Sōki will throw the purifying sword infront of him.Flight - Back R2Sōki will slightly throw the sword forward before thrusting it into the ground.Oni Awakening - Onimusha Transformation When Sōki is in Oni form every attack that he does will draw out their souls and automatically absorb them. Oni Cutter - TriangleSōki attacking with one of his many movesThis move will take the place of the usual Oni Magic while Soki is transformed.  This uppercut attack will hit multiple times.Special OrderAbsorb Souls - D-Pad Left while controlling another characterSōki will stand still and absorb all the souls within distance Jubei's Skills Standard Hold R1 while performing each skillFlurry - Square X Thrust - Forward SquareChaser - Forward Square during "Thrust" Lift - Back SquareRising Dragon - Back, Forward Square Finisher - Square near a downed enemy, press Square again to push the sword deeper into the enemy.Moon Blade - Back, Forward Square Kick - CircleTheir size and shape don't matter because none shall stand in your wayCresent - Square as kick hitsSpecial Attack - Quick Draw Beacon - R2Skim - Forward R2Pinwheel - Back R2Oni Awakening - Demon Eye Everyone except for Jubei will move really slowly once transformed. Shadow Cast - Triangle Special Order Distract Enemy - D-Pad Left while controlling another character Ohatsu's Skills Standard Hold R1 while performing each skill Charge up - Hold Square Thrust - Forward SquareR.Kick - Forward, Back Square Lift - Back Square Meteor Drop - Square X Finisher - Square near a downed enemy Fireworks - Back, Forward Square Kick - Circle Stinger - Forward Square during "Kick" Special Attack - Explosives Gunpowder - R2Bomb Toss - Forward R2 Time Bomb - Back R2 Oni Awakening - Demon Blood Demon Shots - Triangle Special Order Cover Fire - D-Pad Left while controlling another character Roberto's Skills  Standard Hold R1 while performing each skill Hook Storm - Square while swaying left to right in a guard position, keep tapping Square to keep punching and press X to dash. Body Blow - Forward Square Top Spin - Forward Square during "Body Blow" or Back, Forward Square Uppercut - Back Square Flare-up - Back Square during "Uppercut" or Forward, Back Square Finisher - Square near a downed enemy Nova - Hold Square Kick - Circle Strikedown - Square X Special Attack - Death Grip Throw - R2 Yank - Forward R2, Square Overflow - Back R2, Square repeatedly Oni Awakening - Exorcising Fist Every attack Roberto does using Square he will make into a high hit combo High Rush - Triangle  Special OrderBerserk - D-Pad Left while controlling another character Tenkai's SkillsStandard  Hold R1 while performing each skillF. Drill - Back, Forward SquareThrust - SquareHell Jab - Forward Square during "Thrust" tab Square to keep stabbingLift - SquareNirvana - Forward Square during "Lift" keep tapping to keep stabbing or you can tap slowly to end the combo with a powerful attackFinisher - Square near a downed enemyThunderclap - Square XKick - Circle Enlightenment - Forward, Back Square, tap Square to keep spinning his SpearSpecial Attack - Art of PurificationCharm - R2Enchanted Dagger - Forward, R2Space Warp - Back, R2Oni Awakening - Oni GauntletLight Arrows - Triangle   Special OrderPray - D-Pad Left while controlling another character Soundtrack The games music is composed by Hideyuki Fukasawa and Jamie Christopherson. Hideyuki Fukasawa did most of the in-game music and soundtracks. He also worked on the music of                Chaos Legion and it shows as there are quite a few similarities.  You will see a lot of great CGI clips Jamie Christopherson on the other hand worked on the CG cut scenes and FMV's Hollywood-style orchestral scores.  The type of music in this game is quite different to any other in the series as more electronic tones are used.                Ayumi Hamasaki the famous Japanese pop singer has two of her songs in the game "Startin'" and "Rainy Day" for the opening and ending themes for the game. However if played on the normal English setting this will not be heard, but the player can select the Japanese language from the options menu and it will play identically to the Japanese version of the game. MangaThere are 2 manga's based around Onimusha: Dawn of Dreams, Onimusha: Night Of Genesis which has 2 volumes and Onimusha: Twilight Of Desire. Both of which are published by                Udon Entertainment. Onimusha: Night Of Genesis Volume 1Onimusha: Night of Genesis by Mitsuru Ohsaki Volume 1 was released in Japan on 12-22-2005 Volume 2 was released in Japan on 06-28-2006 Onimusha: Twilight of Desire Onimusha: Twilight Of Desire by Takashi Yaguchi Released in Japan on 01-23-2006</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16741">Devil May Cry 2</game><game id="13072">Devil May Cry</game><game id="7750">Tenchu: Return from Darkness</game><game id="890">Devil May Cry 3: Dante's Awakening</game><game id="6681">Devil May Cry 4</game><game id="18546">Ninja Gaiden Sigma</game><game id="20553">Ninja Gaiden II</game><game id="6602">Ninja Gaiden Black</game><game id="19998">Tenchu: Dark Secret</game><game id="14034">Rygar: The Legendary Adventure</game><game id="20131">Otogi: Myth of Demons</game><game id="15569">Genji: Days of the Blade</game><game id="20710">Bayonetta</game><game id="32687">Ninja Gaiden 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2115769-box_onimusha4.png</image></root>