<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21380</id><name>Prince of Persia: The Two Thrones</name><description>PlotThe Two Thrones continues right after the true ending of Warrior Within. After killing the Dahaka and altering Kaileena's fate, he boards a ship to return to Babylon. As Babylon nears in site, the Prince is horrified that the city is burning and being torn apart by war. His ship is attacked and the pair is thrown overboard, and Kaileena is captured upon reaching shore. The Prince must go on one more adventure to thwart the Vizier and his army sand monsters from becoming immortal and destroying all of Babylon.GameplayThe gameplay in The Two Thrones was tweaked a bit. It sports a few new features, primarily in combat. If The Prince stealthily sneaks up on an opponent, he can preform a 'speed kill'. A minigame of button pressing that will down the enemy in one blow. If the game is failed, The Prince must battle the enemy.One of many bossesAnother new feature is the Prince's split personality. Affected by the sands of time, The Prince will transform into The Dark Prince, a black being corrupted by the sands of time. As the Dark Prince, players get a new weapon known as the Daggertail, a chain-like blade. Also, the player continually loses health, which he can replenish by collecting sands from fallen foes, or by stepping into water to revert to the Prince.A chariot racing minigame was also added. Players must avoid crashing into walls, while fending off enemy chariots and soldiers who jump on to your vehicle.DevelopmentUbisoft Montreal stated that they wanted Prince of Persia: The Two Thrones to be a blend of the two previous titles ( Sands of Time was light in tone while Warrior Within was much darker in tone).A censored version was later released in North America that removed decapitation.Sword CodesOn the Pause Screen enter the following code:Left, Left, Right, Right, X, Y, Y, X, Up, Down : Baby Toy of DeathUp, Up, Down, Down, Left, Right, Left, Right, X, Y, X, Y : ChainsawAfter completing the game on Normal: Right, Left, Right, Left, Down, Down, Up, Up, X, Y, X, X, Y, Y :Telephone of SorrowUp, Down, Up, Down, Left, Right, Left, Right, X, Y, X and Y : Unlocks Swordfish WeaponSystem RequirementsSupported OS: Windows® 2000/XP (only)Processor: 1.0 GHz AMD Athlon or Intel Pentium III (1.5 GHz Pentium IV or AMD Athlon recommended)Memory: 256 MB (512 MB recommended)Graphics:32 MB DirectX 9.0c compliant (128 MB recommended) (see supported list*)DirectX: DirectX 9.0cSound DirectX 9.0c compliant (Dolby Digital Live required for Dolby Digital audio)Hard Drive:1.5 GBPeripherals: Windows-compatible gamepad*Supported video cards at time of retail release: ATI 7500/8500/9000/X series, NVIDIA GeForce 3/4/FX/6/7 series (GeForce 4 MX not supported); Laptop versions of these chipsets may work but are not supported. For an up-to-date list of supported chipsets, video cards, and operating systems, please visit the FAQ for this game at: http://support.ubi.com.SoundtrackThe soundtrack was composed by Stuart Chatwood and was released by Ubisoft Music in December 2005, along with Chatwood's music from Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time and Prince of Persia: Warrior Within, as part of Prince of Persia: The Official Trilogy Soundtrack.Prince of Persia: The Official Trilogy Soundtrack (Stuart Chatwood, Inon Zur)No.Track TitleLength (46:53)1."The Sands of Time"1:342."Welcome to Persia"2:383."A Princess Is Captured"1:024."The Sands Are Captured"1:015."Trouble in the Barracks"1:006."Farah"1:577."The Library"2:268."Time Only Knows"3:269."Warrior Within - 01"3:2310."Warrior Within - 02"2:0911."Warrior Within - 03"0:2712."Warrior in Despair"2:0913."Warrior and the Dahaka"1:1214."The Dahaka's Demise"1:4815."Kaileena Free from Fate"2:4416."The Two Thrones - CH - 01"4:2717."The Two Thrones - CH - 02"4:2218."The Two Thrones - CH - 03"3:5319."The Two Thrones - CH - 04"5:15</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12710">Onimusha 3: Demon Siege</game><game id="9088">Onimusha: Warlords</game><game id="7750">Tenchu: Return from Darkness</game><game id="8201">Lara Croft Tomb Raider: Anniversary</game><game id="19861">Onimusha 2: Samurai's Destiny</game><game id="20694">Tomb Raider: Underworld</game><game id="20553">Ninja Gaiden II</game><game id="18546">Ninja Gaiden Sigma</game><game id="6602">Ninja Gaiden Black</game><game id="21876">Ninja Gaiden</game><game id="8554">Lara Croft Tomb Raider: Legend</game><game id="1653">Ninja Gaiden</game><game id="1850">Ninja Gaiden III: The Ancient Ship of Doom</game><game id="22928">Assassin's Creed II</game><game id="6959">God of War</game><game id="10983">Kingdom Hearts</game><game id="25551">Totems</game><game id="28080">Enslaved: Odyssey to the West</game><game id="31001">Assassin's Creed: Brotherhood</game><game id="21213">Mirror's Edge</game><game id="29284">Tron: Evolution</game><game id="4443">TMNT</game><game id="30636">Garshasp: The Monster Slayer</game><game id="37494">Assassin's Creed III</game><game id="2950">Assassin's Creed</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2280504-box_popttt.png</image></root>