<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21436</id><name>TrackMania Nations Forever</name><description>OverviewTrackmania Nations Forever is a free version of Trackmania which was a released as a replacement for Trackmania Nations ESWC . It is available for download from the official Trackmania website or over Valve's Steam service and features over 100 tracks along with a track editor which allows for the creation of custom tracks. Along with an update to its physics engine, to correlate with the release of Trackmania United Forever, this new version features a heavy focus on online play, a built-in forum system, track exchange, and leaderboards based on worldwide and local players. Players with a Trackmania account can log in and play through the avaiable tracks on official mode, which lets the player try to get a gold, silver, or bronze medal on the specified track which awards them with coppers. Coppers can be used to purchase other tracks, replays of the top players, or attempts to get a better official time as the first attempt is free but subsequent attempts cost 10 coppers.EnvironmentsStadiumThe stadium mode is the only mode that has been released for free in the Trackmania Nations ESWC or Trackmania Nations Forever downloadable game. It is driven with a car that is a mix of a Formula-1 and a dirty buggy, which comes in a color scheme matching the flag of the country the player controlling it set as his/her home. The environment itself is contained within a very large stadium which can be modified by track creators to include dirt or water areas. The stadium consists of the track area which begins as a flat grassy area before a track is built on it, and the empty stands surrounding it. Unlike other environments in the Trackmania series, there is very little environment outside the track area.Track Types Tracks are created using an in-game tile-based editor, which allows track creators the freedom to combine regular track pieces with dirt, water and grass sections. More creative tracks also have players racing along the sides of buildings and other pieces of scenery. Although there are some restrictions on where track can be placed to help tracks maintain some form of realism (i.e., grass can only be placed on the ground) or to keep track pieces from clipping, programs exist to allow track creators to expand the capabilities of the editor and create truly unique track layouts.Tracks are created from several types of materials, with dirt and asphalt being the main components. Asphalt provides good grip for precise racing, and dirt provides a much looser experience. Drivers can also race on the grass, which provides low acceleration and grip.Tracks can also have boost pads which increase the player's speed, and free-wheeling sections which cut out the player's engine until the next checkpoint. Obstacles are provided by the track editor in prefabricated pieces, although track creators also design their own obstacles out of scenery pieces. Large jumps, corkscrews and wallrides can be created easily using preset pieces and using scenery pieces as well.System RequirementsSupported OS: Windows 2000/XP/XP-x64/VistaProcessor: Pentium IV 1.6GHz / AthlonXP 1600Graphics: 3D accelerator 16 MB DirectX 9.0c compatible graphics cardDirectX Version: DirectX 9.0c or betterMemory: 256 MB (512 MB with Vista)Sound: 16 bit DirectX compatible sound cardHard Drive: 750 MB free disk space</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9060">Rollcage</game><game id="20610">WipEout HD</game><game id="15918">Stunts</game><game id="3113">GripShift</game><game id="25041">Street Gears</game><game id="29220">Zero Gear</game><game id="28484">Joe Danger</game><game id="3202">Stunt GP</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5872/192398-tmnfbox.jpg</image></root>