<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21454</id><name>Majesty 2: The Fantasy Kingdom Sim</name><description>OverviewMajesty 2 continues the series in the world of Ardania. The franchise's primary feature as an RTS is its indirect control of units. Instead of being directly controlled, units are bribed by bounties that the player places for certain actions. Units (called heroes) act as players would in a traditional RPG. Heroes will go on missions, gain experience, level up, collect bounties, and buy equipment at shops the player builds. This money will in turn be collected by tax collector's hired by the player and will return to the king's coffers to be spent again. Heroes have their own personalities uncontrollable by the player. Some heroes will be lazy and prefer to only complete nearby objectives, some will spend their money at taverns, while others will do their king's bidding diligently.Additions to Majesty 2New FlagsIn the original Majesty, the player influences heroes' movements by setting attack and exploration flags. Setting an Attack Flag on an enemy causes your kingdom's heroes to attack that enemy in an attempt to win the bounty associated with said flag. Setting an Exploration Flag causes the heroes to explore that area and collect the bounty. In Majesty 2, the Protection and Fear flags are introduced. The Protection Flag can be placed on a unit. Part of the money you assign to that flag will then go to every hero that protects that unit. The Fear Flag is meant to keep low level heroes out of places where they will be killed. Setting a Fear flag frightens heroes away from that area. The level of the hero scared by the Fear Flag is directly proportional to the amount of money assigned to the flag, i.e. a low amount of gold will scare away low level characters, and a large amount of gold will scare away higher level characters.PartiesMajesty 2 introduces the traditional party system found in RPGs. Heroes can now form parties and adventure together in groups. Heroes in groups will be able to realize their full potential. For instance, a warrior grouped with a healer will not have to worry so much about health and the healer won't have to worry about offense/tanking damage. As the player's heroes rise in levels, they will will gain special abilities designed uniquely for teamwork. Parties will be formed at taverns. The player will announce the formation of a party at a tavern and heroes will gather with LFG icons above their heads. The player than chooses up to four heroes to form a party. The party will act and move as one unit until either they are disbanded by the player or are all killed.LordshipHeroes cannot pass from one mission to another. However, after completing each mission, the player can grant one of his heroes the title of Lord. That hero will then be available for hire in later missions. Throughout the campaign, the player will build up a list of lords, but only one lord can be hired per mission. Lords will carry over their experience and equipment from previous missions and their hiring price will increase proportionally. Later, the player will be able to build a special Hall of Lords that will allow the hiring of two lords in a mission instead of one.Great ArtifactsAfter beating missions, the player will receive Great Artifacts. These Great Artifacts include the Scepter, the Orb, the Crown, and the Mantle with each relic having its own power. For instance, the Scepter harnesses a powerful offensive spell while the Orb can be used to heal all of the player's heroes.MapsMaps are no longer generated randomly as they were in the original Majesty. Each map is now uniquely created and balanced by hand.  System RequirementsMinimumRecommendedOS: Windows XP/VistaProcessor: 2.0GHz dual core processorMemory: 1 GB RAMGraphics: GeForce 6800 GTX 512MB or better, Pixel Shader 2.0DirectX®: 9.0Hard Drive: 4 GB free Sound: DirectX-compatibleOS: Windows XP/VistaProcessor: 3.0GHz dual core processorMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: GeForce GTX 280 1GB or better, Pixel Shader 2.0DirectX®: 9.0Hard Drive: 4 GB free Sound: DirectX-compatible</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4736">SimCity 4</game><game id="12474">Black &amp; White 2</game><game id="21594">Slaves to Armok II: Dwarf Fortress</game><game id="20648">Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles: My Life as a King</game><game id="22003">A Kingdom for Keflings</game><game id="10812">Beasts &amp; Bumpkins</game><game id="17620">Dungeon Keeper</game><game id="19042">Dungeon Keeper: The Deeper Dungeons</game><game id="28310">The Settlers 7: Paths to a Kingdom</game><game id="32326">Tropico 4</game><game id="8460">Diggles: the Myth of Fenris</game><game id="17680">Pharaoh</game><game id="738">Black &amp; White 2: Battle of the Gods</game><game id="1128">The Settlers II: 10th Anniversary</game><game id="3642">The Settlers II: 10th Anniversary - Vikings</game><game id="16757">Tropico: Paradise Island</game><game id="24458">Tropico 3</game><game id="14638">Northland</game><game id="1489">8th Wonder of the World</game><game id="7965">Tropico 2: Pirate Cove</game><game id="11466">CivCity: Rome</game><game id="6645">Caesar III</game><game id="5652">Caesar II</game><game id="12757">Tropico</game><game id="30573">Tropico 3: Absolute Power</game><game id="4102">Emperor: Rise of the Middle Kingdom</game><game id="18721">Cultures</game><game id="19132">Cultures 2: The Gates of Asgard</game><game id="5457">Cultures: Die Abenteuerbox</game><game id="4820">Dungeon Keeper 2</game><game id="32175">Dungeon Keeper 3</game><game id="3009">Immortal Cities: Children of the Nile</game><game id="18623">Black &amp; White</game><game id="14823">Black &amp; White: Creature Isle</game><game id="6210">Populous</game><game id="10562">Populous II: Trials of the Olympian Gods</game><game id="15960">Evil Genius</game><game id="5211">Zeus Official Expansion: Poseidon</game><game id="3769">Zeus: Master of Olympus</game><game id="9828">The Settlers: Rise of an Empire – The Eastern Realm</game><game id="2815">The Settlers: Rise of an Empire</game><game id="22372">The Settlers IV: The Trojans and the Elixir of Power</game><game id="22371">The Settlers IV: Mission CD</game><game id="16829">The Settlers II: Veni, Vidi, Vici</game><game id="3449">The Settlers II Mission CD</game><game id="15294">The Settlers III: Quest of the Amazons</game><game id="10978">The Settlers III</game><game id="2081">The Settlers II</game><game id="6946">The Settlers: Fourth Edition</game><game id="12922">The Settlers</game><game id="37574">Towns</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2331131-box_mj2.png</image></root>