<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21468</id><name>Time Crisis 4</name><description>OverviewJoin operatives Giorgio Bruno and Evan Bernard to investigate and prevent a top secret weapon from falling into the hands of international terrorists!Now, the most advanced game in the stellar Time Crisis series arrives on the PlayStation 3, delivering totally immersive, intense gameplay. Time Crisis 4 is reborn, and includes a full FPS game mode, stunning HD quality graphics and a newly designed Guncon to enhance every aspect of the game. Superior to its arcade counterpart, Time Crisis 4 brings a fresh new look to launch the series into the next generation.Next Generation Guncon – The most advanced Guncon ever, redesigned specifically to enhance next-gen gameplay.New dual analog stick design- Change camera angles, switch out weapons and control your character’s movement, including crouching and jumping.Full compatibility with all displays- Enjoy the adrenaline pumping action in HD quality graphics whether you have an LCD, plasma or widescreen display. (Also supports Standard Definition displays)FPS mode – Exclusive to the console version and entirely new to the Time Crisis universe, roam freely as a new, console exclusive playable character, and experience FPS style gameplay in 5 new stages.Multiple modes – Time Crisis 4 delivers intense-action in numerous modes of play including:Full Mission – Play through a combination of original stages and brand new FPS stages.Arcade - Experience arcade action in your very own living room!Crisis Missions - The popular Crisis Missions are back and more exciting than ever, now with new tactical missions! Destroy biological weapons and complete other objectives requiring the utmost in stealth and precision.Mini Games - Test your sharp shooting skills and complete your objective within seconds, or go head-to-head with a friend in a variety of challenging mini games.Upgraded Arsenal – In addition to your standard weapons assortment, such as handguns and shotguns, upgrade to grenade launchers and mounted machine guns (FPS mode only) to increase your lethal arsenal. Also features unlockable console exclusive bonus weapons. Select your weapon and be prepared to assault enemies from every direction.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre><genre id="35">Light-Gun Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4751">Point Blank 3</game><game id="9281">Point Blank</game><game id="11427">Point Blank 2</game><game id="16619">Point Blank DS</game><game id="19246">Vampire Night</game><game id="15008">Confidential Mission</game><game id="20460">Target: Terror</game><game id="16218">Battle Clash</game><game id="10543">Virtua Cop</game><game id="2817">Corpse Killer</game><game id="23055">The House of the Dead EX</game><game id="20519">Ghost Squad</game><game id="3484">Metal Combat: Falcon's Revenge</game><game id="24089">Rambo</game><game id="23425">The House of the Dead: OVERKILL</game><game id="26890">America's Army</game><game id="27854">Paradise Lost</game><game id="29602">Nerf: N-Strike Elite</game><game id="30164">2 Spicy</game><game id="30607">Ranger Mission</game><game id="27102">Terminator Salvation</game><game id="35407">Deadstorm Pirates</game><game id="13495">Major Mayhem</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1832168-box_tc4.png</image></root>