<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21463</id><name>Final Fantasy III</name><description>OverviewOn April 27, 1990 Final Fantasy III went on sale in Japan. A different ‘Final Fantasy III’ would be released in the United states some time later for the Super Nintendo, making for a confusing turn of events for US gamers when this game was released there over 15 years later. A 3D remake for the Nintendo DS released in late 2006 in the US and early 2007 in PAL territories marked the first time players outside of Japan could officially get their hands on Final Fantasy III.The over worldAfter a tremendous earthquake by the small Town of Ur ripped open a mountain, 4 characters who lived there went there in search of adventure. They found it in the form of a Wind Crystal which had been buried away. This crystal and those like it that they would find later discover gave them new ‘Jobs’, each of which holding unique powers for them to develop and explore. They would utilize these powers to balance the forces of Good and Evil, of Light and Dark, because should this uneasy truce between the two be disrupted the world would be in great peril. The Job system was fairly elaborate. They included the Scholar, Conjurer, Archer, Viking, Magic Knight, Sage, Bard, Summoner, Geomancer... all of which were entirely new to Final Fantasy.In the past when the Light was threatening to overtake the world 4 Dark Warriors emerged and cut a swath of destruction. In the present these characters now work for the Light, hopefully to once again restore balance to a world now threatened by the Darkness. The Cloud of Darkness was the nihilistic mastermind behind the world’s descent, and the game’s ultimate foe.SummonsSummons could be bought in stores, but more satisfyingly defeated in battle and bent to the party’s service. Conjurers and Summoners lived up to their name allowing for Godlike beings to step into a battle and deal massive damage for the party while they were whisked away totally protected from the effects.These early Summons originally didn’t have much of a back story, but were a critical new innovation to the franchise as a whole. Odin, Ramuh, Shiva, Ifrit, Titan, Bahamut, and the Leviathan were now available for use, all of which are names of gods or forces of pure power. Shiva is worshiped even today in the oldest sect of Hinduism as the supreme divine force.Final Fantasy III DSFinal Fantasy III DSFirst announced on October 24, 2004, Final Fantasy III DS was a full remake of the original game, with a new 3D style based on artwork by Akihiko Yoshida and new main characters replacing the blank Onion Knights (or Freelancers) in the old game. The remake was produced by Square Enix's Tomoya Asano and developed by both Square Enix and Matrix Software. This version of Final Fantasy III marks the first time this game left Japan, launching in America on November 14, 2006. A HD version of this was also released on iOS on March 24, 2011 and for Android on June 27, 2012.TriviaBahamut made his first appearance as a summon in this game.This was the first Final Fantasy game with Moogles. These delightful pint-sized winged cat-bear creatures are a staple of the Final Fantasy franchise and would help party members in this game, and many of those to follow.This was also the first Final Fantasy to use summons. Summons introduced in this game include Shiva, Ifrit, Titan, and Bahamut.No less than 3 Flying ships were in this game. The Nautilus, Enterprise, and the Invincible. The Invincible was a huge ship, practically sized like a small dungeon. The Nautilus also doubled as a submarine, a first for the series.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9249">Chrono Trigger</game><game id="11881">Xenosaga I+II</game><game id="1164">Dragon Warrior I &amp; II</game><game id="7197">Dragon Quest V: Hand of the Heavenly Bride</game><game id="267">Golden Sun</game><game id="4277">Golden Sun: The Lost Age</game><game id="22703">Dragon Quest IV: Chapters of the Chosen</game><game id="19425">Dragon Quest VI: Realms of Revelation</game><game id="23936">7th Dragon</game><game id="21676">Pokémon Platinum</game><game id="3093">Breath of Fire II</game><game id="15629">Breath of Fire</game><game id="21666">Dragon Quest IX: Sentinels of the Starry Skies</game><game id="3775">Mother 1+2</game><game id="20549">Naruto: Path of the Ninja 2</game><game id="3864">Mother 3</game><game id="23478">Suikoden Tierkreis</game><game id="21240">Black Sigil: Blade of the Exiled</game><game id="23987">Nostalgia</game><game id="23983">Mario &amp; Luigi: Bowser's Inside Story</game><game id="2254">Dragon Warrior VII</game><game id="24200">Sands of Destruction</game><game id="20677">The World Ends With You</game><game id="25435">Dragon Ball Z: Attack of the Saiyans</game><game id="26833">Golden Sun: Dark Dawn</game><game id="26932">Glory of Heracles</game><game id="27186">Final Fantasy: The 4 Heroes of Light</game><game id="5827">Final Fantasy Legend II</game><game id="4303">Tengai Makyou: Fuun Kabuki Den</game><game id="25150">Summon Night X: Tears Crown</game><game id="23904">Ni no Kuni: Shikkoku no Madoshi</game><game id="30297">Metal Max 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3715/601851-ff03ns012.jpg</image></root>