<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21478</id><name>Cryostasis</name><description>OverviewPlayers will find themselves looking for heat sources rather than health packs.Cryostasis is a survival horror title set aboard a ship called the North Wind; a Russian, nuclear ice breaker seemingly frozen in an Arctic wasteland. The player takes on the role of a meteorologist named Alexander Nesterov with a task of investigating the events that occurred aboard the ship. Although the game is very slow paced it can still be somewhat described as a modern-day Resident Evil or Doom because of the survival tactics needed to beat the game, and the way the environment and enemies are activated.Integral to the game is the ability to view the last moments of the deceased the protagonist will stumble across during his exploration; key points in the story will be revealed through this method. The player will be able to control some the flashbacks and perhaps even change their outcome. Another distinct feature in the game is the survival of the player: instead of a traditional health bar, the HUD displays a dial representing temperature, which can be replenished by locating sources of heat around the environment. As this represents the heat in the main character's body, both environmental damage and physical damage are tracked using this heat gauge, and there is also a concurrent endurance meter that drops as the character exerts himself in combat and maneuvering.The player will begin with no weapons at all, later finding a torn-off water valve to strike enemies with, as well as other improvised weapons. Later in the game the player will progress to a flare gun followed by various, mostly Soviet-era, rifles.The game can render in Shader models 3.0 and 4.0 ( DX9 and 10 respectively) and includes advanced ice and water effects to simulate the bleak, cold environment the games is based within. The game is also capable of rendering PhysX real-time water effects and is the first game to take advantage of this technology. Naturally the game requires a powerful rig to run upon and even with moderate settings selected it will put a high end PC to the test.The game's narrative is complex enough to actually allow for different interpretations of what is actually going on in the game, providing one of the few purer examples of game play as metaphor in a video game.SoundThe game is pretty much void of any kind of actual music, which conveys the player a further sense of loneliness and helplessness, and thus helping to make the game even more atmospheric and immersive. Despite the absence of music, the sound editing for every little thing surrounding the gamer is top notch and definitely one of the game's many great achievements in the audio department.CreaturesJailerJailer.When alive the jailer took an excessive interest in prisoners’ thoughts and secrets, which has affected his distinct appearance when frozen. Instead of a face he has a small prison cell inside his head. If Alexander does not run away when he hears the slow thumping of the Jailer’s metal legs, he will see that the cell-face gives off an eerie light.ServantServant.After betraying his fellow crewmen, the servant received a special gift in the afterlife -- all the keys to the ship's doors. His appearance also represents his previous life as a servant and he now has metal shoulder straps, a collar of steel and a steel mask. Doomed to eavesdrop forever, he no longer has eyeballs to see foes and now has two rusty nails hammered into his eye sockets.The servant is definitely less dangerous than the Jailer, but players should not make too much noise, in case they attract his attention.GuardGuard.In his previous life, the guard was only responsible for guarding the possessions of others, but after being changed by the cold, he’s just waiting to prove that he’s still a fierce opponent. Armed with a rifle, this is one enemy not to approach from a distance. Instead it’s best to quickly sneak up on him while he’s slowly reloading.WeaponsWater valveAt first Alexander has no decent weapons to help him fight against the various enemies and must fight almost bare-handed. His only saving grace is an old water valve – torn off a rusty high-pressure pipe – that increases the efficiency of his attacks. Although the valve is slow and heavy to swing, it greatly improves the amount of damage he can cause.AxeThe axe is slow but very effective at close range. It’s a two-handed weapon, so it takes a lot of energy to swing but causes a great deal of damage.AC-1940The AC-1940 was originally used by German submariners. It shoots incredibly hot signal flares that can be used as a rocket to burn though frozen enemies. It can even be fired at walls, where it will continue to burn for several seconds. During this time enemies will be attracted to the flare because they think it’s a heat source. As a result the Walter AC-1940 is an important weapon, not only to kill enemies but also to distract enemies.Magazine: Six rocketsRate of fire: Very lowRange: LongDamage: LowFeatures: Distract enemiesMosin-Nagan 1891A rifle that was in use between 1891 and 1960. It was invented by a Russian army captain called Sergey Mosin, who used the bullet feeding system of the Belgian Leon Nagan to create a revolutionary bolt-action rifle. It’s effective at a range of up to 2km and can be shot 10 times per minute. It was the first Russian rifle to use smokeless gunpowder.Magazine: Five shellsRate of fire: LowRange: LongDamage: MediumTokarev SVT-40About 1.5 million SVT guns were produced in the USSR and it was affectionately called Svetka by the Soviet soldiers. It has a high rate of fire – about 25 shots per minute – however it’s not very well equipped to deal with cold conditions and must constantly be cleaned. Although the SVT can fire 1,500m it has a slower rate of fire aboard the North Wind due to the cold climateMagazine: 10 shellsRate of fire: MediumRange: MediumDamage: MediumPPSH-41One of the most popular Soviet weapons during World War II, it is an effective machine gun designed by Georgiy Shpagin. The high capacity of the disk feeders – referred to as “snail” – means you can riddle enemies with bullets.Magazine: 71 shellsRate of fire: HighRange: MediumDamage: MediumPC System requirementsMinimumProcessor: Intel Core 2 Duo E4400 / AMD Athlon64 X2 4000Video Card: NVIDIA GeForce 7600 Series 256MB / ATI Radeon X1900 Series 256MBRAM Memory: 1024MBFree Disk Space: 5.5GBOperating System: Windows XP SP3 / Vista SP1RecommendedProcessor: AMD Athlon64 X2 5200 / Intel Core 2 Duo E4600Video Card: ATI Radeon HD 3870 512MB / NVIDIA GeForce 8800 GT 512MBRAM Memory: 2048MBFree Disk Space: 5.5GBOperating System: Windows XP SP3 / Vista SP1</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17386">Vivisector: Beast Within</game><game id="17639">Chasm: The Rift</game><game id="8804">Condemned: Criminal Origins</game><game id="5651">Penumbra: Overture</game><game id="23596">Penumbra: Requiem</game><game id="17280">BioShock</game><game id="20465">Condemned 2: Bloodshot</game><game id="500">The Thing</game><game id="11085">The Chronicles of Riddick: Escape from Butcher Bay</game><game id="10157">Clive Barker's Undying</game><game id="11725">S.T.A.L.K.E.R.: Shadow of Chernobyl</game><game id="21302">S.T.A.L.K.E.R.: Clear Sky</game><game id="20964">Metro 2033</game><game id="25707">Silent Hill: Shattered Memories</game><game id="18678">Call of Cthulhu: Dark Corners of the Earth</game><game id="30087">Amnesia: The Dark Descent</game><game id="21151">Hydrophobia</game><game id="21144">Singularity</game><game id="22605">Cursed Mountain</game><game id="3346">Penumbra: Black Plague</game><game id="16372">Prey</game><game id="35485">Metro: Last Light</game><game id="38270">Dead Space 3</game><game id="40877">AirBuccaneers</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1894704-box_cryostatis.jpg</image></root>