<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21616</id><name>The Saboteur</name><description>OverviewThe Saboteur is a third person sandbox game set in the lively streets and rooftops of 1940s Paris, at the height of the Nazi occupation. You play as Sean Devlin: drinker, driver, and womanizer. After seeking revenge for being cheated from a win, Sean finds himself looking for revenge for much more than just a race result. He encounters a rival racer, Kurt Dierker, who happens to also be a proud Nazi. Dierker kills Sean's best friend, leaving revenge a hot topic on Sean's mind.GameplayThe sandbox aspect of The Saboteur can be approached in a variety of ways. You can climb up buildings and use stealth to complete objectives, and travel more quietly through the occupied city, or you can go guns blazing into the fight. Regardless of choice, The Saboteur aims to allow players to fight exactly how they want to. Much of the gameplay is based around Sean's attempts to find, and eliminate, Dierker. This means helping the French Resistance, in the hope of finding answers, and also to push the threat of fascism out of the city of Paris.Gestapo GS Cruiser. Yes, be afraid. See one of these in the rear view mirror, FLOOR IT!Fighting against something as powerful as Nazism and the mechanized blitzkrieg is possible in only one way: sabotage. As Devlin, you must sabotage valuable assets to the German war machine to strike a blow in the face of adversity. Sabotaging enemy items is a key part of The Saboteur, and examples of this include planting bombs on railway bridges, bombing fuel depots, and ambushing soldiers, amongst other subversive acts. In a drive to make sabotage a key element of the game, Pandemic added a unique feature called the 'Will to Fight' system. In areas where the Nazis have full control, the game is in black and white. The only relief to this monotone world is the occasional flash of red that signifies something of value to the enemy. For example: the fuel tank on a hostile enemy vehicle would be red. However, as you continue to strike blows against the threat of fascism, the color of that area of the city slowly returns. The idea behind this is that the Nazis sucked all the vibrancy and life from areas under their oppression. When the color in an area returns, it shows the French citizens are more willing to fight. While areas that are colorful are liberated from the fascist regime, this does not remove all enemy presence. It will, however, make the citizens more willing to rise against the invaders. It also includes benefits in the form of French Resistance rebels that are prepared to slow the Nazis to help Sean escape them. Harassment in the liberated locations are much less frequent, and citizens will occasionally get into fist-fights against the German soldiers.Considering that Sean is an avid car lover, there are many different vehicles in the game that can be stolen and added to Sean's personal collection. Vehicles in the game are not licensed, but they are authentic to the era. In addition to vehicles, there are some different weapons that can be purchased from the Black Market dealers around the city. These dealers can sell you ammo for your weapons, and - if you can afford it - imported weapons, as well. Weapons in the game are reasonably accurate, and include the staples of any WWII game, such as the MP40 and the Kar 98k. The importable weapons include the Thompson and Sten. Weapons and other such goods are purchased through a currency known as 'contraband'. Contraband is earned by causing damage to the Nazi war machine. For example, bombing a sniper tower or putting that freight train in the ocean will earn contraband.Zeppelins leave an impression on the mind. Devlin leaves an 'impression' on the Zeppelin.Initially the Nazis you'll encounter are standard fighting soldiers. However, as you anger the aryan invaders, they will send more and more dangerous pursuers after you. These include Zeppelin airships, bombers, the Gestapo, and the fictional Terror Squad. The Zeppelins hover in the air, pelting Sean with extreme firepower. They can be destroyed with anti-aircraft weapons that are frequently mounted on rooftops. Destroying a Zeppelin results in a huge reward of contraband, and a spectacular scene, where it hovers in the air a bit after igniting. Bombers are just that - planes which swoop low over you, and drop bombs. These planes move quickly, but can be taken down as well. The Gestapo have unique vehicles which have a mounted machine gun running along the side. Their cars are also heavier, with more armor, and higher performance. The Terror Squad are fictional super-soldiers who use unique weapons. These weapons also take liberty with history and include an SMG that is more akin to an LMG and an automatic shotgun.As you play through the game, you will find different ‘ Perks’ to upgrade Sean’s abilities. There are three levels to each perk: Bronze, Silver, and Gold. Unlocking the Bronze perk involves nothing more than a simple task, and the tasks grow harder for better perks. The game frequently challenges players to complete different objectives in order to unlock rewards. For example, by destroying four train bridges, Sean can plant explosives without any suspicion. Some of these perk requests make players complete extremely challenging goals; for example: killing 10 Nazis with explosives in less than 10 seconds or gathering up every civilian, race, and Nazi vehicle in the game.The Saboteur features stealth options, in addition to the standard run and gun choice. If you kill an enemy soldier in hand to hand combat, you can steal their uniform and assume the identity of a Nazi soldier. Doing this means you can enter restricted areas. However, if you get too close to another Nazi, you can be identified as an impostor. The most difficult of these soldiers to avoid are the Gestapo agents, as they can blow covers extremely quickly.StoryThe game begins with Sean and the rest of his racing team loading their racing car onto a truck, and then traveling across the border from France into the German village of Saarbrucken, to partake in the 1940 Saarbrucken Grand Prix. Once the group arrive, they store the truck away and head to a local hotel. At this hotel, the group meet the favorites to win the race: Team Doppelsieg. Doppelsieg are a German team, and are almost forced to win to prove the 'superiority' of the 'aryan' race. Their driver is Kurt Dierker. Initially Dierker makes a sexual remark at Veronique, who manages Sean's group finances. Sean turns around and punches the rival before a fight with the Doppelsieg workers breaks out.The fight escalates until the group are outdoors, brawling outside the hotel. This fight is broken when Skylar St. Claire stops to watch. Sean and Jules jump into her car, and proceed to speed off with her in the middle. Skylar seems relaxed about the fact they are driving off in her car, considering the fact that they would have been killed otherwise. After losing their Nazi pursuers, Sean and Jules return to the hotel, where they are informed that Veronique has left the area to return to France, where she will wait on the team to return.The next day dawns, and it is time to put Dierker in his place. To start with, the race goes in Doppelsieg's favor, and they take an early lead. Sean catches up on them, and passes Dierker on the final corner. As he does so, Dierker cheats by pulling out a Luger pistol and shooting out the tire on Sean's car. The car spins out on the final straight, and Sean winds up coming last overall in the race. Understandably, he is furious, and intends to deal with Dierker. The team leader, Vittore restrains Sean and tells him it is not worthwhile to get mixed up in something that is so large. Sean reluctantly backs down, but Jules convinces him to seek revenge on Dierker. The two follow the Doppelsieg driver into the facility on the outskirts of the village of Saarbrucken. Between the two men, they manage to push the racing car off the cliff into the ocean. However, they are captured and interrogated by Kurt himself.You should hate this guy already, if only for that sweet Luger.During this interrogation, Dierker announces to the men that he is able to serve his Reich in more valuable ways than merely driving quickly. He reveals that he is a Nazi, and a member of the SS as well. Initially he believes that Sean is a spy sent by the British. Sean denies this profusely, and then Kurt threatens him. Either he admits to being a spy, or Jules dies. Jules and Sean both deny that either of the men are spies, and Kurt retaliates by firing his entire magazine into Jules, killing him.After this, you manage to escape from the Doppelsieg facility. Sean happens to be traveling the same route that the Nazis are on their way to invading France, and he manages to speed through all the invaders and reach France. At this stage, the farmhouse that the family reside in is being torched by the Germans. Sean stops them being killed and rescues them from the blaze. However, when he reveals that Jules died, Veronique grows hysterical. Sean then vows to kill Dierker.France: Unwilling to fightAfter this, the game cuts to three months after the ill-fated race. Sean is drinking in a bar, when he is contacted by a man named Luc. Luc is a member of the resistance, and he wants Sean’s assistance in fighting the Nazis. At first Sean treats him with hostility. However, after Luc says that the Nazis are all around him, and they will continue to be unstoppable until people rise against them, Sean reluctantly accepts the offer. Luc directs Sean to follow him out of the building and get in his car. In the car, Luc tells him his plans to bomb a German fuel depot. However, he needs Sean’s expertise and skills with explosive weaponry to succeed. The mission goes ahead, and is a success. Sean is thanked by Luc and is told that he will be in contact again. At this stage, Sean can freely to explore Paris.Missions in The Saboteur are structured in a manner similar to that of Grand Theft Auto. As Sean completes missions, he will meet more contacts, and these contacts will request you to fulfill objectives for them as well. After completing some of these missions you will eventually move on to story critical missions. After working with the Resistance for some time, the German soldiers attack the warehouse being used as a base of operations. When Sean arrives, he is ambushed and drugged by special agents. However, these agents are not German. They are working for the British, and Skylar is one of their operatives. Initially Sean dislikes her for capturing him, but he begins to be more relaxed about this fact when he realizes with the British there to help, he could inflict major damage to the Third Reich.After some time, Skylar gets in contact with Sean and instructs him to meet her in the French countryside. She wants him to bomb a freight train from the Germans that will be supplying vital armaments to the Nazi forces. To do this, Sean has to plant explosives at weak points in the structure of the bridge.Skylar then orders Sean to help destroy a Zeppelin airship before it leaves France. However, when Sean arrives it is already preparing to take off. This means breaking onto the Zeppelin, destroying it, and then escaping it. As the ship detonates, you leap into the ocean below. This ocean happens to be near a German harbor, and the Kriegsmarine investigate.Cartoon design for the MP60Before too long, you are forced into hiding in the Paris catacombs. Unfortunately, the leader of the Black Market dealers made an agreement that he would be spared if he sold out your position to the German military. The Germans are hell-bent on killing any resistance, and send in their Terror Squad, which are the elite soldiers of the game. These men are armed with special weapons, such as the Terror Squad MP60. In these catacombs, Luc is trapped under a collapsing piece of rock, where he demands that his fellow rebels kill him, as he feels the Germans would interrogate him, and he would give up information. Sean hesitates to kill him, and Veronique fires a single round from her rifle into Luc’s head. Veronique was Luc’s protégé, and she killed him, despite the fact she was a good friend to him. She feels that his death is a tragedy, but the death of them all would be more of a tragedy. She says Luc would have felt the same way.After completing the majority of story missions, you are contacted. The 1940 Paris Grand Prix is starting. Dierker will be racing in the event, and Vittore has a plan. However, his plan means that he will be killed: he plans to wire his car with explosives, and rather than overtake Dierker, he aims to detonate himself beside his enemy. Sean tells him that he will enter the race, but that the only person who will be dying is Kurt. This race means having to drive a sports car neatly through the streets of Paris without setting off the bomb. After completing this race, Sean puts the car into its highest gear, aims it directly at Dierker as he celebrates victory, and leaps from it. While the car explodes, and destroys the pride of Team Doppelsieg, it does not kill the target. This event terrifies Kurt, and he begins to lose his mind. The Nazis retaliate and fight hard against the resistance, covering all of Paris in black-and-white once more.The final mission of the game involves heading to the Eiffel Tower, where Kurt is making his stand. Upon arrival, you discover that Dierker has completely gone insane and turned on his own men, slaughtering them for imaginary insubordination. He stands at the top of the tower, where he executes a helpless Nazi just as Devlin arrives. Dierker soon realizes he used his last bullet to murder his own man, and finds himself helpless before Sean. He asks, ‘Are we to die here, Irishman?’, to which Sean replies ‘No. You will. I won’t,’ before pulling the trigger. Dierker's lifeless body falls from the tower, and as it hits the ground, the symbolic gesture of killing the German commander restores colour to the entire city. Veronique finds Sean as he descends the tower, asking him if it is finally over. However, Sean is aware that while his personal revenge has been fulfilled, the Germans still control most of France and pose a threat to the entire world. Setting the game up for a sequel, he replies"No. We're just getting started."VehiclesAll the collectible cars in the game. Sean obtains cars either by stealing them, car-jacking or by rewards.CivilianNameClassDescriptionR/PT.S.Acc.S/BBirgitteCivilian" I heard this car’s designer named the ride after his wife. I can only assume she weighed half a ton and belched smoke out her rear end." - Sean Devlin208154Corrino 45Civilian"She takes a while to get up to speed, but once she's moving, it takes a lot to stop her. A good choice when stopping' at checkpoints isn't part of the plan." - Sean Devlin208445Corrino CLCivilian"Average in every respect. She's reliable but she wont turn any heads." - Sean Devlin206754Corrino LXCivilian" Barely beats walking" - Sean Devlin206444Corrino LX JunkerCivilianSome older cars are worth taking home and fixin' up. Then there's this." - Sean Devlin208574Corrino SportCivilianHotter than you might expect. She's got the heart of a racer in the body of a street car" - Sean Devlin208574DauphinCivlian"Not a bad choice if you're planning to pop down to market and pick up some groceries. If you're lookin' for a getaway car, look elsewhere." - Sean Devlin206133Dauphin ConvertibleCivilian"A posh ride for posh wankers with more money than sense." - Sean Devlin206643DominoCivilian"Combines speed and sophisticated sense of style. Perfect for a lady's man on the go." - Sean Devlin5011173DugatiCivilian"Speed, grace, and luxury. She's got it all, if you can afford the mile-high price. 'Course, you could always steal one." - Sean Devlin209383GütmannCivilian"Bishop drives around in the back o' one these, slurpin' caviar and champagne. rumor has it that the design was handcrafted by Gütmann himself." - Sean Devlin208767Palomino SedancaCivilian"The sort of lass you'd expect to find at the Belle - Expensive, frilly and big around the curves." - Sean Devlin209266PegasusCivilian"Big and fast. A good choice for running down krauts in the crosswalk." - Sean Devlin2011455Renoir ClunkerCivilian"Anybody driving one o' these should expect a citation for littering the highway" - Sean Devlin58273Renoir CruiserCivilian"I'm fairly sure my grandmother drives this car to church on Sunday mornings. Nuff said." - Sean Devlin208573Renoir GSCivilian"I'll buy one of these just as soon as I'm married with two kids. In the mean time, Ill steer clear." - Sean Devlin209473TractorCivilian" If I wanted to work on a farm, I never would have left Ireland." - Sean Devlin55434WorkhorseCivilian"Plant a few sticks o' dynamite under the dashboard and you've got yourself an ideal vehicle for makin' 'special deliveries' " - Sean Devlin208554*. R/P= Repair price, T.S.= Top Speed, Acc.= Acceleration, S/B= Strength and BodyMilitaryVehicles that are captured from the Nazis.NameClassDescriptionR/PT.S.Acc.S/BArmed BauerMilitary"Slow as shite but comes conveniently packed with a machinegun on the rear. Not great if you are trying to escape but at least its got some options in a pinch." - Sean Devlin208256Armed SturmwagenMilitary"These Gestapo patrol cars have muscle, wieght, and firepower, an essential addition to any car collection." - Sean Devlin208894Armed ZP750Military"The first choice of Nazi street patrols and an all too common sight in my rear view mirror. The MG42 gives this hound a bite to go with its bark." - Sean Devlin2089101BauerMilitary"Standard kraut transport. Usually carries an infantry squad in back. can take a beating." - Sean Devlin109056Bauer Fuel TruckMilitary"Think of it as a gigantic bomb on wheel. has lots of nasty uses, most of them involving giant balls of fire. Don't try runnin' from the krauts in this deathtrap." - Sean Devlin109056Gestapo CruiserMilitary"This Gestapo pursuit beast is even meaner than the bastards driving her. A reinforces chassis and linked machineguns make her the toughest bitch on the block." - Sean Devlin5011566Gestapo GSMilitary"One of the few Nazi vehicles that the jackboots haven't strapped a cannon. More of a collectors item than a practical addition." - Sean Devlin207653KaiserMilitary"Leave it to the krauts to design a limousine for a warzone." - Sean Devlin207155Kaiser BulletproofMilitary"The champagne cooler is a nice touch, but the bulletproof glass is what really sets this one apart from your typical luxury car." - Sean Devlin507955 / BPKaiser ConvertibleMilitary"And of course, the convertible model. Perfect for victory parades through the capitol cities of conquered nation." - Sean Devlin208455SturmwagenMilitary"The car of choice for Nazi in France. Seats four jackboots comfortably, or one saboteur trying to look inconspicuous." - Sean Devlin108694ZP750Military"The Nazi bikes are quick and small enough to slip down an alleyway. Just don't run into anything." - Sean Devlin109991*. R/P= Repair price, T.S.= Top Speed, Acc.= Acceleration, S/B= Strength and BodyTanks and APCs.Tanks and APCs can be found around Paris unattended. If Sean get the perk "Wheelman" he can store tanks and APCs in the garages. To obtain the Wheelman perk you will have to collect all cars in the game or just buy the Gold Perk upgrade at a weapons dealer.NameClassDescriptionR/PT.S.Acc.S/BAR 33Tank/APC"The ugly little bugger is a common sight on the streets of paris. Don't be fooled by her looks, this baby can cause some serious mayhem in the wrong hands." - Sean Devlin506247 BPFlammwagenTank/APC" The stuff of nightmares—a Nazi tank fitted with multiple flamethrowers. If ya see one comin’ at ya, run the other way." - Sean Devlin503227 BPFoucaltTank/APC"A few of these old French tanks survived the invasion. If you can find one, drive it to a museum." - Sean Devlin503026 BPHalf-TrackTank/APC" The party wagon of the Third Reich, winging the good-time boys around for a go. Fits about six, a gunner, and lots of space for a tossed grenade if you’ve got thearm for it." - Sean Devlin205537 BPPanther MK IIITank/APC"Medium tank. These are the beasts that conquered most of Europe." - Sean Devlin753428 BPWulfTank/APC"Superheavy tank. Rumor has it, this monster is some kind of experimental prototype." - Sean Devlin10040310 BP*. R/P= Repair price, T.S.= Top Speed, Acc.= Acceleration, S/B= Strength and BodyRacing CarsRace cars can be stolen or acquired through completing perk challenges. The racing perks Lead Foot, Speed Demon and Godspeed, all give you a race car in the garage.NameClassDescriptionR/PT.S.Acc.S/BAltairRacing" A top speed that rivals the Aurora , matched with smooth cornering, has earned this car the nickname “The Flying Eagle.” - Sean Devlin5010192AuroraRacing"The pride and joy of Morini Autos, the car that rightfully won the Saarbrücken Grand Prix. We're making the next one with bulletproof tires." - Sean Devlin75121102Beta RomeroRacing"Reminds me of a hot little Italian bird I once knew. Just the thing for a ride in the countryside." - Sean Devlin5096102Beta Romero 12CRacing"T o hear Vittore tell it, he drew up this design years ago and had it stolen from him. Right, and I prototyped the aeroplane." - Sean Devlin50115102DelgadoRacing"The poor man's score points for classic styling, but she's not got the muscle to keep up with top shelf race cars." - Sean Devlin509192DrakeRacing"Skylar's car is a lot like her original owner. Great body. Fairly reliable..." - Sean Devlin7511883Silver ClawRacing"The latest Doppelsieg prototype. Somewhere between a race car and a rocketship." - Sean Devlin7511192Silver Claw MK. IIRacing" Dierker's Car. Not a bad ride if you're a bloody cheating shite." - Sean Devlin100111102Silver DartRacing"Fast on the straightaway, but handles like a kayak. Made famous by winning races all over Europe in the 1920's." - Sean Devlin*. R/P= Repair price, T.S.= Top Speed, Acc.= Acceleration, S/B= Strength and BodyWeaponsWeapons are used throughout the whole game, even though you technically can use your fists to win missions. Here follows a list of the different weapons you can obtain. Some weapons wont be available without finishing some challenge perks to lock them up at the Black Market weapon dealers and smugglers. Other weapons will not be available until you progress in the game and have finished specific story missions.You cannot buy weapons until you have finish the "The Black Market". It is obtainable in Act 1 and is the third mission.PistolsThese are the pistols you can use throughout the game. There are a total of 5 different pistols available.Name and imageBlack Market InformationDAM.RAN.ROFACC.Item PriceAmmo price.44 pistol" One round from this Yankee cannon'll turn a Kraut's insides into shepard pie. Just watch your ammo, cause' she's a bitch to reload." - Sean DevlinUnlocked by Completing “ War on Terror” Perk9757Free10Silenced Pistol" Signature weapon of the English assassin.Perfect for a silent headshot on a snoozing Kraut sentry." - Sean Devlin534550020Kruger" Light and compact, the Kruger is an excellent accessory for any German disguise. She doesn't pack much punch,so make sure you aim for the head." - Sean Devlin4645Free10Raum Pistol"The big dog of German pistols- bark as loud as hell and bite to match. Unlike the Kruger pistol there's no need to go for the headshot." - Sean DevlinUnlocked at the Beginning of the “Buried Secrets” Mission544760010" Kurt Dierker may have been motherless asshole, but he packed one mean motherfucker of a gun.A very useful souvenir." - Sean Devlin9798Free10*. DAM=Damage, RAN.=Range, ROF=Rate of Fire, ACC.=AccuracyRiflesThese are the rifles you can use throughout the game.Name and imageBlack Market InformationDAM.RAN.ROFACC.Item PriceAmmo priceHunting Rifle" Suitable for huntin' birds and such, but if it's a Nazi's head your lookin' to mount on the wall, look for a long gun with more punch." - Sean Devlin5818Free10Carbine Rifle" Standard kraut infantry rifle. She's got a long reach, but she's not much use in close up fights." - Sean Devlin594920010Steiner Rifle" She's semi-automatic and steady, but one shot is all she needs. Perfect for shooting from rooftops." - Sean DevlinUnlocked at the Beginning of the “ Buried Secrets” Mission784850010*. DAM=Damage, RAN.=Range, ROF=Rate of Fire, ACC.=AccuracyShotgunsThese are the shotguns you can use throughout the game.Name and imageBlack Market InformationDAM.RAN.ROFACC.Item PriceAmmo priceDouble Shotgun" Weapon of choice for farmers who want to make me marry their daughters. Short range and slow to reload, but enough fire power to blow any unlucky bachelor out of his socks." - Sean Devlin7223Free10Trenchgun" When the fighting is door-to-door, the trenchgun is a Saboteur's best friend. Just don’t shoot until you see the whites of their beady blue eyes." - Sean Devlin633320010Terror Shotgun"First time I found myself on the wrong end o' this monster, I nearly pissed me pants. The sound alone is enough to send hard men running for their lives. A true tide-turner." - Sean DevlinUnlocked by Completing the “Boiling Point” Mission10486250030*. DAM=Damage, RAN.=Range, ROF=Rate of Fire, ACC.=AccuracySniper RiflesThese are the sniper rifles you can use throughout the game.Name and imageBlack Market InformationDAM.RAN.ROFACC.Item PriceAmmo priceScoped Carbine" Nothin' like the sight of kraut general's smirking face through the scope of a high powered rifle. Zoom in when you are ready to take the shot. " - Sean DevlinUnlocked at the Beginning of the “Buried Secrets” Mission81021080020Scoped Steiner" An impressive combination of speed and precision. The semi-auto Scoped Steiner can put more lead on target then the Scoped Carbine." - Sean DevlinUnlocked after Completing the “Papiere Bitte” Save Point910410130020Terror Scoped Rifle" The perfect tool for long range murder. Set up on a high rooftop, keep your head down, and let the games begin, So easy, it almost feels like cheatin'." - Sean DevlinUnlocked by Completing the “ Longshot” Perk1010109Free30*. DAM=Damage, RAN.=Range, ROF=Rate of Fire, ACC.=AccuracyMachine GunsThese are the machine guns you can use throughout the game.Name and imageBlack Market InformationDAM.RAN.ROFACC.Item PriceAmmo priceMP40 SMG" As common as hookers in the streets of Paris, and sees about as much action. An efficient weapon in close range, but a poor choice for long range work." - Sean Devlin2564Free10MP44 MG" A nasty piece o' German engineering. An efficient weapon. Standard among jackbooted Nazi fuckers." - Sean Devlin677730010Tommy MG" She'll clear a room faster then a fart in a dinner party. Best American invention since Rita Haywood" - Sean DevlinUnlocked after Completing the “Papiere Bitte” Save Point7677120010Viper SMG" One of my personal favorites. She's quiet as a ghost, and quick enough to stop a kraut's heart before he can reach that whistle. A must for any serious collector. " - Sean Devlin7678200020Terror MP60"Y a gotta have brass balls just to pick up one of these monsters up. Kick's like mule, but she'll cut a jackboot into kraut confetti in two seconds. " - Sean Devlin97107200020*. DAM=Damage, RAN.=Range, ROF=Rate of Fire, ACC.=AccuracyPerksAcquired by completing special challenges. There are ten Perk categories, each with three levels: Bronze, Silver and Gold.CategoryPerk NameObjectiveRewardsBrawlingFightin’ IrishKnock out 2 Nazis.Unlock Haymaker attack.Sucker PunchExecute 10 stealth kills from behind.Unlock Sucker Punch attack.Grim ReaperStealth kill 5 generals.Unlock Touch of Death attack.HardwareGunslingerKill 5 Nazis using bullets.Reduced recoil for automatic weapons.War on TerrorKill 5 Terror Squad Nazis.Unlock .44 Pistol in shop.Paint the Town RedDestroy a zeppelin and a Wulf tank during the same alarm.Unlock Panzershrek in the shop.SnipingMarksmanKill 5 Nazis using a sniper scope.Reduced drift while using a scoped rifle.Eagle Eye ScoreScore 15 head shots using a sniper scope.Reduced drift while using a scoped rifle.LongshotScore 10 “Double Kills”Unlock Terror Scoped Rifle in the shop.ExplosivesCheap ThrillKill 10 Nazis using grenades.Carry additional grenades.More Bang for Your BuckKill 5 Nazis in one explosion.All explosives half price.A Real HellionKill 10 Nazis in 10 seconds with RDX or dynamite.No knockdown from explosions.DemolitionsA Nasty SurpriseBlow up 3 Nazi vehicles using dynamite.Unlock trap functionality for dynamite.Mad BomberDestroy 5 Nazi vehicles with dynamite in 300 seconds.Unlock RDX in the shop.Block BusterDestroy 3 Wulf tanks using RDX or dynamite.Unlock Super RDX upgrade.SabotageShort FuseDestroy 2 Nazi installationsImproved planting speed for explosives.I Fell TowersDestroy 10 Nazi towers.Carry additional explosives.Urban RenewalDestroy 4 Nazi train bridges.Planting explosives while disguised is not suspicious.MayhemThrowing a PartyThrow 5 Nazis to their death.Unlock Crowd Clearer throw.Road RageRun over 20 Nazis with a vehicle.Unlock Aurora nitrous upgrade.The Right of WayDestroy 20 Nazi vehicles with one vehicle.Unlock Aurora machine gun.RacingLead FootWin the time trial.Unlock Silver Dart in the garage.Speed DemonWin Country Race 1.Unlock Skylar’s Drake Custom in the garage.GodspeedWin Country Race 2.Unlock Silver Dart 2 in the garage.MechanicsJoy RiderCollect 5 different civilian vehicles.Unlock a race car in the garage.HijackerCollect all 12 Nazi vehicles.Free vehicle repairs in the garage.WheelmanCollect and store all civilian, race, and military vehicles.Garages can collect and store APCs and tanks.EvasionFugitiveEscape from a Level 2 Alarm 5 times.Unlock Getaway Strike.Escape ArtistEscape from a Level 3 Alarm.Gain the ability to select getaway car at any garage.Europe’s Most WantedEscape from a Level 5 Alarm.You can use hiding spots at Alarm Levels 4 and 5.Main MissionsPrologue#Mission NameTypeDescriptionContactReward1Spark One UpSabotageSean meets a stranger named Luc. The two of them decide to work together to blow up a Nazi fuel depot.LucNone2Better DaysTransportationSean and Jules drive into Germany with the race-car Aurora. Vittore’s waiting for them at the Red Ox.VittoreNone3Old Friends,New EnemiesCombatA argument with Dierker and his friends leads to a full-out brawl. Sean, Jules, Veronique, and Vittore must escape the German soldiers.VittoreNone4La Femme St. ClaireEvasionWhile escaping the bar with Jules, Sean runs intohis old friend Skylar. The three of them must escape the Nazi reinforcements and return to their hotel in Saarbrücken for the night.SkylarNone5Pole PositionRacingSean must win the race against his new enemy Dierker.NoneNone6A Sunday DriveTailingSean and Jules tail Dierker and destroy his race car.JulesNone7The Darkest NightEvasion and combat.Sean must escape from the inside of Doppelsieg, and cross the border alive.NoneNone8Out of the Frying PanEvasionSean must go to the farm quickly to find out what has happened to Vittore and Veronique.NoneNone9Into the FireEvasion and combat.Sean must rescue Vittore and Veronique and deliver a message to Jules' parents.NoneAct 1#Mission NameTypeDescriptionContactReward1SlaughterhouseRescueSean rescues Vittore and other captives. They all then set up an HQ in the basement of the slaughterhouse at La Villette.LucDisguse HQ unlocked at La Villette2Bottle ShockTheftSean will have to steal a bottle of champagne for Santos, then Santos will give him medicine for Luc.SantosContraband3The Black MarketSabotage, assassinationTo open up the black market Sean will have to do some errands for Santos.SantosUnlocks black market4Grand Theft LimoTheftSteal a Nazi general's limo for Santos.SantosContrabandShop: Garage atthe BelleShop: Garage atLa Villette5Thirty Pieces of LeadAssassinationKill a traitor.VittoreContraband6Liberty or DeathRescueFree Le Crochet from the Nazi holding area.LucContraband,Backup Strike7Special DeliveryTransportationDrive Veronique to deliver a bomb to a Nazi HQ.VeroniqueContraband8Buried SecretsTheftSean and Skylar needs to recover a mysterious crate in the cemetery.SkylarResistance Fight Back zones9A Trip Up the CoastTransportationDrive Skylar up the coast to Le Havre.SkylarNone10Vive Le VengeanceEvasionSean need to go on board a zeppelin in hunt for vengeance on Dierker.Skylar, BishopContrabandAct 2#Mission NameTypeDescriptionContactReward1A Whisper or a RoarAssassinationSantos agrees that he will give Sean the Area 2 papers in return for blowing up a group of German supply trucks.SantosArea 2 papers2JailbreakRescueMargot gives Sean a mission to free one of their resistance members, Bryman.MargotContraband3The Big GunSabotageBryman gives Sean a mission to destroy a cannon being aimed at civilians in the city.LucContraband4Rolling ThunderRescueSkylar leads Sean on a mission to sabotage a bridge. To blow up a train in order to free a defecting German scientist, Kessler.SkylarContraband5South of the SeineTransportation and CombatLuc tells Sean to drive them to a meeting with Margot and another rebel leader, Duval, in the south of the city.LucUnlock Catacombs6Repo ManTheftSean recovers his Aurora from the occupied chateau.VittoreContraband7Boiling PointRecueSean rescues Maria from the Gestapo HQ.BrymanContraband8Lambs for the slaughterCombatThe Nazis attack the La Villette slaughterhouse HQ.NoneLa Villette closed9Dark ReignSabotageSean needs to plant seven wiretaps on the German communication lines to monitor their communications.BrymanContraband10Needs of theFew…or the OneRescueSean needs to rescue Veronique with the aid of Bryman.BrymanNone11From the AshesRacingSean will race for Paris vs. Dierker and then blows up the grandstands to kill prime targets.NoneNoneAct 3'C'est ici l'empire de la mort'Deja BoomAngel of DeathSide MissionsLe Crochet StoryBelly of the BeastDoppelgangerLegio Patria NostraFather Denis StoryUnforgiven SinsWrath of GodRed WeddingSOE OperationsBehind the Convent GateDying Through ChemistrySet Up Us the BombMargot Bonaire StoryFahreinheit Four FiftyBulletproofSymphony of DestructionDuval Mingo StoryLoose LipsThe Hunter or the HuntedDr. Kwong's StoryThe Bavarian CandidateGuardian AngelDeutschland Uber Phallus' Ten Dollar Project’Ticket to the Midnight Show included with the gameElectronic Arts reward players who buy their games new with codes to download $10 of DLC for free. In the case of The Saboteur, this DLC is the ‘Midnight Show’. Inside the game box, there is a card insert designed to look like a WWII era ticket. This ticket contains the redeem code for the downloadable content. The Midnight Show grants access to the Belle de Nuit's exclusive basement, adding the ability to play a knife-throwing minigame (in which the player can win the Palomino car) and watch exclusive lapdance animations. Also added are several hiding spots, mostly brothels around the city, and an option to add toplessness to the game.Box Art and Other InformationThe official box art of the game.The Saboteur was released with the one box art design globally. The design shows Sean Devlin in black and white, with a red Eiffel Tower on a dirty white colored base in the background. The tagline running along the back of the box is “Viva la Vengeance!”.For an unknown reason, the German release of the game is simply called "Saboteur". The word "the" was dropped from the title, and there are no confirmed reasons as to why this is. Had the game received the same title, it would have been "Der Saboteur".The title is not the only thing that was changed in the German release. Swastikas and other symbols linking to national socialism have been cut out, as well as two audio excerpts from speeches given by Adolf Hitler. If the box is turned upside down, it is possible to see Sean's fist clenched in a manner similar to that of the 'raised fist' design. This is normally a symbol of resistance, and fits with the game itself, though this is of course a coincidence.System requirementsCPU: Core 2 Duo 2.4GHz or AMD equivalentOS: Windows XP SP3, Windows Vista SP1, Windows 7Video: Nvidia Geforce 7800 GTX with 256MB of VRAM or ATI Radeon HD 2600 Pro with 256MB of VRAMRAM: 2GB or moreSound: Direct X 9.0c compatible sound cardHard drive: At least 7GB of free spaceDisc drive: Dual Layer 1x or faster DVD Drive</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20464">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Conviction</game><game id="17853">Sniper Elite</game><game id="22928">Assassin's Creed II</game><game id="2335">Thief: Deadly Shadows</game><game id="18772">Body Harvest</game><game id="20599">inFamous</game><game id="20697">Mercenaries 2: World in Flames</game><game id="7633">Mercenaries: Playground of Destruction</game><game id="20573">Velvet Assassin</game><game id="20742">Just Cause 2</game><game id="20679">Saints Row 2</game><game id="21119">Wolfenstein</game><game id="37494">Assassin's Creed III</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2348796-box_saboteur.png</image></root>