<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21649</id><name>Multiwinia</name><description>OverviewMultiwinia is a real time strategy game that is an offshoot of the single player game Darwinia. It has a simple control scheme, simple gameplay and a simple look, but beyond its simple aesthetic however lies a lot of hidden depth, and the equality of all the teams and lack of tech trees make balance a non-issue. There is a single player option which allows you to face off against up to 3 other CPU players in 6 different gameplay modes on various different maps. There's also a multiplayer option which gives you the same gameplay selection and allows you to play against other players online. A common element in each gameplay mode is to try and use your Multiwinians (flat people bearing your team color that can attack) which constantly respawn from a spawn point to accomplish the goal of the gameplay mode.PlotAfter the destruction of much of the virus from Darwinia, the Darwinians began to change. They became more aggressive and started to splinter into different factions. With the world's resources strained a large civil war began. It is not known if Dr. Sepulveda has taken any actions to stop the war, is still alive or is involved in any way.GameplayThe game is controlled by using the mouse and WASD keys to navigate the map. Units are selected and controlled using the left and right mouse buttons. Multiwinians are selected by using a selection radius, which is a circle that grows by holding the left mouse button down. There are no single units or squads, and you cannot drag select units. There are also no hotkeys, as most the Multiwinians actions are done automatically, and those that are not can be automated. Occasionally crates with powerful power-ups will fall from the sky, and the power-ups can be collected by using Multiwinians. The more Multiwinians harvesting a power-up, the faster it is obtained. Power-ups range from gun, flame and rocket turrets to nuclear warheads, meteors and plagues to giant dragons, spiders and centipedes.Multiwinians by default have the ability to attack with lasers and occasionally throw grenades. They tend to group together, although they will scatter as best as they can when something like a grenade or meteor heads their way. Right clicking a Multiwinians will promote them into an officer, which can be used to direct traffic or form phalanxes. Phalanxes are slow moving units of tightly packed Multiwinians that are very vulnerable from the rear, however they are nearly impervious when it comes to frontal assaults and can usually take on non-phalanx groups that are several times their size head on. Multiwinians will aggregrate around nearby crates or spawn points automatically if there are no nearby enemies.The 6 modes are Domination, King of the Hill, Assault, Capture the Statue, Blitzkrieg, and Rocket Race. Domination involves capturing spawn points (neutral or enemy) within a certain time limit, and the player with the most spawn points at the end of the time limit wins. Players who have 0 spawn points for over 30 seconds are eliminated from the game. Capturing spawn points is both advantageous for completing the goal, as well as for strategy since additional Multiwinians spawn at your captured spawn points, allowing you to build your army and capture other spawn points faster. King of the Hill involves controlling strategic areas which impart points and the team with the most points at the end of the time limit wins. Capture the Statue is a variation on Capture the Flag, and Assault involves protecting or assaulting a heavily fortified area depending on which team you are on. Blitzkrieg involves using limited number of Multiwinians to capture strategic points, while Rocket Race involves collecting resources with the first team to collect a certain amount launching their rocket and winning.Keeping in line with the rest of the game, the graphics are intentionally simple, but the game is capable of generating thousands of Multiwinians onscreen at once, and does so quite often in 4 player games.System RequirementsPCOS: Windows XP or VistaProcessor: 2.0 GHz CPUMemory: 512 MB RAMGraphics: GeForce 6200 or RADEON 9600 seriesHard Drive: 64 MB free spaceMacOS: OS X version Leopard 10.5.8, Snow Leopard 10.6.3, or later.Processor: Intel Core Duo 1.66GHz+Memory: 1GB of RAMGraphics: 64MB of video memoryHard Drive: 64 MBLinuxProcessor: 2 GhzMemory: 1GbGraphics: 64Mb of memoryHard Drive: 70Mb</description><genres><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="29894">Darwinia+</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2330877-pc.png</image></root>