<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21657</id><name>Initial D: Extreme Stage</name><description>OverviewInitial D:Extreme Stage brings Sega's popular arcade, and console racer to the Playstation 3.   Released on 3rd July 2008 in Japan the game has received moderate success.  The game itself is based upon Sega's Initial D Arcade Version 4, albeit with tweaked graphics and console specific features such as an online mode with rankings and chat.  The Japanese release is import friendly due to the inclusion of an English instruction manual.  Sega has proposed future downloadable content for this release, but as of yet nothing has been confirmed.  The Asian release is without the online features.  Courses included in this release Lake Akina (Beginner) *  Mt. Myogi (Normal) *Akagi (Advance)Akina (Advance)Irohazaka (Expert)Tsukuba (Expert) *Happogahara  (Expert)* Indicates new to the franchiseHappogahara was not previously in Arcade Stage 4 and is exclusive to the console. Cars included in this release ToyotaTrueno GT-APEX (AE86)LEVIN GT-APEX (AE86)LEVIN SR (AE85)MR2 G-Limited (SW20)Altezza RS-200 (SXE10) MitsubishiLancer GSR Evolution III (CE9A)Lancer RS Evolution IV (CN9A)Lancer GSR Evolution IX (CT9A) * NissanSkyline GTR V-Spec II (BNR32)Skyline GTR V-Spec II Nur (BNR34)Silvia K's (S13)Silvia Q's (S14)Silvia Spec-R (S15)180SX Type X (RPS13) MazdaRX-7 Type R (FD3S)RX-7 Infini III (FC3S)RX-8 Type S (SE3P)Roadster S Special (NA6C) HondaCivic Type R (EK9)Civic SiR II (EG6)Integra Type R (DC2)S2000 (AP1) SubaruImpreza WRX-STi Version V Type R (GC8V)Impreza WRX-STi 2007 Edition (GDBF) * SuzukiSuzuki Cappuccino (EA11R)* Indicates new to Initial D.   Song ListingLet's Go,Come OnGo Beat CrazySpeed CarFly Me to the Moon and BackRevolutionWe'll See HeavenAll AroundEldoradoRaising HellSpace LoveNo ControlForever YoungRider of the SkyThe Fire's on MeDive Into the StreamKeep on Movin'Soukyuu no Flight</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1101">Ridge Racer 7</game><game id="8844">Need for Speed: Carbon</game><game id="18095">Need for Speed: ProStreet</game><game id="20927">Midnight Club: Los Angeles</game><game id="5875">Midnight Club 3: DUB Edition</game><game id="21689">Wangan Midnight</game><game id="26956">Wangan Midnight Maximum Tune</game><game id="26958">Wangan Midnight Maximum Tune 3</game><game id="26957">Wangan Midnight Maximum Tune 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/10468/221818-initial_d_extreme_stage_cover.jpg</image></root>