<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21654</id><name>Metal Gear Solid 2: Substance</name><description>New FeaturesVR Missions/Alternate MissionsThe main addition to this new release was the 350 VR Missions and 150 Alternative Missions similar to Metal Gear Solid: VR Missions released on the original PlayStation. This gave players the chance to guide either Snake or Raiden through timed virtual missions and getting to the end of a set course. By progressing through the missions, the difficulty of each course increased, and in time, different costumes for Snake and Raiden would unlock, each of them providing a small twist on the gameplay and increasing the difficulty. the mission types included:SneakingThe goal of this mode is to reach the end of the level without being spotted. If the guards see the player it results in game over.Sneaking-Eliminate AllThe goal is the same with the exception that the player must eliminate all the enemies before reaching the end.Weapon ModeThis mode tests the player's aiming and shooting skills against moving targets. Each weapon type has its own subset of missions, these include:Handgun | Assault Rifle | C4  Claymore | Grenade | PSG1 | Stinger | Nikita | HF Blade | No WeaponFirst Person View ModeA mix of several modes but played in the first person.Variety ModeA variety of timed objectives ending with the Zako Survival challenge. The player must survive waves of increasingly agressive soldiers only to face a Giant Soldier in the end.Bomb Disposal ModeWith the aid of sensors the player must dismantel bombs before they go off.Eliminate All ModeThe player must kill all the enemies though the game does not end when the player is spotted. Instead the soldiers call for back up.Hold-Up ModeThe player must hold up the enemies without being spotted.Photograph ModeThe player must photograph a specific and sometimes cryptic object, poster or person in any given environment to complete the level.CharactersRaiden and Snake are available from from the get go while their costumes must be unlocked by completing missions. For each of these costumes there are small alterations in gameplay as well as in music. For instance: the music in the Snake (Tuxedo) missions is meant to evoke James Bond and the Snake (MGS1) missions features music from the original Metal Gear Solid: VR Missions.CostumesDescriptionRaidenStandard model from MGS2. Easy Missions.Ninja RaidenUnlockable. Makes exclusive use of his blade.Raiden XUnlockable. Features only a handful of missions in which Raiden is naked and must reach the goal without being spotted.This is a reference to Metal Gear Solid 2: Sons of Liberty in which Raiden is stripped of his gear and must make his waythrough the Arsenal naked. He is the only character to feature his own mode called "Streaking Mode".SnakeStandard model from MGS2. Easy Missions.PliskinUnlockable. Slightly Harder Missions.Snake (Tuxedo)Unlockable. Hard Missions.Snake (MGS1)Unlockable. Extremely Hard set of missions.Snake TalesSnake Tales gives players the chance to control Solid Snake through five story based missions on the Big Shell and Tanker. The final boss on the Tanker, Olga Gurlukovich, is replaced with Meryl Silverburgh from the original Metal Gear Solid. Unlike the main game this mode does not feature cutscenes, instead the story is told through pages of text.Boss Survival and Casting TheatreThese two new features were previously exclusive to the original PAL and Japanese versions of the game, but have later been implemented to all versions of Substance. Boss Survival gives players the chance to re-live each boss battle within the game. Each battle is timed. The casting theater allows players to watch different cutscenes and replace the character models.SkateboardingEssentially a demo for ‘Evolution Skateboarding’ the mode was exclusively added to the PlayStation 2 version of Substance. The player can use Snake or Raiden to complete small objectives through ‘ Big Shell’ themed levels. These objectives vary from blowing up parts of the level to collecting dog tags. Skateboarding mode is not included in the Metal Gear Solid HD Collection, and it is the only feature that was cut from the HD version of Metal Gear Solid 2.System RequirementsOperating System: Windows 98/Me/2000/XPProcessor: 800 Mhz Pentium III or AthlonInstalled memory(RAM): 128 MB RAM3,8 GB free HDD spaceDVD-ROM driveGraphics Card: Direct X 8.1-compatible graphics card with one of the following chipsets:GeForce 256/GeForce 2/GeForce 2MX/GeForce 3/GeForce 3 Ti/GeForce 4MX/GeForce 4 TiSound card: Direct X 8.1-compatible sound cardDirect X: Direct X 8.1</description><genres><genre id="23">Skateboarding</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15774">WinBack: Covert Operations</game><game id="21866">WinBack 2: Project Poseidon</game><game id="12354">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Chaos Theory</game><game id="457">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Double Agent</game><game id="15549">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Pandora Tomorrow</game><game id="5961">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell</game><game id="11004">Hitman: Blood Money</game><game id="6709">Hitman: Codename 47</game><game id="7004">Hitman 2: Silent Assassin</game><game id="24617">Tenchu: Shadow Assassins</game><game id="16004">Tenchu: Stealth Assassins</game><game id="7539">Tenchu: Wrath of Heaven</game><game id="15737">Tenchu 2: Birth of the Stealth Assassins</game><game id="7750">Tenchu: Return from Darkness</game><game id="21002">Tenchu: Time of the Assassins</game><game id="15282">Tenchu: Fatal Shadows</game><game id="23924">Spy Fiction</game><game id="5704">Shadow of Rome</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1875238-box_mgs2s.png</image></root>