<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21768</id><name>BlazBlue: Calamity Trigger</name><description>OverviewBlazBlue: Calamity Trigger (pronounced as BlazeBlue) is a 2D fighter released by            Arc System Works.  It was released in Japanese arcades on November 19, 2008, and in US  arcades on November 20, 2008.  The game bares many similarities to the company's  previous fighter              Guilty Gear XX,  but features an entirely new setting and lineup of characters. It is also using  high-res sprites, twice the size of those in Guilty Gear XX. The arcade version  of the game is running on the Taito Type X2 system board, meaning that the game  will be one of the few 2D fighters to use a 720p resolution, along with              King of  Fighters XII and              Super  Street Fighter II Turbo HD Remix.   LocalizationBlazBlue Key  Features:The first hi-res 2D fighter from the creators of the Guilty Gear  series! Experience the beauty of high-resoluti on, hand-drawn sprites on  3D backgrounds, all in glorious high-definition. Online Battle Action Get ready to take the action online and  battle the best players from all over the world! Console Exclusive Modes BlazBlue features the  following console-only modes: Arcade, Vs, Practice, and a completely fleshed-out  Story Mode that tells the tales of each character. Over 10 unique combatants to choose from! Choose a character that  represents your own fighting style, like the lightning-fast Taokaka or the  wickedly powerful Tager. Drive your way to victory! Use the unique “Drive Attacks”  specific to each character to decimate your opponent. Depending on the  character, control the elements like wind and ice, or even absorb the life force  from your opponents. A plethora of offensive and defensive options at your disposal! Take advantage of Barriers, Counter Assaults, Rapid Cancels, and Distortion  Drives to turn the tide of battle! Story PrologueIn a time now long past, mankind faced extinction at the  hands of the 'Black Beast,' a creature that appeared out of the darkness. The  Beast was possessed by an awesome power, and it appeared that the time of man  would soon be at an end. It was then, in humanity's darkest hour, that six  heroes of unknown origin came forward to defeat the Beast. They brought with  them the ancient power of 'magic.' which they freely shared with mankind.  Turning their ingenuity to the formation of new, more powerful weapons, humanity  discovered a process by which they could infuse their own technology with the  power of ancient magic. It was in this way that humanity created the "Armagus'  and discovered a power far beyond what magic or technology alone could have  given them.With this new-found power, mankind once again confronted the  Beast, with the six heroes fighting alongside them. After many long,  blood-soaked battles, the Beast finally fell, ending what would come to be know  as 'The First War of Magic.' The heroes who had fought beside human warriors in  the First War of Magic were immortalized for their deeds, and through  generations came to be known as the 'Six Heroes.'It was during the First  War that an organization was formed to regulate the use of the 'Grimoire  Armagus,' the Armagus training texts. Called the 'New World Void Space Cue  Administration Bureau,' it was this organization, and the power it wielded  through the use of the Grimoire Armagus, that brought about great advances  across the spectrum of human technology. These advances threw mankind into a  vast and all-encompassing reconstruction. Decades have passed since the  Bureau established itself as a dictatorship and Armagus became the deciding  factor in nearly all of humanity's affairs. This has led to a large  socioeconomic gap between those who can wield the power of Armagus and those who  cannot. Tensions began to flare, and before long a rebel organization calling  itself the 'Ikaruga Union' appeared, defying the totalitarian authority of the  Bureau, which began referring to itself as the Novus Orbis Librarium Armagus ("The Library"). With the creation of the Ikaruga Union, angry thoughts became open  hostilities and 'The Second War of Magic' began. It was this conflict, which  also came to be known as 'The Ikaruga Civil War,' that saw humans using the  power of Armagus against one another for the first time.The Second War  came to a close with the destruction of the Ikaruga Union. Afraid of further  conflict, the Library consummated its subjugation of the populace by issuing the  following decree: 'Whosoever chooses to defy the New World Void Space Cue  Administration Bureau shall be put to death, without exception.'Several  years after the end of the Second War, a branch of the Library reputed to command  a force as powerful as an entire nation's army was suddenly and utterly destroyed. The few survivors spoke in hushed, shaken tones of a single man who  had appeared out of nowhere, cutting down all in his path. His name was  Ragna the Bloodedge.He wages a one-man war against the power of the  Bureau, fighting to break its iron grip on humanity's throat. He is a man who  has declared war against the world itself. ~A.D. 2199 Dec~"By the end of the year, most citizens were  expecting the beginning of an era of unprecedented development. Unfortunately,  2199 was also the year that the Librarium's greatest foe, the man with the  highest single bounty on record, Ragna the Bloodedge, was rumored to have  appeared in the 13th Hierarchal City of Kagutsuchi. People gave him the nickname  Grim Reaper, and it was said that his goal was the obliteration of the Librarium  in its entirety. Following the rumors, people began to make their way to  Kagutsuchi-some after the incredible bounty on [Ragna's] head others after the  "ultimate power" said to be in his possession... and a few whose only interest  was his assassination for the Librarium."  The story has several different plotlines for the various playable characters that intersect with each other in many ways. Canonically, all these story threads are true, but the explanation is that (except for the True Ending) every single one ends with Ragna falling into the Cauldron with v-13, forming the Black Beast. Then a giant laser beam fired by Take-Mikazuchi at that same Cauldron somehow sparks a time loop which turns the clock back almost a century in time with the first appearance of the Black Beast, erasing the events that happened over and over again.   This continues on and on in everyone's story until the loop is finally broken in the True Ending, when Noel saves Ragna from falling into the Cauldron with v-13 and Rachel activates the Tsukiyomi Unit to save Kagutsuchi from destruction. However, it turns out to be part of the evil Terumi's plan all along, who kept manipulating events so the time loop would repeat over and over until events finally conspired to let him acquire the true copy of the Azure Grimoire from Noel. In the end, Terumi escapes to move on to the next part of his evil plan, which involves conscripting Tsubaki Yayoi to hunt down her former classmates Jin and Noel for treason.  Characters BlazBlue features a plethora of unique characters each with their own backstories:     Ragna the Bloodedge Ragna the Bloodedge "Ragna is a man with such power that he  has become known as the 'God of Death' ( Shinigami, or 'Grim Reaper' in the NA version.)  He fights ceaselessly against the iron rule of The Library, as he wages a one-man war against them to break their grip on humanity's throat. The Library labeled him an SS-class threat in response and now everyone seeks his head. Some want the massive reward, others seek the Azure Grimoire and its incredible power that he is rumored to hold." Jin Kisaragi "Jin was born into the noble Kisaragi line and is a Major within the military of the Novus Orbis Librarium.  For most of his life, he has followed orders without question. What could have driven him to defy them now?"     Noel Vermillion "Noel is a member of the noble  Vermillion Family, and she grew-up in a remote region of the world.  She is a  soldier for The Library and also Jin's direct subordinate. After Jin's sudden  disappearance, Noel was ordered to go to Kagutsuchi to pick up  the  trail."      Iron Tager Iron Tager (TR-0009)  "Iron  Tager suffered what should have been a fatal wound during the Ikaruga Civil War.  However, he managed to survive and return to service as a cyborg with the help  of the scientist Kokonoe. Tager is feared by many as the "Red Devil of Sector  Seven." In reality, though, he is a very gentle person. His mission is to  retrieve Hakumen for Kokonoe as well as find Ragna."  Rachel Alucard "Rachel is the current head of the Alucard vampire  family. She lives a rather mundane life in her castle with only her butler and  pets for company. One day, she decides to leave for the 13th Hierarchical City  of Kagutsuchi, saying only that she is bored." Taokaka "A member of the Kaka clan, a clan that resides within  the bottom layers of Kagutsuchi.  Urban development has covered the sky above  her village, and Tao is determined to bring back the sun.  She hears money is  given to the one who defeats Ragna." Litchi Faye Ling "A doctor in Orient Town, one of the lower parts of  Kagutsuchi. As a scientist and doctor, she is loved and admired by the residents  of Orient Town. She's grown to love Orient Town as well, almost enough to forget  why she came in the first place..."  Arakune"Housing a  myriad of insects, this man walks with corrupted magic.  Living in an  underground waste disposal factory, he has been seen eating humans and the Kaka  clan.  Detecting an immense power, Arakune begins to move  out."     Bang ShishigamiBang Shishigami  "After losing their home in the Ikaruga Civil War, Bang  and his clan of ninjas fled to Kagutsuchi to regroup and wait for a chance to  restore their homeland to its former glory. While in Kagutsuchi, Bang decided to  make his debut as a 'Vigilante of Justice'. When he learned Ragna the Bloodedge  had come to Kagutsuchi, he decided to bring the legendary criminal to  justice!"  Carl Clover"Carl  is considered a first class vigilante.  With his mysterious doll, Nirvana, he  has brought many criminals to justice.  After hearing news of his next target,  Ragna the Bloodedge, Carl heads out to  Kagutsuchi." Hakumen"One of the Six Heroes of legend. When he disappeared  after the war, people assumed he was gone for good. Little do they know, he was  lying in wait in the bowels of Kagutsuchi, but for what? Does his sword exist to  cut the Black Beast, or something else?" v-13"A mysterious  child who appeared out of a giant cauldron hidden in the depths of kagutsuchi.  What can this emotionless cyborg of a girl possibly want with Kagutsuchi?"   Gameplay Systems and Controls Basic Controls  BlazBlue  ControlsThe main controls are the eight-way joystick and the four buttons. Along with the three attack buttons Light (A), Middle (B), and Heavy (C), there is a "Drive" button (D) which gives each character a special attack.  In addition to the basic "dash" and "jump" buttons found in a fighting game, there is an "aerial dash" and "two-step jump".  Life Gauge    Heat GaugeThe "Heat Gauge" is necessary for powerful attacks such as  the "Distortion Drive". It is also necessary for a "Rapid Cancel", where you can  cancel an opponent's move when they try to attack. You can increase the "Heat  Gauge" by landing an attack on the enemy.   Barrier GaugeThe "Barrier Gauge" is needed for "barriers" that will  defend you against the damage dealt by the enemy. The gauge also applies to the  "Barrier Burst" (press all 4 buttons together) where you can blast someone away  while you guard. When the "Barrier Gauge" reaches zero, your defense level will  go down for a period of time. The "Barrier Gauge" will refill over time.  Libra GaugeThe "Libra Gauge" is a shared gauge between both combatants,  that shifts towards each player's side when blocking attacks occur.  When this  gauge has reached all the way to one side, that character will be Guard Crushed  and thus stunned.  It's named after the Zodiac's Libra, referring to the tipping  of the scales of balance.  Useful Links              Official website              Aksys  Games  Releases   Arcades BlazBlue: Calamity Trigger  was released in arcades on Nov 19  20, 2008 in Japan and North America  respectively.    ConsolesThe console version was released June 25, 2009 in Japan on  the Xbox 360 and PlayStation 3, while it saw a North American release on June  30, 2009. The game finally saw a release in Europe on April 2, 2010. Contrary to  earlier reports and rumors, this version was nearly identical to the North  American and Japanese versions of the games, featuring no new characters or  changes to preexisting characters. The European version instead featured more  character colors and "Unlimited" versions of characters, "super" versions of  current characters with better properties on most of their moves. A  limited edition of the game was also released that included the game, a two disc  soundtrack and a bonus Blu-ray or a DVD depending on the console. The bonus disc  showed you the basics of the game as well as going into more details about  character specific stuff such as combos and strategies. The videos feature  expert players from Dustloop.com and Shoryuken.com. The European limited edition  shipped with both a bonus DVD with around 2 hours of tutorials and  character-specific strategies and a 96 page full color art book featuring  original art and illustrations.   HandheldBlazBlue: Calamity Trigger  saw a release on Sony's PSP handheld device on February 25, 2010 in Japan and  March 9, 2010 in North America. The took advantage of the PSPs ad-hoc  capabilities, allowing players to create rooms and battle with up to three  opponents. The PSP version of the game also featured a mode entirely new to the  game, the Legion Mode, a mode in which you choose a character and "conquer a  map" by defeating enemy armies. Defeating an enemy army basically boils down to  a King of Fighters-esque Team Battle. As you progress along the map and defeat  various "armies", you are allowed to recruit characters you have defeated into  your squad.  PCA PC version of Blazblue: Calamity Trigger  has been announced and is slated for a Japanese release on August 26, 2010. The PC  version will feature all of the released DLC--the color palettes and the  unlimited characters--included for free. More significantly, the PC version will  feature cross-platform play with the Xbox 360 version, allowing owners of the PC  version to play against owners of the Xbox 360 version.  System Requirements Minimum System RequirementsOperating System : Microsoft Windows XP / Windows Vista / Windows 7Processor : Intel Pentium IV at 3.0 GHz (XP) / Intel Core 2 Duo (Vista / Win 7)Video Card : 256 MB VRAM – NVIDIA Geforce 7900 / ATI Radeon X1900Memory : 1 GB RAMHard Disk : 10 GB of free Hard Drive spaceSound Card: DirectX CompatibleDirect X : 9.0cControls : Keyboard  MouseInstallation : DVD-ROM Drive Recommended System RequirementsOperating System : Windows Vista / Windows 7Processor : Intel Core 2 Quad / Intel Core i5/i7Video Card : 512 MB VRAM – NVIDIA Geforce 8800 / ATI Radeon HD3700Memory : 2 GB RAMHard Disk : 10 GB of free Hard Drive spaceSound Card: DirectX CompatibleDirect X : 9.0cControls : Keyboard  MouseInstallation : DVD-ROM Drive      Other Requirements: Multiplayer requires log-in to Games for Windows - LIVE.</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21344">Hokuto no Ken: Shinpan no Sousousei Kengou Retsuden</game><game id="21367">Sengoku Basara X</game><game id="21863">Melty Blood: Act Cadenza</game><game id="20477">Arcana Heart</game><game id="22812">Battle Fantasia</game><game id="17678">The Last Blade</game><game id="5692">Samurai Shodown</game><game id="21519">The King of Fighters XII</game><game id="20456">Street Fighter IV</game><game id="11813">Guilty Gear</game><game id="617">NeoGeo Battle Coliseum</game><game id="20728">Tatsunoko vs. Capcom: Ultimate All Stars</game><game id="379">Waku Waku 7</game><game id="18647">JoJo's Bizarre Adventure</game><game id="16738">Galaxy Fight: Universal Warriors</game><game id="28437">Super Street Fighter IV</game><game id="20292">Astra Superstars</game><game id="29341">Arcana Heart 3</game><game id="27723">Vanguard Princess</game><game id="21930">Touhou 7.5 - Immaterial and Missing Power</game><game id="21325">Touhou 10.5 - Scarlet Weather Rhapsody</game><game id="27857">Touhou Hisoutensoku - Choudokyuu Ginyoru no Nazo o Oe</game><game id="34218">Chaos Code</game><game id="34082">Skullgirls</game><game id="35719">Ougon Musoukyoku X</game><game id="36051">Ougon Musou Kyoku</game><game id="36274">Persona 4 Arena</game><game id="36947">Ougon Musou Kyoku Cross</game><game id="37140">Melty Blood: Actress Again: Current Code</game><game id="42679">Guilty Gear Xrd -SIGN-</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1871435-box_bbct.png</image></root>