<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21788</id><name>Jump Ultimate Stars</name><description>OverviewJump Ultimate Stars is a fighting video game developed by Ganbarion and published by Nintendo for the Nintendo DS, released on November 23, 2006. It is the sequel to Jump Super Stars. It is similar to the popular Super Smash Bros. series, except it uses characters from the Weekly Shonen Jump.IMPORTANTIt should be noted that the game is in Japanese, from the story to the menus, and will require you to be knowledgeable in reading Japanese. This should not be a reason for stopping people from importing this game. There are several tutorials online on how to navigate the menus. Not only that, they are very intuitive and become second nature after a few play sessions.Several people are turned off by this fact though, so its important to keep this in mind before venturing any further into importing this game.Koma SystemJump Ultimate Stars utilizes the same "panel" system as it did in its predecessor, Jump Super Stars. Once again, players have a 5x4 grid that allows them to place whatever panels they seem fit to be part of their "deck". The koma come in different shapes and sizes. There are three types of "koma", battle koma, support koma, and help koma. Battle koma are 4-8 panels large, and serve as the playable characters a player can use in a battle. Higher panel koma usually yield higher damage special attacks and hp, but at the cost of having more characters in a deck. Support koma are 2-3 panels, and are a one time effect when used. They can be used as long as the player has at least one energy(SP) bar. Help koma are only 1 panel, and grant certain effects to a selected character, such as granting the ability for a triple jump, air boost, gaining more energy from attacking/blocking, etc. When creating a deck, one of each koma must be put in the deck, or else it will be invalid and unusable. As well, a "leader" character must be chosen (this character will appear first and be the "face" of your deck), and the player can set macros to the L and R buttons to any koma they wish to use.GameplayBattles are fought on a 2D plane on different stages. Each stage is made to be related to a particular anime/manga series, and it is also made to look like a page inside a manga book. In fact, players can destroy the sides of the page and fall out (which results in a ring out). Platforms are present in most of the stages, as well as "gimmicks", such as the platforms moving or random effects that occur throughout the stage. Crates also appear in the stage, and can be broken to yield items that either positively or negatively affect the player.Fighting is similar to Super Smash Bros. Players have a jump (and double jump) in the A button, two attacks buttons (B and Y), and a special attack button(X). Each character also has an Ultimate Action (UA), done by pressing or holding the select button, and these actions range from a short stun attack, to healing HP or SP. The player can also dash by double tapping a direction, and Jump Ultimate Stars introduces the ability to air dash as well. The attacks a character can do vary, as like Super Smash Bros, the player can perform neutral, side, up, and down attacks. This is done by pressing said direction with B or Y. The special attack only has neutral and Up X attacks. The L and R shoulder buttons can be used to map hot-keys to summon Support characters or call in Battle characters.Nature SystemJump Ultimate Stars uses a nature system, which has a rock, paper, scissors relationship. Each battle koma has its own affinity, strength, knowledge, or laughter. Strength beats knowledge, knowledge beats laughter, and laughter beats strength. The stronger type will deal more damage to the weaker type, and this is visible in-game as contacting hits will result in a blue "hit" instead of the regular "hit".ModesJump Ultimate Stars features three different modes, which offer various things from the main storyline to online play.J-UniverseWith your deck, go on the different worlds of Shonen Jump and complete the different objectives to gain new characters and new gems used to upgrade characters. There are also hidden objectives that can be unlocked.J-ArenaThis Includes a ranking play mode, that requires the player to compete in a tournament of 20 battles to see how far they can go. The battles have different objectives and modes, such as deathmatch, star collection, and point mode. At the end of each battle, points are awarded based on their place in the battle (1st - 4th). If a player manages to stay 1st in the tournament by the end, they are granted a bonus battle at the end, and if they win that one as well, they are rewarded with a pre-made deck.There is also a mission mode in J-Arena, as well as practice and regular battle modes.WirelessPlay against people from all around the world with Wifi connection or against friends with multi-card gameplay. After a battle, a player can choose to "save" their opponent's deck, either for practice or observation. There is also the option for Download Play. It is limited, however, to a single stage and set Koma.J-QuizTake quizzes about your favorite mangas to test if your knowledge about these series is as good as you think it is.CharactersThe list of characters is pretty big so here's the list of characters with the different franchises they are from and how you can use them in Game:Black CatBattle Character(s)Train HeartnetEve BlackSupport Character(s)Sven VolfiedHelp Character(s)Saya MinatsukiKyoko KirisakiBleachBattle Character(s)Ichigo KurosakiRukia KuchikiRenji AbaraiToshiro HitsugayaSupport Character(s)Uryu IshidaYasutora "Chad" SadoOrihime InoueYoruichi ShihoinKonSousuke AizenByakyuya KuchikiHelp Character(s)ZangetsuIsshin KurosakiTatsuki ArisawaKisuke UraharaKaname TosenGin IchimaruBobobo-bo Bo-boboBattle Character(s)Bobobo-bo Bo-boboDon PatchSupport Character(s)Tokoro TennosukeGaohBeautyHeppokomaruHelp Character(s)HatenkouSoftonService ManGyorai GirlDengaku ManKo PatchBusou RenkinBattle Character(s)Kazuki MutouSupport Character(s)PapillonHelp Character(s)Tokiko TsumaruCaptain TsubasaSupport Character(s)Tsubasa OzoraGenzo WakabayashiKojiro HyugaHelp Character(s)Roberto HongoSanae NakazawaCobraSupport Character(s)CobraLady ArmaroidCrystal BoyD.Gray-manBattle Character(s)Allen WalkerLenalee LeeSupport Character(s)RabiYuu KandaAleister CrowleyHelp Character(s)Miranda LottKomui LeeRiver WenhamCross MarianDr.SlumpBattle Character(s)Arale NorimakiDr. MashiritoSupport Character(s)Gajira NorimakiUnchi-kunHelp Character(s)Senbei NorimakiMidori NorimakiObocchamanDeath NoteSupport Character(s)Light YagamiLNearMelloMisa AmaneDragon BallBattle Character(s)GokuGohanGotenksVegetaPiccoloFriezaMajin BuuSupport Character(s)KrillinFuture TrunksHelp Character(s)BulmaMuten-RoshiHerculeKaiousamaEyeshield 21Support Character(s)Sena KobayakawaYoichi HirumaKurita RyoukanGen " Musashi"Taro "Monta" RaimonCerberusJumonji, Kuroki, ToganoDevil BatSeijuro ShinHelp Character(s)Mamori AnezakiSuzuna TakiYukimitsu ManabuDaikichi KomusubiNatsuhiko TakiTetsuo IshimaruDoburoku SakakiHaruto SakurabaGintamaBattle Character(s)Gintoki SakataKaguraSupport Character(s)Shinpachi ShimuraKatsura "Zura" KotaroAyame SarutobiIsao KondoToshiro HijikataSogo OkitaHelp Character(s)Tae ShimuraOtoseTaizo HasegawaYamazakiSadaharuHokuto no KenBattle Character(s)KenshiroRaohSupport Character(s)ReiTokiHelp Character(s)YuriaBatRinHoushin EngiBattle Character(s)TaikoubouSupport Character(s)So DakkiHelp Character(s)Ou TenkunSibuxiangHunter x HunterBattle Character(s)Gon FreecsKillua ZaoldyeckSupport Character(s)KurapicaHisokaKuroro LuciferHelp Character(s)LeorioBiscuit KrugerI''sSupport Character(s)Iori YoshizukiItsuki AkibaIchigo 100%Support Character(s)Aya ToujoTsukasa NishinoSatsuki KitaojiYui MinamitoJigoku Sensei NuberSupport Character(s)Nueno "Nube" MeisukeYukimeHelp Character(s)Hiroshi TatenoKyoko InabaJungle King Ta-ChanSupport Character(s)Ta-chanHelp Character(s)JanePedroEtekichiJojo's Bizarre AdventureBattle Character(s)Jotaro KujoDio BrandoSupport Character(s)Joseph JoestarJosuke HigashitakaGiorno GiovannaJolyne KujoGyro ZepelliHelp Character(s)Rohan KishibeJohnny JoestarJonathan JoestarKatekyo Hitman Reborn!Battle Character(s)Tsuna  RebornSupport Character(s)Hayato GokuderaTakeshi GokuderaLamboI-PinKyoya HibariBianchiHelp Character(s)Kyoko SasagawaHary MiuraLeonKinnikumanBattle Character(s)KinnikumanSupport Character(s)TerrymanRobin MaskRamenmanBrocken Jr.WarsmanBuffalomanAshuramanHelp Character(s)MeatMayumiKochi KameBattle Character(s)Ryotsu KankichiSupport Character(s)Dajiro OharaReiko AkimotoKeiichi NakagawaVolvo SaigoKaipan DekaHayato HondaNeruo HigurashiHelp Character(s)Lemon GiboshiHigureHaya IsowashiTeraiAi Asato (Maria)Haru MidoTatsunosuke SakonjiMajin Tantei Nougami NeuroBattle Character(s)Neuro NogamiHelp Character(s)kane-chanEishi SasazukaX MajinMidori no MakibaouSupport Character(s)MakibaouCascadeHelp Character(s)ChuubeiMuhyo to RoujiBattle Character(s)Muhyo ToruSupport Character(s)Jirou KusanoYoichi "Ryouji" HikoPikoEsocheeHelp Character(s)Nana TakenouchiPageNarutoBattle Character(s)Naruto UzumakiSasuke UchihaSakura HarunoKakashi HatakeSupport Character(s)SaiGaaraHelp Character(s)JiraiyaTsunadeOrochimaruNinkuBattle Character(s)FuusukeHelp Character(s)PochiHiroyukiOne PieceBattle Character(s)Monkey D. LuffyRoronoa ZoroNamiSanjiNico RobinFrankySupport Character(s)Usopp/SogekingTony Tony ChopperHelp Character(s)ShanksKiwi  MozuThe Prince of TennisSupport Character(s)Ryoma EchizenTezuka KunimitsuShusuke FujiOishi  EijiTakeshi MomoshiroKaoru KaidohInui SadaharuTakashi KawamuraKeigo AtobePyuu to Fuku!Battle Character(s)Jaguar JunichiSupport Character(s)Piyo HikoHammerHamilHelp Character(s)Takane ShirakawaJirouPogiiRokudenashi BluesSupport Character(s)Maeda TaisonHelp Character(s)YoenjiKatsuji RokudenashiMasa-chanChiakiRurnouni KenshinBattle Character(s)Kenshin HimuraSupport Character(s)Sanosuke SagaraHajime SaitoYahiko MyojinMakoto ShishioHelp Character(s)Seijuro HikoKaoru KamiyaSaint SeiyaBattle Character(s)SeiyaSupport Character(s)ShiryuShunHyogaIkkiSaori "Athena" KidoHelp Character(s)MuSakigake!! OtokojukuBattle Character(s)Momotaro TsurugiEdajima HeihachiSupport Character(s)JOmito DateJaki DaigourinHienHelp Character(s)Genji TogashiRyuji ToramaruRaidenShaman KingBattle Character(s)Yoh AsakuraAnna KyoyamaSupport Character(s)Hao AsakuraHorohoroHelp Character(s)Ren TaoMantaAmidamaruChocoloveSlam DunkSupport Character(s)Hanamichi SakuragiKaede RukawaTakenori AkagiRyota MiyagiHisashi MitsuiHelp Character(s)Haruko AkagiMitsuyoshi AnzaiTaizo Mote King SagaSupport Character(s)Taizo MomoteHelp Character(s)SpinAisuTottemo! LuckymanSupport Character(s)LuckymanSuperstar ManYu-Gi-Oh!Battle Character(s)Yugi MutouSupport Character(s)Seto KaibaHelp Character(s)Katsuya JonouchiHiroto HondaAnzu MazakiYu Yu HakushoBattle Character(s)Yusuke UrameshiShuichi "Kurama" MinaminoHieiSupport Character(s)Kazuma KuwabaraHelp Character(s)GenkaiBotanInternational ReleaseThe game is not going to be brought over from Japan due to copyright issues. Reggie Fils-Aime confirmed this shortly after the games launch. Many import retailers like Play-Asia offer the game at a significantly higher price than most local DS games but that has not stopped it from being one of the most heavily imported titles as the DS is region free.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20588">Super Smash Bros. Brawl</game><game id="17743">Super Smash Bros. Melee</game><game id="20547">Naruto: Ninja Destiny</game><game id="21241">Jump Super Stars</game><game id="21697">Katekyo Hitman Reborn! DS Flame Rumble Hyper - Moeyo Mirai</game><game id="20100">Power Stone</game><game id="28102">Kabuki Ittou Ryoudan</game><game id="22980">Windy x Windam</game><game id="24766">Cartoon Network Universe: FusionFall</game><game id="30633">One Piece Grand Battle: Swan Colosseum</game><game id="30558">Sunday vs. Magazine: Shuuketsu! Choujou Daikessen</game><game id="34084">One Piece: Gigant Battle</game><game id="34429">Cartoon Network: Punch Time Explosion</game><game id="36239">Famicom Jump: Hero Retsuden</game><game id="37452">Famicom Jump II: Saikyou no Shichinin</game><game id="38140">PlayStation All-Stars Battle Royale</game><game id="38313">Cult Jump</game><game id="39954">Pen 1 Grand Prix: Penguin no Mondai Special</game><game id="40839">J-Stars Victory Vs</game><game id="35573">Super Smash Bros.</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2215048-box_jus.png</image></root>