<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21793</id><name>Downhill Domination</name><description>OverviewMOOSE!  Downhill Domination is an intense racer featuring mountain bikes, interactive environments, and cheeky riders. You race downhill against numerous riders and fight your way to the finish line. You have the ability to knock down your fellow racers with a variety of attacks including: kicks, sticks, and homing water bottles. You also have the ability to pull off a large amount of tricks in order to fill your energy meter, which gives you the ability to sprint for a brief period of time. The game features a full career mode that allows you to upgrade your racer, bike, and compete for an array of sponsorships. Career mode features a number of different events including: Freeride, Technical Downhill, Mountain Cross, and Freestlye. When you’ve had enough of single-player, the game also features full multi-player for up to 4 players. Multi-player features a few exclusive modes including: Moshbowl, Super Jump, and Dual Slalom. GameplayBit of Flare  Domination is a mountain biking game that focuses much more heavily on an arcade racing approach. The tracks take place on vast, expansive environments that offer multiple paths to the end goal. Environments are riddled with trees, rocks, hazardous zones, cliffs and jumps. Every course is set in a very steep, downhill slant and the game heavily encourages fighting. The player has two buttons dedicated to fighting, either to chuck water bottles at opponents or simply to punch them. Upgrades and stat boosts can be picked up along the course, ranging from score multipliers to super-speed pedaling.  When you play you will notice that the controls are very tight and responsive, this makes it feel arcady though that is for the better.  You are bound to bail off your bike multiple times during a race which makes it interesting and enjoyable because watching your character flying down the hill is hilarious!    Cooperative play is also supported, but not just between you and your friends.  You are able to do a 2 player campaign which is great if you don't have 4 friends to play with.  This acts just like a single player campaign except it is adjusted so that you are also competing against your friend.   Gametypes There are several different types of mountain biking and several of those types are found in this game.  This includes Mountain Cross, Technical Downhill and Freeride.   Free Ride - is an open  course, free of competitors and time restraints.  Technical Downhill -  presents various kinds of specialist challenges, narrow courses,  multiple obstacles, etc.  Mountain Cross - a motocross-style set of  races, is designed with wide, short courses and more jumping  possibilities.   Riders While Downhill Domination features a cast of mostly fictional characters (14 to be exact),  professional bike riders can be unlocked such as Tara Llanes, Eric Carter, Brian Lopes, Richie Schley and Missy Glove. Some of the fictional riders include: Cosmo of Great Britain, Jonnie of Australia, Mai of Japan, Ajax of the U.S.A., Kalolo of Tonga, and T-Bag (yes, that's his real name) of unknown origins.  Customization  You are able to customize your character and upgrade to your bike with better parts as you progress through the game.  You are also able to learn new attacks and even equip yourself with weapons.  You do this all through the money that you earn for placing in a race, performing tricks during the race, weaving through flags and how much damage you did to the other racers.  All of the bike parts in the game are actual manufacturers that develop and design parts for mountain bikes in the real world.  You can also get sponsored by certain companies to gain access to certain parts and bikes. Events/Courses  The courses featured in Downhill Domination are based off of real locations, for the most part, though are in no way actual reproductions of the mountains themselves.  There is a great amount of diversity in each of the courses, some are on snowy mountains others are covered in trees or rocks.  Believe it or not there are even some courses that have mine shafts and of course there is a fair share of waterfalls, creeks and rivers.  Most courses have a change in each of these environments as you travel down the mountain.  On these courses you will also finding living obstacles such as polar bears, moose, elk, deer, hikers and vehicles.  The weather is also an aspect that changes on the courses, so in some cases there will be rain and lightning.     There are 27 different courses and they are the following:  Mt. Middule, ItalyRed Pass, U.S.A.Mt. Konawaki, U.S.A.Mt. Quintanardo, PeruMt. Zorkovaska, RussiaMt. Liddelroch, ScotlandMt. Imasaki, JapanSalt City, U.S.A.Mt. McShiey, Canada Soundtrack "Go" by Andy Hunter"Let's Get Retarded" by Black Eyed Peas"8-Track" by Brian Setzer"Soul Creation" by Cinder"Breakbeat Suckers" by CIRRUS"Let Down And Alone" by Death by Stereo"Take It Off" by The Donnas"Simple Minded" by Dragpipe"Feelin' Kinda Strange" by Drummatic Twins"Bike Thief (Schnellspanner Remix)" by Freezepop"Time 2 Build" by The Herbaliser feat. Blade"I Got You (I Feel Good) (Digital Johnson Remix)" by James Brown"Pedal to the Metal" by Kazzer"Thursday" by Morphine"Bang On!" by The Propellerheads"Mary, Mary" by Run D.M.C."Your Disease" by Saliva"(sic)" by Slipknot"The Corn Rocket" by Southern Culture On The Skids"Extreme Days" by Toby Mac</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2341">Mat Hoffman's Pro BMX</game><game id="3238">Dave Mirra Freestyle BMX 3</game><game id="5474">BMX XXX</game><game id="7099">Mat Hoffman's Pro BMX 2</game><game id="9243">Dave Mirra Freestyle BMX</game><game id="6737">Dave Mirra Freestyle BMX: Maximum Remix</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2275982-box_dhd.png</image></root>