<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21815</id><name>Backyard Football</name><description>Backyard Football was the first football game from the        Backyard Sports franchise. It had cartoon looking 2-D graphics, and had smooth gameplay. And in signature Backyard Sports style, it features real NFL players, as kids.  CharactersNFL Players This game had eight pro players, six of them being Quarterbacks. Backyard Football Team Photo        Steve Young (QB) Drew Bledsoe (QB)      John Elway (QB) Barry Sanders (RB)     Randall Cunningham (QB)    Brett Favre (QB)   Jerry Rice (WR)  Dan Marino (QB)  Fictional CharactersNo backyard game would be the same without the 30 core players.  Jocinda SmithDmitri Ronny Dobbs Mario Luna Achmed Khan Tony Delvecchio Dimitri Petrovich Gretchen Hasselhoff Lueane Lui Kimmy Eckman Ricky Johnson Annie Frazier Mikey Thomas Lisa Crocket Amir Khan Sally Dobbs Pete Wheeler Dante Robinson Vicki Kawaguchi Reese Worthington Kenny Kawaguchi Stephanie Morgan Sidney Weber Ashely WeberKiesha Angela Delvecchio Marky Dubois Pablo Sanchez Billy Jean Blackwood Jorge Garcia Ernie Steele Kiesha Phillips  Teams Every NFL team as well as other custom teams were available for play. NFL Teams  Baltimore Ravens Cincinnati Bengals Cleveland Browns Chicago Bears Detroit Lions Green Bay Packers Pittsburgh Steelers Colts Minnesota Vikings Atlanta Falcons Indianapolis Colts Carolina Panthers Jacksonville Jaguars New Orleans Saints Tampa Bay Buccaneers Buffalo Bills Dallas Cowboys Miami Dolphins New York GiantsRams New England Patriots Philadelphia Eagles New York Jets Washington Redskins Denver Broncos Kansas City Chiefs Oakland Raiders San Diego Chargers Arizona Cardinals Sand Francisco 49ers  Seattle Seahawks St. Louis Rams Tennessee Titans  Custom TeamsThere are 9 custom teams you can pick to play as in this game. You can pick what ever color combination you want as well Wombats Rockets Pigskins All Stars Fishers Hornets Monsters Melonheads Bombers  Create a Player ModeYou can create a player to play on your team along with the NFL and core players. You can decideGender Ethnicity Hair style Head shape Name Right or Left handed Abilities (stats)  Birthday  </description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="21">Football</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25614">NCAA Football 10</game><game id="35598">Jerry Rice and Nitus' Dog Football</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1516/345305-pkgimg1.jpg</image></root>