<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21830</id><name>Initial D: Street Stage</name><description>OverviewThis game is a port of Initial D Arcade Stage 3 with some features that separate it from its arcade counterpart. The most significant one is the point system which has been replaced with a trading card based system. Trading Cards Trading cards are acquired whenever a race is finished, regardless of the outcome (except when the player quits). These trading cards range from character profiles, unlockables such as bonus music, or parts to  upgrade or customize your car. The game runs at 30 FPS with a slight downgrade of the graphics, however it remains true to the arcade game.Unlike the PS2 Initial D: Special Stage, this version of Initial D has a multiplayer function for wireless head to head battles. This game also features the ability to save replays.GameplayThe gameplay is much like an arcade racer where you are able to select a track and race on it. There are multiple races on the same track, however they are all one on one. A skillful use of shifting is needed to conquer the much tougher courses in the game. Cars will understeer or oversteer depending on the car type.As you win or lose races, you will obtain trading cards which either unlock various goodies such as sound tests for the characters, or gain parts to upgrade your car with. ModesThe modes in this game are essentially the same as the arcade version with a few extras.ArcadeThe same thing as the arcade. Basically, players race rivals until they become the new legend of the street.Bunta ChallengeRace Bunta on varying difficulties on all tracks. He has ten difficulty settings on each track.Time TrialYour usual time trial. You will receive feedback from Ryosuke after your run.MultiplayerNo, there is no infrastructure link unfortunately. You can, however race your friends who also have this game. Within multiplayer, you are able to choose varying types of races. You can choose the default "race to the finish" rule, or like the anime, you can try your hand at "cat and mouse". Basically, you win if you are leading and outrun the opponent at a set distance, or if you are behind, you overtake your opponent. Trading CardsView your trading cards here basically. You can only unlock items by viewing what is on the trading card in this mode.Project D WebsiteMajority of your goodies will result in additions to Project D's website which include soundtests. You are also able to view tips to master each track as well as time trial records.Garage (Uncertain about real translation)This is where you are able to change your cars and tune your cars.CarsAll cars are divided into four different types of drive trains:FR - Rear Wheel DriveFF - Front Wheel Drive4WD - Four Wheel DriveMR - Mid Rear DriveFR and MR cars tend to be drifiter than the other drive trains. 4WD and FF cars are grip types, however 4WD cars also have superior traction in unfavorable weather conditions.This version of Initial D basically contains the same cars from arcade stage 3 which are the following:(*  New to this version from previous games)Toyota:Trueno GT-APEX (AE-86) FRTuned up Trueno GT-ApexLevin GT-APEX (AE-86) FRLevin SR (AE-85) FRMR2 G-Limited (SW-20) MRMR-S S Edition (ZZW30) MRAltezza RS200 (AKA: Lexus IS) (SXE10) FRCelica GT-4 (ST205) 4WDNissanSkyline GTR V-Spec II (BNR32) 4WDSkyline GTR V-Spec II (BNR34) 4WDSkyline GT 25 Turbo (ER34) FRSilvia K's (S14) FRSilvia Q's (S14) FRSilvia K's Aero (S14) FRSilvia Spec-R (S15) FR180SX Type X (RPS13) FRSileighty (RPS13) FRMitsubishiLancer GSR Evolution III (CE9A) 4WDLancer RS Evolution IV (CN9A) 4WDLancer RS Evolution V (CP9A) * 4WDLancer Evolution VI T.M. Edition (CP9A) * 4WDLancer GSR Evolution VII (CT9A) 4WDHondaCivic SIR II (EG6) FFCivic Type R (EK9) FFIntegra Type R (DC2) FFS2000 (AP1) FFMazdaRX7 Infiniti III (FC3S) FRRX-7 Type R (FD3S) FRKeisuke's RX-7 Type RRX-7 Spirit R Type A (FD3S) FRRX-8 Type S (SE3P) * FRRoadster S Special (NA6C) FRRoadster RS (AKA: Miata MX-5) (NB8C) FRSubaruImpreza WRX Type R STi Version V (GC8V) 4WDImpreza WRX-STi Version VI (GC8) 4WDImpreza WRX-STi (GDB) 4WDSuzukiCappuccino (EA11R) FRTracksCompared to Arcade Stage 3, the most noticeable track that has been removed was Akina (Snow). Otherwise, all tracks have remained intact.MyogiUsuiAkagiAkinaHappogaharaIrohazakaShomaruTsuchisakaBackground MusicThe background music loops much more than in the arcade. What is different in this version is the addition of certain bonus tracks and the replacement of "Black Out" with "Power of Sound".Dog FightSpeedy Speed BoyRemember MeSave MeOver the RainbowStop Your Self ControlCrazy for LoveExpress LovePower of SoundFall in the Web of DesirePamelaFight for Love TonightGet Another Chance (New)Fire on the Beat (New)Ready to Go (New)Changes (New)Demolition (New)Mad About You (New)Overload (New)Fevernova (New)Dancin' in My DreamsArcade RivalsThe following is the list of characters you will face in Arcade mode along with the car they drive:MyogiItsuki Takeuichi - Levin SR (AE85)Rival Selection ScreenKenji - 180SX Type X (RPS13)Shingo Shoiji - Civic SIR II (EG6)UsuiToru Suetsugu - Roadster RS (NB8C)Atsurou Kawai - Skyline GT 25 Turbo (ER34)Mako Sato and Sayuki - Sileighty (RPS13)AkagiTwo Guys from Tokyo - Silvia Spec-R (S15)Dialogue vs. ItsukiKenta Nakamura - Silvia Q's (S14)Keisuke Takahashi - RX-7 Type R (FD3S)AkinaIketani Kouichiro - Silvia K's (S13)Takeshi Nakazato -  Skyline GTR V-Spec II (BNR32)Kyouichi Sudo - Lancer GSR Evolution III (CE9A)Ryosuke Takahashi - RX-7 Infiniti III (FC3S)Takumi Fujiwara - Trueno GT-APEX (AE86)IrohazakaSeiji Iwaki - Lancer RS Evolution IV (CN9A)Kyouichi Sudo - Lancer GSR Evolution III (CE9A)Kai Kogashiwa - MR2 G-Limited (SW-20)HappogaharaDaiki Ninomiya - Civic Type R (EK9)Smiley Sakai - Integra Type R (DC2)Tomoyuki Tachi - Civic Type R (EK9)ShomaruNobuhiko Akiyama - Altezza RS200 (SXE10)Sakamoto - Cappuccino (EA11R)Wataru Akiyama - Levin GT-APEX (AE86)TsuchisakaKyoko Iwase - RX-7 Type R (FD3S)Ryosuke Takahashi - RX-7 Infiniti III (FC3C)Kuru Waru - Lancer RS Evolution V (CP9A)Shiro Waru - Lancer Evolution VI T.M. Edition (CP9A)Keisuke Takahashi - RX-7 Type R (FD3S)Takumi Fujiwara - Trueno GT-APEX (AE86)AkinaBunta Fujiwara - Impreza WRX Type R STi Version V (GC8V)</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21689">Wangan Midnight</game><game id="26956">Wangan Midnight Maximum Tune</game><game id="26958">Wangan Midnight Maximum Tune 3</game><game id="26957">Wangan Midnight Maximum Tune 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2776/246186-initial_d.jpg</image></root>