<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21848</id><name>Final Fantasy Type-0</name><description>OverviewFinal Fantasy Type-0 is an action RPG for the PSP that was released in Japan in October of 2011. The original direction of the game, however, was quite different. Type-0 was originally entitled Final Fantasy Agito XIII, and was intended to be a part of Square Enix's Fabula Nova Crystallis sub-series of games set within the universe of Final Fantasy XIII. It was also originally developed as a cell phone game due to the popularity of Before Crisis, with functions only available on cellphones, but development shifted to the PSP in hopes of broadening the game's audience. Another reason for the shift was that Square Enix wanted to release the game for a more powerful platform.At a Square Enix event held on January 18th, 2011, it was officially announced that Final Fantasy Agito XIII was being renamed Final Fantasy Type-0, a title with the intent of becoming the starting point for a new franchise. The game has been completely separated from Final Fantasy XIII's story and world, and is now set within its own original universe. At the same event, it was also announced that Type-0 would ship on two UMDs due to the large amount of voice acting in the game with over thirty speaking parts.StoryMap of OriensThe world of Type-0 is called Oriens and is broken up to 4 regions each powered by a crystal. (Crystals have for years been a staple in Final Fantasy universes, and typically their purpose powering stuff. If the crystal breaks usually that place is screwed.) The names of the 4 regions are as follows: Rubrum, Milites, Anaze, and Kogai. [I don't think the names will be changed much if at all later.] These 4 regions are surrounded around a magic school called "Peristylium", specifically in Type-0 it will focus on the Rubrum Peristyilum Suzaku Magic academy, which is on an island not attached to the main land of the continent.Rubrum Peristylum Suzaku Magic Academy seen in the game.A pact/treaty of peace called "Pax Codex" was signed between the nations where the crystals are located. Under the command of High Commander Cid Oldstien, (Final Fantasy sure loves their Cids) Byakko breaks said peace treaty and begins an assault on other nations in airships and L'Cie with magical armor. He (Cid) manages to take over all the nations except Suzaku because of their strong resistance. Byakko does manage to disable the crystal's power though and tries to convince the Rubrum president to lay down their weapons and surrender because without the crystal the nation is pretty much without power and can't defend themselves. 12 students some how managed to keep their powers with the crystal pact (I am assuming this crystal pact is what one needs to do to get their magic powers in the first place and if the crystal goes down or becomes disabled they cant use them but, this is different for these 12.) and plan to stop Cid's hostile take over with an operation they have dubbed "Operation Apostle" to take down his forces.Extra infoMoogle in this game actually means something. MOOGLE - Military Operation Organization Guidance Logistic Expert. Talk about a mouth full.Characters12 main characters that were first announced.Machina Kunagiri, a black haired young male, that uses 2 Volt rapiers in battle. Machina can easily rack up a 10 hit combo with his sabers, including his Spin Drive ability that damages enemies within a radius.Rem Tokimiya, a brown haired young woman that uses a pair of dual daggers in battle and can also cast magic like the others. Rem uses a mix of strikes and magic in battle with her daggers. Her special attack, Aspir Venom, does damages from enemies and saps them of their MP.Machina and Rem are said to be the main protagonists of the game.Ace: Like the Aces in playing cards, his originally going to be named just "Card" but since the entire cast is now based around playing cards, except Machina and Rem, it was changed. His weapon is Tarot cards.Playing Ace is almost a game in itself. He has an ability called deck open which allows him to draw 4 new cards and depending on the cards he can heal or enhance abilities of other party members. He can also throw cards at close range or a distance.Trey: Trey is Italian for "three" so that explains his name. His weapon is a bow and arrow.Cinque: Italian for "five" and she is armed with a mace.Seven: She is armed with a chain whip that will probably remind you of Ivy's whip from Soul Calibur.Eight: He only fights using martial arts, only his legs in particular. Male Chie Satonaka anyone?Nine: He is armed only with a Spear that has a red tip. Nine is the dragoon of the group. He can spin and damage enemies in a circle. He also has a jump ability like Freya from Final Fantasy IX that damages enemies from the sky by landing on them.Jack: He uses a katana as his main weapon.Queen: The one with the glasses that uses a saber and has a fencing style and uses a lot of acrobatic moves in combat. Her attacks are easily chain-able, she even has an ability called "Cross" that hits enemies in a line.Kurasame: Who seems to be known as the "Ice Blade of Death" (what a title.) and is the instructor of these students and is not featured in the picture above and apparently uses a Tonberry in battle. Not a playable character though.The others that don't have names seem to be a female with a shotgun, a male with dual handguns, a female with a flute and a female with a scythe.These characters have just been released as of April 25th 2011, the 3rd characters name has not yet been romanized into English.Kariyashibal VI - The 174th headmaster I assume of Suzaku Academy.Izana in the trailer on the verge of death.Izana - A chocobo user that is almost dead in the latest trailer.Katolbashthal - Name not romanized and not much info is known.Another new character that was thought to be a rumor actually is a Moogle (name not specified).King- A character revealed recently that has dual handguns ( like in the concept art)Saice - Another character that was revealed recently, the one that wields a giant scythe.Gameplay and Battle SystemA TGS 2010 trailer and gameplay info the game is familiar and will feel at home to old Final Fantasy players.Queen and Nine in battle with an enemy leader.The game is mission based, kind of like a bunch of quests and seem to be non-linear, which not a lot of Final Fantasy games do. There will also be sub-missions that can be accomplished mid-battle. The trailer also revealed that you will be able to ride chocobos, like all Final Fantasy games should allow, or fly in an airship on the world map to get around. The game seems to be the most free roam based final fantasy game that is not on of the MMO's of 11 or 14.The ATB system that was later altered into the ATB Kai system in Final Fantasy X-2 and later refined again in Crisis Core is now being refined again in Type-0 but unlike Crisis Core it will be party based. It plays like Final Fantasy XII as well with the fact that whoever is the leader in the party are the ones that are playable. Summons also return but they are back to Final Fantasy X status of Aeons, where the summons themselves are controllable and have their own growth and attributes. Speaking of summons, Odin has been one of the summons confirmed to be in the game thanks to an official screenshot. Looks to be summon-able by Ace. Shiva is also a confirmed summon-able aeon in the game thanks to a trailer. In battle enemies have been said to have weak points that can be targeted in battle. In this case this weak point can be used to deal a death blow to an enemy causing an instant kill.Students of Suzaku can summon Ifrit a popular fire summon in the final fantasy series. They can also summon Golem a rock spirit. Odin from older final fantasy games has been confirmed as one of the "War Gods."In Type 0 Summons are called "War Gods" but, this time around instead of expending MP, the cost of nothing or filling up a meter to summon creatures, this time around you have to sacrifice one of your own characters to bring them out.A character dying for a summon..There seems to be a list of free missions one can take for extras in the game.It has also been stated that the gameplay is similar to The 3rd birthday if you are just looking at it by the camera angles and animations. Despite the games being completely different mechanics wise.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="595">Tales of Eternia</game><game id="255">Tales of Phantasia</game><game id="21460">Gurumin: A Monstrous Adventure</game><game id="11703">Tales of Rebirth</game><game id="21441">Tales of Destiny 2</game><game id="21108">Star Ocean: First Departure</game><game id="11602">Valkyrie Profile</game><game id="21464">Star Ocean:  Second Evolution</game><game id="13822">Monster Hunter Freedom</game><game id="20223">Monster Hunter Freedom 2</game><game id="20887">Phantasy Star Portable</game><game id="19621">Ys: The Ark of Napishtim</game><game id="25690">Ys SEVEN</game><game id="28131">Last Ranker</game><game id="28428">Exorsister</game><game id="29104">Mimana Iyar Chronicle</game><game id="27657">Phantasy Star Portable 2</game><game id="839">Ys: The Oath in Felghana</game><game id="30580">Monster Hunter Portable 3rd</game><game id="22023">The 3rd Birthday</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/97089/2136121-box.png</image></root>