<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21932</id><name>Destiny of the Doctors</name><description>Featuring newly recorded audio from Tom Baker, Peter Davison, Colin Baker, Sylvester McCoy (4th, 5th, 6th and 7th Doctors respectively) and Nicholas Courtney (the Brigadier), the game was a spin-off following the Doctor Who TV movie in 1996.  The majority of the game takes place in the Doctor's space ship, called the TARDIS, whilst trying to find the Master. It features the chosen Doctor character completing puzzles to advance stages, and the Master has placed several of the Doctor's old enemies in the TARDIS, including the Daleks, Cybermen, Silurians and the Zygons.   The game also features voice impersonations of the first two Doctors, and video from Anthony Ainley (the Master) in between puzzles. The 3rd Doctor was due to be voiced in the game, however Jon Pertwee (the actor who portrayed the third Doctor) died shortly before production. He was replaced by audio clips from the television series. The game features weapons which can be used to kill the above monsters, something which differs from the TV show's non-violence policy due to being aimed at children. The game however, was aimed at an older audience. The conclusion of the game sees the Doctor face off against the Master in several different ways depending on the chosen Doctor. These are:   The 1st Doctor being chased around the Celestial Toymaker's toybox The Master races against the 2nd Doctor on London Underground trains. The 3rd Doctor has to try and destory a Dalek spaceship There's a maze in the 4th Doctor's mind that he must escape A Sontaran jousts with the 5th Doctor The 6th Doctor searches round an icy alternative version of Mars Finally, the 7th Doctor races against the Master's car in Bessie The game is the last game before the new series of Doctor Who began in 2005.</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5258/257680-destiny_of_the_doctors.jpg</image></root>