<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>21963</id><name>Peggle</name><description>OverviewPeggle Deluxe is a 2D game from the popular website and developer PopCap Games. Peggle combines game mechanics from the Japanese casino game Pachinko and the 1976 Atari arcade game Breakout. The gameplay of Peggle consists of players firing balls from the top of the stage at multi-colored pegs. When a ball contacts a peg, said peg lights up and is added to a combo meter. As the ball continues to bounce around the play area and hit more pegs the player receives more points. A turn is ended when the ball either falls through the bottom of the stage, or is caught by an osculating bucket and thus saved for reuse.GameplayTypes of PegsIn Peggle Deluxe there are four different types of pegs. The orange peg is the object peg. In most instances a player will need to strike all oranges pegs to advance. The blue peg is a point peg, each blue peg you hit will add to your combo and score. Green pegs are power-up pegs. These pegs allow you use of the selected characters ability. Finally purple pegs are score point boost pegs that increase the number of points you get for each peg that the ball contacts after hitting the purple one.Modes of PlayPeggle Deluxe has 4 modes of play. These modes are:AdventureQuick PlayDuelChallengeAdventure ModeAdventure mode is where most new players will start learning the game's mechanics and is set up to take you though each of the game's boards and power ups. Adventure mode is divided into stages and levels. There are 10 stages and 5 levels to each stage. The object of level in Adventure Mode is simple, you must use your balls to hit all of the orange pegs, and you have ten balls to complete this task. Before each stage you are introduced to a new character via a small intro paragraph and picture. Each character has their own unique power-up that can be used to help players completed the levels.The stages and levels are as follows:Stage One: BjornPegglelandSlip and SlideBjorn's GazeboDas BucketSnow Day     Stage Two: Jimmy LightningBirdy's CribBuffalo WingsSkate ParkSpiral of DoomMr. Peepers    Stage Three: Kat TutScarab CrunchInfinite CheeseRa DealCroco-Gator PitThe Fever Level    Stage Four: SplorkThe AmoebanLast FlowerWe Come in PeaceMaid in SpaceGetting the Spare     Stage Five: ClaudePearl ClamInsane AquariumTasty WavesOur Favorite EelLove Story     Stage Six: Renfield PumpkinWavesSpiderwebBlockersBaseballVermin     Stage Seven: TulaHolland OatsI Heart FlowersWorkin From HomeTula's Ride70 and Sunny     Stage Eight: WarrenWin a MonkeyDog PinballSpin AgainRoll 'emFive of a Kind    Stage Nine: Lord CinderbottomThe Love MoatDoom With a ViewRhombi9 Luft BalloonsTwisted Sisters     Stage Ten: Master HuPaw readerEnd of TimeBillions and BillionsDon't PanicBeyond ReasonQuick Play ModeQuick Play mode allows players to replay levels that they have previously unlocked though adventure mode. Quick play gives players the ability to use any power up on any stage. High scores are show for each level which promotes competition between players.Duel ModeIn Duel Mode Players take turns shooting balls on the same level. The object is to score more points than your opponent, be it computer or real. Players are also penalized if they do not hit an orange peg on their turn.Challenge ModeChallenge Mode tasks the player with completing various goals that are different than Adventure Mode Goals. These goals are set on the same normal Adventure mode levels.The Adventure Mode Goals are as follows:35 Orange pegs (instead of the normal 25)45 Orange pegs (instead of the normal 25)55 Orange pegs (instead of the normal 25)Score 300,000 pointsScore 350,000 pointsScore 400,000 pointsClear all pegs (orange and blue)Beat CPU in duel (normal, hard  master)Beat Multiple levels in a row (2,3,4,5,6)Beat CPU in three level duel (normal, hard, master)700,000 points over three levels800,000 points over three levels850,000 points over three levels900,000 points over three levels1,000,000 points over three levelsBeat a level with only 2 ballsBeat a level with only 1 ballBeat 3 levels with only 10 ballsBeat 750,000 on any levelsBeat a ten random levels in a rowOnce a player has completed all the challenges they are crowned the Peggle Master.CharactersThere are ten playable characters in Peggle, each with their own themed maps and special powers, which are normally activated when hitting a green peg.Bjorn - Superguide: Creates a guide showing part of the initial bounce of the balls trajectory.Jimmy Lightning - Multiball: Spawns another ball which falls at random.Kat Tut - Pyramid: Attaches a Pyramid to the free ball bucket, which helps prevent the ball from falling off the screen.Splork - Space Blast: Lights up all pegs in a small radius.Claude - Flippers: Causes lobster claw shaped pinball flipper to appear on either side of the screen.Renfield Pumpkin - Spooky Ball: The ball appears again at the top of the screen after falling through the bottom (Note: the first ball then cannot go through the ball bucket)Tula - Flower Power: Lights up 1/5 of the orange pegs remaining in the stage.Warren - Lucky Spin: Randomly activates 4 options; either Triple Score, Magic Hat (attaches a hat to the top of the ball, which can also light up pins), Extra Ball or any other random powerup from the other characters.Lord Cinderbottom - Fireball: Replaces the ball with a fireball that can go through and eliminate all pegs in its path.Master Hu - Zen Ball: Tweaks the shot for a better score.ReceptionPeggle Deluxe has been very well received by the gaming press. Critics cite its addictive nature and "feel-good" moments as strengths. It has a Metacritic score of 92, which is extremely high for a cheap, download only game. Even the usually harsh Yahtzee said that "I started playing around noon and emerged from my room sometime later to find the authorities had declared me legally dead" in reference to how addictive the gameplay was. PC Zone Magazine called Peggle "Addictive and happy", which seemed to be a pretty good sum-up of the general reception.System RequirementsPCOS: Windows 2000/XP/Vista/7/8CPU: 600 MhzRAM: 128 MBDirectX: 6.0Hard Drive: 21 MBMacOS: OS X version Leopard 10.5.8, Snow Leopard 10.6.3, or laterProcessor: Intel Core 2 Duo 1.66Memory: 512 MB of RAM </description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="45">Block-Breaking</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="42911">Peggle 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1381532-peggle_box.png</image></root>