<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22006</id><name>Dragon Ball: Origins</name><description>PlotSon Goku stands off against the shapeshifting pig Oolong, as seen in the Manga  AnimeThe plot of Dragon Ball: Origins follows both the Emperor Pilaf Saga and the 21st World Martial Arts Tournament Saga, as well as including various original stories. Overall, Origins covers the first 28 episodes of the animated series and 54 chapters of the manga.GameplaySon Goku in combat.Playing as     Son Goku, the player navigates 3D environments based on those seen in the Manga and Anime. Mostly the game consists of environmental puzzle solving and combat. Goku can make use of various abilities such as his Nyoi-bō (Power Pole), basic martial arts techniques and the    Kamehameha energy attack, both for combat and puzzle solving / navigation. Not all abilities will be available from the beginning of the game as some are learned only through the course of the story.The game is divided into episode stages. Each stage has a goal the player must complete, which is often the defeat of a boss, to unlock the next episode stage. While the environments and enemies are based on the Manga and Anime they are expanded upon. For example, levels contain multiple enemies and are not limited only to encounters as seen in either the Manga or Anime.</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3666">The Legend of Zelda: Phantom Hourglass</game><game id="7060">Lunar Knights</game><game id="24226">Legacy of Ys: Books I &amp; II</game><game id="21633">Soma Bringer</game><game id="21371">Avalon Code</game><game id="22015">Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles: Ring of Fates</game><game id="6145">The Legend of Zelda: The Minish Cap</game><game id="9471">Children of Mana</game><game id="22044">From the Abyss</game><game id="11662">Shin Bokura no Taiyou Gyakushuu no Sabata</game><game id="14556">Boktai 2: Solar Boy Django</game><game id="7136">Boktai: The Sun is in Your Hand</game><game id="10252">Dragon Quest Heroes: Rocket Slime</game><game id="24123">Slime MoriMori Dragon Quest: Shougeki no Shippo Dan</game><game id="24307">Steal Princess</game><game id="25657">The Legend of Zelda: Spirit Tracks</game><game id="28324">Shounen Kininden Tsumuji</game><game id="29232">Lufia: Curse of the Sinistrals</game><game id="21723">Elebits: The Adventures of Kai and Zero</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1814861-box_dbo.png</image></root>