<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22015</id><name>Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles: Ring of Fates</name><description>OverviewFinal Fantasy Crystal Chronicles: Ring of Fates is an action RPG released by Square Enix in March 2008 for the Nintendo DS. It is the spiritual successor to 2004's Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles on the GameCube.  PlotIn traditional Final Fantasy style, Ring of Fates is not a direct sequel to the GameCube original. Instead, it is a prequel, set in the same world but focusing on different characters and a different storyline. In Ring of Fates, the plot focuses on a pair of Clavat twins named  Yuri and  Chelinka.The Game also features several hints and references to the original Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles. GameplayRing of Fates is an action RPG, similar to Kingdom Hearts (another popular Square Enix franchise). Like most RPGs, the gameplay has three main focuses: visiting towns, exploring dungeons, and engaging in combat. Like its predecessor, Ring of Fates also features a wealth of dedicated multiplayer content. The Overworld and TownsAs with most RPGs, Ring of Fates uses an overworld, commonly referred to as a "world map". While the majority of RPGs feature fully explorable over worlds, Ring of Fates follows the example set by the original Crystal Chronicles and offers an overworld which acts as more of a map. There are several destinations on this map, and rather than physically walking from place to place, the player can simply cycle through the locations using the DS' D-pad and select a town or dungeon using the A button. The game can be saved at any point on the world map by pressing the Y button.The town of Rebena Te Ra acts as the central hub for the game's proceedings. Here, players can shop for new weapons, armour, magicite and items before venturing into a dungeon.   Items   Players can find three types of items throughout their adventure,  magicite which acts as a resource to cast magic  Recipes which allow you to craft new weapons and armour whilst at Rebena Te Ra  Materials which are required to craft items from recipes.  Items are gained by using recipes, each time generating a slightly different item.   Multiplayer  Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles Ring of Fates features a unique multiplayer mode that strips the game of its story and cutscenes but adds a unique quest system, this adds up to an excellent multiplayer cooperative experience.   Quests  In multiplayer players can complete quests for rewards, these quests involve the players completing a unique challenge such as defeating all enemies within a time limit ect.in these challenge stages, unique power-ups appear such as super jump or invincibility. SoundtrackThe soundtrack for Final Fantasy Ring of Fates was composed by Kumi Tanioka, and the soundtrack was released September 17, 2007. FINAL FANTASY CRYSTAL CHRONICLES Ring of Fates Original Soundtrack FINAL FANTASY CRYSTAL CHRONICLES Ring of Fates Original SoundtrackTotal length: 76:03Ring of FatesThe BeginningThe World Where We LivePeaceful EverydayThe Cave in the Hill Behind Our HouseMog's TutoringA Duel!Get the Treasure!A Moment of SilenceLight of the CrystalScenery of the Castle TownShoppingAbandoned TownTeteo's FeelingsPope GardesPicking Moogle GrassEvil ShadowWith Sadness and DespairDeterminationCourage From FriendsAn Important ComradeThe Tainted ForestThe Person Living in the ForestRabena Te Ra CastleA City Resting At the Bottom of the SeaReckless MeethA Small VestmentIsland of SinnersBattleThe UnderworldThe Caretaker of SoulsFather PossessedLela CielThe City's CollapseExistence of the CrystalTemple of the CrystalTemple of the MoonFinal Decisive BattleDestruction of the EgoCrystal RecordBondsThe Place I've Longed ForWelcome Back... I'm HomeFinaleCharacter MakingQuest Together! No. 1Level UpGame OverQuest Together! No. 2Prize ContestRace Start!The Race and the Royal BalconyRace VictoryRace... DefeatA Moogle OutingRoF MedleyMemories of the Ring of Fates</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9471">Children of Mana</game><game id="21448">Kingdom Hearts 358/2 Days</game><game id="3666">The Legend of Zelda: Phantom Hourglass</game><game id="22044">From the Abyss</game><game id="24232">Ragnarok DS</game><game id="24226">Legacy of Ys: Books I &amp; II</game><game id="21371">Avalon Code</game><game id="21633">Soma Bringer</game><game id="7060">Lunar Knights</game><game id="21445">Tales of Hearts</game><game id="21446">Tales of the Tempest</game><game id="23777">Phantasy Star Zero</game><game id="22006">Dragon Ball: Origins</game><game id="24225">Destiny Links</game><game id="25152">Blue Dragon: Awakened Shadow</game><game id="25657">The Legend of Zelda: Spirit Tracks</game><game id="21636">Dungeon Explorer: Warriors of Ancient Art</game><game id="27893">Cross Treasures</game><game id="27199">Rune Factory 3: A Fantasy Harvest Moon</game><game id="20615">Summon Night: Twin Age</game><game id="28324">Shounen Kininden Tsumuji</game><game id="29232">Lufia: Curse of the Sinistrals</game><game id="31644">Kingdom Hearts Re:coded</game><game id="11771">Brave Story: New Traveler</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1814639-box_ffccrof.png</image></root>