<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22107</id><name>Interstellar Marines</name><description>Interstellar Marines starts at the dawn of the 22nd century, man’s lust for resources has taken him beyond Earth  into space. This new frontier has brought new challenges and opportunities, dangers, rewards,  awaits the ultimate discovery: another sentient species."The Journey"Follow the development of the game, from the the smallest details, to the biggest factors. Only made possible with the AAA Indie vision, you can be part of shaping the game, by participating in the journey of Interstellar Marines. Divided up into chapters, and made available for the public, the following chapters have been released and announced:Chapter 1 - Community WebsiteLaunch date: 15th of May, 2009The in-house created official website is finally launched, after several years of Interstellar Marines already being in development. A community forum was later rolled out in a website update, and is used today for the players to provide input for Zero Point Software.Chapter 2 - The VaultLaunch date: 11th of October, 2009The Vault is the first introduction to the universe of Interstellar Marines. Learn more about the universe, firsthand and in 3D in your own browser, made possible with the Unity Engine browser plugin. Several characters and objects of the game can be seen in this virtual theater.Chapter 3 - BullseyeLaunch date: 22th of December, 2009Bullseye is the first playable chapter of Interstellar Marines. Introducing prototype gunplay to the players, set in an dynamic gunrange where the player has to shoot down cardboard targets in several challenges to level up and unlock upgrades or himself and his weapon. This chapter of Interstellar Marines is also run through your browser with the Unity Engine browser plugin.Chapter 4 - Running ManLaunch date: 2nd of July, 2010The second playable prototype of Interstellar Marines. Alongside the firing model introduced in Bullseye, Running Man added in the game's movement setup to show how they worked together in the Unity Engine. The premise of the demo is that it is an increasingly fatal training program for Interstellar Marine candidates.The Running Man also served as a prototype/proof of concept for Interstellar Marine's basic enemy AI and pathfinding- as the player is pitted against four varieties of training bots: A standard black variant, a fast moving yellow variant, an explosive white variant, and a tall grey variant that essentially serves as a boss-type entity- and only starts appearing on the second difficulty level.In addition to the reappearance of the AI SARA, who's voice had been present in the previous Interstellar Marine demos, the Running Man introduced Drill Sergeant Barry. He keeps ordering SARA to send the candidates through increasingly fatal training exercises against the bots, despite SARA's complaints about the rapidly decreasing percentage of candidates passing- let alone surviving.TechnicalThe game is currently testing the Unity Engine for use in creating it as a commercial product.FeaturesSingleplayer or up to four players cooperativeCustom game modes featuring arcade, RPG and tactical elementsCaptivating storyline with heavy focus on realismAdvanced weapons simulationRandomized and non-linear gameplayCharacter growth and specializationFully interactive environmentsTriviaThis game was first named Project IM.System RequirementsPCMinimumOS: Windows XP SP3 or Windows VistaProcessor: 2.4 GHz Dual CoreMemory: 2 GB GB RAMGraphics: Nvidia Geforce 8800 GT / ATI Radeon HD 4770DirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 1 GB HD spaceSound: DirectX 9.0c CompatibleRecommendedOS: Win 7 or laterProcessor: 2.4 GHz Quad CoreMemory: 4 GB GB RAMGraphics: Nvidia Geforce GTX 280 / ATI Radeon HD 5830DirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 1 GB HD spaceSound: DirectX 9.0c CompatibleOther Requirements: Broadband Internet connectionMacMinimumOS: 10.7.5 (Lion)Processor: 2.2 GHz Intel Core 2 DuoMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: Nvidia Geforce 8800 / ATI Radeon HD 3850Hard Drive: 1 GB HD spaceRecommendedOS: 10.8.2 (Mountain Lion)Processor: 2.4 GHz Intel Quad CoreMemory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: Nvidia Geforce GT 120 / ATI Radeon HD 4870Hard Drive: 1 GB HD spaceOther Requirements: Broadband Internet connection</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7754">Doom 3: Resurrection of Evil</game><game id="1339">Star Wars: Republic Commando</game><game id="8870">System Shock 2</game><game id="4800">F.E.A.R.: First Encounter Assault Recon</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3026/298615-interstellar_marines_logo.jpg</image></root>