<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22176</id><name>Taiko no Tatsujin DS</name><description>OverviewTaiko no Tatsujin DS (Taiko Drum Master) is a rhythm game developed by Namco and published by Nintendo released for the Ninendo DS only in Japan.  Like the other games in the series, the player plays the notes of a chosen song's drum part as they are displayed on the screen.  The game can be played with the touch screen or buttons.  The game also has up to 4 player local wireless multiplayer and comes with two drum styli to be used as drum sticks.Song ListJ-Popさくらんぼ (Sakuranbo) 気分上々↑↑ (Kibun Joujou↑↑) 夏祭り (Natsu Matsuri) 決意の朝に (Ketsui no Asa ni) Won't Be Long マタアイマショウ (Mata Aimashou) DANCE2 feat.ソイソース (Pocky Chocolate Commercial Song - DANCE2 feat.Soysauce)  AnimeTouch Together (Pokémon: Diamond and Pearl series Japanese Opening) Jūken Sentai Gekiranger Yes! PreCure 5 Smile GoGo! Doraemon no Uta Detective Conan Main Theme Anpanman  ClassicalSymphony No. 7 (Beethoven) William Tell Overture (Rossini) Orpheus in the Underworld (Offenbach) (aka the can-can song) Flight of the Bumblebee (Rimsky-Korsakov) Classic medley (Wedding compilation) Fantaisie-Impromptu (Chopin) (Unlockable)  Video Game MusicSuper Mario Bros. "Go my way" (The Idolm@ster) Namco medley, including music from Mappy and Battle City  Namco Originalキミにタッチ！ もじぴったんメドレー KAGEKIYO 風雲！バチお先生 黒船来航 (unlockable) 太鼓乱舞　炎の卷 (unlockable) 太鼓乱舞　風の卷 (unlockable) 太鼓乱舞　水の卷 (unlockable) てんぢく２０００ (unlockable)  VarietyTarako Tarako Tarako  Traditionalもりのくまさん (Mori no O-Kumasan) (A Bear in the Forest) いぬのおまわりさん (Inu no O-mawarisan) (Dog Policeman) </description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7037">Osu! Tatakae! Ouendan</game><game id="254">Moero! Nekketsu Rhythm Damashii Osu! Tatakae! Ouendan 2</game><game id="21312">Rhythm Heaven</game><game id="17965">Rhythm Tengoku</game><game id="505">Daigasso! Band Brothers</game><game id="21366">Jam with the Band</game><game id="6343">Daigasso! Band Brothers Request Selection</game><game id="20556">Ontamarama</game><game id="11982">Elite Beat Agents</game><game id="20639">Guitar Hero: On Tour</game><game id="24122">Rock Revolution</game><game id="24127">Rhythm de Cooking: Sweets Party e Youkoso</game><game id="10707">Kira Kira Pop Princess</game><game id="23989">Pop Town</game><game id="23676">Osu!</game><game id="31655">Gabrielle’s Ghostly Groove</game><game id="32210">Taiko no Tatsujin Wii: Do Don to 2 Daime!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14097/754354-1.jpg</image></root>