<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22187</id><name>Flyff - Fly For Fun</name><description>OverviewFly for Fun or Flyff is a popular free MMORPG developed by Aeonsoft. Currently in its 11th version Flyff features:Cash Shop for Micro-transactionsPeer vs Peer (PvP)Free for all arenas120 levels 60 when completed Mastery4 Classes to choose from at Level 15 and a choice of 2 classes (depending on your class) when you reach level 60PetsIn-game private shopClassesLevel 1 ClassesVagrant: A class for beginners with simple weapons and skills.Level 15 ClassesAssist: Assists have a mix of both physical and melee attacks with buffs.Mercenary: Mercenarys are very similar to vagrants with there use of melee weapons.Magician: Magicians use 2 handed staffs or one handed wands, they are not as melee based as other classes.Acrobat:: Acrobats are based in long ranged attacks with special abilites to use bows, or Yo-Yos.Level 60 ClassesAssistRingmaster: A class detected to helping others with buffs and is more of a team class. Other builds for this class can make it into a fighting class but primary role is to healBillposter: Can have the buffs of a RM but is a fighter at heart. The builds for this class are all fighter relatedMercenaryBlade: Quick and duel wielding artist for the mercenary class. Most successful builds will try and tailor to speed and attack and less on tankingKnight: Big swords/axes and heavy armor pave the way for this class. This class can handle the tanking but also the attack build if done correctlyMagicianPsykeeper: Mental spells are this classes specialty and can be one of the best classes to have during a boss monster fight. This class floats as well =DElementor: This classes attacks are based off the classes name; with elements. Good for hurting monster with elemental weaknesses and can be effective when leveling with an Assist/RMAcrobatJester: Master of the Yo-Yo as it can deal dual damage to monster. Builds can be used for this class to use a bow but it's primary role is to use Yo-Yo'sRanger: A bow and arrow master this class can deal damage at a safe range from monsters.Level 130 ClassesRingmasterSeraph: A pumped up healing/support class with even better heals and better buffs.BillposterForcemaster: A buffer class that improves attack, defense, and other attributes.BladeSlayer: Main DPS class of the game. Provides the most amount of damage output, unmatched by any other class.KnightTemplar: Main Melee Tanker class. Has the ability to increase its defense rate ten-foldPsykeeperMentalist: Main Magic Tanker/DPS class. Uses defense based skills to demolish enemy defenses and debuff them.ElementorArcanist: Master of the Arcane. The Main AOE/Nuker class of the end game. Provides massive amounts of damage.JesterHarlequin: Another Melee DPS class, used mostly for traps.RangerCrackshooter: Uses a crossbow instead of a bow and arrow to demolish enemy fronts. Weak Defense grants it Slayer-like damage to any and all enemies.</description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16614">Ragnarok Online</game><game id="19783">World of Warcraft</game><game id="17494">Guild Wars</game><game id="5767">Ultima Online</game><game id="12376">The Lord of the Rings Online: Shadows of Angmar</game><game id="11142">Final Fantasy XI Online</game><game id="2268">RuneScape</game><game id="21545">Tibia</game><game id="22502">Fantasy Earth Zero</game><game id="22085">CABAL Online</game><game id="23342">Tales of Pirates</game><game id="23559">Priston Tale</game><game id="22228">Helbreath</game><game id="23583">ROSE Online</game><game id="21985">zOMG!</game><game id="25460">Conquer Online</game><game id="18547">EverQuest II</game><game id="20701">World of Warcraft: Wrath of the Lich King</game><game id="18603">World of Warcraft: The Burning Crusade</game><game id="22602">Mabinogi</game><game id="23411">Runescape Classic</game><game id="24448">Luna Online</game><game id="26467">Dragonica</game><game id="21909">Atlantica Online</game><game id="29110">Dream Of Mirror Online</game><game id="32050">Ragnarok Online 2: Legend of the Second</game><game id="32274">Knight Online</game><game id="29571">Arcadia Saga</game><game id="35439">Kal Online</game><game id="40859">Age of Wulin</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3691/316462-flyff_logo.png</image></root>