<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22190</id><name>Street Racer</name><description> Overview This kart racing game, developed by Vivid Image and published by Ubisoft and inspired heavily by Super Mario Kart, was the first of its genre to allow 8 players to race simultaneously on split-screen, this respectable achievement however is overshadowed by the fact that the game performed very poorly commercially on all systems, particularly selling badly on the PlayStation compared to other racing games released in the same year, the decision was made to give the game a price drop almost immediately upon release due to poor initial sales figures and the game is now classed as very rare to find.  The game featured 9 characters and 8 tracks, and several different game modes, one of which being the 'Championship' mode, which was essentially a set of races with increasing difficulty, once a player completed the 'Championship' mode on Bronze difficulty, they could play through again on Silver, then Gold, and ultimately Platinum. The game also allowed for players to cherry pick their own tracks and settings to create a Custom Championship, head-to-head racing with a CPU driver was also a game option, along with practice races. Probably the most unique aspect of Street Racer however was its Rumble mode, in which the 8 drivers began facing each other in a circular arena with a destructible outer barrier along the edge, with the objective of the mode being to be the Last Man Standing in the ring, to win, one had to eliminate all of the opponents using the in-built weapons/abilities on each car or by simply punching the other players out of the ring (an ability that was available to all drivers). These offensive aspects of the game were also included in the race mode, weapons were not in the form of pickups like in Super Mario Kart, but rather each car had its own specific recharging weapons/abilities to suit the driver, for example, Frank Instein's car had the ability to grow bat wings and fly. There were  9 featured characters in the game (one of which was unlockable):  Helmut - An ace pilotHodja - A turkish magicianFrank Instein - (Frankenstein's Monster)Suzulu - An african voodoo specialistBiff - A bald american 'bully' type characterSurf Sister - An australian teenage girl (and the only playable female character in the game)Sumo - A sumo wrestler from JapanRaphael - A suave ladies man from Italy Rabbit - The secret unlockable character, essentially just a rabbit who is featured in the intro movie to the game and on the box art, he was unlocked by either completing the 'Championship' mode of the game on 'Platinum' difficulty, or by simply entering a password into the cheats section of the game.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19071">Super Mario Kart</game><game id="20645">Mario Kart Wii</game><game id="18757">Mario Kart: Double Dash!!</game><game id="6539">Mario Kart DS</game><game id="16769">Mario Kart: Super Circuit</game><game id="22373">Mario Kart Arcade GP</game><game id="25285">Mario Kart Arcade GP 2</game><game id="6196">Crash Team Racing</game><game id="21405">Crash Tag Team Racing</game><game id="2278">Crash Nitro Kart</game><game id="21205">Crash Bandicoot Nitro Kart 3D</game><game id="15990">Diddy Kong Racing</game><game id="5561">Diddy Kong Racing DS</game><game id="37413">SD F-1 Grand Prix</game><game id="38076">Battle Racers</game><game id="38678">Road Riot 4WD</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2364797-snes_streetracer_au.jpg</image></root>