<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22194</id><name>F1 Career Challenge</name><description>History The game was originally scheduled to be released on all then  current platforms (PC, Playstation 2, XBOX and Game Cube) world wide.  The XBOX and Game Cube versions where later dropped in the US, do to  lack of interest in F1 racing compared to Europe. This game was the last  in the series of F1 games from EA Sports. They lost the official F1  license to Sony, who signed a multi year exclusive deal for there  Formula One series.Gameplay ModesCareer Mode The  career mode has a very realistic F1 driving experience and is therefor  also a very hard and challinging racing mode. In career mode the  player creates its own driver and race four season from the official F1  calender, from the '99 to the '02 season.The first step is to the  racer. Choose the racers name, country, likeness and helmet.To  become a F1 driver a Superlicense must first be obtained. This is done  by passing a series of tests.The tests a split into three blocks. The  first block teaches  the basic like starting, stopping and cornering. The  second block teaches more advance cornering. The final block teaches  handling during rain, overtaking and  The starting grid on  Circuit de Monaco pit stopping. At the end of the  tests a  couple  of teams will ofter you a contract, the teams quality  depends on the drivers performance during these test. This does not lock  the driver to the one team for the duration of the four seasons,  during  or at the end of each season the driver will receive offers from other  teams depending on the drivers race performance.        The actual Grand  Prix races in career mode is split into three parts. A 60 minutes  practices session where the driver can learn the track, a 60 minutes  qualifying session where the driver has 12 laps to set the best possible  single lap time and the race it self. During the races the driver will  earn points for completing different challenges and feats. These points  can be spend on car upgrades and more.   Quick Race  Cockpit view     Jump  straight into a race. Choose one for the four season to select team,  driver and circuit from. Qualifying can be enabled to decides your  position on the starting grid. It is possible to customize the racing  experience in a variant of ways. Besides the standard racing setup like  opponent difficulty, weather and race length, it is possible to change  settings to get a more or less realistic racing experience. These  includes car damage, fuel use, tire ware and gear shifting. Interactive  pit stops ( A "quick time events" like mode to get the fastest possible  pit stop), slipstreaming (drafting) and the strictness of the racing  rule set. Gamebreakers are back. When a major event occur during a race,  like a huge crash, the game will enter a instant replay mode where the  event is shown from multiple angles in a mix of real time and slow  motions. Multiplayer Multiplayer is not a big part of the  game. It has been criticized for not being very deep and for laggy  races. It consists of two modes:Split screen. A two player  local multiplayer mode. Race head-to-head or against a full grid of  racers.Online. Online multiplayer is a time trail mode for  up to 8 players. Choose a track and try to set the best lap time one by  one.Modding The game has a fairly large modding community,  largely because it is so easily modded. The game use various known  standards for storing data. Player and team data is accessible via  simple text file and for the circuit geometry an industry known format  is used. There are many types of mods, including modes that depicts the  seasons from 1968 all the way up to the 2009 season, including the look  of the cars and tracks from the particle era.Grand Prix1999 Season RoundGrand PrixCircuit 1 AustralianAlbert Park Grand Prix Circuit, Melbourne 2Brazilian       Autódromo José Carlos Pace, São Paulo 3San Marino  Autodromo  Enzo e Dino Ferrari, Imola   4Monaco      Circuit de Monaco,  Monte-Carlo  5Spanish      Circuit de Catalunya, Barcelona   6Canadian      Circuit Gilles Villeneuve, Montreal  7French           Circuit de Nevers Magny-Cours  8British           Silverstone Circuit   9Austrian      A1-Ring, Spielberg   10German      Hockenheimring  11Hungarian      Hungaroring, Budapest  12Belgian          Circuit de Spa-Francorchamps, Spa  13 Italian           Autodromo Nazionale Monza  14 European      Nürburgring   15 Malaysian      Sepang International Circuit, Kuala Lumpur  16 JapaneseSuzuka Circuit, Suzuka2000 Season RoundGrand PrixCircuit 1Australian Albert Park Circuit,  Melbourne  2BrazilianAutódromo José Carlos Pace, São  Paulo  3San Marino Autodromo Enzo e Dino Ferrari, Imola  4British     Silverstone Circuit  5Spanish     Circuit de  Catalunya, Barcelona  6European     Nürburgring 7Monaco     Circuit de Monaco, Monte-Carlo  8Canadian      Circuit Gilles Villeneuve, Montreal  9French     Circuit de  Nevers Magny-Cours  10Austrian     A1-Ring, Spielberg  11German     Hockenheimring 12Hungarian     Hungaroring,  Budapest 13Belgian     Circuit de Spa-Francorchamps, Spa 14Italian     Autodromo Nazionale Monza  15United States Indianapolis Motor Speedway 16JapaneseSuzuka Circuit 17MalaysianSepang International Circuit, Kuala Lumpur     2001 Season  RoundGrand PrixCircuit 1Australian Melbourne Grand Prix Circuit, Melbourne 2Malaysian Sepang  International Circuit, Kuala Lumpur  3Brazilian Autódromo José  Carlos Pace, São Paulo  4 San Marino Autodromo Enzo e Dino  Ferrari, Imola  5Spanish   Circuit de Catalunya, Barcelona  6AustrianA1-Ring, Spielberg  7MonacoCircuit de  Monaco, Monte Carlo  8CanadianCircuit Gilles Villeneuve,  Montreal  9EuropeanNürburgring  10FrenchCircuit  de Nevers Magny-Cours, Magny-Cours  11BritishSilverstone  Circuit  12GermanHockenheimring  13HungarianHungaroring, Budapest  14BelgianCircuit de  Spa-Francorchamps, Spa  15ItalianAutodromo Nazionale Monza  16United States Indianapolis Motor Speedway  17JapaneseSuzuka Circuit  2002 SeasonRoundGrand PrixCircuit 1Australian     Melbourne Grand Prix Circuit, Melbourne  2Malaysian     Sepang International Circuit, Kuala Lumpur  3Brazilian         Autódromo José Carlos Pace, São Paulo  4San  Marino Autodromo Enzo e Dino Ferrari, Imola  5Spanish          Circuit de Catalunya, Barcelona  6Austrian         A1-Ring,  Spielberg  7Monaco         Circuit de Monaco, Monte Carlo  8Canadian     Circuit Gilles Villeneuve, Montreal  9European      Nürburgring  10British         Silverstone Circuit  11French         Circuit de Nevers Magny-Cours, Magny-Cours  12German         Hockenheimring  13Hungarian     Hungaroring,  Budapest  14Belgian     Circuit de Spa-Francorchamps, Spa  15Italian     Autodromo Nazionale Monza  16United StatesIndianapolis Motor Speedway  17JapaneseSuzuka Circuit Teams/Drivers1999 SeasonArrowsPedro de la RosaToranosuke TakagiBARJacques  VilleneuveRicardo ZontaBenettonGiacarlo FisichellaAlexander  WurzFerrariMichael SchumacherEddie IrvineJordanDamon  HillHeinz-Harald FrentzenMcLarenMika HäkkinenDavid  CoulthardMinardiLuca BadoerMarc GenéProstOlivier  PanisJarno TrulliSauberJean AlesiPedro DinizStewartRubens  BarrichelloJohnny HerbertWilliamsAlessandro ZanardiRalf  Schumacher2000 SeasonArrowsPedro de la RosaJos  VerstappenBARJacques VilleneuveRicardo ZontaBenettonGiacarlo  FisichellaAlexander WurzFerrariMichael SchumacherRubens  BarrichelloJaguarEddie IrvineJohnny HerbertJordanHeinz-Harald  FrentzenJarno TrulliMcLarenMika HäkkinenDavid  CoulthardMinardiMarc GenéGastón MazzacaneProstJean  AlesiNick HeidfeldSauberPedro DinizMika SaloStewartRubens  BarrichelloJohnny HerbertWilliamsRalf SchumacherJenson  Button 2001 SeasonArrowsJos VerstappenEnrique  BernoldiBAROlivier PanisJacques VilleneuveBenettonGiacarlo  FisichellaJenson ButtonJaguarEddie IrvineLuciano  BurtiJordanHeinz-Harald FrentzenJarno TrulliFerrariMichael  SchumacherRubens BarrichelloMcLarenMika HäkkinenDavid  CoulthardMinardiTarso MarquesFernando AlonsoSauberNick  HeidfeldKimi RäikkönenProstJean AlesiGastón  MazzacaneWilliamsRalf SchumacherJuan Paplo Montoya2002 SeasonArrowsHeinz-Harald FrentzenEnrique BernoldiBAROlivier  PanisJacques VilleneuveBenettonGiacarlo FisichellaJenson  ButtonFerrariMichael SchumacherRubens BarrichelloJaguarEddie  IrvinePedro de la RosaJordanGiancarlo FisichellaTakuma  SatoMcLarenDavid CoulthardKimi RäikkönenMinardiMark  WebberAlex YoongProstJean AlesiGastón MazzacaneRenaultJarno  TrulliJenson ButtonSauberNick HeidfeldFelipe MassaToyotaMika  SaloAllan McNishWilliamsRalf SchumacherJuan Paplo  MontoyaSystem requirements Microsoft Windows 98,ME,2000 or XP450  MHZ or better Intel Pentium II or 100% Compatible128 MB or better1  Gigabyte free space.4x CD/DVD or better16 MB or better DirectX  8.1 compliant graphic card.Direct X 8.1 compliant sound card.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7723">Grand Prix 4</game><game id="11266">Formula One 2002</game><game id="25985">F1 2010</game><game id="26638">Michael Andretti's Indy Car Challenge</game><game id="20130">rFactor</game><game id="29496">Formula 1 '97</game><game id="14919">Grand Prix Challenge</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3699/550305-589696_47271_front.jpg</image></root>