<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22218</id><name>WarRock</name><description>War Rock is a free multiplayer online First Person Shooter but you need to register an account before you can play (Registration requires a valid e-mail address). Although the game is Free to Play, you can buy a retail version, and there are also different levels of Premium which you pay monthly for depending on the level of Premium being Purchased.Premium 1 InformationIntense Online ActionPrice-$5.95 for 30 days No Marketplace discount Dinar (In-Game Money)- 21, 000  Purchase any weapon from Marketplace no matter what level you are Full Access to all maps Access the clan system, avatar, events for clan, etc Bonus Exp 20% Premium 2 InformationPrice-$9.95 for 30 days 10% Discount Dinar (In-Game Money)- 40, 500  Purchase any weapon from Marketplace no matter what level you are Full Access to all maps Access the clan system, avatar, events for clan, etc Bonus Exp 30% Ability to create private room Premium 3 InformationPrice-$14.95 for 30 days 20% Discount Dinar (In-Game Money)- 55, 500  Purchase any weapon from Marketplace no matter what level you are Full Access to all maps Access the clan system, avatar, events for clan, etc Bonus Exp 50% Ability to create private room Custom Room naming A 5th Weapon Slot Access to In-Game voice chat GameplayThe game plays similarly to the Battlefield series of games. You take control of a soldier on one of the two opposing factions, though they only differ by appearance. The game features a class based system where you are able to play as a Medic, Soldier, Heavy Weapons, Support, and a Sniper. From there, you are able to equip weapons that you have have bought from the in game store to further customize your character. Like battlefield, there are several vehicles to pilot or drive.WeaponsSuit up and attack!SidearmsColt (Pistol) Glock (Pistol) Desert Eagle (Pistol) .357 Magnum (Pistol) MP5K (Mini-SMG) Dual Berettas (Pistols) PrimaryMP5 (SMG) TMP9 (SMG) Dual Scorpions (SMG) P90 (SMG) Uzi (SMG) K1 (SMG) G36C (SMG) G36C_D (SMG) MP7A1 (SMG) K-2 (Assault Rifle) AK-47 (Assault Rifle) L85A1 (Assault Rifle) Tar 21 (Assault Rifle) M4 (Assault Rifle) G36 (Assault Rifle) FAMAS (Assault Rifle) M-60 (Machine Gun) Minimi (Machine Gun) M24 (Sniper) SSG (Sniper) PSG1 (Sniper)  AWM (Sniper) AUG (Sniper) Barrett (Sniper)A sniper waiting for the enemy Winchester (Shotgun)  MK-1S (Heavy) Panzerfaust (Heavy) RPG-7 (Heavy) Stinger (Heavy)  M134 (Heavy) GrenadesK400 Smoke Grenade Flashbang TMA-1A There are also a dozen or so Vehicles Which include: Humvees, a Motorcycle, Several tanks and a plane.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16866">Battlefield 2</game><game id="12716">Battlefield 1942</game><game id="13029">Battlefield 2: Special Forces</game><game id="22609">Soldier Front</game><game id="21591">Combat Arms</game><game id="21646">Battlefield 2: Modern Combat</game><game id="21220">Battlefield Heroes</game><game id="20989">CrimeCraft</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/217/326247-warrock_cover.jpg</image></root>