<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22254</id><name>Spec Ops: Stealth Patrol</name><description>Spec Ops: Stealth Patrol follows five members of the United States Army Ranger Corps as they carry out a series of covert missions across the world. The title was originally available for the PlayStation, and later released for download on PlayStation Network for $5.99 on July 9, 2009.Game ModesThe game includes one and two-player campaign modes, both involving a five-mission campaign.In one-player mode, the player can switch between two rangers at any point during each mission, as well as issue commands to the ranger not currently being controlled. Two-player mode uses a split-screen co-op model.CampaignStealth Patrol is structured as a sequence of independent missions, with the player choosing two of the five squad members to complete each one. The five playable characters are:Martinez, Machine GunnerExpert in the use of machine guns (M249 and M60E3).O'Conner, GrenadierExpert with the M203 grenade launcher and is deadly accurate when throwing grenades by hand.Ericsson, Recon/SniperExpert with rifles (SS^  M82A1) and with silenced weapons (HK MP5  HK G11).Schmidt, Close QuarterExpert with the shotgun (Ithaca 37) in close quarter battle situations.King, RiflemanExpert in the use of assault rifles (M16A2, M4 and HK G11).Each mission features a different terrorism hot spot, including:Veronye Forest, SiberiaPale, BosniaRayat, IraqKapsan Mountains, North KoreaThon an Thal, VietnamWeapons and ArmamentsWeapons available in the game include:M4, AK47, and HK G11 assault riflesM249, M60, and RPK machine gunsM203 grenade launcherSSG and Barret M82A1 sniper riflesIthaca 37 shotgunHK MP5SD sub-machine gunThe player can choose from an arsenal of realistic inventory items, including:SATCOM RadioEvery Ranger carries a SATCOM Radio in his inventory.Satchel ChargesThese are highly explosive charges, which are set to detonate in a user-determined time.Claymore  ClackerThe claymore is a fragmentation anti-personnel mine. After placing the claymore, use the clacker as the remote detonator to blow the mine when the enemy is within the range of the mine.GrenadesIncludes Fragmentation Grenade, HE Grenade, Smoke Grenade, White Phosphorous Grenade, and M203 Grenade.Med. KitsMed. kits are used to restore health.Night Vision Goggles (NVG's)These light amplification goggles increase your viewing distance in low light levels, creating a green field of view.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2179501-box_sosp.png</image></root>