<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22297</id><name>BS Zelda no Densetsu: Kodai no Sekiban</name><description>Released only in Japan over the  Satellaview, BS Zelda no Densetsu: Kodai no Sekiban (BS The Legend of Zelda: Ancient Stone Tablets) was a remake of  Link to the Past. Taking place chronologically during  Link's Awakening, the player controls not Link, but one of the two Satellaview mascots (replacing Link's hat with hair for female and a baseball cap for male) referred to as the "Hero of Light" who descends into  Hyrule from "another world."  Princess Zelda and Sahasrala find the protagonist and inform him/her that he/she must find the eight "Ancient Stone Tablets" with the words of the three goddesses to find a way to prevent  Ganon from taking over Hyrule.  Gameplay The game is very similar to LttP (taking place in the same Hyrule) but has added a few changes: Bombable walls aren't as easily noticeable, blending in perfectly. To find it, the player must tap the sword against the wall while charging; the bombable walls make a different sound effect.The Pegasus Boots allow players to turn while running.Upgrade thieves appear in hidden areas, upgrading either bomb or arrow capacity (for a price). The game took place in four weekly episodes, each containing two dungeons and numerous side quests. At first, the player is limited to the parts of the map he/she can access, but as the weeks went by, more and more of the world could be explored. All of the cutscenes in the game were voice acted, live. Even the optional side quests were spoken by a live voice actor as the game was being played.A live clock was added, as the game was only available to play an hour each day (voice actors can't say the same lines all day). Various events occur depending on the time (spawning fairies, infinite arrows or bombs, or a fog that defuses bombs and turns all overworld enemies into Zoras.A rental shop was added where players can purchase a sword upgrade or a shovel for ten minutes. </description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1320">Klonoa Heroes: Densetsu no Star Medal</game><game id="26402">BS Chrono Trigger: Jet Bike Special</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5431/348930-bs_zelda_kodai_no_sekiban_title_screen.png</image></root>