<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22292</id><name>Dead or Alive 2: Hardcore</name><description>OverviewDead or Alive 2 Hardcore is an expansion to Dead or Alive 2 that came out on the Dreamcast. Some new content include features and playable characters.ChangesDead or Alive 2: Hardcore is a re release of the Dreamcast version of Dead or Alive 2. Moving the game onto the Playstation 2, several changes were made to the game to make the game more enjoyable.Characters now look more realistic, opposed to the previous Anime look.8 more stages than the Dreamcast version.Some fighting animations were added and some were cut from this version.Faster Gameplay speed: now runs at a full 60 FPS (along with the cutscenes, as opposed to the Dreamcast's 30 FPS cutscenes.)English voice overs were added, in addition to the Japanese voice overs.Other changes include more character costumes (the max being 11 costumes for Ayane), more special moves, a CG gallery for the female characters, changes to the Survival mode and more.ModesStory - In this mode players will choose their character and battle through the cast of fighters. During key fights in that specific characters' story there will be a brief cutscene before and after the battle. In the end you will face the final boss, Tengu. Each character has their own reason for wanting to fight this great demon and it will be revealed to you after you defeat him.Time Attack - Your selected character battles through the story mode but without cutscenes and your performance is timed. At the end of the mode your time will be posted on your in-game leaderboard.Survival - In this mode you will have to fight character after character with a single life bar. There will be no breaks in between matches as your next opponent enters the screen immediately after you defeat your current opponent. On rare occasions your defeated opponent will drop an item. If you pick up the item you will be rewarded with a point bonus and sometimes health recovery. The items are listed below.Tag Battle - This mode can be played with one to four characters. It is a two on two battle and you can switch out for your teammate at anytime. This is the only mode where you will be able pull off certain team attacks. You will also be able to take on the computer in a five stage battle. You are able to choose any two characters you want but are not able to choose two of the same fighter.Team Battle - Players may make up teams consisting of 1 to 5 characters per team. You will not be able to switch out at any time unlike Tag Battle. The person to knockout all of the other characters first wins. This mode may be played against a person or the computer.Versus - Standard one on one fights. Players pick their characters and set health handicaps then fight. After each bout the game will return to the character select screen.Sparring - This is the training mode of Dead or Alive 2. Pick your character and practice combos on a AI dummy.Watch - This mode is.... a weird mode to have in your game. Pick two characters you want to see fight and watch the AI control both characters. Can be entertaining when you set the difficulty to the highest setting.UPS (User Profile System) - This is where you are able to load your profile. If you brought your memory card over to a friend's house you are able to fight with your own profile.Battle Recorder - If you have had a good fight and you want to save it, you can. In this mode you can view your saved replay, rewind it, and even change the camera angle.CG Gallery - Here is where you will be able to view scantily clad pictures of all the female characters. You can also make a slide show and have it run on your television. (Which is super creepy)CharactersKasumiKasumi is ready to kick high.Country: JapanFighting Style: NinjutsuAge: N/AHeight: 5'2" Weight: 106 PoundsMeasurements: B35" W21" H33"Occupation: NinjaRyu HayabusaCountry: JapanFighting Style: NinjutsuAge: 23Height: 5' 10" Weight: 154 PoundsMeasurements: B41" W33" H36"Occupation: Curio Shop OwnerHelenaCountry: FranceFighting Style: Pi Qua QuanAge: 21Height: 5' 7" Weight: 108 PoundsMeasurements: B35" W22" H34"Occupation: Opera SingerGen FuHis beard will be your doomCountry: ChinaFighting Style: Xinyi Liuhe QuanAge: 65Height: 5' 7" Weight: 172 PoundsMeasurements: B38" W40" H39"Occupation: Bookstore OwnerTina ArmstrongCountry: U.S.A.Fighting Style: Pro-WrestlingAge: 22Height: 5' 9" Weight: 115 PoundsMeasurements: B37" W24" H35"Occupation: Pro-WrestlerBass ArmstrongCountry: U.S.A.Fighting Style: Pro-WrestlingAge: 46Height: 6'5" Weight: 346 PoundsMeasurements: B56" W53" H54"Occupation: Pro-WrestlerZackThis is the most tame picture of Tina on GB....Country: U.S.A.Fighting Style: Thai-Style BoxingAge: 25Height: 5'11" Weight: 172 PoundsMeasurements: B42" W33" H37"Occupation: DJLeonCountry: ItalyFighting Style: Russian Martial ArtsAge: 42Height: 6'4" Weight: 282 PoundsMeasurements: B53" W47" H48"Occupation: MercenaryJann LeeCountry: ChinaFighting Style: Jeet Kune DoAge: 20Height: 5'8" Weight: 165 PoundsMeasurements: B39" W31" H36"Occuptaion: BouncerLei FangSee, even ninjas go to schoolCountry: ChinaFighting Style: T'ai Chi QuanAge: 19Height: 5'4" Weight: 110 PoundsMeasurements: B34" W22" H34"Occupation: College StudentAyaneCountry: JapanAge: N/AHeight: 5'2" Weight: 104 PoundsMeasurements: B37" W21" H33"Occupation: NinjaEinCountry: UnidentifiedFighting Style: KarateAge: 23Height: 5'11" Weight: 165 PoundsMeasurements: B43" W33" H39"Occupation: Karate InstructorSecret CharactersBaymanCountry: RussiaFighting Style: Russian Martial ArtsAge: 31Height: 6'0" Weight: 231 PoundsMeasurements: B47" W36" H37"Occupation: AssassinTenguTengu punching dudes in the faceCountry: UnidentifiedFighting Style: Tengu-DoAge: 1500Height: 7'1" Weight: 500 PoundsMeasurements: N/AOccupation: N/AStagesThe White Storm - The battle takes place on a snowy covered mountain. If the players to go the edge of the mountain they will fall several stories to an icy cave below. Where they will continue their battle.The Aerial Garden - This is a single level stage with beautiful scenery of a lake and ancient japanese buildings.The Miyama - This is the stage where you will encounter the final boss. It takes place in front of a monstrous tree.The Death Valley - Players will engage in battle on an elevated platform in the middle of a windfarm. Players may knock their opponent off the platform to continue battling on the stage.The Danger Zone - The fighters will battle on a moving platform in the depths of a missile silo. The walls are lined with explosive material so when you hit the wall, BOOM!The Spiral - Battles take place in a high tech skyscraper. There are places to knock your opponent to a lower floor but the stage will never get to a bottom.The Dragon Hills - This level has the most points to knock your opponent from. You may either punch them off one roof to another lower roof. Or you can kick them through a window into an inner monastery with a giant golden dragon overlooking your fight.The Bio Lab - Self explanatory. You fight in a science lab.The Demon's Church - Players will start in a room with four stain glass windows. Once kicked/punched through said window, your opponent will fall several stories to the outside entrance of the church.The Crimson - Your battle will take place in a run down shanty town. There is only one area to throw your opponent off into the alley way below.The D Octagon - A UFC style ring. FIGHT!The Pancratium - The fight will take place in a destroyed gladiator arena. Some of the walls are electrified because of the ongoing thunderstorm.The Koku An - This is a Karate Dojo. The perfect place to get your Karate on.The Prairie - Fight in a Prairie.... enough said.The Danger Zone 2 - Exactly like the danger zone 1... except more dangerous.The Iron Hell - Surrounded by cold steel you and your opponent must battle to the death. Why a fighting arena is in the middle of a factory I do not know.The Burai Zenin - Fight in a historical Japanese Temple. But only the entrance to the Temple not inside.The L's Castle - An ancient chinese castle. Fight your opponent on the stairs to be worthy of entrance to this great structure.The Blanca - Fight in what seems the drive way on a mansion. This guy must be RICH!Multi-Tiered ArenasA new (and now standard) feature in the Dead or Alive series was the multi-tiered stage design. This allowed players to smash their opponent through walls, windows, etc. to reveal new parts of the stages. (For example, in The Demon's Church, you can smash your opponent through the church window to fight in the lower level of the church.)While this feature is awesome, it's only available in the Single Player stages.Survival ItemsCarrot - 5000 PointsLipstick - 10,000 PointsMoneybag - 20,000 PointsMelon - 30,000 PointsHamburger - Minimum Health Recovery. 20,000 Points if health is at MAX.Onigiri (Rice Ball) - Medium Health Recovery. 30,000 Points if health is at MAX.Meat- -Maximum Health Recovery. 50,000 Points if health is at MAX.There are many more items to collect but these are the ones that are specified in the Instruction Manual.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12411">Soulcalibur</game><game id="11822">Soulcalibur II</game><game id="9855">Soulcalibur III</game><game id="20678">Soulcalibur IV</game><game id="4313">Virtua Fighter 4</game><game id="4891">Virtua Fighter 4: Evolution</game><game id="707">Virtua Fighter 5</game><game id="11189">Tekken 3</game><game id="14684">Tekken 4</game><game id="20689">Tekken 6</game><game id="6588">Mortal Kombat: Deadly Alliance</game><game id="383">Mortal Kombat: Deception</game><game id="11843">Mortal Kombat: Armageddon</game><game id="20449">Mortal Kombat vs. DC Universe</game><game id="3744">Def Jam: Fight for NY</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="11065">Shaman King: Power of Spirit</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="16842">Street Fighter: Anniversary Collection</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="5206">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1894012-box_doa2hc.png</image></root>