<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22304</id><name>Yakuza 3</name><description>OverviewYakuza 3 is an action game developed by Amusement Vision, and once again it follows the series lead character Kazuma Kiryu. It was released February 26, 2009 in Japan, and March 9, 2010 in the U.S. and March 12, 2010 in Europe. Sega has also been releasing free downloadable content (exclusive to Japan) for the game as of March 5, 2009. These downloadable packs contain 29 new costumes for Kazuma, two-player modes for some of the minigames (including darts, golf and billiard), 8 packs of new items and more. Most of this DLC is made available in Western releases through redemption codes packed into the game or via pre-order bonuses with specific retailers.PlotThe Yakuza wars are spreading over to the tropical paradise of Okinawa. After leaving his last base in Kamurocho, Kazuma Kiryu went to Okinawa and opened an orphanage named Sunshine Orphanage (U.S.) / Asago (Japan: translated to a flower called Morning Glory) with Haruka (from the first Yakuza game), a young girl who acts as his assistant. Together with the children they have taken in, the two slowly let go of the violent lives they have led prior to their arrival.However, the happy days are short lived for the Yakuza are tightly connected with the Japanese government. A shady deal that involves the land that has Kazuma's orphanage on it. After a mysterious man resembling Kazuma's supposedly deceased father shoots Daigo Dojima, the current chairman of the Tojo Clan, Kazuma returns to Tokyo once again.GameplayThe two main areas you will be exploring are Ryukyugai in Okinawa and Kamurocho in Tokyo. They are both fictional areas, although based on the real life locations of Naha's Makishi and Tokyo's red-light district, Kabukicho . They contain lots of activities to enjoy such as bowling alleys, batting cages, noodle houses, bars, and convenience stores. The main gameplay is brawling. Throughout the game Kazuma earns experience (through combat, eating and sub-stories) and will learn new moves and techniques as he becomes more and more powerful. Also, Yakuza 3 adds a change to random battle load sequences using a streamlined transition from exploring than jumping right into combat causing the player to stay with the action without a major load time or blank screen. This also is utilized in the new Chase Sequences, where Kazuma is forced to attack and force down a fleeing target in order to continue the story.Yakuza 3 contains many key features that are inherent to the series:Arena FightingBowlingBillardsCasino GamesBatting CagesSega Arcade GamesKey LockersYakuza 3 adds new features that weren't present in the previous entries:Karaoke: Another addition to the Yakuza series is Karaoke, containing a total of 6 songs. Kazuma can only sing one song, 'Kamurocho Lullaby' as well as Haruka having her own as well. The other four are accessible by inviting a Hostess, otherwise they involve Kazuma clapping and playing small instruments.Fishing/Golf/Darts: Thanks to the new Okinawa location, Kazuma can now access new mini games such as Fishing on the beach in front of the Sunshine Orphanage and Golf, which can be accessed by taking a Cab or Monorail. Another mini game making a debut is Darts which can be located in one of the games many Bars.Pub/Bars: Although originally accessible through various story missions, the addition of Bar hopping is a welcome feature to the franchise. Every beverage in several bars are actual drinks and contains informative dialogue attached as to how some are created and or/type of alcohol. The result of a few drinks actually displays a drunken meter on the players HUD and can cause Kazuma to access certain techniques/abilities.Revelations/First Person View: Kazuma has learned to blog allowing him to turn everyday situations in possible scenarios and unlocks new abilities. This is capable using the new First Person View system when in unison with emails sent from you companion, Mack Shinozuka, giving the player a description of where to find a new Revelation.Kamiyama's Workshops: In either Okinawa or Kamurocho, the player now has the ability to create, repair or purchase weapons and carry it in their inventory while accessing them using the directional buttons. Renji Kamiyama runs the Kamurocho branch while his younger brother, Renta Kamiyama, runs the Okinawa store. The weapon crafting adds a unique ability, never before utilized in the Yakuza franchise. Before hand, players would only be allowed to use certain weapons by completing certain side quests or by using specific locker keys. The new Workshop system allows players to start with a basic set of Accessories, Armor  Weapons, than upgrade them to various special forms or editions. While still retaining the same framework of finishing side quests or finding locker keys, the items necessary to craft are now rewards and some may also be found in local stores or pawn shops.This is also the first Yakuza title to include Playstation Trophy support, adding a total of 45 trophies including the series first Platinum.KamurochoKamurocho is a fictional district of Tokyo that serves as a major setting of the Yakuza series. It is regarded as Tokyo's "Sin City" district, and is home to such activities as underground gambling operations, loan sharks and similar illegal activities as well as more legitimate adult establishments including host and hostess clubs, massage parlors and nightclubs. It is also a district heavy with the influence of the yakuza, who frequently clash over Kamurocho's control. At the heart of Kamurocho is a towering skyscraper called the Millennium Tower, which serves as a key location to many events throughout the series.RestaurantsAlps Tea House (Cafe Alps)Food/DrinkPriceBlended Coffee500Blue Mountain800Mocha600Earl Grey500Milk Tea500Tomato Juice450Lemon Tea500Strawberry Parfait680Chocolate Parfait650Green Tea Float550Cake Set800Toast Set800Sandwich Set950Pasta Set1300Original Beef Curry1300MatsuyaFood/DrinkPriceBeef on Rice (Medium)380Beef on Rice (Large)480Pork on Rice (Medium)350Pork on Rice (Large)450Korean Style Vegetables on Rice (Medium)430Korean Style Vegetables on Rice (Large)530Original Curry  Rice (Medium)350Original Curry  Rice (Large)450Beef on Rice Curry610Kalbi on Rice with Kimchi (Medium)490Kalbi on Rice with Kimchi (Large)590Tuna Yamakake (Medium)490Tuna Yamakake (Large)780Barbecued Beef Set Meal630Korean Barbecued Beef Kalbi Set Meal680Demiglace Sauce Hamburger Steak Meal580Barbecued Pork Set Meal550Ginger Pork Set Meal580GelateriaFood/DrinkPriceVanilla Gelato280Strawberry Gelato280Chocolate Gelato280Red Bean Gelato280Caramel Gelato280Coffee Gelato280Double350Triple430Quadruple*780**Only appears on the menu if "Tokyo Week 1 Magazine" is in your inventoryShellacFood/DrinkPrice25-Year Yamazaki5,00012-Year Yamazaki70012-Year Hukushuu600The Macallen 194640,00012-Year The Macallen70030-Year Laphroaig5,00010-Year Laphroaig60012-Year Bowmore50012-Year Glenfiddich60017-Year Hibiki70012-Year Hakuto500Kakubin400Suntory Whisky Old40017-Year Ballantine's800Ballatine's Finest500Jack Daniel's600Early Times400Suntory Brand XO600Courvoisier XO3,000Carlsberg600Kyougetsu Green350Awamori Churajima400Aged Awamori Tenryugura400Atenshi (Earth Angel)Food/DrinkPrice12-Year Yamazaki70012-Year Hakushuu60017-Year Hibiki70012-Year Hokuto500Kakubin400Suntory Whisky Old400Ballantine's Finest500Early Times400Suntory Brand V.S.O.P.400Suntory Brand V.O.350The Premium Malts350Kyougetsu Green350Smile BurgerFood/DrinkPriceSmile Burger Set520Smile Cheeseburger Set560Teriyaki Smile Burger Set580King Smile Burger Set690Tuna Burger Set580Stewed Burger Set600Smile Shake220Smile Fries240Giga Smile Burger Set*880**Only appears on the menu if "Tokyo Week 1 Magazine" is in your inventoryBantamFood/DrinkPrice12-Year Yamazaki70012-Year Hakushuu60030-Year The Macallen5,25012-Year The Macallen85010-Year Laphroaig75012-Year Bowmore70030-Year Glenfiddich4,20012-Year Glenfiddich70030-Year Hibiki5,18017-Year Hibiki82030-Year Ballantine's4,65017-Year Ballantine's920Ballantine's Finest580Jack Daniel's700Early Times500Suntory Brand V.S.O.P.400Courvoisier XO3,000The Premium Malts600Carlsberg650Beefeater640Lemon Heart Demerara740Herradura Tequila Silver730Skyy Vodka730Pronto (Cafe Time Menu and Bar Time Menu)Cafe TimeFood/DrinkPriceGrapefruit Juice300Mango Drink330Hot Coffee250American Coffee250Cafe Latte300Cappuccino300Cafe Mocha350Royal Milk Tea300Milk250Cocoa290Eggplant Bacon Spaghetti690Shrimp  Tomato Spaghetti690Spaghetti with Meat Sauce630Spicy Fish Roe Spaghetti580Rich Egg Carbonara730Bar Time MenuFood/DrinkPriceGin Buck480Lime Refreshing Tequila Rickey580Tequila  Blood Orange580Campari  Soda530Kahlua  Milk58012-Year Yamazaki63012-Year Bowmore68010-Year Laphroaig700Suntory Whisky Old450Early Times480Boiled Hokkaido Soybeans400Octopus Carpiccio480Jamon Iberico (Ham)1,000Tomato Mozzarella Salad480Margherita Pizza600Kyushu No.1 RamenFood/DrinkPriceKyushu Tonkotsu Ramen750Stewed Tonkotsu Ramen980Pork Ramen950Spice Roe Tonkotsu Ramen860Egg Tonkotsu Ramen820Limited Ramen with the Works*1,250**Only appears on the menu if "Tokyo Week 1 Magazine" is in your inventorySushi GinFood/DrinkPriceTomago200Kappamaki200Tuna300Ama-Ebi300Engawa300Tsubugai300Namatako300Kampachi500Kamburi500Hirame500Shima-Aji500Kimmedai500Ikura1,000Akagai2,000Otoro2,500Awabi3,000Uni3,000Worker's Scattered Sushi*1,280**Only appears on the menu if "Tokyo Week 1 Magazine" is in your inventoryKanraiFood/DrinkPriceSalted Tongue1,400Grade A SaltedTongue2,500Kalbi1,200Grade A Kalbi2,700Sirloin1,100Grade A Sirloin2,400Harami1,000Grade A Harami2,500Liver Sashimi1,300Horumon-yaki800Seafood Platter1,700Kimchi Combo600Stone-Roasted Bibimap1,500Spicy Beef Soup1,400Special Limited Sirloin*2,800**Only appears on the menu if "Tokyo Week 1 Magazine" is in your inventoryInstallationThis game requires a 5 GB installation on the PlayStation 3.ReceptionIt currently holds an 80 average on Metacritic.According to VGChartz, the game sold approximately 48,164 copies in North America in its first week; 76,535 total after 3 weeks. Some point to the fact that Sega chose to release the game on the same date as the Western release of Final Fantasy XIII as part of the reason for low sales.Downloadable ContentThe US release of Yakuza 3 includes a package of four different DLC bundles, already included in packaging.A new Boss Rush mode, called "Battle for Survival."Two new Tournament modes, including a single and tag division.Also the new Haruka's Request, where Kazuma is able to escort Haruka around Kamurocho in order to raise her approval meter.Sega has also released an exclusive set of DLC included as a Gamestop pre-order gift. This package is now available for purchase in the Playstation Store, they contain:Extra Costumes for the main characters.A new competitive mode, where 2 players can compete in Pool, Golf, Darts and Bowling.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7812">Shenmue</game><game id="8195">Way of the Samurai</game><game id="27256">Kenka Bancho: Badass Rumble</game><game id="24516">Way of the Samurai 3</game><game id="33006">Way of the Samurai 4</game><game id="6608">River City Ransom</game><game id="1187">Shenmue II</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1832938-box_yakuza3.png</image></root>