<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22356</id><name>Dance Dance Revolution UNIVERSE</name><description>OverviewDDR Universe is the first DDR game made for HD-capable machines and is an Xbox 360 exclusive. Gameplay remains largely unchanged using the Dance Mat though the game can be played using the 360 controller. The game features a variety of familiar modes improved for the new generation.GameplayThe basics of the gameplay established by previous games in the series remains unchanged. Using the Dance Mat players must step in the appropriate direction which is dictated by the arrows that appear on the screen. These actions range from simple directional manoeuvres to and intense acrobatics. Using the Xbox 360 controller, the D pad and face buttons (X, Y, B, A) serve the same directional purpose. The game demands the use of both the D pad and the face buttons since pressing down on the D pad cancels out the ability to press up, hence the Y button emulates this function.Groove RadarPlayers can rely on a graphical representation to indicate just how demanding a song will be and in what way, based on the difficulty level that they choose.Stream: Indicates the amount of stepsVoltage: Indicates the density of stepsAir: Indicates the amount of double steps and jumpsFreeze: Indicates the intensity of freeze arrows (continuous notes)Chaos: Indicates the intensity of off-beat notesModesGame ModeIn game mode you can play the default set of songs to try and earn the highest "AAA" grade.Party ModeContains a subset of minigames for up to 4 playersPower: An endurance game that contains 5 special song mixes from previous games.Speed: Players must clear all arrows as fast as possibleAttack: Each direction is tied to a power up. Succesful hits fill up the meter. The power ups are automatically used against the opponent.Bomb: Make a combo before the bomb blows and pass it to the other player.Sync: Players must keep each other's steps synchronized to succeed.Triple: Play using three dance mats at once, or with two other playersQuad: Same principal, only with 4 dance mats or players.Point: Starting with 16 points the player with the least accuracy per step, loses a point.Score: Player with the highest score at the end of the song, wins.Relay: Players take turns on a song.Quest ModeIn quest mode you travel across a map of the United States in order to battle against other dancers and eventually become the champion of all competitions. The overhead view is similar to that of a board game and the player must pay a small amount of money each time he advances. Hiring back up dancers will speed up the process when building your fever meter in a crowd pleasing event. The game will present the player with specific challenges like upholding a combo or only hitting freeze arrows. In battle, players can pick their song of choice which gives them an advantage. Playing in Quest Mode is the only way to unlock new songs.Challenge ModeAs the title suggests this mode is the most challenging one in the game. It features a variety of minigames spread across 10 increasing difficulties in which the songs are pre-determined. The difficulties are:SimpleModerateOrdinarySuperiorMarvelousGenuineParamountEorbitantCatastrophicApocalypticAdditional ModesOther modes include: Xbox Live, Training, Edit Mode, Workout Mode, Jukebox, A list of Records and a simplified version of the game called Basic Edition.Visual StyleThe game makes use of flashy patterns and vivid colors superimposed over anime style characters performing dance routines. A minority of the songs feature their original music video.SoundtrackSong TitleArtistU.S.EUROPETYPE8 bitDrew CampbellYesYesDefaultAcceptable In The 80'sCalvin HarrisNOYesDefaultAll Up In My FaceDJ AcucrackYesYesDefaultB4U (B4 ZA BEAT MIX)NAOKIYesYesDefaultBeyond Here and NowNeuropaYesYesUnlockableBongo!Wavefroup Feat. Scotty DYesYesDefaultBrightness DarknessSparkerYesYesDefaultCachacaMokky De Yah Yah'sYesYesUnlockableCastlevania (Freestylin' mix)WaveGroup Feat. Nicky GYesYesDefaultCaught By The FuzzSupergrassNOYesDefaultChange ChannelLo-Fi-FnkNOYesDefaultChelsea DaggerThe FratellisNOYesDefaultCish CashBasement JaxxNOYesDefaultClose Your Eyes (mix)DaybehaviorYesYesDefaultCosmic HammerJondi  SpeshYesYesDefaultDancefloor KillerRichard KayvanYesYesDefaultDiamond JealousyAkira YamaokaYesYesDefaultDon't Play NiceVerbaliciousYesYesDefaultDrivin'NAOKI Feat. Paula TerryYesYesUnlockableEverytime We Touch (Radio Mix)CascadaYesYesDefaultFeels Just Like it ShouldJamiroquaiYesNODefaultGirlsThe ProdigyNOYesDefaultGO!DM AshuraYesYesDefaultGrandolinZerofuserYesYesDefaultGuilt is a Useless Emotion (Mac Quayle Mix)New OrderYesYesDefaultGyruss (Full Tilt Mix)JT.1UPYesYesDefaultHate To Say I Told You SoThe HivesNOYesDefaultHealing Vision (Gridlok Mix)DE-SIREYesYesUnlockableHeart With A View (Echo Image Mix)The Echoing GreenYesYesDefaultHorsemen of the InvisbleSecret Chiefs 3YesYesDefaultHOT LIMITJohn DesireYesYesDefaultHydrasoundGeomancerYesYesDefaultIgnitionAudio MagneticsYesYesDefaultIndian SummerCantonYesYesDefaultInfinite PrayerL.E.D. Light Feat. GoroYesYesDefaultINSERTiONNAOKI UndergroundYesYesDefaultKagerow (Dragonfly)Des-ROW UnitedYesYesDefaultKoibitoTogo Project Feat. SanaYesYesUnlockableLess 'Yap-Yap'Temporary LoversYesYesDefaultLoopsJondi  Spesh feat J.BoneYesYesDefaultLonely At The TopThe Ordinary BoysNOYesDefaultLove is On Our SideFrank Popp EnsembleYesYesDefaultLove Me Do (The Acolyte's Mix)Akira YamaokaYesYesUnlockableMagic Carpet Ride (Steir's Mix)Philip Steir Feat. SteppenwolfYesYesDefaultMaximizerCLI-MAX S.YesYesUnlockableMonsterThe AutomaticNOYesDefaultMy Only Shining StarNAOKI Feat. Becky LucindaYesYesUnlockableNightshade (Diskowarp Easily Amused Mix)Melody and MezzoYesYesDefaultPARANOiA Evolution200YesYesUnlockablePrecious (Sasha's Gargantuan Vocal Mix)Depeche ModeYesYesDefaultPut Your Faith In Me (Steve Porter Mix)UZI-LAYYesYesDefaultRace Against TimeJeff SteinmanYesYesDefaultRain of SorrowNM Feat. Ebony FayYesYesDefaultRapper's DelightSugar Hill GangYesYesDefaultReturn of the Toe JamBig IdeaYesYesUnlockableRock SteadyAll SaintsNOYesDefaultRoughneckskylab 2000YesYesDefaultRun It!Chris BrownYesNODefaultSaturday NightOzomatliYesYesDefaultSensesJ1.1UPYesYesDefaultSeptember '99Earth, Wind, Fire Vs. Phats  SmallYesYesDefaultSky HighDJ MikoYesYesDefaultSlamPendulumYesYesDefaultSlow (Chemical Brothers Remix)Kylie MinogueYesYesDefaultSomeboy To LoveBoogie PimpsYesYesDefaultSomething WonderfulL.E.D.YesYesDefaultStop Violence!TogoYesYesUnlockableSummer FantasyAlien SixYesYesDefaultSuperfreakBeatfreakzNOYesDefaultTest RoomPlus Tech Squeeze BoxYesYesDefaultThe CreepsCamille Jones Feat. Fedde Le GrandNOYesDefaultThe HopOR-IF-ISYesYesDefaultThere's A RhythmDig BearYesYesDefaultThink Ya Better DsAmiYesYesUnlockableTir Na N'ogWorld SequenceYesYesUnlockableTreble, Bass and AttitudeThe AcolyteYesYesUnlockableTsugara (OR-IF-IS Mix)RevenG vs DE-SIREYesYesDefaultTwistGoldfrappYesYesDefaultVanity AngelFIXXYesYesDefaultWe Are Connected (Overdrive Mix)Jondi  SpeshYesYesDefaultWhat Have HerChris FortierYesYesDefaultWraithMonolithicYesYesDefaultWWW.BLONDE.GIRL (MONO MIX)Jenny RomYesYesDefaultXenonMr. TYesYesUnlockableYoungmen BluesRound TableYesYesDefaultDownloadable ContentThe following songs are available for purchase on the Xbox Live Marketplace separately for 80 Microsoft Points ($0.99) each, or as part of the two Mega Packs for 800 Microsoft Points ($9.99) each.These songs are not available in some European countries.Mega Pack 1Song TitleArtistAM-3PKTzAudiophilosophyNeverakkaBeside YouIntuitionBroken My Heart (Cusimo  Co. Starlite Remix)NAOKI feat. Paula TerryCANDY*Luv UNLIMITEDEctasyd-complexKiss Me All Night LongNAOKI J-STYLE feat. MIUMe and My FriendsThe Dandy WarholsOn the Jazz (Smooth House Mix)Jonny Dynamite!White HotR.A.S.T.Mega Pack 2Song TitleArtistBattle BreaksDJ TAKAWOCatch It!TOTAL SCIENCEDynamite RaveNAOKIGradiusic CyberTAKAHimawariRiyu from BeForUJelly KissTogo Project feat. SanaMoment 40MoshicLove This Feelin' (ZONK Remix)Akira YamaokaPut Your Faith in Me (Saturday Night Mix)UZI-LAYToe JamBig Idea Xbox 360 Game InstallationDance Dance Revolution Universe requires 3.4GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD.</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2280569-box_ddru.png</image></root>