<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22399</id><name>Ore no Ryouri</name><description>OverviewOriginal box art Ore No Ryouri is a Japanese restaurant management simulator, originally released in Japan for the Playstation on September 9th, 1999. A demo was also included on a Playstation Underground demo disc as a featured import. A digital version was released on August 20, 2007 on the Japanese PlayStation Store.Due to the games popularity it was added to the “Best of” Playstation releases in Japan and later a Playstation 2 party/board game, Gacharoku, was created based on the characters and art style.Premise You play a young chef, who must cook his way up through 9 different restaurant levels, cooking a variety of 39 different dishes.Is that a tongue or his mouth?The game utilizes the dual-analog sticks in an innovative way to simulate the actions of various kitchen activities such as chopping carrots, stirring soup and pouring beers. Also occasional mini games pop up that have you washing dishes, squashing bugs and chasing robbers down the street. All controlled with the dual-analog sticks.The game features single-player and various multiplayer modes. Including cooking challenges and a head to head mode. GameplayPatrons enter the restaurant and take a seat at the bar on the bottom of the screen. Their order is then added to a queue on the left of the screen. You can have up to 6 orders in queue at once and multiple dishes-in varying stages-on the go.  Pouring a beer Selecting the order brings up the cooking mode. Utilizing the dual sticks similar to your hands you fulfill the order. For example, to chop a carrot you move the left stick to slide your hand down the carrot and use an up and down motion on the right stick to chop. To pour a beer, you tilt the glass with the left stick and pour with the right, filling the glass to the customer’s request. More complicated dishes require multiple steps. To make soup you need to chop the vegetable in step one, and then stir the soup for step two. With multiple dishes on the go it can get quite hectic managing everything and still satisfying the customer. All your hard work gains you cash, the better the job the bigger the pay-off.Battling grandpa-sanAs you progress through the different restaurant levels the variety and difficulty of the dishes increases. Also, in between levels you are occasionally challenged to cook-offs by a rival frog chef and his crew.</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6163">Cooking Mama</game><game id="40093">Cook, Serve, Delicious!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/7/72276/1425274-ore_no_ryori__my_cooking__cover.jpg</image></root>