<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22394</id><name>Slap Happy Rhythm Busters</name><description>OverviewSlap Happy Rhythm Busters is a a 3D cel-shaded music-infused fighting game developed by Polygon Magic and published by ASK on  June 29, 2000. The game features a 4-button layout similar to King of Fighters, and plays strictly as a 2D game despite the polygonal graphics. Despite only being released in Japan, the game is entirely in English. Comparisons to Jet Set Radio have been made, featuring a comparable visual aesthetic. Most of the music in the game is hardcore breakbeat techno, performed by several Japanese techno artists. The game's story is a bit piecemeal: There is a tournament that has been put on by Rude Boy, but at the same time a UFO has landed near "Down Town" and a wide number of characters have various interests in it.Gameplay The Beat Combo minigame.Slap Happy Rhythm Busters plays like most typical fighting games, but the game's most notable addition is the Rhythm mechanic. Throughout the fight, the player will slowly fill up their Beat meter while dealing and receiving damage. Once the player has stored three bars of the Beat meter, they can perform a Beat Combo. When used, this is where the game's Rhythm aspect comes into play, in the form of a DDR-style minigame. The player must match the oncoming "beats" on a corresponding 4-directional pad. If the player manages to beat the opponent in this mode, they will be treated to a Fever finishing move. The player is able to practice this minigame in DJ Practice in the main menu, where they can also unlock additional extras by perfecting the minigames as each character. In battle the opponent can attempt to interfere with your beat combo by altering the direction some of the "beats" come from. The Beat meter can also be used to perform conventional supers (referred to in this game as "rave attacks"); these cost one bar rather than three. If a player is heavily damaged in a short period of time, they begin to flicker yellow instead of becoming dizzy. While in this state they cannot block attacks.  After each fight, the player can choose between two opponents to fight next.Characters  CharacterInformation April       April A Cowgirl proficient with her knives and guns who closely takes after her father. Her prize bull has been stolen by a mysterious UFO, and she's looking to find him. She is 15 years old (!!)   SPECIAL MOVES:  Western edge: While in the air or on the ground: QCF,   Square or triangleHanging Shotgun: While in the air or on the ground: down down, square or triangleHowling Lasso: Back,  X  SUPERS Agile Dance Edge: QCF,  both square and triangleEternity Pendulum: Down Down,  Square and triangleHer Fever finish brings out a large bull, which attacks the opponent and sends them into the air, allowing her to finish them off with dual 6-gauge shotguns.       Baron  Volt Baron  Volt Doctor Volt is a 48 year-old mad scientist who, like any mad scientist, delights in experimentation. He created Nitro, who promptly ran away; Baron, a gorilla from the Congo, is a much more controllable individual. Still, he gets up to all sorts of hijinks which embarass Volt to no end. Dr. Volt does not fight, he simply stands in the background while Baron does all the work.   SPECIAL MOVES: Bolgani-turn: back, forward, square or triangle Nara congo: QCB,  square or triangle  SUPERS: Bolgani Over Spin: back, forward,  square and triangleTando Nara congo: QCB,  square and triangle His Fever finish is a brutal uppercut, sending his opponent into the air before being struck down into the ground by another attack. Chad  Gram Chad  Gram Chad and Gram are a pair of freakish (and lazy) brothers who are employed by Holemon at his butcher shop. Gram, the larva-like older brother, is essentially unintelligent and serves as a mount for the younger, hammer-wielding Chad. They are 22 and 24 respectively. Chad decided to name most of their moves after himself, even though Gram does most of the work!   SPECIAL MOVES:  Rising Chad: down down, square or triangle Bad Smell: QCF, square or triangle  SUPERS: Skydive Chad: down down, square and triangleChad missile: QCF, square and triangle   Their Fever finish is a series of violent blows, sending the opponent into the air followed by an explosion.Dark-Ramos  Dark-Ramos Ramos who has apparently been somehow corrupted by Markantyle. He is very similar to the normal Ramos.    SPECIAL MOVES: Burning disc: QCF, square or triangleBurst flare: back, forward, square or triangleQueuing upper: down down, square or triangle  SUPERS:  Club cannon: QCF, square and triangleJank death rush: QCF, X and circle  His Fever finish is similar to Chad  Gram's.Euri  Euri She is sixteen year old "gas girl" (apparently this is fashionable in the Slap Happy universe). She has a huge crush on Trash and is candy-obsessed; she spends most of her time hanging out at the Candy Shop. She is capable of air-dashing!  SPECIAL MOVES: Gas shot: While on the ground or in the air: QCF, square or triangleHip pack shot: While on the ground or in the air: QCB, square or triangleShooting Sugar: While in the air: QCF, X or circleGumgum thow: back forward, X or circle  SUPERS: Gas over shoot:  QCF, square and triangleSugar rave limit: While in the air: QCF, X and circle    Her Finish finish is a psychedelic romp through a town made of candy with her opponent, followed by their demise. Frosty Frosty The creepy and psychotic mascot of the Candy Store. When he sees violence, he just can't control himself... and he really hates people who browse and don't buy!  SPECIAL MOVES: Frosty Beam: QCF, square or triangle Head Hunting: QCF, X or circle  SUPERS: Spread Bazooka: QCF, square and triangleSweet Manslaughter: QCF, X and circle His Fever finish involves freezing his opponent before smashing them into the sky. Garia Garia  A wise, strong, and beautiful fortune teller apparently from Morocco. She senses both the threat of the UFO and the evil of Markantyle and sets out to prevent anyone from getting hurt. She is 25 years old.    SPECIAL MOVES:  Somtam: QCF, square or triangleGaichie: QCF, X or circleNuasadoun: QCB, square or triangle SUPERS:Somtam Gaiyan: QCF, square and triangleMoosate Bobian: QCF, X and circle  Her Fever finish involves her summoning a large behemoth which rises up and swallows her opponent.  Holemon  Holemon   A creepy, disturbing and often silent butcher. He absolutely loves the art of cutting meat; having heard about the cow thefts and the UFO, he intends to invade the UFO and steal all the cows to supply his shop on the cheap. He is 40 years old.  SPECIAL MOVES: Butcher press: down down, X or circleMince cleaver: back forward, square or triangleBirdcage: QCF, square or triangle  SUPERS:Endless butcher press: down down, X and circleManiac slaughter: back forward, square and triangleHis Fever finish involves him running over the opponent with a silly looking tricycle.             Jacköo  Jacköo  Zeköo's mysterious and evil older brother. Little is known about him, but he is apparently quite violent and destructive. He shares most of his movelist and regulars with Zeköo. SPECIAL MOVES:  Nami slash: QCF, square or triangleTenshouken: Down down, square or triangleShouji-otoshi giri: QCF, X or circle SUPERS: Fuujinranbuken: QCF, square and triangleHayate tenshouken: down down, square and triangle His Fever finish is a series of dance moves followed by a swift strike with his blade on his opponent.   Markantyle Markantyle An incredibly cruel and evil old man from Russia whose attacks are in fact by his trained wolves, similar to the Pokémon Trainer in Super Smash Bros. Brawl. While he normally doesn't fight himself, if his wolf is ever guard-broken he is forced to enter combat and is severely at a disadvantage. He is an assassin, and has met and fought Galia before; he's trying to kill Vivian and Roxy for some unknown reason. He's 62 years old.  SPECIAL MOVES: Suvoborg: down down, triangle or square Duruuk: QCF, triangle or squareLiuvov: QCF, X or circle SUPERS: Dovall Chestova: down down, triangle and squareMunoga duruuk: QCF, triangle and square  His Fever finish sends his wolf after his opponent, unleashing a barrage of attacks on them. Mia Mia A 16 year old Kung-Fu practitioner, she's always getting in street fights... but only for justice! She is friends with Ramos and Oreg, although she refuses to ride in Oreg's taxi...   SPECIAL MOVES: Haganshou: QCF, square or triangleKyuudankyaku: down down, X or circlehouhoko: back forward, square or triangle SUPERS: Resshin saihaiken: QCF, square and triangle Oukagiten enbu:   Down down, X and circle Her Fever finish involves dance moves before unleashing a series of punches on her opponent. Nitro Nitro   A cyborg created by Dr. Volt who has escaped. He's quite destructive and has a bad temper.  SPECIAL MOVES: Crane throw: QCB, square or triangleDrill crusher: QCF, square or triangle  SUPERS: Death crush crane: QCB, square and triangleMelt ray down: down down, square and triangle His Fever finish involves him hijacking an orbital laser cannon and obliterating his opponent.      Oreg Oreg  A tough and crazy 29 year old  taxi driver obsessed with speed. His taxi has been dramatically souped-up by Dr. Volt. He and Sledge (who shares many of the same moves) are buddies; Sledge is responsible for the checkered tattoo on Oreg's face.   SPECIAL MOVES: Jerky upper: QCF, square or triangle (can be held)Wheel head: back forward, square or triangleRejection ride: QCB, square or triangle   SUPERS:  Wheelspin head: back forward, square and triangleOverheat full course: QCF, square and triangle His Fever finish is him bringing his opponent along in his speeding taxi before ejecting him out of his car and into the sky. Ramos Ramos  The chief protagonist of the game, Ramos is a 17 year old "Fighting DJ". He's very hot blooded and gets very worked up in clubs, especially if anyone criticizes his "beat". He's also rather foul-mouthed; despite all this he's actually a good person.   SPECIAL MOVES: Burning disc:  QCF, square or triangleBurst flare: back forward, square or triangleQueuing upper: down down, square or triangle SUPERS: Club cannon: QCF, square and triangleJangling rush: back forward, square and triangle  His Fever finish move is a barrage of sound using his mixing deck and speakers, followed by a physical attack on his deafened opponent. Rude Boy Rude Boy The leader of the Down Town gang called "Cloud". He put on a tournament to prove nobody is stronger than himself. He is filled with "chaos power" and can transform into another form thanks to this fact. He hates Ramos.  SPECIAL MOVES: Interceptor: QCB, X or circleMoon slicer: QCB, square or trianglePulse direct: back forward, square or triangle (can be held)Spiral sword: down and X while airborne  SUPERS:Chaos sword: QCB, square and triangleNuclear pulse direct: Both triangle and square when the player has three stocks of "beat" meter.Rude change: QCF, square and triangle  His Fever finish involves trapping his opponent into a ball of energy before striking them repeatedly with his sword. Sledge Sledge A 30 year old tattoo artist who has "tattoo mania". He fights in much the same as Oreg. He wants to go to Japan and learn more tattoo techniques from Japanese tattoo masters; he's also really keen to ask Zeköo who did his tattoos.  SPECIAL MOVES:  Flying bomb: QCB, square or triangleDengeki spike: down down, square or triangleWheel head: back forward, square or triangleDrop shoulder: While airborne, down and X or circle SUPERS: Wheelspin head: back forward, square and triangleOverheat full course: QCF, square and triangle His Fever finish is a powerful punch, sending his opponent into the sky. Stealth Stealth  An evil alien who is an homage to the Predator. He has the bizarre dream of collecting one of every type of cow, and has been kidnapping cows from all over the world. Soon, his collection will be complete! He apparently loves "wagyu" beef the best. Unsurprisingly, he is the kidnapper of April's prize bull.  SPECIAL MOVES:  Astroid flare: QCF, square or triangleCosmo fusion: QCB, square or triangleQ-ball: down down, square or triangleMagnet sphere: back forward, square or triangle   SUPERS:  Cosmo explosion: QCB, square and triangleQ limit: down down, square and triangleHis Fever finish involves him flying up into space, charging up his arm and unleashing it on his opponent. Tom Tom Tom Tom Tom Tom is an 11 year old troublemaking graffiti artist and street urchin. Apparently his graffiti is so well done that it can take on a life of its own, as in the ghost that assists him in a number of attacks. Having heard about the UFO, he would love to paint graffiti all over it so even the residents of space can see his work.  SPECIAL MOVES: Flash hand: down down, square or triangle Graffiti shot: QCF, square or triangle SUPERS: Mad painting: QCF, X and circleScribble rise: QCF, square and triangle His Fever finish involves him summoning a ghost and kicking his opponent into the sky. Trash Trash Trash is a cool sanitary worker who has made it his personal quest to totally clean up "Down Town". He apparently has a nihilistic streak, and is constantly cleaning up Tomtom's graffiti and messes left by Chad and Gram. His special vacuum can suck up objects of virtually any size! He's 18.  SPECIAL MOVES: Cleanup: QCF, square or triangleStruck dust: QCB, square or triangleTriple dart: back forward, square or triangle   SUPERS: Vacuum box: QCF, square and triangleGeneral cleaning: QCB, square and triangle His Fever finish involves him sucking up his opponent in his vacuum cleaner. Vivian-Roxy Vivian-Roxy A pair of young girls who go everywhere and do everything together. Even though they're young, in combination they are quite skillful! Markantyle is attempting to kill them for unknown reasons; he may be their grandfather. What an awful guy!    SPECIAL MOVES: One, two, bang: QCF, square or triangleGuruguru bang: QCB, square or triangleReverse bang: QCF, X or circle     SUPERS:  Bokoboko bang: QCF, square and triangleMechyamechya bang: QCF, X and circle Their Fever finish involves them doing a backflip before kicking their opponent into the sky.   Zeköo  Zeköo A cool American samurai who is half Japanese. He inherited his sword from his father and is looking for his evil brother. He shares most of his movelist with Jacköo.  SPECIAL MOVES: Nami slash: QCF, square or triangleTenshouken: down, down, square or triangleShouji-otoshi giri: QCF, X or circle  SUPERS:  Kurofune raiko: QCF, square and triangleHayate tenshouken: Down down, square and triangle  His Fever finish is a brutal attack from his blade.</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20498">Draglade</game><game id="20096">Jet Grind Radio</game><game id="30762">Custom Beat Battle: Draglade 2</game><game id="5964">The King of Fighters '99</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2579/1703369-1703012_slaphappymanualfront.jpg</image></root>