<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22429</id><name>Super Robot Wars Alpha 3</name><description> Original Characters  Touma Kanou    The main character of the male super robot route. He works as a delivery boy as his part-time job. During an attack by Balmarian forces, he was forced to pilot the experimental super robot           RaiOh, which is equipped with the system LIOH, to prevent the destruction of the city. An inexperienced pilot but he has a strong sense of justice. Under the tutelage of Guy Shishio and Tetsuya Tsurugi, he joins the Alpha Numbers and undergoes training to become a better super robot pilot.  He would later form a strong rivalry against Balmarian pilot, Baran Doban and his Bemidoban. On one of their encounters,          RaiOh is heavily damaged as a result it would be upgraded to the DaiRaiOh.  Theme Song:  Toushi, Hatenaku (RaiOh) Shippuu Jinrai (DaiRaiOh)   Kusuha Mizuha as seen in Alpha 3         Kusuha returns as a the main female character of the super robot route.  This time her initial starting robot is the Gouryu Kai.  Theme Song: Ano Aoi Sora e (Gouryu Kai) Ryuko Tenshou ~ Warera ni Teki Nashi  (Shin Ryukoou)          Featured Series A list of the anime series which are featured in the game. Series that premiered in the Super Robot Wars series in this game are marked with "(new)". Mobile Suit Gundam 0083: Stardust Memory  Mobile Suit Zeta Gundam  Mobile Suit Gundam ZZ  Mobile Suit Gundam: Char's Counterattack  New Mobile Report Gundam Wing: Endless Waltz   Mobile Suit Gundam SEED (new)Mazinger Z Great Mazinger  Mazinkaiser (Banpresto Original version)Neon Genesis EvangelionThe End of EvangelionKing of Braves GaoGaiGarKing of Braves GaoGaiGar FINAL (new)Aim for the Top! Gunbuster  Cyber Troopers Virtual On: Oratorio Tangram (new) Cyber Troopers Virtual On: MARZ (new)Demon Sky Dragon GaikingDemon God of War GoshogunBrave RaideenSpace Runaway IdeonSuper Dimension Fortress Macross: Do You Remember Love?Marcross PlusMarcross 7Steel JeegBrave Leader DaimosSuper Electromagnetic Machine Voltes VSuper Electromagnetic Robot Combattler VInvincible Steel Man Daitarn 3Getter Robo GShin Getter Robo (manga version)Super Beast Machine God DancougarBanpresto Originals (original characters created for the game)SRX (Banpresto Original storyline)  </description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14424">Vanguard Bandits</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/12421/416197-926291_62563_front.jpg</image></root>