<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22443</id><name>Big Buck Hunter Pro</name><description>The GameBig Buck Hunter Pro is a simple and addictive game, but like all great games, has a great difficultly curve and great replayabilty. Each round will present you with 3 Bucks to take down, and as the game progresses it gets more challenging. For there are plenty of trees, bushes and Doe's that get in your line of sight. The Bucks can also be way off in the distance, making it harder to shot them or they might be right in front of you but hiding behind a doe. Don't shot the Doe, otherwise it's game over! Taking the Bucks down can be done in a variety of ways; you can go for the tricky head shot, you can go for the underneath shot and get lucky and hit thier heart or you can just pepper the poor animals! captionThe ModesSingle Gun PlayUsually for 1 credit you get to do one area, this consists of 5 rounds or for 2 credits you can do 3 areas of 5 rounds. Up to 4 players can play, taking it in turns to shoot the most Bucks. This is proably the best mode because with 4 players you get quite a lot of value for money.Two Player Head to HeadThe cabinet has two guns which both come into play when you pick head to head mode. Everything about this mode is pretty much the same except both players are shooting at the same Bucks. Which means the clever player will steal kills off the other player once the bucks have taken a hit or too. However if some one gets a head shot they get the all the points.Bonus RoundsBetween each area players take part in a bonus round. Usaully this involves hitting 30 odd targets, which include shooting at bottles, cow pats and gophers, in the quickest time and with the most accuracy.  captionThe CabinetBBHP comes in two styles of cabinet; the 38" deluxe and the 29" standard cabinet. caption</description><genres><genre id="35">Light-Gun Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10598">Cabela's Deer Hunt: 2005 Season</game><game id="20925">Cabela's Dangerous Hunts 2009</game><game id="3837">Cabela's Big Game Hunter II</game><game id="6895">Cabela's Ultimate Deer Hunt</game><game id="10278">Cabela's Big Game Hunter III</game><game id="1074">Link's Crossbow Training</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15138/389056-big_buck_hunter_pro.jpg</image></root>