<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22493</id><name>Florensia</name><description>Florensia is a new free-to-play MMORPG developed by Netts and Studio NJ in Japan. After numerous Closed Beta's, Florensia has recently opened up its servers for the Western Global Open Beta trial where anyone can sign for an account using the Alaplayer account website for free. Unlike the Closed Beta's, you do not need an activation key and all characters that are created will not be wiped after the Beta. The current Open Beta build will be used for main game once the Beta is finished and a Cash Shop is added, and will still remain free-to-play. A planned balancing update, as well as new character classes and other aditions, will be released in August 08. The official Florensia website, where you can create and account and download the client, is:  http://en.florensia-online.com/There are three online servers that you can choose from: LuxPlena: The Official European server.Pardioc: The Official United States server.Bergruen: The Official German server.   Karanir: The Official International Server GameplayFlorensia is based around a seafaring world with a maritime theme. The world is devided between three major islands, Cardiff, where the game initially starts, Magnel and Exeter, as well as  smaller isles home to quests, dungeons and shops. You are encouraged to build your own ship which you can then use to sail the seas and visit other islands. The gameplay is  split into traditional MMORPG dungeon, hunting and quest elements which take place on land and sea. Land battles are standard to the genre, with auto attack, skills and the ability to form groups. Sea battles take place at sea, and also use auto attacks and skills, but with cannons, and other ship based weapons such as harpoons, etc. There are two seperate leveling and  experience systems for land and sea combat, and thus your Land and Sea levels are seperate, along with your skill trees.An area of Florensia Players can create their own guilds (You will need three players at level 10 Land and Sea, as well as 10,000 Gelt to do so) and also take part in one on one PvP, as well as party versus party PvP modes. Later on, a Guild versus Guild system will also be implemented. As of yet, there is no detailed crafting system, but players can combine items to upgrade their weapons and armour, and can also take part in fishing for items by purchasing a Fishing skill book. The development team have also mentioned that a 'pet' system will also be implemented within the future.ClassesIn Florensia, you can choose from four seperate classes, although a fifth class, the 'Pirate' class, will be introduced to the game within a future update. All five classes have a different sub-class for extra specialisation, but these are not currently available and will be implemented within a planned update in August 08. The current available classes are:Character CreationMercenaryThe Mercenary is the offensive choice in Florensia, and can be developed for a tank or warrior role. They specialise in fighting monsters and wear armour to protect themselves. The Mercenary uses daggers, dual swords, one handed swords, two handed swords, rapiers, rifiles and shields.ExolorerThe Explorer is a master at long ranged attacks and can be developed for deadly precision or for a faster shooting role, and later will be able to use traps. They specialise in keeping enemies at a distance and attack with accuracy. The Explorer uses daggers, one handed swords, two handed swords, dual pistols and rifles.NobleThe Noble has highly developed magical abilities which can be used for devastating offensive attacks or illusion magic to lower the attributes of enemies. They specialise in magical skills, although cannot wear heavy protection. The Noble uses daggers, rapiers and magical weapons called the Cariad.SaintThe Saint is aligned with natural forces and uses their natural abilities to heal, buff and protect their allies. Their physical strength may be weaker than the other classes, but they are a valued member of all parties. The Saint uses daggers, one handed swords, two handed swords and magical weapons called the Cariad.ShipsAt the start of Florensia you are given your first ship, but you are free to create your own. You can create a new ship by buying a frame and sail, and then adding on extras such as an anchor, cannons and other devices. There are five types of ships that you can create in Florensia, each with their own strengths:Travel by Sea Armored ShipThe armoured ship has the most HP and defense of all the ships and is basically a seafaring tank, making it useful for beginners. It isn't as fast as other ships as a result, but comes equipped with special harpoons that can be shot out from the sides.Big Gun Ship The big gun ship has higher shooting power but is very slow to steer and handle, making it quite sluggish. It also has lower HP than the armoured ship. It comes equipped with the big gun cannot, capable of tremendous damage with a short cooldown period.Torpedo ShipThe torpedo ship is the fastest of all the ships and quick to steer, although with much lower defense and HP than other ships. It has above average attack and comes equipped with torpedos which can be shot out in front of it for a pre-emptive strike.Maintenance ShipThe maintenance ship is more unique than the other ships and is used more as a support ship. It has good defense and HP, but is slow to steer. It comes equipped with mines, which can be deployed behind the ship and explode when enemy ships get close.Assault Ship The assault ship is well rounded with average attack, defense and HP. It comes equipped with a special harpoon cannon which can be fired in front of a ship.Skills and StatsSkills in Florensia have to be bought before they can be learnt. When you level up your Land level, you gain three points which you can use to spend on your stats to improve them. When you level up your Sea level, you gain an extra point which can be spent on your stats. Both Land and Sea have their own skill trees. Each level by Land or Sea gives you a point that can be spent on new skills for either your character or ship, or can be spent on upgrading your skills to make them more effective. The stats that you can add, and what they do, are explained below:StrengthAdding to this increases your physical attack power for all weapons.DexterityAdding to this increases your evasion of physical attacks and also increases your physical attack rate and accuracy.ConstitutionAdding to this increases your maximum HP and also increases your HP recovery rate.IntelligenceAdding to this increases your magical attack power, as well as the hit rate and accuracy of magical skills and attacks.WisdomAdding to this increases your maximum MP and also increases your MP recovery rate.WitAdding to this increases the freeuency of attacking with a critical hit.System RequirementsFlorensia is a PC game that requires an Internet connection to play. It uses a client which can be downloaded for free from the official Florensia website. The system requirements for Florensia are:Minimum Requirements:Windows 2000, Windows Vista or Windows XP Intel Pentium 4 1.3 GHz 512 MB or more of RAM 64 MB 3D video card like GeForce4 Ti Series or better 4.0 GB free HD space 9.0c DirectX or higher 56 kbit/s or faster Internet connection </description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22063">Perfect World</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/10421/406917-250px_florensia.jpg</image></root>