<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22519</id><name>Naruto: Uzumaki Chronicles 2</name><description>OverviewA brand new tale arrives as Naruto faces different challenges to defend the Hidden Leaf Village and surrounding villages from the evil force trying to dominate it. An ancient organization, which was thought to have been disbanded, is alive and in search of orbs to resurrect a mechanical terror. It's now up to Naruto and all of the Hidden Leaf Genin to join forces with those of the Hidden Sand Village to stop this menace.UnlockablescharactersChoji Complete chapter 6 Gaara  Finish chapter 9 Kakashi  Beat chapter 1 Itachi Beat kakashi gaiden Kakashi Gaiden  Beat all missions(including S-rank) Kankoro    Unlocked from the start Kisame    Beat kakashi gaiden Might Guy Beat chapter 8 Neji   Beat chapter 3 Rock Lee Beat chapter 5 S-rank missions Beat Story once Sakura  Beat chapter 1 Sasuke Beat story mode twice Shikamaru Beat chapter 4  Unlock Individual Skill Chips for Character Stats Unlock Each of these Chips by completing all 12 battles in Survival Mode with Each Character. This can only be done after you've unlocked all of the Survival Mode battles. Each chip is a 4x6 rectangle (based on the R1  R2 jutsu chips being 4x4).Restore Chakra During the Loading screen if allocated enough time to move the right thumbstick enough in a circle. A Blue Chakara Ball will pop-out and if you notice your unfilled Stamina / Chakara Bar. It will refill a little about 25% worth everytime you do this. Between Loading screens with the Konoha Symbol in the lower right corner</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11814">The Bouncer</game><game id="10081">Tekken</game><game id="10387">Tekken 2</game><game id="11189">Tekken 3</game><game id="14684">Tekken 4</game><game id="18753">Tekken 5</game><game id="20678">Soulcalibur IV</game><game id="14300">Dragon Ball Z: Sagas</game><game id="31109">Kinnikuman Muscle Grand Prix MAX</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2215072-box_narutouc2.png</image></root>