<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22540</id><name>Powershot Pinball Constructor</name><description>OverviewPowershot Pinball Constructor is a take on the popular arcade       pinball game, released for the                 DS on January 24, 2008 in Australia and March 28, 2008 in Europe. The main selling point is the feature for players to                 create their own pinball tables and then share them with friends (as advertised in the tagline, "Play it. Create it. Share it."). The game had a quiet release, with barely any promotion or hype besides the odd interview, and wasn't covered extensively at all by media outlets as a result. However, it was panned by those who got their hands and reviewed it.   Gameplay    The first of three tables  The objective in games is to attain                high scores with a limited number of balls. Three single-player modes are included: Score Mode, Time Attack, and Stylus Mode. Time Attack gives players a                time limit to post the highest score possible, unlike Score Mode, in which there is no time limit and where games last until all   lives are lost. Stylus Mode is the equivalent to Score Mode, but has the twist of forcing players to control the        flippers by poking them with a stylus instead of using the shoulder buttons. There are also three multiplayer modes: Versus Mode, Tournament Mode, and Team Battle Mode. Three tables are included in this game, one of which is unlocked at the start. These feature the usual array of           bumpers,          score multipliers, and chutes that are present in more conventional pinball interpretations. Players can also build custom tables with the construction         editor using the stylus to place items, though the size and the shape of the tables cannot be manually altered with only a limited number of presets to choose from. Created tables can be tested at any time before saved, and can be played in the main game modes. Graphics Initially, the development team wanted to implement the core game in 3D, but due to hardware constraints, the team was dissatisfied with the end result. They then redid everything in                2D, before touching it up with 3D-looking graphics. ReceptionUpon its release, limited reception towards the title was overwhelmingly negative, with reviews specifically criticising it for the lack of customisation available during the table creation process. For example, only three bumpers can be placed in one pinball table. The Stylus Mode was also the target of negative comments as it was called redundant. Reviews cited that the stylus was nowhere near as intuitive as using the shoulder buttons.</description><genres><genre id="30">Pinball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5436">Metroid Prime Pinball</game><game id="19154">Pokémon Pinball</game><game id="8812">Pokémon Pinball: Ruby &amp; Sapphire</game><game id="4287">Mario Pinball Land</game><game id="20875">Dream Pinball 3D</game><game id="1557">Full Tilt! Pinball</game><game id="20994">Pinball Hall of Fame: The Williams Collection</game><game id="16223">Pinball Quest</game><game id="11121">MegaPinball</game><game id="12059">Pinball FX</game><game id="10645">Digital Pinball: Last Gladiators</game><game id="17172">KISS Pinball</game><game id="7971">3-D Ultra Pinball</game><game id="14646">Kirby's Pinball Land</game><game id="4979">Sonic Pinball Party</game><game id="391">Ruiner Pinball</game><game id="19109">Alien Crush</game><game id="7843">Virtual Pinball</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2717/399532-powershot_pinball.jpg</image></root>