<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22602</id><name>Mabinogi</name><description>Mabinogi features several different aspects that most MMORPGs do not have.Rebirth SystemThe rebirthing system is rather simple. Each character starts out at a certain age and with each week that goes by, a year is added to the character. After turning twenty, the character may be rebirthed, meaning having the option to alter his/her appearance and start back at level one with all his/her skills intact. Players tend to rebirth in order to gain AP faster and because, after a certain age, AP is no longer gained for aging. Rebirthing was originally a paid extra feature, but has since been made free of cost.Class and Race SystemThere are 3 races Elf, Giants and Humans. Each race is best fited from a certain class Elf have high dexterity and intelligence but low strength and unable to wear heavy armor or duel wield are better for ranger and mages. Giant have high Strength, more close range combat skill, able to carry 2 hand-sword with only one hand and heavy armor make them prefect for warrior. As for Human are balance able to wear anything except for race restricted gear make them good but not great for any class. The Class system in mabinogi is not the same as many mmo as there is no class restriction you can use and learn any skill you want too but the class system in mabinogi make it easier to earn skill experience for that class skill. You can also change your class anytime your rebirth.SkillsOne of the features that makes Mabinogi unique is it skill system. Skills are upgraded through different usage for skills. For example, two ways to advance the Critical Hit skill include both dealing and receiving critical hits. Once a skill has reached a certain number of experience, it can be either upgraded with the required number of AP or it can be even further advanced with experience so that bonus experience is given to the player.Combat SkillsCombat skills are associated with physical combat and combat support skills. These include:Ranged CombatSupport ShotMagnum ShotArrow RevolverCritical HitSharp MindFinal Hit(Human only)WindmillSmashDefenseCounterattackCombat MasteryLance MasteryGold StrikeCrash shotChargeEvasionLance CounterAxe MasterySword MasteryBlunt MasteryCrossbow MasteryBow MasteryLance ChargeStomp(Giant only)Spirit Weapon Awakening(require lv 21 Social)Taunt(Giant only)Final Shot(Elf only)Life SkillsLife skills are associated with non-combat skills. This includes the following:Music PlayingMusic TheoryComposingWeavingTailoringPotion MakingHerbalismCookingCampfireRestProduction MasteryRefiningBlacksmithFishingHandicraftFirst AidAlchemy SkillsAlchemy Skills are associated with range attack using cylinder and crystals.Alchemy MasterySummon GolemFlame BurstChain CylinderBarrier SpikesFrozen BlastHeat BursterRain CastingLife DrainSand BurstShockTransmutationClay AlchemyFire AlchemyWater AlchemyWind AlchemyWind BlastWater CannonSynthesisMetal ConversionMana CrystallizationMagic SkillsMagic skills are associated with magical combat and support skills. These include:Ice SpearHealingIceboltFireboltLightningFireballEnchantThunderMagic MasteryMeditationMagic FusionHail StormBlazeBolt MasteryFire MasteryIce MasteryLighting MasteryParty HealingCombatThe game features a combat system unlike most Traditional MMORPG's in that the outcome of a battle is largely dependent on the players skill, and not just stats. Timing and strategy are key, as you do not continually attack an enemy once they are targeted. The system is similar to a Rock, Paper, Scissors type of fighting. You can be interrupted during an attack, and left open for a counterattack from the enemy. You do not just land hits on each other back and forth until one dies, if properly planned you can kill the enemy without even being touched. An example of a strategy is to land a successful string of hits on an enemy, this will knock them back leaving you some space and a few seconds to act. Then you will follow up by preparing a combat skill such as Counterattack, which will then dodge their attack and attack back. This is only one strategy of many that can be made by using not only the Combat Skills, but Magic Skills to.PvPThere are 2 types of player vs player. First the traditional pvp challenging an other player to a head on head fight no skill restriction unless you use the honor system. but you may lessen damage deal to each other by % which mean even if your low lv you won't die in 2 hit. But the character with the higher skill will have an advantage. The second type of pvp is race or transformation war, if you are a elf or elf's supporter you can pvp the any giant or giant's supporter if you both have the elf vs giant option on. This also apply to paladin vs dark knight but it only take effect if you both transform and giant vs elf you do not have to transform.PC System RequirementsMinimum:OS:Windows速 XPProcessor:Single Core 2.0GHzMemory:512 MB RAMGraphics:GeForce FX5700, ATI Radeon 9500DirectX速:9.0cHard Drive:3 GB HD spaceSound:16 Bit Sound CardOther Requirements:Broadband Internet connectionAdditional:Web Browser: IE 8, Firefox, ChromeRecommended:OS:Windows速 8 / 7 / Vista / XPProcessor:Dual Core or higherMemory:1 GB RAMGraphics:GeForce 6600GT, ATI X800 or higherDirectX速:9.0cHard Drive:4 GB HD spaceSound:16 Bit Sound CardOther Requirements:Broadband Internet connectionAdditional:Web Browser: IE 8, Firefox, Chrome</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16614">Ragnarok Online</game><game id="21958">MapleStory</game><game id="22994">Shaiya</game><game id="1036">RYL: Path of the Emperor</game><game id="22187">Flyff - Fly For Fun</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14761/406327-mabinogi.jpg</image></root>