<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22605</id><name>Cursed Mountain</name><description>SynopsisEric Simmons' brother, Frank, is one of the worlds best high altitude climbers.  He was sent on a mission to climb the  Himalayan peak Chomolonzo with his climbing partner Paul Ward by Edward Bennett who wants them to retrieve an ancient artifact from the mountain.  After after finding the artifact, however, Frank and Paul have some kind of argument; Paul returned to basecamp alone and Frank is still on the mountain.  At basecamp the artifact, a stone, blows up and the Sherpas refuse to set foot on the mountain they call 'the sacred one' to find Frank. Now its up to you, playing as Eric Simmons, to scale Chomolungtso and save your brother.Cursed Mountain is attempting to get rid of horror game conventions like zombies and vampires. Instead the game's main enemies are spirits who are trapped in between the realms of life and death. These spirits are heavily based on the Buddhist religion, since Chomolonzo is located in Asia where the religion is prominent. Your character, Eric Simmons begins in a small monastery in the valley beside Chomolonzo, where he is trying to gather villagers to go up the mountain with him. The villagers strongly object because they say the goddess of Chomolonzo has been angered, so you must ascend to the peak alone. As you get closer and closer to the summit (a goal that is always in view) Eric will start to speculate that some of the horrors he is seeing are caused by the thin mountain air and that he is going insane. Instead of using conventional weapons like shotguns or melee weapons, Cursed Mountain makes you use Buddhist prayers to fight spirits. The prayers will be performed using the Wiimote to do pulling motions to gain a set of prayer instructions. Then you will have to follow the instructions which will usually be a series of motions that you will have to wave out using the Wiimote. Other motion controls will be used for things like quickly avoiding falling rocks by running and swinging an ice pick over your head. Developer Deep Silver has set Cursed Mountain in the 80s because they wanted the player to not have any modern technology like GPS, cell phones, or helicopters.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20475">Alone in the Dark</game><game id="18070">Fatal Frame</game><game id="9255">Fatal Frame II: Crimson Butterfly</game><game id="7225">Fatal Frame III: The Tormented</game><game id="21139">Fatal Frame IV: Mask of the Lunar Eclipse</game><game id="27264">Calling</game><game id="21478">Cryostasis</game><game id="5651">Penumbra: Overture</game><game id="3346">Penumbra: Black Plague</game><game id="25707">Silent Hill: Shattered Memories</game><game id="25112">Winter</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5911/1099399-cursed.jpg</image></root>