<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22621</id><name>pop'n music 5</name><description>Pop'n Music 5 also worked as a Key Disc for Pop'n Music 3 and Pop'n Music 4. CS version song list(Numbers represent difficulty level for Normal / Hyper / EX)      CS Original SongsIDOL POP / ファーストステップ / KAORI / Idol Pop (Moe) - 6 / 22 / -CLASSIC 5 / Step in Space / Waldeus von Dovjak (Harmanof) - 7 / 26 / 30BALLAD / Shooting Star / 岡めぐみ (Rachel) - 8 / 20 / -CIRCUIT / Drivin' High / Force083 (Hayata) - 9 / - / -D.I.Y. / 日曜大工 / Waldeus von dovjak (Tobyz) - 11 / 19 / -CRYSTAL / Escapes from your love / 長沢ゆりか (Ageha) - 14 / - / -KG / Sweaty Guys / ナメカワ・キミヲとザ・ハイターズ (Suit) - 14 / 21 / 26AOR / Harvest Moon / 植松和俊 (Paul) - 15 / 23 / -SKY / それから / パーキッツ (Poet) - 17 / - / -PURE / セイシュンing / くまのきよみ (Nanako and Soramame) - 18 / 26 / -POWER FOLK 4 / SLOW DOWN / 新堂敦士 (Ash) - 27 / - / - Arcade Version SongsNEW AGE / 龍舞~DRAGON DANCE / WORLD SEQUENCE (Karen) - 6 / - / -ALLEGRIA / クチビル / 中山マミ (Jose) - 8 / - / -CINEMA / 映画「SICILLIANA」のテーマ / Q-Mex (Kevin) - 9 / - / -US DANCEPOP / WITHOUT YOU AROUND / Geila Z. (Judy) - 10 / - / -PERCUSSIVE / 西新宿清掃曲 / サイモンマン (Mr. KK) - 10 / 26 / 32J-TECHNO 2 / power plant / Youhei (Shollkee) - 12 / - / -LATIN POP / In a Grow / Noriko Fukushima (Olivia) - 12 / - / -J-RAP / 昇りつめるの / Asako (Nyami) - 13 / 21 / -POWER ACO / 君が好きだよ～守って守ってあげるから～ / 新堂敦士 (Makoto) - 13 / 19 / -COMIC SONG / 天麩羅兄弟 / TEMPULA-BROS (PierreJill) - 14 / 17 / -SAMBA / Viva!2000 / MariliaKaorin (Nawomi) - 15 / - / -ROCK OPERA / Ti voglio bene ancora / Baleni Stella (Grappa) - 15 / - / -MONDO POP / BICYCLE / sugireo (Sugi-kun) - 16 / - / -FRENCH POP / Une fille dans la pluie / Fabienne Haber (Belle) - 16 / - / -NEO GS / Shock of Love / Kiddy  Sunshine Lovers (Wacky) - 16 / 18 / -PARAPARA / ウルトラハイヒール~I JUST WANNA TELL YOU / dj TAKA feat.ANGEL (Tamako) - 17 / 23 / 27SOFT ROCK / Homesick Pt.2  3 / ORANGENOISE SHORTCUT (Rie Chan) - 18 / - / -SENTAI / ビーマニ戦隊ポップンファイブ / うた:石原慎一 さくし:RYO (Akagi_Takayuki) - 19 / 23 / -JODLER / LA LA LA LA YO-DEL / DJ Simon (Clara) - 19 / 24 / 26ANIME HEROINE / 魔法の扉(スペース★マコのテーマ) / a.s.a (Space Maco) - 20 / 23 / -MUSICAL / ミュージカル"5丁目物語"よ りオーヴァーチュア / ナヤ～ン  his orchestra (Hotaru) - 21 / - / -HI-TENSION / どうなっちゃったって / チャーミングス (Lisa) - 21 / 25 / -HEAVY ROCK / INNOVATION / Des-ROW (Fat Boy) - 26 / - / -POWER FOLK 3 / 君が好きだよ～守って守ってあげるから～ / 新堂敦士 (Ash) - 20 / - / - Returning SongsBONUS TRACK REMIX / すれちがう２人 Millennium mix / apresmidi/Millennium Project (Sanae Chan) - 29 / - / -POPS REMIX / I REALLY WANT TO HURT YOU ～僕らは完璧さ Single edit～ / Sugi  Reo (Rie Chan) - 24 / - / -DANCE REMIX / Hi-Tekno Millennium mix / Hi-Tekno/Millennium Project (Shorty) - 18 / - / -J-TECHNO REMIX / Quick Master Millennium mix / act deft/Millennium Project (Shorky) - 16 / - / -BRIT POP / Girls Riot / Political Trees (Dona) - 22 / - / -HORROR / 妖怪Zの唄 / ナヤ～ン・ブラザーズ・バンド (Smile) - 13 / - / -SPECIAL ENDING / Tap'n! Slap'n! Pop'n Music! / Popper Head (Rave Girl) - 20 / - / -CLASSIC 4 / Concertare / Waldeus von Dovjak (Harmanof) - 20 / 32 / - Preview Songs(All these songs must be unlocked.)ONDO / ポップン音頭 / 高田香里 (Pop'n All Stars) - 11 / 16 / -TECHNO KAYOU / うるとら ボーイ / V.C.O featuring Yuko Asai (Pino) - 12 / 21 / -EVER POP / 2nd ADVENTURE / Jimmy Weckl (Higurashi) - 8 / 17 / -MODERNISM / 電波の暮らし / Q-Mex feat.フレディー波多江 (Mebae) - 13 / 20 / -LIGHT FUSION / micro dream / Mr. T (Kika) - 15 / 19 / 28TAIYOU / 太陽にほえろのテーマ / - (Nyami) - 18 / 22 / 30SOUL / Gotta Get My Groove on / good-cool feat. Aundréa L Hopkins (Jessica) - 22 / 26 / -HIP ROCK / 大見解 / Des-ROW feat. TSUBOI for ALPHA (Roku) - 20 / 29 / -TRANCE / Foundation of our love / dj TAKA feat. ASAKO (Tran) - 19 / 28 / -GUNDAM / 翔べ!ガンダム / ミッキーマサシ (Nyami) - 11 / 25 / -  Hidden SongsLESSON / POP-STEP-UP / SOUNDROID / Lesson (Mimi) - 30 / - / -FRENCH POP J / Une fille dans la pluie 日本語バージョン / 新谷さなえ (Sanae Chan) - 18 / - / -POSITIVE REMIX / Candy Blue～Vocal Best Version / 浅井裕子 (MZD) - 19 / - / -NEO ACO REMIX / fly higher than(the stars) 2 STEP mix / DJ SIMON (Reo Kun) - 20 / - / -GIRLY REMIX / Love Is Strong To The Sky～V.B.-Remaster / SAORI (MZD) - 16 / - / -ENKA REMIX / お江戸花吹雪 TEYAN-day MIX / 高田香里 ReMIXed by SEIYA (MZD) - 23 / 26 / 31NEWS / Landmark / NAKATEK (Boy) - 14 / - / -FUNK ROCK / 熟れた花 / ミッキーマサシ (Shark) - 21 / - / -CUBAN GROOVE / サナ・モレッテ・ネ・エンテ / Togo Project feat. Sana (Banten) - 21 / 24 / 27HEART / Pink Rose / Kiyommy Seiya (Judy) - 18 / - / - Unlock InformationThere's always time unlocks. In CS 5, theres so many unlocks that multiple songs will be unlocked every half hour of play after 2 hours. For example, after 2 hours of play, you will unlock Heart, Cuban Groove, News, and Funk Rock. All songs will have been unlocked after 5 and a half hours of play.To unlock Ondo, get a high score of 240000 or more on Party Mode.To unlock Techno Kayo, get a high score on 260000 or more in 5-Line Mode.To unlock Ever Pop, clear an EX song in free mode.To unlock Modernism, get a score of 35000 or less on your first stage. Alternatively, do not get a 4, 2, or 9 in your entire clear screen for stage 1. That includes score, max combo, greats, goods, and bads.To unlock Light Fusion, play Circuit as your first stage and get a score of 90000 or greater. Alternatively, clear stage 1 with a max combo greater than 30, and when you add the ones and tens places of the max combo together, they must equal 10. For example, a max combo of 253 would not unlock Light Fusion, but a max combo of 46 would.To unlock Taiyou, get more than 110 goods on your first stage. Alternatively, play with Suit as your character, and get more than 85000 points on your first stage.To unlock Soul, from stages 1 and 2 combined, get more greats then bads, and more bads than goods. You must have less then 40 goods.To unlock Hip Rock, select a male as your character (for example, Boy) and on your first two stages combined, get less than 10 bads.To unlock Trance, play J-Tekno as your first stage with a score of 80000 or more and a max combo of 30 or more, then play US Dance Pop as your second stage and clear with a score of 85000 or more and a max combo of 50 or more. In 5-Line Mode, play US Dance Pop as your first stage and J-Tekno as your second stage instead.To unlock Gundam, clear Sentai with a score of 85000 or more. Or, pick Smile as your character and in one of your first two stages, get the last two digits of your great, good, or bad column to be 79. For example, if on you second stage you had 279 greats, Gundam would be unlocked.To unlock News, select Space Maco, Sugi-kun, Suit, or Smile as your character, then clear New Age as your first stage.To unlock Heart, play a game with Rie Chan as you character.To unlock Cuban Groove, clear Percussive as your first stage, then clear Crystal as your second stage.To unlock Funk Rock, select Fat Boy as your character, and on your second stage clear Rock Opera. In 5-Line Mode, clear Rock Opera on your first stage.To unlock Lesson, on your first stage, get the last two digits of your max combo to be "55", "77", or "33". Then, on your next stage, get the same digits to be "22", "88", or "33". Alternatively, in any clear screen, get the last columns of your greats, goods, and bads to be "0, 0, 0" or "5, 7, 3".To unlock Positive Remix, get a max combo of exactly 32 on your first stage, then clear your second stage with a max combo of 32 or more. Or, get the last digit of your max combo to be 3.To unlock Neo Aco Remix, clear Mondo Pop with a score of 90000 or more. Alternatively, clear Power Aco as your first stage with 80000 or more points, and on your second stage, clear Neo GS with more than 80000 points as well.To unlock Girly Remix, clear French Pop with more than 85000 points. Alternatively, clear a song that has a girl for its character (for example, French Pop), or a preview song from AC 6 (other than Hip Rock, so for example, Modernism) as your first stage with more than 90000 points. Then, as your second stage, play another song that fits into those categories and clear it with a max combo of greater than 80. Phew.To unlock Enka Remix, clear a song on hyper for your first stage with more than 90000 points, and clear another hyper song for your second stage with less than 15 bads. Or, clear your first stage with a combo of greater than 30, and your second with a combo greater than 70. Unlock CodesThe above songs can also be unlocked through codes entered at the title screen. Played songs will not be saved. The buttons correspond to the buttons on the Pop'n Controller from left to right.LESSON: 94781362POSITIVE REMIX: 4466373721NEO ACO REMIX: 222122222222213GIRLY REMIX: 133131313122132ENKA REMIX: 98968989687ONDO: 28333TECHNO KAYO: 1191191119EVER POP: 999911112819MODERNISM: 444422229999LIGHT FUSION: 1977714TAIYO: 129889211199SEOUL: 446673286HIP ROCK: 6666661TRANCE: 12344329GUNDAM: 4170NEWS: 778866692233441HEART: 2347646221288CUBAN GROOVE: 43212468JUNGLE ROCK: 3473479 </description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20673">Guitar Hero World Tour</game><game id="1420">Amplitude</game><game id="4031">Guitar Hero III: Legends of Rock</game><game id="5825">Frequency</game><game id="20639">Guitar Hero: On Tour</game><game id="8631">GuitarFreaks 3rdMIX &amp; DrumMania 2ndMIX</game><game id="6311">Guitar Hero</game><game id="21844">GuitarFreaks V &amp; DrumMania V</game><game id="12241">Guitar Hero Encore: Rocks the 80s</game><game id="14916">Guitar Hero II</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2424/413348-ac_05bannar_o.jpg</image></root>