<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22665</id><name>The Lost Crown: A Ghost-Hunting Adventure</name><description>The Lost Crown is an adventure game with horror elements. There are several  acknowledged influences from the works of writers Montague Rhodes James (1862 -  1936) and Joseph Lloyd Ca:rr (1912 - 1994). The main setting is the fictional  town of Saxton and its surrounding area, placed in the Fenlands of eastern  England. The town settings are based on two actual towns of Cornwall: Looe and  Polperro. Several of the landmarks outside the town, particulatly two Medieval  churches, are based on actual locations in Cornwall.   The main  character is Nigel Danvers. A former employee of the Hadden Corporation, Nigel  fled after stealing classified documents from the company. He starts the game by  leaving the  train Sleepwalker, though rather confused on how he got there.  There is only one other passenger Lucy Reubans. Originally aimless, Nigel soon  finds a new mission in treasure-hunting, He searches for clues of the current  whereabouts of an Anglosaxon crown. Its original owner was King Ganwulf,  apparently one of the founders of Saxton. The Crown has been missing for  centuries but seems to have had a long-term effect on the fates of the city and  its residents.   Hadden Corporation seems to have some contacts in the  city and Nigel is soon contacted by them. Assigned to do some ghost-hunting to  get back in their good graces. In practice, this means investigating various  mysteries and murders occuring throughout  the long history of Saxton. Not to  mention a number of ongoing crimes in modern-day Saxton. Various of the missions  require Nigel working alone. Others team him up with Lucy, a college student  visiting her family. They end the game as partners, apparently both hired by  Hadden Corporation for future missions.  The ghosts encountered in the  game range between decidedly human-looking entities, transparent  apparitions and smoke-like wraiths. In disposition they can be  friendly, mischievous or extremely threatening. Some require assistance, others  provide information and a few are opponents. The living residents of Saxton have  their own peculiarities. Nigel and Lucy act as if the year is 2007. But the  general appearances, clothing or speech patterns of the other characters tend to  point to older time periods. For some there are written or spolen hints of them  being active in the 1950s, 1940s or even earlier. The anachronisms arguably  making Saxton appear even more mysterious.  </description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5010">Dark Fall: The Journal</game><game id="6212">Dark Fall: Lights Out</game><game id="8441">Sherlock Holmes: The Awakened</game><game id="6870">Sherlock Holmes: Secret of the Silver Earring</game><game id="3970">Myst</game><game id="16230">Riven: The Sequel to Myst</game><game id="20146">Shivers</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1987/730241-lost_crown_front.jpg</image></root>