<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22699</id><name>MotoGP 08</name><description>The 2008 edition of the MotoGP franchise is the first time a single developer, Capcom, will bring the game to all current system platforms. This also marks the first time in recent years that the 125cc and 250cc support classes are available in addition to the MotoGP class.The Wii edition, as with most Wii ports, makes use of the Wii remote as the handlebars of the motorcycle to bring a much more realistic feel to the title.Capcom editions have carried a reputation for a more realistic sim racer than the MotoGP games published by THQ, who have been acused of a more arcadey style. Capcom has allowed players to customize their experience between these two styles of gameplay for MotoGP 08.GameplayThere are various modes of gameplay in MotoGP08, such as Single Race, Championship, Challenge, and Time Trial. Much like more recent races released today, you work your way from the ground up as you race through Career mode with 125cc, 250cc, and MotoGP races. The points you accumulateThe graphics aren't too shabby either.Moto GP is the continuation of the Moto GP series on the next generation consoles. As well as the improved graphics and physics in the game it continues its blend of reality and sheer difficulty with an arcade element that has grown to be a signature trademark to the series. Moto GP 08' is one of the recent Moto GP games to come out in North America. The series has made all of its appearances in Europe but has skipped a years due to economic downturn in the North American market for motorcycle racing games  System Requirements   Minimum System Requirements Recommended Specs   OSWindows® XP / Windows Vista® Windows Vista®  CPU Intel® Pentium® 4 processor  Intel® Core™2 Quad processor or higher / AMD Athlon™ 64 X2 or higher    Memory  512 MB (Windows XP) / 1 GB (Windows Vista)   1 GB (Windows®  XP) / 2 GB (Windows Vista®)    Hard Drive  8.0 GB free space    Video DirectX®9.0c/Shader3.0, NVIDIA® GeForce®6600 series or higher*, or ATI Radeon™ X1600 or higher  VRAM 512 MB, NVIDIA® GeForce® 8600 series or higher, or ATI Radeon™ HD 2600 or higher    Sound  DirectX®9.0c compatible sound cards Controller Support Keyboard or Xbox 360 Controller  </description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23187">Ducati World Racing Challenge</game><game id="15429">Excitebike 64</game><game id="20935">SBK: Superbike World Championship</game><game id="26995">Powerbike</game><game id="28043">SBK: Superbike World Championship 09</game><game id="29936">SBK X: Superbike World Championship</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1817655-box_mgp08.png</image></root>