<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22769</id><name>Neon Genesis Evangelion: Battle Orchestra</name><description>OverviewReleased over 10 years after the debut of the original series, this PS2 game was never released outside of Japan. It came in the same year that the first in the Rebuild of Evangelion series of films was released, a remake/re-imagining of the first six or so episodes of the series. Whilst this release date was likely targeted as part of the film's hype machine, the game sticks mostly to the continuity of the original series, aside from a few of it's own unique divergences.The PSP release, which came almost exactly 2 years later, includes a few extra characters, including designs unique to the Rebuild continuity.Game ModesThere are 6 game options available from the main menu:Story modeRumble modePractice modeEndless modeShop  GalleryOptionsThese are largely self-explanatory. Rumble mode is a free match/versus mode, and Endless mode is a survival-type mode. The Shop menu features 2 sub-sections: a store where points earned in other modes are spent to unlock new characters, stages, BGMs etcetera, and a sound test menu to listen to BGMs and sound sets purchased through said store.Playable charactersEvangelion UnitsUnit 00Unit 01Unit 02Unit 03Unit 04Rebuild Unit 00 *Rebuild Unit 01 *AngelsSachielShamshelRamielGaghielIsrafelSahaquielLelielZeruelBardiel (as a variation on Unit 03)Lilith *OthersJet AloneGunbuster(* denotes a PSP exclusive character.)Many of the Angels in the game, due to the less direct or more unusual natures of the threats they pose, have their combat capabilities abstracted quite far from those presented in the subject material. Sahaquiel, for example, bombards the world from orbit using pieces of itself in the series; here, it floats around at ground level, and spins itself at enemies to attack.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17743">Super Smash Bros. Melee</game><game id="38140">PlayStation All-Stars Battle Royale</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2579/1791823-684a50cc2379e40fd84bf720ab98acc1.jpg</image></root>