<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2279</id><name>Project Gotham Racing 2</name><description>Project Gotham Racing 2 is a racing game for the Xbox and is the highly anticipated sequel to Project Gotham Racing from   Bizarre Creations and Microsoft.  It is the first game in the series to have online multiplayer for 8 players via Xbox Live.Project Gotham Racing 2 is a game which encourages a combination of speed and style, which is represented through its Kudos points system where elaborate moves such as overtaking, drifting and power sliding will award players Kudos points which will advance their ranking and will allow the purchase of new cars.  The game launched with races in exotic locations throughout the world from Barcelona to the famous motorsport track, Nürburgring.   Game TypesKudos World SeriesPlayers must compete in a series of races throughout the world in 14 categories beginning from the Compact Sport class and ending with the Ultimate class.  The objective is to finish races in the top positions to win medals.  Depending on difficulty level, players can achieve steel to platinum medals.  Kudos World Series' modes include street races, one on one, cone challenges, hot lap, timed runs, overtake and speed camera.Arcade RacingThere are 60 races and the game will provide you with the track, car and game mode.  The races are evenly split by 20 street racing, timed runs and cone challenges events.Time AttackThe player must complete the course as fast as possible.  The player can choose their car, city and race track though they must first be unlocked from Kudos World Series. Cars ListCompact Sports  Mini Cooper S  Seat Leon Cupra R  Volkswagen New Beetle RSi  Ford Focus RS  Honda Civic Type-R  Renault Clio V6  Volkswagen R32  Lancia Delta Integrale Evo    Sports Convertible  Audi TT Roadster  Mazda Miata RX-5  Toyota MR2 Spyder  Porsche Boxster S  Honda S2000  BMW Z4 3.0i  Coupe  Audi TT Coupe  Mazda RX-8 Honda Integra Type-R Nissan 350Z Audi S4 BMW M3 Audi TT Quattro  Sports Utility Volvo XC90 Chevrolet SSR Mercedes ML55 AMG Porsche Cayenne Turbo BMW X5 4.6is Ford SVT Lightning  Pacific Muscle  Mitsubishi 3000 GT VR4  Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution VII Mazda RX-7   Toyota Supra Twin-Turbo Subaru Impreza WRX STi Nissan Skyline GT-R (R34) Nur  Roadster  AC 427 MkIII Renault Spider  Caterham 7 Classic  Lotus 340R  Lotus Elise  Vauxhall VX220  Classic  Porsche 550 Spyder  Toyota 2000GT  Mercedes 300SL Gullwing  Nissan 240Z  Ferrari Dino 246 GT  Jaguar E-Type  Porsche 911 RS 2.7  Ferrari 275 GTB  Lancia Stratos  Ferrari 250 GTO *Bronze  Sports Coupe Cadillac XLR Lexus SC 430 Audi RS6 Jaguar XKR Iceni Porsche Carrera Coupe (996 Morgan Aero 8 TVR Tamora  American Muscle  Chevrolet Camaro Z28  Pontiac GTO  Ford Mustang Fastback 2 2  Pontiac Trans Am  Chevrolet Camaro SS  Corvette Sting Ray  Ford SVT Mustang Cobra Super Car  Ferrari 355 F1 Ferrari 360 Spider Chevrolet Corvette Z06 Dodge Viper GTS Ferrari 360 Modena Porsche 911 Turbo (996) TVR Tuscan Speed 6 Delfino Feroce *Steel  Grand Touring  Bentley Continental GT  Ferrari Testarossa Ferrari 550 Barchetta Mercedes SL55 AMG Ferrari 575M Maranello Aston Martin Vanquish Lotus Esprit V8  Track Specials  Lotus Exige Vauxhall VX220 Turbo Dodge Viper SRT-10 Honda NSX Type-R (J) Noble M12 GTO3 Porsche 911 GT3 (996) Ferrari Challenge Stradale  Extreme  Ford GT40  Porsche 959 Ferrari F40 Ferrari F50 Porsche 911 GT2 (993 Jaguar XJ220 Ascari KZ1  Ultimate  Saleen S7 Ford GT Porsche Carrera GT Koenigsegg CC V8S Enzo Ferrari Pagani Zonda Mercedes CLK-GTR * Gold Porsche 911 GT1 *Silver TVR Cerbera Speed 12 *Platinum   * Unlock in completing Kudos World Series Locations  Barcelona Chicago Edinburgh Florence Hong Kong Moscow Nürburgring Stockholm Sydney Washington D.C. Yokohama  Downloadable ContentLocations  Long Beach Paris  Cars Paris Booster Pack  TVR Cerbera Speed 12 (Live)  Ferrari 288 GTO  BMW 645Ci  Ferrari 365 GTS4  Porsche 356A Carrera Speedster  Ferrari 250TR  Chevrolet Corvette C6  BMW M3 CSL  Long Beach Booster Pack  Radical SR3 Turbo  Porsche 911 GT2 Clubsport  Volkswagen Nardo  Ferrari 612 Scaglietti  Dodge Challenger R/T Hemi  Dodge RAM SRT-10  Ariel Atom 2  Subaru Impreza 22B STi  OnlinePGR2 had a strong online community with the community created game, Cat and Mouse. Played with 8 players, people would form teams of two, one player would be the cat; an upper level car and the other would be the mouse, normally a mini.  The first player who is mouse to cross the finish line wins. TriviaIn the garage area of PGR2 there is a usable arcade machine that hosts the first appearance of   Geometry Wars before it was made into a franchise.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9927">SRS: Street Racing Syndicate</game><game id="11055">NASCAR 08</game><game id="12395">Need for Speed: Hot Pursuit 2</game><game id="20038">NASCAR: Dirt to Daytona</game><game id="20597">Gran Turismo 5 Prologue</game><game id="2416">Gran Turismo</game><game id="17784">Gran Turismo 4</game><game id="12950">Gran Turismo 3 A-Spec</game><game id="8100">Gran Turismo 2</game><game id="21297">Gran Turismo HD</game><game id="7482">Gran Turismo Concept: 2001 Tokyo</game><game id="21390">Gran Turismo Concept: 2002 Tokyo-Seoul</game><game id="7313">Gran Turismo Concept: 2002 Tokyo-Geneva</game><game id="13895">Gran Turismo 4: Prologue</game><game id="10124">Midnight Club: Street Racing</game><game id="20927">Midnight Club: Los Angeles</game><game id="21114">Midnight Club: Los Angeles Remix</game><game id="20418">Midnight Club II</game><game id="5875">Midnight Club 3: DUB Edition</game><game id="8437">TOCA 2: Touring Car Challenge</game><game id="531">TOCA Race Driver 2</game><game id="5869">TOCA Touring Car Championship</game><game id="13734">TOCA Race Driver 3</game><game id="17872">TOCA Race Driver 3 Challenge</game><game id="12976">Need for Speed: Most Wanted</game><game id="18095">Need for Speed: ProStreet</game><game id="8844">Need for Speed: Carbon</game><game id="20741">Need for Speed: Undercover</game><game id="9651">Need for Speed Underground 2</game><game id="12254">Need for Speed Underground</game><game id="8831">Need for Speed: Porsche Unleashed</game><game id="5977">Need for Speed III: Hot Pursuit</game><game id="18021">Need for Speed: Carbon - Own the City</game><game id="367">Need for Speed II</game><game id="589">R:Racing Evolution</game><game id="20858">NASCAR 09</game><game id="20729">GRID</game><game id="7019">Ridge Racer V</game><game id="16276">Ford Bold Moves Street Racing</game><game id="20919">Ford Racing: Off Road</game><game id="7431">Ford Racing</game><game id="7777">Juiced</game><game id="3027">Metropolis Street Racer</game><game id="284">NASCAR 2005: Chase for the Cup</game><game id="22693">RACE Pro</game><game id="16882">Running Wild</game><game id="24866">OutRun Online Arcade</game><game id="25254">Roadsters</game><game id="24513">DiRT 2</game><game id="2453">R4 Ridge Racer Type 4</game><game id="25961">Blur</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2213166-box_pgr2.png</image></root>