<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22828</id><name>Sunday Funday: The Ride</name><description>Overview Sunday Funday is a Christian based video game by        Wisdom Tree released for the Nintendo Entertainment System. It was the last video game to be released for the US  NES by any company. Sunday Funday was not officially licensed by Nintendo due to the religious overtones. The player controls a skateboarder who is late for Sunday School. He must defeat the obstacles that lie in his path to make his way to Sunday School.  Sunday Funday comes with two other games: an arcade style game called Fish Fall, and a NES karaoke version of the song "The Ride" by a Christian pop band    4Him. Comparison To Menace BeachSunday Funday is nearly identical to game called Menace Beach.        Menace Beach was also released by Color Dreams, but when Color Dreams decided to make Christian games instead of action games, they began releasing their older games with a few graphically changes. In the case of Sunday Funday they also made changes to the story.  Changes ObjectMenace BeachSunday FundayProtagonistBoy riding a skateboard Boy riding a skateboard while carrying a Bible Overworld Enemy 1Ninja Person in a white shirt  Overworld Enemy 2  Sumo wrestler Overweight woman Overworld Enemy 3 Clown on a balloon throwing water balloons  Clown on a balloon throwing water balloons   Overworld Enemy 4 Mole in a manhole throwing bananas  Mole in a manhole throwing bananas Overworld Weapon Bottle  Newspaper  Underworld Enemy 1 Elvis impersonator Plumber Underworld Enemy 2 Sumo wrestler  Overweight man in a suit and bright green pants Underworld Enemy 3 Bat Butterfly Bay Enemy 1 Surfer man Surfer man  Bay Enemy 2 Sumo wrestler Overweight man with a moustache wearing a tank top Bay Enemy 3 Person in a manhole throwing kisses  Elder woman in a manhole throwing kisses  Bay Enemy 4  Seagull  Seagull  Bay Weapon  Bottle  Newspaper  Cave Enemy 1   Bear Enemy Killed The number "100"  Dove  In between levels Bunny, the protagonist's girlfriend, with her clothes gradually rotting away.   The protagonist imagines what his Sunday school teacher would say. </description><genres><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11825">Menace Beach</game><game id="2022">King of Kings: The Early Years</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/11300/464796-sunday_funday___nes.jpg</image></root>