<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22846</id><name>Stronghold Crusader Extreme</name><description>Overview All units  Stronghold Crusader Extreme contains the original           Stronghold Crusader and a added "Extreme" component which contains 20 new skirmish missions and multiplayer via Gamespy. The basic gameplay is the same, but the engine has been enhanced to make greater use of modern CPU's, which makes it possible to show up to 10.000 enemies on the screen at once. To make the game take use of this feature, players start with special barracks that automatically spawn units constantly, which quite fast can enable the players to engage in massive battles.  There is also "Tactical Powers" feature added to the game. The tactical powers consist in spawning troops, acquiring goods or casting field "spells" such as dropping rocks or arrows onto your enemies. After being used you have to wait for them to recharge in order to use them again. The outposts (who constantly spawn units on the field) and the tactical powers are also available in multiplayer. New maps have been added to the skirmish section of the game. A new, extreme crusader trail is available to play. 20 hardcore missions to play against AIs just like in the original Stronghold Crusader.   Tactical powers  Arrow volley attack - drops a rain of arrows onto the selected area. Deals medium damage. Heal units - heals all units in the selected area to the maximum. Spawn spearmen - as titile says, spawns 40 spearmen in the selected area. Spawn engineers - again, spawns 20 engineers in the selected area. Spawn macemen - spawns 20 macemen in the selected area. Uncover gold - gives few thousand gold coins. Spawn knights - spawns 10 knights in the selected area. Stone   volley attack - drops a rain of rocks onto the selected area. Deals   heavy damage and can destroy any building or unit in the game. Minimum system requirements Operating System: Windows 98SE/ME/2000/XP/Vista  Processor: Pentium® III 500 Mhz (1 Ghz recommended)  RAM Memory: 128MB (256MB recommended for multiplayer)  Hard Drive Space: 850MB  Video Card: 4MB DirectX 8.1 Compatible  Sound Card: DirectX 8.1 Compatible</description><genres><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6164">World in Conflict</game><game id="19887">Rome: Total War</game><game id="19641">Medieval: Total War</game><game id="2846">Age of Empires II: The Age of Kings</game><game id="8546">Age of Empires III</game><game id="10485">Age of Empires</game><game id="14590">Age of Empires II: The Conquerors</game><game id="4391">Age of Empires: The Rise of Rome</game><game id="12483">Age of Empires III: The WarChiefs</game><game id="14291">Stronghold Crusader</game><game id="8897">Stronghold 2</game><game id="186">Stronghold</game><game id="4685">Medieval II: Total War</game><game id="11286">Nemesis of the Roman Empire</game><game id="8760">1503 A.D.: The New World</game><game id="6442">1503 A.D.: Treasures, Monsters and Pirates</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3715/715380-shcepc0f.jpg</image></root>