<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2285</id><name>Bust-A-Move 2: Arcade Edition</name><description>Gameplay The objective of the game is to remove all the bubbles off a stage without the bubbles going underneath the line. Types of Bubbles  Aim carefully!Normal Bubbles: There are no special qualities on what these bubbles can do. Just pop 3 or more bubbles of the same color to free the characters that are held inside. Star Bubbles:Shoot this special star bubble at a normal bubble to cause all the bubbles that are alike in color to pop! However, if you shoot it at another star bubble, it will have no effect whatsoever. Metal Bubbles:A very special and mighty bubble that destroys any bubbles in its way: however, it will pop when it reaches the top. Jama Bubbles:You cannot bust these bubbles. You must get rid of them by popping its neighbors. Jama Block: This bubble can never be popped, and you can't drop them due to bubbles sticking to them.Game modesBust them bubbles!Puzzle Game 1 player game where you have to make your way to the top on a map that is spread out in all directions by choosing a level, and you clear all the stages within a level.Player vs. Computer See you you can beat a variety computer characters in a head-to-head challenge.Player vs. Player Play against a friend in a head-to-head challenge to see who can survive the longest.Time Attack Clear stages as fast as you can to see who can pop the bubbles the quickest. 1-2 players can play. Cover Art ControversyThe Sega Saturn and Playstation  release became controversial in the US after the box art showed human faces screaming, with there eyes force open with white sticks.These faces were encased in the Large bubbles.    Other Information Bust-A-Move Plus!for WiiWarehas two additional service packs that are for download for 200 points each, and levels from this game are seen again in one of the additional service packs available in Bust-A-Move Plus!</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26416">Money Puzzle Exchanger</game><game id="25945">Bubble Bobble Neo!</game><game id="29660">Trajectile</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/19490/691147-bustamove2b.jpg</image></root>