<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22947</id><name>Backyard Baseball 2007</name><description>OverviewBackyard Baseball is back with a new generation of kids, new environments, and a new style of gameplay. In this edition of Backyard Baseball they try to make the kids look older, and edgier. They want the 400 foot home runs to be more believable. Also the game will feature new environments, which like the last Backyard Baseball, are all in 3D. Gameplay This game, that came out in 2007, features way faster load times then the previous games. More notably though, it has a new physics engine, for more accurate ball flight, and ball bounce. This new engine also makes the players look more natural when they run. PlayersThis game features some of the original backyard players, as well as 16 MLB players, as animated kids. MLB Players Bobby Abreu (Plillies) Lance Berkman (Astros) Eric Chavez (Athletics) Vladimer Guerrero (Angels) Derek Jeter (Yankees) Andruw Jones (Braves) Paul Konerko (White Sox) Derrek Lee (Cubs) David Ortiz (Redsox) Albert Pujols (Cardinals) Alex Rodriguez (Yankees) Alfonso Soriano (Cubs) Johan Santana (Twins) Ichiro Suzuki (Mariners Miguel Tejada (Orioles) Dontrelle Willis (Marlins)  Backyard PlayersThis game lost a few of the original backyard characters, but still kept these 19. Mario Luna Achmed Khan Tony Delvecchio Dmitri Petrovich Ricky Johnson Annie Frazier Lisa Crocket Pete Wheeler Dante Robinson Vicki Kawaguchi Reese Worthington Sidney Weber Ashely Weber Angela Delvecchio Marky Dubois Pablo Sanchez Jorge Garcia Ernie Steele Kiesha Phillips  </description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="34">Baseball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20687">MLB Power Pros 2008</game><game id="20686">MLB Power Pros</game><game id="814">Mario Superstar Baseball</game><game id="20942">Little League World Series</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1516/487323-backyardbaseball2007_boxart.jpg</image></root>