<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>22996</id><name>Wish</name><description>Ultra MassiveWish was deemed an "Ultra Massive Multiplayer Online Role Playing Game" (UMMORPG) by its developer,    Mutable Realms, because of its supposed ability to handle far more users at one time than other online RPGs. There were plans to have only one server to handle the entire player base, which would allow the game to have much more frequent and interactive live content than other games. The quality and scale of this live content was a key feature of the game, but ultimately lead to its downfall. It was determined the anticipated player base would not be able to support the infrastructure needed to create it as they had planned. This lead to the cancellation of the beta and the game.CancellationWish was cancelled suddenly only ten days into its open beta, even after over 60,000 downloads and gaining acclaim from the press and online community. After careful consideration of all the facts and analyzing all the data which we have gathered from the Wish Beta 2.0 test so far, we have decided to cancel the Wish project. Our Beta test will end this evening at 6pm EST, and at this time our Beta forums will close as well.We enjoyed working together with our fans very much, and we are very sorry about this development. We wish you the best of luck in the future, and hope that you continue to enjoy online gaming, even with Mutable Realms and Wish not being available anymore. We also wish the best luck to our competitors, and hope that they will not suffer the same fate as us.Mutable Realms itself shut down a short time later. Many of the artists that worked on Wish ultimately went to     Colossal Studios. Some of its assets were sold to Irth Online, which then became    Irth Worlds, and much is still available for purchase from the company. Some of the artwork has also been purchased for   Valhyre: The Aftermath.</description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5767">Ultima Online</game><game id="13869">Istaria: Chronicles of the Gifted</game><game id="23290">Irth Worlds</game><game id="29305">Valhyre: The Aftermath</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15693/494951-wishgameover_2_.jpg</image></root>