<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23007</id><name>Naruto: Ultimate Ninja Heroes</name><description>OverviewThe latest edition of the series offers a furious fighting game experience with up to 3-on-3 team-based gameplay, intense single player action and a wireless multi-player versus mode for up to two users all within the Naruto Universe. With eight interactive stages and 20 playable characters to choose from, gamers can take the battle outside the perimeters of the home to become the ultimate Hokage. In a new addition to the franchise, gamers also have the ability to create and customize their own ninja dream squads to battle opponents or trade player's profiles via wireless connectivity.Unlockable CharactersGaara complete Leaf Destruction!! (Normal) Itachi  Kisame complete Atatsuki Returns (Insane) Kakashi  Guy complete  Survival Exercise (Easy) Tsunade, Orichmaru  Jiraiya complete The Legendary Sannin (Hard)  Unlocable TeamsAkatsuki: Itachi and Kisame Association of Ninja: Itachi, Kisame, and Orochimaru Thugs. Author  Fan: Jiraiya and Kakashi Cunning Master: Tsunade and Sakura  And Student. Dark : Sasuke, Orochimaru, and Kabuto Eternal Rivals: Kakashi and Guy Hard Workers United: Naruto, Hinata, and Lee Hokage and assistant: Tsunade and Shizune Hot Blooded Master and: Guy and Lee  Student Leaf Jonin: Kakashi, Guy, and Shizune Maidens in Love: Sakura, Ino, and Hinata Master  Student: Naruto and Jiraiya Shadows of Evil: Orochimaru and Kabuto Team Byakugan: Neji and Hinata Team Genius: Sasuke, Neji, and Shikamaru Team Kakashi: Naruto, Sakura, and Sasuke Team Sharingan: Itachi, Sasuke, and Kakashi The Cursed: Orochimaru and Sasuke The Guides: The Third Hokage and Tsunade The Leaf's Greatest: The Third Hokage, Jiraiya, and Tsunade The Legendary Sanin: Jiraiya, Tsunade, and Orochimaru  Those Who Know: Naruto, Sasuke, and Garra Loneliness. Triple Trouble: Naruto, Kiba, and Choji Uchiha Clan: Sasuke and Itachi </description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18753">Tekken 5</game><game id="20678">Soulcalibur IV</game><game id="7792">Dead or Alive 4</game><game id="14684">Tekken 4</game><game id="11189">Tekken 3</game><game id="10387">Tekken 2</game><game id="10081">Tekken</game><game id="2045">Dead or Alive 2</game><game id="3839">Dead or Alive</game><game id="12411">Soulcalibur</game><game id="11822">Soulcalibur II</game><game id="9855">Soulcalibur III</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2215078-box_narutounh.png</image></root>