<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23032</id><name>Mobile Suit Gundam: Gundam vs. Gundam</name><description>Units IncludedUnits included in Mobile Suit Gundam: Gundam vs. Gundam. PSP-exclusive units are marked with an asterisk (*).Mobile Suit GundamGundam (Amuro Ray) Guntank (Hayato Kobayashi) *Guncannon (Kai Shiden) Char Custom Zaku (Char Aznable) Dom (Gaia)  Mobile Suit Gundam: The 08th MS TeamGround Gundam Mass Production Type (Shiro Amada) Gouf Custom (Norris Packard)  Mobile Suit Gundam 0080: War in the PocketZaku II Custom (Bernard Wiseman) Gundam Alex (Christina Mackenzie) *Kampfer (Mikhail Kaminsky)  Mobile Suit Gundam 0083: Stardust Memory*GP-01 Zephyranthes (Kou Uraki; becomes GP-01 Full Vernian after it is destroyed once) GP-03 Stamen (Kou Uraki) GP-02 Physalis (Anavel Gato)  Mobile Suit Zeta GundamZeta Gundam (Kamille Bidan) Gundam Mk. II (Emma Sheen)  Mobile Suit Gundam ZZZZ Gundam (Judau Ashta) Quebely Mk. II (Elpeo Puru)  Mobile Suit Gundam: Char's CounterattackNu Gundam (Amuro Ray ver. UC 0093) Sazabi (Char Aznable ver. UC 0093)  Mobile Suit Gundam F91Gundam F91 (Seabook Arno) Vigna Ghina (Cecily Fairchild)  Mobile Suit Victory GundamVictory 2 Gundam (Uso Evin) Victory Gundam (Uso Evin)  Mobile Fighter G GundamGod Gundam (Domon Kasshu) Master Gundam (Master Asia) Devil Gundam (No Pilot; Final Boss)  New Mobile Report Gundam WingWing Gundam Zero (Heero Yuy; TV version) Gundam Heavyarms Custom (Trowa Barton; TV version)  After War Gundam XGundam X (Garrod Ran) Gundam Virsago (Shagia Frost)  Turn A GundamTurn A Gundam (Loran Cehack) Kapool (Sochie Heim)  Mobile Suit Gundam SEEDStrike Gundam (Kira Yamato) Aegis Gundam (Athrun Zala)  Mobile Suit Gundam SEED DestinyImpulse Gundam (Shinn Asuka) *Destiny Gundam (Shinn Asuka) Freedom Gundam (Kira Yamato ver. CE 73)  Mobile Suit Gundam 00Gundam Exia (Setsuna F. Seiei) </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22533">Another Century's Episode 3: The Final</game><game id="23686">Mobile Suit Gundam: Gundam vs. Gundam Next</game><game id="26733">Mobile Suit Gundam SEED Destiny: Rengou vs. Z.A.F.T. II</game><game id="28190">Mobile Suit Gundam: Gundam vs. Gundam Next Plus</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/16207/500742-gundamvsgundam.jpg</image></root>