<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23086</id><name>Super Robot Wars 4</name><description>StoryA few months after the battle with the Inspectors (Super Robot Wars 3), the Earth Federation's economy is in shambles; to add to the problem, spacenoids (people living in space colonies) have begun to commit terrorist attacks. To counter these acts, Jamitov Hymem creates the Titans, an elite group whose strength gives them a great deal of influence in the Federation. A huge contributing factor to the Titans' swift rise to power is the drastic downscaling of the Londo Bell unit due to their sudden disappearance during the La Gias incident (Super Robot Wars EX).To make matters worse, the ever-scheming Haman Karn creates the Neue Divine Crusaders on the asteroid Axis. The spacenoids fully support the Neue DC due to their treatment by the Earth Federation, which makes this group extremely powerful. However, the old DC is still not dead. Under the command of Don Zauser, the original DC has amazingly regained its power once again; they are ready to strike a third time.Fortunately, there is hope. Quattro Bajeena, who was chased out of the Federation Army, forms the Anti-Earth Union Group to oppose the Earth's current government...Featured SeriesA list of the anime series which are featured in the game. Series that premiered in the Super Robot Wars series in this game are marked with "(new)".Mobile Suit GundamMobile Suit Gundam 0080: War in the PocketMobile Suit Gundam 0083: Stardust MemoryMobile Suit Zeta GundamGundam Sentinel (units only; new)Mobile Suit Gundam ZZMobile Suit Gundam: Char's CounterattackMobile Suit Gundam F91Mazinger ZGreat MazingerUFO Robo GrendizerGetter RoboGetter Robo GShin Getter Robo (manga version; new)Brave RaideenSuper Electromagnetic Robot Combattler VBrave Leader Daimos (new)Invincible Super Man Zambot 3 (new)Invincible Steel Man Daitarn 3Demon God of War GoshogunAura Battler DunbineNew Story of Aura Battler Dunbine (units only; new)Heavy Metal L-Gaim (new)Super Beast Machine God Dancougar (new)Banpresto Originals (original characters created for the game)Masoukishin - Lord of Elemental (Banpresto Original storyline)New FeaturesManual Counterattack. In the preceding entries in the franchise, the player is allowed to define how their units should deal with a counterattack; however all units follow a single method, and the weapon you counterattack with can't be chosen. This game allows the player total control of how enemy attacks are handled on a case-by-case basis.Customizable Protagonists. This game gives the player the option to create their own original, changing their name, appearance, personality, etc. If the player chooses so, they may also create a "lover" based on the main character's personality type. This system would appear in Super Robot Wars Alpha, and the ability to name protagonists appears in every game since. One pairing, Irmgult Kazahara and Ring Mao, would reappear in the Super Robot Wars Alpha and Original Generation universes (using aged versions of their F/F Final appearances).Real Robot/Super Robot. The type of Gespenst unit your character receives (and the opening stages in the PlayStation version) are based on a choice between "Super Robot" (fantastical, Mazinger-like robots) and "Real Robot" (realistic, Gundam-like robots). These two terms continue to be used in the franchise, and even in the mecha genre itself.Alternate Openings. As mentioned above, the PlayStation version of Super Robot Wars 4, Super Robot Wars 4 Scramble, feature different openings depending on the choice of "Real" or "Super".</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23047">Super Robot Wars F</game><game id="3731">Phantom Brave</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/14/149200/2133791-sup_4.jpg</image></root>