<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23080</id><name>Super Robot Wars 2</name><description>StoryBian Zoldark, in fear of an extraterrestrial invasion, has formed a group known as the Divine Crusaders (DC); they have conquered the world in an attempt to unify the planet and stand a better chance against the supposed threat. However, three robots were able to escape the DC's grasp: Mazinger Z, Getter Robo, and the RX-78-2 Gundam. These robots, piloted by Kouji Kabuto, the Getter Team, and Amuro Ray respectively, rally against the DC...Featured Series A list of the anime series which are featured in the game. Series that premiered in the Super Robot Wars series in this game are marked with "(new)".Mazinger Z Great Mazinger UFO Robo Grendizer (new) Getter Robo Getter Robo G Mobile Suit Gundam Mobile Suit Zeta Gundam Mobile Suit Gundam ZZ Mobile Suit Gundam: Char's Counterattack Mobile Suit Gundam F91 Banpresto Originals (original characters created for the game; new)  New FeaturesBanpresto Originals: While the boss of the first Super Robot Wars never appeared in animation, it was still based on an anime design. This game is the first to include character designs created entirely by Banpresto.Pilots: Unlike the first SRW, which featured sentient robots, Super Robot Wars 2 introduces human characters. However, they have little to no effect on the actual gameplay.Story scenes: The first Super Robot Wars had little-to-no story aside from the opening demo and an extremely brief description before each map. While the story is still largely superficial in SRW 2, characters now converse before and after each mission.Convincible Characters: SRW 2 doesn't allow you to convince every enemy like the original; however, there aren't any stats that affect your probability of convincing in this game.Purchasable Items: The funds that you gain by destroying enemy units are used to purchase items that increase your stats, recover HP, etc.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3731">Phantom Brave</game><game id="23224">Super Robot Wars 2G</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/16207/513308-srw2.jpg</image></root>