<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23102</id><name>South Park Let's Go Tower Defense Play!</name><description>OverviewSouth Park is being invaded by hordes of evil minions by some unknown evil. The only ones that can save the town are Stan, Kyle, Cartman, Kenny, and a few of their friends. As the player moves through the eleven stages and five challenge levels, clips from the television show and new playable characters are unlocked. All of the original voice actors are present in the game and it features four player co-op. Each level begins with the player(s) receiving a handful of coins and some time to prepare. The player(s) has to use this time to build up a series of towers that can take down the massive amount of enemies before they can destroy the town. The enemies are taken from the world of South Park -- ranging from Mongolians to ginger kids to crab people.Avatar AwardsThe game has these 2 avatar awards.Cartman's Hat - (Achievement: Come On. Catch Me.) Complete a full level.Kenny's Coat - Finish the last level of the game. Can be earned without beating levels. There is the option to skip any level, so you can just skip them all and get this. If you do this, the game will label you a "Turd Sandwich".CharactersAll sixteen playable characters have different stats as well as a special ability. All stats are out of a possible five.StanMove Speed: 4.5Throw Rate: 3.5Throw Range: 5Throw Damage: 2.5Town Defense: Town health is partially restored.CartmanMove Speed: 4Throw Rate: 3.5Throw Range: 4Throw Damage: 4Carpet Bomb: The area is carpet bombed with explosive shells and all enemies take moderate damage.KyleMove Speed: 5Throw Rate: 2.5Throw Range: 4Throw Damage: 1.5Passion: All players do 10x damage and move faster for 7 seconds.KennyMove Speed: 3.5Throw Rate: 5Throw Range: 5Throw Damage: 5Wellfare Check: All on screen enemies drop up to 20 coins together.ButtersMove Speed: 4.5Throw Rate: 3.5Throw Range: 5Throw Damage: 2.5Tap Dance Attack: Butters' tap dance shoes fly off and damage enemies.JimmyMove Speed: 4.5Throw Rate: 3.5Throw Range: 5Throw Damage: 2.5Tornado Fit: Jimmy spins around to damage nearby enemies with his crutches.CraigMove Speed: 3.5Throw Rate: 5Throw Range: 5Throw Damage: 5The Pessimist: Slows down all on screen enemies for 20 seconds.ClydeMove Speed: 4.5Throw Rate: 3.5Throw Range: 5Throw Damage: 2.5Colostomy Bomb: Explodes colostomy bag for heavy damage to nearby enemies.TweekMove Speed: 5Throw Rate: 2.5Throw Range: 4Throw Damage: 1.5Caffeine Hit: A heavy and fast attack on nearby enemies for 5 seconds.PipMove Speed: 3.5Throw Rate: 5Throw Range: 5Throw Damage: 5I'm Not French Rage!: Pip rages through enemies causing massive damage.TimmyMove Speed: 5Throw Rate: 2.5Throw Range: 4Throw Damage: 1.5Battery Boost: Electro-charges his wheelchair to blash through nearby mobs.WendyMove Speed: 4Throw Rate: 3.5Throw Range: 4Throw Damage: 4Sale Time: Wendy can build towers at half price for 10 seconds.BebeMove Speed: 5Throw Rate: 2.5Throw Range: 4Throw Damage: 1.5Gold Digger: Collects all coins on screen automatically.RedMove Speed: 4Throw Rate: 3.5Throw Range: 4Throw Damage: 4Pleases and Sparkles: Sparkles and stars rain down medium damage on all on screen enemies.TokenMove Speed: 4Throw Rate: 3.5Throw Range: 4Throw Damage: 4Plays The Blues: All enemies in range are depressed and take medium damage.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22139">Desktop Tower Defense</game><game id="12764">PixelJunk Monsters</game><game id="21064">Lock's Quest</game><game id="23311">Defense Grid: The Awakening</game><game id="29428">PixelJunk Monsters Deluxe</game><game id="24871">Fieldrunners</game><game id="23319">Savage Moon</game><game id="25000">Crystal Defenders</game><game id="25709">Plants vs. Zombies</game><game id="25758">Comet Crash</game><game id="16164">Immortal Defense</game><game id="28325">Toy Soldiers</game><game id="30400">Sol Survivor</game><game id="31207">Murky Horizon</game><game id="32629">Trenches</game><game id="33366">System Protocol One</game><game id="33408">Revenge of the Titans</game><game id="32495">Robo Defense</game><game id="34419">Toy Soldiers: Cold War</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1841454-box_splgtdp.png</image></root>