<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23112</id><name>The Maw</name><description>OverviewThe Maw begins with Frank, an alien kidnapped by the galactic bounty hunters to be held alongside other various alien creatures. Suddenly, the galactic bounty hunters' spacecraft crashes, and Frank is left stranded on an unknown planet with The Maw by his side. Frank soon finds a strange looking device and decides to slip it onto his wrist, which allows him to control The Maw just like a dog from a sort of grapple beam leash. It is then that the player is given the task of guiding The Maw through eight different levels, to eat as much as he can find and increase his size while he goes.CharactersFrankFrank is a Teltarian who has been captured by the galactic bounty hunters. His planet was quarantined by the galactic council due to the psychic emanations caused by the gemstones on their head, an ability which also allows him to keep control over The Maw and hypnotize it into not eating him. He quickly befriends The Maw in order to help himself escape the planet they become stranded on.The MawA small purple, large-jawed monster with a huge appetite, The Maw is able to devour any creature it comes across and even absorb any special abilities that creature may have had, such as fiery breath or laser beam eyes. The Maw is practically indestructible - gunfire and other larger creatures may be able to stun it, but they do not stop him from growing.Galactic Bounty HuntersTheir goal is to uphold the will of the Galactic Council, and to protect the citizenry from any creatures which may become a threat to their way of life, no matter how abstract their 'threats' may be. They inhabit large spire towers on each planet and will send as many troops as required from these spires to capture offending creatures when necessary.Other CreaturesYumsYums are tiny, pink lifeforms which may seem cute at first glance (at least, to Frank) but are really just the basic food substance for The Maw. They can be found in large groups and are able to boost The Maw's size fairly easily if enough are consumed.GastroFiery hot lizards made from molten rock, Gastros possess a fiery breath attack allowing them to burn forests and roast their food prior to consumption. If The Maw eats a Gastro he will inherit their fire-breathing ability.BulbousGenetically modified flying bug creature originally created with the intention of being used for organic lighting and power sources. After the accidental electrocution of a Galactic Senator's child, the Bulbous creatures are now quarantined and executed if found by the galactic bounty hunters, but can prove hard to execute due to their high mobility, as well as their ability to disrupt nearby electronic equipment.Downloadable ContentNew levels can be downloaded from Xbox Live Marketplace and the Steam Store for 100 points or $1.25 respectively. These "deleted scenes" take place between existing levels of the game.PC System RequirementsMinimum:Operating System: Microsoft® Windows® XP/VistaProcessor: AMD® Athlon® 64 2.2 GHz or equivalentMemory: 1024 MB RAMHard Disk Space: 300 MB Available HDD SpaceVideo Card: Nvidia® Geforce® 7600 256 MB or equivalent, (ATI® 2400 worked just as well)Sound Card: DirectX® CompatibleDirectX® Version: DirectX® 9.0cController Support: Xbox 360 controller and other DirectInput supported controllerRecommended:Operating System: Microsoft® Windows® XP/VistaProcessor: Intel® Pentium® Core 2 Duo 2.2 GHz or equivalentMemory: 2 GB RAMHard Disk Space: 300 MB Available HDD SpaceVideo Card: Nvidia® Geforce® 8800 GT 512 MB or equivalent, (ATI® 3870 on the ATI side)Sound Card: DirectX® CompatibleDirectX® Version: DirectX® 9.0cController Support: Xbox 360 controller and other DirectInput supported controller</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19788">Kirby's Dream Land</game><game id="20314">David Crane's A Boy and his Blob: Trouble on Blobolonia</game><game id="25508">A Boy and His Blob</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1331151-themaw_box.png</image></root>