<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23129</id><name>SNK vs. Capcom: Card Fighters DS</name><description>OverviewSNK vs Capcom: Card Fighters DS is the third installment of the SNK vs Capcom: Card Battle games and is part of the SNK vs Capcom franchise. The first two card battle games were released for the Neo Geo Pocket Color.  Game Breaking BugWhen the game was released in NA, there was a bug which stopped players from progressing through the game.  On the 9th floor of your second play through the game will crash after talking to an opponent named Jon, he had to be defeated to carry on through out the game, so it was impossible to get past the 9th floor. On June 25 a replacement cartridge was available for those who purchased the game.Gameplay  The game takes place in Card Tower, which consists of 21 separate floors. All the opponents on each floor have been brainwashed by MAX, to revert them back to their usual self, you have to beat them in a card battle. You have to beat everyone on a floor to advance tot he next floor of the tower. To move around the floors, you don't have direct d-pad control, instead you can select opponents on the floor and your sprite will automatically move to that opponent.Each floors have different gimmicks to them, certain floors contain shops which allow you to purchase new packs of cards, or a a single card chosen at random. To buy cards from the shops you have to use the currency CP which you get for defeating opponents. Some floors are trading floors, you don't need to defeat anyone to advance on this floor you can just skip it completely, or you could trade cards with the AI. For most of the tower,t he levels are split up into two sides, Capcom and SNK. When you choose which side to take you can not go back and go along the other side either due to story related reasons. The only way to go along the other side is after you complete the game you can do a New Game  and carry your card decks over to a new game.   Types of Cards There are three types of cards that can be used in S NK vs Capcom: Card Fighters DS; Character Card - These cards are summoned into the ring and are used to attack your opponent or defend against their attacks. Each character card has Health points (HP) and Battle points (BP), HP is how much damage that character can take, BP is how much damage that character can deal.Action Card - These cards are summoned but don't stay in the ring. Different actiosn will have different effects. They can hurt or heal characters, buff them, make you draw cards etc.Counter Card - Counter cards can only be used when your opponent is attacking, they are used to give you an advantage while defending.  How to PlaySNK vs Capcom: Card Fighters DS is a trading card game very similar to the rule set of Magic: The Gathering. To decide who goes first, both players roll a dice, whoever rolls the highest decides who get the first turn.Each player starts with 2000 Health Points, the objective is to make your opponents health go down to 0, before they do the same to you.At the start of the game you draw 5 cards from your pile and you receive 3 white force. (Force is what you need to use to summon cards on your turn, there are five types, white, red, yellow, green and blue. Certain cards can only be summoned by certain colors)On your turn, you can summon character cards or action cards into the ring. When a character card is summoned it is frozen on it's first turn and can not attack or defend. Or you can discard a card and you will get a force icon depending on the trait of that card. (i.e. if you discard a blue trait card, you will get 1 blue force icon)At the begging of each turn you receive 1 white force, to get more force, you need to have character cards in your ring. (i.e. if you have a yellow character card summoned in your ring, you'll receive 1 yellow force each turn while that card is in the ring)If you have any injured characters you can use character cards in your hand to back them up, this will heal the injured character depending on how much HP the character being used to back up has. You can only back up a character with another character of the same color trait.When you have un-frozen characters in your ring, you can have multiple options with them. you can attack with them, force them, which will freeze them but give you another force icon depending on the characters trait or use their power if they have a power.If you have two characters of the same trait, they can do a fusion attack, a fusion attack costs more force icons, but it adds both characters BP together, if another character counter attacks this card, the remaining BP that is left over will still hurt the opponents life force.Once your turn is over, the opponents takes their turn and this is repeated until one of the players HP is down to 0 and wins.  Card ListYou can have a total of 50 cards in one deck in the game, but there are over 500 cards for you to collect in the game. Here's an alphabetical list of them all.  Card Name (Rarity)       SNK Cards  Adelheid (B) Ai (A)  Akari Ichijo (A)  Alba Meira (S)  Andy Bogard (B) Ash Crimson (S) Asura (B) Athena Asamiya (S)  Atomic Gai (D) B. Jenet (A)  Benimaru (C) Billy Kane (B) Blue Mary (B) Carol (C) Chae Lim (C) Cham Cham (B) Chang Koehan (D) Charlotte (B) Chin Gentsai (D) Choi Bounge (D) Chris (B) Clark (C) Cyber Woo (D) Duke (B) Duo Lin (C) Eagle (D) Eiji Kisaragi (C) Elizabeth (C) Eri Kasamoto (B) Fio Germi (A)  Fuma (B) Gai Tendoh (C) Gaira Caffeine (D) Galford (C) Gao Kyougoku Hinowanokami (B) Gato (C) Geese Howard (S)  General Morden (D) Goenitz (B) Goro Daimon (D) Hanzo (A) Hanzo Hattori (B) Haohmaru (S)  Hayate (A)  Heidern (B) Hibiki Takane (C) Hinako Shijo (C) Hotaru Futaba (A)  Hyo Amano (C) Iori Yagami (S)  Iroha (A)  Janne (C) Jin Chonrei (B) Jin Chonshu (B) Jivatma (B) Joe Higashi (B) Jubei Yagyu (C) Juzo Kanzaki (C) K' (S) [By Tonko] Kaede (A)  Kain R. Heinlein (C) Karmen Kole (D) Kasumi Todoh (C) Kazuki Kazama (B) Keiichiro Washizuka (C) Khushnood Butt (D) Kim Kaphwan (B) Kim Sueil (D) King (B) Kisara (C) Kojiroh Sanada (Kaori)  (C) Kouryu (C) Kula Diamond (A)  Kyo Kusanagi (S)  Leona (C) Li Xiangfei (C) Lien Neville (C) Lin (C) Lordran (C) Luise Meyrink (A)  Mai Shiranui (A)  Malin (D) Marco Rossi (B) Mars People (D) Maxima (C) Mignon Beart (D) Mina Majikina (A)  Momoko (C) Moriya Minakata (B) Mr. Big (C) Mudman (C) Mukai (C) Nagase (C) Nakoruru (S)  NeoDio (A)  Nicotine Caffeine (D) Ninon Beart (C) Omega Rugal (A)  Orochi (A)  Orochi Chris (B) Orochi Iori (A)  Orochi Leona (B) Orochi Shermie (B) Orochi Yashiro (B) Oswald (B) Ralf (C) Ramon (C) Rera (B) Rimururu (B) Robert Garcia (B) Rock Howard (A)  Rosa (C) Rose (C) Ryo Sakazaki (A)  Ryuji Yamazaki (B) Saisyu Kusanagi (B) Sasuke (C) Setsuna (C) Shen Woo (C) Shermie (B) Shiki (A)  Shingo Yabuki (C) Shinnosuke Kagami (C) Shiro Tokisada Amakusa (A)  Shishioh (C) Shizumaru Hisame (B) Sie Kensou (D) Silber (C) Sogetsu Kazama (B) Soiree Meira (B) Sokaku Mochizuki (D) Super Zion (D) Takuma Sakazaki (B) Tam Tam (D) Tarma Roving (C) Terry Bogard (S)  Time Buttermitt (C) Tizoc (D) Tung Fu Rue (C) Ukyo Tachibana (B) Vanessa (C) Whip (B) Wolfgang Krauser (C) Wyler (D) Yashiro Nanakase (A) Yoshitora Tokugawa (A)  Yuki (A)  Yuki (B) Yuri Sakazaki (A) Zankuro Minazuki (A) Capcom Characters Ada Wong (C)Adon (D)Akira (Unmasked Ver.)  (A)Akuma (A)Al  Evan (B)Albert Wesker (B)Alex (B)Amingo (D)Anakaris (C)Anita (B)Arthur (B)Axl (D)B.B.Hood (B)Baby Head (D)Balrog (D)Bass (C)Batsu (A)Bilstein (C)Birdie (D)Bishamon (C)Blanka (D)Blodia (B)Cammy (A)Captain Commando (C)Charlie (B)ChunLi (S)Cody (B)Cyber Akuma (C)Dan (B)Dante (B)Dee Jay (B)Demitri Maximoff (A)Devilotte (B)Dhalsim (D)Dr. Wily (C)Donovan Baine (B)Dudley (D)E. Honda (D)Eagle (D)Ele (C)Elena (B)Evil Ryu (C)Fei Long (B)Felicia (A) Fiona Belli (B)Franziska Von Karma (B)G. Kaiser (Junpei)  (A)Gen (C)Gill (A)Ginzu (C)Guile (B)Guy (B)Hayato (A)Hinata (B)HsienKo (A) Hugo (C)Huitzil (C)Hyo (B)Ibuki (B)Incho (C)Ingrid (S) Jedah Dohma (B)Jill Valentine (S)Jin Saotome (A)Jon Talbain (B)Juli (B)June (A)Juni (B)Karin (B)Ken (A) Kenji (C)Kyoko (C)Kyosuke (C)Leo (B)Lilith (A)Lord Raptor (B)Lucia (C)M. Bison (S)Mack the Knife (D)MaiLing (C)Maki (C)Makoto (B)Marionette (B)Mary Miyabe (C)Mega Man (S)Mega Man X (A)Mei Ling (D)Metal Zangief (D)Mia Fey (C)Mike Haggar (B)Miles Edgeworth (B)Morrigan (A)Morrigan (Lilith Ver.)  (C)Morrigan (Nurse Ver.)  (C)Morrigan Aenslaed (S)Necro (D)Nelo Angelo (C)Nemesis (A)Nina (C)Oro (D)Phoenix Wright (S)Poison (C)Protoman (C)Pyron (A)Q (D)QBee (B)R. Mika (C)Rain (C)Raizo (C)Red Arremer (A)Regina (B)Remy (C)Rikuo (D)Rolento (C)Rose (B)Ruby Heart (B)Ryu (S)Ryu (A)Ryu (SSF2T Ver.) (C)Sagat (A)Saki (A)Sakura (S)Sakura (Swimsuit Ver.)  (C)Sakura (Tanned)  (C)Sasquatch (B)Sean (C)Servbot (C)Shadow Lady (C)Shin Akuma (S)Sodom (D)Sonson (A)Strider Hiryu (B)T. Hawk (D)Tessa (A)Thrasher (C)Ton Pooh (C)Trish (C)Tron Bonne (C)Twelve (D)Tyrant (A)Urien (D)Vega (C)Vergil (C)Victor von Genderheim (C)Yang (B)Yun (B)Zangief (C)Zero (C)Zero (A)Zero Akuma (C) Action Cards 3 Point Shot (B)A Secretary's Lot (D)Across Borders (S)Antiseptic Spray (B)At One with Nature (C)BioWeapon (A)Brainwash (C)Cat Fight (A)Chow Time! (A)Concentration One (A)Dark Force (B)Death Blow (A)Death Wish (D)Diversionary Attack (C)Dramatic Battle! (B)Duck Dance (D)Enja's Immolation (S)Fate's Arrow (C)Fixit Shop (C)Game Over (B)Goooooh Team! (C)Heroes Never Die (B)Holy Star (D)Honey Bee (C)Hyena Funfest! (B)Imprisoning Maiden (D)Invitation (C)Kill Them All (B)Loki's Rage (C)Lord's Way (C)Magic Meds (C)Mano e Mano (S)Miraculous Magic (D)Moronic MixUp (D)New Image? (C)Next Generation (A)Nirvana (D)Noblesse Oblige (C)Out of Order (S)Pao Pao Cafe (B)Pathetic Puppet Show (A)Placid Prayer (C)Shadow Warrior (C)Shape Shifter (A)Smite of Swirl (C)Sorry! (D)Soup's on! (C)Subjugation Day (B)Swig o'Courage (C)Sword Lord's Slash (C)Talking Trash (C)This's War (B)Tight Fix! (C)Time Warp (B)Treasure Hunt (C)Universe Distortion (C)Wag The Dog (D)Wild Fussilade (C)Worker Bees (D)You're Grounded (C) Counter Cards Battle Download (C)Battle Stations! (C)Blessed Rain (B)Brocken Bomber (B)Can O'Energy (A)Card Shark (C)Center of Attention (C)Camomile (C)Charge! (D)La Ka Cho La (C)Colossal Cleave (C)Cosmo Disruption (C)Explosive Blowback (A)Final Judgement (S)Free at Last (C)Ghouls' Curse (C)Green Orb (D)Guardian Angel (S)Hanzo's Help (D)Hostage (C)Hypnotized! (D)Ice Crusher (C)Irresistible Agent (C)Lap of Luxury (D)Mongolian Tiger Flash! (D)Music Magic (S)Nature's Pain (S)Noh Cry (C)Oncoming Kamikaze (D)Primo Jackpot (A)Recurring Nightmare (B)Revenge (B)Revolution Francaise (B)Saving Shift (B)Scarfing Sushi (B)Scoop Artist (D)Seizing Fate (B)Shooting Star (C)Supply Run (C)Ultimate Guard (A)</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="13">Card Game</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5134">SNK vs. Capcom: Card Fighter's Clash - SNK &amp; Capcom Version</game><game id="23127">SNK vs. Capcom: Card Fighter's Clash 2 Expand Edition</game><game id="10489">Pokémon Trading Card Game</game><game id="9558">Magic: The Gathering Online</game><game id="3210">Marvel Trading Card Game</game><game id="31581">Tekken Card Challenge</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2151662-box_svccfds.png</image></root>