<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23159</id><name>One Piece: Unlimited Cruise</name><description>Overview One Piece Unlimited Cruise 1, for             Nintendo Wii  was delayed in the west a long time due to legal issues at the intended  time of release with 4Kids Entertainment. Once they were no longer in  control of the rights the game was set for release in the west late June  2009.The game features the            One Piece crew, fully up to date with the manga as of just after the Thriller Bark story ark (          Brook  is on the crew from the beginning of the game) and features a new story  written specifically for the game by Eichiro Oda the series creator.  The game is a third person action/adventure and features a variety of  characters, nine playable in total,          Luffy,         Zoro,        Chopper,       Sanji,      Nami,     Nico Robin, Brook,    Franky and   Usopp, as well as a character specific to the game (who is not playable) Gaabri.The  game sees the player controlling the crew of the Sunny Go pirate ship  adventuring on four mystery islands, all of which contain plants that  must be sought out and provide treasures when beaten, each plant spawns a  copy of one of the crews previous enemies, from Bartholemew Kuma to  Captain Kuro they are all present and accounted for, although some of  them are secret.During gameplay, players can collect a  significant amount of items, from mineral ore, to bugs, fruit, sticks  and blocks of stone, with which the players can create items for their  own use, or repair existing items. The main creations include cooking  food items, making weapons or repairing storyline specific items, and  making medical equipment. In addition to this, Franky can build bridges,  or remove other obstacles if you give him enough materials, and some  materials/items must be sacrificed in order to unlock new areas through  the storyline.   The IslandsThe game features 4 islands, all of which contain  many hidden areas as well as a main storyline path, most islands contain  a sub-boss and a boss, as well as at least 2 areas in which the player  is trapped until he defeats a large number of foes. Island OneIsland  one is a golden beach paradise, filled with palm trees, fishing spots,  white rocks and other delights. While the in-land sections feature  forests, glades and other areas high in vegetation. This island has  Bartholemew Kuma as its sub-boss, and God Eneru as its main boss. Items  found on the island include bamboo, various herbs and leaves, several  types of fish and some animals. Weaker enemies populate this island as  it is the first island, it is also the shortest. It also holds several  hidden areas only accessible once players obtain other items along the  storyline (such as the vacuum cleaner, pickaxe and others) there is at  least one hidden boss on this island.  Survival ModeThe  game also features a Survival Mode (unlockable) that pits the player  against hordes of enemies, survival mode contains 50 rounds against  increasingly powerful enemies and features a reward upon completion (A  new special attack for Nami, Usopp, Robin and Brook) Versus ModeIn  addition to single player, the game also features a Versus  mode, the  plays like a fighting game. Players pick characters and fight against   each other, it supports up to 2 players. All of the main  playable characters are available to play as, in addition to several of  the boss characters from the main game being unlockable extras, playable  only in versus mode. Those characters are as follows, Admiral  Aokiji, the Merman Pirate Arlong, Calgara, God Eneru, Don Krieg,  Batholemew Kuma, Captain Kuro, Enraged Chopper, Moria, Nightmare Luffy,  Spandam and Lord Wapol.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5962/1065989-op_uc_pal.jpg</image></root>