<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23162</id><name>One Piece: Gear Spirit</name><description>OverviewThere is no story within Gear Spirit, instead the story mode features players being sent to random locations to fight battles against three random enemy characters. However, there will occasionally be battles which correspond to fights in the anime, with some random characters thrown in e.g. Luffy will have to fight Smoker and then fight Rob Lucci.GameplayThe characters of One-Piece duke it out.Gear Spirit is a 2D fighter, much like Super Smash Bros. or Jump Super Stars. Characters are controlled using the d-pad to move, the face buttons are used to attack and jump, and special attacks are performed by using cards on the touch screen. Fights consist of four player characters each gaining points from killing another characters via depleting their health or pushing them out of the ring, however, each player loses points for dying. The winner from each round is the player with the most points at the end of the time.CharactersEight characters are available from the start, while there are twelve further unlockable characters.Monkey D. Luffy Unlocked from the startRoronoa Zoro Unlocked from the startNami Unlocked from the startUsopp Unlocked from the startSanji Unlocked from the startTony Tony Chopper Unlocked from the startNico Robin Unlocked from the startFranky Unlocked from the startVivi Nefertari Unlocked by Completing Story Mode with any four charactersKaku Unlocked by Completing Story Mode with Nico RobinRob Lucci Unlocked by Completing Story Mode with FrankyPortgas D. Ace Unlocked by completing Story Mode with any two charactersAokiji Unlocked by completing Story Mode with Tony Tony ChopperSir Crocodile Unlocked by completing Story Mode with any three charactersEnel Unlocked by completing Story Mode with any five charactersDracule Mihawk Unlocked by completing Story Mode with every characterShanks Unlocked by completing Story Mode with MihawkBlackbeard Unlocked by completing Story Mode with ShanksBrook Unlocked by max out bounties on all starting charactersFour different costumes are available for each character. Three of these re-colour of the original costume and one slightly alters the costume.StagesMost stages (except Rocketman Train) are multi-platform 2D stages and some stages have specific items that can be used to the player's advantage e.g. Skypiea has a bell that can be knocked to send a shockwave towards enemies and other stages can have special events which endanger the characters e.g. On Rocketman Train a giant wave will occasionally appear which can kill characters caught in it.Rogue TownAlabasta RuinsRocketman TrainEnies Lobby'sTower of JusticeSkypieaThousand SunnyBanaro IslandCardsCards are how the player uses special attacks and status effects. Each player character has 3 levels of special attacks, each one causing a cut-scene to take place in which damage from the attack is dealt. The other cards are used to heal characters, boost their strength or defence, or lower enemies stats. All cards cost between 1–3 points of which the player being able to accumulate a total of 15 points.Apart from the standard three cards the player can collect assist cards which call in other characters to convey some kind of specific effect. These are not unlike the assist trophies from Super Smash Bros. Brawl.Mayor Woop SlapKuinaGaimonThe Usopp PiratesMiss KayaLady AlvidaBuggy the ClownJangoKuroYosakuJohnnyZeffDon KriegArlongGenzoBell-mèreTashigiDorryBrogyWapolDr. KurehaDaltonDr. HilulukMiss ValentineMr. 5Miss Merry ChristmasMr. 4Miss GoldenweekMr. 3Mr. 2 Bon KureiMiss DoublefingerMr. 1PellChakaIgaramCobra NefertariKozaCarueBellamyMontblanc CricketGedatsuConisWiperGan FallFoxy the Silver FoxFukuroKumadoriKalifaJabraSpandamBluenoCommander T-BoneChimneyKokoroPaulieIceburgTomJaguar D. SaulOimoKashiHelmeppoCobyMonkey D. GarpDonquixote DoflamingoBartholomew KumaLaboonWhitebeardHinaMonkey D. DragonStrawhatRocket ManGoing MerryThousand Sunny</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25447">One Piece Unlimited Cruise: Episode 2</game><game id="34429">Cartoon Network: Punch Time Explosion</game><game id="21870">The Outfoxies</game><game id="20588">Super Smash Bros. Brawl</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15777/526882-965486806_471551773d.jpg</image></root>