<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23193</id><name>Perfect World International</name><description>OverviewPerfect World was initially launched in China as a subscription-based game, Perfect World’s conversion to a free-to-play model established a level of quality not found in other free-to-play titles. Perfect World International aims to be the ultimate version of this immensely popular role-playing game. For the first time, Perfect World is being localized specially for American audiences.The closed beta was launched on August 19, 2008. The open beta launced September 2, 2008 and an expansion pack was released as early as December 3, 2008 which is also free-to-play. On December 15, 2009, another expansion added a new race, two new classes and more. Customization Perfect World contains a level of character customization not seen in many other Free To Play (F2P) MMORPGs or even Pay To Play MMORPGs. When you first create your character, You are able to customize most parts of the body (eyes, lips, face). These are not only customizable by picking certain face types through a menu, but You may also change these through sliders that let you change each part individually. RacesHuman   The Human’s  home city is Etherblade. The two classes you can choose between as a Human are Blademaster  and Wizard.   Untamed  Untamed are  creatures that have developed a consciousness. Their home city is City of the  Lost and their Classes are Barbarian and Venomancer. Normally one can choose  a gender despite the classes, but with the Untamed each class has a set gender.  The Barbarian is male, while the Venomancer is female. Even though the gender  is set, you can still customize your character a lot.  Winged  Elves  The Winged  Elves live in Plume City. The two classes are Archer and Cleric. Winged Elves  is the only race that has the ability to fly from the start.   ClassesBlademasterThe Blademaster uses swords, hammers, spears and the like. He specializes in melee so he has high physical attack, but he has low magical defence.WizardThe Wizard uses long range elemental spells to attack. The wizard has the highest skill damage, but the spell has a long cast time. BarbarianThe Barbarian specialises in melee as the Blademaster, but has a lot more health than the Blademaster. The downside is that he also deals less damage than the Blademaster.VenomancerThe Venomancer can capture and train the monsters running around in Perfect World and use them in battle. She also uses poisonous spells. The Venomancer is the best solo class in Perfect World.ArcherThe Archer attacks using a bow and arrow. Being a ranged specialist, he has low physical defence.ClericThe Cleric is the healer in Perfect World. It is the best class for those who like to play with others in a party.</description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18547">EverQuest II</game><game id="22087">Silkroad Online</game><game id="2268">RuneScape</game><game id="12376">The Lord of the Rings Online: Shadows of Angmar</game><game id="17494">Guild Wars</game><game id="11082">Guild Wars: Nightfall</game><game id="18110">Guild Wars: Eye of the North</game><game id="21223">Guild Wars 2</game><game id="21399">Last Chaos</game><game id="11142">Final Fantasy XI Online</game><game id="9641">Age of Conan: Hyborian Adventures</game><game id="13479">Anarchy Online</game><game id="2403">Anarchy Online: Alien Invasion</game><game id="7697">Anarchy Online: The Notum Wars</game><game id="5767">Ultima Online</game><game id="20666">Warhammer Online: Age of Reckoning</game><game id="25125">Ether Saga Online</game><game id="22239">Runes of Magic</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2352/535808-ssssssssss.jpg</image></root>