<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23212</id><name>Virtual Pro Wrestling 64</name><description>RosterWrestling Legends   Antonio Inoki Giant Baba Rickson Gracie Terry Funk Tiger Mask Mil Mascaras Rikidozan Andre the Giant Seiji Sakaguchi Bruiser Brody Maurice Smith Dory Funk, Jr. Dynamite Kid Dos Caras The Destroyer Manami Toyota  World Championship Wrestling   Sting Lex Luger Rick Steiner Diamond Dallas Page Dean Malenko Chris Benoit Ric Flair The Giant Scott Steiner Steven Regal Rey Mysterio Eddie Guerrero  New World Order   Hollywood Hogan Kevin Nash Scott Norton Randy Savage Eric Bischoff Scott Hall Buff Bagwell Syxx  New Japan Pro Wrestling   Riki Choshu Tatsumi Fujinami Shinya Hashimoto Keiji Mutoh Masahiro Chono Jushin Liger Shinjiro Otani Kensuke Sasaki Shiro Koshinaka Junji Hirara Kazuo Yamazaki Hiroyoshi Tenzan El Samurai Koji Kanemoto  All Japan Pro Wrestling   Mitsuharu Misawa Toshiaki Kawada Kenta Kobashi Jumbo Tsuruta Steve Williams Stan Hansen Jun Akiyama Akira Taue Johnny Ace Masanobu Fuchi Gary Albright Hiroshi Hase  World of Universe (UFC, Pancrase, UWF, RINGS)   Nobuhiko Takada Yoji Anjoh Akira Maeda Volk Han Masakatsu Funaki Ken Shamrock Masahito Kakaihara Yoshihiro Takayama Yoshi Yamamoto Dick Vrij Minoru Suzuki Bas Rutten  Dead or Alive Wrestling (FMW, IWA, WAR)   Genichiro Tenryu Koji Kitao Atsushi Onita Samson Fuyuki Big Van Vader Abdullah the Butcher Ultimo Dragon Tarzan Goto Hayabusa Jado Gedo Hawk Animal Tiger Jeet Singh  Michinoku Pro Wrestling   Great Sasuke Super Delfin TAKA Michinoku Shunji Takano Jinsei Shinzaki Gran Naniwa Dick Togo Yoshiaki Fujiwara  </description><genres><genre id="10">Wrestling</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25623">Toukon Retsuden 4</game><game id="22408">Giant Gram 2000: All Japan Pro Wrestling 3</game><game id="18320">WCW/nWo Revenge</game><game id="557">WCW vs. the World</game><game id="23213">Virtual Pro Wrestling 2: Ōdō Keishō</game><game id="3667">WWF Wrestlemania 2000</game><game id="11394">WWF No Mercy</game><game id="14786">WCW vs. nWo: World Tour</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1632/538237-256px_virtual_pro_wrestling_64_cover.png</image></root>