<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23230</id><name>Cortex Command</name><description>StoryThe story of Cortex Command lays in the very distant future, in which humans have left their obsolete bodies in order to pursue the goal of long distance space travel and ultimate control of their surroundings. These disembodied humans have implanted themselves into an interfacing technology which allows them to control, build, and buy many types of machinery and crafts. With all of this control and the ability to travel great distances, the humans have been able to explore and exploit many planets for natural resources of various types. Though many types of resources are found, the main commodity in the world of Cortex Command has become gold and with gold comes the need to trade.The TradeStarSince the need to trade is so vast in Cortex Command, the humans have set up a rather large space ship called the TradeStar. This massive ship serves as a safe haven and marketplace for miners. People can visit or connect to the TradeStar and order clones, guns or whatever they need get started. The items are then delivered via a wide range of delivery craft which the player can choose during the time of order.EnemiesDrop ship landingEnemies in Cortex Command come in two types. The first types of enemies are the local wild life of the planet which consists of crabs and other animals. The second type is decisively more deadly and are rival gold mining corporations which have all the same abilities that you do. Rival corporations can use a TradeStar connection to order new units and will pose a significant threat if not dealt with quickly.CharactersAs of Build 22 there have been a great addition of characters due to two new content producers, who were originally mod-makers on the official forums. While no two units are exactly the same, they might be similar in their purposes.GameplayThe game currently has multiple campaign levels with a variety of gameplay experiences. There is a skirmish mode in which the player defends their brain from enemy onslaught. As of Test Build 27, the campaign mode has been implemented and includes a strategy game on top of the individual brain attack/defense combat. Players can scan sites from orbit before combat, lifting the fog of war as far down as the surface layer. This gives the player greater tactical choice when selecting a landing location. Players take control of areas by destroying the commanding brain of all other players/AI. With control of a site, players gain resources each round, and can place defences on to the map to prepare for future invasions. The campaign is won when the player controls all available sites.Mod SupportLua CodingSince Build 21, the engine has been exposed to Lua, a popular programming language that is perhaps more well known for its uses in Garry's Mod. Lua opens up extra modding opportunity such as creating black holes and homing missiles..ini EditingAn "ini" file is the current standard for configurations. This already opened up the ability to create new actors, weapons and scenes without using an in-game editor. This functionality is present in every currently known build (excluding the "DIRT" versions)PC System RequirementsOS: Windows XP, Vista, 7, 8Processor: 1.6 Ghz Core 2 DuoRAM: 1GB RAMDisk: 300 mbMac System RequirementsMinimum:OSX: 10.4 (OSX Tiger or Greater)Processor: 1.6 Ghz Core 2 DuoRAM: 1GB RAMGraphics: Intel GMA X3100Disk: 300 mb</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="31">Dual-Joystick Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2007">Worms</game><game id="10757">Liero</game><game id="13773">Soldat</game><game id="2587">Dig Dug</game><game id="847">Metal Slug</game><game id="32738">Delve Deeper</game><game id="37839">Starbound</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2334965-cortex.png</image></root>