<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23251</id><name>Tomoyo After: It's a Wonderful Life</name><description>OverviewTomoyo After: It's a Wonderful Life is a spin-off of Clannad. It was first developed by Key and released for a limited period of time by Visual Art's in Japan for the Windows PC on November 11, 2005. An all-ages version was later released by Prototype for the PlayStation 2 on January 25, 2007, PlayStation Portable on March 19, 2009, Xbox 360 on September 22, 2010, PlayStation 3 on July 29, 2012, and the Android on February 27, 2013 which is called CS Edition which contains additional content in place of adult content which increased the length of the game by roughly 50%. The all-ages version for the PC was first released for a limited time on July 7, 2009 as part of the Key 10th Memorial Box which included voices from the PSP version which included voice acting for the lead character Tomoya. It was later released separately on April 30, 2010 which is known as Memorial Edition.Tomoyo After: It's a Wonderful Life was never released outside of Japan, but an unofficial English translation patch was initiated by Baka-Tsuki on June 4, 2008. The project was then taken over by Doki Fansubs on April 27, 2011 and released on September 21, 2012. An updated version was later released on March 24, 2013.StoryTomoyo After's story revolves around Tomoya Okazaki and Tomoyo Sakagami. Tomoya has graduated from high school and is now employed as a garbage collector. He and Tomoyo are now seeing each other in a romantic relationship, though Tomoya lives alone in his apartment. One day it is discovered that Tomoyo has a younger half-sister named Tomo Mishima who had been living with her mother, but was recently abandoned. It is eventually decided that Tomo will live in Tomoya's apartment for the time being.Main CharactersTomoya Okazaki: Tomoya has graduated from high school and is now working as a garbage collector and repairman. He moved out of his father's house and is now living alone in an apartment.Tomoyo Sakagami: Tomoyo is currently in her third year of high school. She would visit Tomoya frequently to cook for him and to spend time with him.Takafumi Sakagami: Tomoyo's younger brother who is currently in his first year of high school. He used to be a runner but he is now a skilled computer programmer.Tomo Mishima: Tomoyo's and Takafumi's step-sister. She is currently attending kindergarten. Tomo had been living with her mother and she was recently abandoned.Kanako: Takafumi's ex-girlfriend. Her mother is about to remarry but she disagreed and she ran away from home. She came looking for Takafumi and decided to freeload at Tomoya's apartment.GameplayTomoyo After features a single main story path. It occasionally presents a dialogue choice of up to 3 options. The choices will further the story and / or influence events in the story or lead to a bad ending.There is a minigame called Dungeons and Takafumis that can be unlocked early in the game. Once it is unlocked, the option to play it will be made available from the main menu.Dungeons and TakafumisDungeons and Takafumis is a tactical role-playing game. Its save file is separate from the visual novel save file. According to the main story, Takafumi worked with people over the internet to create the game, and Kanako wrote the story.StoryA castle had a laboratory where magicians created Takafumi clones. The clones performed household chores for people in the day and worked as male escorts at night. The clones had no emotions. This changed when clone number 054 was created under the contract with a gay devil. This granted Takafumi 054 a full range of human emotions. 10 days ago, a storm hit the castle and and Takafumi 054 disappeared. Many Takafumi clones sold themselves to the beastmen to obtain information and discovered that Takafumi 054 was in a labyrinth under the beastmen's castle. The magicians were unable to defeat the beastmen, thus they resorted to hiring mercenaries.Floor 10Tomoyo explained that Takafumi 054 was a criminal. Kanako wanted to believe that he remembered her. Tomoyo explained that Takafumi 054 wasn't the one who saved her but Kanako wanted to see him regardless.Floor 25Takafumi clone 054 was discovered. He was suffering from amnesia. Tomoyo tried to attack him but Kanako protected him. Takafumi 054 revealed that the beastmen were researching a time travelling magic, Almighty High Magic Delorean. Tomo explained that the beastmen intended to travel back in time to kill all humans. Takafumi 054 explained that they must reach the lowest floor and defeat the beastmen.Floor 30Takafumi 054 recalled a memory of a travelling swordsman who rescued Kanako and fell in love with her. He explained that that memory wasn't his own. Kanako revealed that the Takafumi who rescued her lost his life rescuing her.Floor 35Takafumi 054 was ambushed and kidnapped by the beastmen.Floor 45Takafumi 054 sent a hologram explaining that the beastmen is almost ready to cast the time travelling magic and that they only had 3 more days to stop them.Floor 50The beastmen successfully traveled 1000 years into the past. Tomoya, Tomoyo, Tomo, and Takafumi traveled back in time to defeat them. Kanako discovered that they had saved the world but they were no where to be seen.EpilogueThe beastmen appeared in the Central Region and waged war against humans. They took over the Central and Eastern Regions and drove the humans to the Western Region. Tomo created Takafumi clones and formed the volunteer army led by Tomoya, Tomoyo, and Takafumi 054. They reclaimed the South and Eastern Regions within 6 months. They spent the next several years assaulting the Southwestern and Central Regions and managed to establish a base in the Central Region.The beastmen withdrew their army from the east focused on the Western Region. The volunteer army assaulted the beastmen's base and successfully sealed off the beastmen's reinforcements. Tomoya, Tomoyo, and Takafumi 054 lost their lives in that battle. The remaining Takafumi clones spent the next several decades wiping out the remaining beastmen.The remaining Takafumis were imprisoned and the kingdom's magicians conducted research on the clones, attempting to reverse engineer the technique to clone them. They were unsuccessful because Tomo disappeared and the cloning technique disappeared with her. The clones created by the magicians lacked emotions.After Kanako read the history, she matured as a leader. She succeeded the throne after her father passed away. Kanako started a History Museum. Excavation for artifacts lasted for a year and she discovered many dead Takafumi clones. One day, she heard rumors of a living Takafumi clone in the west. The clone had no memory of her. He announced that he speaks on behalf of the real Takafumi and explained that he has returned home.GameplayDungeons and Takafumis consists of 2 sections, the intermission area and battles. It features familiar game elements which can be found in other tactical RPGs with one major difference.IntermissionThe Intermission area is the default area when the player is not in combat. This area allows for changing of jobs, replenishment of potions, and the save and load features.BattleBattles are fought on a 3D isometric grid field with 2D sprites. Dungeons and Takafumis employs an Active Time Battle system, where characters with high speed stat will act more often. It features a single dungeon which consists of 50 floors. Every fifth floor will feature a boss character, which is a stone golem for the first 45 floors, and a catgirl boss for the 50th floor. 5 floors must be cleared in a single attempt in order to save dungeon progression.The player can also choose to retreat at any time, retaining all the items and experience that has been collected. If the party is wiped out or the player chooses to retreat, the player must fight through all 5 floors again on the next attempt. If a character dies on a floor, he or she will be revived with 1 HP on the next floor.The party will be forced to retreat at floors 35 and 45 in accordance to the story.DaysThe score is recorded in number of days. Every time the player retreats, the number of days increase by 1. Thus, the least number of days in which the dungeon can be cleared is 3.Clearing within 7 days awards an S rank. 8 to 9 days awards A. 10 to 14 days awards B. 15 to 19 days awards C. 20 to 25 days awards D. 26 days or more awards E.ItemsThere is no currency and shops. All equipment can only be obtained in battle with the 'Search' command and / or after clearing a floor. Items that are obtained via the 'Search' command can only be kept after the current floor is cleared. All items has its own weight and the inventory size is limited by weight. Items can be tossed away in the intermission and in battle.CombatUnlike most tactical RPGs, the only control the player has over combat is to set the characters up at the start of every floor. The battle will then play out until either side wins by wiping out the opposition. Actions and skills will be assigned to each character and they will carry it out in the sequence that was laid out for them. Each character also has a 'last' action that will cause the character to repeat that action until the floor is cleared, the character dies, or the team is wiped out. Characters cannot be ordered to consume potions or change equipment in combat.SkillsSkills can only be used once per dungeon attempt. A buff or debuff skill will cause the character to stay on the same spot. An attack skill will cause the character to move towards an enemy.ExperienceExperience points will be granted to all characters who remain alive after a floor is cleared. Additional points will be granted per killing blow. A large amount of experience points will be given when a floor is cleared the first time and it will be decreased by 90% for subsequent clearings.Buffs and DebuffsTaunts and evade buffs cannot apply to the same character at the same time. Only the most recently cast taunt or evade will take effect.StatsCharacter stat increase at level up depends on job class. A level up grants 3 bonus stats from levels 1 to 20, 4 bonus stats from levels 21 to 40, and no bonus stats from level 41 onward.StatDescriptionAttack power (ATK)Increases physical damage dealt. Displays right and left hand separately. While dual-wielding, left hand weapon deals half damage.Defense (DEF)Reduces damage receivedIntelligence (INT)Increases magic damage dealt and healing strengthDexterity (DEX)Increases accuracy and dodge rate. Maximum dodge rate is at 230 DEXCarry Weight (CPW)Amount of weight the character can carry. Maximum inventory weight is shared between all characters. 1 CPW equals 2 maximum inventory weightSpeed (SPD)How soon the character can act again. Increases by 1 point for every 5 levels. Decreased by the weight of equipped items divided by 10Move (MOV)Walking distance. Permanently set at 3 tilesCharactersTomoya OkazakiThe Red Fang of Rigaldo. He is disconnected from the story.Initial stats: HP 30, ATK 15, DEF 8, INT 6, DEX 9, CPW 8, SPD 25LevelSkillDescription2GutsSelf buff to increase damage dealt. Lasts for 5 turns4Six Mat Room AttackDeals damage to a 3 tile radius area7LeadershipDamage dealing buff to all allies except Kanako. Lasts for 5 turns11Handmade DioxinDeals damage to a 4 tile radius area14Summon FukoSummons Fuko to attack independently. Appears at a random location18Porno MagazineTaunts all enemies to attack Tomoya and self buffs defense for 1 turn 21Sweet AtmosphereDamage dealing buffs to all allies except Tomoya. Lasts for 5 turns25Fuko DecoySummons Fuko to attack independently and taunts all enemies while active. Appears at a random location28Kanako's Killer TechniqueWhile bare-handed, greatly increases damage dealt and has a chance to instantly kill the target for 5 turns33Will of the TownDeals damage to an 8 tile radius areaTomoyo SakagamiThe Red Fang of Zarionti. Tomoyo is the leader of the Bear Association, a group of rebels. She had a dream that the Takafumi clones will overrun the world. She consulted a fortune teller and he confirmed her dream. Her objective in joining the group is to kill Takafumi 054.Initial stats: HP 30, ATK 16, DEF 8, INT 6, DEX 9, CPW 8, SPD 25LevelSkillDescription2SeriousSelf buff to increase damage dealt. Lasts for 5 turns4Full Power KickKick an enemy and send it flying across the field. If it rams another enemy, the initial enemy will stop and the inertia will send the next enemy flying. Deals damage to all enemies that were hit7Pantie FlashTaunts all enemies to attack Tomoyo for 1 turn. Also causes Tomoyo to heal Tomoya for the next 2 turns11BabysitWhen Tomo is at low health, Tomoyo will act to protect her14Gravity JumpJump to the middle of the floor, dealing damage to all enemies in a 6 tile radius18No BraTaunts all enemies to attack Tomoyo for 2 turns. Also causes Tomoyo to heal Tomoya for the next 3 turns21YellEvade all enemy attacks for 2 turns25Power of LoveWhen an enemy attempts to attack an ally, Tomoyo will teleport to that ally and attack the enemy instead, canceling its attack2810 Kick ComboKick all enemies in a 3x3 area around Tomoyo33Tomoyo, the Ultimate WeaponA self buff that greatly increases all stats. Lasts for 5 turnsKanakoThe Red Fang of Torucoone. She is the princess of the kingdom. Kanako was once rescued by a Takafumi clone and she fell in love with him.Initial stats: HP 30, ATK 15, DEF 8, INT 6, DEX 9, CPW 8, SPD 26LevelSkillDescription2High TensionSelf buff that increases critical rate. Lasts for 5 turns4SpitA 4 tile attack that stops enemy action for 1 turn7FriendsWhen Tomo is at low health, Kanako will act to protect her11Gust StrikeCharge in a straight line to the edge of the map, damaging all enemies on the way. 3 tiles wide14PapicoWhen at critical health, self heal to full health18ChallengeTaunts all enemies to attack Kanako for 3 turns21High Speed RushWhile equipping a one-handed or two-handed sword, grants double weapon swings. Lasts for 3 turns25Super High TensionA self buff that grants 100% critical strike rate. Lasts for 5 turns28Omega DriveDeals damage to a 6 tile radius. Causes all enemies to avoid allies for 2 turns33One-man ShowWhile bare-handed, grants a chance for attack to instantly kill enemies. Lasts for 5 turnsTomoA powerful magician. Her extensive practice of rejuvenation magic has stunted her aging. Tomo is also in close contact with the kingdom.Initial stats: HP 30, ATK 15, DEF 8, INT 10, DEX 8, CPW 8, SPD 24LevelSkillDescription2AttackGrants a buff to self and all allies, increases damage dealt. Lasts for 5 turns4CryCalls for help from all allies7SleepCast a spell on all enemies, has a chance to put them to sleep. Lasts for 1 turn11TagTaunts all enemies to attack Tomo for 2 turns14TeleportSends all allies to the enemy line18Kiss of FriendshipCauses enemies to ignore Tomo until she attacks21ShieldGrants a buff to self and all allies, reduces damage taken. Lasts for 5 turns25Hide and SeekEnemies will ignore Tomo for 5 turns28SpeedGrants a buff to self and all allies, increases SPD. Lasts for 5 turns33MatureA self buff that greatly increases all stats. Lasts for 5 turnsNote: Changes the graphic for TomoJob ClassesThe skills of a job class will be lost when the class is changed.SwordsmanStat requirements: ATK 20, DEF 15Stat growth: HP +8, ATK +3, DEF +2, INT +1, DEX +2, CPW +2SkillLevelDescriptionCounterattack+1When receiving an attack, has 1/3 chance to attack the attackerSword Wielder+4While equipping a two-handed sword, increase damage dealtDual Wielder+7While equipping a one-handed sword, grants double weapon swingEvade+10While equipping a sword, increase dodge rate. Lasts for 2 turnsSword Dance+13While equipping a sword, deal damage in a 3x3 areaKnightStat requirements: ATK 45, DEF 40Stat Growth: HP +7, ATK +2, DEF +3, INT +1, DEX +2, CPW +2SkillLevelDescriptionSword Wielder+1While equipping a two-handed sword, increase damage dealtDual Wielder+4While equipping a one-handed sword, grants double weapon swingSpear Wielder+7While equipping a spear, every attack hits in a 3x3 areaEvade+10While equipping a sword, increase dodge rate. Lasts for 3 turnsSpear Dance+13While equipping a spear, every attack hits in a 5x5 areaLordStat requirements: ATK 75, DEF 65, INT 45Stat growth: HP +9, ATK +2, DEF +2, INT +2, DEX +2, CPW +2SkillLevelDescriptionSword Wielder+1While equipping a two-handed sword, increase damage dealtHeal x3+3Heals an ally. Can be activated 3 times. Effect carries over to the next floorSword Master+5While equipping a sword, increases attack range to 8 tilesEvade+7While equipping a sword, increase dodge rate. Lasts for 3 turnsSword Rush+9 SamuraiStat requirements: ATK 90, DEF 65Stat growth: HP +7, ATK +3, DEF +2, INT +1, DEX +2, CPW +2SkillLevelDescriptionHide+1Reduce defense and increase attack powerNiten Ichi-ryu+3While dual-wielding, increases damage dealtHealing technique+5When an ally is at low health, heals self and all allies for 100 HPSingle Slice+7Increases the damage for the first hitGreat Swordsman+9While equipping a katana, increases damage dealtThiefStat requirements: DEX 20, CPW 20Stat growth: HP +6, ATK +2, DEF +1, INT ​​+1, DEX +3, CPW +3SkillLevelDescriptionSearch+1Increase quality of items using the 'Search' commandDagger Wielder+4While equipping a dagger, grants double weapon swingTurbulence+7While equipping a ranged weapon, every attack fire in 4 directionsSwift Warrior+10Self buff that increases SPDAim Vitals+13Self buff that increases critical strike rateNinjaStat requirements: ATK 65, DEX 60Stat growth: HP +6, ATK +2, DEF +2, INT +1, DEX +3, CPW +2SkillLevelDescriptionDagger Wielder+1While equipping a dagger, grants double weapon swingTurbulence+4While equipping a ranged weapon, every attack fire in 4 directionsSwift Warrior+6Self buff that increases SPDCovert Action+9Enemies will ignore the character for 4 turnsAim Vitals+11Self buff that increases critical strike rateAssassinStat requirement: ATK 75, DEX 70Stat growth: HP +6, ATK +2, DEF +2, INT +1, DEX +3, CPW +2SkillLevelDescriptionDagger Wielder+1While equipping a dagger, grants double weapon swingSwift Warrior+3Self buff that increases SPDCovert Action+5Enemies will ignore the character for 4 turnsAim Vitals+7Self buff that increases critical strike rateAssassination+9The first attack will kill the enemyMagicianStat requirement: INT 21Stat growth: HP +5, ATK +1, DEF+2, INT +3, DEX +2, CPW +2SkillLevelDescriptionFireball+1Deal fire damage in a 3 tile radiusEarthquake+4Confuse all enemies for 1 turnThunder+7Deal lightning damage to enemies in a 3 tile wide lineFireball x3+10Launch 3 Fireballs. Deal fire damage in a 3 tile radiusThunderstorm+13Deal lightning damage to enemies in a 5 tile radiusPriestStat requirement: INT 60Stat growth: HP +4, ATK +1, DEF +2, INT +3, DEX +2, CPW +2SkillLevelDescriptionHeal+1Heals an ally. Can be activated once. If not consumed, effect carries over to the next floorHeal x3+4Heals an ally. Can be activated 3 times. If not consumed, effect carries over to the next floorShield Wielder+6While equipping a shield, increases defenseEarthquake+9Confuse all enemies for 1 turnInvisible+11Grant a buff to self and all allies, evading all attacks for 3 turnsWizardStat requirement: INT 110Stat growth: HP +4, ATK +1, DEF +2, INT +3, DEX +2, CPW +2SkillLevelDescriptionShield Wielder+1While equipping a shield, increases defenseFireball x5+2Launch 5 Fireballs. Deal fire damage in a 3 tile radiusThunderstorm x2+4Launch 2 Thunderstorms. Deal lightning damage to enemies in a 5 tile radiusFireball x10+6Launch 10 Fireballs. Deal fire damage in a 3 tile radiusMeteor+9Deal damage in an 8 tile radiusEnemiesEnemies tends to prioritize attacking characters in this order: Tomoyo  Tomoya  Kanako  TomoMonsterDescriptionGreen BeastmenRegular monsterRed BeastmenHigher stats than Green BeastmenBlue BeastmenHigher SPD and MOV than Green Beastmen. Targets character with the lowest defenseStone GolemVery high HP and defense. Attacks will always damage a 3x3 areaCatgirl999 HP  </description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23250">Air</game><game id="8059">Kanon</game><game id="18953">Planetarian ~Chiisana Hoshi no Yume~</game><game id="23252">Little Busters!</game><game id="23253">Rewrite</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9536/546652-tomoyo.jpg</image></root>