<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23282</id><name>Henry Hatsworth in the Puzzling Adventure</name><description>OverviewHenry HatsworthFirst appearing at GDC 2008, the game was known as Unannounced: The Game. Little was known of the gameplay at that time but the mustachioed British professor known as Henry Hatsworth made his debut. Making a return at E3's Into The Pixel art exhibit, the professor had a new style and promised an innovative platforming experience. Henry Hatsworth in the Puzzling Adventure was officially announced and it's name made public the summer of 2008 by EA Tiburion. A product of the EA Casual division, Henry Hatsworth features platforming on the top screen with a puzzle game on the lower touchscreen.GameplayExample of platforming/puzzling action In  the game, all the platforming takes place on the upper screen. The game features 30 levels over five exotic worlds. You'll be collecting artifacts in order to build a golden mech suit. You can also expect to see such amazing sights as an opera singing boss, a robotic construct of Big Ben and countless varied enemies. The professor is so badass, however, that he chooses to do tons of puzzling whilst going about his adventures.The puzzle game aspect of Henry Hatsworth in the Puzzling Adventure takes place on the bottom screen. It's a Planet Puzzle League style game where tiles are slid horizontally to create rows of at least three.  Once enemies are killed on the upper screen, they become tiles on the bottom. Over time they will move upwards and if they make it to the top they return as enemies to fight Hatsworth. You can also gain power-ups by working on the puzzle. Filling up the Super Meter on the right side of the puzzle screen will make Hatsworth younger and give him an extension on his life meter. This helps create an incentive to do the puzzle part.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19256">Planet Puzzle League</game><game id="11103">Mega Man ZX</game><game id="14169">Bejeweled</game><game id="20567">Puzzle Quest: Galactrix</game><game id="25552">Mighty Flip Champs</game><game id="9071">Wario: Master of Disguise</game><game id="25516">Puzzle Kingdoms</game><game id="22336">Professor Layton and the Unwound Future</game><game id="11865">Professor Layton and the Curious Village</game><game id="22322">Professor Layton and the Diabolical Box</game><game id="29373">Turn</game><game id="23983">Mario &amp; Luigi: Bowser's Inside Story</game><game id="31644">Kingdom Hearts Re:coded</game><game id="30173">Alice in Wonderland</game><game id="32403">Rabbit x Labyrinth</game><game id="31268">Monster Tale</game><game id="34209">Puzzle Agent 2</game><game id="20043">Viewtiful Joe: Double Trouble!</game><game id="39155">10000000</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5150/886857-henryhatsworth.jpg</image></root>