<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23315</id><name>Carrier Command: Gaea Mission</name><description>OverviewMANTAs hovering around a Carrier.Carrier Command: Gaea Mission is a real-time strategy / vehicular action / first-person shooter hybrid developed by Bohemia (in collaboration with Black Element) and published by Rising Star (in North America, Bohemia in other regions) for the Xbox 360 and PC on September 28, 2012. The sequel to the 1988 game Carrier Command, players take control of either the United Earth Coalition (UEC) or Asian Pacific Alliance (APA) as they use their Carriers (as well as mobile aircraft, amphibious rovers, drones, and combat droids) to take control of a vast group of islands in the planetoid Taurus.The game also features a vast single-player campaign based on the Gaea Universe trilogy of sci-fi novels.Key featuresDynamic weather systemThe weather is more than eye-candy in Carrier CommandWeather is simulated across the whole vast archipelago of Taurus in real time. From nasty storms on ice covered islands, through foggy weather on marsh islands, to the cloudless sky of summer temperate islands.The system in place is not only influencing visibility and graphic appeal, but has dynamic effects on the game's environment including grass, trees, sea and even the nearby moon.Large-scale mapA forest island on TaurusCarrier Command: Gaea Mission will feature a large 32 island archipelago occupied by enemies. It is up to the player to claim the territory and establish his presence on this colony planetoid.The islands found in the game differ in shapes, sizes (up to 16 square kilometres), in that they're being spread amongst six different climatic zones, and also in weather conditions and flora. The developers are known for their open-world games, and they've brought years of focused experience with them on this project.WastelandsIslands in this zone are covered grasslands with scattered trees similar to Earth’s savannas.Being mostly flat with only occasional mountains or ridges these islands are ideal for building large factory or refinery complexes but it also makes them easily accessible from the shoreline and thus preparing effective defenses is difficult.UnitsThere will be plenty of vehicles and equipment to help you in the coming struggle for supremacy. For example:C-class Survey VesselThe C-class Survey Vessel was originally designed as a survey and support ship, primarily to be the main support unit of the colonization and terraforming off-world process. Soon after the UEC attack on Taurus it was refitted to meet new requirements and converted into a multipurpose armed vehicle carrier of immense power.Codenamed Green Dragon. This specific carrier was originally seized by the Gaea crew on planet M38 and rebuilt on Taurus. As such, it lacks several upgrades which the enemy has available. These advanced technologies can be discovered and adapted during the game.The purpose of this carrier is to act as an armed mobile platform with a command base, hangars, repair bays and a flight deck, launching unmanned drones, autonomous Manta aircraft or Walrus amphibious vehicles all with custom armor, equipment and weapon load configuration suitable to complete any mission goals. However, even without the vehicles it’s a mighty floating fortress equipped with strong defensive and hard-hitting offensive weapon systems of its own.The WALRUS (Water And Land Roving Utility Shuttle)A six-wheeled amphibious vehicle. Heavily armored and packing a punch, they are perfect for ground or sea assaults.The most versatile of your vehicles, they can deploy droids and construction pods from their cargo bays onto an island.Armor kits available: Light (Scout), Medium (Balanced) and Heavy (Assault).Known weapon options: Machine gun, HE shells, AA guns, grenade launcher, plasma and laser turret.Known utility options: Various construction pods, hacking capsules, repair arms and deployable ammo boxes.Carrier WALRUS capacity: 4The MANTA (Multi-role Aircraft for Nautical Tactical Assault)An aerial survey craft which has been adapted with weapons capabilities to assist in battle.Designed to enter hazardous zones for mining and exploration, they are hardy and highly maneuverable. While their primary purpose is for reconnaissance and expanding your telemetry network, their new role of combat strike vehicle has been a wild success.It can be manually controlled remotely from the carrier if it remains within the telemetry (the connection radius).Armor kits available: Light (Recon), Medium (Balanced) and Heavy (Assault).Known weapon options:Known utility options: Adaptable carrying harness for WALRUS deployment.Carrier MANTA capacity: 4DronesThere are two different drone types: defense drones and scout drones.Combat DroidsHuman troops are limited on the colony planet, but these squads of recyclable Droids can be manufactured quickly.A Droid has a limited internal power core which drains both over time and for every shot of their hardwired weapons. During attacks, a balance must be struck between impact and longevity. Each squad of 8 Droids deposited by a Walrus consists of basic Assault units, Snipers, Heavy Weapons and Command Droids, which carry the control virus to hijack an enemy’s Command Centre.PC System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows XP, Windows Vista, Windows 7Processor: Intel Core2Duo 2.2 GHz or AMD Dual-Core Athlon 2.5 GHz or fasterMemory: 2 GBHard Disk Space: 4 GB HD spaceVideo Card: NVIDIA GeForce 8800GT with Shader Model 3 and 512 MB VRAM or fasterDirectX®: 9.0cSound: DirectX Audio compatibleRecommendedOS: Windows 7Processor: Intel Core i5 or AMD Athlon Phenom X4 or fasterMemory: 4 GBVideo Card: NVIDIA GeForce GTX460 with Shader Model 3 and 1 GB VRAM or faster</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1111">Hostile Waters: Antaeus Rising</game><game id="16088">Battlezone</game><game id="17672">Battlezone II: Combat Commander</game><game id="3720">Battlezone: Rise of the Black Dogs</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2345117-box_ccgm.png</image></root>