<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23327</id><name>Star Trek:  The Next Generation:  Future's Past</name><description>Star Trek: The Next Generation: Future's Past centers around the bridge of the USS Enterprise-D. From here the player can scroll left or right to choose what they would like to do. For example, they can access the computer which provides access to Star Trek lore, both specific to the game and not, or can access navigation, or provide access to the briefing room and a run down of the current situation; etc.Over the course of the game's story the player is given objectives usually involving navigating to a planet, choosing who will be in the 'away-team', and completing mission-objectives. These objectives involve moving the away-team, each member of which can only be controlled one at a time, through a top-down maze and flipping switches to open doors; not unlike many dungeon crawlers of the time.The plot centers around the Enterprise searching for some kind of time-machine. The game's antagonists are the Romulans and a non-canon species called the Chodak.Star Trek: The Next Generation: Future's Past, was released simultaneously with the nearly identical, yet much better, Sega Genesis version, Star Trek: The Next Generation: Echoes of the Past. The biggest difference between the two is that the bonus level in the Genesis version, which is unlocked through a laborious process, is made to be the first level in the SNES version. This added level makes the beginning of the SNES version bafflingly difficult. Further, the inclusion of this level in the SNES version created plot incongruities which were corrected by eliminating the ability to use certain away-team members in certain levels. However, the difficulty of these levels does not adjust itself for this fact and again renders the game a controller-thrower.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="996">Star Trek: The Next Generation - Echoes from the Past</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/5/59593/2323835-us_front.jpg</image></root>