<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23377</id><name>Swords &amp; Soldiers</name><description>IntroductionSwords  Soldiers is a RTS that features side-scrolling play in an art style that is inspired by "Super Moine" animation. Swords  Soldiers is the second project from the team that created the original concept for the THQ published De Blob. Swords  Soldiers offers split screen multiplayer with players being able to command one of three factions in the game. The game prides itself on "historical inaccuracy," and takes an over the top approach to their characters and situations. The game also includes 25 achievements for players to unlock.GameplaySwords  Soldiers includes a variety of game modes, which include single player campaigns for each of the three factions, local split screen multiplayer, AI skirmishes, and other challenge modes. Players command the action on a 2D side-scrolling playing field. Although individual units are not controllable by the player (if a player builds a miner, they will mine stuff without the player's input), the maps have branching paths. Players control which path their units take by changing the sign posts located at these forks. The player's main role is to build units and support them with spells or upgrades. These spells can range from simple healing auras, to damage lightning bolt strikes.HD VersionThis version of the game has higher resolution graphics than it's Wii counterpart and also adds the option of Online multiplayer. Matchmaking can take place in the background, giving the opportunity to play singleplayer game modes until a match has been found.PC RequirementsOS: Windows 7/Vista/XPProcessor: 1GHzMemory: 256 MB RAMGraphics: 64 MB graphics cardHard Drive: 300 MBMac RequirementsOS: OS X version Leopard 10.5.8, Snow Leopard 10.6.3, or later.Processor: Intel Core DuoMemory: 512 MBGraphics: 64 MBHard Drive: 300 MB</description><genres><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21222">GrimGrimoire</game><game id="15886">Steam Brigade</game><game id="34455">Creeper World 2</game><game id="37725">Cubemen</game><game id="38498">CastleStorm</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1570/562626-swordssoldiers01.jpg</image></root>