<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23427</id><name>Blockland Retail</name><description>OverviewBlockland is a multiplayer focused sandbox game for Windows and Mac.FeaturesBlockland allows players to start a single player game or on a local area network. Players can connect to the hundreds of user-created servers that can host up to 99 people. The in-game event system allows programing of basic functions for bricks, or complex ones.GameplayThe game is a sandbox game with many different possibilities. Some of these gameplay possibilities are outlined below.ShootingA variety of deathmatch and team deathmatch are possible, with game modes like capture the flag, control certain capture points, dog fights and more.RacingPlayers can also race; there is a variety of vehicles and for racing. Players can have a race while shooting rockets at each other, or going off jumps.Role-PlayingExperienced Blockland players that have mastered the in-game eventing system can program leveling mechanics and money systems. Users can create environments with spawning enemies or quests.You can build a base then defend it from waves of zombie attacks, or try to escape a spreading virus that spreads from brick to brick.BuildingPlayers can build almost anything. Once a creation is built, players can create minigames and use any game-mode.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre><genre id="45">Block-Breaking</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20602">LittleBigPlanet</game><game id="20617">Garry's Mod</game><game id="20237">Second Life</game><game id="10575">LEGO Creator: Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets</game><game id="23534">Lego Creator</game><game id="30475">Minecraft</game><game id="24293">Atmosphir</game><game id="25462">Roblox</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/17544/575739-betacity1.jpg</image></root>