<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23433</id><name>Shin Megami Tensei: Imagine</name><description>OverviewShin Megami Tensei: Imagine was originally released in Japan on March 30th, 2007 and in North America on December 31st, 2008. It was Cave Co.'s first Massively Multiplayer Online (MMO) game for the PC.On February 29th, 2012, it was announced that the international publishing rights for Imagine would be transferred to Atlus Online, with the transfer time initially being set for April 7th, 2012 at 11 AM PST, but then being postponed to April 9th at 11 AM PST, and the planned relaunch of the game's servers being April 16th. All characters that logged in from February 1st, 2012 to April 9th retained all of their progress.Atlus Online launched their servers for Imagine on April 27th, 2012.StorylineShinjuku BabelTokyo, Japan was destroyed in 202X. Under the guidance of the seven wise-men, the survivors of the destruction began construction of a massive tower called Shinjuku Babel. The tower serves as headquarters for the Devil Buster (DB) organization.The game starts off in a an area known as "3rd Home," an underground shelter where the "Innocents" live. The "Innocents" are artificial beings created to replace the people who died in the "Great Flood." Due to losing their homes, the people along with the "Innocents" have taken residence in this nuclear shelter and a city has been built inside it. Players belong to an organization called the Devil Busters, and it is their job to defeat the devils across the land. Capturing and recording these demons in their "Demonic Compendium," is yet another essential task. Players have the ability to summon and command devils by using a device called a "COMP".After the Tokyo holocaust, three pillars appeared, and have been called "Obelisks." The pillars emit power and change their surroundings constantly. The Nakano obelisk created a forest. The Ichigaya obelisk has prompted the eruption of lava in the area. The Shibuya obelisk is associated with the appearance of mysterious crystals, known as "Altered Magnetite."Chapter One: DB LicenseIn the first chapter, players will complete tasks to obtain their Devil Buster's license, giving them an extra slot in their COMP and the ability to teleport between 3rd Home and Shinjuku Babel. This teleport can only be used once every 24 hours.Act Zero: The Sin of WeaknessAct One: A Demon FriendAct Two: OmenAct Three: The RaidAct Four: AzuraAct Five: The Thick ForestAct Six: The Obelisk of BalanceAct Seven: DB LicenseChapter Two: Children of AdamAll of the Acts in this Chapter, will be given to the player via Yamamoto the Steel-Willed, who is located in Shinjuku Babel.Act Eight: The Obelisks of Form and PowerAct Nine: Setsu's AnxietyAct Ten: Azura's SearchAct Eleven: Azura's Special TrainingAct Twelve: Vizionz of the PastAct Thirteen: Envoy for the Messiah/Gaia ChurchAct Fourteen: OgamiAct Fifteen: The PrisonersAct Sixteen: Spiral WaltzDemon FusionIn all towns, there is a building called the "Cathedral of Shadows," that allows players to fuse two or more demons together. If players are in a party of three or more, three party members can donate a demon to the fusion, but only the person who started the fusion will be able to get the end result. The way you repay your party members for offering their demon is through "bribes."During the triple fusion you will be prompt to give something to your party members this can be any item in your inventory, unless otherwise stated (you can also give multiple items to the members, as well.) Remember that some Triple-Fusion's require a "Plug-in!" Through fusion, a demon will have inherited skills that are not directly usable because they have to be learned. These skills can be learned by either using a spell of that attribute, or being hit by one. The stronger the spell is that you use or get hit by, the faster you'll inherit the skills you want! You can also use an "Incense of Heredity" to speed up the process even more.Tri-Fuse ListThe following demons are only available through Tri-Fusion.Uriel (Plug-in Optional)Surt (Plug-in Optional)King FrostThothBishamonten (Plug-in needed)OdinMithraLokiHecateZhu Que (Plug-in needed)Mot (Plug-in needed)ReferencesOfficial Website (English) - http://megaten.atlusonline.com/Official Website (Japanese) - http://www.megatenonline.com/Unofficial Wiki - http://megaten.sesshou.com/wiki/Japanese Wiki - http://megatenonline.wiki.fc2.com/</description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11142">Final Fantasy XI Online</game><game id="16614">Ragnarok Online</game><game id="18603">World of Warcraft: The Burning Crusade</game><game id="18547">EverQuest II</game><game id="12376">The Lord of the Rings Online: Shadows of Angmar</game><game id="21906">Digimon RPG</game><game id="25906">Tales of Eternia Online</game><game id="22239">Runes of Magic</game><game id="25223">Fallout Online</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3776/577517-smto_imagine_cover.jpg</image></root>