<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23440</id><name>Princess Debut</name><description>Overview Princess Debut is a rhythm and dating sim  otome game developed by   Cave and published by  Natsume. It was released on June 17, 2008 in Japan and on September 30, 2008 in the US. The game puts you in control of a young girl named  Sabrina who steps through a magical portal and ends up in a fairy tale world with talking animals where she's now a princess. You have 30 days to get ready for the big ball, and will have to pick a partner from six dashing princes and master a variety of dance styles during that time. Once you have convinced a prince to be your partner in the adventure portion of the game, you can take them to the dance floor where the rhythm gameplay comes in. Similar to  Ouendan, differently shaped strokes appear on screen that you will have to follow with your stylus. The game has a total of 14 possible endings, giving it lots of replay value. You are also able to  unlock up to 20 outfits for Sabrina to wear.  PlotYou play as a young girl named  Sabrina who is bored of her ordinary life and who wishes to be a princess. One night a princess and her servant from a parallel world come to your house through a magical portal in your room.  The Princess, who looks exactly like you, offers you to take her place for the ball that is to be held in Saint Lyon that is to be held in 30 days since she is a terrible dancer. You accept her offer and go through the portal, switching identities with the princess who stays in your world. It does not take you long to notice that in this new world all the residents have an uncanny resemblance to the people you know in your life.StoryCatherineSabrina is walking home with a class mate named  Catherine, discussing the boys in their class and comparing them to princes. After a while Sabrina and Catherine split ways and Sabrina heads for home. Once she gets home, however, a strange small flying creature with pink glasses resembling a mouse appears, accompanied by a young girl looking identical to Sabrina pop out of a portal in Sabrina's closet. The little flying creature refers to the young girl as the Princess, and they seem to be happy that they made it to the "other world" in one piece. The princess introduces herself as Sabrina and the flying creature as  Kip Hamoon Stallon the 777th. They explain you that they are from a parallel world "just beyond the closet" and that they come through the portal in search for a girl looking just like the Princess to replace her at an annual ball that is to be held in 30 days. The ball is called the "Ball in Saint-Lyon." The princess was supposed to attend it, but she can't dance and decided to run away. Kip offers Sabrina to come to their world where she can live as a princess. After hesitating somewhat, Sabrina accepts their offer, and follows Kip through the portal, leaving the real princess behind in her world. However, before leaving, the princess tells you to not touch the Emerald Necklace in her room under no circumstance. On the other side of the portal, Sabrina finds herself in a beautiful fairy tale like world filled with flowers, castles, and  talking animals. She doesn't have much time to appreciate the view, however, since the maids quickly enter her room and tell her to hurry and dress up for a dinner party that is to be held at the Waltz Castle.  Sabrina can't take it any more and ask Kip to take her home to her own world, but Kip tells her that in order to do so, she'll need the key to open the portal, which the real princess has with her in Sabrina's world. Having no other option, Sabrina decides to make the best of it and heads for the dinner party. At the dinner party she meets up with four princes,  Prince Vince,  Prince Cesar,  Prince Luciano and  Prince Klaus, whose appearances all bear an uncanny resemblance to the boys at her school.  The next day Kip tells you to meet up with  Tony Rabbit, your new dance instructor. From this point on it is you who decides how future events will happen!GameplayStructurePrincess Debut at its core is structured like a traditional dating sim. Depending on the day and the location, you'll encounter different NPCs to interact with, and most of the time you'll be able to choose from a dialogue tree how to interact with them. What makes Princess Debut unique is that in order to seduce one of the princes to come with you to the ball at Saint Lyon, you'll have to dance with them; the better you execute a dance, the more their love rating will go up. However, dancing costs stamina, and you only have a certain amount of stamina a day, so once your stamina runs out, you'll be unable to dance; thus you'll have to choose who if you would like to accept or not to dance with the different princes you encounter. Once you run out of stamina, your only option is to go to your room and to sleep until the next day to regain your stamina. When you dance with a prince, you also gain experience that will allow you to level up and gain up to 5 stamina units so that you'll be able to dance more dances in one day. By leveling up you also gain "technique" and "artistry" plus by leveling up you learn/unlock new dances.Dance MechanicsTony Rabbit is your dance teacher in Princess Debut.The  dance mechanics in Princess Debut seems similar to  Ouendan at first glance, but is actually quite different and generally easier. When the characters are dancing, the touch screen will display strokes that you will have to trace with your stylus. These strokes correspond directly to the variety of dance moves the characters will preform; the more complicated the move, the more complicated the stroke will be. Along this stroke, there will also be a rolling ball that you can follow; however, unlike in similar rhythm games like Ouendan, you aren't 't forced to follow the rolling ball, and simply have to trace the stroke before the ball reaches the end and a new stroke appears, making the game easier and more suited for its intended audience. If you opt to follow the ball anyway, you will be rewarded with bonus points. The top screen also displays the upcoming two strokes so you can prepare for them in advance. If you move your stylus outside of the stroke or don't complete it in time, you fail that particular dance move. Every new dance stroke starts at the end of where the last one ended, so you don't need to lift your stylus from the screen whilst you're dancing. However in a more advanced stage of the game you can gain more points by putting you stylus on the ball at a precise timing more in the vein of  Ouendan. The game also has a combo system that tracks how many strokes you successfully perform.Game ModesStory Mode Play through the game's 30 days to unlock accessories and try to achieve one of the 14 endings.Ballroom Mode In ballroom mode you have to dance 5 songs from either the standard or the salsa selection of songs in a row and score above a minimum number of points, if you get less then the minimum you'll have to start over from the beginning. Beating ballroom mode grants you songs and outfits.Movie Mode Dance it yourself.Movie mode is one of the more unique modes in Princess Debut. At first glance it is just a mode where you can choose (from the content you have unlocked in Story Mode) with whom, where, on what music, and with what dress you want your main character to dance. Once all this is chosen you can enjoy the dancing sequence without actually having to play the game while being able to freely rotate the camera, zoom in and out, play the sequence in slowmotion and make it play on repeat.The unique thing about this mode is that there is also a option named "Steps". When activated the actual footwork of the dance being danced will be displayed allowing the player to learn the moves for ones self at a desired speed by pausing and using slowmotion.Practice Mode Play any dance you've unlocked without losing mid game.New Game PlusOnce you beat the game you unlock a  New Game Plus mode. This mode allows you to skip most of the epilogue and the initial training sequence. Also in New Game Plus, the 6th prince,  Prince Keifer Bergmann, will appear in the story. Furthermore, New Game Plus uses the second, harder song list (instead of beginning with the song "Nocturne" you will begin with "The Swan" and so on).LocationsThere are 3 areas in Princess Debut each with several locations.The Castle Area Waltz Castle: Home of the royal family.  Your Room: Where you can save or sleep.  Practice Hall: Where dance practices are held.  Dance Hall: Where the two monthly dancing competitions are held.  The City Area Samba Square: Where the traveling market is held for 3 days.  Jive Park: Where people play, dance and relax in the sun.  Rumba Beach: Where the waves crash to the sound of Rumba music.  Cha-Cha-Cha Arena: Where the horse racing derby is held.  The Forest Area Paso Doble Park   Tango Garden: Where the 5 day flower expo is held.  Foxtrot Forest   Viennese Waltz Lake: The most beautiful and quiet place in the Kingdom  MusicThe soundtrack in Princess Debut is a mix of original pieces and classical songs rearranged to fit a certain musical genre.  Standard MusicWaltz "Nocturne" As inspired by Frédéric Chopin (Easy)  "The Swan" (Easy)  Tango "Eine Kleine Nachtmusik" as inspired by Wofgang Amadeus Mozart (Medium)  "Military March" (Medium)  Slow Foxtrot "When the saints go marching in" made famous by Louis Armstrong (Easy)  "The Entertainer" as inspired by Scott Joplin (Easy)  Quickstep "American Patrol" as inspired by F.W. Meacham (Hard)  "J'ai perdu le do (de ma clarinette)" (Hard)  Viennese Waltz "Voices of Spring" as inspired by Johann Strauss II (Hard)  "Waltz of the Flowers"  as inspired by Piotr Ilitch Tchaïkovski (Hard)  Latin MusicRumba "Swan Lake" as inspired by Piotr Ilitch Tchaïkovski (Easy)  "Polovetsian Dances" as inspired by Alexander Porfiryevich Borodin (Easy)  Cha-Cha-Cha "Minuet" as inspired by Johann Sebastian Bach (Medium)  "The Dances of the Hours" as inspired by  Amilcare Ponchielli (Medium)  Paso Doble "Carmen" as inspired by Georges Bizet (Medium)  "Under the Double Eagle" as inspired by Josef Wagner (Medium)  Jive "Funiculi funicula" as inspired by Luigi Denza (Hard)  " Danny Boy " made famous by Frederick Edward Weatherly  (Hard)  Samba "Turkish March" as inspired by Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart (Hard)   "Tico Tico" as inspired by Zequinha de Abreu  (Hard)  TriviaThe "Debut" in Princess Debut refers to "balle des débutantes" which is French for "Beginner's Ball". These "beginner's balls" were balls created so that young nobility would meet up among each other and eventually develop a relationship.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23452">Angelique</game><game id="254">Moero! Nekketsu Rhythm Damashii Osu! Tatakae! Ouendan 2</game><game id="7037">Osu! Tatakae! Ouendan</game><game id="10707">Kira Kira Pop Princess</game><game id="23429">Tokimeki Memorial Girl's Side</game><game id="23472">Tokimeki Memorial Girl's Side: 2nd Kiss</game><game id="23144">Pop Cutie! Street Fashion Simulation</game><game id="23970">Oshare Princess DS: Oshare ni Koishite! 2</game><game id="23969">Oshare Princess DS: Oshare ni Koishite!</game><game id="23978">Style Savvy</game><game id="23989">Pop Town</game><game id="23990">Pinky Street: Kira Kira Rainbow Pack</game><game id="22437">Harvest Moon DS Cute</game><game id="24127">Rhythm de Cooking: Sweets Party e Youkoso</game><game id="24131">Princess on Ice</game><game id="13108">Imagine Figure Skater</game><game id="24314">KuruKuru Princess: Yume no White Quartet</game><game id="20556">Ontamarama</game><game id="24317">Imagine Ballet Star</game><game id="24337">Cosmetic Paradise: Make no Kiseki</game><game id="24338">Cosmetic Paradise</game><game id="24343">Otometeki Koi Kakumei Love Revo!!</game><game id="24294">Imagine Rock Star</game><game id="25668">Rockin' Pretty</game><game id="27864">High School Musical 3: Senior Year</game><game id="28912">KuruKuru Princess: Tokimeki Figure Mezase! Vancouver</game><game id="31655">Gabrielle’s Ghostly Groove</game><game id="35857">Hakuoki: Demon of the Fleeting Blossom</game><game id="23451">Yo-Jin-Bo: The Bodyguards</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/112/578385-950807_20080714_screen022.jpg</image></root>