<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23461</id><name>FUEL</name><description>OverviewFuel is an open world racing game that's claim to fame is that it hold the Guiness world record for largest race enviornment. The game takes place in an alternate history version of the present where global warming has caused various natural disaster to transform the landscape dramatically. As such fuel in this world has become scarce and is used as currency.In addition to the career mode the game also allows players to create their own races anywhere in the wasteland and race online with friends.Game Play:The game is an open world racer containing 5,00 miles of terrain. The world is split up into several zones most of which require stars to unlock. In each zone players start out at a base camp from where they can freely roam around searching for challenges and collectibles. The main goal in the game is to complete career races which earn the player stars. Each race has three difficulty levels and completing each grants players a separate star. To enter most races players usually need a specific vehicle which they have to buy using fuel. Fuel can be won from completing either career races or challenges. Challenges are for the most part, similar to career races although completing them does not get the player any stars, only fuel. Like career races most challenges require certain vehicles although challenges are more plentiful than career races so chances are better that players will be able to find a challenge that they can qualify for.Since the world is so large the game makes a couple of concessions to help players navigate through. Career races, for instance, do not have to be found on the map, and can be selected from the Base camp menu immediately upon unlocking a zone. Furthermore, the game contains helicopter pads throughout where players can fast travel too. Challenges however do need to be discovered in free roam mode before becoming selective.PC System RequirementsOS: Windows Vista (Service Pack 1) / Windows XP (Service Pack 3)Processor: Pentium D @ 3.0GHz or equivalent Athlon 64 X2 CPUMemory: 1GB RAMGraphics: GeForce 7800 / Radeon X1800 with 256 MB of VRAMDirectX®: DirectX 9.0cHard Drive: 6GB Hard Drive spaceSound: DirectX Compatible Sound CardInitial activation requires internet connection; Online play requires log-in to Games for Windows - LIVE; software installations required including Sony DADC SecuROM, Games for Windows - LIVE. Broadband internet connection required for online play (512kbps recommended).</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3916">DiRT</game><game id="20451">MotorStorm: Pacific Rift</game><game id="20933">Baja: Edge of Control</game><game id="24513">DiRT 2</game><game id="20729">GRID</game><game id="6499">RalliSport Challenge 2</game><game id="5648">Burnout Paradise</game><game id="25226">Need for Speed World</game><game id="24793">MotorStorm</game><game id="25424">MotorStorm: Arctic Edge</game><game id="19032">ATV Offroad Fury</game><game id="19001">ATV Offroad Fury 2</game><game id="22064">ATV Offroad Fury 3</game><game id="22065">ATV Offroad Fury 4</game><game id="20957">Pure</game><game id="10124">Midnight Club: Street Racing</game><game id="20418">Midnight Club II</game><game id="5875">Midnight Club 3: DUB Edition</game><game id="20927">Midnight Club: Los Angeles</game><game id="21114">Midnight Club: Los Angeles Remix</game><game id="34155">ATV Wild Ride</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1824035-box_fuel.png</image></root>