<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23498</id><name>Football Manager 2009</name><description>The match engine:One of the areas improved from Football Manager™ 2008 is the match engine. The famous Football Manager™ match engine can now be viewed in full 3D with motion captured animations the players. Sports Interactive has been working on the 3D match engine with the support of SEGA Japan’s football development team who provided the motion capture data and some of the animations.You can now watch your matches in 3D from multiple camera angles and re-watch any part of the match by fast forwarding and rewinding the action using a new match time bar that flags the key moments in the game.The old 2d view of the match engine is still there, especially for those people whose computers aren’t powerful enough to take advantage of the 3d views.Watch your matches in new full screen TV view and customise your match day screen with widgets to view the information you need as a football manager, be it player performance, match action zones, pitch radar, latest scores and many more.Other Improved FeaturesThe game also contains many more improved aspects. A few improvements are:Improved Media – SI have worked hard to reflect the greater impact the media has been having in recent years on the world of football, in the in-game dealings with the press. The game now features more news stories, more detail and greater media interaction than ever before. Board Confidence – Following on from its addition in Football Manager™ 2008, board confidence has been expanded and improved. In addition, the board will now also feedback to you on your squad harmony and the club’s stature in the football world. Realistic Finances – SI have listened to feedback from all of their researchers to try and model every single financial area of the game correctly for each country, including transfers, staff wages, budgets, ticket prices, season tickets, competition bonuses and club sponsorships. Updated Competitions – Fully updated for the new 2008/09 football season with all the latest league, club and player data, featuring over 5,000 playable clubs from over 50 countries, and around 350,000 players and staff from around the world, drawn fresh from the famous Sports Interactive database. Transfer System – Completely new and re-written transfer system code, providing an even more realistic simulation of real-life football transfers.And regens have also been improved....New Features:SI have also included a number of brand new features in the game. They are:Assistant Feedback–Pre-match and in-match feedback from your Assistant Manager on how the team is performing and your player’s motivation levels, as well as hints on how your tactics are working and how you could outwit the opposition’s tactics.Press Conferences –Attend pre-match and post-match press conferences with local and national journalists and build up relationships with them over time, but choose your answers carefully because they could come back to haunt you in the media at a later date.Transfer Rumours – View the latest news on what players are being speculated on, and who’s said to be interested in securing their services.Preferred Moves – Train your players to learn ‘preferred moves’ to add to their game. For example, train central defenders to not dive into tackles, or wingers to do stepovers before crossing the ball..Female Manager – For the very first time you can now play as a female manager. All of the text in the game now also has a female gender so the game represents female managers and staff in the game in the correct gender.Widescreen Support – As a result of usability testing on Football Manager 2008, this year sees widescreen support for the game for the first time, as well as lots of tweaks to the user interface for easier navigation.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="40">Soccer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1586">Total Club Manager 2003</game><game id="15714">Total Club Manager 2005</game><game id="22092">LMA Manager 2007</game><game id="2004">LMA Manager 2006</game><game id="11938">LMA Manager 2005</game><game id="10269">Championship Manager 2006</game><game id="24888">FIFA Manager 09</game><game id="8025">NHL Eastside Hockey Manager</game><game id="25688">Baseball Mogul 2010</game><game id="20807">Baseball Mogul 2009</game><game id="26655">Pro Cycling Manager: Season 2009</game><game id="20837">NFL Head Coach 09</game><game id="26936">Front Office Football 2007</game><game id="26654">Pro Cycling Manager: Season 2008</game><game id="27148">Let's Make a Soccer Team!</game><game id="26935">Front Office Football</game><game id="26946">Front Office Football 2</game><game id="9757">Front Office Football 2001</game><game id="26951">Front Office Football: The College Years</game><game id="26947">Front Office Football: The Fourth Edition</game><game id="26949">Front Office Football 2004</game><game id="7666">Pro Rugby Manager</game><game id="5035">NFL Head Coach</game><game id="27246">Pro Rugby Manager 2</game><game id="17090">LMA Manager</game><game id="4728">LMA Manager 2001</game><game id="13450">LMA Manager 2002</game><game id="4715">LMA Manager 2003</game><game id="2237">LMA Manager 2004</game><game id="27881">Championship Manager 2010</game><game id="30630">Baseball Mogul 2011</game><game id="20279">Championship Manager 5</game><game id="27051">Championship Manager 2007</game><game id="6697">Premier Manager Ninety Nine</game><game id="11088">Hockey League Simulator</game><game id="4805">Soccer Team Manager: English and Italian Leagues</game><game id="32911">FIFA Manager 11</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/6/63119/1421656-pc_football_manager_2009_boxart_uk.jpg</image></root>