<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23550</id><name>Yu-Gi-Oh! Online</name><description>OverviewYu-Gi-Oh! Online was a massively multiplayer card battling game developed and published by Konami for the PC platform.The servers for Yu-Gi-Oh! Online were shut down on 09/30/2012.GameplayIn Yu-Gi-Oh! Online players would start with a starter deck comprised of 40 to 60 cards. The duels themselves used the same up-to-date rules as the physical Yu-Gi-Oh! card game.Duelpass PointsIn order for players to be able to participate in a duel a Duelpass Point would have to be used. When a player first signed up for the game they would receive 10 free Duelpass Points. The Duelpass Points could be purchased in multiple ways.Online Duelpass OptionsThe first way to purchase Duelpass Points was to buy them digitally in packages called a Duelpass. A Duelpass came with 30 Duelpass Points, 10 Mileage Points and 1 random in-game card.Another digital bundle was called the Duelpass 150. A Duelpass 150 came with the contents of 5 entire Duelpasses. If the player purchased a Duelpass 150 they would be granted 150 Duelpass Points, 50 Mileage Points, and 5 in-game cards.Duelpass USB ThumbdriveA Duelpass USB ThumbdriveThe USB thumb drive was only available in the United States and Mexico and was sold at retail stores. Players could purchase the physical USB drive and on it was 3 Duelpasses. Also included in the package for the USB drive was a CD-ROM of the games installer, so players would not have to download the entire game off of the internet.Duelpass SMSThe final method of obtaining Duelpass Points was by SMS message. This service was only available for UK region players.Yu-Gi-Oh! Online: Duel EvolutionThe first major update to the game.When Yu-Gi-Oh! Online went through it's first major overhaul, the game was renamed Yu-Gi-Oh! Online: Duel Evolution. Included in the Duel Evolution update was the ability for a player to create their own avatars. These avatars could then be used to walk around and interact with NPCs in Domino City (from original Yu-Gi-Oh!) and the Duel Academy (from Yu-Gi-Oh! GX).Also updated were various parts of the games graphics including the UI, deck editor, and duel screens.Yu-Gi-Oh! Online: Duel AcceleratorThe Second and final update to the game.Yu-Gi-Oh! Online: Duel Accelerator was the second and final major overhaul done to Yu-Gi-Oh! Online. With this update it added lots of new cards and card types as well as added a new section for characters from the Yu-Gi-Oh 5Ds series.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="36373">Pokémon Trading Card Game Online</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/10/103881/2419046-duel_accelerator.png</image></root>