<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>236</id><name>The Revenge of Shinobi</name><description>OverviewThe opposing ninja clan from the original  Shinobi title, Zeed, has returned and renamed itself Neo Zeed. They seek revenge on  Joe Musashi and his clan.GameplayThe game is a 2-D  side scrolling beat-em up. Joe is armed with  shuriken for distance attacks and ninja magic to handle difficult bosses. He is armed with the Ninjitsu, or quite simply, Ninja Magic. The game consists of differing difficulty levels, with the higher difficulty levels having more enemies, less ability to handle damage, and fewer lives to start with.NinjitsuSpecial techniques that the player can use that can cause massive damage, increase mobility, and provide invulnerability.Ikazuchi, the Art of ThunderYou call upon Thunder to surround you with its protection. While enveloped in Ikazuch, you will not be injured and your Life Bar won't decrease. After taking several enemy hits, Ikazuchi fades away.Kariu, the Art of the Fire DragonAssume this jitsu to envelope yourself in a fire column, which then spits and travels, scorching every enemy it touches. Kariu is over when the fire columns disappear.Fushin, the Art of FloatingIncrease your jumping prowess with this jitsu. When you assume Fushin, your jumps and somersaults have maximun height and distance. Fushin stays with you until the scene ends, even if you assume another jitsu.Mijin, the Art of PulverizingBy assuming Mijin you become a human explosion that destroys everything in its blast. Use Mijin as a desperate resort, when your life bar is short. Mihin takes your life, so make sure you have another life remaining.CratesInside crates the player will find a variety of items, that will both help, or hinder their progress.Power PackIncreases your strength and adds to your weapons. You throw your Shurikins faster and more accurately, you gain a lethals sword for combat, and you apply the skill of Cross Guard, warding off enemy Death Stars with crossed Shurikins.5 ShurikinsYou gain 5 more throwing knives.20 ShurikinsYou acquire 20 more throwing knives.Small HeartYour Life Bar gains 2 small bars.Large HeartYour Life Bar increases to full strength.MusashiYou gain an extra life.NinjitsuNinjitsu (ninja magic) can be used again in the same life, even if you've used it already.BombAn explosive that detonates either when you touch it or its time runs down. Keep away from the blast!LegacyRevenge of Shinobi is somewhat well-known for some infamous instances of copyright infringement. The game had bosses who very closely resembled  Spider-Man,  Batman,  Godzilla   The Terminator. All Bosses were altered or replaced in later versions of the game: In version 1.01 Batman was replaced by a bat-like mutant, in 1.02 Spiderman is re-designed to look more like the character (because Sega was developing  The Amazing Spider-Man vs. The Kingpin for the Genesis at the time) also the bat creature is removed from the battle entirely, and in 1.03 Godzilla is replaced by a skeletal dinosaur. The copyright issues have been a major reason why the game is not often included in Sega compilation discs. The  Virtual Console version has a totally unique version where Spider-Man had a palette swap, but identical abilities (this is due to the license for using Spider-Man was for only limited time, that license is now owned by  Activision).SEGA AGESAs part of the SEGA AGES Online initiative, the game will hit Xbox Live Marketplace and PlayStation Network on May 23rd in Japan (as it's Japanese title, The Super Shinobi). For the PlayStation 3, the title is released for ¥600. For the Xbox 360, the title is released in a bundle with  Alex Kidd in Miracle World and  Super Hang-On for 800 MS Points.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14416">Ninja Gaiden II: The Dark Sword of Chaos</game><game id="13329">The Pirates of Dark Water</game><game id="11874">Ghostbusters</game><game id="12644">Ganryu</game><game id="34589">Super Ninja-kun</game><game id="40139">The Revenge of Shinobi</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2412948-box_trosgen.png</image></root>