<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23613</id><name>Guitar Praise: Solid Rock</name><description>OverviewThink there's too much "Sex drugs  Rock'n'roll Praise the Devil" in today's music? Don't want your children from being corrupted internally by Lou, the devil in digital form? Than Guitar Praise: Solid Rock is right for you and your family! From the guys who brought you Dance Praise 2: The ReMix, Solid Rock offers a wide selection of the best God-praising Christian music, all of which you can play along to with your blessed wireless holy guitar! Want to face off against Jesus, Mary, Moses or any of your other friends for that matter? Well, now you can, in the Face-off mode, where players can use power ups to send the power of god to their opponents in hopes that they become distracted!Key FeaturesIn terms of key features, Guitar Praise offers many of the same features offered by other leading games in the industry such as Guitar Hero and Rock Band. The game features over 50 songs which can be played on four different difficulty levels (easy to expert), online rankings and leaderboards and multiplayer with a bass guitarist. One feature which differes to that of Guitar Hero, is that despite no vocal support for the game, on screen vocals will appear which "reflect christian values".Track Listing12 Stones - BrokenBride - Same Ol' SinnerCaedmons Call - There You GoCasting Crowns - LifesongChris Tomlin - Made to WorshipDarrell Evans - So Good To MeDavid Crowder Band - Foreverandever Etc.Day Of Fire - Reap and Sowdc Talk - Jesus FreakFamily Force 5 - Love AddictFlyleaf - PerfectHawk Nelson - The ShowHawk Nelson - Friend Like ThatInhabited - Rescue MeIsrael  New Breed - All AroundJames Clay - Franklin ParkJared Anderson - Blind ManJennifer Knapp - Undo MeJeremy Camp - TonightJessie Daniels - What I HearJonah33 - Father's SongJosh Bates - Perfect DayKutless - Beyond the SurfaceKutless - Hearts of the InnocentLincoln Brewster - SpinNate Sallie - All About YouNevertheless - The RealNewsboys - Something BeautifulPaul Baloche - Rock of AgesPaul Baloche - All The Earth Will Sing Your PraisesPetra - Backsliding BluesPillar - When Tommorrow ComesRed - Breathe Into MeRelient K - I Need YouSeventh Day Slumber - AwakeSkillet - The Older I GetSkillet - RebirthingSkillet - SaviorSpoken - Wind In My SailsSpoken - Falling FurtherSpur 58 - SleepwalkersStellar Kart - ProcrastinatingSuperchick - We LiveThe Crucified - The PitThis Beautiful Republic - Going UnderThousand Foot Krutch - The Flame in All of UsThousand Foot Krutch - The Art of BreakingtobyMac - I'm For YouTodd Agnew - This Fragile BreathWarren Barfield - My Heart Goes OutWhitecross - Who Will You FollowWhitecross - When The Walls Tumble Down</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6311">Guitar Hero</game><game id="9860">Rock Band</game><game id="20673">Guitar Hero World Tour</game><game id="4031">Guitar Hero III: Legends of Rock</game><game id="14916">Guitar Hero II</game><game id="20639">Guitar Hero: On Tour</game><game id="20714">Rock Band 2</game><game id="20635">Rock Revolution</game><game id="7477">Phase</game><game id="21290">Tap Tap Revenge</game><game id="1529">King James Bible For Use On Game Boy</game><game id="24711">Guitar Hero 5</game><game id="5639">Quest for Fame</game><game id="25765">LEGO Rock Band</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4923/610468-guitar_praise.gif</image></root>