<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23621</id><name>Super Robot Taisen OG Saga: Endless Frontier</name><description>Gameplay The battle system is a timing and turn based battle system that is similar to previous Super Robot Taisen games. Outside of battle the play decides the combo that is to be done during battle. For instance, a Player decides to alternate between 2 styles of combo attacks. Then every time the attack button is pressed the character will initiate the next combo that has been set. The key to the combat is timing the button press and attack with keeping the enemy airborne. The turns are decided by basic speed stats where the character with the higher speed goes first. Once the turn has been initiated A character can do up to 5 combo attacks. The player can then press a button to switch to the next characters turn mid attack, as a sort of interruption. The character that then joins in begins their sets of combo attacks, once again having a full 5. The game also contains Special moves which when activated they cancel all actions then proceed to make a very flashy and powerful move. The damage is also concurrent with the number of the combo. The longer the player keeps the enemy in the air the more damage each attack will do. New combo attacks and special moves are unlocked with progression.FeaturesMultiple WorldsMechas controllable via the playerUnique Battle SystemCharacters  MechsProtagonistsHaken BrowningKaguya Nanbu                               Aschen BrödelSuzuka-Hime                                     KOS-MOSReiji Arisu      AntagonistsShutenKatze KotolnosKaldia BasirissaOtoneEzel GranadaHenne ValkyriaKyon FeulionAnne SirenaBonny MaxmadT-elosMechaGespenstAlt Eisen NachtWeiss Ritter AbendJyaki-GUN-OhArkGain</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23986">Shining Force Feather</game><game id="23693">Cross Edge</game><game id="9369">Namco x Capcom</game><game id="21400">Valkyrie Profile: Covenant of the Plume</game><game id="24247">Dengeki Gakuen RPG: Cross of Venus</game><game id="21445">Tales of Hearts</game><game id="21444">Tales of Innocence</game><game id="21376">Guilty Gear Dust Strikers</game><game id="25435">Dragon Ball Z: Attack of the Saiyans</game><game id="21446">Tales of the Tempest</game><game id="23983">Mario &amp; Luigi: Bowser's Inside Story</game><game id="9306">Mario &amp; Luigi: Superstar Saga</game><game id="15439">Mario &amp; Luigi: Partners in Time</game><game id="23669">Code Geass: Hangyaku no Lelouch</game><game id="29252">Keroro RPG: Kishi to Busha to Densetsu no Kaizoku</game><game id="29271">Negima!?: Chou Mahora Taisen Kattoiin, Keiyaku Shikkou Dechai masuu</game><game id="31284">Hyperdimension Neptunia</game><game id="37959">Project X Zone</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2478699-box_srtogsef.png</image></root>