<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23626</id><name>Amorous Professor Cherry</name><description>OverviewAmorous Professor Cherry was first developed and released for the PC in Japan as 微熱教師 ちえり (Japanese: Binetsu Kyoushi Cherry) by Zyx on September 24, 2004. It was later translated and released in the US by G-Collections on July 3, 2008.PlotI'm Kouta Koikawa, and I'm having a problem with my studies. It's not that my classmates' ruckus bothers me, I sit at the front of the room to avoid their antics. The real problem is my social studies professor, Chieri Hase. From the day she started teaching here I haven't been able to keep my eyes off her! She's a rookie teacher, but I'm captivated by every movement of her beautiful body. I can't work up the nerve to confess my feelings - I'm her student, after all, and I'm sure she wouldn't find this sort of forbidden love to be proper... until one day when fate brings us together in an encounter that changes our lives forever.HeroinesChieri HaseChieri HaseA rookie social studies professor at Kouta's school. While she's quite good looking, most men can't see past her glasses and plain fashion sense. Living the studious life until now she hasn't had much experience in the world, though she's heard a lot of stories from her best friend Mamiko... She's had a hard time getting her students to pay attention in class, so she's especially grateful for Kouta's devotion.Kiyoka YoriiKiyoka YoriiKouta's classmate. She's an honor student from a wealthy family, gifted with good grades and athletic ability - on top of which she's got great looks and is nice to just about everybody. She's the idol of the school, but her hidden side has a tremendous competitive streak.... When she falls for Kouta, who knows how far she'll go to win his affections away from Chieri?Mamiko KanaiMamiko KanaiA math professor who started work at Kouta's school the same time as Chieri. They've been friends since their college days, though unlike Chieri her bright personality and carefree attitude have won her plenty of welcome companionship. She enjoys her role as Chieri's mentor in the ways of the world, and her sexy looks make her quite popular among the students.GameplayAmorous Professor Cherry is heavy on narrative which will occasionally present an option of 2 or 3 choices which will lead to different story lines and affect the outcome of the story. Several scenes have simple animations.PC System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows 9564 MB RAMPentium II 264 MHzMIDI or DirectSound Soundcard16 MB Video CardRecommendedWindows 98128 MB RAMPentium III 300 MHzDirectSound soundcard64 MB Video Card</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="24400">Kangoku Suieibu: Kyouei Mizugi ni Kuikomu Inbi na Shitai</game><game id="23265">X-Change 3</game><game id="16531">X-Change</game><game id="992">X-Change 2</game><game id="24365">Cleavage</game><game id="14699">The Sagara Family</game><game id="23633">Pick Me, Honey!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4938/617756-cherry_ev023.jpg</image></root>