<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23648</id><name>Machinarium</name><description>PlotA little robot named Josef is discarded in a scrapyard and must find his way back into the city. Along the way, he'll escape his old tormentors (the Black Cap Brotherhood), foil their bomb plot, and rescue his robotic girlfriend. The plot is divulged through silent animated speech bubbles. If Josef is left idle, he will remember memories that flesh out the plot.GameplayMachinarium plays like classic 2D point-and-click adventure games. The player uses an inventory system and the world around him (or sometimes his robotic girlfriend) to progress through the game. To solve certain puzzles, the player can combine items in his or her inventory. The game takes place in a mechanical city that is divided into various screens. The screens are sometimes further divided into several smaller screens for dramatic and gameplay-related reasons.Machinarium differs from other point-and-click adventure games in that Josef has a cone of reach. In most adventure games, the player can simply click on any selectable item in the environment no matter where there character is. Usually, the character will simply walk over to the desired object and interact with it. In Machinarium, the player can only interact with objects within Josef's reach. Josef can alter his height to interact with elements of the environment otherwise out of reach.Both a simple and in-depth hint system are available: the former offers a single image that suggests the solution; the latter (unlocked after completing a short side-scrolling shooter minigame with a flying key) presents the complete puzzle formula.Console VersionsA PlayStation 3 version was released on September 6th, 2012 in Europe, being described as the ultimate version of Machinarium by Amanita Design. New features include a zoom function and trophies, as well as Playstation Move support.A Nintendo Wii version of Machinarium was cancelled in November 2011. Jakub Dvorský, founder of Amanita design, cited reasons such as the 40MB WiiWare download limit and the Wii's comparatively low resolution as reasons behind the cancellation.On September 8th, 2011, a tablet version of Machinarium was released on the iPad platform.The game comes to PlayStation Vita in North America on March 26 at a price of $6.99.ReceptionMachinarium won the award for Excellence in Visual Art at the 2009 Independent Games Festival, and was selected for the 'PAX 10', the ten best indie games of the Penny Arcade Expo as decided by a panel of 50 industry experts. Three days after release the game's Metacritic score was 83.SoundtrackLP Album CoverThe original score for Machinarium was composed by Tomas Dvorak and has been divided in two different releases:LP -- official soundtrack for saleEP -- official bonus tracks, free for download at the game's official website.LPTrack #Track TitleLength of Track01The Bottom5:3002The Sea3:5403Clockwise Operetta3:5404Nanorobot Tune3:0705The Mezzanine2:1506Mr. Handogote3:1707Gameboy Tune4:3708The Furnace2:5809The Black Cap Brotherhood Theme1:5010The Prison2:3411The Glasshouse With Butterfly3:3612The Castle3:3713The Elevator7:1314The End (Prague Radio)2:39EPTrack #Song TitleLenght of Track01The Robot Band Tune01.4702Pipe Wrench Dubstep02.3603Game In the Brain02.5604Defusing the Bomb02.0705By the Wall05.04System RequirementsPC requirementsOS: Microsoft® Windows® XP/Vista/7Processor: 1.8 GHz ProcessorRAM Memory: 1 GBHard Drive: 380 MB free spaceMac RequirementsOS: OS X version Leopard 10.5.8, Snow Leopard 10.6.3, or laterProcessor: Intel Mac 1.8 GHzRAM Memory: 1 GBHard Drive: 380 MB free space</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12860">Samorost</game><game id="20343">Samorost 2</game><game id="22111">The Whispered World</game><game id="10915">Beneath a Steel Sky</game><game id="28518">Axel &amp; Pixel</game><game id="19124">Full Pipe</game><game id="2368">Mr. Robot</game><game id="34256">The Tiny Bang Story</game><game id="35029">The Dream Machine</game><game id="35156">Lume</game><game id="35011">Botanicula</game><game id="20794">Wall-E</game><game id="39154">Unmechanical</game><game id="29133">Windosill</game><game id="5269">Oddworld: Abe's Oddysee</game><game id="39355">Primordia</game><game id="43014">Morphopolis</game><game id="44284">Journey of a Roach</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3699/1816768-machinarium.jpg</image></root>