<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23686</id><name>Mobile Suit Gundam: Gundam vs. Gundam Next</name><description>Units IncludedCurrently confirmed units in Mobile Suit Gundam: Gundam vs. Gundam NEXT. New units (not including those that debuted in the PSP version of                 Gundam vs Gundam) are marked with "(new)." Mobile Suit GundamGundam (                Amuro Ray) Guntank (                Hayato Kobayashi) Guncannon (                Kai Shiden) Char Custom Zaku (                Char Aznable) Dom (                Gaia) Acguy (Akahana) (new)  Mobile Suit Gundam: The 08th MS TeamGround Gundam Mass Production Type (                Shiro Amada)Gundam Ez-8 (                Shiro Amada) (new) Gouf Custom (Norris Packard)  Mobile Suit Gundam 0080: War in the PocketZaku II Custom (Bernard Wiseman) Gundam Alex (                Christina Mackenzie) Kampfer (Mikhail Kaminsky)  Mobile Suit Gundam 0083: Stardust MemoryGP-01 Zephyranthes (    Kou Uraki; becomes GP-01 Full Vernian after it is destroyed once) GP-03 Stamen (   Kou Uraki) GP-02 Physalis (Anavel Gato)  Mobile Suit Zeta GundamZeta Gundam (                Kamille Bidan) Gundam Mk. II (                Emma Sheen; can switch to Super Gundam at will)Gundam Mk. II Titans Colors (                Kamille Bidan) (new) Hyaku Shiki (                Quattro Bajeena) (new) Quebeley (                Haman Karn) (new)  Mobile Suit Gundam ZZZZ Gundam (                Judau Ashta) Quebeley Mk. II (                Elpeo Puru)Quebeley Mk. II Red (                Puru Two) (new) Hamma Hamma (Mashymre Cello) (new)  Mobile Suit Gundam: Char's CounterattackNu Gundam (                Amuro Ray ver. UC 0093) Sazabi (                Char Aznable ver. UC 0093)  Mobile Suit Gundam UnicornUnicorn Gundam (No Pilot) (new) Mobile Suit Gundam F91Gundam F91 (                Seabook Arno) Vigna Ghina (Cecily Fairchild)  Mobile Suit Victory GundamVictory 2 Gundam (                Uso Evin; can switch to Victory 2 Gundam Assault Buster for a limited time) Victory Gundam (                Uso Evin) Gedlav (                Katejina Loos) (new)  Mobile Fighter G GundamShining Gundam (                Domon Kasshu) (new)God Gundam (                Domon Kasshu) Master Gundam (                Master Asia) Gundam Spiegel (Schwarz Bruder) (new) Nobel Gundam (                Allenby Beardsley) (new)  New Mobile Report Gundam Wing(all designs use the TV version)Wing Gundam Zero (                Heero Yuy) Gundam Heavyarms Custom (Trowa Barton) Gundam Deathscythe Hell (Duo Maxwell) (new) Gundam Epyon (                Zechs Merquise) (new) Tallgeese (                Zechs Merquise) (new) After War Gundam XGundam X (                Garrod Ran)Gundam Double X (                Garrod Ran) (new) Gundam Virsago (Shagia Frost)  Turn A GundamTurn A Gundam (                Loran Cehack) Kapool (Sochie Heim) Turn X (                Gym Ghingnham) (new)  Mobile Suit Gundam SEEDStrike Gundam (                Kira Yamato)Freedom Gundam (                Kira Yamato; was originally part of Gundam SEED Destiny in the first game) Aegis Gundam (                Athrun Zala) Duel Gundam Assault Shroud (Yzak Joule; becomes standard Duel Gundam after "Armor Purge "attack) (new)  Mobile Suit Gundam SEED DestinyImpulse Gundam (                Shinn Asuka) Destiny Gundam (                Shinn Asuka) Strike Freedom Gundam (                Kira Yamato ver. CE 73) (new) Akatsuki (                Neo Roanoke; can switch between "Oowashi" and "Shiranui" packs in battle) (new)  Mobile Suit Gundam 00Gundam Exia (                Setsuna F. Seiei) Gundam Virtue (                Tieria Erde; becomes Gundam Nadleeh after "Armor Purge" attack) (new) </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23032">Mobile Suit Gundam: Gundam vs. Gundam</game><game id="27021">Real Robots Final Attack</game><game id="28190">Mobile Suit Gundam: Gundam vs. Gundam Next Plus</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/16207/624941-gundam_vs_gundam_2.png</image></root>