<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23695</id><name>Shadow Harvest: Phantom Ops</name><description>OverviewShadow Harvest: Phantom Ops is a third-person shooter created by German developers, Black Lion Studios and published by Viva Media. The game features two protagonists who can be switched at any time by the player in order to complete a variety of missions.PlotThe year is 2025 and as the world's natural resources are dwindling, warlords and dictators are rising to power in underdeveloped countries across the globe. Highly advanced, American-made weapons systems are finding their way into the hands of these warlords despite an official arms embargo. In response, ISA secret agent Captain Myra Lee and Delta Force operator Captain Aron Alvarez are put together under a new unit codenamed "Shadow Harvest" to find the source of these weapons and shut down both the dictators who wield them and the people who are supplying them. But as Lee and Alvarez dig deeper, they discover a global conspiracy that threatens to engulf them both.GameplayThe developers claim that Myra Lee and Aron Alvarez play differently, with "very specific and fully fleshed out sets of skills, preferences and abilities." Players can switch between Aron for a more combat-based solution or Myra for a more stealthy approach.LevelsPrologue: Fiery HorizonChapter 01: Mosquito VenomChapter 02: Silent AnvilChapter 03: Infernal SandsChapter 04: Mog RendezvousChapter 05: Welcome AboardChapter 06: Raging IntelligenceChapter 07: Tagged warlordChapter 08: Ping TrackerChapter 09: Malicious BlingChapter 10: Distress FlagChapter 11: Mala VistaChapter 12: Golden PromiseSystem RequirementsMinimum:OS: Windows XP / Vista / Windows 7Processor: Intel 3.2 GHz (or equivalent)Memory: 1GB of RAMGraphics Card: 256 MB nVidia GeForce 9600GT (or equivalent)Sound Card: DirectX compatibleHard Disk Space: 8 GBRecommended:Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo 2.2GHz / AMD Athlon 64 X2 4400 (or better)Memory: 2GB of RAMGraphics Card: nVidia GeForce 260 GTX / AMD ATI Radeon 4870 (or better)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1248">Syphon Filter</game><game id="20669">Metal Gear Solid 4: Guns of the Patriots</game><game id="5961">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell</game><game id="16140">Metal Gear Solid</game><game id="7004">Hitman 2: Silent Assassin</game><game id="14979">Mission: Impossible - Operation Surma</game><game id="12388">Metal Gear Solid 2: Sons of Liberty</game><game id="18082">Metal Gear Solid 3: Snake Eater</game><game id="9594">Metal Gear Solid: The Twin Snakes</game><game id="18599">Syphon Filter 2</game><game id="15691">Syphon Filter 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1849089-box_shpo.png</image></root>