<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23716</id><name>Hokuto no Ken: Hokuto Kami Denshoumono no Michi</name><description>StoryThe story takes place in the Hokuto No Ken manga which covers up to Raoh's story with a total of 22 chapters.Chapter 1: A Cry From the HeartChapter 2: Southern Cross!!Chapter 3: Gods' LandChapter 4: To the Depths of HellChapter 5: Kiba ClanChapter 6: Say My Name!Chapter 7: The Fake GeniusChapter 8: The City of Wailing DemonsChapter 9: An Ominous Star ExplodesChapter 10: The Man From NantoChapter 11: The Destiny of the Justice StarChapter 12: The Red Fangs of the Enchantment StarChapter 13: The Furious NantoChapter 14: Because of LoveChapter 15: Aim for the HeavensChapter 16: A Fated Rival!Chapter 17: A Sad Mad WolfChapter 18: The Goshasei Arrives!Chapter 19: An Offering to the Devil KingChapter 20: The Last General of NantoChapter 21: Farewell My Rival!Chapter 22: A Life Without RegretGameplayThe game takes the player through a bunch of manga panels. Sometimes, certain stylus actions are prompt on screen. When successful, the manga will go on. If not, the player must try again until he is successful, or he runs out of lives as shown by the big dipper constellation on the stop screen. During fight sequences, players must tap the hit marks shown on the enemies within a certain time frame. The longer the player goes on without missing (by inaccurate tapping) or running out of time, the better score he achieves. Eventually, the player may be able to control Rei with his Nanto Seiken style. Instead of tapping, you must stroke the stylus much like cutting with a knife to simulate the Nanto Seiken martial art.Game ModesThere are also games modes that can be played:VS ModeVital Point Striking BattleCharacter Illustration GuideThe Hundred Questions of HokutoFamous Lines Cards</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3564/633683-611rmbrovel.jpg</image></root>