<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2373</id><name>Freddi Fish and the Case of the Missing Kelp Seeds</name><description>OverviewFreddi Fish and the Case of the Missing Kelp Seeds is a childrens adventure game that was first released in 1994 for the Mac and PC platforms by Humongous Entertainment. It's success spawned four sequels and several spin offs. The game was lauded by critics and is considered a standard for childrens adventure games. PlotAt the beginning of the game we see Freddi Fish swimming to her Grandma Grouper's house. When she gets there she is horrified to learn that someone has stolen Grandma Grouper's magic kelp seeds. Without the seeds the entire area will got without food. Freddi proclaims that she will aide her grandma and find the missing kelp seeds. After making this heroic speech Freddi finds her best friend, Luther, and enlists him to help find the kelp seeds. Freddi and Luther save a small fish from a murderous rock.After mere minutes of searching the pair stumble upon a note that reveals were the kelp seeds are hidden. Meanwhile the two sharks who stole the seeds are searching for were they hid them. While one is confident that he left a series of notes that will help them remember where the seeds are the hidden the notes have already been found by Freddi Fish, but this is unknown to the sharks. After Freddi and Luther go to the location specified in the note they find another note pointing them in yet another direction.The dastardly sharks.This monotonous cycle continues for a while until they find out the treasure is on an old sunken ship. When they arrive at the ship they find that the treasure is being kept behind a window that is too heavy for them to open. In a different part of the ocean the sharks have consulted their employer, the Squidfather, but have been given no help. Fortunately the sharks miraculously remember and hastily swim towards the boat. By this time Freddi and Luther have gotten past the window and are about to take the seeds back to Grandma Grouper. But before any such thing can happen the sharks arrive and halt the moving of the seeds. Freddi and Luther plead their case and to their surprise the sharks are swayed by their logic and the seeds are returned.  Grandma Grouper is thrilled and no one ends up dying of starvation.GameplayFreddi Fish and the Case of the Missing Kelp Seeds is run on a streamlined version of the SCUMM engine. Instead of selecting actions the player only needs to click on an object to interact with it. This simplification makes the game much more accessible to younger gamers. All the items collected are gather in a small inventory shown at the bottom of the screen. To use an item the player must select the item and then the object they wish to use with the item. Voice ActorsFreddi Fish- Annette ToutonghiFreddi FishLuther- Michael McAuliffeGrandma Grouper- Haley AustinSharks- Jim Bach, Johhny Koenig</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="8">Educational</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14824">Spy Fox in "Dry Cereal"</game><game id="14441">Pajama Sam 2: Thunder and Lightning Aren't so Frightening</game><game id="11865">Professor Layton and the Curious Village</game><game id="3090">Fatty Bear's Birthday Surprise</game><game id="14961">Pajama Sam: Life is Rough When You Lose Your Stuff</game><game id="7900">Pajama Sam 3: You Are What You Eat From Your Head To Your Feet</game><game id="8430">Pajama Sam: No Need to Hide When It’s Dark Outside</game><game id="11177">Putt-Putt Joins the Parade</game><game id="931">Putt-Putt Travels Through Time</game><game id="3785">Putt-Putt Saves the Zoo</game><game id="10431">Putt-Putt Joins the Circus</game><game id="3136">Putt-Putt and Fatty Bear's Activity Pack</game><game id="15183">Putt-Putt Enters the Race</game><game id="13134">Putt-Putt Goes to the Moon</game><game id="13465">Spy Fox 2: Some Assembly Required</game><game id="5914">Spy Fox: Operation Ozone</game><game id="18816">Spy Fox in Cheese Chase</game><game id="18903">Pajama Sam: Games to Play on Any Day</game><game id="4615">Putt-Putt and Pep's Dog on a Stick</game><game id="19472">Fatty Bear's FunPack</game><game id="13791">Putt-Putt and Pep's Balloon-o-Rama</game><game id="22727">Spy Fox in: Hold the Mustard</game><game id="7793">Putt-Putt: Pep's Birthday Surprise</game><game id="17987">Pajama Sam: Lost and Found</game><game id="17824">Pajama Sam's SockWorks</game><game id="11852">Sam &amp; Max Hit the Road</game><game id="5729">The Curse of Monkey Island</game><game id="4372">Maniac Mansion: Day of the Tentacle</game><game id="14743">Blue's 123 Time Activities</game><game id="14412">Blue's Reading Time Activities</game><game id="17810">Blue's Clues: Blue's Art Time Activities</game><game id="11848">Blue's ABC Time Activities</game><game id="5784">Blue's Treasure Hunt</game><game id="16775">Blue's Clues: Blue's Birthday Adventure</game><game id="13230">Grim Fandango</game><game id="9345">Zack &amp; Wiki: Quest for Barbaros' Treasure</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8884/328259-freddifish1.jpg</image></root>