<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23778</id><name>Strong Bad's Cool Game for Attractive People Episode 3: Baddest of the Bands</name><description>StoryAfter his VidelectrixFun Machine breaks, Strong Badneeds to raise money to fix it. Strong Bad's solution to this problem is to hold a Battle Royale of the Bands to raise funds. Strong Bad's Battle Royale of the Bands requires security, celebrity judges, and of course actual bands to perform.Strong Bad convinces Strong Sad of the awesomeness of Security.By claiming that "Security" is a hot new band, Strong Bad manages to trick his brother Strong Sadinto working security for the concert. He also manages to create a kickass photo that he sends to Limozeen, winning a Limozeen photo contest and earning him a meeting with Limozeen.With the security and celebrity judges covered, all that's left is to get a few bands to perform. He helps Homestaraudition for Pom-Pom's band Pomstar, reunites Bubsand Coach Z''s band Two-o-Duo, and convinces the Cool Tapes to blow off a benefit concert for bats.However, once all the required bands have registered for the Battle Royale of the Bands Bubs deducts much of Strong Bad's earnings, and he still doesn't have enough money to fix the Fun Machine. Strong Bad's only option is to join the Battle Royale of the Bands himself, but unfortunately the only people still available are the King of Townand Homsar.The King of Town is carried off by fans, leaving Strong Bad alone on stage.Strong Bad's band D.O.I. fails to impress Limozeen at the Battle Royale of the Bands, which leaves Strong Bad with only one option: sabotage. After sabotaging the other three bands, Strong Bad returns to D.O.I. and gives the audience the most amazing performance they've ever seen. The King of Town is carried away by the crowd, D.O.I. wins the contest, and Strong Bad now has enough money to fix the Fun Machine. At home, Strong Bad can't play his game again. Strong Sad solved the problem which is areasol cheese spray inside the Limozeen game. The game ends with the game, Strong Bad and Strong Sad saying "Rock N' Roll, baby!"Limozeen's Hot Babelien OdysseyThe Videlectrixgame featured in this episode is Limozeen's Hot Babelien Odyssey.Limozeen's Hot Babelien Odyssey is based on the short-lived Saturday morning cartoonLimozeen: "but they're in space!". Players take control of the Space Machine tour bus, picking up women with a tractor beam and avoiding Nebulon.Strong Bad plays the game for a very short period at the beginning of the episode, and the game cannot be played again until after beating the episode.  PC Requirements Operating System: Microsoft® Windows® XP/Vista/Windows 7Processor: 2.0 Ghz or better (3 GHz Pentium® 4 or equivalent recommended)Memory: 512 MB RAM (1GB recommended)Hard Disk Space: 310 MBVideo Card: 64 MB DirectX® 8.1 compliant video card (128 MB recommended)Sound Card: DirectX® 8.1 sound deviceDirectX® Version: DirectX® Version 9.0c or better (DirectX updater included)Controller Support: Yes No internet connection required to play </description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5729">The Curse of Monkey Island</game><game id="11852">Sam &amp; Max Hit the Road</game><game id="13230">Grim Fandango</game><game id="10837">Bone: Out from Boneville</game><game id="10505">Bone: The Great Cow Race</game><game id="4372">Maniac Mansion: Day of the Tentacle</game><game id="6728">Zak McKracken and the Alien Mindbenders</game><game id="3019">The Secret of Monkey Island</game><game id="21174">Full Throttle</game><game id="2614">The Dig</game><game id="14748">Indiana Jones and The Last Crusade: The Graphic Adventure</game><game id="4399">Sam &amp; Max Episode 204: Chariots of the Dogs</game><game id="4720">Sam &amp; Max Episode 2: Situation: Comedy</game><game id="18560">Sam &amp; Max Episode 3: The Mole, the Mob, and the Meatball</game><game id="4797">Sam &amp; Max Episode 4: Abe Lincoln Must Die!</game><game id="7344">Sam &amp; Max Episode 5: Reality 2.0</game><game id="26779">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 4: The Trial and Execution of Guybrush Threepwood</game><game id="30008">Sam &amp; Max Episode 301: The Penal Zone</game><game id="9015">Sam &amp; Max Episode 202: Moai Better Blues</game><game id="30372">Sam &amp; Max Episode 303: They Stole Max's Brain</game><game id="30374">Sam &amp; Max Episode 305: The City That Dares Not Sleep</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4938/660830-logo.png</image></root>