<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23924</id><name>Spy Fiction</name><description>OverviewThe plot involves an evil terrorist organization's (called ENIGMA) plot to wreak havoc on the world with a flesh eating virus called Lahder, and cause it to bring about World War 3. You are a member of the the fictional Special Execution Agency (S.E.A.), part of their special Phantom Unit. Your mission is to stop ENIGMA from spreading the Lahder virus. The story is told in medias res (the first level is actually the final chapter), with the actual story beginning two months prior to the game's opening.CastMoriah Angeline as Sheila CrawfordErin Ashe as Kelly WongMarc Biagi as Various voicesRyan Drummond as MIchael KwanLani Minella as Eve and Alice ColemanDavid Mosby as Samuel BerkeleyJon Saint John as General Douglas LysanderJim Vollman as Dietrich Troy and Nicklaus NightwoodJeffrey T. Weaver as Dr. Kaysen and Various voicesChris Wilcox as Billy BishopProducer: Brian GlazebrookAssistant Producer: Aaron HabibipourTriviaBoth the gameplay and the plot contain numerous homages to famous pieces of "spy fiction" such as the 007, Mission: Impossible and Metal Gear franchises.The alert status is copied from Metal Gear Solid, and Metal Gear Solid 2. Instead of an Alert, Evasion, Caution, and Normal phase, it's Danger, Search, Caution, and Safety.Similar to Metal Gear Solid 2 and 3, the shoulder button allows the player to view the environment in the first person.Another feature from the Metal Gear Solid franchise that is present in game is optical camouflage, which renders the player practically invisible to the naked eye. This is available to the player from the very start of the game, it is activated by crouching against a wall and staying still. It can also be used in conjunction with the items that allow the player to cling to the ceiling.The vault scene from the Mission: Impossible movie is homaged. Wherein the player sprays coolant over their body to avoid setting off a temperature alarm, there's lasers that must be carefully navigated through, and player can't touch the floor. Their is also a level that copies Mission: Impossible's bullet train sequence.Both agents carry silenced Walther P99's. This is the same handgun that James Bond carries.This is Access Games first studio title. The same developer that is best known for the game Deadly Premonition.It is also the first game that Hidetaka Suehiro (better known as SWERY) directed.This game marks Forrest Kaysen's first appearance. He would go on to become a recurring concept for the developer, featuring in the mystery game Deadly Premonition as well. However, it should be noted that while the two share the same name and appearance, they are in fact separate characters, and there is no known direct story link between the two games.Another connection with Deadly Premonition is the character Lysander. Much like with the aforementioned Forrest Kaysen, there is a character named General Lysander in Deadly Premonition. Once again, they are different characters, despite sharing a name.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20464">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Conviction</game><game id="9594">Metal Gear Solid: The Twin Snakes</game><game id="457">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Double Agent</game><game id="21331">Tenchu Z</game><game id="9085">Vampire Rain</game><game id="14979">Mission: Impossible - Operation Surma</game><game id="16140">Metal Gear Solid</game><game id="20726">Quantum of Solace</game><game id="20488">Robert Ludlum's The Bourne Conspiracy</game><game id="15282">Tenchu: Fatal Shadows</game><game id="20669">Metal Gear Solid 4: Guns of the Patriots</game><game id="18082">Metal Gear Solid 3: Snake Eater</game><game id="10267">Metal Gear Solid 3: Subsistence</game><game id="12388">Metal Gear Solid 2: Sons of Liberty</game><game id="21654">Metal Gear Solid 2: Substance</game><game id="26817">Metal Gear Solid: Peace Walker</game><game id="14555">Metal Gear Solid: Portable Ops</game><game id="7501">Stolen</game><game id="17614">Rogue Ops</game><game id="2521">Critical Bullet: 7th Target</game><game id="9050">Kaena</game><game id="32093">James Bond 007: Blood Stone</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2080543-box_sfiction.png</image></root>