<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23962</id><name>Bowmaster Prelude</name><description>Overview  BowMaster Prelude is a flash game that can only be found online. It's a decently long game, and has a pretty fair amount of entertainment value. There's a nice amount of upgrades to keep you playing as well.  Gameplay The BowMaster You are the BowMaster. At the start of each level, you start in your castle. From there, depending on your shooting style, you fire the BowMaster's Bow, to defeat the oncoming waves of enemies. Each time you deal damage, you get 10 gold. You can purchase new things to fire from your bow after each level.   You win by either surviving all the waves on a level, or capturing the enemies flag, with units you can buy on the Upgrades screen, and bringing them all the way across to your side. You lose if the BowMaster dies, or if the enemy brings your flag all the way across to their side.  The BowMaster can leave the castle if you want. There are other places besides the castle in later levels, called towers. The advantage of the towers is just to be closer to the enemies and have a better angle to shoot.  You can leave a structure by pressing D to go right, and A to go left. And W to enter a structure. You can NOT enter the enemies castle.  All the arrows take time to recharge, depending on which arrow it is.   Shooting Styles  Auto Aim - Basically you point where you want the bow to shoot, and click, and it fires to that spot. Pretty basic and straightforward. Good accuracy. Point Aim - Angle from where the BowMaster is to where you want to shoot. Pull String - Wherever the BowMaster is, you click and pull back like a bow and it will fire at the angle you pulled it back at. Drag Anywhere -  Basically the same thing as Pull String, except for you can pull it back from anywhere.    Upgrades  Once an upgrade is purchased, it doesn't need to be purchased ever again.   Bow Upgrades   All the arrows take time to recharge, depending on which arrow it is. Some arrows require detonation, and they are detonated by hitting the SPACEBAR.  Basic Arrow - Free - The arrow you start off with. Very fast recharge time. Fire Arrow - 1000 Gold - An arrow that does fire damage and damage over time for a short time. Can be canceled by ice. Bomb Wave Arrow - 3000 Gold - Causes a wave of small explosions starting from where it landed. Comet Arrow - 5000 Gold - An Ice Comet hits the ground from where the Comet Arrow hits. Small delay from when the arrow hit, until when the Comet comes down. Fire Wave Arrow - 3000 Gold - Causes a wave of small fires starting from where it landed. Heal Wave Arrow - 1500 Gold -  Causes a wave of small healing plus symbols. Meant to heal purchasable units. Ice Arrow - 1000 Gold - An arrow that does ice damage. When in contact with an enemy, the enemy moves slower. Meteor Arrow - 5000 Gold -  A Fire Meteorite hits the ground from where the Meteor Arrow hits. Small delay from when the arrow hit, until the Meteor comes down. Thunder Arrow - 5000 Gold - A detonatable Thunder Cloud. Fire it into the air and press the SPACEBAR when ready. A Thunder Cloud will appear and strike lightning upon enemies underneath the cloud. Ice Wave Arrow - 3000 Gold - Causes a wave of small ice spikes starting from where it landed. Flak Bomb Arrow - 2000 Gold - A detonatable Flak Bomb. Good against flying enemies. Bomb Arrow - 2000 Gold - Huge explosion upon impact. Pierce Arrow - 3000 Gold - Goes through enemies in a row until it reaches the ground. Low damage upon multiple enemies if aimed correctly.   Unit Upgrades  Units will flow onto the screen to take on the enemies.  Archers - 1000 Gold - Allows archers to be used in battle. They can NOT capture the enemies flag. They deal Pierce damage. Foot Soldiers - 1000 Gold - Allows Foot Soldiers to be used in battle. They can capture the enemies flag. They deal Slice damage. Heavy Soldiers - 1500 Gold -  Allows Heavy Soldiers to be used in battle. They can capture the enemies flag. They deal Blunt damage. Horse Riders - 1500 Gold - Allows Horse Riders to be used in battle. They can capture the enemies flag. They deal Slice damage. Priest - 2000 Gold - Allows Priests to be used in battle. They can NOT capture the enemies flag. They heal allied troops. Trebuchet - 2500 Gold - Allows Trebuchets to be used in battle. They can NOT capture the enemies flag. They fire at enemy troops and the enemies castle, dealing Blunt damage.</description><genres /><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3614/704806-bm1.jpg</image></root>