<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2397</id><name>Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon: Advanced Warfighter</name><description>OverviewTom Clancy's Ghost Recon: Advanced Warfighter is the third installment of the Ghost Recon series. Various versions of this tactical shooter were released on Xbox 360, Xbox, PlayStation 2, and PC.PlotMexico D.F. (Districto Federal). The Ghosts have been ordered to participate in a joint operation designed to capture Mexican military officials engaged in illegal technology sales to Columbia's FARC rebels.The U.S. President has joined the Canadian Prime Minister and the Mexican President in the metropolis to sign the NAJSA (North American Joint Security Agreement), a policy to control illegal immigration and the movement of drugs and terrorists in the hemisphere. During the public signing of the document, the three leaders are attacked by Mexican soldiers. The Ghosts are ordered to meet up with Secret Service agents protecting the U.S. President and ensure his safety until he is extracted. While the U.S. President is on route to the Airport, the Ghosts secure the Mexican president. Thanks to the Ghosts actions, the Mexican president will "Green light" U.S. intervention on Mexican soil in order to bring back Democracy. Unfortunately, the U.S. President never reached the Airport and is now in enemy hands…GameplaySquad-based combat plays a significant role in GRAW. The player controls the Ghost leader, who's responsible for directing the actions of the squad, such as whether to move out or take cover, though the player still does the majority of the fighting. While more forgiving than past Ghost Recon games, with the ability to take more than one shot before dying, the player is unable to recover health during an active mission.Campaign MissionsContact!Coup D'etatVIP 2 is DownStrong PointMayday! Mayday!Ready for BearQuarterbackGuardrail IXBulldogFierce ResistanceNORAD on the LineReleasesThree versions of Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon: Advanced Warfighter were released.Xbox 360Developed by UbiSoft Paris for the Xbox 360, this version of the game is played from a behind the shoulder third-person perspective similar to Gears of War, but the player still has an option to switch to a first-person perspective. The third-person perspective allowed for a unique cover mechanic, where players are able to hide behind cover and see around or over walls.PCThe PC version of Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon: Advanced Warfighter was developed by GRIN, a Swedish game developer. This version is more attuned to the original Ghost Recon game by forcing a first-person perspective. The seemingly harder difficulty of this version was an effort to get fans of the original Ghost Recon games back into the series. The PC version also added more options for the player to issue commands to their squadmates by allowing the player to issue individual commands for each friendly AI.PlayStation 2  XboxThe PlayStation 2 and Xbox version was developed by UbiSoft Shanghai. Unlike past Ghost Recon games on these consoles, Ghost Recon: Advanced Warfighter is played from a strictly first-person perspective. Also unlike the Xbox 360 and PC counterparts, the PS2 and Xbox version only featured one friendly AI as opposed to three.ReceptionWhen the Xbox 360 version of the game was released it reserved very high reviews. The game was praised for it's smart A.I., immersive atmosphere, wide variety of weapons and believable storyline. The Xbox 360 version was also noted for it's very realistic graphics. GameTrailers gave it 9.9 out of 10, which is the highest review score GT has ever given out. It has a 91% average from reviews while the versions for the Xbox has a 66% average and the PS2 has 60%. The versions for the PS2 and Xbox was criticized for being watered-down. The graphics and lack of content was also a complaint.On October 5th, 2006, it won a BAFTA award for Game of The Year.System RequirementsAs written on the back cover of the boxMinimum System Requirements:Operating System: Windows 2000/XPProcessor: Pentium 4 2Ghz (2.8 recommended)Memory: 1GB recommended3D Card: DirectX 9.0c compliant Video Card, 128MB Shader 2.0 (256MB Shader 2.0 recommended)Direct X: DirectX 9.0cDVD ROM DRIVE: 4xSound Card: DirectX 9.0c compatibleHard Disk: 5GBXbox 360 Game InstallationTom Clancy's Ghost Recon: Advanced Warfighter requires 5.2GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD.DLCThe only DLC for GRAW is the Chapter 2 expansion. This contains:A new 4 mission co-op campaign set in Nicaragua and taking place after the main game's co-op campaign12 new multiplayer maps (including the 4 from the co-op missions)A new game mode called Team BattleNew weaponsNew camouflage patterns</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="178">ArmA: Combat Operations</game><game id="20676">SOCOM: U.S. Navy SEALs - Confrontation</game><game id="2444">Full Spectrum Warrior: Ten Hammers</game><game id="19874">Kane &amp; Lynch: Dead Men</game><game id="7288">SWAT 4</game><game id="14048">SOCOM 3: U.S. Navy SEALs</game><game id="21827">SOCOM: U.S. Navy SEALs - Combined Assault</game><game id="21414">Metal Gear Online</game><game id="7747">John Romero's Daikatana</game><game id="9993">Halo 3</game><game id="22960">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six: Lone Wolf</game><game id="15503">The Outfit</game><game id="20655">Battlefield: Bad Company</game><game id="18883">Enemy Territory: Quake Wars</game><game id="24442">NPPL Championship Paintball 2009</game><game id="12311">Delta Force: Black Hawk Down - Team Sabre</game><game id="20662">Gears of War 2</game><game id="20455">Haze</game><game id="25246">Battlefield: Bad Company 2</game><game id="25413">Lost Planet 2</game><game id="12098">Turning Point: Fall of Liberty</game><game id="24713">Modern Warfare 2</game><game id="30615">Gears of War 3</game><game id="1339">Star Wars: Republic Commando</game><game id="30185">Blacklight: Tango Down</game><game id="36230">Blacklight Retribution</game><game id="30813">The Bureau: XCOM Declassified</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2215045-box_graw.png</image></root>