<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>23985</id><name>WarioWare D.I.Y.</name><description>OverviewWarioWare: D.I.Y. (Made in Ore in Japan) is a DS game that allows users to create their own microgames, as well as records and comics. 90 pre-made microgames are be included with the game. Players are able to send game to friends, transfer them to WarioWare D.I.Y. Showcase on Wii, or upload their own microgames, music and comics to Nintendo as part of contests, and free games can be downloaded from the store every week. Up to 90 of each type of content (games, records, comics) can be stored on the DS cartridge.Creation (D.I.Y. Studio)Super MakerMatic 21Dr Crygor's invention, the Super MakerMatic 21, includes modes for creating games, music and comics, which are unlocked as the D.I.Y. 101 tutorials are cleared.Making each game takes the player through several steps:Name the game.Create Graphics, including backgrounds, objects and animations.Compose Music.Put them together and set up the AI and Win Conditions in the Assembly stage.Choose a cartridge design and Ship it to the Shop.The creation tools are similar to those found in Mario Paint. As well as microgames, players can make music tracks and 4-panel black and white comics using expanded versions of the music and graphics tools. These can both be shared the same way as microgames.D.I.Y. DataThe data screen tracks the player's stats, like Jobs Completed, Total Sales, Contest Entries, etc. It also displays all the unlocked medals. There are 120 medals to earn, for just about everything you can do in the game.D.I.Y. ForumsA forum where other Diamond City residents post. While the player cannot post here themselves, it contains some useful info regarding making games, D.I.Y. Showcase, internal politics at WarioWare, Inc. etc.Tutorials (WarioWare, Inc.)The game includes a robust set of tutorials and pre-made games to help players get to grips with the tools quickly.D.I.Y. 101: The main tutorial mode hosted by Penny Crygor; contains the core tutorials on making games, records and comics.Job Center: 16 games that Wario was too lazy to finish. These require the player to create graphics to finish them off.Assembly Dojo: Here, the player is presented with 32 challenges that require them to work out what AI must be used to make a set event happen. Unlocked by finishing the D.I.Y. 101 tutorials.Playing Games (D.I.Y. Shop)Players can use the Game Blender to play a random mix of microgames (like traditional WarioWare games) or pick a single microgame from the shelves to play on a loop.Diamond SoftwareFive characters have playable stages in the DS game, similar to how previous WarioWare titles worked. 90 pre-made microgames are split between them. Each character has a TV show that their stage is based around, rather than the the stories of previous games. Instead of an epilogue cutscene, a simple interactive animation is played after the boss stage.Mona: "Mona: Temple Explorer!" - Mona is trekking through the jungle with Joe when they stumble across an old temple. During the break, Mona sells treasure via a TV shopping channel.Jimmy T.: "Jimmy's Aerobics" - Jimmy is hosting his own exercise show. During the break, the animation shows his two sides (Funky and Fit). Unlike the other stages, a music track with vocals is played over the stage which overrides the microgame music.Ashley: "Magical Witch Ashley" - Ghosts film Ashley and Redd as they walk through the forest. During the break, Ashley shows off masks that re on sale at her Mask Emporium.Orbulon: "Diamond News" - As Diamond News covers the launch a of a new rocket, Orbulon's ship is struck by lightning and he falls into the nose of the rocket. As the rocket proceeds further through the atmosphere, scientists attempt to work out what's stuck int he rocket.9-Volt: "Super 9-Volt" - A Super Mario Bros. parody starring 9-Volt on his skateboard. After each Boss Stage, he completes the level by entering the castle.There are also two remix stages which mix together all the pre-made microgames. Instead of a TV show, the remixes use differently-colored Wario TVs.Shuffle: The games start at normal speed and get progressively faster. Unlocked once all Diamond Software microgames have been played.Ultra-Hard!: The games start at a very high speed. Unlocked by clearing 30 games in the Shuffle stage.D.I.Y. GamesD.I.Y. games are sorted into five categories labeled D.I.Y. 1-5 . The stage theme is the default blue Wario TV, however it can be changed to Mona, Ashley, Orbulon or 9-Volts stage theme once the Mix All mode is unlocked. Like the Diamond Software games there are two remix modes, Shuffle and Ultra-Hard! , which mix up all five sets of games.Mix AllThese three stages mix up both the pre-made and player-made game sets at once once. They are unlocked by clearing 15 games on Diamond Software's Ultra-Hard remix.Shuffle: The games start at a normal speed.Ultra-Hard!: The games start at a very high speed.Mirror: The games are played as normal but are flipped left-to-right. The game instructions are also flipped.Sales ChartsAlso viewable in the D.I.Y. Shop is the Sales Rankings board, which breaks down how the games are selling. Individual sales charts for each game can also be seen by tapping the book icon while browsing the shelves.Music  Comics (D.I.Y. Shop)MusicAs well as a Jukebox that allows the player to listen to multiple songs in a playlist, the game includes a record player to mess around with individual tracks. The five instrument/sfx channels can be toggled on and off, the player can skip between phrases or put a phrase on loop, apply filters and sound effects and adjust tempo and volume. Like with the games, each character has 18 records for a total of 90. Records are unlocked by earning medals in the D.I.Y. Studio.ComicsAs with the games and records there are 90 comics by Diamond Publishing divided into five sections, each by a different Japanese manga artist:Kotobuki ShiriagariIsami MakagawaSekaiichi AsakuraMasakazu AmahisaRei BetsuyakuThe comic viewer itself is fairly simple, with no extra features - the player simply taps through the pages and a small jingle is played at the start and end. A comic is unlocked in each section every day.Sharing (Distribution Center)Exchanging CreationsGames, comics and music can be exchanged with other DS consoles via local wireless, or sent to WarioWare D.I.Y. Showcase for Wii. Content can be sent between the North American and European versions of the game, but not the Japanese version.WarehouseEach player gets the ability to store two of each content type online in "crates" which registered friends can access via Nintendo Wi-Fi Connection. Up to 50 friends can be registered, either by exchanging friend codes or using local wireless.NinSoft StorePlayers can access the NinSoft Store to download new microgames. Nintendo released 2 new Weekly Games each Monday for 50 weeks, for a total of 100 games.In addition, Nintendo has partnered with a variety of "celebrities" such as game developers and published their microgames for download as Big Name Games. As well as Nintendo developers such as Sakamoto and Sakurai, many indie game developers have been recruited for the North American selection, such as Studio Pixel, WayForward, Gaijin Games, Team Meat and others. Big Name Games were released every week from launch until July 26 in North America, and then from December 6 until January 3. In Japan a mostly different selection of Big Name Games was offered, and were removed one year after release.Design ChallengesNintendo runs regular contests for players to enter. Each one has a theme (eg. "Sports", "Cute") and runs for around two weeks. Winning entries are then available for everyone to download and play for a limited time. Design Challenges are still being regularly posted in all regions. Successful Design Challenge entries are available to download in the Theme Games section for a limited time after judging has ended.Settings (Options Garage)As well as changing their name and brand name, the settings allow the player to delete their game data, switch between speaker and headphone sound, and test the mic. The credits minigame can also be played here, once the D.I.Y. 101 tutorials are completed. In the credits, the player can shoot down the UFOs that hold the names. Some require multiple hits, while most need only a tap. The alien can be shot down as he changes the heading too.WarioWare D.I.Y. ShowcaseReleased at the same time as the DS game, WarioWare D.I.Y. Showcase allows created games to be played on the TV. The Wii can store up to 72 of each type of content, though it features no creation tools. It also contains 72 exclusive microgames and 18 comics and records, new character stages like Wario-Man, and a 2-4 player multiplayer mode. The exclusive content can be sent to the DS game, but pre-loaded DS content cannot be sent to Wii.Complete Microgame ListingEvery pre-loaded microgame is listed below in the order they appear on the D.I.Y. Shop shelves. There are 95 premade microgames included on the cartridge (18 and a Boss Stage for each character) not including the 16 incomplete Job Center games or the 3 tutorial games. Each character has a theme that applies to all their games. The themes are actually the same as the ones from the original GBA game, bar Ashley's since she was introduced in Touched.Mona (Strange)All AflutterMy New BowStop That!Off-lineCrayon EpicThe IronyDrop  StopBug HuntEmoticubeTooth HasteDry EyeGold DiggerBig DripperStop LightJoker FaceI Saw It!BreakdownI Can Smash!Boss Stage: Fly 'n' FallJimmy T. (Sports)Micro GolfOff-FenceVolley GirlGoal in OneSpare Me!Swing BatterSync  Swim!Pumped PoserAlpine LinesPass, Shoot!Get Some AirDartistryOn Your MarkServed!Glove HurtsKickin' ItHurdling OnSmoooooooth!Boss Stage: ReflectingAshley (Food)Rice StuffedCake DefenceSnack SuckerKetchup DownMelon HoundCracked UpCooking BugShoot FruitFruit FansHarvest TimeFood ColorsPiece MealCone CatchSalad DazeTrue SkewerIce Pop StarDouble OrderFarm HandsBoss Stage: Bread TrapOrbulon (IQ)Breaking UpRhythm MakerFace FinderMind the GapCoin CatHouse PlantBird SearchGarlic/FronkSame DiffDance DudesWhich One?Circuit PathShaped LikeFollow AlongOdd NumberWin!/Lose!Head CountWhuzzat?Boss Stage: Wily Tiles9-Volt (Nintendo)ParatroopaFly SwatterSpinyStar FoxPikminShootingIce ClimbersUrban ChampExcitebikeYoshiTightropeGreenhouseShadow ShiftB. FightMetroidZeldaMario PaintT. BridgeBoss Stage: BlooperJob GamesAll 16 of these games are missing art that must be drawn in to complete the job. Many are remakes of older WarioWare microgames, and all of them feature Wario in some way.WarioQuestHit ParadeMob RuleCrazy CarPuzzled FaceNasalblasterSnapped ShotEggstractionManic MemoryFarm FreshFrozen FishMug ShotWarioQuest 2Dead RingerWario Is HOTSHHHHHHH!Tutorial GamesThese games are assembled by the player during the D.I.Y. 101 Lessons.LadybugBalloon POP!ButterfliesDownloadable Microgame ListingListed below is every game available to download from the NinSoft Store to date in North America. The same games are available for WarioWare D.I.Y. Showcase.Weekly GamesTwo of these were released every week for the first 50 weeks after launch.Dragon Duel [3/29/10]Color-Full [3/29/10] (Europe: Colour-Full)Fright Light [4/5/10]Finger-Flex [4/5/10] (Europe: Home Stretch)Matching Man [4/12/10]Snow Fall [4/12/10]Sky-Scrape [4/19/10]1-UP [4/19/10]Digital Daze [4/26/10]Rocky Road [4/26/10]Sink Whole [5/3/10]Multi-Fly [5/3/10]Braking News [5/10/10]Fossil Flop [5/10/10]Bubble Break [5/17/10]Wario Swarm [5/17/10]Eject Reject [5/24/10]Temple Trap [5/24/10]Cheer Check [5/31/10]Hue-Down [5/31/10]Soccer To Me [6/7/10] (Europe: Go On My Son)Flycatcher [6/7/10]Power Grill [6/14/10]Laser Aliens [6/14]10]Stop Them! [6/21/10]Stop Thief! [6/21/10]Count 'Em Up [6/28/10]Mario Maze [6/28/10]Sleeper Swat [7/5/10]Zoo Zounds [7/5/10]Pencil Pinch [7/12/10]Eggplant Fog [7/12/10] (Europe: Aubergenie)Sumo Robots! [7/19/10]Bear Afoot [7/19/10]Maze Maestro [7/26/10]Water Drop [7/26/10]Falling Eggs [8/2/10]Watchful "I" [8/2/10]Memory Blobs [8/9/10]Beam Me Out [8/9/10]Cakesplitter [8/16/10]Saving Rain [8/16/10]Roach Blast [8/23/10]Rhythm Count [8/23/10]Fried Shrimp [8/30/10] (Europe: Fried Prawns)Switch Back [8/30/10]Mountennis [9/6/10]Toppings! [9/6/10]Polterball [9/13/10]Squid Lunch [9/13/10]Bird Breath [9/20/10]Ready, Aim [9/20/10]Jump Jets [9/27/10]Ladies' Man [9/27/10]Fan Boys [10/4/10]Kickback [10/4/10]Bun Blitz [10/11/10] (Europe: Service-ice)Volume Deal [10/11/10]Tissue Trap [10/18/10]Fish  Game [10/18/10]Lost Child [10/25/10]Box  Blocks [10/25/10]Hare Raising [11/1/10]Go, Dad! [11/1/10]Donut Wholes [11/8/10]Masterpiece [11/8/10]Matador-able [11/15/10]Apple Thief [11/15/10]Penguin Chow [11/22/10] (Europe: Penguin Grub)Blob Blast [11/22/10]Bulb Change [11/29/10]Boxed Up [11/29/10]Perform Ants [12/6/10] (Europe: Perform-Ants)Weigh of War [12/6/10]Blown Away [12/13/10]Art Practice [12/13/10]Winding Up [12/20/10]How Low? [12/20/10]Sheep Hunt [12/27/10]Gator Bites [12/27/10]Thirsty? [1/3/11]Sonar Sea [1/3/11]My Boyfriend [1/10/11]...Surprise! [1/10/11] (Europe: Intruder)Deflect Beam [1/17/11]The Big Race [1/17/11]Mouse Hotel [1/24/11]Keep Walking [1/24/11]Line Connect [1/31/11]Ugly...Bird [1/31/11]Cowabunga? [2/7/11]Final Battle [2/7/11]Blob  Key [2/14/11]Rock Hard [2/14/11]Chute, Score [2/21/11]Dating 101 [2/21/11] (Europe: Date Spot)Tennis Pro [2/28/11]Hideout [2/28/11]Goombas [3/7/11]Bird  Beans [3/7/11] (Europe: Pyoro)Big Name GamesThese games feature an exclusive gold, star-shaped cartridge. Japan received a completely different set of Big Names Games which which have now been removed from the store, with the exception of except Sakurai and Sakamoto's games which are permanent.Metroid [3/29/2010 - Yoshio Sakamoto of Sora]Line Slash [3/29/2010 - Masahiro Sakurai of Nintendo]Suck Goo! [4/5/10 - Ron Carmel of 2D Boy]Ikachan [4/5/10 - Daisuke Amaya of Studio Pixel]Fire Bad! [4/12/10 - Alex Neuse of Gaijin Games]Shantae NAB! [4/19/10 - Matt Bozon of WayForward]MEAT BOY [4/26/10 - Edmund McMillen of TEAM MEAT]Fly Home! [5/3/10 - Todd Lewis of 5th Cell]SayThatAgain [5/17/10 - Gary, co-host of Nintendo Week - only in North America]LUNCH BREAK [5/17/10 - Alison, co-host of Nintendo Week - only in North America]Funky Boxing [5/24/10 - Chris Slate, editor-in-chief of Nintendo Power - only in North America]Revenge [5/31/10 - Steve Thomason, executive editor of Nintendo Power - only in North America]Power Surge [6/7/10 - Chris Hoffman, editor at Nintendo Power - only in North America]ChronosTwins [6/14/10 - Julio Moruno of EnjoyUp Games]Ice Cream [6/21/10 - Nintendo of America's Treehouse team - only in North America]Walkies [6/28/10 - Nintendo of America's Treehouse team - only in North America]Hungry Robot [7/5/10 - Nintendo of America's Treehouse team - only in North America]Cow Swat [7/12/10 - Nintendo of America's Treehouse team - only in North America]Wing Man [7/19/10 - Nintendo of America's Treehouse team - only in North America]InterMission [7/26/10 - Nintendo of America's Treehouse team - only in North America]MAx [12/6/10 - Bo Strandby of Press Play]OM NOM NOMS! [12/13/2010 - Fabian Akker of Ronimo]Toki Drop [12/20/2010 - Collin van Ginkel of Two Tribes B.V.]Jett Rocket [12/27/2010 - Manfred Linzer of Shin'en Multimedia]AndYetItMovs [1/3/2011 - Felix Bohatsch of Broken Rules]Present Day! [12/24/2010 - "Nick" (Santa Claus) - only in Europe]It's Cold! [12/31/2010 - "Nick" (Santa Claus) - only in Europe]Theme GamesThese user-submitted games are only available for a limited time. Each theme contains 48 microgames, chosen from entries to the Design Challenges and conforming to a certain theme set for each, like Sports, Back  White or Auto-Name. As of 2/27/11, there have been 16 Themes in North America and 28 in Japan.</description><genres><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8791">Mario Paint</game><game id="20602">LittleBigPlanet</game><game id="24930">Flipnote Studio</game><game id="6282">Drawn to Life</game><game id="25161">Spore Galactic Adventures</game><game id="38824">McPixel</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1887917-box_wwdiy.png</image></root>