<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24025</id><name>Scratch: The Ultimate DJ</name><description>OverviewScratch: The Ultimate DJ is a rhythm game originally developed by 7 Studios before development responsibilities were passed to Commotion Interactive. It claims to allow players flexibility and creativity bucking the rhythm gaming trend of rigid emulation of available songs.GameplayThe game is played using an accessory, the Scratch Deck, designed by Numark, a renowned manufacturer of professional audio equipment. It consists of a turntable along with five color-coded buttons lined up horizontally and a cross-fader. Each button is assigned to play a sample even if they are pressed at a time when that sample is not required, giving the player an opportunity to improvise and create actual music rather than simply emulating the actions used to play a static background track.Soundtrack2Pac - Niggaz NatureBeastie Boys - IntergalacticBlack Eyed Peas - Let's Get It StartedDeltron 3030 - MastermindDilated Peoples - This WayDr. Dre - The Next EpisodeEric B.  Rakim - Don't Sweat the TechniqueGorillaz - Feel Good Inc.Kanye West - Flashing LightsKelis - MilkshakeKid Koala - Skanky PankyThe Knux - Life In A CageMurs - Looking FlyN.A.S.A. - Gifted (feat. Kanye West, Santigold, Lykke Li)Nelly - Hot In HerreOutkast - Flip Flop RockOutkast - The Way You MovePete Rock  C.L. Smooth - They Reminisce Over YouRJD2 - Iced LightningRun DMC - Peter PiperSalt n Pepa - Push ItShop Boyz - Party Like a RockstarTech N9ne - SlackerWhodini - FriendsConfirmed ArtistsSnoop DoggMixmaster MikeDelayLegal problems surrounding the game's developer along with their purchase and a reassignment of the game to a different studio have caused the game's anticipated release to be adjusted from September '09 (beating DJ Hero to market) to a more vague estimate of "early 2010." In the meantime, developers are working on an updated art style and additional tracks for the release.</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23882">DJ Hero</game><game id="21171">Lips</game><game id="27000">DJ Mix Tour</game><game id="26554">Armin van Buuren - In the Mix</game><game id="29778">DJ Hero 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/578/1154492-scratch_ultimate_dj.gif</image></root>