<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24218</id><name>Sonic's Ultimate Genesis Collection</name><description>General infoMSRP: $29.99All games (except for Zaxxon and Congo Bongo) can be played in either 4:3 or 16:9 ratio. The game also comes with a "smoothing filter", which makes the games look less pixelated.Each game has three "state save" slots, which allows you to save your game at any time.Each game has an art gallery, featuring the box art as well as the cartridge.Includes a trivia section.Video interviews with some of the games creators.There is local multiplayer only, no online multiplayer is available.Included Games:Alex Kidd in the Enchanted CastleAlien StormAltered BeastBeyond OasisBonanza Bros.ColumnsComix ZoneDecap Attack starring Chuck D. HeadDr. Robotnik's Mean Bean MachineDynamite HeaddyEcco the DolphinEcco II: The Tides of TimeE-SWATFatal LabyrinthFlickyGain GroundGolden Axe IGolden Axe IIGolden Axe IIIKid ChameleonPhantasy Star IIPhantasy Star III: Generations of DoomPhantasy Star IV: The End of the MillenniumRistarShining in the DarknessShining ForceShining Force IIShinobi III: Return of the Ninja MasterSonic 3D BlastSonic and KnucklesSonic SpinballSonic the HedgehogSonic the Hedgehog 2Sonic the Hedgehog 3Streets of RageStreets of Rage 2Streets of Rage 3Super Thunder BladeVectormanVectorman 2Unlockable Games:The following games are unlockable. Contrary to the name of the game, they are either Master System, or Arcade games.Altered Beast (Arcade)Unlock by earning 100,000 points in stage one of Altered Beast (Genesis)Alien Syndrome (Arcade)Unlock by completing stage one and two of Alien Storm without dying.Congo Bongo (Arcade)Unlock by finishing stage one of Streets of Rage 3 with all three characters.Fantasy Zone (Arcade)Unlock by earning 80,000 points in Flicky.Golden Axe Warrior (Sega Master System)Unlock by using magic ten times in Golden Axe III.Phantasy Star (Sega Master System)Unlock by finishing act 1 of Sonic the Hedgehog 2 with two players.Shinobi (Arcade)Unlock by finishing stage one of Shinobi III: Return of the Ninja Master without dying.Space Harrier (Arcade)Unlock by earning 1,500,000 points in stage one of Super Thunder Blade.Zaxxon (Arcade)Unlock by collecting five coins in Decap Attack starring Chuck D. Head.MultiplayerThe following games support co-op:Alien StormAltered BeastBonanza Bros.Gain GroundGolden AxeGolden Axe IIGolden Axe IIISonic the Hedgehog 2Sonic the Hedgehog 3Streets of RageStreets of Rage 2Streets of Rage 3Versus Games:ColumnsDr. Robotnik's Mean Bean MachineGolden AxeGolden Axe IIGolden Axe IIISonic SpinballStreets of RageStreets of Rage 2Streets of Rage 3</description><genres><genre id="15">Compilation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1671">Midway Arcade Treasures 3</game><game id="14457">Sega Genesis Collection</game><game id="2138">Capcom Classics Collection</game><game id="7740">Midway Arcade Treasures 2</game><game id="18579">Midway Arcade Treasures</game><game id="461">Capcom Classics Collection: Volume 2</game><game id="12200">Sega Classics Collection</game><game id="3340">Sega Smash Pack</game><game id="282">Rockman Complete Works: Rockman</game><game id="25349">SEGA AGES 2500 Vol.32: Phantasy Star Complete Collection</game><game id="3902">Capcom Classics Collection Remixed</game><game id="9500">Capcom Classics Collection Reloaded</game><game id="2949">Atari Arcade Hits: Volume 1</game><game id="26604">Atari Anthology</game><game id="30227">Arcade Action</game><game id="10958">Activision Hits Remixed</game><game id="6359">Intellivision Lives!</game><game id="10965">EA Replay</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14036/890367-sonic.jpg</image></root>