<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24324</id><name>Natural Selection II</name><description>OverviewIn October 2006; the newly founded company,  Unknown Worlds, officially announced that it was developing Natural Selection 2. Charlie Cleveland and Cory Strader (Natural Selection creators) will be continuing their work on the new game. On December 1 2006, Unknown Worlds, announced on their development blog, the first major feature, named " Dynamic Infestation."On July 10 2008, Unknown Worlds announced their move from the Source Engine to an  in-house developed engine. However, fans of the game were worried that going from the stable  Source Engine to a new engine would delay the game. The creators stated that making the switch was the right call. This was because, at that time, most of the new engine was already completed, and Natural Selection 2 was on schedule for launch.GameplayAfter joining a player run server, you will be able to walk around in an area known as the Ready Room. This room is used for after round banter and team selection. The three options in the room are Marines, Aliens, and Spectator.Marines start the game with a Command Station and an Infantry Portal (spawns Marines.) Once a player decides he wants to command the team, he will jump in the Command Station. The Marine Commander is unique in that his view changes to a top-down perspective ala  Starcraft. He can then drop buildings, health, ammo, and scan the area for aliens. While the commander supports, Marines are the ground are sent out to kill and take resource nodes.Resources nodes are important to each team as it will provide money for the individual player (PRes) as well as the commander (TRes). A Marine can use his PRes to purchase different weapons from the Armory while Aliens can evolve into different life forms. TRes is used by the commander to purchase buildings and upgrades for the team.Aliens start the game with a Hive, Eggs, and three Drifters. The Hive is the equivalent to the Marine’s Command Station and will provide the person with a top down perspective. Unlike the Marine Comm, the Alien Comm duties are slightly different. In order to take resource nodes or another Hive, the Alien Comm has to spread infestation throughout the map by dropping Cysts. Infestation allows Aliens to move faster and will slow down Marines. In addition, the Alien Comm does not need players to build the teams structures (although Gorges can help out.)In order for any team to win, all Hives or Command Stations must be destroyed.Aliens/KharaaSkulkAll Kharaa start off as the Skulk. The Skulk moves fast on four legs and can climb walls to take advantage of ambushes and alternate passage ways such as vents.Primary Attack - Bite: The crushing power of a Skulk's jaw comes down on an unfortunate foe.Ability - Parasite: A projectile is shot at an opposing player therefor making them viewable at all times on the map.Augmentation Tier 1 Attack - Leap: With the power of all four legs, the Skulk can launch himself at his enemies.GorgeThe Gorge is the helper class for the Kahraa commander. Gorges can heal and build structures to help secure victory. He can also slide on his belly.Primary Attack - Spit: A green ball of corrosive slime slowly kills anything it touches.Secondary Attack - Heal Spray: Releasing fluids, the Gorge can heal any wound inflicted on an ally or structure. Healing a structure also decreases its build time.Ability - Build: The Gorge can choose to build a set number of two different structures. Up to 3 Hyrdas (projectile flower plants), and up to 10 Clogs (green balls that can be built up like a fort.)Augmentation Tier 1 Attack - Bile Bomb: A sack of corrosive liquid is dropped on structures and foes below doing damage over time.LerkLerks are kings of the sky. They can fly around the map and cause mayhem using guerilla warfare.Primary Attack - Spikes: From the sides of their mouths, Lerks can shoot spikes in rapid succession.Ability - Toxic Gas: As the Lerk flies, it can release a deadly toxin gas that will confuse sentry turrets and slowly choke a player to death.FadeA teleporting Kharaa with two scythe-like blades for hands.Primary Attack - Swipe: With one scythe after another, the Fade turns into a meat grinder.Augmentation Tier 1 Movement - Shift: A teleport with the power to propel the Kahraa upwards.OnosThe Kharaa power house. With it's huge size, the Onos is the equivalent of a living Tank.Primary Attack - Gore: Uses the horn on the front of it's head to attack.Augmentation Tier 1 - Stomp: Two front legs come down creating a shockwave disabling players and structures.MarinesThe marines do not have different classes like the Kharaa. Instead they have a variety of weapons and items they can purchase to give them access to new abilities. Items can be purchased with personal resources or the marine commander can use team resources and purchase items for an individual.Switch-AxeThis is the Marine's last-resort melee weapon.Cost: FreeThe Switch-Axe deals double damage versus structures.PistolThis is the Marine's standard secondary weapon. The pistol does a moderate amount of damage with high accuracy.Cost: FreeHolds 10 round clips, with each marine starting with 5 reserve clips.Assault RifleThis is the starting weapon for every newly spawned Marine.Cost: FreeAlternative attack: Attack with the butt of your gun in order to do a small amount of melee damage. If used on a jumping skulk it can stun the skulk for several seconds.Benefits from the weapon damage researchShotgunThis weapon can be researched early, and is a large improvement over the Light Machine Gun, especially at close quarters.Cost: 20 resourcesHolds 8 shotgun shells at one timeGrenade LauncherThe Grenade Launcher fires a powerful grenade over a moderate distance, effectively giving the wielding Marine siege capabilities.Cost: 25 resourcesSimilarly to the Switch-Axe, the Grenade Launcher does double damage to structures.Detonation can trigger on impact on a hostile target.Clips contain 7 grenades.FlamethrowerThe Flamethrower is a powerful area-clearing weapon, which can set any alien lifeforms and structures on fire.Cost: 25 resourcesDeals 5x damage to Cysts and Clogs.Flaming aliens have a decreased energy regeneration rate.Instantly burns away gasses such as Spores and Umbras.Very effective in removing infestation in general.MinesCost: 15 resourcesSold in packs of 3 mines which can be placed anywhere on the map.Useful for protecting buildings and outposts from roaming aliens.WeldersCost: 5 resourcesWelders are needed to repair buildings and restore armor to other marines.Having several marines with welders following exosuits for repairs is a popular late game strategy.ExosuitThe exosuit is the most powerful weapon at the marines' disposal. The exosuit has infinite ammo and instead has a weapon that can overheat if used too much. When inside the exosuit the marine loses his personal health pool and instead just has a large amount of armor. This means they are more susceptible to anti-armor attacks such as the the gorge's bile bomb.Cost: 50 resourcesResearch Upgrade Dual Miniguns - The exosuit gains access to a second minigun with it's own overheating bar. When properly controlled the dual exosuit can fire bullets indefinitely. Note: Once you buy the exosuit you cannot upgrade to the dual minigun version.ExtendabilityThe game will ship with a powerful editor in which you can script and create your own mods, weapons and scenario's. All the editor tools the developer used to create the content is available like a level editor, a cinematic tool and the full source code of all scriptable objects in Natural Selection 2. The game was mostly written using the standard  LUA language and is therefore heavily moddable.The game will be part of Steam  Workshop to easily add and get the modded files.Organic Indie Pre-order PackOn January the 6th 2010,  Unknown Worlds teamed up with  Wolfire Games to make a pack available for pre-order. This pack contained  Overgrowth and  Natural Selection 2 available for $40, saving the consumer money if they were planning to buy either of the games. On top of this offer, anyone who had already pre-ordered Natural Selection 2 or Overgrowth was given the other game for free if they redeemed their code in the set time period. The pre-order pack offer closed on January 13th 2010.PC System RequirementsMinimumOS:Windows 7 32/64-bit / Vista 32/64 / XPProcessor:Core 2 Duo 2.6 ghzMemory:2 GB RAMGraphics:DirectX 9 compatible video card with 1GB, ATI X800, NVidia 8600 or betterDirectX®:9.0Hard Drive:5 GB HD spaceRecommendedOS:Windows 7 32/64-bit / Vista 32/64 / XPProcessor:Core 2 Duo 3.0 ghzMemory:4 GB RAMGraphics:DirectX 9 compatible video card with 1GB, AMD 5770, NVidia GTX 450 or betterDirectX®:9.0Hard Drive:5 GB HD spaceOther Requirements:Broadband Internet connection</description><genres><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="240">Natural Selection</game><game id="26532">Aliens vs. Predator</game><game id="4666">Aliens Online</game><game id="29601">Nuclear Dawn</game><game id="11254">Savage 2: A Tortured Soul</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2343148-2.png</image></root>