<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2436</id><name>Dynomite Deluxe</name><description>OverviewDynomite is a puzzle game wherein the player clears levels by destroying all the eggs on the playing field. To do this, a player must match like-colored eggs by firing from a cannon at the bottom. Players are rewarded extra points for increased eggs above the minimum number to match, as well as collateral damage by disconnecting other eggs from the main block (if an egg is not connected to the main egg pile, it is automatically destroyed regardless of whether or not it was matched). Sticks of dynamite are also present amongst the eggs, which indicate available matches to be destroyed for the player.. Dynomite has four game modes, three difficulty levels, and a tutorial.Game ModesEndless PuzzleIn this game mode, the player must keep a slowly descending pile of eggs from passing below the warning line near the egg cannon. As you clear eggs faster, the egg pile begins to descend faster. But as the eggs get closer and closer to the bottom, the egg pile will slow down. An hourglass on the right side of the screen slowly ticks down at a fixed rate as the game progresses; when it runs out, a bird named Whirly will appear and fly to the top of the screen, adding an egg color not present on the screen; making matches more difficult for the player. Firing an egg at Whirly will prevent this, but the player can not shoot through other eggs to do so, and the puzzle will also speed up slightly. Allowing Whirly to reach the top of the screen will slow the puzzle down again. This allows the player the choice of a faster puzzle by shooting Whirly and clearing eggs quickly, or a slower puzzle by allowing him to reach the top and giving the players additional eggs to clear.Stomped PuzzleIn this game mode, the player must clear a predetermined egg arrangement. There is no hourglass and hence no real "time limit;" in it's place is a temper gauge of Mama dinosaur.. Firing eggs will raise this temper gauge slowly; when it fills up, Mama will "stomp" the level and lower the roof level, bringing the egg arrangement closer to the warning line at the bottom and resetting the gauge.Fossil ChallengeThe goal in this game mode is for the player to dislodge a fossil within a predetermined egg arrangement by matching the eggs directly around it. Two modes are available within Fossil Challenge; Strategic and Panic. In Strategic mode, an hourglass on the right side of the screen slowly runs down; when it does the entire puzzle is lowered a bit closer towards the player. In Panic mode, the eggs are lowering constantly at a fixed rate towards the warning line at the bottom; there is also an hourglass running down, but in this mode it will speed up the rate at which the eggs lower. Completing levels in this game mode gives the players fossils for their museum, measuring their progress and seeing how many fossils they have left to obtain.Time TrialIn this game mode, the player is given a fixed number of egg rows to clear and is scored based on how quickly they clear them all. There is no time limit, and eggs passing by the warning line in this game mode will simply add an additional row to clear.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4641">Snood</game><game id="14228">Bust-A-Move</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/10/103881/2181589-dd.jpg</image></root>