<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2444</id><name>Full Spectrum Warrior: Ten Hammers</name><description>OverviewFull Spectrum Warrior: Ten Hammers is a squad based shooter that involves little shooting on the players part as the majority of the game consists of moving two accompanying squads around the map. However, the game did continue to iterate on the mechanics established by the original Full Spectrum Warrior. New editions include the ability to divide fire teams into smaller teams of two and deploy troops inside of buildings.StoryThe story begins six months after the fall of the Zekistani regime as allied forces cope to ease the transition toward democratic government. The core story focuses on the efforts of American, UN, British and National Militia forces to quell sectarian division in the country. The seeds of civil war in Zekistan are being sown by Mullah Abdul Hassan, the leader of the Mujahideen. The narrative is broken up into four chapters consisting of three levels each.The first chapter revolves around the seasoned Sergeant Santiago Mendez and rookie Sergeant Thomas Randolph as they fight their way to the Tien Hamir Monastery to save a captured American Sergeant. However, upon arriving at the monastery both Mednez and Randolph discover the body of Sergeant Eric Daniels in a nearby shed.The second chapter revolves around the British forces in Zekistan as the player is given control of squads led by Sergeant Brian Sims and Sergeant Hyde who are tasked with capturing the Tien Hammir Bridge. This chapter actually precedes the events of chapter one as the player assists Sergeant Daniels repel insurgents before capturing the Tien Hammir Bridge itself.The third chapter centres on Sergeant Daniels and his mission to destroy stockpiled weapons at a nearby boathouse. After destroying the ship loading cranes and weapons at the boathouse, Daniels is redirected to assist nearby British forces in neutralizing enemy artillery stationed near the Tien Hammir Parliment building. The chapter ends with a miscalculated Allied air strike that kills two members of Daniel's squad.The fourth and final chapter focuses on a disoriented Sergeant Daniels in the immediate aftermath of the botched air strike. Daniels is able to form a slapdash squad amongst the confusion in order to escort a bus filled with wounded soldiers and civilians through hostile territory and back to friendly lines. While en route to friendly lines, Daniels and his squad locate two MIA American soldiers, Corporal Picoli and Private Ota, but are surprised by an insurgent attack that rapidly overruns the Tien Hamir Monastery. During extraction via helicopter, Daniels decides to make the ultimate sacrifice and hold off the attackers rather than preserve himself.System RequirementsMinimum: Windows 2000/XP (only), AMD Athlon XP or Pentium III 1.5 GHz, 256 MB RAM, DirectX 9.0b-compatible graphics card from NVIDIA® GeForce® 3 and higher (excluding GeForce® 4MX) or ATI® Radeon® 8500 and higher, DirectX 9.0c-compatible sound card, DirectX 9.0c (included), 2.56 GB Free Hard Drive Space, MS Compatible mouse, Broadband Internet Connection (for multiplayer)Recommended: Windows XP, AMD Athlon 64; or Pentium 4 2.8GHz ; 1 GB RAM, DirectX 9.0c-compatible graphics card from NVIDIA® (GeForce® 6600 and above), DirectX 9.0c-compatible sound card - Sound Blaster® X-Fi™ series preferred</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3550">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six: Vegas</game><game id="2397">Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon: Advanced Warfighter</game><game id="9137">Brothers in Arms: Road to Hill 30</game><game id="3617">Brothers in Arms: Earned in Blood</game><game id="7023">SOCOM: U.S. Navy SEALs - Tactical Strike</game><game id="20940">Brothers in Arms: Double Time</game><game id="17947">Brothers in Arms: D-Day</game><game id="1339">Star Wars: Republic Commando</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1798098-box_fswth.png</image></root>