<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2454</id><name>Duke it out in D.C.</name><description>  OverviewDuke it Out in D.C. is  both  Sunstorm  Interactive's first  Duke Nukem 3D  expansion pack and the first official third party expansion pack for the  game. It would later be bundled with the game as the " Duke  Nukem 3D Kill-A-Ton Collection." The storyline entails President  Bill Clinton being kidnapped by the aliens and Duke being called in to  rescue him. The expansion is set within Washington D.C., takes the player  through a variety of famous landmarks and in the time since its release, has maintained polarized opinions amongst the Duke Nukem 3D community for its sometimes expansive and non-linear maps.The expansion would  contain the first commercial work of noted  Build engine  level designers  Charlie  Wiederhold (later hired by  3D  Realms to work on Duke Nukem Forever and a major reason for the release  of the  Shadow  Warrior source code) and  Robert Travis (who would work on more Build engine expansions than any other level designer and who designed 80% of the maps in the expansion). LevelsThe  expansion consists of one new episode comprised of nine levels and a  secret level. DUKEDC1.MAP -  "Hell to the Chief," Duke starts off on the lawn of the White House and has to blast his way through to look for the President. DUKEDC2.MAP  - "Memorial Service," begins outside of the Lincoln Memorial and  continues through a secret bunker underneath. DUKEDC3.MAP - "Nuked Files," initially starts off in the streets outside of the FBI Headquarters and then progresses in and through.DUKEDC4.MAP - "Smithsonian Terror," a massive, sprawling, somewhat non-linear level that incorporates the museum with three large exhibits to explore.DUKEDC5.MAP -  "Capitol Punishment," again, Duke is required to work his way through the back alleys of D.C., drop down into the sewer, and worm his way on up into the now-destroyed Capitol building.DUKEDC6.MAP - "Metro  Mayhem," a large three-line subway map.DUKEDC7.MAP - "Brown  Water," Fight through the sewers of D.C. DUKEDC8.MAP -  "Dread October," a submarine pen complete with a full size submarine to  battle through.DUKEDC9.MAP - "Nuke Proof," battle the Cycloid  Emperor deep underground in a nuclear hardened bunker. DUKEDCSL.MAP -  "Top Secret," the government's secret warehouse of evidence. Stumbling on the time machine catapults Duke forward and backwards in time to different periods.   ReceptionJeff Sengsack of Gamespot pointed out the lack of any new music, enemies, or engine enhancements but praised the quality of the level design and its low price ( link). GamesDomain reviewed the expansion as part of the Kill-a-Ton collection and similarly praised its level design for being "superb" ( link). In the years following its release, the expansion's levels have caused split opinions amongst the Duke Nukem community as some find the levels (in particular, "Smithsonian Terror") to be too large and frustrating ( link).Derivative Projects NightFright  currently maintains the  Duke DC High Resolution Project, which seeks to replace the low resolution textures in the game with higher quality substitutes. In addition, higher quality OGG-format music has been implemented, replacing the previous MIDI music. With the DukeDC HRP, the theme song changes to, "Hail to the Chief". </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="324">Duke Nukem 3D: Plutonium Pak</game><game id="17127">Redneck Rampage: Suckin' Grits on Route 66</game><game id="2043">Wanton Destruction</game><game id="16048">Blasto</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/13692/695369-686238boxart_160w.jpg</image></root>