<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2459</id><name>Body Blows</name><description>OverviewKen vs Ken in an alternate universeBody Blows is a title born out of the quality of the Amiga port of Street Fighter II. Upon the Amiga port of SFII being released Team 17 realized that the port was of low quality and this now left them with a hole in the Amiga market that, with the right game, they could exploit. Body Blows was the result of this.Body Blows is as classic a SFII clone as you can possibly get and many moves for the titles main two characters (Nick and Dan) are clones of Ryu and Ken's moves from the Street Fighter series. One of the key achievements Team 17 reached when developing Body Blows is that it is one of the first titles that could run on every Amiga ever made giving the game a large player base.Body Blows was followed up by Body Blows Galactic and then Ultimate Body Blows. Both of which contained more than the 11 characters found in the original Body Blows.CharactersNick is a local gang leader and has hatred for his brother Dan. His main moves were a powerful uppercut and the ability to throw lightning balls.Dan, Nick's brother. Similar in fighting style to Nick.Junior, British bulldog boxer. Junior's style comes form his boxing background and his main attack is a quick punch flurry. He is actually named after one of the designers on the game.Lo Ray, a monk who was lured away from his temple by the temptation of big dollars on the fighting circuit.Cossack was originally a USSR dancer that won many medals for his country. Embarrassed by the ridicule he received for his background Cossack set about building the world's most perfect body. This led to him becoming incredibly strong but very slow. Much like Zangief in SFIIDug, fat wrestler with a special earthquake move that is performed by jumping up in the air and splashing down chest first.Maria uses her "assets" and good looks to distract her opponents. She is a fighter that is low on power but high on speed.Ninja is a character that could use the ability to transport and turn invisible to turn the tide of a match. One of the most annoying things about this character was the incessant need for the character to shout "ninja" every 2 seconds.Mike, business man and slave to the rat race turned nutter fighter. Enough said.Yit-U, a character that lacked any interesting back story but did have one notable ability. Yit-U could teleport across the entire screen before punching someone in the face then teleporting back. Handy.Max, general all round brawler. Boss champion of the game.</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="243">Street Fighter II: The World Warrior</game><game id="15743">Mortal Kombat</game><game id="16444">Eternal Champions</game><game id="4292">Elfmania</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/16/164924/2459379-bodyblows.jpg</image></root>