<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24667</id><name>The Beatles: Rock Band</name><description>OverviewThe Beatles: Rock Band was released on September 9, 2009 (09/09/09) across the globe, in North America, Europe, Australia, and New Zealand. The game features 45 songs that span The Beatles' career and a detailed storyline that highlights some of the band's biggest moments in history.GameplayFollow in The Beatles' footsteps as they progress through their career, starting at the Cavern Club.Along with the basic gameplay modes of the Rock Band series, The Beatles: Rock Band includes a story driven mode that takes players through the Fab Four's career, starting with their early Cavern Club Days and going all the way to their last live show, the famous concert atop the Apple Corps rooftop. All characters, venues, and songs are exclusively related to The Beatles, meaning no songs are cross compatible with other Rock Band titles and The Beatles: Rock Band.The newest feature in The Beatles: Rock Band is the inclusion of three-part vocal harmonies, allowing up to six players to join in at the same time. Players are able to mimic The Beatles by playing and singing at the same time, or simply let two additional players sing the backup and harmonizing vocals. A special training mode will be included to help singers adjust to singing in harmony.The game's career mode follows the band chronologically from 1963 to 1969. It starts with the band's landmark touring appearances, then transitions to their recording studio period at Abbey Roads Studio, and culminates in their famous rooftop performance in 1969. The venues include:1963: Cavern Club, Liverpool, England1964: Ed Sullivan Show, New York, USA1965: Shea Stadium, New York, USA1966: Budokan, Tokyo, Japan1966-1968: Studio 2 at Abbey Road Studios, London, England1969: Apple Corps Rooftop, London, EnglandDuring the Abbey Road Studios period, several dreamscape backgrounds accompany certain songs. These are artistic interpretations of the songs, akin to music videos. While some of these dreamscapes are set in the studio with color filters, lyrics, and other effects being seen some are set in an entirly new location based on the mood or lyrics of the track. For example, "Here Comes the Sun" features the band playing on top of a hill in front of a sunny background while, in contrast, "While My Guitar Gently Weeps" shows the same landscape with a more moody atmosphere. Meanwhile, some Dreamscapes are based off of an original video or film that featured the track. "I Am the Walrus" and "Yellow Submarine," for example, are both set or feature references to the original music video and animated movie, respectively.Throughout the career mode, players are rewarded with photos and studio chat between the band members and crew that have never before been seen or heard, giving them extra insight on the band and their music.Track ListingThe game is comprised of 45 songs, taken from The Beatles' catalog of studio albums between Please Please Me (1963) and Abbey Road (1969). It has been confirmed that the United Kingdom-released versions will be used, and will not be released as downloadable content for main iterations of the Rock Band series. The game features unheard dialogue and footage from the band that, prior to release, has never been released in any form.Song TitleAlbumVenueA Hard Day's NightA Hard Day's NightEd Sullivan TheaterAnd Your Bird Can SingRevolverBudokanBack in the U.S.S.R.The BeatlesAbbey Road StudiosBirthdayThe BeatlesAbbey Road StudiosBoysPlease Please MeCavern ClubCan't Buy Me LoveA Hard Day's NightEd Sullivan TheaterCome TogetherAbbey RoadAbbey Road StudiosDay TripperSingleBudokanDear PrudenceThe BeatlesAbbey Road Studios Dig a PonyLet It BeRooftop ConcertDo You Want to Know a SecretPlease Please MeCavern ClubDon't Let Me DownSingleRooftop ConcertDrive My CarRubber SoulBudokanEight Days a WeekBeatles for SaleShea StadiumGet BackLet It BeRooftop ConcertGetting BetterSgt. Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club BandAbbey Road StudiosGood Morning Good MorningSgt. Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club BandAbbey Road StudiosHello, GoodbyeMagical Mystery TourAbbey Road StudiosHelter SkelterThe BeatlesAbbey Road StudiosHere Comes the SunAbbey RoadAbbey Road StudiosHey BulldogYellow SubmarineAbbey Road StudiosI Am the WalrusMagical Mystery TourAbbey Road StudiosI Feel FineSingleShea StadiumI Me MineLet It BeRooftop ConcertI Saw Her Standing TherePlease Please MeCavern ClubI Wanna Be Your ManWith The BeatlesEd Sullivan TheaterI Want to Hold Your HandSingleEd Sullivan TheaterI Want You (She's So Heavy)Abbey RoadRooftop ConcertIf I Needed SomeoneRubber SoulShea StadiumI'm Looking Through YouRubber SoulShea StadiumI've Got a FeelingLet It BeRooftop ConcertLucy in the Sky with DiamondsSgt. Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club BandAbbey Road StudiosOctopus's GardenAbbey RoadAbbey Road StudiosPaperback WriterSingleBudokanRevolutionSingleAbbey Road StudiosSgt. Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club Band / With a Little Help from My FriendsSgt. Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club BandAbbey Road StudiosSomethingAbbey RoadAbbey Road StudiosTaxmanRevolverBudokanThe EndAbbey RoadAbbey Road StudiosTicket to RideHelp!Shea StadiumTwist and ShoutPlease Please MeCavern CLubWhile My Guitar Gently WeepsThe BeatlesAbbey Road StudiosWithin You Without You / Tomorrow never KnowsLoveAbbey Road StudiosYellow SubmarineRevolverAbbey Road StudiosDownloadable ContentUnlike previous Rock Band titles, downloadable content will be released specifically for The Beatles: Rock Band and will not be compatible with other Rock Band games; nor will previous and future releases to the general Rock Band platform be available for play in The Beatles: Rock Band. The game will also not export any on-disc songs for play in other Rock Band games. Currently these are the only songs available for download. Harmonix have said the future of downloadable content for this game depends a lot on how well the sales go for the songs currently available.The songs cost $2 each, either as 160 Microsoft Points or 200 Nintendo Points. The Abbey Road album can be downloaded as a medley for $16.98 or 1360 Microsoft Points. Abbey Road is not available as a medley on the Wii.Song TitleAlbumVenueRelease DateAll You Need Is LoveSingleAbbey Road Studios9 September 2009Maxwell's Silver HammerAbbey RoadAbbey Road Studios20 October 2009Oh! DarlingAbbey RoadAbbey Road Studios20 October 2009BecauseAbbey RoadAbbey Road Studios20 October 2009You Never Give Me Your MoneyAbbey RoadAbbey Road Studios20 October 2009Sun King / Mean Mr. MustardAbbey RoadAbbey Road Studios20 October 2009Polythene Pam / She Came In Through The Bathroom WindowAbbey RoadAbbey Road Studios20 October 2009Golden Slumbers / Carry That Weight / The EndAbbey RoadAbbey Road Studios20 October 2009Her MajestyAbbey RoadAbbey Road Studios20 October 2009Abbey Road MedleyAbbey RoadAbbey Road Studios20 October 2009Fixing A HoleSgt. Peppers Lonely Hearts Club BandAbbey Road Studios17 November 2009She's Leaving HomeSgt. Peppers Lonely Hearts Club BandAbbey Road Studios17 November 2009Being For The Benefit Of Mr. Kite!Sgt. Peppers Lonely Hearts Club BandAbbey Road Studios17 November 2009Within You Without YouSgt. Peppers Lonely Hearts Club BandAbbey Road Studios17 November 2009When I'm Sixty-FourSgt. Peppers Lonely Hearts Club BandAbbey Road Studios17 November 2009Lovely RitaSgt. Peppers Lonely Hearts Club BandAbbey Road Studios17 November 2009Sgt. Peppers Lonely Hearts Club Band (Reprise)Sgt. Peppers Lonely Hearts Club BandAbbey Road Studios17 November 2009A Day In The LifeSgt. Peppers Lonely Hearts Club BandAbbey Road Studios17 November 2009Norwegian Wood (The Bird Has Flown)Rubber SoulAbbey Road Studios15 December 2009You Won't See MeRubber SoulShea Stadium15 December 2009Nowhere ManRubber SoulAbbey Road Studios15 December 2009Think For YourselfRubber SoulShea Stadium15 December 2009The WordRubber SoulShea Stadium15 December 2009MichelleRubber SoulAbbey Road Studios15 December 2009What Goes OnRubber SoulShea Stadium15 December 2009GirlRubber SoulAbbey Road Stadium15 December 2009In My LifeRubber SoulAbbey Road Stadium15 December 2009WaitRubber SoulShea Stadium15 December 2009Run For Your LifeRubber SoulShea Stadium15 December 2009PeripheralsThe Beatles: Rock Band peripherals.New instrument peripherals have been designed specific to The Beatles, and include Paul's Höfner bass guitar, George's Gretsch Duo, John's Rickenbacker 325, and a Ludwig branded drum kit sporting Ringo's classic pearl finish and Beatles "Drop T" logo bass drum head. The kit also includes a newly designed pedal with an intricate Beatles design embossed on the plate. The Höfner bass, Ludwig kit, and microphone (along with stand) are all included in the premium bundle, however the Rickenbacker and Gretsch are only available as separate purchases. The premium bundle only comes with a single stand, so people who plan on having more than one mutli-instrumentalist will be required to purchase more stands (most standard microphone stands will suffice). All peripherals are wireless, excluding the mic.The game is compatible with Lips and Sing Star microphones for Xbox 360 and PS3 respectively, allowing players to use them as opposed to the wired Rock Band mics.</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1891338-box_beatlesrb.png</image></root>