<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24713</id><name>Modern Warfare 2</name><description>OverviewRangers lead the way.Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 is publisher Activision's sixth major installment in the Call of Duty franchise, and developer Infinity Ward's fourth. The game is a continuation of the story of Call of Duty 4: Modern Warfare. Players will cycle through a number of characters including a member of Task Force 141, led by Captain John "Soap" MacTavish, one of the main protagonists of the first game.CampaignOverviewThe game's plot unfolds over 18 levels (the first one serving as a tutorial) and lets you choose between four different difficulty levels, the hardest one being veteran. Like in previous Call of Duty games, the player switches characters after each level. In Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2, you take control of 4 different characters: Private Joseph Allen, Sgt. Gary "Roach" Sanderson , Captain John "Soap" MacTavish, an ISS astronaut, and Private James Ramirez. The game also has a bonus mission, the museum. More of a playground than a mission, the game puts you in a museum where you see statues of every character. By pressing a red button that the game tells you not to press, all the statues come to life, directly attacking you. The museum also holds every weapon that can be found in the game.Like in the first Modern Warfare, the game's levels are peppered with Intel Items (little laptops). Finding all of them doesn't unlock anything other than an achievement/trophy. The game keeps track of all your stats (percentage complete, number of Intel items found, time played) and lets you replay any level telling you how many Intel items you have left to find.SynopsisTaking place five years after Call of Duty 4: Modern Warfare, the Ultranationalist party ultimately seizes control of Russia with a statue of deceased leader Imran Zakhaev erected in the capital city of Moscow. In spite of their success, a seperatist group led by Vladimir Makarov initiates multiple terrorist attacks throughout Europe demanding the removal of the party from office.In Afghanistan, United States Army Private Joseph Allen demonstrates how to handle firearms and grenades to the local Afghan security force as well as being tasked to complete an obstacle course under the supervision of Lieutenant General Shepherd, leader of the multinational counter-terrorism unit Task Force 141. Soon Allen and the rest of his unit moves out to an Afghan city controlled by Insurgents. Immediately after taking over a portion of the city, an impressed Shepherd takes and recruits Allen to Task Force 141 with his first assignment a covert operation in Makarov's terrorist group, under the directive of the CIAInsurgents taking fire.Meanwhile in the Tian Shan mountains, Task Force 141 field operators Captain John "Soap" MacTavish and Sergeant Gary "Roach" Sanderson infiltrate a Ultranationalist base to recover an ACS (Attack Characterization System) from a downed satellite. Both Roach and Soap narrowly escape the base with the ACS module after being compromised.Sent to Russia, Allen is recruited by Makarov to participate in a brutal massacre in Zakhaev International Airport. After fighting through airport security and FSB, Makarov was able to escape the airport. Before fleeing, with Makarov aware of Allen's identity, shoots him for dead causing the Russians to believe it was an American attack; instigating a war between the two countries.To suppress the situation and reveal that Makarov was the mastermind of the airport attack, Task Force 141 traces a bullet left in the crime scene to a Brazilian arms dealer named Alejandro Rojas. After brutally interrogating Rojas, Roach, Soap, and Lieutenant Simon "Ghost" Riley narrowly escape Brazil from the local militia with a way to expose Makarov; by extracting his arch enemy, known as Prisoner 627, out of a Russian gulag located east of the country.In the United States of America, the Russians, shortly after the airport attack, launches a massive surprise attack on both the east and west coasts of the country. Private James Ramirez, Allen's former squad members Sergeant Foley and Corporal Dunn, and many Army Rangers are tasked to defend both Virginia and Washington D.C. as well as secure some high valued personnel to safety.The airport massacre.With the help of the United States Navy SEALS and Marine Corps, Task Force 141 initiate the operation to secure Prisoner 627. Prior to invading the gulag, Task Force 141 is to secure a series of surrounding oil rigs containing hostages and anti-air weaponry. During the assault on the prison, it was revealed that Prisoner 627 was Captain Price. Upon freeing Price, he and Task Force 141 now plans to stop Makarov. With stopping the conflict in America as priority, Price plans to infiltrate an Ultranationalist base containing a nuclear weapon. With the weapon inside the sub, Price goes rogue to launch the missile to Washington D.C. but detonates outside the Earth's atmosphere destroying the nearby International Space Station.With Ramirez, Foley, and Dunn in a last stand against the Russians, they witness the nuclear weapon detonating. The effect creates an electromagnetic pulse causing all electronics and vehicles to cease, giving the Americans a slight advantage. They escape the immediate EMP effect and proceed to The White House only to find out that the city will be carpet bombed to minimize Russian forces. Ramirez, Foley, Dunn, and the Rangers hastily reach the rooftops to signal green smoke indicating that the area is still in American control. At the last second, the planes intended to bomb the city withdrew their attack.In an attempt to stop Makarov once and for all, Task Force 141 splits up to two different areas Makarov can be hiding. Roach and Ghost are to raid a possible safe house while Soap and Price infiltrates an Afghan aircraft boneyard where an arms deal is likely occurring. Roach and Ghost discover vital intelligence that can benefit taking down Makarov while they narrowly escape Makarov's surrounding men. Near extraction, both Roach and Ghost were shot and left for dead by Shepherd who took the intelligence. Price and Soap escape a battle between Makarov's men and Shepherd's Shadow Company force thanks to associate Nikolai. While in the boneyard, Price engages in a radio conversation with Makarov where he tells Price the location of Shepherd's base in Afghanistan.Knifing some Shadow Company troops from above.Soap and Price now wanted, the infiltrate Shepherd's base of operations in a vengeful suicide mission. They eventually find Shepherd escaping and both Soap and Price give chase through boats. Nearing a waterfall, Shepherd attempts to be extracted through helicopter but was unsuccessful thanks to Price shooting the main rotor. The helicopter crash lands and the boat Price and Soap was on tumbles from the waterfall. Waking up, Soap finds Shepherd and attempts to kill him but he gets the upper hand by stabbing Soap with his own knife.Shepherd reveals that he was the mastermind of the whole conflict against Russia. Shepherd hopes to have the American public to enlist in the military and fight the Russians after enduring the pressure of losing 30,000 troops during the battle against Khaled Al-Asad in the previous Modern Warfare. At gunpoint, Price stops Shepherd from killing Soap. Shepherd gets the upper hand on Price before being stabbed in the eye by Soap's own knife. Nikolai appears to help extract Price and severely wounded Soap. Nikolai warns about the repercussions of killing Shepherd but knows a safe place to go to help Soap's wounds and be secluded.IW4 Engine"Texture Streaming" ComparisonIW Engine 4.0 is the latest build of their game engine for the Call of Duty series. The framework of the engine is derived from id Tech 3. Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 takes advantage of a new graphics engine technology that saves disc space, while adding graphical fidelity. Dubbed "Texture Streaming" it allows the designers to create larger environments without sacrificing object and character detail. The streaming tech also enables the developer to focus development on weather effects and environmental destruction.Special Ops ModeSpecial Ops mode is a standalone mode separate from the campaign narrative. It is inspired by CoD4's "Mile High Club" epilogue, in that the player must complete a specific objective within a set time limit. You can play solo or co-op with one other player, online or in split-screen. A debriefing screen lists mission type, resistance you will face, and expected completion time before you start the mission. At the start of the missions, you have a choice of switching weapons and/or equipment.Spec Ops ModeSpec Ops mode also has a new enemy type not seen in the campaign. Dubbed "Juggernaut", this enemy's purpose is to flush out the player from entrenched positions. Clad in bomb disposal gear, the Juggernaut's heavy armor makes it tough to kill.There are different difficulty levels, ranging from Normal to Veteran. By completing missions, the player is able to earn stars that further unlock later mission groups. The harder the difficulty on which one completes a mission, the more stars one gains. There are six mission tiers to unlock, from Alpha to Echo.Alpha missionsThe Pit - Complete the training course found in campaign mode.Sniper Fi - Use sniper rifles, claymores and Predator Drones to hold off waves of enemies.Evasion - Use silenced sniper rifles and stealth to slip past enemy patrols.Suspension - Push through invading forces on the bridge to reach the safe zone.O Cristo Redentor - Based on Takedown (a single player mission), Hunt down and eliminate The Favela Gang, and minimize civilian casualties.Bravo missionsOverwatch - Rain down death from an AC-130 gunship to escort your partner. (Two-player only)Body Count - Rack up a large enough body count, quick kills = bonuses.Bomb Squad - Race through the Favela market place defusing bombs along the way.Big Brother - Fire explosive ammunition from the Vulcan gun of a Black Hawk helicopter, providing cover fire for your teammate. (Two-player only)Race - Speed you snowmobile down the mountain avoiding various obstacles and enemies.Charlie missionsI'm the juggernaut...Hidden - Evade enemy patrols and Ghillie snipers near Chernobyl.Breach and Clear - Breach enemy defenses in Gulag and escape.Time Trial - Launch your snowmobile across the chasm before time runs out. Run through flags to gain bonus time.Homeland Security - Use sentry guns, thermal sights, claymores, and rocket launchers to defend against waves of enemies.Snatch  Grab - Battle Shadow Company and Juggernauts in the airplane graveyard. Grab the intel and escape.Delta missionsWar Driving - Laze targets for the Striker armored vehicle in suburbia, house to house and room to room. Intel must be collected from three different buildings.Wreckage - Use C4, grenade launchers, RPGs, sentry guns, semtex, and more to destroy every vehicle on the bridge.Acceptable Losses - Sabotage the remote airbase with silenced weapons and a heartbeat sensor.Terminal - Pummel your way through enemy riot shield ambushes.Estate Takedown - Eliminate Ghillie Snipers, Elite Mercs, and Juggernauts, defending the estate.Echo missionsWet Work - Breach two rooms full of enemies and hostages to secure the oil rig.High Explosive - Kill ten Juggernauts using only explosives and your knife.Armor Piercing - Kill all fifteen Juggernauts on the oil rig.Multiplayer ModesA firefight on the multiplayer map "Invasion"Free For All - No teams, every man for himself. Kill or be killed.Team Deathmatch - Work with your team to kill opponents and reach the score limit.Mercenary Team Deathmatch - Team Deathmatch with random players, no parties allowed.Demolition - Two teams are on defense and offense. The offensive team's objective is to plant a bomb, while the defensive team defends a certain area. You are able to respawn in this mode and during halftime the teams switch sides.Domination - Capture and defend three objectives spread across the map.Ground War - Large team based games. Consists of Team Deathmatch and Objective game types.Headquarters Pro - Your objective is to capture and defend the headquarters on a map from enemy forces. After a base is destroyed by the attacking team, a new headquarters will be located on the map. This gives both teams the ability to take over the base first. The longer a base is held, the more points you accumulate to win the match.Sabotage - A bomb based game mode, where the bomb is neutral and both teams try and destroy the others base.Search and Destroy - No respawning. Two factions with one playing defense and one playing offense. Offensive Team has one bomb and two locations to choose from. Defensive team must protect these sites from attackers. There is a short interval and both factions switch sides.3rd Person Team Tactical - Team Deathmatch, Domination, Demolition and Capture the Flag in 3rd Person view.Hardcore Ricochet SD - Search and Destroy with friendly fire, limited HUD and ricochet damage for team killing.Hardcore Team Deathmatch - Team Deathmatch with friendly fire on and a limited HUD.Team Deathmatch Express - Team Deathmatch with shortened wait time between matches.Barebones Pro - Team Deathmatch and Free For All game modes with killstreak rewards disabled.Objective Barebones Pro - Mix of objective game types consisting of Capture the Flag, Domination, Demolition, and Headquarters Pro with killstreak rewards disabled.Hardcore Ricochet: Headquarters Pro - Headquarters with friendly fire, limited HUD, extra bullet damage and ricochet damage for team killing.Resurgence - Mix of team game modes on the maps in the Resurgence map pack.Hardcore Resurgence - Resurgence with limited HUD, extra bullet damage, and ricochet damage for team killing.Hidden Modes:(These game modes were found hidden within the game's files, however never made it into the actual game. There were occasionally hacks that would put these modes into public lobbies.)Global Thermonuclear War - Two teams must battle against each other to gain the most control over a central nuke. Once the maximum points is reach by one team, it detonates and the game ends.Arena - A single flag is spawned in the map. The team to capture it, or eliminate the other team first, wins. The rules are incredibly similar to Search and Destroy, in that each team member has one life, and must wait for the round to end to respawn.Multiplayer MapsMapDescriptionScreenshotAfghanWide open, expansive desert map with mountainous terrain and a downed AC-130. The rocky terrain and cliffs provide plenty of sniper positions while the downed AC-130 provides temporary cover. There are also several underground caves that allow for flanking.AfghanDerailSnow map with three primary building structures (One at each end and one slightly off the middle) A derailed train runs from one spawn to the off middle building providing limited cover from sniper advance. A frozen river bed bisects the map and provides high visibility for snipers. NB: Thermal is less effective but still usable with white targets blending well with the snowy terrain.DerailEstateA Mountain chalet tends to host the majority of the action on this map. It is somewhat defendable but can be approached and breached from three sides. A few outlining buildings also provide good views of the approach to the estate. Watch for enemies in the boathouse region if leaving via the front door. The map is taken from the single player mission "Loose Ends".EstateFavelaA Brazilian shantytown with tight confined spaces. The map is a small village with various buildings and tight alleyways. Expect plenty of close quarters combat.FavelaHighriseRooftop of a highrise office building. Both teams starts on opposite ends of two separate office buildings and converge on a central rooftop. The central rooftop has small huts and shacks with a helicopter perched on a helipad. An open trench links bases and runs underground to the across the map. Watch for snipers on the cranes both in and outside the map (especially at the apex of the cranes outside the map which command a near perfect view of the battlefield) Also be aware players can access the roof of one base and the upper level of the other.HighriseInvasionAlleys and buildings, some of which are scaleable, make up this map. Taking place in an Afghan city, the many streets make for some intense encounters and several building make for excellent flanking maneuvers.InvasionKarachiKarachi is a remake of map called "de_karachi" that was designed for Counter-Strike 1.6 by CompoSITe (aka Geoffrey Smith) who now works for Infinity Ward at the Design  Scripting department.KarachiQuarrySet in a stone quarry, this is the map with the biggest difference in elevation. Players can snipe each other from high and low, take positions inside warehouses that have windows overlooking the battlefield. The huge marble blocks littering the area is perhaps Quarry's most distinguishing feature.QuarryRundownA small and very open Brazilian town with a river crossing the town in the middle of the map, resulting a intense fire fights from all angles.RundownRustAn old abandoned mining facility. This is the smallest map of all the multiplayer map, which makes the scaleable crane in the middle a highly contested area. Players can also seek refuge in small containers around the map.RustScrapyardSet in an airplane scrapyard where multiple airplane hulls litter the middle of the map. Two main buildings sit on each side of the map and provide starting points for each team. Some parts of the map are obscured by smoke that is a result of oil tanks burning.ScrapyardSkidRowThis map has many narrow alleys that provoke a lot of close combat. In the middle of the map is a two-leveled building with windows overlooking both sides of the battlefield, making it the most contested area of the map.SkidrowSub BaseA snow based map set at a nuclear submarine base. Most of the action takes place in a "courtyard" in the middle of the map. There are multiple structures with staircases and high visibility for sniping.Sub BaseTerminalBased on the single player campaign mission "No Russian", this level occurs inside and outside of a Russian airport terminal. This is a small-medium size map with plenty of close quarters combat. The map also features an airplane, the inside often being a contested area.TerminalUnderpassThis rainy map takes place underneath a ruined underpass. Featuring buildings, narrow alleys and a wide channel cutting through the map, it makes up for some interesting player decisions in regard to weapon load-out.UnderpassWastelandWasteland is a remake of Brecourt from the original Call of Duty and Call of Duty 2 MP maps and locations, with slight differences in this version.WastelandStimulus Map PackMapDescriptionScreenshotBailoutOverrun apartment complex. Long sight lines with great flank routes.BailoutCrashDowned Sea Knight in a desert town originally in Call of Duty 4. Fantastic team games.CrashOvergrownLarge overgrown Russian area this was a fan favorite from the original Modern Warfare. Sniper ghillie suits make for good cover.OvergrownSalvageA snow-covered junkyard. Lots of fast paced action.SalvageStormStormy warehouse district. Intense team games.StormResurgence Map PackMapDescriptionScreenshotStrikeThis map is a remade version of the Call of Duty 4 map of the same name. It has a large open road through the center, a courtyard, and various buildings and walls, making this map ideal for all sorts of play styles.StrikeVacantPreviously seen in Call of Duty 4, Vacant is set in a Russian office complex, this is a fairly small map with extensive inside and outside areas.VacantFuelA "sniper haven" according to Robert Bowling. Fuel is set in an oil refinery and is one of the largest maps.FuelCarnivalSet in an abandoned amusement park, Carnival has a lot of the things you'd expect, from rollercoasters to funhouses to bumper cars and many, many snack stands.Oh, yes, you will find clowns.CarnivalTrailer ParkA maze of trailers and tight corridors, with long sight lines along the edges.Trailer ParkWeaponsPrimaryPrimary weapons is the standard weapon the player will start with every match. Each Weapon has a maximum amount of damage per bullet and a minimum, stated below, which varies depending on attachments and range. Sniper rifles do the same damage each bullet but depending on the rifle they have different multipliers for certain areas on the body. For every other weapon a headshot gives you a 1.4 damage multiplier.Assault RiflesWeaponSpecificationsAppearanceM4A1Unlocked - Level 4 (Private First Class)Fire Mode - AutomaticDamage - 30 - 20M4A1 statsFAMASUnlocked - Level 4 (Private First Class)Fire Mode - Three-shot BurstDamage - 40 - 30FAMAS statsSCAR-HUnlocked - Level 8 (Specialist I)Fire Mode - AutomaticDamage - 40 - 30SCAR-H statsTAR-21Unlocked - Level 20 (Sergeant First Class I)Fire Mode - AutomaticDamage - 40 - 30Tar-21 statsFALUnlocked - Level 28 (Sergeant Major)Fire Mode - Semi-Automatic (Single fire)Damage - 55 - 35 (55-40 with holographic sight)FAL statsM16A4Unlocked - Level 40 (Captain)Fire Mode - Three-shot Burst like the FAMASDamage - 40 - 30M16A4 statsACRUnlocked - Level 48 (Lieutenant Colonel II)Fire Mode - AutomaticDamage - 30 - 20Very accurate with almost no recoil.ACR statsF2000Unlocked - Level 60 (Major General II)Fire Mode - AutomaticDamage - 30 - 20F2000 statsAK-47Unlocked - Level 70 (Commander)Fire Mode - AutomaticDamage - 40 - 30AK-47 statsM14 EBRFire Mode - Semi-Automatic (Single fire)Non-Multiplayer Assault RifleM14 EBRG3Fire Mode - Semi-Automatic (Single fire)Non-Multiplayer Assault RifleG3Sub Machine GunsWeaponSpecificationAppearanceMP5KUnlocked - Level 4 (Private First Class)Fire Mode - AutomaticDamage - 40 - 20MP5K statsUMP45Unlocked - Level 4 (Private First Class)Fire Mode - AutomaticDamage - 40 - 35UMP45 statsVectorUnlocked - Level 12 (Corporal II)Fire Mode - AutomaticDamage - 25 - 20Vector statsP90Unlocked - Level 24 (Master Sergeant II)Fire Mode - AutomaticDamage - 30 - 20P90 statsMini-UziUnlocked - Level 44 (Major I)Fire Mode - AutomaticDamage - 30 - 20Mini-Uzi statsLight Machine GunsWeaponSpecificationAppearanceL86 LSWUnlocked - Level 4 (Private First Class)Fire Mode - Fully AutomaticDamage - 40 - 40Silenced Damage - 30 - 30L86 LSW statsRPDUnlocked - Level 4 (Private First Class)Fire Mode - Fully AutomaticDamage - 40 - 40Silenced Damage - 30 - 30RPD statsMG4Unlocked - Level 16 (Staff Sergeant)Fire Mode - Fully AutomaticDamage - 30 - 30Silenced Damage - 20 - 20MG4 statsAUG HBARUnlocked - Level 32 (Sergeant Major I)Fire Mode - Fully AutomaticDamage - 40 - 40Silenced Damage - 30 - 30AUG HBAR statsM240Unlocked - Level 52 (Colonel II)Fire Mode - Fully AutomaticDamage - 30 - 30Silenced Damage - 20 - 20M240 statsSniper RiflesWeaponSpecificationAppearanceInterventionUnlocked - Level 4 (Private First Class)Fire Mode - Bolt ActionDamage - 70Damage Multipliers - Head 1.5 Chest 1.5 Stomach 1.1Can kill enemies in one (body shot) hit if Stopping Power is used.Intervention statsBarret .50calUnlocked - Level 4 (Private First Class)Fire Mode - Semi-Automatic (Single fire)Damage - 70Damage Multipliers - Head 1.5 Chest 1.5 Stomach 1.1Barret .50cal statsWA2000Unlocked - Level 36 (2nd Lieutenant II)Fire Mode - Semi-Automatic (Single fire)Damage - 70Damage Multipliers - Head 1.5 Chest 1.5 Stomach 1WA2000 statsM21 EBRUnlocked - Level 58 (Major General)Fire Mode - Semi-Automatic (Single fire)Damage - 70Damage Multipliers - Head 1.5 Chest 1.1 Stomach 1the M21 EBR is the best sniper rifle for two shot kills.M21 EBR statsSVD DragunovFire Mode - Semi-Automatic (Single fire)Non-Multiplayer Sniper RifleDragunovShieldsWeaponSpecificationAppearanceRiot ShieldUnlocked - Level 4 (Private First Class)Bullet resistantShield BashRiot Shield statsSecondarySecondary weapons functions as the sidearm weapon of a player. They consists of weapons often used in rare occasions only, such as Rocket Launchers and close-quarter weapons like ShotgunsMachine PistolsWeaponSpecificationAppearancePP2000Unlocked - Level 4 (Private First Class)Fire Mode - Fully AutomaticDamage - 40 - 20PP2000 StatsG18Unlocked - Level 22 (Major Sergeant)Fire Mode - Fully AutomaticDamage - 30 - 20G18 statsM93 RafficaUnlocked - Level 38 (1st Lieutenant I)Fire Mode - Three-shot BurstDamage - 40 - 30M93 Raffica statsTMPUnlocked - Level 58 (Major General)Fire Mode - Fully AutomaticDamage - 30 - 20TMP statsShotgunsWeaponSpecificationAppearanceSPAS-12Unlocked - Level 4 (Private First Class)Fire Mode - Pump Action (Single fire)SPAS-12 statsAA-12Unlocked - Level 18 (Staff Sergeant II)Fire Mode - Fully AutomaticAA-12 statsStrikerUnlocked - Level 34 (2nd Lieutenant)Fire Mode - Semi-Automatic (Single fire)Striker statsRangerUnlocked - Level 42 (Captain II)Fire Mode - Double BarrelRanger statsM1014Unlocked - Level 54 (Brigadier General)Fire Mode - Semi Automatic (Single Fire)M1014 statsModel 1887Unlocked - Level 67 (General I)Fire Mode - Lever Action (Single fire)Model 1887 statsW1200Fire Mode - Pump Action (Single fire)Non-Multiplayer ShotgunW1200HandgunsWeaponSpecificationAppearanceUSP .45Unlocked - Level 4 (Private First Class)Fire Mode - Semi-Automatic (Single fire)Damage - 40 - 25USP .45 stats.44 MagnumUnlocked - Level 26 (First Sergeant I)Fire Mode - Semi-Automatic (Single fire)Damage - 50 - 35.44 Magnum statsM9Unlocked - Level 46 (Lieutenant Colonel)Fire Mode - Semi-Automatic (Single fire)Damage - 40 - 30M9 statsDesert EagleUnlocked - Level 62 (Lieutenant General)Fire Mode - Semi-Automatic (Single fire)Damage - 50 - 40Desert Eagle statsM1911Fire Mode - Semi-Automatic (Single fire)Non-Multiplayer HandgunM1911LaunchersWeaponSpecificationAppearanceAT4-HSUnlocked - Level 4 (Private First Class)Fire Mode - Single FireDoesn't need a lock-on, can be very effective if used well.AT4-HS statsThumperUnlocked - Level 14 (Sergeant I)Fire Mode - Single FireCan be a good alternative to a Grenade Launcher aka "Noob Tube"Thumper statsStingerUnlocked - Level 30 (Sergeant Major II)Fire Mode - Single Fire (Lock-On Required)Needs a vehicle (Killstreak air-support) to lock on.Stringer statsJavelinUnlocked - Level 50 (Colonel)Fire Mode - Single Fire (Lock-On Required)Needs a vehicle or area lock on.Javelin statsRPG-7Unlocked - Level 65 (Lieutenant General III)Fire Mode - Single FireDoesn't need a lock on to fire.RPG-7 statsEquipmentsExplosives and GrenadesEquipmentSpecificationAppearanceFrag GrenadeUnlocked - Level 4 (Private First Class)Has a time delay that can be user controlled(cooking) and rolls on the ground depending on the slope.Can be thrown back and can kill a player with a direct impact.Frag GrenadeSemTex GrenadeUnlocked - Level 4 (Private First Class)Has a set time delay and sticks to surfaces, including enemies and teammates. A blinking red light is visible from the thrown SemTex grenade.Can be used to easily 'dispose' of a Riot Shield user.SemtexFlash GrenadeUnlocked - Level 4 (Private First Class)Temporarily disables the enemies vision and hearing.Can kill a player if hit (direct impact) twice (once on Hardcore mode).Flash GrenadeStun GrenadeUnlocked - Level 4 (Private First Class)Temporarily restricts enemy movement, causing them to move very slowly.Can blind target for a bit and can even kill a player if hit (direct impact) twice (once on Hardcore mode).Stun GrenadeSmoke GrenadeUnlocked - Level 4 (Private First Class)Ejects a cloud of smoke, impairing sight in a thrown location.Good for snipers with a Thermal Sight.Smoke GrenadeClaymoreUnlocked - Level 31 (Sergeant Major)Motion triggered explosive where the explosion is directional. The 'back' of the claymore faces the player deploying the claymore, with two red light emitted from the front.One player can deploy two at once. When a third is deployed, the first claymore deployed will explode.Can be shot, can be jumped over and it can be ran past with Marathon and Lightweight.ClaymoreC4Unlocked - Level 43 (Major)A manually triggered explosive. Unlike singleplayer, the player does not need to equip the C4 switch to detonate it.Can be shot to kill people, can even be used for an assisted suicide.C4Misc.EquipmentSpecificationAppearanceThrowing KnifeUnlocked - Level 7 (SpecialistHas an arced trajectory like a grenade. Can be picked up over and over by anyone who has Throwing Knife equipped as their equipment. Bounces off some hard surfaces.The Throwing Knife is a one hit kill weapon, like the standard knife attack. It does not disable a Sentry Gun in a single hit however.Throwing KnifeTactical InsertionUnlocked - Level 11 (Corporal I)Allows players to create their own spawn point. Can be destroyed by enemies players. Emits a noise that can be heard by other players when spawned using the Tactical Insertion.Can be destroyed by either smashing it or with a grenade (Semtex or Frag, even C4 can destroy it) but bullets cannot destroy it.Usually best to kill the player and then stand next to the Tactical Insertion and kill the player again as smashing a Tactical Insertion doesn't give you exp.Tactical InsertionBlast ShieldUnlocked - Level 19 (Sergeant First Class)When you wear the Blast Shield, you'll take less damage from explosives. Creates a slight tunnel vision for the user with a dark border, blocking out radar and the rest of the HUD.Blast ShieldAttachmentsAttachmentSpecificationAppearanceGrenade LauncherUnlocked - Weapon ChallengeTwo grenade rounds that explode on impact. It's possible for the grenades to not explode if there isn't sufficient impact with an object.Can also kill an enemy by hitting them with the projectile directly, which is indicated by a different kill icon.Needs to be used to get Shotgun, 20 kills with grenade launcher attachment.Grenade Launcher a.k.a., "Noob Tube" or "Pro Pipe"ShotgunUnlocked - Weapon Challenge, get 20 kills with Grenade Launcher.Masterkey ShotgunSilencerUnlocked - Weapon ChallengeGunfire makes less noise and does not indicate your position on enemy minimap.Shortens the range of the gun and can often make sniper's two shot killers, even with head shots.SilencerGripUnlocked - Weapon Challenge.Reduces recoil and muzzle rise.Can make the gun's range longer (not shown on stats) because recoil is reduced.GripTactical KnifeUnlocked - Weapon Challenge.Like the regular knife attack, but is quicker and has less delay between attacks.This attachment works only with handguns.Tactical KnifeHeartbeat SensorUnlocked - Weapon ChallengeAttaches a screen to the gun being used and indicates the location of other players in front of the user. Enemies using the Ninja perk does not show up on the sensor.Heartbeat SensorRed Dot SightUnlocked - Weapon Challenge.Note: Some weapons uses the MARS Sight instead of the Red Dot Sight.Red Dot SightHolographic SightUnlocked - Weapon Challenge.Holographic SightACOG ScopeUnlocked - Weapon Challenge.A gun scope with a small amount of magnification.This scope is very sensitive to recoil.ACOG ScopeThermalUnlocked - Weapon Challenge.A gun scope with magnification and infrared thermal vision. Enemies using Cold Blooded perk does not show up in thermal vision.An EMP will cause the thermal scope to have the same affect as a magnification scope.Thermal ScopeAkimboUnlocked - Weapon Challenge.Equips two weapons that can be fired independently, but disables the option to aim down sight.AkimboRapid FireUnlocked - Weapon Challenge.Increases the rate of fire for you gun, but increases recoil and muzzle rise.Rapid FireFMJUnlocked - Weapon Challenge.Improves damage when bullets hit enemies through objects.Much easier for bullet penetration, and is needed to unlock Extended Mags.Full Metal JacketExtended MagsUnlocked - Weapon Challenge, get 40 bullet penetration kills with FMJ (Full Metal Jacket).Extended MagsKillstreaksYou are able to customize killstreak rewards to your liking. There are a total of 15 to unlock and you are limited to carry 3 every game. Once every few levels you'll earn a point to unlock a killstreak award.KillstreakDescriptionKills RequiredIconUAVDeploys a UAV to scan the map and reveal enemy locations on the minimap. Enemies with Cold Blooded perk will not be revealed. The deployed UAV can be shot down by enemies rockets or small arms fire.3 killsUAVCare PackageDeployed by throwing a red smoke grenade. The airdropped package contains a random killstreak or ammo (except Care Package, Emergency Airdrop and Tactical Nuke). The care package can be picked up by anyone once it hits the ground, including the enemy team, although picking up the package takes much longer for those whom the package does not belong to.4 killsCare PackageCounter-UAVTemporarily disables the enemy's minimap, regardless of whether they are using UAV or not. Also disables the map screen for other kill streaks such as airstrikes.4 killsCounter-UAVSentry GunDeployed by throwing a red smoke grenade. The airdropped package contains a placeable Sentry Gun. The Sentry Gun automatically fires at enemies in its line of sight, but it can be destroyed by enemy fire, or temporarily disabled by enemy Stun and Flash Grenades. The owner of the Sentry Gun can pick up and relocate it at anytime as long as it's not disabled. Can be destroyed by a single knife attack, but not a throwing knife. It has 1000 health.5 killsSentry GunPredator MissileFires a remote controllable missile via laptop at a designated target area, leaves the user of the missile defenseless for the time being. Its speed can be boosted by pressing the fire button. Can also be used to shoot down enemy air support in a single shot, as flares do not affect the missile.5 killsPredator MissilePrecision Air StrikeThree planes drops an airstrike on a targeted area. The user can control the direction of which the airstrike comes from.6 killsPrecision Air StrikeHarrier StrikeCalls in three harriers on targeted area. The first two will fly over to drop a small cluster of bombs. The third will remain hovering over the battlefield, gunning down enemies. The harrier does not move around, but instead spins to target enemies while hovering. It has 3000 health and cuts player damage against it in half.7 killsHarrier StrikeAttack HelicopterCalls in a support helicopter to attack enemy players. The helicopter moves around the map, occasionally stopping and change direction. It has 1500 health.7 killsAttack HelicopterEmergency AirdropDeployed by throwing a red smoke grenade. Like the Care Package, the airdropped packages contains killstreaks or ammo. However, the Emergency Airdrop drops four packages instead of the Care Packages' single drop. These packages are also less accurate than the single version, requiring an open area to make sure all packages dropped are accessible. The packages dropped by the Emergency Airdrop have a greater chance to have higher tier killstreaks than the Care Packages.8 killsEmergency AirdropPave LowCalls in a heavy armored assault helicopter, far better equipped than the Attack Helicopter. Can deploy two anti-missile flares.Once the flares have taken two or more hits the Pavelow will be vulnerable. It has 3000 health.9 killsPave LowStealth BomberCalls in a Stealth Bomber to drop a large carpet of bombs. The Stealth Bomber cannot be shot down or stopped, even using EMP. Like the airstrike, the direction of the bomb drop can be chosen.9 killsStealth BomberChopper GunnerDeploys an Apache gunship, of which the player controls its gun via a laptop, leaving the user defenseless for the time being. Equipped with a single flare. It has 1000 health.11 killsChopper GunnerAC-130Deploys an AC-130 plane, of which the player control its 105mm, 40mm and 25mm cannons, leaving the user defenseless for the time being. Equipped with 2 flares. Like the UAV it is invisible on the minimap to enemies, but can in fact be shot down by a Predator missile. It has only 1000 health.11 killsAC-130EMPCalls in an Electromagnetic Pulse bomb, which disable all electronics (including claymores, C4, etc.), crashing all helicopters and airplanes (except the Stealth Bombers), disabling Sentry Guns and Red Dot or Holographic Sights (except F2000 red dot). Does not stop a Tactical Nuke. The opposing force hit with an EMP will also see screen distortion slightly impairing the team's entire HUD and visual line of sight.15 killsEMPTactical NukeThis nuclear bomb is dropped by a plane and causes instant death for anybody on the map. Results in an instant win for the activator's team. A ten second countdown is initiated when the tactical nuke is called in. A tactical nuke stops the current match's time the instant it's initiated, halting any score additions to the match's total, however, XP can still be obtained within the ten second countdown. Any killstreaks that are in the air at the time of the blast get destroyed and the player who launched the nuke receives the XP for it.25 killsTactical NukeDeathstreaksSimilar to killstreaks, deathstreaks are provided to players for dying a number of times in a row without acquiring any kills.DeathstreakDescriptionDeaths RequiredIconCopycatUnlocked - Level 4Allows the player to copy the class of the player that killed him.3 deathsCopycatPainkillerUnlocked - Level 6Double health for ten seconds after respawn.4 deathsPainkillerMartyrdomUnlocked - Level 27Drop a live grenade when killed.4 deathsMartyrdomFinal StandUnlocked - Level 39Final stand allows the player to crawl around with their primary weapon before dying, with the possibility to recover.4 deathsFinal StandPerksBlue PerksPerkStandardProStandard IconPro IconSleight of HandUnlocked - Level 4Faster ReloadingUnlocked - 120 kills using sleight of hand.Quicker sight aiming.Sleight of HandSleight of Hand ProMarathonUnlocked - Level 4Unlimited sprintUnlocked - Sprint 26 miles.Enables you to climb obstacles faster.MarathonMarathon ProScavengerUnlocked - Level 13Get ammunition, including claymores, grenade launcher rounds and frag grenades from dead bodiesUnlocked - Resupply 100 times using scavengerStarts with extra magazine clips.ScavengerScavenger ProBlingUnlocked - Level 21.Allows two attachments for primary weapon.Unlocked - Get 200 kills using a weapon with two attachments.x2 attachments for secondary weapon.BlingBling ProOne Man ArmyUnlocked - Level 45Switch classes in-game (while alive).Unlocked - Get 120 kills using one man army.Quicker in game class swapping.One Man ArmyOne Man Army ProRed PerksPerkStandardProStandard IconPro IconStopping PowerUnlocked - Level 4Increased Bullet Damage.Unlocked- Get 250 kills with stopping power.Increases bullet damage on helicopters and vehicles.Stopping PowerStopping Power ProLightweightUnlocked - Level 4Increased Mobility.Unlocked - Sprint 30 miles using light weightQuick aim after sprinting.LightweightLightweight ProHardlineUnlocked - Level 9One less kill required per killstreak.Unlocked - Get 40 killstreaks with hardlineDeathstreaks requirements reduced by one.HardlineHardline ProCold BloodedUnlocked - Level 25Invisible to UAV, sentry guns, thermal imagery, and air support.Unlocked - Destroy 40 enemy killstreak rewards using cold bloodedNo red crosshair or name shown when you are targetedCold BloodedCold Blooded ProDanger CloseUnlocked - Level 33Increases explosive weapons damage.Unlocked - Get 100 kills with explosives using danger closeAdds extra damage to killstreak explosions (such as airstrikes, predator missile, and AC-130).Danger CloseDanger Close ProYellow PerksPerkStandardProStandard IconPro IconCommandoUnlocked - Level 4Increased Melee Range.Unlocked - Get 20 melee kills using commandoNo fall damage.CommandoCommando ProSteady AimUnlocked - Level 4Increased Hip Fire Accuracy.Unlocked - get 80 kills from the hipExtends steady sight aiming with scopes.Steady AimSteady Aim ProScramblerUnlocked - Level 17The ability to jam nearby radar.Unlocked - Get 50 close range kills using scramblerPuts a delay in enemy claymores.ScramblerScrambler ProNinjaUnlocked - Level 29Invisible to heartbeat sensors.Unlocked - Get 50 close range kills with ninjaUser footsteps are heard at 25% of normal sound.NinjaNinja ProSitRepUnlocked - Level 37Shows enemy explosives and tactical insertions deployed.Unlocked - Destroy 120 enemy devicesEnemy footstep sounds are heard 400% louder while ally and user footsteps are 25% of normal but only to the user.SitRepSitRep ProLast StandUnlocked - Level 41Use your secondary weapon while crawling around on the ground until you bleed out.Unlocked - Get 20 kills while in Last StandUse of equipment while in Last stand.Last StandLast Stand ProPrestige ModeAfter reaching level 70, players can give it all back to earn a little something special. Upon entering Prestige Mode, you are reset to level 1 of the next prestige, losing everything but your titles and emblems. You also get exclusive prestige challenges.UnlocksPrestige EmblemsPrestige 1: Extra Custom Class Slot(6 Total), New Emblem, New TitlePrestige 2: New Emblem, New TitlePrestige 3: Extra Custom Class Slot(7 Total), New Emblem, New TitlePrestige 4: New Emblem, New TitlePrestige 5: Extra Custom Class Slot(8 Total), New Emblem, New TitlePrestige 6: New Emblem, New TitlePrestige 7: Extra Custom Class Slot(9 Total), New Emblem, New TitlePrestige 8: New Emblem, New TitlePrestige 9: Extra Custom Class Slot(10 Total), New Emblem, New TitlePrestige 10: New Emblem, New TitleCallsignsOne of Many TitlesModern Warfare 2 introduced Callsigns (Titles and Emblems) to the franchise. In an interview with Giant Bomb, Robert Bowling explained that Callsigns were designed to personalize the experience of players by rewarding them for their style of play. There are 512 Titles and 350 Emblems in the game. The systematic rewarding of players is a concept that has since been used in many other competitive online shooters and games in general.Glitches, Bugs  PatchesSince its' release Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 has encountered numerous in-game glitches and bugsThe Javelin - An exploit in which the player equips a Javelin (or any launcher) and the second they are killed set off the launcher killing those in the blast radius.Care Package/Emergency Airdrop - An exploit in which the player is able to call air drops infinitely.Infinite Ammo - A 360 specific bug which enables infinite ammunition in online multiplayer matches.Prestige Mode - A PS3 specific bug that grants Prestige Status, unlocking all emblems, titles, etc.Private Matches - Allows Private Matches with custom rulesets to be joined via Matchmaking.Model 1887 - Many have complained about the range and firepower of these shotguns even when dual wielded.Ice Skating Glitch - Speeds up player movement significantly and reduces friction when sprinting.Negative XP - A 360 specific bug that causes people to lose millions of XP whenever they kill someone that has the hack on their consoleForehead bullets - Although not technically a glitch, it is a problem that has plagued the Call of Duty series from the start. The issue is that bullets come out of the top of the players head as opposed to their gun. This means players are able to hide behind objects almost completely out of site from the enemy yet still be able to see them clearly and shoot in clear space above the cover.In response, Infinity Ward has been constantly updating the game to fix these issues. Here is a list of fixed issues so far:Dec '09 Fixes1887s Balanced.Public "private" Match fix.Infinite Ammo fix.Prestige Hack on PS3 fix.Texture Hack on PC fix (eliminates any edits to IWD files also)Playlist Update: Prevention for "Chopper Gunner Ammo" HackYou may notice a playlist update today on Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 for Xbox 360 and PS3. This update adds preventative measures that restrict a recent "Chopper Gunner ammo for all weapons" hack from spreading into public matchmaking.We'll continue to monitor and work to keep games as cheating free and fair as possible.This specific hack isn't on PC, however banning cheaters via VAC on PC is a continual effort and focus of ours nonetheless.Patch 1.05 (PS3)Improves matchmaking on the PS3Patch 1.06 (PC, PS3 and Xbox 360)Released on Jan 18, '10 for the PC versionCare Package, Emergency Airdrop, and Sentry Gun marker grenades sprint speed normalized.Sentry Guns: Improved placement detection, preventing cases of Sentry Guns inside geometry.Model 1887: Bling using Akimbo and FMJ combination now has same range and damage as non-Bling Model 1887sImproved player collision removing cases of getting into geometry and 'elevators'Mouse latency tweaks for more mouse movement consistency.Fixes to prevent various texture and XP hacks.Production  MarketingLos Angeles Times reported that Activision and Infinity Ward spent roughly "$40-50 million" on development of MW2. The launch budget, which included marketing and the production  distribution of the physical discs, was significantly higher at $200 million. From promos during the NBA playoffs to showing demos to movie stars, Infinity Ward was keen on hyping Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 well into its' November release date.Primetime PromotionFlexing their muscle and pull, Activision started this commercial onslaught with an NBA playoff reveal trailer. Essentially two minute video about the campaign. The trailer itself was cut short only after 30 seconds and wasn't shown until the end of the basketball game.AftermathThe next commercial though, titled Infamy, fared better than their first attempt and was shown in its' full two minute running time. It was aired during Sunday Night Football with the San Diego Chargers and Pittsburgh Steelers. The most notable images from the video were of Washington, D.C.; specifically locations of a Capitol Building and White House burning after a terrorist attack that garnered controversy from the public.Nearing its release date and seeing another prime time sporting event it was time for the launch trailer. The trailer was shown during game 6 of the World series. It used Eminem's "Till I Collapse" and was mostly recycled footage from previous videos but also featured new video of the player in outer space.MW2: Ghost ComicVariant CoverThere will be a new series of comics based on a character named " Ghost". The series is simply titled MW2: Ghost and will be worked on by David Lapham. It is a six issues series that will tell the origins of the character and how he got his nickname. The series will take place across the world from Mexico, Afghanistan to the United Kingdom.The NameWhen the first teaser trailer for Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 was revealed, the Call of Duty brand was missing. For a long time, the game was just called Modern Warfare 2. This was in part due to the fact that Infinity Ward wanted Modern Warfare to stand out as its own IP and to show that this was a direct sequel to the first Modern Warfare.However, the Call of Duty name still ended up on the game's box. This is due to a study conducted by the research firm OTX, showing that brand awareness for the game dropped 20% when it didn't have the Call of Duty name on the box. In their report, OTX stated this:The Call of Duty brand association essentially doubles the awareness for the game.The game's official cover was revealed on Robert Bowling's Twitter. An Activision spokesperson came out and explained the name change to Kotaku:Infinty Ward's Modern Warfare 2 is the direct sequel to Call of Duty 4: Modern Warfare. We have focused our attention on Modern Warfare in order to most effectively communicate the fact that this is the first true sequel in the Call of Duty series. Infinity Ward, the original creators of the Call of Duty franchise, has said from the beginning Modern Warfare 2 resides in the Call of Duty universe. This is reflected in the title's package .Despite this comment, the Modern Warfare 2 logo can be found on parts of the collector's edition without the Call of Duty brand name over it.Seeing Stars in Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2It has been confirmed that rapper 50 Cent will have his voice featured as a squad leader in MW2's multiplayer Special Ops mode. Also, rock group Good Charlotte were seen with 50 Cent during the gameplay session. Other well known testers of Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 have included comedian Dane Cook and The Office star Rainn Wilson.Monster Energy Drink MW 2 EditionMonster Energy and Activision have partnered together bring a Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 branded beverage to the US. This will hit store shelves in four packs beginning in October. Included in each package is a code that can be redeemed online for a chance to win one of several prizes. The giveaway list is as follows:100 copies of Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 for Xbox 360 or PS35,000 Map pack codes - planned release Spring 201010,000 codes for a Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 dashboard themeFree cans of Monster Energy drinksRelease VersionsStandard EditionIncludes the game disc and manual.Priced at $59.99.Hardened EditionHardened EditionIncludes everything found in the Standard Edition in addition to:Special metallic and holographic limited edition packaging.Token to download Call of Duty Classic on XBL Arcade and PSN.Hardbound art book, “Behind the Lines” with concept art from the game.Priced at $79.99.Veteran EditionVeteran EditionSpecial Edition only available in the UK and exclusive to British online retailer Game.co.uk.Includes everything found in the Hardened Edition in addition to:Captain MacTavish ARTFX Statue sculpted by Kotobukiya as seen in the "Cliffhanger" mission.Priced at £119.99 (roughly $174.99).Prestige EditionPrestige EditionIncludes everything found in the Hardened Edition.Fully functional night vision goggles branded with the Modern Warfare 2 and Infinity Ward logo.Soap MacTavish Sculpted head designed to display the night vision goggles when not in use.Priced at $149.99.Limited Edition Modern Warfare 2 Xbox 360MW2 360 BundleThis special edition Xbox 360 shipped on November 10, 2009 for $399.99 It included the followingDetachable 250GB HDD2 Black wireless controllersBlack headset (not the Madcatz throat mic)Regular edition of Modern Warfare 21 Ethernet Cable1 Xbox 360 Composite A/V cableFree one month subscription to Xbox LIVE GoldFree Netflix trial offerSales  PiracyCall of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 achieved record-breaking sales following its release, with nearly 5 million copies sold within the first 24 hours in the USA and UK.After crossing $550 million in revenue during the first 5 days, Activision declared it the biggest entertainment launch in history. According to NPD numbers, the game sold more than 6 million copies during November 2009 in the US alone. As of August 2010 combined PS3 and Xbox 360 sales of MW2 total over 19 million.Apart from being the best selling game of 2009, Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 also earned the unfortunate title of being the most pirated game of the year. Torrentfreak released a report on Dec 27 '09, saying that over 4.1 million copies of the game had been illegally downloaded through BitTorrent services.ControversyPC Issues  Lack of Dedicated ServersRobert Bowling, community manager at Infinity Ward, announced on the BASH podcast that the PC version of MW2 will be taking a more console-like approach towards multiplayer and would use the IWnet matchmaking system. He also confirmed that the PC version won't support any fully dedicated servers or mods. This sparked a huge outcry from the PC community, who started a petition directed at Infinity Ward to reconsider their decision. The petition garnered over 240,000 signatures but Infinity War still successfully launched the PC version in Nov '09.During a promotional Best Buy web-chat with Infinity Ward on November 3rd, a representative of Infinity ward confirmed details of previous IW PC announcements and made a controversial comment concerning the PC version of MW2.Ignoring IW.net, is the PC version a direct port of the console version?Mackey-IWNo, PC has custom stuff like mouse control, text chat in game, and graphics settings.On November 5th, Vince Zampella of Infinity Ward indirectly confirmed the fact that players of the PC version will not allow players to access to the dev console so change settings such as FOV, weapon damage etc.Party Chat DisabledCall of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 does not support party chat on the Xbox 360. When you try to enter a multiplayer game with party chat on, the game automatically ask you to switch party chat off or quit the game. This was meant to encourage team work in multiplayer.Viral VideoA couple weeks before the game launched, a viral video was released by Infinity Ward to promote the game. In this video, Philadelphia Phillies pitcher Cole Hamels starts telling the viewer about the dangers of grenade spam. The video is set up as if it were a public service announcement with the pitcher telling us how spamming grenades is bad and for "pussies". The ad ends with the name of the fake organization that promotes this message: Fight Against Grenade Spam (or F.A.G.S.).Many people criticized the ad, calling it a proof of bad taste and an acceptance of the homophobic behavior of some players on Live. Some thought of better acronyms that wouldn't offend like F.R.A.G.S. The problem was finally resolved on Twitter between the freelancer Michael Dyer and Infinity Ward's Robert Bowling. After reacting to the video and arguing with a viewer about it, Dyer ended up talking to Bowling when Robert saw Michael's complaints about the video. Robert Bowling told Michael Dyer this:I think it was more of a social commentary joke of that stereotype than it was a fist-bump of acceptance to it.To which Dyer answered:The problem is that it was so poorly handled/executed that it looks derogatory. It seems to enforce the asshole-ry.Finally, Bowling responded to this, deciding to pull the video:I agree. I think the core gag is great, the end is a bit too far from the intent of the joke  can appreciate the concerns. Pulled.The video was later parodied in a Battlefield Bad Company 2 ad where Sweetwater and Yankee's CC Sabathia promote "Friends Really Against Grenade Spam" (F.R.A.G.S.).This wasn't the last time Infinity Ward would make an edgy joke about homosexuality. In the game's tutorial level at the army camp, there's an easter egg where the player can overhear a conversation between two soldiers, one asking the other one if he's ever seen a grown man naked and if he's still gay. The dialog ends with the soldier telling you "don't ask, don't tell". This is a reference to the US military's former policy that barred openly homosexual men and women from joining the military unless they kept their sexual orientation a secret.Objectionable ContentAdditional controversy arose when a video was posted on the internet that leaked gameplay footage of one of the "No Russian" mission, which set the player as an undercover CIA-operative in a Russian airport alongside Makarov and other terrorists as they gun down civilians. Infinity Ward later confirmed the chapter's authenticity and claimed that it can be skipped by the player at anytime after a displayed warning via the pause menu.Since the game's release reactions to the sequence have been mixed; some point out that it allows the player to have a genuine reason to hate the main villain and they don't have to partake in the massacre whereas others have found the scenario to be in poor taste.Due to this level, the Russian government recalled all copies of the game, and banned its further sale. Infinity Ward has responded to the banning by promising to make a version of the game with the level completely omitted. Activision quickly cut the scene for Russian retailers and released this statement to Eurogamer:"Other countries have formal ratings boards that we regularly work with. However, Russia does not have a formal ratings entity. As a result, we chose to block the scene after seeking the advice of local counsel."SoundtrackThe Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 Original SoundtrackThe music heard in the game is all orchestral and sounds a lot darker than in previous games. The game's main themes were composed by Hans Zimmer who also produced the score (this was the first time he worked on a video game). The rest of the score was also composed by Lorne Balfe. The soundtrack was released on June the 1st, 2010 for 10 US dollars.Track #Song TitleRunning Time1.Opening Titles3:252.Extraction Point3:253.Breach3:224.Guerrilla Tactics2:585.Siege4:056.Infiltration4:277.Esprit de Corps3:078.Retreat and Reveille2:579.Ordinance1:5810.Contingency2:1511.Onwards2:2712.Code of Conduct2:0913.Chain of Command2:0014.Safeguard2:4315.Deadline3:5516.Protocol3:4717.Coup de Grace3:21PC System RequirementsMinimum RequirementsOS: Microsoft Windows XP, Windows Vista and Windows 7Processor: Intel Pentium 4 3.2 GHz or AMD Athlon 64 3200 processor or betterMemory: 1 GB RAMGraphics: ATI Radeon 1600XT or better or 256 MB NVIDIA GeForce 6600GT or betterDirectX: Microsoft DirectX(R) 9.0cHard Drive: 12GB of free hard drive spaceSound: 100% DirectX 9.0c compatible sound cardInternet: Broadband connection required for Multiplayer Connectivity. Internet Connection required for activation.Co-op/Multiplayer Hosting: To host Co-op or MP matches, a 2Ghz dual-core or better processor is recommended.Xbox 360 Hard Drive InstallInstalling Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 on your Xbox 360 hard drive takes up 6.8 GB of space.Japanese versionThe Japanese version is published by Square Enix, it has both Japanese language but also subtitles, which many Japanese gamers complained about for being wildly inaccurate. For example, during the No Russian mission Makarov says "Remember - no Russian", but in the Japanese version of the game the translation comes out to "Kill them - they are Russians", which is the exact opposite of his intentions.Downloadable ContentFirst announced at E3 2009, there will be at least two map packs released for Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 - both will be timed Xbox 360 exclusives. The first map pack, dubbed "The Stimulus Package," was released on March 30th, 2010 for 1200 Microsoft Points ($15) and was then released on the PS3 and PC on May 4, 2010 for the same price. It contains five maps, entitled:CrashOvergrownBailoutSalvageStormCrash and Overgrown were maps found in Call of Duty 4 ported over to Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2.The second map pack is called "Resurgence" and was first released on the Xbox 360 June 3, 2010 for the same price as the first map pack and was then released on the PS3 and PC July 3, 2010. It contains five maps, entitled:CarnivalTrailer ParkFuelVacantStrikeVacant and Strike were maps found in Call of Duty 4 ported over to Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2.</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20601">Killzone 2</game><game id="6246">SOCOM: U.S. Navy SEALs</game><game id="21116">MAG</game><game id="1986">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six: Vegas 2</game><game id="8369">Black</game><game id="15048">Killzone</game><game id="20699">Resistance 2</game><game id="17491">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six 3: Black Arrow</game><game id="2397">Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon: Advanced Warfighter</game><game id="270">Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon: Advanced Warfighter 2</game><game id="29336">Medal of Honor</game><game id="29463">Alliance of Valiant Arms</game><game id="28952">Marines: Modern Urban Combat</game><game id="25246">Battlefield: Bad Company 2</game><game id="30470">Battle Territory: Battery</game><game id="30185">Blacklight: Tango Down</game><game id="20665">Far Cry 2</game><game id="30566">Sniper: Ghost Warrior</game><game id="30478">Breach</game><game id="34081">Duty Calls: The Calm Before the Storm</game><game id="27006">Battlefield 3</game><game id="35432">Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon Online</game><game id="35972">Battlefield 2: Armored Fury</game><game id="36113">Counter-Strike: Global Offensive</game><game id="36230">Blacklight Retribution</game><game id="35307">Gotham City Impostors</game><game id="36816">Tom Clancy's Rainbow 6: Patriots</game><game id="38072">Ravaged</game><game id="38773">Persian Gulf Soldiers</game><game id="39691">Killzone Trilogy</game><game id="34412">Hawken</game><game id="42860">Titanfall</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8169/1112856-modern_warfare_2_cover.png</image></root>