<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24738</id><name>3 on 3 NHL Arcade</name><description>OverviewThe same development team that behind NHL 09 returns to the rink but with a radically different take on hockey.  3 on 3 NHL Arcade is a simple and easy to play game. You really don't have to know anything about the game of hockey to be able to enjoy the game. After big hits, power-ups drop on the ice (for instance, super speed, faster shots or one that makes your opponents goalie tiny). It also features an easy to use control scheme. The online play is your usual 1-on-1 or  you and your friends can play on the same side and face-off vs random people online. There are the options to play unranked games and ranked games and play a friend , just like in past "official" NHL games. Offline options are limited to a quick play option against the CPU, there is no season mode.  On May 24, 2010, the game was moved into the Arcade Hits section of the Xbox Live Marketplace and its price was changed to 400 Microsoft Points. Power-ups Super Shot : Super Fast Shot That Clears A Path Big Player : Makes your player HUGE! Freeze: Freeze 1 opponent Banana: Slip and Fall Super Speed: Makes Your Player Skate Super Fast Double Score: Two Goals For The Price Of One Small Goalie: Shrink The Opponent's Goalie Big Goalie: Big Saves From A Big Goalie RosterEach of the 30 NHL teams are represented in the 40 man roster for the game while some teams (like Washington, Detroit and Montreal) are represented by multiple players.You can pick any three of the skaters (any combination of fast, all around or strong players) and one goalie per team. The division between player types is somewhat similar to the NES classic game;    Ice Hockey, which featured a skinny guy (fast), a fat guy (strong) and a normal guy (all-around).Here are the players featured in the game: Is that blocker regulation size? All Around Players:Brad Boyes - St. Louis BluesSidney Crosby - Pittsburgh PenguinsShane Doan - Phoenix CoyotesMarian Gaborik - Minnesota WildMike Green - Washington CapitalsDany Heatley - Ottawa SenatorsKristian Huselius - Columbus Blue JacketsJarome Iginla - Calgary FlamesAnze Kopitar - Los Angeles KingsIlya Kovalchuk - Atlanta ThrashersVincent Lecavalier - Tampa Bay LightningAlexander Ovechkin - Washington CapitalsJeremy Roenick - San Jose SharksJason Spezza - Ottawa Senators  It's not a hockey sim, but the object is still to score goals on the other team. Fast Players:Sean Avery - Dallas StarsDaniel Briere - Philadelphia FlyersAndrew Cogliano - Edmonton OilersPavel Datsyuk - Detroit Red WingsPatrick Kane - Chicago BlackhawksSaku Koivu - Montreal CanadiensAlexei Kovalev - Montreal CanadiensEvgeni Malkin - Pittsburgh PenguinsMike Modano - Dallas StarsEric Staal - Carolina HurricanesJoe Sakic - Colorado AvalancheJonathan Toews - Chicago BlackhawksThomas Vanek - Buffalo SabresHenrik Zetterberg - Detroit Red Wings Big heads and big hits.   Strong Players:Nik Antropov - Toronto Maple LeafsZdeno Chara - Boston BruinsNathan Horton - Florida PanthersMilan Lucic - Boston BruinsDion Phaneuf - Calgary FlamesChris Pronger - Anaheim DucksJoe Thornton - San Jose SharksShea Weber - Nashville PredatorsGoalies:Martin Brodeur - New Jersey DevilsRick DiPietro - New York IslandersHenrik Lundqvist - New York RangersRoberto Luongo - Vancouver Canucks</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="39">Hockey</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8270">Mutant League Hockey</game><game id="2437">NHL Hitz Pro</game><game id="11863">NHL Hitz 20-02</game><game id="19447">NHL Hitz 20-03</game><game id="22324">Hit the Ice</game><game id="28440">Madden NFL Arcade</game><game id="1899">Backyard Hockey 2005</game><game id="26458">NHL 10</game><game id="27025">NHL 2K10</game><game id="34710">NBA Jam: On Fire Edition</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1795333-box_nhlarc.png</image></root>