<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24793</id><name>MotorStorm</name><description>PremiseThe game revolves around the MotorStorm Festival, an extreme off-road racingWelcome to MotorStormevent based on Monument Valley. In order to progress in the game, the player must complete tickets, which can consist of up to four races. Completing races earns you points, which unlock more tickets and vehicules. Both first and last races take place in "The Grizzly", the biggest course of the entire game.The online servers for the game have been shut down on January 1st, 2012.GameplayThere are seven vehicules classes in MotorStorm: there are bikes, ATVs, buggies, rally cars, racing trucks, mudpluggers and big rigs. Each track in the game have multiples routes which the player must choose based on his vehicule, routes that can either advantage or disadvantage the player against other racers. For example, if the player has a lightweight vehicule, chances are he will choose a higher line, which is narrow with lots of jumps. On the flipside, if the players drives a heavyweight vehicule, he must stick to the lower ground, filled with mud, to win the race. Players must take those considerations in mind to win, and most of all, to not be swallowed by other, bigger vehicules.The racers are also given a boost meter, which can help them pass other racers. Players must be cautious though, because if the meter gets too high, the engine will overheat and make the vehicule explode. All vehicules are also destructable.TracksCoyote RageDust DevilThe GrizzlyThe MudpoolRain God MesaThe Rock HopperSidewinder GulchThe TenderizerNew tracks have been added through downloadable content.Coyote Revenge, based on the previous Coyote Rage track;Devil's Crossing, build on the remains of Dust Devil, marketed as the largest circuit of MotorStorm yet;DiamondBack Speedway, a track specially made for online multiplayer destruction through two high-speed crossings;Eagle's Nest, first showcased during the Sony E3 2007 Press Conference.VehiclesBikesMohawk IndianaMohawk Roadhog (DLC)Monarch ChampWakasashi Razor (DLC)Wasabi Oshizushi (DLC)Wasabi TwinbladeWasabi Wildcast MXWulff EnduroATVsAztec SabretoothIbex Bushfire (DLC)Mirage CalianoMolotov StuukaWasabi PhoenixWasabi RascalWombat Mudslide (DLC)BuggiesBeelzebuggy CarabidHumber Diablo (DLC)Jester BXRJester Super BXRLunar-Tec Rollcage (DLC)Voodoo RattlerWombat TyphoonRally CarsFalfer Domino (DLC)Italia GaglianoOzutsu RoninPatriot '85 (Europe Only DLC)Patriot RenegadePatriot SurgerPatriot V8 (DLC)Wulff RevoRacing TrucksCastro Capitano (DLC)Castro RobustoItalia VulcanOzutsu DaimyoSpringbok KalahariVoodoo IguanaMudpluggersAtlas Varjack (DLC)Atlas JackhammerLunar-Tec AsylumMcQueen Adventure (DLC)Mojave SluggerMonach BulldogPatriot BushwackerBig RigsAtlas Arizona (DLC)Atlas GouvernorCastro VaraderoLunar-Tec Invader (DLC)Lunar-Tec InvaderMolotov DragoNord VikingPatriot ThunderchiefSoundtrackCurve - Hell Above WaterElite Force - PreshaEvery Time I Die - The New BlackThe Experiment - The Cost of FreedomGluecifer - Automatic ThrillHyper - Hot Rockin'Kings of Leon - Spiral StaircaseKrafty Kuts feat. Tim Deluxe - Bass PhenomenonLunatic Calm - Leave You Far BehindMonster Magnet - PowertripNirvana - BreedPendulum - SlamPitchshifter - Scene ThisPrimal Scream - The 99th FloorPrimal Scream - Dolls (Sweet Rock'n Roll)Queens of the Stone Age - MedicationThe Reverend Horton Heat - Big Red Rocket of LoveSlipknot - Before I ForgetSpiritualized - ElectricityTrash Palace - Animal MagicWolfmother - WomanUpdate 3.1 added two new songs to the soundtrack:Elite Force - Devil's CrossingJiffster feat. Bard - Beat the DevilReleaseMotorStorm was first released in as a launch title for the PlayStation 3. It is important to note that this version did not support online play, a feature that both North American and European versions had when they hit store shelves. Japanese players could finally play online when an update was released on June 20, 2007, along with a new version of the game called MotorStorm Complete. The game also became one of the best-selling games on the system, as 3.31 million copies had been sold as of December 2007.Downloadable ContentMultiples downloadable content was made available for the game, which included new vehicules, paint jobs, and of course, new tracks. The first major DLC pack for MotorStorm was the Revenge Weekend pack, in which took place the Revenge Weekend, a small event that included nine new single-player races over the course of three tickets, celebrating the brand new track, Coyote Revenge. The pack also included new vehicules, like the Wombat Mudslide and the Atlas Arizona. Europe players also received the Patriot '85, a rally car based on the Delorean DMC-12. The vehicule never made it stateside.The second major downloadable pack was the Devil's Weekend pack, which included new vehicules and the largest MotorStorm course ever; the Devil's Crossing. Build on the now-destroyed Dust Devil, the track included a portion in which light to medium-weight vehicules must race on multiples crossroads, where violent crashes can take places any time those vehicules come to this part of the circuit. Of course, the pack also included ten single-player races which took place over the Devil's Weekend event, the very last race being a one-on-one showdown against the Humbler Diablo, at night.The last pack released for the game was MotorStorm Track Pack, which included two small courses made for time trial and online multiplayer.Updates1.1 March 2007:This added a buddy list feature which allowed players to play online with friends.1.2 June 2007:The fixed several technical issues, added several minor features to improve the online mode, and added a Time trial mode.2.0:Fixed more Online issues including headset issues.3.0 November 2007, in The U.S. (October 2007 in Europe):Fixed more Online Issues, and added Support for the DualShock 3.3.1 December 2007:Fixed several bugs. Allowed a 2D vehicle selector for online mode, (Instead of the default 3D selector which rendered each car, causing significant load times), and two new songs.TriviaTwo single-player races in the game are named “ Giant Enemy Crab” and “ Massive Damage”, in reference to the E3 2006 Sony Press Conference.The Dust Devil track has a banner which reads "Free The Runcorn 4". This is a reference to the four people who handled the builds for the game, which often took 12-13 hours. During this time these people were locked in the build room and were not allowed to leave until the build was completed and the discs burned ready for distribution to the test departments. The development company, Evolution Studios, is based in Runcorn.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15821">4 Wheel Thunder</game><game id="23461">FUEL</game><game id="20933">Baja: Edge of Control</game><game id="13645">Excite Truck</game><game id="5648">Burnout Paradise</game><game id="16492">Burnout Revenge</game><game id="3916">DiRT</game><game id="24513">DiRT 2</game><game id="20957">Pure</game><game id="26441">Monster Truck Madness 64</game><game id="26452">MX vs. ATV: Reflex</game><game id="20889">MX vs. ATV Untamed</game><game id="9981">MX vs. ATV Unleashed</game><game id="5389">MX vs. ATV: On the Edge</game><game id="30986">Nail'd</game><game id="30383">DiRT 3</game><game id="33354">Harms Way</game><game id="33779">Road's Edge</game><game id="44253">Angry Birds Go!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1832152-box_mstorm.png</image></root>