<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2487</id><name>Crystals of Arborea</name><description>AboutCrystals of Arborea is the predecessor to Simaril's Ishar series of RPGs in terms of story, but vastly different in gameplay. You take the role of a prince who must find four crystals that are scattered throughout one of the few remaining lands not devastated by the wrath of the gods, in order to return the crystals to their rightful places and bring about a new age. Alongside your prince is a party of six companions who can be rangers, wizards, or warriors in any combination.The game combines real-time navigation of the game world with turn-based strategic combat. Your hero character does not get directly involved in battles normally, but each of the six companions can. If the companion is a warrior, they can hit adjacent squares; if a ranger they can shoot in a straight line as long as there's one space between the ranger and the target; if a wizard they may cast a spell on any visible target, friend or foe, as long as they have enough psy power in reserve.As the characters level they grow stronger, and the game adjusts its difficulty to match player character power. While navigating the map you will run across secrets that will aid your quest, and you can look from the prince's perspective close-up at the things you find and interact with them. The prince also has other special roles, including being able to heal wounded party members and gain special abilities.AvailabilityThe game is available at gog.com and is part of the Ishar Compilation package.Minimum System RequirementsWindows XP or Windows Vista1 GHz Processor (1.4 GHz recommended)512MB RAM (1 GB recommended)3D graphics card compatible with DirectX 7 (compatible with DirectX 9 recommended), Mouse, Keyboard.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19501">Ishar: Legend of the Fortress</game><game id="20068">Ishar 2: Messengers of Doom</game><game id="7426">Ishar 3: The Seven Gates of Infinity</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15693/639579-951816_109631_front_1_.jpg</image></root>