<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>249</id><name>Command &amp; Conquer: Red Alert</name><description>OverviewSomeone helps Albert Einstein alter history by killing Adolf Hitler, and someone plants the idea to invade Europe into Joseph Stalin's head. Instead of preventing World War II they simply change it as Russia invades Europe. Spies lurk, land mines wait, and strange new technologies aid both sides in their struggle for ultimate control. Many new technologies are used by Russia and the Allies including Tesla, the Chronosphere's teleport, Iron Curtain's invulnerability and the Gap Generator's satellite surveillance blocking system. Ore, the most abundant and valuable resource on the planet, is the primary resource that funds the military might of the Soviets  Allies.The War over land and the resources it brings has gotten deadly in this alternate universe as the Soviet Union deploys Mammoth Tanks  Tesla Coils to crush the allies. Not only does the war rage on land, but also in the air and on the oceans. The allies deploy devastating Destroyers  Cruisers while the soviets deploy Submarines to counter the allies' massive navy. In the air the Allies deploy deadly Apache Helicopters while the Soviets deploy Yak  MiG aircraft and helicopters of their own. It's up to the player to decide who will win Soviet Union or the Allied Forces. Command  Conquer Red Alert gives you the opportunity to be more devious, cunning and ruthless than ever before. Easy to play and highly addictive, Command  Conquer Red Alert puts the fate of the world in your hands. On August 31st 2008, EA announced Red Alert as freeware available for download.PlotIn 1946 Trinity, New Mexico Albert Einstein forever altered history,and the world would never be the same.With help from an unnamed assistant Einstein successfully goes back in time and removes Adolf Hitler from existence. Instead of Nazi Germany rising to power, the industrialized and powerful Soviet Union quickly becomes the red menace and a threat to the free world.. Quickly Stalin's plan comes to fruition as nearly all of Europe falls to his unstoppable Soviet war machine. With Great Britain the only free country standing ,hopes are grim. But even though they are outgunned, they are not outsmarted. Using Einsteins Chronosphere mass teleportation device, the allies manage to get behind the Soviet forces, slowly retaking Europe and eventually fight back to Moscow to save themselves from the communist oppressors.Allied EndingFollowing the destruction of the remaining Soviet forces, Allied soldiers find the Stalin buried in the rubble of the former Soviet stronghold. Before recovering Stalin, General Stravos stops them and convinces them to walk away. As the soldiers leave, Stravos stuffs a handkerchief down Stalins throat and places a boulder over his head, walking away with his revenge. This is the canon ending, leading to the events of Red Alert 2.Soviet EndingThe commander finds the Soviets celebrating in the newly conquered Buckingham Palace with Stalin drinking tea. He then finds out that the tea has been poisoned by Nadia and dies. Following Stalin's death, Nadia states that the Soviet Union is under the commander of Nod but is then shot in the back with Kane revealing to be the mastermind behind everything. This is a link to the central Command and Conquer series, the struggle between Nod and the GDI.SoundtrackLike the original Command  Conquer, Red Alert is scored by Frank Klepacki.Hell March (6:26)Radio (4:07)Crush (3:51)Roll Out (3:56)Mud (4:50)Twin Cannon (3:57)Face the Enemy (5:38)Run (5:15)Terminate (5:22)Big Foot (5:17)Workmen (4:46)Militant Force (1:52)Dense (5:00)Vector (4:17)Smash (4:35)</description><genres><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14805">KKND2: Krossfire</game><game id="680">Chaos Island</game><game id="20674">StarCraft II: Wings of Liberty</game><game id="13062">StarCraft</game><game id="17672">Battlezone II: Combat Commander</game><game id="21982">Small Soldiers: Squad Commander</game><game id="17353">Star Wars: Force Commander</game><game id="20103">Warcraft II: Tides of Darkness</game><game id="1552">Dune 2000</game><game id="13125">Aliens Versus Predator: Extinction</game><game id="11360">Warrior Kings: Battles</game><game id="24890">Warfare Incorporated</game><game id="3537">Conflict Zone</game><game id="25482">Codename Panzers: Cold War</game><game id="20952">World in Conflict: Soviet Assault</game><game id="19932">Emperor: Battle for Dune</game><game id="24079">StarCraft II: Legacy of the Void</game><game id="9719">Warcraft: Orcs &amp; Humans</game><game id="14236">Dune II: The Building of a Dynasty</game><game id="4926">KKND: Krush, Kill 'N' Destroy</game><game id="33907">APOX</game><game id="9004">Rising Sun: Imperial Strike</game><game id="18237">Mission: Humanity</game><game id="20195">War Front: Turning Point</game><game id="15235">Dark Reign: The Future of War</game><game id="32355">Age of Empires Online</game><game id="31231">Achron</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2130/637220-ra.jpg</image></root>