<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24901</id><name>MLB 09: The Show</name><description>The newest addition to Sony's MLB: The Show series. It adds new gameplay and depth to the franchise. The game was released for the PS2, PSP, and PS3. It features Dustin Pedroia of the Boston Redsox on the cover.Game ModesQuick GameAllows you to one game against a friend or against a computer. You can pick between any of the baseball teams.Road to the ShowYay we won.The Road to the Show is the main feature of MLB 09: The Show and the franchise itself. It does what the other games did. Lets you create a character and play with them throughout a career. It does add much more features though. Players can now interact with the manager and negotiate their contracts. After playing 6 full seasons in the Major Leagues, players become free agents and can then receive contracts from other MLB teams. Players can also take batting practice to gain points to upgrade their characters.Players are given advancement goals that vary based on their position. These consists of 3-6 goals a player must complete in a specified time in order to remain in good standing with their organization. For a pitcher, a player may be asked to increase Stamina rating over a 3 week period, and a first baseman for example may need to increase more offensive statistics such as contact and power.If the layer repeatedly fails to complete these goals, the manager may choose to bench, demote, or even release the player from the team for the remainder of the season.FranchiseAllows players to control a team for multiple years. Players can control every aspect of their team such as editing the lineup, pitching rotation, vendors at their home stadium, ticket pricing and vendor pricing. Players can also trade for players and also be offered trades by CPU controlled teams, sign free agents, and draft players. Games can be simulated or played and players can have some innings simulated from withing the game. There is also a limited way to set training to players based on position and you can view stats for each player, view league leaders, the top All Star vote receivers, and the leaders in the various awards MLB hands out to deserving players such as MVP and Rookie of the Year.Introduced for the first time in the series, the Franchise Mode in MLB 09: The Show featured an expanded feature set in dealing with free agents including arbitration, contract renewal, management of 40 man roster, Rule 5 drafts and the monitoring of service time. The inclusion of these features allowed players to have more authentic General Manager experience.SeasonThis feature allows players to take control of one team for a full season (162 games) and into the playoffs, though lacks the in-depth managerial options that is found in Franchise mode.RivalryAllows you to play against your rival. The game keeps track of who wins and loses games so you always know who is ahead.Manager ModeManage a game. You have limited controls over the gameplay and can only make decissions an acting MLB manager can make. In this mode players are even able to view the game from their teams dugout, however this offers a fairly limited view of the games events.Practice ModeAllows you to practice either batting or Road to the Show baserunning. In batting a player can chose any batter from any team and hit against any pitcher from any team. The player can also chose which pitches in the chosen pitchers repertoire, and then chose the difficulty, stadium, and other options.In baserunning the player can practice running the bases using the same gameplay from Road to the Show.Sports ConnectMLB 09: The Show's online portion of the game. Players can form and join leagues, get matched into an online game, and challenge other playeys in chat rooms. Players can also upload and download other user's customly edited rosters and sliders (settings) and also give a limited rating. Sports Connect also provides a live ticker of current, past, and future MLB game scores.Create-A-PlayerPlayers can create custom players and enter them into the games roster system. Players can choose from hundred of animated batting stances and pitching windups, control attire, facial characteristics, and adjust attributes as they see fit. This is the same system used in the Road to the Show mode, but with unlimited attribute points.Team RankingsAll 30 Major League Baseball teams are ranked in game by 4 separate categories: Overall, Batting, Pitching, and Defense. The team rankings are the following:Overall RankingBatting RankingPitching RankingDefense Ranking1. Boston Red SoxYankeesRed SoxRed Sox2. New York YankeesCubsYankeesBlue Jays3.Chicago CubsIndiansCubsPhillies4. Philadelphia PhilliesRed SoxRaysMets5. New York MetsPhilliesAngelsMariners6. Los Angelas Angels of AnaheimRangersMetsTigers7. Tampa Bay RaysBrewersRockiesDodgers8. Detroit TigersWhite SoxBlue JaysRays9. Minnesota TwinsTigersRedsYankees10. Cincinnati RedsRaysPhilliesCubs11. Atlanta BravesRockiesGiantsAngels12. Los Angeles DodgersCardinalsAstrosBraves13. Colorado RockiesAngelsBravesTwins14. Arizona DiamondbacksRedsTwinsOrioles15. Cleveland IndiansDiamondbacksDodgersAstros16. Toronto Blue JaysMetsIndiansCardinals17. Milwaukee BrewersBravesMarinersRangers18. Houston AstrosRoyalsTigersPadres19. Texas RangersMarlinsDiamondbacksAthletics20. Kansas City RoyalsNationalsAthleticsRockies21. Chicago White SoxDodgersRoyalsIndians22. San Francisco GiantsPadresMarlinsNationals23. St. Louis CardnialsTwinsCardinalsGiants24. Seattle MarinersAstrosWhite SoxRoyals25. Florida MarlinsBlue JaysBrewersBrewers26. Oakland AthleticsAthleticsRangersPirates27. San Diego PadresMarinersPadresReds28. Washington NationalsGiantsPiratesWhite Sox29. Baltimore OriolesPiratesOriolesDiamondbacks30. Pittsburgh PiratesOriolesNationalsMarlinsSoundtrackTwo Ways Out- Darker My LoveWannabe In L.A- Eagles of Death MetalWork, Work, Work- HockeyNever Miss a Beat- Kaiser ChiefsEl Barrio Boricua- MingShine On Me- Night HorseCollapse (Post-Amerika)- Rise AgainstDon't You Evah- SpoonMan Up- The Blue VanBudos Rising- The Budos BandEverything You're Breathing For- The Parlor MobRooibos- The StillsGolden Age- TV on the RadioSafe to Say- ValenciaM. Mambo- Zodiac Death ValleyYou can also add your own music to the soundtrack from your hard drive, and arrange them as you see fit.</description><genres><genre id="34">Baseball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="24440">Major League Baseball 2K9</game><game id="9978">MVP Baseball 2005</game><game id="21255">Major League Baseball 2K7</game><game id="5295">MVP Baseball 2004</game><game id="4908">MVP Baseball 2003</game><game id="25511">The BIGS 2</game><game id="7266">Ken Griffey Jr Presents Major League Baseball</game><game id="21259">MVP 06 NCAA Baseball</game><game id="23470">Home Run King</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1832924-box_mlb09.png</image></root>