<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24967</id><name>Disgaea 2: Dark Hero Days</name><description>Overview Disgaea 2: Dark Hero Days is a port of the original Disgaea 2 game for the Playstation 2.  This game was released on September 6th, 2009 for the PSP system in America by Nippon Ichi Software Inc.  In the game, you play as Adell, a Demon Hunter who's family has been turned into demons by Overlord Zennon.  In a strange summoning ritual, Adell's mother summons forth from a cauldron the daughter of Lord Zennon, Rozalin.  With Rozalin bounded to her captors, she must lead Adell to the home of her father so that he may battle him and save the souls of his family and loved ones.  But, since Rozalin is a demon, will she lead him to the correct location or try to kill him along the way? Changes from Disgaea 2: Cursed Memories  New ShopsThe Music Shop introduced in Disgaea: Afternoon of DarknessThe Character Paint Shop that was introduced in Disgaea 3The Record Shop from Disgaea: Afternoon of DarknessNew ModesAxel Mode: In this mode, you can play as Axel and explore the events that took place before the events of the previous game.New ClassesFemale SamuraiDeath SaberGreat WyrmCelestial HostMass Produced KurtisNew Playable CharactersMaoRaspberylMr. ChamplooPrism RedMarjolyPriereCaptain GordonMid-BossZettaMagichange - a feature that was first introduced in Disgaea 3 that allows a human character to use a monster character as a weapon to cause massive damage.Throw and Receive - Another feature from Disgaea 3, this lets you throw characters and have other humanoid characters catch them.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20593">Jeanne d'Arc</game><game id="7281">Astonishia Story</game><game id="21996">Dungeons and Dragons Tactics</game><game id="9600">Metal Gear Ac!d</game><game id="8702">Metal Gear Ac!d 2</game><game id="21961">Wild Arms XF</game><game id="29245">Queen's Blade: Spiral Chaos</game><game id="29281">Akatsuki no Amaneka to Aoi Kyojin: Pashiate Bunmei Kenkyuukai Koubouki</game><game id="13936">Warhammer 40,000: Squad Command</game><game id="27388">Valkyria Chronicles II</game><game id="27861">Shin Megami Tensei: Persona 3 Portable</game><game id="33448">Vantage Master</game><game id="30167">Zettai Hero Project: Unlosing Ranger vs. Darkdeath Evilman</game><game id="29872">Dokapon DX</game><game id="36104">Card Hunter</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1832912-box_disgaea2psp.png</image></root>