<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24980</id><name>Grand Ages: Rome</name><description>OverviewGrand Ages: Rome is a historical city-building strategy game by Bulgarian developers Haemimont Games and released on March 17th, 2009. It was originally designed as a sequel to 2008's Imperium Romanum.GameplayBefore starting a game, the player must create a character by choosing their family, name, gender and portrait. There are five families to choose from — the Flavii, Valerii, Julii, Aemilii and the Lucii — each of which confer different bonuses. The player's character may be shared across campaign, free build and multiplayer modes.The primary goal of each mission is to construct a Roman colony which meets certain conditions, all the while balancing the needs of the colony's different classes.CampaignSet during the final years of the Roman Republic, the campaign tasks the player with restoring their family's fortune and establishing themselves as a Roman statesman and leader. Certain missions are given by historical figures like Marcus Tullius Cicero and Marcus Crassus.Free BuildFree Build allows the player to build a colony free from the campaign's objectives.MultiplayerUp to four players may compete or co-operate across 6 different multiplayer modes.System RequirementsMinimum System RequirementsOperating system: Windows XP  VistaProcessor: 2.5 GHz Single Core ProcessorMemory: 1GB RAMHard disk space: 4GBVideo: 128MB 3D Video Card (GeForce 6600/Radeon 9600 or better)DirectX Version: 9c</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15035">SimCity</game><game id="4736">SimCity 4</game><game id="21729">Cities XL</game><game id="1628">SimCity Societies</game><game id="15262">Imperium Romanum</game><game id="19887">Rome: Total War</game><game id="31387">Stronghold 3</game><game id="8897">Stronghold 2</game><game id="32326">Tropico 4</game><game id="24458">Tropico 3</game><game id="7965">Tropico 2: Pirate Cove</game><game id="12757">Tropico</game><game id="6940">Stronghold</game><game id="11466">CivCity: Rome</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/495/909867-952396_110926_front.jpg</image></root>