<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>24995</id><name>Forza Motorsport 3</name><description>OverviewA race in Forza 3.Forza Motorsport 3 is the next racing game in the     Forza series from     Turn 10 Studios. The single-player portion of the game is a career mode that features a dynamic calendar. The game decides which of the 200 events it thinks they player would like to compete in based on their skill level and the types of cars they like to use. Modes include Oval Racing, Drag Racing, Circuit Racing, Drift Competitions, and Time Attack. The "cover car" for the game is Audi's new roadster, the Audi R8. It is being featured heavily in promotional videos and articles for the game put out by Turn 10.At Forza 3's official reveal at     E3 it was announced that the game will release sometime in October 2009, running at 720p and 60 frames per second. The game will also include a new cockpit view, one stick driving, more car customization, a video editor, and the ability to upload HD videos, most likely to forzamotorsport.net, similar to how Halo 3 players can upload their videos to Bungie.net.Forza Motorsport 3 comes on two discs, the first disc containing the core game and the second containing extra cars and tracks. Disc 2 is transferred to the hard drive for use on Disc 1.DemoA demo hit the    Xbox Live Marketplace on September 24th, 2009. Its features include the cock-pit view, damage modeling with rollover, and rewinding. The available demo track is Camino Viejo.The five cars playable in the demo are:2007 Porsche #80 Flying Lizard 911 GT3-RSR2010 Audi R8 5.2 FSi Quattro2009 Ferrari California2008 Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution X GSR2009 Mini John Cooper WorksFeatures2 discs (Disc 1 - Game Disc, Disc 2 - Extra Cars and Tracks)400 cars from over 50 manufacturers100 tracksRuns in 720p @ 60fps"Rewind" feature, activated by pressing the BACK button on the Xbox 360 controller. You can rewind to a specific point in a race and redo that section. This feature can be used to undo a crash or retake a turn with a better line."One Button Driving". Forza 3 introduces 'auto-braking', which allows you to steer and keep one finger on the gas, while the game takes care of the rest for you.  Xbox LIVE  leaderboards for racers and the most prolific car tuners and painters in the community.The Season mode features guidance and voice-overs by Peter Egan.Online Race Rules Editor, Allows the player to manipulate the game rules. Change the number of laps, Which driving assists can be used, What class cars, etc.A new party system that allows players to hop into one room and then jump from race to race together.Manual with a clutch, Hold left bumper to engage the clutch. Then you shift, then let off of the clutch. There is a missed shift if you don't hit it right. You can damage the car if you miss a shift with simulation damage on. The manual with clutch is faster than manual and automatic.Auto-Upgrade system. Adds parts to a car based on what class you want it to upgrade to. It will upgrade the car to as close to the top of the Performance Index of the class you choose.You can now roll your car over in single player and multiplayer races. Cars will be able to be flipped back over after a roll by using the analog sticks.Drift Scoring System. There is no "drift mode", drift points will be awarded during regular races, as all races record the player's drift performance "in the background." However, only Drift Points will win Drift events.New Performance Index (PI) system. All cars get a PI rating including R classes. Production cars will now be able to upgrade to and through the R classes. PI is based on the ability of the car not the ability of the AI's to drive it.Career ModeForza 3's new career mode will be two things; dynamic and accessible. The career mode will let you have several chances is customizing your own experience; Whether that be by adjusting assists or more subtly by picking a car. After your test drive with the Audi R8 the game will give you a choice of seven cars and the car you pick will determine your future races and your future prize cars. Each race will award you driver experience (like     Forza 2) and again will award you with car experience, however unlike its predecessor Forza 3 will award you a new car with each driver level you achieve until level 50. And these cars awarded to you will differentiate depending on your previous decisions in the career mode. Career mode will also feature 220 events including: Asian Manufacturer Open, Nissan Infiniti's Owners Meeting, Executive Car Open, English Car Elite etc etc... Similar to Forza 2 these races will differentiate on Make, Model, Residing Country, Horsepower, Engine type and position as well as Car class and race types: Rally races will be included for the first time in the Forza series.TracksCamino Viejo de Montserrat, one of the over 100 tracks featured in the game.Suzuka CircuitSebring International RacewayNürburgring NordschleifeCamino Viejo de MontserratLadera Test TrackLe MansIberian International CircuitSilverstone International CircuitMazda Raceway Laguna SecaTsukuba CircuitTwin Ring MotegiMaple Valley RacewayCircuit de CatalunyaAutodromo Internazionale del MugelloSedona Raceway ParkRoad AmericaRoad AtlantaAmalfi CoastFujimi KaidoSunset PeninsulaNew York CircuitVehiclesTurn 10 was unable to fit all the contents of Forza Motorsport 3 on a single DVD, so the game was divided into two discs. Disc 1 includes the main game, around 300 cars, and most of the tracks. Disc 2 contains another 104 cars and 29 tracks, split up into four packs. Players with the required amount of space (1.9 GB) on their Xbox 360 Hard Drive will be able to completely install the contents on Disc 2, which Disc 1 will be able to read and integrate into the game seemlessly. If players do not have enough space on their hard drive or use Xbox 360 Memory Units, they will be able to choose which of the four packs they want to install. If not installed onto the hard drive or memory unit, the content will not be available in either the single player or multiplayer.Cars on disc 12008Acura#15 Lowe's Fernandez ARX-01b2008Acura#26 Andretti-Green Racing ARX-01b2002Acura#42 Realtime Racing NSX2008Acura#66 de Ferran Mortorsports ARX-01b2009Acura#66 de Ferran Mortorsports ARX-02a2005AcuraNSX2002AcuraRSX Type-S2007Alfa Romeo8C Competizione2009Alfa RomeoBrera Italia Independent2008Alfa RomeoMito2006Aston Martin#007 Aston Martin Racing DBR92008Aston Martin#008 Bell Motorsports DBR92008Aston Martin#009 Aston Martin Racing DBR92005Aston MartinDB9 Coupe2003Audi#1 Champion RS 62008Audi#2 Audi Sport North America R10 TDI2006Audi#2 FSI Champion Racing R82006Audi#8 Audi Sport Team Joest Audi R10 TDI2008AudiA4 Touring Car2009AudiQ7 V12 TDI2010AudiR8 5.2 FSI quattro2006AudiRS 42003AudiRS 62000AudiS42004AudiS42007AudiS51983AudiSport Quattro2004AudiTT Coupe 3.2 quattro2007AudiTT Coupe S-Line2004BentleyContinental GT2009BMW Motorsport135i Coupe1971BMW Motorsport3.0 CSL2001BMW Motorsport#6 Prototype Technology Group M3-GTR2009BMW Motorsport#92 Rahal Letterman Racing M3 GT21997BMW MotorsportM3 E362005BMW MotorsportM3 E46 Coupe1991BMW MotorsportM3 E302008BMW MotorsportM3 E922002BMW MotorsportM3-GTR2009BMW MotorsportM5 E602009BMW MotorsportX5 xDrive48i2008BMW MotorsportZ4 M Coupe2009BugattiVeyron 16.42008Cadillac#8 Remington Shaving CTS-V2009CadillacCTS-V2004Chevrolet#3 Corvette Racing C5.R2005Chevrolet#31 Whelen Engineering Corvette Z062006Chevrolet#4 Corvette Racing C6.R2007Chevrolet#4 Corvette Racing C6.R2003Chevrolet#50 Corvette Racing C5.R2003Chevrolet#73 3R-Racing Corvette Z062005Chevrolet#99 Tiger Racing Corvette Z062009ChevroletAveo5 LT2002ChevroletCamaro 35th Anniversary SS1990ChevroletCamaro IROC-Z2010ChevroletCamaro SS1969ChevroletCamaro SS Coupe1969ChevroletCamaro Z281979ChevroletCamaro Z281970ChevroletChevelle SS-4542005ChevroletCobalt SS Coupe2002ChevroletCorvette Z062006ChevroletCorvette Z062008ChevroletMonte Carlo SS Stock Car2008Chrysler300C SRT-82006ChryslerCrossfire SRT62009CitroenC4 VTS2002Dodge#1 Team Zakspeed Viper GTS-R2008Dodge#11 Primetime Racing Group Viper Competition Coupe2008Dodge#2 Mopar Viper Competition Coupe2004Dodge#22 3R-Racing Viper Competition Coupe2003Dodge#23 Magellan Financial Viper Competition Coupe1970DodgeChallenger R/T Hemi2009DodgeChallenger SRT-81969DodgeCharger R/T2006DodgeCharger SRT82008DodgeCharger Stock Car2006DodgeRam SRT-102003DodgeViper Competition Coupe2003DodgeViper SRT102008DodgeViper SRT10 ACR2005Ferrari#11 Larbre Competition 550 Maranello GTS1964Ferrari250 GTO1998Ferrari#30 MOMO Doran Racing F333 SP1967Ferrari330 P41994FerrariF355 Berlinetta1995FerrariF355 Challenge1999Ferrari360 Modena2003FerrariChallenge Stradale1991Ferrari512 TR2002Ferrari575M Maranello2006Ferrari599 GTB Fiorano2004Ferrari612 Scaglietti2006Ferrari#62 Risi Competizione F430GT2008Ferrari#71 Tafel Racing F430GT2003Ferrari#88 Veloqx / Prodrive Racing 550 Maranello2008Ferrari#90 Farnbacher Racing F430GT2009FerrariCalifornia1969FerrariDino 246 GT2002FerrariEnzo Ferrari1987FerrariF401989FerrariF40 Competizione2004FerrariF4301995FerrariF501996FerrariF50 GT2005FerrariFXX1984FerrariGTO2010Fiat500 Abarth SS2009Ford#1 TeamVodafone FG Falcon2004Ford#10 Tiger Racing Mustang2009Ford#25 Britek Motorsport FG Falcon2009Ford#5 Ford Performance Racing FG Falcon2009Ford#9 Stone Brothers Racing FG Falcon2009FordFiesta Zetec S2009FordFocus RS2006FordFocus ST2003FordFocus SVT2008FordFusion Stock Car2005FordFord GT1970FordMustang Boss 4292000FordMustang Cobra R1993FordMustang SVT Cobra R1985FordRS200 Evolution2009Holden#2 Toll Holden Racing Team Commodore VE2009Holden#33 Garry Rogers Team Commodore VE2009Holden#39 Supercheap Auto Racing Commodore VE2009Holden#51 Sprint Gas Racing Commodore VE2005Honda#18 TAKATA DOME NSX2005Honda#8 ARTA NSX2004HondaMugen Civic Type-R2006HondaCivic Si Coupe2007HondaCivic Type-R1991HondaCR-X SiR2009HondaFit Sport2002HondaMugen Integra Type-R2000HondaIntegra Type-R2002HondaIntegra Type-R1992HondaNSX-R2005HondaNSX-R GT2003HondaS20002010HyundaiGenesis Coupe2003HyundaiTuscani Elisa2008InfinitiG37 Coupe Sport2009JaguarXKR-S2008KoenigseggCCGT1988LamborghiniCountach LP5000 QV1999LamborghiniDiablo GTR1997LamborghiniDiablo SV2005LamborghiniGallardo2006LamborghiniMiura Concept2005LamborghiniMurcielago2007LamborghiniMurcielago LP6402008LamborghiniReventon2003LexusIS3002006LexusIS3502009LexusIS F2002LexusSC4302005LotusElise 111S2009LotusEvora2006LotusExige Cup 2402008Land RoverRange Rover Supercharged2005Maserati#15 JMB Racing MC122008MaseratiGranTurismo2004MaseratiMC122009Mazda#16 Dyson Racing B09/862009MazdaMazdaspeed 31994MazdaMiata2007MazdaMX-5 Roadster Coupe2001MazdaMazdaspeed Roadster1997MazdaRX-72002MazdaRX-7 Spirit R Type-A2004MazdaRX-8 Mazdaspeed1997McLaren#43 Team BMW Motorsport McLaren F1 GTR1997McLarenF1 GT2009MercedesA200 Turbo Coupe2004MercedesC32 AMG2009MercedesC-Class Touring Car2009MercedesML 63 AMG2009MercedesSL 65 AMG Black Series2005MercedesSLR2003MINICooper S2009MINIJohn Cooper Works2006MitsubishiEclipse GT2006MitsubishiHKS Time Attack Evolution2006MitsubishiLancer Evolution IX MR1999MitsubishiLancer Evolution VI GSR2004MitsubishiLancer Evolution VIII MR2008MitsubishiLancer Evolution X GSR2008Nissan#12 CALSONIC IMPUL GT-R2003Nissan#12 CALSONIC SKYLINE2008Nissan#23 XANAVI NISMO GT-R2008Nissan#24 WOODONE ADVAN Clarion GT-R2008Nissan#3 YellowHat YMS TOMICA GT-R2010Nissan370Z1970NissanDatsun 5102003NissanFairlady Z1994NissanFairlady Z Version S Twin Turbo2007NissanSentra SE-R Spec V1992NissanSilvia CLUB K's1994NissanSilvia K's2000NissanSilvia Spec-R1993NissanSkyline GT-R V-Spec1997NissanSkyline GT-R V-Spec2002NissanSkyline GT-R V-Spec II2002NissanMINE'S R34 Skyline GT-R2000NissanTop Secret D1-Spec S152009NissanVersa SL2004OpelSpeedster Turbo2003Pagani#17 Carsport America Zonda GR1999PaganiZonda C122002Panoz#50 Panoz Motor Sports LMP-012005Panoz#51 Panoz Esperante GTLM2005PanozEsperante GTLM2004Peugeot206 RC2007Peugeot207 RC2007Peugeot207 Super 20002007Peugeot#8 Peugeot Sport 9082009Peugeot#9 Peugeot Sport Total 9081968ChryslerPlymouth Barracuda Formula-S2009PontiacG8 GXP2006PontiacSolstice2002PontiacFirebird Trans Am Ram Air1973PontiacFirebird Trans Am SD-4551987PontiacFirebird Trans Am GTA2008Porsche#16 Dyson Racing RS Spyder Evo1987Porsche#17 Racing Porsche AG 962c2008Porsche#2 Gruppe Orange Racing 911 GT3 Cup1998Porsche#26 Porsche AG 911 GT1-982005Porsche#31 Peterson-White Lightning 911 GT3-RSR2008Porsche#45 Flying Lizard 911 GT3-RSR2005Porsche#5 XBOX 360 911 GT3-RSR2005Porsche#55 Applied Materials 911 GT3 Cup2005Porsche#66 AXA Racing 911 GT3 Cup2008Porsche#7 Penske Racing RS Spyder Evo2007Porsche#80 Flying Lizard 911 GT3-RSR2006Porsche#82 Red Bull 911 GT3 Cup1995Porsche911 GT21982Porsche911 Turbo 3.31970Porsche914/61989Porsche944 Turbo1987Porsche9591998Porsche911 GT12004Porsche911 GT3 (996)2008Porsche911 GT2 (997)2007Porsche911 GT3 (997)2007Porsche911 Turbo (997)2003PorscheBoxster S2003PorscheCarrera GT1973Porsche911 Carrera RS2009PorscheCayenne Turbo S2006PorscheCayman S1980Renault5 Turbo2003RenaultSport Clio V6 RS2007RenaultClio Renaultsport 1972009RenaultTwingo Renault Sport Cup2008Saab9-3 Turbo X2002Saleen#11 Graham Nash Motorsport S7R2003Saleen#2 Konrad Motorsports S7R2006SaleenS281 E2008SaleenS331 Supercab2004SaleenS72006SaturnION Red Line2007SaturnSky Red Line2005SciontC2009ScionxD2009SEATIbiza Cupra2007SEATLeon Cupra2007SEATLeon Supercup2007FordShelby GT5001968ShelbyMustang GT-500KR2003Subaru#77 CUSCO SUBARU ADVAN IMPREZA2006SubaruImpreza S2042004SubaruImpreza WRX STi2005SubaruImpreza WRX STI2008SubaruImpreza WRX STi2008Lexus#25 ECLIPSE ADVAN SC4302008Lexus#36 PETRONAS TOM'S SC4302008Lexus#6 ENEOS SC4302004ToyotaAltezza RS2002003ToyotaCelica SS-I1994ToyotaCelica GT-Four ST2051984ToyotaCelica Supra2002ToyotaMR-S1985ToyotaSprinter Trueno GT Apex1998ToyotaSupra RZ2008ToyotaYaris S2005TVRSagaris2006VauxhallAstra VXR2009VauxhallCorsa VXR2004VauxhallVX220 Turbo2009VolvoC30 R-Design2004VolvoS60 R2003VolkswagenBora VR61995VolkswagenCorrado VR62006VolkswagenGolf GTi2010VolkswagenGolf GTI Mk61992VolkswagenGolf Gti 16v Mk22003VolkswagenGolf R321984VolkswagenRabbit GTI2008VolkswagenScirocco GT2008VolkswagenTouareg R50Cars on Disc 22003Honda#16 G'ZOX NSX2004HondaCivic Type-R1999HondaCivic Si Coupe1994HondaCivic 1.5 VTi1995HondaCR-X Del Sol SiR2005HondaNSX-R2000HondaPrelude SiR2005MazdaAxela Sport 23S2001MazdaMazdaspeed Familia1990MazdaSavanna RX-71995MitsubishiEclipse GSX2003MitsubishiEclipse GTS1998MitsubishiFTO GP Version R1997MitsubishiGTO2003Nissan#23 XANAVI NISMO GT-R1997Nissan#23 Nissan Motorsports R3902003Nissan#3 HASEMISPORT ENDLESS Z1998Nissan#32 NISSAN R390 GT12005Nissan#46 Dream Cube's ADVAN Z1969NissanFairlady Z 4321998NissanR3902003NissanSkyline Coupe 350GT1993NissanMINE'S R32 Skyline GT-R1998SubaruImpreza 22B STi2005SubaruLegacy B4 2.0 GT1969Toyota2000GT2006Toyota#25 ECLIPSE ADVAN SUPRA1999Toyota#3 Toyota Motorsports GT-ONE TS0202004Toyota#35 Yellow Hat YMS Supra2005Toyota#36 OPEN INTERFACE TOM'S SUPRA2005Toyota#6 EXXON Superflo Supra1995ToyotaMR2 GT1995ToyotaTom's T020 MR22002ToyotaTom's W123 MR-S2002ToyotaSoarer 430SCV1992ToyotaSupra 2.0 GT Twin Turbo1998ToyotaTop Secret 0-300 Supra2001Aston MartinV12 Vanquish2002Audi#1 Champion S4 Competition2001Audi#4 Johansson Motorsport R82004Audi#5 Audi Sport Japan Team Goh R82004Audi#8 Audi ABT TT-R2008AudiR82003Bentley#7 Team Bentley Speed 81999BMW Motorsport#15 BMW Motorsport V12 LMR2005BMW Motorsport#2 BMW Motorsport M3-GTR1998Ferrari#12 Risi Competizione F333 SP2003Ferrari#72 Team Alphand Aventures 550 Maranello GTS1961JaguarE-type S11993JaguarXJ2202002KoenigseggCC8S1992LanciaDelta Integrale EVO1974LanciaStratos HF Stradale1989LotusCarlton1972LotusElan Sprint2002LotusEsprit V82005Maserati#35 Risi Competizione MC122005Maserati#9 Vitaphone Racing Team MC122006MaseratiGranSport1997McLaren#41 Team McLaren F1 GTR1998McLaren#41 Gulf Team Davidoff McLaren F1 GTR1954Mercedes300SL Gullwing Coupe2003MercedesCLK55 AMG Coupe1998MercedesAMG Mercedes CLK GTR2003Opel#5 OPC Team Phoenix Astra V82007Peugeot#1 Peugeot 207 Super 20001993Peugeot#3 Peugeot Talbot Sport 905 EVO 1C2005Porsche#3 Lechner Racing School Team 1 911 GT3 Cup1998Porsche#5 Zakspeed Racing 911 GT1-982002Saab9-3 Aero2003SEATLeon Cupra R1998TVRCerbera Speed 122001TVRTuscan S2005VauxhallMonaro VXR2004Volvo#24 At-Speed S60 R2004VolkswagenBeetle2001AcuraIntegra Type-R1997AcuraNSX1987BuickRegal GNX2004Cadillac#16 Team Cadillac CTS-V2002Cadillac#6 Team Cadillac Northstar LMP-022004CadillacCTS-V1996ChevroletCorvette Grand Sport1967ChevroletCorvette Stingray 4271970ChevroletCorvette ZR-12004ChryslerPT Cruiser GT2003Dodge#126 Team Zakspeed Viper GTS-R2000Dodge#57 Carsport Holland Viper GTS-R2000Dodge#91 Viper Team Oreca GTS-R2003DodgeSRT41996DodgeStealth R/T Turbo1999DodgeViper GTS ACR1998ChryslerEagle Talon TSi Turbo1966FordGT40 MkII2005FordMustang GT2003InfinitiG35 Coupe2003Panoz#11 JML Team Panoz LMP-012006Panoz#81 Team LNT Panoz Esperante GTLM2004PontiacGTO1968PontiacGTO Hardtop2001Saleen#26 Konrad Motorsports S7R2000SaleenS2811965ShelbyCobra 427 S/C1999ShelbySeries 1Limited Collector's Edition Cars2005AcuraForza Motorsport NSX2005Aston MartinForza Motorsport DB9 Coupe2010AudiForza Motorsport R8 5.2 FSI quattro2008DodgeXbox 360 Charger Stock Car2003NissanForza Motorsport Fairlady ZVIP Membership Cars2008Aston MartinDBS2009ChevroletCorvette ZR12007Ferrari430 Scuderia2007LamborghiniGallardo Superleggera2007Porsche911 GT3 RS (997)Pre-order Cars2009BMW MotorsportWalmart M5 E602009BMW MotorsportGameStop M5 E602009BMW MotorsportGAME M3 E922009BMW MotorsportMicroMania M5 E602008MitsubishiGameStation Lancer Evolution X GSR2010AudiR8 5.2 Community EditionUnicorn CarsTurn 10 have released 3 so called "unicorn" cars. As in previous Forza titles, these cars are typically made available through the auction house feature, and can fetch an extraordinarily high price as they are unavailable to most players and extremely rare. Turn 10 also gives away unicorn cars for various contests. The three currently released unicorn cars are:2006 Subaru Impreza S2041969 Chevrolet Camaro SS Coupe2002 Mazda RX-7 Spirit R Type-A Downloadable ContentSince Launch, Downloadable Content for Forza Motorsport 3 has been bountiful.On March 2nd, 2010 - Turn 10 Studios made available for purchase for non-VIP and not new copies of Forza 3:VIP Car Pack for 800 MSP ($10): Receive recognition on Scoreboards, in Multiplayer Lobbies, in the Forza Motorsport 3 Storefront, and it places your VIP Auctions at the top of the Auction House. VIP membership also includes the ‘08 Aston Martin DBS, ‘09 Chevrolet Corvette ZR1, ‘07 Ferrari F430 Scuderia, ‘07 Lamborghini Gallardo Superleggera, and ‘07 Porsche 911 GT3 RS (997) (included in Limited Collector's Edition of Forza 3)Sidewinder Proving Grounds for 400 MSP ($5): Includes the Sidewinder Proving Grounds 18 different tracks (included in new copy of Forza 3)Benchmark High Speed Ring for 400 MSP ($5): Includes the Benchmark High Speed Ring oval track, and several infield variation tracks (included in new copy of Forza 3)Nurburgring GP Track Pack for 400 MSP ($5): This track pack brings a modern touch to the 'Ring: run either the Full or Short loops, famous for hosting the ADAC 1000km Nürburgring endurance raceMotorsport Legends Car Pack for 400 MSP ($5): Includes the 1965 Alfa Romeo Giulia Sprint GTA Stradale, 1964 Aston Martin DB5 Vantage, 1981 BMW Motorsport M1, 1960 Chevrolet Corvette, 1969 Dodge Charger Daytona Hemi, 1957 Ferrari 250 Testa Rossa, 1980 Fiat 131 Abarth, 1967 Lamborghini Miura P400, 1971 Nissan Skyline 2000GT-R, and the 1965 Shelby Cobra Daytona Coupe (included in new copy of Forza 3)The AutoWeek Car Pack for 400 MSP ($5): Includes the 2010 Aston Martin One-77, 2010 Chevrolet Corvette Grand Sport, 2010 Ford Shelby GT500, 2010 Porsche Boxster S, 2010 Pagani Zonda R, 2009 Audi R8 LMS Show Car, 2010 BMW Motorsport Coupe M6, 2009 Audi RS 6, 2009 Lotus 2-Eleven, 2010 Saleen S5S Raptor.The Road and Track Car Pack for 400 MSP ($5): Includes the 2010 Volkswagen Golf R, 2009 Holden HSV w427, 2010 Ford Taurus SHO, 2010 Mercedes-Benz E 63 AMG, 2010 Renault Megane RS 250, 2010 Vauxhall Insignia VXR, 2010 MINI Coupé Concept, 2010 Bentley Continental Supersports, 2010 Mazda MX-5 Superlight, 2010 SEAT Leon CUPRA RThe Hot Holiday's Car Pack for 400 MSP ($5): Includes the 2010 Ferrari 458 Italia, 2010 Nissan GT-R SpecV, 2010 Ferrari 599XX, 2009 Audi #2 Audi Sport Team Joest R15 TDI, 2010 Lamborghini Murcielago LP 670-4 SV, 2009 Aston Martin #007 Aston Martin Racing Lola, 2010 Porsche Panamera Turbo, 2009 Mercedes SLR Stirling Moss, 2010 Jaguar XFR, 2010 Audi S4The Jalopnik Car Pack for 400 MSP ($5): Includes the 2008 Mazda Furai, 2010 Jaguar #33 Jaguar RSR XKR GT, 2009 Ford #40 Robertson Racing Ford GT Mk7, 2010 Aston Martin V12 Vantage, 2010 Porsche 911 Sport Classic, 1992 Bugatti EB110 SS, 2011 BMW Motorsport Z4 sDrive35is, 2010 Audi TT RS Coupe, 2010 Aston Martin Rapide, 2010 Honda Mugen Civic Type-R 3DThe Exotic Car Pack for 400 MSP ($5): Includes the 2010 Devon GTX, 2010 Gumpert Apollo S, 2010 Joss JT1, 2010 Mosler MT900S, 2010 Radical SR8 Supersport, 2010 Rossion Q1, 2010 Spada Vetture Sport Codatronca TS, 2010 Spyker C8 Laviolette LM85, 2010 SSC Ultimate Aero, 2010 Wiesmann GT MF5The Summer Velocity Car Pack for 400 MSP ($5): Includes the 2010 Lotus Evora Type 124, 2010 Ford Fusion Sport, 2009 Chrysler Jeep Grand Cherokee SRT8, 2010 Subaru Legacy B4 2.5GT, 2010 Bertone Mantide, 2010 Mazda Mazdaspeed 3, 2010 Morgan Aero SuperSports, 2010 Peugeot RCZ, 2010 Mercedes-Benz SLK 55 AMG, 2010 BMW Motorsport X6 MThe World Class Car Pack for 400 MSP ($5): Includes the 2011 McLaren MP4-12C, 2010 Mercedes-Benz C63 AMG, 2010 Mercedes-Benz CL 65 AMG, 2011 Cadillac CTS-V Coupe, 2010 Fiat Punto Evo SPORT, 2010 Kia Forte Koup, 2011 Citroen DS3, 2011 Mazda 2, 2010 Acura TSX, 2010 Mitsubishi Colt RalliartForza Motorsport 3 Limited Collectors EditionForza Motorsport 3 Limited Collectors Edition In the USA, the Limited Collectors Edition of Forza 3 is only available at GameStop. In the LCE you get a Forza Motorsport 3 collector’s keychain and a 2GB USB thumbdrive. Also, instant VIP membership within the Forza community including special recognition in the new Storefront feature as well as the online Auction House, Scoreboards, ForzaMotorsport.net and more. Being a VIP gives you access to a VIP Member car pack which includes:2009 Aston Martin DBS2009 Chevrolet Corvette ZR12007 Ferrari 430 Scuderia2007 Lamborghini Gallardo Superleggera2007 Porsche 911 GT3 RS (997)Another car pack in the LCE is, The Exclusive Collectors Car Pack which includes cars picked, tuned and painted by Turn 10. This car pack includes:Audi R8 5.2 FSI Quattro (Forza Motorsport 3 Hero Car)Acura NSX (Forza Motorsport Cover Car)Nissan Fairlady (Forza Motorsport 2 Cover Car)Aston Martin DB9 (Forza Motorsport 2 European Cover Car)2008 Dodge Charger Stock Car (with Xbox 360 livery)In the future Turn10 plans to add more cars that are just for VIP members who purchased the Limited Collectors Edition. They have not announced specifics what will be added but they have said they will have custom tuned and painted cars from various members of the community, other developers and Turn10 themselves.Custom Painted Audi R8 V10If you Pre-Order Forza Motorsport 3, you will get a custom Audi R8 V10 painted by a user in the Forza community.Several Cars have been Gifted to VIP members at various intervals. The cars are available in game, but the gifted versions have been painted and tuned. The cars that have been gifted thus far are:Audi R8 5.2 FSI Quattro (Nightmare paint scheme) (Tuned to A-600)Mazda RX-8 Mazdaspeed (Mazda Raceway Laguna Seca safety car paint) (Tuned to A-600)#66 de Ferran Motorsports ARX-02a (Petron Tequila #9 Race Livery) (R1-984 tuned)#66 de Ferran Motorsports ARX-02a (XM Radio #66 Race Livery) (R1-984 tuned)Lamborghini Murcielago (Halo Waypoint paint scheme)Porsche 911 GT1 StrassenversionForza 3 - Ultimate EditionStigs Garage Car PackOn October 29th an Ultimate Edition was released, containing new cars and all previous DLC. This edition also shows the beginning of the new partnership between Turn 10 Studios and BBC's Top Gear, with The Stig on the cover of the Ultimate Edition, and the introduction of "Stig's Garage Car Pack", that are available only in this package. The three "Stig's Garage" cars are: tLexus LFAKoenigsegg CCXMercedes-Benz SLS AMGIn addition to “Stig’s Garage Car Pack”, Ultimate Collection owners will receive a free download of a 90-minute Top Gear video compilation featuring Top Gear hosts produced especially for Ultimate Collection owners, as well as an exclusive Xbox LIVE Top Gear premium dashboard theme. Ultimate Collection will feature all cars and tracks found in the previously released Forza 3 Add-on Packs and will also include seven new car models:Lancia 037 StradaleJaguar D-TypePlymouth CudaAudi R8 5.2 FSI QuattroAudi TT RS CoupeAudi R15 TDIPorsche 550A SpyderSoundtrackThe Whip - TrashThe Hives - Tick Tick BoomRise Against - Long Forgotten SonsFall From Grace - BurnedTorche - Across The ShieldsCelldweller - SolarisThe Black Halos - No Tomorrow GirlsAlkaline Trio - We've Had EnoughPendulum - ShowdownHard Fi - Suburbian NightsThe Fratellis - My Friend JohnThe Duke Spirit - Send a Little Love TokenCommix - Talk To FrankThe Qemists - Lost WeekendThe Qemists - On The RunThe Qemists - SWAG99 Men - 100 PercentTC - Borrowed TimeAdam Freeland - Under ControlAdam Freeland - Borderline (aka Blocks)Alex Medric - What NowDJ Drunken Master - OversquareMistabishi - Talk Me DownEvil Nine - Twist The KnifeTurbonegro - Do You Dig DestructionLogistics - CosmonautLogistics - InterventionLogistics - ToyTownMr Sam (ft clAud9) - CygnusEl Caco - One WeekXbox 360 Game InstallationForza Motorsport 3 requires 6.8 GB of space to install on an Xbox 360     HDD.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20597">Gran Turismo 5 Prologue</game><game id="17784">Gran Turismo 4</game><game id="19809">Project Gotham Racing 3</game><game id="25225">Need for Speed: SHIFT</game><game id="22693">RACE Pro</game><game id="3916">DiRT</game><game id="6137">Driving Emotion Type-S</game><game id="6978">Enthusia Professional Racing</game><game id="20936">Ferrari Challenge Trofeo Pirelli</game><game id="16276">Ford Bold Moves Street Racing</game><game id="7431">Ford Racing</game><game id="20919">Ford Racing: Off Road</game><game id="21297">Gran Turismo HD</game><game id="20729">GRID</game><game id="14858">GTR 2: FIA GT Racing Game</game><game id="16220">GTR: FIA GT Racing Game</game><game id="7777">Juiced</game><game id="19522">Live for Speed</game><game id="18095">Need for Speed: ProStreet</game><game id="327">Race 07: The Official WTCC Game</game><game id="6213">Race: The Official WTCC Game</game><game id="19563">Sports Car GT</game><game id="1052">Super PickUps</game><game id="8437">TOCA 2: Touring Car Challenge</game><game id="531">TOCA Race Driver 2</game><game id="5869">TOCA Touring Car Championship</game><game id="22215">V8 Supercars 2</game><game id="21790">Gran Turismo 5</game><game id="24513">DiRT 2</game><game id="26842">Gran Turismo</game><game id="8100">Gran Turismo 2</game><game id="12950">Gran Turismo 3 A-Spec</game><game id="13734">TOCA Race Driver 3</game><game id="12976">Need for Speed: Most Wanted</game><game id="32253">SHIFT 2: Unleashed</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1887888-box_forza3.png</image></root>