<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25024</id><name>Dance ManiaX 2nd MIX</name><description>Game ConceptThe sensors are located on the top and bottom.Dance ManiaX 2nd MIX is played the same way all Dancia ManiaX games are played. Similarly to the Guitar Hero series, the player is presented with four "chords". On these four chords "notes" will appear in a rhythmic sequence, which the player has to clear by activating the games mechanism, the moment the "notes" hit the bottom of the screen. Dance ManiaX machines Guitar Hero and Dance ManiaX have a very similar conceptfeature four sensors for each player, located on the top and bottom of two tube shaped controllers located at hip level in front of each player. The player now activates these sensors to clear the notes, by moving their hand over the top or bottom sensors, or using their hands for the top sensors and their knees for the bottom sensors. That way, the game is rhythmically involved in the game with full body movement. Of the four notes that appear on screen, the center two (red)  are cleared with the top sensors and the outer ones (blue) are cleared with the bottom sensors. The sensors do not need to be pysically touched by the player, the hand can simply be held over them to activate them. In the game, notes can appear single (eg. red), double (eg. two reds at the same time) or combined (eg. blue and red at the same time).Aim of the GameBy clearing the notes in time correctly, the player accumulates combos. The more notes are cleared, the higher the highscore is. If the player plays too many notes wrong or misses the note completely, the player loses the game.RoundsUsually, the player will get to play five songs in a row, which are combined by pre-existing playlists, given that the player will not fail any song. All songs can be played in two player mode, in which two players will clear the same song at the same time, on the same difficulty. There is also a double mode available in which one single player has to play on both controllers actually designated for two players. Song List   TAEKO THE V.O.W - I WILL FOLLOW HIM   CARTOONS - DOODAH! (K.O.G Re-Edit)   COO COO - UPSIDE DOWN (Hyper Euro Mix)   EDDY HUNTINGTON - MEET MY FRIEND (B4 ZA BEAT Mix)   JUDY CRYSTAL - TOKYO ALL READY   NAOKI feat.SHANTI - KISS KISS KISS   SMiLE.dk - PETIT LOVE   E-ROTIC - CAT'S EYE (Ventura Mix)   B3-PROJECT - ENTER THE DRAGON (G'z Island Mix)   CAPTAIN JACK - TOGETHER AND FOREVER (KCP Euro Mix)   SMiLE.dk - BOYS (Euro Mix)   CHUMBAWAMBA - TUBTHUMPING (KCP Happy Mix)   KING KONG  D.JUNGLE GIRLS - BOOM BOOM DOLLAR (Red Monster 2000 Mix)   JOE RINOIE - SYNCHRONIZED LOVE (Red Monster Hyper Mix)   Emi - STAY (Organic house Version)   TOMOSUKE - STAY (Mod bouncy Version)   Brian Morris feat.Thomas - VIRTUAL MIND   ANGIE GOLD - EAT YOU UP (Phat K Mix)   DJ MOjo - DO ME (MONDO DISCO ITALO STYLE)   K.Wit feat.Anthony Shoemo - KEEP IT GOING   JOGA - DAM DARIRAM (B4 ZA BEAT Mix)   NAOKI J-STYLE feat.MIU - Kiss Me All Night Long   RE-VENGE - Õ (J-SUMMER MIX)   SPAKER - FUNKY MODELLING   TOMOSUKE - Mind Parasite   dj TAKA - Quickening   PARANOiA jazzy groove TRIP MACHINE CLIMAX DEAD END 2nd MIX append JPARADICE   CAPTAIN JACK - DANCING POMPOKOLIN (Captains eurasia hyper mix)   JUDY CRYSTAL - GOD OF ROMANCE   NI-NI - BE TOGETHER (Upper Version)   dj TAKA - ABSOLUTE   CJ CREW FEATURING CHRISTIAN D - RHYTHM AND POLICE (Hyper K Mix)   BAMBEE - SEVENTEEN (Upper Version)   FinalOffset - Twin Bee -generation X-   JOHN DESIRE - HOT LIMIT   LIBERTY ALL STAZ - THE TWIST (DOUBLE PUMP MIX)   Osamu Kubota - Sanctus   MM - WONDA (Speed K Mix)   TaQ - DXY!   NAOKI - B4U   BUS STOP - KICK THE CAN (Hyper KCP Mix) 2nd MIX PRODUCTION B.G.M. </description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20629">Dance Dance Revolution UNIVERSE 3</game><game id="22411">Dance Dance Revolution UNIVERSE 2</game><game id="21746">Dance Dance Revolution SuperNOVA 2</game><game id="1417">DDRMAX Dance Dance Revolution</game><game id="8743">Pump It Up : Prex 3</game><game id="8631">GuitarFreaks 3rdMIX &amp; DrumMania 2ndMIX</game><game id="23017">GuitarFreaks 7thMIX</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15228/955437-maniax.jpg</image></root>