<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25027</id><name>Cuboid</name><description>Cuboid will have 66 levels  in the future have downloadable level packs. The price of the game is $9.99.Developer Synopsis: A stunning 3D puzzle game in which players navigate ancient ruins and lush environments, maneuvering a rectangular block through mystical exits. Cuboid's 66 twisted levels will bend your mind with their addictive puzzles, and engage the senses with amazing graphics and soothing music, immersing you in a surrealistic puzzle world. This game is very similar to an online video game called Bloxorz which can be found on many Flash-Game based sites such as addictinggames.comThe game has two play modes: Beginner and Expert. Each of the modes has 33 levels. There is no multiplayer either online or offline, but there a online stats and tracking. The game supports the Dualshock 3 rumble feature.Update: expansion pack includes a new professional mode with 33 levels  and a level editor. The game has 16 PSN trophies. 13 Bronze, and 3 Silver. Updated with 6 Bronze and 2 silver trophies.Bronze:Ring - Complete "Ring" LevelRod - Complete " Rod" LevelGoblet - Complete "Goblet" LevelSword - Complete "Sword" LevelShield - Complete "Shield" LevelCrown - Complete "Crown" LevelBronze Master - Collect 20 bronze medals in Expert or 30 in BeginnerSilver Master - Collect 15 silver medals in Expert or 20 in BeginnerGold Master - Collect 10 gold medals in Expert or 15 in BeginnerSpeed Master - Complete 20 levels with lightning speedGround Breaker - Play the First LevelAbyss - Fall of the platform 50 timesDetermined - Spend at least 8 hours playing the gameMaze builder (Editor pack trophy) Architect (Editor pack trophy) Neophyte (Editor pack trophy)Amulet (Professional pack trophy)Axe (Professional pack trophy)Helmet (Professional pack trophy)Silver:Equilibrist - Complete 15 levels in a row without falling offBeginner Master- Complete Every Beginner Level Expert Master - Complete All Expert LevelsVirtuoso (Editor pack trophy)Professional Master (Professional pack trophy)</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="31400">Voodoo Dice</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/6/63119/2292990-cuboid.jpg</image></root>