<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25114</id><name>Super Meat Boy</name><description>OverviewThe poster included within the 'Ultra Edition'.Super Meat Boy is a downloadable 2D platformer developed and published by Team Meat for the Xbox Live Arcade , PC and Mac. The game follows Meat Boy, a cube of meat with great skill in jumping, as he attempts to rescue his girlfriend Bandage Girl from the menacing Dr. Fetus while avoiding sawblades, piles of salt, lava, missiles, and other deadly obstacles. The Xbox release, as part of Microsoft's Game Feast 2010 promotion, was sold for 800 Microsoft Points ($10) until November 21, 2010, when the price was cruelly raised to 1200 Microsoft Points ($15). The PC version was first released via Steam on November 30, 2010 for the same price. The PC level editor, PC level portal, PC non-Steam version, and Mac version of Super Meat Boy came out in 2011. The game was originally going to be released on Nintendo's WiiWare service, but was later cancelled due to their small file size restrictions.Like Alien Hominid, the concept for Super Meat Boy began as a free online game made in Adobe Flash for Newgrounds. The game, originally called Meat Boy, was released on October 5, 2008, and a map pack featuring custom levels was soon followed two months later. Super Meat Boy features homages to other games and movies in Newgrounds, as well as other video games and Internet culture such as unlockable characters from other indie games (Including N, Aquaria, VVVVVV, I Wanna Be The Guy, Braid, and Flywrench).The XBLA version of Super Meat Boy includes 12 achievements (worth 200 gamerscore) and two avatar awards: a t-shirt resembling Meat Boy (unlocked after a certain number of deaths) and a prop of Meat Boy running around the avatar (unlocked after completing the game). The Steam version of Super Meat Boy includes 41 achievements, adding new ones such as clearing all the levels in each world (Light World or Dark World) consecutively without dying, clearing bonus levels, and unlocking new characters.The game is not without its issues; glitches pop up on both the Steam and XBLA versions. The PC version suffers from the occasional crash, but the XBLA version has a "save glitch", which causes Super Meat Boy to lose the ability to auto-save after every completed level. Since manually saving is not an option, players are forced to quit to the dashboard and restart the game. Collected bandages will also fail to display on the map screen, and as such can be collected over and over again with each level replay. This allows for faulty completion rates of over 100% as the bandage counter exceeds its maximum of 20 per world. Team Meat has claimed that a patch is finished but has yet to come out due to Microsoft's terrible approval process.DevelopmentIn Indie Game: The Movie, Team Meat's progress was covered in great lengths. McMillen and Refenes were very interested in creating a game that reflected a part of themselves and were striving to make a game that could be a success without compromising their visions. Super Meat Boy was in development for eighteen months. A month prior to it's release, the team was offered a feature on the Xbox Live Dashboard despite the project being far from done. Facing financial struggle and left with almost no options, McMillen and Refenes spent the last month crunching to meet the deadline. In spite of their feature being absent for the first eight hours of release day, Super Meat Boy was able to sell 20,000 copies by the end of the day. It was announced that in April 2011 more than 600.000 copies were sold through Xbox Live and Steam. Steam was responsible for 400.000 copies. In January 2012, Super Meat Boy had sold over 1,000,000 copies across all platforms. At the Indie Game: The Movie premiere, Team Meat announced that they have moved on from Super Meat Boy and are currently working another project.GameplayThe objective of Super Meat Boy is to guide Meat Boy (or one of the other playable characters) past deadly obstacles to reach Bandage Girl, who will be promptly kidnapped by Dr. Fetus. Navigation of these obstacles requires extremely precise timing to pass. Failure means instant death and a quick restart from the beginning of the level. The player is given an infinite amount of lives and near-instantaneous respawns, but Meat Boy leaves a trail of blood to mark where he has been and what obstacles previously killed him. When a regular level is completed, a replay showcases every attempt within the level simultaneously.Characters have two abilities at their disposal: a jump button and an ability button. For Meat Boy (and most other characters), pressing the ability button engages sprinting. Some characters sprint automatically and replace the ability button with another power, such as Tim's ability to rewind time or Viridian's ability to inverse his own personal gravity. To keep the difficulty in check, the game features extremely precise controls. Quickly tapping the jump button performs a small hop, while holding down the jump button performs a tall leap. Players can also stick to the wall (which may either slow their descent or slightly continue their ascent) and press the jump button again for a wall jump. Some unlockable characters have special jumping abilities, such as the Kid's ability to double jump and Jill's ability to stall her descent.Over the course of the game, new mechanics are introduced and obstacles become more complex. These include rising tides of lava, portals, magnetic fields, fans, lava rocks, and eventually enemies that hunt down the player character. All obstacles will result in instantaneous death upon contact. The "bosses" in the games are equally indestructible, and instead of actually fighting them, these levels require players to navigate difficult puzzles under time restraints until a cutscene is triggered.Players can also collect bandages scattered around certain levels to unlock characters and certain levels. In order for the player to keep Bandages, they must collect them and successfully reach the exit in one attempt. Some bandages require specific characters and all are difficult to collect, especially in purple WARP ZONEs, where players must not only collect the Bandage, but clear each of the three levels with a limited number of lives.LevelsSuper Meat Boy features five main worlds, each with forty regular levels. The initial twenty levels are referred to as the "Light World". If the player is able to clear a "Light World" level under its par time, they will be able to access the "Dark World" counterpart (which shares the same basic geometry, but has a different appearance and increased difficulty). Each Light World version of the five main worlds also include a boss level, which must be completed in order to progress to the next world. Boss levels are unlocked after the player beats 17 out of the 20 Light World levels.Meat Boy entering a Warp Zone. Along the way, players can also find purple Warp Zones within certain levels. These portals vanish after a set period of time during the level attempt, though reaching these portals makes the Warp Zone available in the level selection screen. Entering a Warp Zone will transport Meat Boy (regardless of which character reaches the warp zone) to a retro-themed zone which is notably difficult. Each zone comes with three levels that must be completed consecutively with a special version of Meat Boy. Bandages are found within these warp zones, but the player will only have three attempts per level to collect them and clear the Warp Zone. If Meat Boy dies during the final attempt at any level, all bandages found during the Warp Zone attempt will be reset, and the player will be kicked back to the level selection screen. Replays and par times are unavailable for Warp Zones.Red Warp Zones function similarly to purple Warp Zones but are played instead with a secret character . There are no bandages in red warp zones but there are also unlimited lives. There are only five red warp zones, one in each of the main Light Worlds. Each main world also has a special " glitch zone", reached by getting to Bandage Girl while she is in a randomly occurring "glitch state". Glitch zones feature no bandages and only one level, which is typically longer and more difficult than any of the world's Warp Zones.Chapter 1: The ForestIntro Cutscene Tribute: Street Fighter II: The World WarriorBoss: Lil' Slugger (giant walking chainsaw driven by Dr. Fetus)The Forest introduces buzzsaws, static sawblade launchers, and impassable tiles that crumble away soon after the player touches it.Chapter 2: The HospitalIntro Cutscene Tribute: CastlevaniaBoss: C.H.A.D. (mutated living abomination of blood and tissue)The Hospital introduces fans, crawling slimes that stick to surfaces, floating enemies that bounce around aimlessly, piles of deadly needles, keys that unlock certain tiles, and timed laser beams.Chapter 3: The Salt FactoryIntro Cutscene Tribute: The Adventures of LoloBoss: BrownieThe Salt Factory introduces harmful salt, homing missile launchers, moving platforms, tiles that only crumble away after coming in to contact with a missile, and high-speed conveyor belts.Chapter 4: HellIntro Cutscene Tribute: Ninja GaidenBoss: Little Horn (monster created by dead Meat Boy corpses)Hell introduces lava pits (that sometimes rise), moving lava rocks, portals, rotating eyes that slowly lock on to the player while shooting laser beams, and demon homing missiles that split in to separate small missiles on impact.Chapter 5: RaptureIntro Cutscene Tribute: Mega Man 2Boss: Larrie's Lament (a group of enormous carnivorous worms)Rapture introduces orbs that repulse the player, abominations (both running and flying) that head towards the player, and homing sawblade launchers.Chapter 6: The EndIntro Cutscene Tribute: Pokémon Red/BlueBoss: Dr. FetusUnlocked after completing Chapter 5, The End includes five regular levels (with both Light World and Dark World variations) that can only be played by Meat Boy and are designed to test the player's mastery of previous concepts. After completing all five levels, the player can face Dr. Fetus in a boss level. The boss level is divided in to two parts, featuring a halfway checkpoint and a Dark World variant unlocked after completing 85 Dark World levels.Chapter 7: Cotton AlleyIntro Cutscene Tribute: Ghosts 'N GoblinsUnlocked after completing Chapter 6, Cotton Alley is a special 40-level world that can only be played by Bandage Girl (who is, ironically, rescuing Meat Boy from Dr. Fetus). Despite the pink and cheery atmosphere, the levels are extremely difficult. There are no bandages in this world; the obstacles are mainly limited to giant buzzsaws.TEH INTERNETS (Xbox 360) / Super Meat World (PC/Mac)Intro Cutscene Tribute: Bubble BobbleUnlocked after collecting 20 Bandages, TEH INTERNETS is a special chapter that provides downloadable chapters. All past and future chapters will be free in the Xbox 360 version, due to Team Meat's method of uploading the content in space reserved for free title updates. (Which bypasses Microsoft's normal method of distribution in their marketplace, which would cost either Team Meat or the end user money) All chapters will also be free for the PC and Mac versions.As of 1st April 2011, Super Meat World is released on the PC version, along with eight chapters of levels. It is also unlocked after collecting 20 Bandages. The level editor is still unavailable, and should be included in the next update.Each downloadable chapter contains 20 retro- themed levels (with par times to beat) and its own leaderboards separate from the main game. Chapters consist of either a mix of developer favorites (from user-generated maps on the PC level editor or from the original flash game), levels designed exclusively for certain characters, and other levels.Released TEH INTERNETS ChaptersThe Butcher Boy (by Team Meat, released 10/20/2010) - 8-bit Meat Boy only. Retro-looking chapter that explores mechanics that weren't used in the main game.Sewers of Dross (by Team Meat, released 11/21/2010) - Gish only. Makes use of his ability to stick to walls.Cramps (by NovaSilisko, released 2/22/2011) - Meat Boy only. User-made chapter.Expert Remix (by Team Meat, released 2/22/2011) - Meat Boy only. Remixes twenty levels from the main game (including the first level of the Chapter 5-7 Warp Zone, previously exclusive to The Kid) while making them significantly harder.Remnants (by Code92, released 4/28/2011) - Any Character. User-made chapter.Playable CharactersAll of the game's playable characters. Each version of the game comes with around twelve unique playable characters to choose from, half of them being platform-exclusive characters. They can either be unlocked by collecting bandages, reaching certain Warp Zones, or entering secret cheat codes in the character selection screen. Each character has his/her own unique abilities that differentiate them from Meat Boy, such as the ability to double jump, perform unique jumps, or act differently around map tiles.Standard CharactersMeat BoyMeat BoyAvailable by default. Made of meat. Heroic by nature.Also unlockable in 8-bit form (40 bandages), 4-color form (60 bandages), and 4-bit form (80 bandages). Achieving 100% completion earns you Meat Ninja, who sacrifices the ability to be ranked on the leaderboards for the power to temporarily teleport out of existence right before he dies.The default character, he is the fastest in the game with the most pinpoint control.Bandage GirlBandage GirlOnly playable in Chapter 7. Made of bandages. Only has eyes for Meat Boy.Bandage Girl plays exactly like Meat Boy, only swapping his red blood trail for a pink trail of calamine lotion.Known as "Band-Aid Girl" in the original Meat Boy Flash game. Her name was changed to avoid copyright issues.BrownieBrownieOnly playable via cheat code after completing Chapter 3. Made of feces and corn. One of Dr. Fetus's evil creations.Brownie plays exactly like Meat Boy, only swapping his red blood trail for a brown fecal trail.On the character select screen, quickly enter RB, RB, RB, B, B, B, X (when using the Xbox 360 controller), then choose any character.Commander VideoCommander VideoCameo from the Bit.Trip series. 8-bit rainbow runner.Unlockable in the chapter 1-12 Warp Zone.Although the Commander is the slowest character in the game, he has the ability to stop his fall and float horizontally in mid-air for a limited amount of time by holding down the jump button.JillJillCameo from Mighty Jill Off. Masochistic lesbian shoe fetishist who will do anything to please the Queen.Unlockable in the chapter 2-8 Warp Zone.By pressing the jump button multiple times, Jill can slow her descent.OgmoOgmoCameo from the Jumper series. Failed experiment longing for freedom.Unlockable in the chapter 3-16 Warp Zone.Ogmo has the ability to double-jump horizontally, despite his weak wall jumping.Resemblance to Meat Boy coincidental.FlywrenchFlywrenchCameo from Flywrench. Abstract wing-flapping spacecraft.Unlockable in the chapter 4-18 Warp Zone.Flywrench is very heavy and very unruly, but has a strong triple-jump and can slide up walls with a very thin frame.The KidThe KidCameo from I Wanna Be The Guy. He wants to be The Guy.Unlockable in the chapter 5-7 Warp Zone.Sacrifices speed and jump height for the ability to double jump.Alien HominidAlien HominidCameo from Alien Hominid. Fragile alien invader; friend to children, enemy to the government, connoisseur of heads.Unlockable by collecting 30 Bandages.Pressing the run/action button while jumping allows the Alien Hominid to fire his gun downwards, slowing his falling speed slightly or increasing his jump height and wall-climbing speed.TimTimCameo from Braid. Gentlemanly sort, seeks to rescue the princess. Mastery over time.Unlockable by collecting 50 Bandages.Holding the run/action button rewinds Tim's position for up to three seconds and doubles as an invincible force field. Unlike in Braid, this power does not work if he dies.To play as him on PC type in (outtatime) on the character select screen and select your character, when you do it it wont say "PUSH THE BUTTONS"Xbox 360 Exclusive CharactersGishGishCameo from Gish. Sentient glob of tar; seeks to rescue his human girlfriend.Unlockable by collecting 10 Bandages.Just like the Headcrab and Goo Ball, Gish is able to stick to walls (by holding down the run/action button) and slide along ceilings (by holding both run/action and jump buttons down).SpelunkySpelunkyCameo from Spelunky. Adventurer by trade. Never-ending cave explorer.Unlockable by collecting 70 Bandages.Pressing the jump button while in the air causes an explosion, propelling Spelunky horizontally in a chosen direction. Then, while still in mid-air, pressing the jump button again causes another explosion, propelling Spelunky downward.The Pink KnightThe Pink KnightCameo from a Castle Crashers fangame. Heroic knight with a sweet tooth.Unlockable by collecting 90 Bandages.While fairly weak in speed and jumping ability, pressing the jump button in the air causes the Pink Knight to flail his arms ("flutter jumping"), granting him extra height and distance based on the point during the jump it is used. He can also jump in mid-air if he runs over the edge.NNCameo from the N series. Skilled ninja. Very fast. Limited lifespan.Unlockable by collecting 100 Bandages.N is much lighter than the other characters, allowing precision air control. Pressing and holding the run/action button will cause N to start sprinting for two seconds, greatly increasing his run speed and potential jumping distance.PC/Mac Exclusive CharactersHeadcrab (Steam version only)HeadcrabCameo from the Half-Life series. Alien parasite. Seeks heads; create zombies.Unlockable by collecting 10 Bandages.Just like Gish and the Goo Ball, the Headcrab can stick to walls (by holding down the run/action button) and slide along ceilings (by holding both run/action and jump buttons down).Goo BallGoo BallsCameo from World of Goo. Incredibly unintelligent blobs of goo; like to become structures.Unlockable in non-Steam versions by collecting 10 Bandages. Unlockable in the Steam version by inputting "ballgoo" in the character selection screen, then picking any character.Just like Gish and the Headcrab, the Goo Ball can stick to walls (by holding down the run/action button) and slide along ceilings (by holding both run/action and jump buttons down).JosefJosefCameo from Machinarium. Confused for trash, wants to find his way home.Unlockable by collecting 30 Bandages.Josef has the ability to perform a helicopter spin, which increases his jump height, or jump in mid-air should he run off an edge.NaijaNaijaCameo from Aquaria. Lone mermaid seeking the history of her lost people.Unlockable by collecting 50 Bandages.Naija has the ability to transform into her Energy Form and fling herself at high speed through the air.RunManRunManCameo from RunMan: Race Around the World. Amazingly enthusiastic, nothing can keep him down.Unlockable by collecting 70 Bandages.Runman can use his signature Star Dive to hurl himself long distances horizontally very quickly.Captain ViridianViridianCameo from VVVVVV. Gravity-defying. Courageous. Cyan.Unlockable by collecting 90 Bandages.Viridian has the ability to reverse his own personal gravity.Mr. Minecraft ("Steve")Mr. MinecraftCameo from Minecraft. Loves to build. Hates hissing green things.Unlockable by collecting 100 Bandages.Mr. Minecraft can build solid tiles out of thin air and destroy tiles in front of him, allowing him to easily bypass almost all challenges.Tofu Boy (Steam version only)Tofu Boy"Cameo" from Super Tofu Boy, a parody game by the militant animal rights group PETA (People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals). Wishes he were Bandage Girl's boyfriend. As if.Unlockable by inputting the code "petaphile" in the character selection screen and picking any character.Tofu Boy, being malnourished due to iron deficiency, cannot run or jump as well as the other characters, making it impossible for him to clear the vast majority of levels.SoundtrackNICE TO MEAT YOU Soundtrack CoverSuper Meat Boy's old school soundtrack was engineered by Danny Baranowsky of dB Soundworks. Composed of 34 tracks, it can be listened to and bought from http://www.meatboymusic.com.A two-disc soundtrack titled "NICE TO MEAT YOU" has also been released, with an additional 39 songs for a total 73 tracks. It contains new remixes, menu and cutscene music, and some unused songs. The design of the CD labels reflects the sawblade motif seen on the retail install disc.Playable Rock Band 3 remixed tracks are available for download via Rock Band Network:The Battle of Lil' Slugger (Remix) ( XBL  PSN)Betus Blues (Retro Remix) (XBL  PSN)Can o' Salt (Remix) (XBL)Super Meat Boy OST Track ListNo.Track NameRemix Artist NameTrack Length1Boy Meats Girl (Intro Movie)1:042Super Meat Boy! (Main Theme)0:383Forest Funk (Ch 1 Light World)3:004Ballad of the Burning Squirrel (Ch 1 Dark World)2:515The Battle of Lil' Slugger (Ch 1 Boss)2:146Betus Blues (Ch 2 Light World)3:127C.H.A.D.'s Broken Wind (Ch 2 Dark World)3:468C.H.A.D.'s Lullaby (Ch 2 Boss)2:259Can o' Salt (Ch 3 Light World)3:2010Rocket Rider (Ch 3 Dark World)3:0011Fast Track to Brown Town (Ch 3 Boss)2:2412Hot Damned (Ch 4 Light World)2:5413Devil N. Bass (Ch 4 Dark World)2:4014Meat Golem (Ch 4 Boss)2:4515It Ends (Ch 5 Light World)3:2316Dr. Fetus' Castle (Ch 6 Dark World)3:0217Larries' Lament (Ch 5 Boss)2:4918It Ends 2: End Harder (Ch 6 Levels)3:0619Carmeaty Burana (Ch 6 Boss)4:2520Escape!2:3621End Credits1:3822McLarty Party People (Ch 7 Levels)3:0023Meat Spin (Teh Internets Levels)3:1224Forest Funk RETRO (Ch 1 Warp Zone)3:0025Betus Blues RETRO (Ch 2 Warp Zone)3:1226Can o' Salt RETRO (Ch 3 Warp Zone)3:2027Hot Damned RETRO (Ch 4 Warp Zone)2:5328It Ends RETRO (Ch 5 Warp Zone)3:2429MATTIAS' MANMEAT MIX (REMIX of Ch 1 Light)Mattias Häggström Gerdt3:2530Metal Meat (REMIX of Main Theme)George "Android-Music" Dziov3:2031Boss Burger N' Chips (REMIX of Ch 1 Boss)Inverse Phase3:3332Meatcraft (REMIX of Ch 3 Light)C4183:3133Power of the Meat (REMIX of Ch 1  2 Light)Josh Whelchel feat. Melinda Hershey5:3134It Ends with a Whimper3:05Super Meat Boy Double CD Special Edition Track ListDisc One (Soundtrack) is identical to the first 28 tracks of the OSTDisc Two (Extras)No.Track NameRemix Artist NameTrack Length1mAEt b0y (REMIX of Ch 4 Light World)A_Rival4:402Spoiled R0TT3N (REMIX of Teh Internets Theme)Benjamin Briggs3:293MATTIAS' MANMEAT MIX (REMIX of Ch 1 Light)Mattias Häggström Gerdt3:264Metal Meat (REMIX of Main Theme)George "Android-Music" Dziov3:215Boss Burger N' Chips (REMIX of Ch 1 Boss)Inverse Phase3:346Meatcraft (REMIX of Ch 3 Light)C4183:317Power of the Meat (REMIX of Ch 1  2 Light)Josh Whelchel feat. Melinda Hershey5:328Trailer Intro1:099Meat Boy (Flash) - Title1:1410World Map Theme1:1311Meat Fighter II0:2812Dun Dun Dun!!!0:0513Chapter 1 Menus1:0814Meat Boy (Flash) - Forest1:4415The Tragic Squirrel0:5416Wups!0:0317Meatroidvania0:0618Chapter 2 Menus1:0819...And Potatoes1:2020Chapter 2 Cutscene Score0:4321Chapter 3 Menus1:0822Meat Boy (Flash) - Salt Factory2:5423Chapter 3 Cutscene Score0:3424Chapter 4 Menus1:0825Chapter 4 Cutscene Score0:2926Chapter 5 Menus1:0827Meat Boy (Flash) - Hell3:2428It Ends with a Whimper3:0629???0:0530Chapter 5 Cutscene Score0:1731Chapter 6 Menus1:3432Chapter 6 Cutscene Score0:4033The End Cutscene Score1:2534Cotton Alley Menus1:08354-bit Meat Boy Theme0:3036Internets Menus0:51374-bit Internets Menus0:51388-bit Internets Menus1:423990's Ad Track1:1840World Map Theme (unused)1:1241World Map Theme 2 (unused)1:3542Character Select Theme (unused)0:3443Character Select Theme 2 (unused)1:1944Demo Cutscene Score0:2345Dun Dun Dun? (unused)0:04System Requirements (PC)MinimumRecommendedOS : Microsoft® Windows® XP / Vista / 7Processor: 1.2GHz processorMemory: 256 MB RAMGraphics: Graphics Card that supports Pixel Shader 2.0 and Vertex Shader 2.0(Vertex Shader Support can be supported with software emulation)DirectX®: DirectX® 9.0cHard Drive: 300 MBOS : Microsoft® Windows® XP / Vista / 7Processor: 1.4GHz or fasterMemory: 1 GB RAMGraphics : Graphics Card made within the last 4 years (Pixel Shader 3.0, Vertex Shader 3.0)DirectX®: DirectX® 9.0cHard Drive: 300 MBSystem Requirements (Mac)Minimum (developed on a 2008 iMac)OS: OSX 10.5Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo 2.66GhzMemory: 2GB 800 Mhz DDR2 SDRAMGraphics: ATI Radeon 2600 HD (see link for graphics performance support settings)External linksOfficial websiteMeat Boy Prototype</description><genres><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="35015">Meat Boy</game><game id="43081">Spewer</game><game id="43037">Triachnid</game><game id="35887">They Bleed Pixels</game><game id="38839">Cloudberry Kingdom</game><game id="41970">Electronic Super Joy</game><game id="42576">Freedom Fall</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1633133-box_supermeatboy.png</image></root>