<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25158</id><name>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Smash-Up</name><description>OverviewTeenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Smash-Up is a four-player fighting game for the PlayStation 2 and Nintendo Wii. The developers of the game, Game Arts, also worked on Super Smash Bros. Brawl, which this game's engine borrows heavily from. The art style is based off the 2007 CGI film, TMNT, yet includes different costumes for the characters based on both the 1987 and 2003 animated series. The game features multiple modes of play, including multiplayer online and a single-player Arcade mode, complete with cutscenes done by Mirage Studios, the comic book company that created the original Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles comic. The game was released on September 22, 2009.GameplayThe game plays incredibly similar to the Super Smash Bros. series, though with slight variations. It still has up to four players trying to KO each other. However, while everyone is still able to launch the other players out of the stage to defeat them, everyone has a health bar that will have the character blink out and respawn when depleted. With this, there are various traps and items scattered about the stages that the players may utilize to their advantage. There are also various options to customize the gameplay.CharactersThere are 16 characters to choose from:LeonardoDonatelloMichelangeloRaphaelApril O'NeilCasey JonesMaster SplinterFoot NinjaUtrominatorFugitoid (Wii only)KaraiNightwatcherShredderRaving Rabbid (Wii only)Ninja Rabbid (Wii only)Splinter Rabbid (Wii only)StagesThere are 14 stages, each varying in size, shape, and traps.DojoTurtle BaseCastleCruise ShipManhattanSewerTrainJungleEnemy BaseGarbage DumpSpacelabUndergroundWarehouseWestern TownItemsThere are 11 different item pick-ups, with varying uses for each of them.CratePizzaKunaiTriple KunaiBombMineFireEarthquakeTornadoLightningByakko</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20588">Super Smash Bros. Brawl</game><game id="17743">Super Smash Bros. Melee</game><game id="28102">Kabuki Ittou Ryoudan</game><game id="21241">Jump Super Stars</game><game id="22307">Battle Stadium D.O.N</game><game id="34429">Cartoon Network: Punch Time Explosion</game><game id="21870">The Outfoxies</game><game id="38140">PlayStation All-Stars Battle Royale</game><game id="41325">Digimon Tamers: Battle Spirit Ver 1.5</game><game id="35573">Super Smash Bros.</game><game id="42043">Toriko: Gourmet ga Battle</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2285740-box_tmntsu.png</image></root>