<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25226</id><name>Need for Speed World</name><description>GameplayIn this game you will find yourself in the familiar cities of Rockport and Palmont, where you are once again free to roam around as you please. Around the cities you will find event markers scattered about. When you approach an event marker you will have the option to play it in three different modes: single player, multiplayer, or a private match with friends. As you progress through the game you will unlock more events to play through. There is no limit to how many times you can play a particular event, nor is there a set order you have to complete them in - you don't even need to complete a certain number of them. You are free to participate in any event you like, and are able to progress through the game no matter which mode you complete the events in.Winning races and evading police pursuits will get you three things: rep, cash, and a random reward card. Random reward cards can contain extra cash or rep, or powerups. During races and pursuits you can use powerups to help give yourself an advantage. Some powerups are used to give yourself a boost, and others are used to attack other players.Police PursuitsYou also have the option to initiate a police pursuit, which is very similar to the police system in Need for Speed: Most Wanted. When in a pursuit you will see a meter on the bottom of the screen, telling you how close you are to losing sight of the cops or getting busted. If you manage to lose sight of the cops long enough for the meter to fill, a second meter will fill, which will slowly fill at a fixed rate. If the second meter fills, you've successfully evaded the cops. If the cops see you before the second meter fills, the pursuit starts again. Getting busted will reward you with a small amount of rep, but you will also have to pay a fine.During pursuits the police will try to use many tricks to make it challenging for you to escape. At first they will only ram into you, try to box you in when you slow down, and call for reinforcements. As you become more wanted they will use stronger and faster vehicles, and try to use other tricks, such as road blocks and spike traps. The more challenging a pursuit is to escape, the greater the reward will be for escaping it.ReputationRep is used to measure your progress throughout the game. You will get rep every time you complete a race or finish a police pursuit - no matter the outcome of them. The better you do in these events, the more rep you will get from them. There is a rep meter at the top of the screen that shows how much rep you currently have. Each time the meter fills, you gain a level. As your level increases, you will unlock new content, such as events, vehicles, and performance upgrades.Each time you level up you will also get to pick one skill to learn. Skills are divided into three categories: explore, racing, and pursuit. Each category contains skills which will help you in its respective event. Skills will allow you to do new things, or make existing things easier or more convenient. For example, you can learn a skill that will allow you to see where cops are on your mini-map, to help you during pursuits.MicrotransactionsThis game is supported by microtransactions, rather than a monthly fee. Microtransactions are small payments in exchange for in-game items or benefits. In Need for Speed World, you can buy the following through microtransactions:Powerups (sets of 5 or 10 of each)Vehicle rentals (one day)Vehicles slots in your safehouseBeta testsEA had two closed beta tests and one open beta test for the game, throughout the month of June and early July. Some of the features seen in these betas included:Single player racesMultiplayer racesLeveling-up/RepCar CustomizationCar DealershipPowerupsIn-game chat (text)Graphics/Physics Engine based on Need for Speed Most Wanted and CarbonPrivate Matches50 levels of progression'Car Show' Meeting AreasThe last beta ended on July 5th. EA has not announced any plans to open another beta trial sessions before the game launches.Current Car ListTier 1Mazdaspeed3* (Best Buy)1969 Dodge Charger R/TNissan Silvia S15* (Direct2Drive)Volkswagen Scirocco* (GameStop)Mitsubishi Eclipse GTNissan 240SXToyota Corolla AE86* (EA Store)1971 Dodge ChallengerTier 2BMW Z4 M CoupeLotus EliseNissan 350ZMazda RX-7Audi S5Porsche Cayman S2008 Dodge Charger R/TVolkswagen Golf R32Lexus IS-FMitsubishi Lancer Evo IXNissan 370ZSubaru WRX STiTier 3BMW M3 GTR (E46)Nissan GT-R (R35)Chevrolet Corvette Z06Lamborghini Gallardo LP560Audi R8*Cars were available during Beta, but in order to get them once the game is released, you MUST purchase the Need For Speed World Starter Pack</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6582">Test Drive Unlimited</game><game id="5648">Burnout Paradise</game><game id="5881">Forza Motorsport 2</game><game id="17599">Forza Motorsport</game><game id="23461">FUEL</game><game id="20729">GRID</game><game id="3916">DiRT</game><game id="20451">MotorStorm: Pacific Rift</game><game id="10124">Midnight Club: Street Racing</game><game id="20418">Midnight Club II</game><game id="5875">Midnight Club 3: DUB Edition</game><game id="20927">Midnight Club: Los Angeles</game><game id="21114">Midnight Club: Los Angeles Remix</game><game id="25485">Test Drive Unlimited 2</game><game id="12619">Motor City Online</game><game id="25961">Blur</game><game id="25523">Split/Second</game><game id="12976">Need for Speed: Most Wanted</game><game id="8844">Need for Speed: Carbon</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5150/1394940-957705_119555_front.jpg</image></root>