<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2523</id><name>The Daedalus Encounter</name><description> Overview    The Daedalus Encounter is a four CD,              full motion video  game developed for the 3DO console, PC and Mac. The video sequences are  added into pre-rendered  3D backgrounds. It was released in 1995 and  garnered moderate reviews.   It's the sort of game that quickly becomes  frustrating, especially when scenes have to be started all over again if  a mistake is made by the player.   The fact that it stars Tia Carrere  was used as a selling point, as demonstrated by the front cover of the  box.   The live action scenes were directed by Scott Ewers and filmed    in San Francisco at Cinerent Stage A.      Gameplay       Casey open the door, Casey do this, Casey do that.  I shall have my revenge, you'll see. Yay, I killed Ari, woohoo!  Now to deal with Zack.The video cut scenes are linked together with various puzzles and  limited exploration areas.   A great deal of the puzzles involve either  opening doors or activating consoles.   You are occasionally tasked with  saving the lives of your companions, but it is usually far more  entertaining to watch them die.  The game ends if any of the main  characters die, but you can restart the current scene to continue.   Plot Hi Casey, you had a horrific accident and only your brain survived, but I'm sure you'll bounce back! Ari and Zack are ex-military personnel turned scavengers.   You play the  role of their comrade Casey, who suffers a serious accident but is  brought back as a cyborg with limited capabilities.   For most of the  game you see through the eyes of a remote probe controlled by Casey (the  player) from the ship.   Zack and Ari decide to roam the Galaxy hunting  for "juicy derelict ships" to plunder, but they soon get into trouble  and need Casey's help to escape their predicament.   Characters    Ariel MathesonTough and disciplined, Ari (    Tia Carrere) used to be a military pilot and commanded the TAS Interceptor Talon  in the first interstellar war.   She likes to play things by the rules  even though she now no longer works in the military.   She finds Zack's  "loose cannon" approach irksome at times, but tolerates his behaviour  because of his friendship and loyalty. Zack Smith  Zack (   Christian Bocher) used to be the Warrant Officer and co-pilot aboard the Talon  under Ari's command.   He has a relaxed approach to situations, and  sometimes wishes Ari would let her hair down and not be so disciplined  all the time.Casey O'BannonCasey used to be the gunner on the Talon and has known Ari and  Zack since basic training.   A serious accident reduces him to a "brain  in a box" as Zack puts it.   Zack and Ari couldn't resist putting the  old team back together and so rescued Casey from the lab where he was  held. Casey is the character controlled by the player. </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2365948-3do_thedaedalusencounter.jpg</image></root>