<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25241</id><name>Madden NFL 10</name><description>Madden 10 Cover Athlete The official cover announcement was made on Friday, April 24th at the NFL Draft. Two athletes are on the cover for the first time in series history.  The cover athletes are Larry Fitzgerald, Wide Receiver of the Arizona Cardinals and Troy Polamalu, Safety of the         Pittsburgh Steelers.  The cover athletes embrace the motto of Madden NFL 10: "Fight For Every Yard."The candidates for Madden NFL 10 cover athlete were:           Adrian Peterson, Running Back (Minnesota Vikings) Ed Reed, Safety (Baltimore Ravens)          Ben Roethlisberger, Quarter Back (Pittsburgh Steelers)Brandon Jacobs, Running Back (New York Giants)DeMarcus Ware, Line Backer (Dallas Cowboys)Matt Cassel, Quarter Back (Kansas City Chiefs)Larry Fitzgerald, Wide Receiver (Arizona Cardinals)         Peyton Manning, Quarter Back (Indianapolis Colts) Troy Polamalu, Safety (Pittsburgh Steelers)Developer Interaction Super Bowl 43 Lead Designer of Madden NFL 10 Ian Cummings posted the first in a series of blogs during the halftime show of Super Bowl 43. Throughout the development cycle, news on various updates and improvements such as Procedural Awareness and changes to the speed of the game. The first screen-shot of Madden NFL 10, revealed by EA Sports president Peter Moore, displays a number of changes to the game.   Refs patrol the field. A chain gang runs on the field to measure first downs. Super Bowl patches on uniforms.  Super Bowl sidelines display team colors. Single-digit numbers sit on the yellow line of the Steelers' helmets.  Last year, the number was incorrectly to the right of the stripe. Enhanced secondary team colors. Big Ben is now equipped with a towel.  Towels are one of the most requested enhancements.  Gamers are demanding!     Make the call, coach  Injuries have been revamped in Madden NFL 10 to be more realistic. The outcome of an injury's severity is delayed rather than immediate. Trainers will run out onto the field and in serious cases, the injury cart. The user is prompted when a player can return to the field, but with the risk of re-injury.   Presentation has received a much needed upgrade as well, both on the field and off. Franchise mode now has The Extra Point, a week summarizing highlight show similar to the one found in               ESPN NFL 2k5. Players are shown warming up before the game as well tailgating fans. Finally, the USAF Thunderbirds will fly over the Super Bowl.  Madden Ultimate Team In January, EA released a new gameplay mode, Madden Ultimate Team, that was downloaded as a patch for free. The mode is played like a card game, the player is given a large deck of bronze cards to begin with. Four levels of card packs can be purchased through the store, either with "coins" that you make through the mode, or they can be purchased with real money over Xbox Live/Playstation Network. The games are played with every player that you have in your deck of cards in either CPU matches against real football teams, or other users online against their Ultimate Team card deck. Each card can suffer from an injury or run out of games for their contract, both can be healed with an injury card or contract card. Other ways to find players for your team include an auction house and a deals of the week section.   Team Ratings TeamOffenseDefenseOverall Bears848585 Bengals847781 Bills818383 Broncos817882 Browns808282 Buccaneers798080 Cardinals898588 Chargers898586 Chiefs847580 Colts918287 Cowboys878386 Dolphins857882 Eagles888486 Falcons897781 49ers798181 Giants858686 Jaguars828283 Jets818785 Lions787778 Packers868485 Panthers878285 Patriots908689 Raiders758381 Rams818080 Ravens838484 Redskins858685 Saints898084 Seahawks838585 Steelers898990 Texans848283 Titans838484 Vikings808684 Ratings: Top 10 by Position Quarterback Peyton Manning              99  Tom Brady                       98Drew Brees                     97Kurt Warner                     94Ben Roethlisberger       93Donovan McNabb          91Philip Rivers                    88Carson Palmer               87 Jay Cutler                         87Tony Romo                          87Running BacksAdrian Peterson             97  Michael Turner               95 LaDainian Tomlinson  94 Brian Westbrook            94 DeAngelo Williams       94 Clinton Portis                 93Steven Jackson             92Frank Gore                      91Brandon Jacobs            90Thomas Jones              90      Wide ReceiversLarry Fitzgerald              99 Andre Johnson              98Steve Smith                    97Randy Moss                   96Reggie Wayne               95Anquan Boldin               94Roddy White                   94Brandon Marshall         92Calvin Johnson             92Terrell Owens                91 Tight EndTony Gonzalez               98  Jason Witten                  97 Antonio Gates                95 Chris Cooley                  91 Kellen Winslow             90Heath Miller                    88 John Carlson                 87 Zach Miller                      86 Owen Daniels                86  Defensive PlayersNnamdi Asomugha (CB)         99 Albert Haynesworth (DT)          99 Ed Reed (S)                                99Troy Polamalu (S)                      99 Patrick Willis (LB)                      98 Jared Allen (DE)                        98 DeMarcus Ware (LB)                98 Kevin Williams (DT)                  97 Ray Lewis (LB)                          97 Julius Peppers (DE)                 97SoundtrackThe Soundtrack consists of 25 songs from a variety of different artists:2Pac - Can't C MeAirbourne - Heads Are Gonna RollAlice In Chains - Them BonesB.o.B - Created A MonsterBang Camaro - RevolutionBeastie Boys - SabotageBlack Sabbath - ParanoidCypress Hill - Get 'Em UpHelmet - UnsungIron Maiden - Aces HighJudas Priest - PainkillerKid Rock - I Am The BullgodKillswitch Engage - ReckoningKoRn - BlindMastadon - DivinationsNas feat. Puff Daddy - Hate Me NowNirvana - BreedPantera - WalkPublic Enemy - Shut Em DownRage Against The Machine - Guerrilla RadioSet Your Goals - Gaia Bleeds (Make Way for Man)Slipknot - DualitySystem Of A Down - SugarThe Vanity Plan - Before I DieYoung Dre The Truth - Cheah Beah Xbox 360 Hard Drive Install Installing Madden 10 takes up about 5.7 GB of space on the hard drive.Links for Madden 10 The                      Madden Developer Blog will take you behind the scenes of Madden 10.                      Official Madden NFL 10 Website                     Giant Bomb Online Franchise Thread</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="21">Football</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2632">Mutant League Football</game><game id="20848">NCAA Football 09</game><game id="8480">All-Pro Football 2K8</game><game id="5629">Backyard Football 2002</game><game id="13056">ESPN NFL 2K5</game><game id="25614">NCAA Football 10</game><game id="21449">Eyeshield 21</game><game id="20920">Blitz: The League II</game><game id="4166">Blitz: The League</game><game id="20810">NCAA Football 09: All-Play</game><game id="21951">NCAA Football 08</game><game id="27692">NFL 2010</game><game id="20986">Backbreaker</game><game id="30003">NCAA Football 11</game><game id="23246">Football</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2250694-box_madden10.png</image></root>