<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25345</id><name>Eternal Silence</name><description>Eternal Silence is a Cinematic Multiplayer Space Mod built on the Source Engine. It has been in development since 2003.FeaturesCinematic Battles between Capital Ships on battlefields as large as 32768 cubic kilometers Choose between ataining victory on foot by capturing the enemy's subsystems, or be a pilot and bomb vital systems from space. Fast and Furious dogfights between Fighters and other Tactical Craft in deep space. Escort you gunships to deliver a squad of marines to the enemy hangar. A True Space Experience. Cut your ship's engines and drift in the frictionless void of space. Action-Packed ground battles. Seize decks of your enemy’s ship, controlling or disabling their shields, weapons... Fight off the enemy and work as a team, fulfilling the role of one of many classes with an array of unique weapons at your disposal. Achieve Victory by destroying the enemy capital ship inside and out. A Complete Story behind the Eternal Silence universe, released chapter by chapter as a novella is available online  ClassesThere are two sides that the player can choose to join, either the United Terran Forces or the Neo-Galactic Militia. Both sides consist of only two classes.United Terran Forces (UTF)UTF MarineIdeal for boarding ships and fighting in close combat, they can use Carbines, Tankbusters, Machine Guns, Grenade Launchers and Ion Cannons.UTF HackerUTF Hackers are used to disable the NGM's computer systems easily and quickly as well as being able to secure communication with the commander. They can be equipped with a SMG, Railgun and a Hackbox.Neo-Galactic Militia (NGM)NGM MilitiamanSimilar to the UTF Marine a Militiaman is a fast and well trained soldier who can be equipped with Carbines, Tankbusters, Machine Guns, Flamethrowers and Ion Cannons.NGM HackerJust like a UTF Hacker a NGM Hacker is used to shut down the UTF's computer systems and secure communication with the commander. They can be equipped with a SMG, Railgun and a Hackbox.ShipsUTF Fighter UTF Interceptor NGM Fighter NGM Heavy Fighter Bomber Gunship </description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25130">Dystopia</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1379/891005-untitled_1.png</image></root>