<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2543</id><name>Super Scope 6</name><description>OverviewSuper Scope 6 (known in Europe as Nintendo Scope 6) is a minigame collection developed by Nintendo's RD1 division and published by Nintendo for the Super Nintendo Entertainment System on February 1992. Bundled with the Super Scope light-gun accessory, this collection includes six minigames that require the use of the accessory, ranging from the Blastris series of action puzzle games to the LazerBlazer series of action rail shooters.GamesThe six games are split into two categories: Blastris (for casual games, including Blastris A, Blastris B, and Mole Patrol) and LazerBlazer (for action games, including Intercept, Engage, and Confront).Each game has three difficulty settings: Low, Medium, and High. Higher difficulty settings start the player in later levels.Blastris ALoosely based on Tetris.This game can be played in two-player mode (playing alternately).Blastris BLoosely based on Columns.The game has two variations:Type A is a stage-based mode in which players must clear each game board of Monster Blocks (blocks that are "wiggling" to differentiate them from normal blocks) to proceed to a harder stage (with more Monster Blocks to start with).Type B is a score-based mode in which players progress through one endless game board. As players gain points, the speed at which blocks drop increases.Mole PatrolMole Patrol is a Whac-A-Mole game in which players must blast blue moles that pop out of one of twelve holes on the ground. Players must be quick, as the moles sink back into their hole soon after popping up. They must also be careful, as shooting pink moles cause the moles to temporarily move at a faster speed (making them more difficult to hit). At certain times throughout the game, a bonus mole appears in the sky (flying on a rocket). Shooting that mole grants bonus points.Each round is won when all blue moles are blasted before the timer reaches zero. If the timer ever reaches zero, the game is over. Players earn less points at the end of the round by missing shots and having blue moles sink back into their hole.The main game mode is called "Stage Mode". A second mode, called "Score Mode", requires players to shoot blue moles in order for one round (with no pink moles or bonus moles).Intercept Engage Confront</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="15">Compilation</genre><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="35">Light-Gun Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1744">Lethal Enforcers</game><game id="12213">Lethal Enforcers II: Gun Fighters</game><game id="22002">TinStar</game><game id="2758">Duck Hunt</game><game id="12460">Super Mario Bros. / Duck Hunt</game><game id="16834">City Killer</game><game id="40593">Space Shadow</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14994/493736-super_scope_6.gif</image></root>