<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25442</id><name>Tiger Woods PGA Tour 10</name><description>New to this year's version:U.S. Open: The first time the U.S. Open has been in the Tiger Woods series.Tournament Challenge: Play in past PGA Tour event scenarios as you attempt to change the outcome.Dynamic Weather Conditions: Real-time weather conditions on each course you play.Live Tournaments: Real-World events where you compete against the pros. Daily and weekly tournaments for leaderboard dominance.Precision Putting: A new putting meter and fixed length putter.No Saving ReplaysNew to the Wii:Wii Motion Plus: Buy it bundled or play without it. The Motion Plus adapter should increase the control of the club; better draw and fade mechanic and more of a 1:1 motion for your golfer.Disc Golf: Play on custom tees on all 27 courses in the game. Motion Plus will also be implemented.Precision Putting: Backswing length and downswing tempo have been added along with the fixed putter length.Dynamic Weather Conditions: You get real-time weather conditions on each course you play using the Wii Forcast Channel.Live Tournaments: New for the Wii, daily and weekly tournaments, plus play the pros.Courses confirmed for the Wii version:Disc GolfNew for 10:1. Banff Springs ( Stanley Thompson 18 )2. Bethpage ( Black )3. Hazeltine National C.C.4. Oakmont C.C.5. Pinehurst ( Course #2 )6. Torrey Pines G.C. ( South Course )7. Turnberry ( Ailsa Course )Returning from 09:8. Bay Hill Club  Lodge9. Cog Hill Golf  CC ( Dubsdread Course )Precision Putting10. Doral ( Blue Monster )11. East Lake C.C.12. Fancourt ( Links Course )13. Firestone C.C. ( South Course )14. Gary Player C.C.15. Harbor Town Golf Links16. The K Club Golf Resort17. Kiawah Island Golf Resort ( Ocean Course )18. Pebble Beach Golf Links19. Riviera C.C.20. Sheshan Golf ClubDraw and Fade like the pros with Motion Plus21. St Andrews Links ( Old Course )23. TPC Sawgrass24. TPC Scottsdale25. Wentworth ( West Course )26. Westchester C.C.27. Wolf Creek G.C.List of Pro Golfers:Tiger WoodsAnthony Kim *new*Rocco Mediate *new*Michael CampbellDarren ClarkPaula CreamerChris DimarcoLuke DonaldNick DoughertyJim FurykRetief GoosenNatalie GulbisChristie KerrRory McilroyColin MontgomerieSe Ri PakIan PoulterMorgan PresselJustin RoseAdam ScottVijay SingAnnika SorenstamCamilo VillegasMike Weir</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="28">Golf</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20598">Hot Shots Golf: Out of Bounds</game><game id="20811">We Love Golf!</game><game id="19716">Mario Golf</game><game id="20058">Mario Golf: Advance Tour</game><game id="21364">Golf: Tee It Up!</game><game id="1598">Mario Golf: Toadstool Tour</game><game id="22203">Super Swing Golf</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2269434-box_twpgat10.png</image></root>