<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25468</id><name>Wallace &amp; Gromit's Grand Adventures Episode 3: Muzzled</name><description> Plot   Shortly after their  holiday season  has ended,  Wallace and Gromit's  local town is visited by a charity fair, run by  Monty Muzzle  in aid of building a new dog shelter. At home in West Wallaby Street, Wallace has to deal with 3 stray dogs whilst he attempts to fine tune his latest invention, an Ice Cream Maker than can create any flavour of Ice Cream. The duo visit the Charity fair, and after some investigating, Gromit discovers that Monty is pocketing the townspeople's donations for himself and is in fact using the stray dogs as manual labour for the fake Fair.   Wallace confronts Mr. Muzzle about the scam, who then flees the scene in a giant hot air balloon in the shape of his own head. Wallace and Gromit give chase, and eventually stop Monty, freeing the stray dogs and getting the town's money back.   Wallace meets the nefarious con-man, Monty Muzzle.     As a sub-plot throughout the episode, Felicity Flitt dumps Duncan McBiscuit and becomes enamoured with Wallace's bravery in dealing with Monty Muzzle. At the end of the episode she confuses Wallace finding a loose fastening nut as a marriage propsal for her, ending the game with a cliffhanger.  Gameplay  Muzzled!  follows a similar gameplay design to other Telltale adventure games such as the Tales of Monkey Island series and the Sam  Max series. Players interact with the game's world by collecting and combining items, as well as talking to other characters, to progress the story. The game also makes use of a variable hint system controlled by the player in the Options Panel - players can change the intensity and detail of the amount of Hints the game gives the player when they are stuck.  Peter Sallis, the actor who lends his voice to Wallace in all of the Wallace and Gromit films, does not return as the voice of Wallace in any of the Grand Adventures games. Instead, Aardman Animation's Offical Back Up voice actor for Wallace, Ben Whitehead, voices the character instead.       PC Requirements Operating System: Microsoft® Windows® XP/VistaProcessor: 2.0 Ghz or better (3 GHz Pentium® 4 or equivalent recommended)Memory: 512 MB RAM (1GB recommended)Hard Disk Space: 310 MBVideo Card: 64 MB DirectX® 8.1 compliant video card (128 MB recommended)Sound Card: DirectX® 8.1 sound deviceDirectX® Version: DirectX® Version 9.0c or better (DirectX updater included)Controller Support: Yes    No internet connection required to play    </description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="30008">Sam &amp; Max Episode 301: The Penal Zone</game><game id="26778">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 3: Lair of the Leviathan</game><game id="9015">Sam &amp; Max Episode 202: Moai Better Blues</game><game id="4885">Sam &amp; Max Episode 203: Night of the Raving Dead</game><game id="4399">Sam &amp; Max Episode 204: Chariots of the Dogs</game><game id="21643">Sam &amp; Max Episode 205: What's New, Beelzebub?</game><game id="30372">Sam &amp; Max Episode 303: They Stole Max's Brain</game><game id="30373">Sam &amp; Max Episode 304: Beyond the Alley of the Dolls</game><game id="30374">Sam &amp; Max Episode 305: The City That Dares Not Sleep</game><game id="7344">Sam &amp; Max Episode 5: Reality 2.0</game><game id="32592">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 1: It's About Time</game><game id="33414">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 2: Get Tannen!</game><game id="33415">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 3: Citizen Brown</game><game id="33416">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 4: Double Visions</game><game id="33417">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 5: OUTATIME</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4938/1057769-logo.png</image></root>