<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25469</id><name>Wallace &amp; Gromit's Grand Adventures Episode 4: The Bogey Man</name><description> Plot In order to diffuse Felicity Fitt's mistake from the end of the previous game, Gromit suggests that Wallace join the Prickly Thicket Country Club. Ms Flitt's aunt absolutely loathes the Club, and forbids Felicity from marrying Wallace as long as he is a member.   PC Dibbins, the local constable, is jealous that Wallace was admitted over him. He uses an obscure bylaw to threaten the club with closure since it doesn't have a golf course–or rather it does, but members don't know where it is because the deed is missing, safely held in a security system designed by Wallace's (apparent) ancestor, Alderman Willis. Using his detective equipment Wallace manages to find the deed, but discovers that the entire town was built on the golf course, and a vengeful Duncan McBiscuit, the current Club Chairman, decides to have the town destroyed in order to rebuild the course. Wallace challenges Duncan to a golf tourney so that he may become chairman and tear up the deed, saving the town, and manages to win with Gromit's help. However, as he goes to tear the deed, the security system traps him and the other townsfolk in a room, and Gromit is forced to disable the trap and free everyone. Wallace tears up the deed, and is thankful to find that Ms. Flitt has cancelled their engagement and gone back to Duncan, who her aunt now approves of since he is no longer the club chairman. GameplayThe Bogey Manfollows a similar gameplay design to other Telltale adventure games such as the Tales of Monkey Island series and the Sam  Max series. Players interact with the game's world by collecting and combining items, as well as talking to other characters, to progress the story. The game also makes use of a variable hint system controlled by the player in the Options Panel - players can change the intensity and detail of the amount of Hints the game gives the player when they are stuck. Peter Sallis, the actor who lends his voice to Wallace in all of the Wallace and Gromit films, does not return as the voice of Wallace in any of the Grand Adventures games. Instead, Aardman Animation's Offical Back Up voice actor for Wallace, Ben Whitehead, voices the character instead.  PC RequirementsOperating System: Microsoft® Windows® XP/VistaProcessor: 2.0 Ghz or better (3 GHz Pentium® 4 or equivalent recommended)Memory: 512 MB RAM (1GB recommended)Hard Disk Space: 310 MBVideo Card: 64 MB DirectX® 8.1 compliant video card (128 MB recommended)Sound Card: DirectX® 8.1 sound deviceDirectX® Version: DirectX® Version 9.0c or better (DirectX updater included)Controller Support: YesNo internet connection required to play</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20587">Strong Bad's Cool Game for Attractive People Episode 1: Homestar Ruiner</game><game id="10837">Bone: Out from Boneville</game><game id="10505">Bone: The Great Cow Race</game><game id="30008">Sam &amp; Max Episode 301: The Penal Zone</game><game id="26778">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 3: Lair of the Leviathan</game><game id="9015">Sam &amp; Max Episode 202: Moai Better Blues</game><game id="4885">Sam &amp; Max Episode 203: Night of the Raving Dead</game><game id="4399">Sam &amp; Max Episode 204: Chariots of the Dogs</game><game id="21643">Sam &amp; Max Episode 205: What's New, Beelzebub?</game><game id="30372">Sam &amp; Max Episode 303: They Stole Max's Brain</game><game id="30373">Sam &amp; Max Episode 304: Beyond the Alley of the Dolls</game><game id="30374">Sam &amp; Max Episode 305: The City That Dares Not Sleep</game><game id="7344">Sam &amp; Max Episode 5: Reality 2.0</game><game id="32592">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 1: It's About Time</game><game id="33414">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 2: Get Tannen!</game><game id="33415">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 3: Citizen Brown</game><game id="33416">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 4: Double Visions</game><game id="33417">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 5: OUTATIME</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4938/1094264-a.png</image></root>