<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25467</id><name>Wallace &amp; Gromit's Grand Adventures Episode 2: The Last Resort</name><description>PlotWith the profits from their now defunct Honey making business , Wallace and Gromit plan to go to Blackpool on holiday. Gromit eagerly anticipates the upcoming trip, however he is disheartened by the awful weather, which means that the duo are unable to go. The bad weather also causes their basement to flood, and Gromit has to navigate eletrocuted waters to switch off the power before Wallace can hurt himself.In order to cheer the depressed dog up, Wallace decides to convert the water logged basement into a seaside resort so they can have all the fun of Blackpool in their own home - he also opens it up the the local townsfolk, who are also unable to go on holiday because of the weather. However, try as he might, Wallace has a hard time pleasing everyone with his resort - Duncan McBiscuit is loud and offensive to other guests, and Felicity Flitt's two puppies are causing havoc and too much noise for Mr. Paneer and PC Dibbins. Wallace eventually manages to put things straight amongst the guests, but later on Duncan is mysteriously attacked by an unknown assailant.Wallace and Gromit both investigate the attack, and eventually deduce that the assailants were in fact Ms. Flitt's two dogs attacked Duncan when he took their favorite chew toy from them. During the episode's finale, the drain in the basement dislodges, flushing the two puppies and their chew toy through the sewers and into a cell at the local Police station. With his Home-made Seaside Resort in tatters, Wallace begins to clean up the mess in the basement.GameplayThe Last Resort follows a similar gameplay design to other Telltale adventure games such as the Tales of Monkey Island series and the Sam  Max series. Players interact with the game's world by collecting and combining items, as well as talking to other characters, to progress the story. The game also makes use of a variable hint system controlled by the player in the Options Panel - players can change the intensity and detail of the amount of Hints the game gives the player when they are stuck.Peter Sallis, the actor who lends his voice to Wallace in all of the Wallace and Gromit films, does not return as the voice of Wallace in any of the Grand Adventures games. Instead, Aardman Animation's Offical Back Up voice actor for Wallace, Ben Whitehead, voices the character instead.PC RequirementsOperating System: Microsoft® Windows® XP/VistaProcessor: 2.0 Ghz or better (3 GHz Pentium® 4 or equivalent recommended)Memory: 512 MB RAM (1GB recommended)Hard Disk Space: 310 MBVideo Card: 64 MB DirectX® 8.1 compliant video card (128 MB recommended)Sound Card: DirectX® 8.1 sound deviceDirectX® Version: DirectX® Version 9.0c or better (DirectX updater included)Controller Support: YesNo internet connection required to play</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5729">The Curse of Monkey Island</game><game id="30008">Sam &amp; Max Episode 301: The Penal Zone</game><game id="26778">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 3: Lair of the Leviathan</game><game id="9015">Sam &amp; Max Episode 202: Moai Better Blues</game><game id="4885">Sam &amp; Max Episode 203: Night of the Raving Dead</game><game id="4399">Sam &amp; Max Episode 204: Chariots of the Dogs</game><game id="21643">Sam &amp; Max Episode 205: What's New, Beelzebub?</game><game id="30372">Sam &amp; Max Episode 303: They Stole Max's Brain</game><game id="30373">Sam &amp; Max Episode 304: Beyond the Alley of the Dolls</game><game id="30374">Sam &amp; Max Episode 305: The City That Dares Not Sleep</game><game id="7344">Sam &amp; Max Episode 5: Reality 2.0</game><game id="32592">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 1: It's About Time</game><game id="33414">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 2: Get Tannen!</game><game id="33415">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 3: Citizen Brown</game><game id="33416">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 4: Double Visions</game><game id="33417">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 5: OUTATIME</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4938/967732-title.png</image></root>