<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25513</id><name>Ceville</name><description>OverviewCeville is a third person point and click adventure game developed by German-based developer Realmforge. Features detailed 3D environments and has four playable characters.GameplayA traditional adventure game, it features hotspot highlighting where pressing the space bar shows all interactive items on screen. Optionally it can also show what items can be combined with the currently selected inventory itemThe game has several sequences where you control two characters at the same who can switch inventory items with each other. It also features timed sequences where a certain action has to be preformed in a certain time limit. You can never fail these, as they are infinitely restartable.PlotAct 0: FugitiveThis act serves as the tutorial to the game and thus is rather short and simple, it tells the story of the short evil tyrant Ceville ruler of Faeryanis who is faced with a revolt and has to flee his castle which.. doesn't go perfectly.Act 1: Fellowship of the KingCeville finds himself in Jail and meets a little girl named Lilly who decides to help him break free and as such they set out to escape out of the castle to escape to the wilderness.Meanwhile Basilius has taken the King position before a new one has been elected. His plans however are to rule all of Faeryanis by fear with a demonic army.Act 2: The Emperor Strikes BackCeville gets told that he can't leave town because he doesn't have the required paperwork that's now required to leave the castle due to new laws by Basilius.Council Members are gathering to vote for the new king, but they're not exactly in a hurry to come and need a helping hand.Act 3: Get BasiliusA group of heroes goes towards Basilius' throne room to face him and get the elected Gwendolyn on the throne but the plan backfiresAct 4 : Return of the KingThe final stretch to get Ceville back on his beloved throne and face off against the mighty mage Basilius.CharactersCevilleThe main character of the game who's very self-centered, egotistical, greedy and all in all very unlikable, but in his own way extremely charming and lovable.LillyThe alter-ego of Ceville and in many ways an all "good" character who really is there to save Ceville from acting on his evil thoughts and the only person to believe the fallen tyrant Ceville in his moment of need.AmbrosiusA proud knight who's entirely too fixated on his looks and can stare at his body and hair for hours on end. He also loves to tell stories about his adventures, especially to the women.CholloChollo can best be seen as a man who does it all, he'll do the job that seems like the best thing to do at the time, from perfume salesman to having a laundry service to having a travel agency, all in his trusty caravan.He's also a lover of smelly cheeses and overall greedy.PC System RequirementsOperating system: Windows® XP  VistaProcessor: CPU with 1,7GHzMemory: 512MBHard disk space: 2GBVideo: 3D Graphic Card with 256 MB RamDirectX® Version: 9c</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="31451">The Book of Unwritten Tales</game><game id="39143">Haunted</game><game id="10528">Monkey Island 2:  LeChuck's Revenge</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/7439/914971-ceville_video_game.jpg</image></root>