<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25512</id><name>Clutch</name><description>Overview Clutch is a vehicular combat and racing game by      Targem Games. The core concept is very similar to the popular      Carmageddon series, which in turn is based on the cult-classic film,  Death Race 2000. The game places players in a post-apocalyptic future where people attach giant blades to the sides of their cars and then race in areas populated by the      living dead. Cars are mangled, pedestrians are disemboweled, and points are undoubtedly earned.StoryDrivers fight to the death. The Franco-Swiss border near Geneva, Switzerland has been transformed into a wasteland following a catastrophe at the Large Hadron Collider facility. A quarantine of the area has been established, yet a group of thrill-hungry treasure hunters known as The Harvesters have made their home inside the zone. Within the perimeter, The Harvesters transform cars into high-octane war machines, outfitting them with giant blades and other weapons. Zombies and mutants occupy the irradiated area surrounding the LHC facility making it a dangerous location to traverse, but priceless artifacts have also been created in the wake of the catastrophe. Is collecting these valuables worth the risk? Perhaps deep down in the core of the ruins of the LHC lies the ultimate prize. The only way to find out is to make it there alive... Features  High-speed racing and vehicular destructionAn open world environment based on the Large Hadron Collider facility and surrounding areaA single player campaign with 20 story missions6 modes of racing and combat, including race, destruction derby, and zombie slaughter-festAdvanced collision detection and damage physicsA wide selection of drivable vehicles with upgrades such as blades, grinders, and nitrous injectorsOver 20 artifact types that can be used to affect the abilities of yourself and your opponentsPC System Requirements Windows XP / Vista3.0 Ghz processor or higher1 GB of RAMVideo card with 128 MB of RAMDirectX 9 or 10</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18394">Carmageddon</game><game id="10553">Carmageddon II: Carpocalypse Now</game><game id="11124">Carmageddon TDR 2000</game><game id="15113">Carmageddon Splat Pack</game><game id="786">Destruction Derby</game><game id="13776">Destruction Derby 2</game><game id="16810">Destruction Derby 64</game><game id="6836">FlatOut: Ultimate Carnage</game><game id="859">FlatOut 2</game><game id="13177">FlatOut</game><game id="20998">FlatOut: Head On</game><game id="16436">Twisted Metal 2</game><game id="6426">Twisted Metal: Black</game><game id="9259">Twisted Metal: Head-On</game><game id="4635">Twisted Metal III</game><game id="10173">Twisted Metal 4</game><game id="12318">Twisted Metal</game><game id="22286">Death Track: Resurrection</game><game id="32627">Blood Drive</game><game id="14950">Death Race</game><game id="37034">Dirt Showdown</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14982/913428-1007.jpg</image></root>