<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25565</id><name>Army of Two: The 40th Day</name><description>OverviewArmy of Two the 40th day was developed by                            EA Montreal and is the                    sequel to the original                            Army Of Two. Like its predecessor, T.F.D. focuses heavily on                   co-op play either with a human or an                  A.I. controlled partner. Following                 Salem and                Rios again, this time they are working for their own               private military corporation, Trans World Operations (TWO). 40th day is set solely in              Shanghai rather than the globe-trotting of the first game to create a more believable experience and it puts players in the middle of an ongoing catastrophe and conflict.  Gameplay   The game added a new feature called "two-man tactics" to give players a greater amount of choice as to how they will tackle each challenge in the game. Other new features are an overhauled A.I. system, new co-op partner controls, a realistic materials system that allows shooting through walls.  Also the             weapon customization has been upgraded; now you can put any part of a weapon onto another weapon, which changes both the look and            stats.Plot  At the end of the first game, Salem and Rios took down the SCC corporation, thus making them start their own private military organization called TWO (Trans World Operations). There is a           cutscene with Rios and Salem in a          helicopter along with Cha Min Soo and Viktor Roshanko, weapon and armor dealers,  and their investors. They ask         Alice to be their contract filer and she agrees.  In this second installment in the series, Rios and Salem travel to Shanghai for a reason that is "yet unknown". As the two are there, the        city turns to chaos and an unknown army has attacked for an unknown reason.  It is the choice of Rios and Salem to fight their way out, or to discover the mystery of the 40th Day and save the city.  Soundtrack  The soundtrack is composed by Tyler Bates:Introduction                 What Else Could Go Wrong?        Highrise                    Embassy                    Descent                    Bossa China (Interlude)        Vertigo            Can Your Contact Hear Me?        Highway                Free Murray                Get To Ground        A Few Extra Bullets        Zoo                    Cages            Hospital Streets            Auditorium                Breznev                Back To Back        Bund Downloadable ContentSo far they have released one       DLC add-on named Chapters of Deceit which adds 2 new      campaign levels: The Assassination and Collateral Damage. It is $9.99 on     PSN and 800    Microsoft Points on   Xbox Live Arcade.  Xbox 360 Game  Installation on the  Xbox 360 hard drive takes up 6.0GB of space. It is currently unknown whether this results in increased performance or a decrease in load times for the game.</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20662">Gears of War 2</game><game id="12231">Gears of War</game><game id="20454">50 Cent: Blood on the Sand</game><game id="24514">Terminator Salvation</game><game id="5556">Killzone: Liberation</game><game id="20703">Dark Void</game><game id="26394">Kane &amp; Lynch 2: Dog Days</game><game id="24041">Quantum Theory</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1887860-box_aot40d.png</image></root>