<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25577</id><name>Touhou 12 - Undefined Fantastic Object</name><description>OverviewUndefined Fantastic Object is the 12th game in the Touhou Project released on the Windows OS in 2009.PlotEven before arrival of spring, a rumor began to spread that a treasure ship had been spotted in the sky above Gensokyo. Some considered it as a great luck and started to compete over the ship. However, there were black shadows chasing the girls at high speed behind the ship...CharactersUndefined Fantastic Object features 3 unique characters, each with 2 different bullet types. The player decides the character and bullet type to play at the beginning of the game:Reimu HakureiAttack Type A (Concentrated attack type)Shot: Persuasion NeedleBomb: Wild Exorcism DanceAttack Type B (Anti-pattern focused homing type)Shot: Homing AmuletBomb: Fantasy SealMarisa KirisameAttack Type A (If it's a treasure ship, there's gotta be treasure.)Shot: Illusion LaserBomb: Master SparkAttack Type B (I'm very interested in this, whatever it is.)Shot: Super Short-waveBomb: Ultimate Short-waveSanae KochiyaAttack Type A (Just as Lady Kanako says.)Shot: Sky SerpentBomb: Orochi of Ancient TimesAttack Type B (Just as Lady Suwako says.)Shot: Cobalt SpreadBomb: Wily ToadScoringEnemiesAny damage dealt to any enemy, whether it be caused by your shots or your bombs, will cause your score to increase very slightly. Defeating enemies will give you slightly more points, but the points earned from this vary from hundreds to thousands of points per enemy. This is amount of points is very little, but defeated enemies release items for you to collect which is more important for scoring.Point ItemsPoint items are the major source of points in the game. The higher up on the screen you collect them, the more points they give points, up to a defined maximum. Whenever you collect point items with their maximum value, they show the value in yellow text. The auto-item-collect line is the same height as the height where point items reach their maximum value. Unlike in the previous games, autocollected items don't lose their point worth if you leave the autocollect area before items contact your hitbox.The Point Items starting value depends on the chosen difficulty:- Easy: 5,000- Normal: 10,000- Hard: 20,000-Lunatic: 50,000The value of Point Items is increased by:1,000 points for each small UFO collected while there is a summoned UFO on the screen. Otherwise, they don't increase your points.10 points for every 10 graze.Power ItemsWhenever an enemy is defeated, they may release a power item. These increase your power gauge by 0.01. Power items collected at full power will give you 100 points.UFOsSome enemies have small green UFOs circling above them. These enemies drop a small UFO after you defeat them, some stage mid-bosses will drop 2 small UFOs after you defeat them during their final attack. The small UFOs fly around the screen, changing their colour between red, blue and green. There are two versions of them, blinking and non-blinking. The blinking UFOs change colours every few seconds, while the non-blinking ones will keep their original colour. The colours of the non-blinking UFOs' are not random, so the same enemies always drop the same specific coloured small UFOs.Collecting either three same-coloured UFO items or one UFO item of each colour will cause a large UFO enemy to appear on the screen. If you collect three same-coloured UFO items, a big UFO of that colour will be summoned, while collecting one of each colour will summon a flashing big UFO. If you have picked up two UFO items of the same colour and then pick up one with a different colour, the first item in the line will be replaced by the colour of the item you just picked up. If you have two UFOs, a UFO of the color that will result in summoning a large UFO will be surrounded by a flashing pentagon, so you will know what type to collect without having to look at the bottom-left corner. Each summoned UFO has a life bar and timer that shows how much you have time to defeat it before it leaves. At about two seconds left on the timer, the UFO will start leaving the screen. If the UFO leaves before you deafeat it, all the items it has sucked in will be lost. If the UFO is on the screen at same time with a boss, it will fly away even if there is time left, and in-game dialogues will make UFOs explode.All UFOs suck in the point and power items on the screen. A circle around the UFO show the score multiplier for the UFO. The multiplier increases by 3% for every item the UFO sucks in to a maximum of 100% (34 items needed to be sucked for the maximum multiplier).The multiplier ranges for the UFOs are:0 to 1 for Red UFOs0 to 2 for Green UFOs0 to 4 for Flashing UFOs0 to 8 for Blue UFOsBlue UFOs are potentially best for scoring. When defeated, they will drop a small UFO and give you points.Red UFOs are for life parts. When its multiplier circle is full, a red UFO will drop a life part. When defeated, it drop will a small UFO, a life part, and several power items.Green UFOs are for bomb parts. When its multiplier circle is full, a Green UFO will drop a full bomb. When defeated, it will drop a small UFO and a bomb part.Flashing UFOs change the items they suck in; power items will turn into point items and point items will turn into power items. When the multiplier circle is full, the Flashing UFO drops a small blinking UFO, and when defeated, it also drops a small blinking UFO.When defeated, a UFO provides a score bonus depending on how far the score multiplier is filled, following the formula below:- (Point items in UFO * Point item value at UFO destruction * multiplier)UFOs also clears some of enemy bullets on the screen when defeated, in a bomb-like fashion. The power of the explosion is based on how full the multiplier circle is.Spell Card BonusWhenever a boss or mid-boss' Spell Card is defeated within the time lime, without dying or using bombs, the Spell Card bonus will be added to your total score. The Spell Card bonus decreases over time, so the faster you defeat the boss the more points you will get.The bonus starts at out at a value equal to:- (stage number * 2 million Difficulty level * 2 million)Difficulty level: Easy = 0, Normal = 1, Hard = 2, Lunatic = 3Clear BonusAt the end of each stage, you will be awarded with bonus points. The bonus is calculated like this:Stage- 1,000,000 (Stage 1)-2,000,000 (Stage 2)- 3,000,000 (Stage 3)MusicIn Undefined Fantastic Object, every stage has different music, while every boss has their own theme. The translated name of each theme is provided below the original version:- Title Screen Theme青空の影A Shadow in the Blue Sky- Stage 1 Theme春の湊にAt the End of the Spring- Stage 1 Boss: Nazrin's Theme小さな小さな賢将A Tiny, Tiny, Clever Commander- Stage 2 Theme閉ざせし雲の通い路The Sealed Cloud Route- Stage 2 Boss: Kogasa Tatara's Theme万年置き傘にご注意をBeware the Umbrella Left There Forever- Stage 3 themeスカイルーインSky Ruin- Stage 3 Boss - Ichirin Kumoi and Unzan's theme時代親父とハイカラ少女The Traditional Old Man and the Stylish Girl- Stage 4 Theme 幽霊客船の時空を越えた旅Interdimensional Voyage of a Ghostly Passenger Ship- Stage 4 Boss - Murasa Minamitsu's themeキャプテン・ムラサCaptain Murasa- Stage 5 Theme魔界地方都市エソテリアInterior of an Underworld Provincial City- Stage 5 Boss - Shou Toramaru's Theme虎柄の毘沙門天The Tiger-Patterned Vaisravana- Final Stage Theme法界の火Universal Fire- Final Boss - Byakuren Hijiri's theme感情の摩天楼　〜 Cosmic MindEmotional Skyscraper ~ Cosmic Mind- Extra Stage Theme夜空のユーフォーロマンスUFO Romance in the Night Sky- Extra Boss - Nue Houjuu's Theme平安のエイリアンHeian Alien- Ending Theme妖怪寺- Staff Roll Theme 空の帰り道　〜 Sky Dream</description><genres><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="24144">Deathsmiles</game><game id="216">Dodonpachi Dai-Ou-Jou</game><game id="17644">Espgaluda</game><game id="22956">Ibara</game><game id="22393">Mushihime-Sama</game><game id="32099">Akai Katana</game><game id="34712">Koumajou Densetsu 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14184/1340242-th12cover.jpg</image></root>