<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25623</id><name>Toukon Retsuden 4</name><description>OVERVIEWToukon Retsuden 4 was developed by Yukes, and is mainly focused on providing a realistic representation of professional wrestling.  Toukon Retsuden's presentation is similar to real life broadcasts, including crowd noise and extravagant introductions.  The gameplay found in Toukon Retsuden is vastly different from traditional American/Japanese wrestling games.   Gameplay Toukon Retsuden is controlled by using the D-pad.  However, the game does utilize analog control during specific lock-up situations.  The game has three main attacks: strike moves (A), power moves (B), and submission moves (Y).  Strikes beat power moves, power moves beat submissions, and submission moves beat strikes.  If both a move is performed at the same time, the higher classed attack will prevail. Players can also run by pressing the X button and appeal to the crowd (L R triggers).  As with traditional wrestling games, when an opponent takes damage, he will become groggy and dazed.  This can make performing powerful finishing moves a lot easier.  Each wrestler has three critical combos, which inflict huge amounts of damage when performed on opponents.  Game Modes Exhibition Matchsingle matchtag matchbattle royaltournamentleagueelimination matchIWGP Title Challenges Heavyweight (single/tag)Juniors (single/tag)Series MatchG1 ClimaxSG Tag leagueBest of super juniorsSuper junior atg leagueChallenge the burning spiritsSingleTagEditInternetProfilesOptionsComputer difficulty level Ring entrancesName displaymove displayvibrationHP and strength displayTag markerCamera PointSoundBackground MusicBackground music volumeSound effects volume  Venues    Tokyo A (Tokyo Dome)Tokyo BTokyo CYokohamaOsaka AOsaka BSapporo    WrestlersNew Japan(heavyweights):Riki ChoshuYuji NagataKensuke SasakiMasa Saito Shinya HashimotoTatsumi FujinamiShiro KoshinakaKengo KimuraJunji HirataOsamu KidoKazuo KidoTakashi IiuzukaManabu NakanishiTadao YasudaTatsutoshi GotoMichiyoshi OharaPower WarriorSeji SakaguchiTanakaTiger HattoriNWO Japan:Masahiro ChonoKeiji MutohGreat MutaHiro SaitoHiroyoshi TenzanSatoshi KojimaAKIRAFreelance:Genichiro TenryuDon FryeAtsushi OnitaUFO:Naoya OgawaAntonio InokiJuniors:Jyushin LygerEl SamuraiKohji KanemotoShinjiro OhtaniKendo KashinTastsuito TakaiwaDr. Wagner Jr.The great sasukeDragon KidSasuke</description><genres><genre id="10">Wrestling</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11067">Fire Pro Wrestling Returns</game><game id="14721">Super Fire Pro Wrestling  X Premium</game><game id="14202">Fire Pro Wrestling G</game><game id="18302">Fire Pro Wrestling</game><game id="7835">Fire Pro Wrestling 2</game><game id="11265">Super Fire Pro Wrestling Queen's Special</game><game id="22260">King of Colosseum II</game><game id="22813">King of Colosseum Red</game><game id="22829">King of Colosseum Green</game><game id="22477">Wrestle Kingdom</game><game id="22408">Giant Gram 2000: All Japan Pro Wrestling 3</game><game id="23212">Virtual Pro Wrestling 64</game><game id="23213">Virtual Pro Wrestling 2: Ōdō Keishō</game><game id="9816">Natsume Championship Wrestling</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8701/936475-toukon.jpg</image></root>