<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25653</id><name>Caster</name><description>Overview Heal the land for health bonuses.Caster is  third-person shooter where the player controls an inexperienced hero. This hero descends from a rare lineage of people with extraordinary abilities that interact unusually with both the terrain and the plants that sprout from it. The player is employed by an organization to eliminate an incursion of beasts known as the Flanx, bug-like monsters that dwell in water, land, and air. The game can be purchased on Steam, or the Elecorn website for $4.99. UpgradesAt first, the player is relatively weak and fragile, but as he completes missions, earned points may be spent on a variety of unlockable upgrades, both passive and active. Base Abilities      Shield - increases hit points Pickup Distance - increases the radius that  power ups are pulled toward the player Dash - increases the duration that the player may sprint Super Jump - increases the height and duration of the  double jump Projectile Abilities  Blast - lobs a ball of energy that deals heavy damage to an area and lowers the terrain Pulse - propels a small but powerful line of energy in a straight line Seeker - fires multiple, enemy-seeking arcs of energy that deal light damage Orbit - generates orbs of energy that shield the player and may be released towards a target Stun - fires an arc of energy that auto-targets and stuns enemies Eruptor - lobs a ball of energy that deals heavy damage to an area and raises the terrain  2010 Update   A new campaign. Modding capabilities.A female player character. A new soundtrack.System RequirementsOperating system: Windows XP, Vista Processor: 800 MHz or better RAM: 64 MB Graphics: 16 MB Graphics Card (GeForce 2 or better) Hard Drive: 32 MB Available Space Sound: DirectX Compatible Input: Xbox Controller supported </description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13629">Giants: Citizen Kabuto</game><game id="12696">Jet Force Gemini</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2891/939566-caster_key_art02.png</image></root>