<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25654</id><name>Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kizuna: Daiichikan Tatari</name><description>OverviewThe Kizuna series breaks up the original eight chapters of Higurashi into 4 different parts, while also adding new chapters. Tatari is the first part, it contains the following chapters, all of which are narrated by Keiichi Maebara except for the the last:Onikakushi-hen (鬼隠し編, "Spirited away by the Demon Chapter")This chapter introduces the player to the village of Hinamizawa, the main characters of Higurashi, and sets the stage on what's to come.Watanagashi-hen (綿流し編, Cotton Drifting Chapter)This chapter marks the first appearance of Shion Sonozaki and for revealing a more sensitive side to Mion Sonozaki. It manly focuses on the past of the Sonozaki Family, and the relationship between the twin sisters, Mion and Shion.Tatarigoroshi-hen (祟殺し編, Curse Killing Chapter)This chapter manly focuses on the Hojo family. It is the first chapter to reveal any details on Satoshi Hojo, Satoko's older brother who disappeared one year before Keiichi moved to Hinamizawa It is the first chapter to be told by a character other then Keiichi. It also includes the first appearance of Kyousuke Irie, the doctor who runs the local clinic as well as the local baseball team, and Teppei Hojo, Satoko's abusive uncle.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="36">Text Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25219">Another Time Another Leaf: Kagami no Naka no Tantei</game><game id="25156">Lux-Pain</game><game id="22330">Jake Hunter: Detective Chronicles</game><game id="19409">Phoenix Wright: Ace Attorney</game><game id="7894">Phoenix Wright: Ace Attorney - Trials and Tribulations</game><game id="17547">Apollo Justice: Ace Attorney</game><game id="13351">Phoenix Wright: Ace Attorney - Justice For All</game><game id="23075">Ikatan: Ikamono Tantei</game><game id="25628">Kenshuui Tendo Dokuta</game><game id="25980">Suzumiya Haruhi no Chokuretsu</game><game id="26447">Hayarigami: Toshi Densetsu Kaii Jiken</game><game id="20145">Sprung</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/112/939806-front.jpg</image></root>