<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25672</id><name>Brass Restoration</name><description>Brass Restoration is the English title of a visual novel by Japanese developer Twincle Drop, translated into English by Yandere Translations.  As of March 2009 it was released in both English and Japanese as freeware.Players take the role of Ryo, an orphan who goes to a private high school.  His parents left behind enough money for him to live in their old home comfortably, with his basic needs met.  His life is hard without his parents, but he is a successful musician who has brought fame to his school through his abilities.  He carries the drumsticks his musician father used as a symbol of his duty to his father to carry on the tradition of being an excellent musician.But one day, an accident leaves Ryo with permanent, debilitating injuries which force him to confront his promises to his father's memory.  Players guide Ryo through a series of pivotal decisions in his attempt to come to terms with the fate he has been given and attempt to continue to grow as a human being.  Ryo is by no means a mature, humble young adult, and often results to fantasy and geeky, half-serious rationalizations for events around him which include pop culture references and overreacting to his fellow students' behavior.  This contributes to the humor of the game, but also gives Ryo some room to grow as a human being (if possible).The game is a visual novel, which means that large portions of the game are text which contributes to scenes and situations, and at certain points the character is given the choice of different actions or statements, similar to dialog trees in RPGs.  Players' decisions sometimes have few consequences, but they often result in drastic changes in narrative, and the final choices dictate one of many endings for the game.The game also collects the special portraits of the different characters you meet, depending on the choices you make.  You unlock these as you progress in the game, and it's impossible to unlock them all without loading saves or progressing to decision points and choosing other than you had before.  </description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>NONE</image></root>