<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25686</id><name>Hot Dog Storm</name><description>Hot Dog Storm, plays just like any other top-down vertical scrolling shootem' up. It has you playing as a futuristic space fighter against a horde of futuristic spacecraft and others such as mechs, tanks, giant robots and massive gunships. These enemies will you attack you from every angle of the screen, as well as from below your fighter, you be unable to shoot these until they are level with you. You'll battle these foes across five stages, all with their own theme, and boss. These stages become increasingly tougher, with multiple enemies of different strengths making you pay for every pixel on the screen. At the end of each stages, and perhaps during the course of the stage you will have to take down a boss to progress. You will beat these massive enemies by destroying them piece by piece, or turret by turret. All of the bosses have multiple attacks and a super weapon. Your attacks will be impeded by lesser enemies that will try to take you down during these battles. The game never explains its unusual  title.Your fighter's weaponary ranges from what you pick up from defeated enemies. These picks up will float around on the screen, and come in different colours: Blue: Upgrages your fighters primary weaponBlue B:Adds a mega-bomb to your arsenal. Dropping one of these will destroy all incoming projectiles instantly, gaining you some breathing room, as well as vapourizes any of the weaker minions on screen.Red:Adds either a two Laser Beams that will fire from red orbs that appear either side of you ship, that when fired pass through multiple enemies causing moderate damage.Or two sets of missle pods, that both fire in a ' Y ' pattern dealing moderate-to-heavy damage.Each further red pickup upgrades your weapons more so.Green:Two Green mini ships that fire slow moving orbs that deal heavy damage on contact, useful against structures. Fires in a ' Y ' pattern, has splash damages.Upgrades make these fire faster and have a longer range against enemies.Player One's FighterPlayer Two's Fighter</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16693">Raiden</game><game id="2032">Aero Fighters</game><game id="30347">Raiden Trad</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/21096/942787-hotdog_start.png</image></root>