<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25708</id><name>SD Gundam G Generation Wars</name><description>Overview SD Gundam G Generation Wars is the newest in the long-running G Generation franchise, and carries the distinction of being the first multi-platform game in the G Gen franchise. Wars is based on the previous game,     SD Gundam G Generation Spirits, but includes series from Gundam's alternate timelines; this game marks the G Gen debut of Mobile Suit Gundam 00 and Mobile Suit Gundam C.E. 73: Stargazer. Several new features have been added, including Support Attack/Defend and Wars Break. Featured SeriesList of series featured in SD Gundam G Generation Wars. Scenario SeriesUniversal Century - One Year WarMany MS from G Generation Spirits return, including the Zeta Gundam. Mobile Suit Gundam (Master Character:     Amuro Ray 0079 version)Universal Century - Neo-Zeon WarsMobile Suit Zeta Gundam (Master Character:     Kamille Bidan)Mobile Suit Gundam ZZ (Master Character:     Judau Ashta)Mobile Suit Gundam: Char's Counterattack (Master Character:     Amuro Ray 0093 version)Universal Century - Next Century WarsMobile Suit Gundam F91 (Master Character:     Seabook Arno)Mobile Suit Victory Gundam (Master Character:     Usso Evin)Future CenturyGundam Wing is one of many alternate Gundam series to appear in G Gen Wars. Mobile Fighter G Gundam (Master Character:     Domon Kasshu)After Colony New Mobile Report Gundam Wing (Master Character:     Heero Yuy)After WarAfter War Gundam X (Master Character:     Garrod Ran)Correct CenturyTurn A Gundam (Master Character:     Loran Cehack)Cosmic Era - First Bloody Valentine WarMobile Suit Gundam SEED (Master Character:     Kira Yamato)Cosmic Era - Second Bloody Valentine WarMobile Suit Gundam SEED Destiny (Master Character:     Shinn Asuka)Anno DominiMobile Suit Gundam 00   (Season One; Master Character:     Setsuna F. Seiei)Unit-only SeriesMobile Suit Gundam: 08th MS TeamMobile Suit Gundam 0080: War in the PocketMobile Suit Gundam 0083: Stardust Memory (Master Character:   Kou Uraki)Mobile Suit VariationsMobile Suit Gundam MS IGLOO: The Hidden One Year WarMobile Suit Gundam MS IGLOO: Apocolypse 0079Mobile Suit Gundam Side Story: The Blue DestinyMobile Suit Gundam Side Story: From Place Beyond the BlazeMobile Suit Gundam: Zeonic Front Advance of Z ~The Flag of Titans~Gundam SentinelMobile Suit Gundam: Hathaway's FlashMobile Suit Gundam F90Mobile Suit Gundam Silhouette Formula F91Mobile Suit Crossbone GundamMobile Suit Crossbone Gundam: Skull HeartMobile Suit Crossbone Gundam: Steel SevenNew Mobile Report Gundam Wing: Endless WaltzMobile Suit Gundam SEED C.E. 73 StargazerMobile Suit Gundam 00 (Season 2)G-Gen OriginalsThe scenarios are divided into 3 eras: Origin Generation (Universal Century), Another Generation ('90s alternate universe, namely G, Wing, X, and Turn A) and New Generation (Shows from the last decade, in other words all SEED series and 00).New Features Wars BreakPerhaps the game's most distinctive feature, the Wars Break system causes crossover situations to occur whenever certain conditions are met on the battlefield. Currently known Wars Break situations include Gundam 0080 and 08th MS Team characters appearing in a stage for the original Mobile Suit Gundam, and Gundam 00 characters appearing in a stage based on Gundam X.Team Trinity prepares for a combination attack.Combination Attack/Support Attack/Support DefenseNot much information is given on these new features, but they are most likely identical to the similarly-named systems in the     Super Robot Wars series.ExchangeUnits from one series can be exchanged for units from other series with equivalent stats.Character AbilitiesCharacters are now given separate abilities, such as     Newtype.Master CharacterThe Master Character system once again changes the way that non-Original characters are obtained. At the start of the game, the player is asked to choose one Gundam protagonist. That character becomes the "Master Character," and all pilots from their series (or any coinciding unit-only series, such as 08th MS Team and 0080 to the original MSG) are unlocked for purchase. Eventually, you will be able to buy other Master Characters.OP PartsEach mobile suit can now use three OP Parts instead of just one. Also, one-time-use OP Parts are implemented for the first time.Other Changes"Chance Step" (the ability to move again after destroying an enemy) has been limited; unlike     G Generation Portable and Spirits, destroying an enemy will only give you a "Chance Step" the first 3 times.  The limit increases as the pilot gains levels.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22983">SD Gundam G Generation Spirits</game><game id="22508">Super Robot Wars Z</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5911/1056659-gungwii.jpg</image></root>