<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25709</id><name>Plants vs. Zombies</name><description>OverviewZombies are invading your home and the only way to stop them is by making use of your supply of undead-killing plants. You have a variety of plants at your disposal such as pea-shooters, cherry bombs, wall-nuts, and potato mines to name a few. There are different kinds of zombies with unique properties that attempt to cross the player's lawn. Earn an arsenal of 49 plants to stop the zombies from invading your home. The game features obstacles such as a setting sun, a creeping fog, and a swimming pool to make each level more challenging. This game plays similarly to a traditional tower defense game that will enhance your action-strategy skills.Plants vs. Zombies was originally released as a flash game on PopCap's website. It is also available as an installable game PC, Mac, and iOS devices. However, the versions available on iOS devices only contain Adventure mode and lack the modes available in the other versions. The iPad version of the game, named Plants vs. Zombies HD features higher resolution graphics over the iPhone and iPod Touch version. The game was released on XBLA on September 8th, 2010. The Xbox 360 version has been available bundled in a retail disk with Zuma and Peggle since September 28th, 2010.GameplayLevel 1-4Plants vs Zombies is a tower defense game. The player saves up resources (solar energy) to buy and place plants on a 5x9 grid that represents their lawn. Zombies slowly move from the right of the screen to the player's house on the left. Unlike most tower defense games, the zombies generally move in a straight path along the grid. Over the course of the game, the player earns and buys additional plants. The player is only allowed to use a certain number of plants in a level. At the beginning of every level, the player must choose which plants to use. There are a variety of unique plants to choose from, ranging between multiple types of offensive and defensive plants.The goal of the game is to prevent the zombies from reaching your home and eating your brains. Each level has a column of lawnmowers, pool cleaners, or roof cleaners that serve as a final line of defense. If a zombie manages to get through every obstacle in its way then one of the defenses is triggered and all enemies in that row are automatically destroyed. Their is only one defensive machine in each row and each one can only be used once per level. Lawnmowers are automatically given to the player, but pool and roof cleaners must be purchased from Crazy Dave's Twiddydinkies, which serves as the game's shop. If a single zombie manages to make it past the final line of defense the player loses.Players are awarded coins or diamonds at the end of the level, with bonus coins awarded for remaining final defenses. Zombies sometimes also drop coins. Coins can be used to buy new plants and other items from the player's neighbor, Crazy Dave.Every ten levels, the game changes from day to night (and so on), requiring different strategies and plants that normally only work at night. Some night stages also feature a blanket of fog that hides a portion of the playing grid from the player. After 20 levels, the zombies make an attempt on the player's backyard, where they have a pool that spans the length of the level, requiring completely different plants to defend. The final set of levels has the player fighting zombies on the roof of their house where the player needs to buy flower pots to be able to use any plant.Some levels in the game's Adventure Mode don't use solar energy or let the player choose which plants to bring into the level. These levels instead have a scrolling bar at the top of the screen where different plants appear in the form of a card. The player then simply takes the card and plants it whenever he or she chooses, without having to use the economic portion of the game. However, the unpredictability of the scrolling bar tends to make these levels more hectic than usual.Other modes and levels change the game mechanics entirely, presenting the player with bowling levels, variations on PopCap favorites such as Bejeweled and Insaniquarium, or allowing the player to control the zombies in order to defeat the plants.PlantsEconomy PlantsEconomic Plants are the plants that add to the player's resource-collection rate. These plants spawn solar-points which are then used to create more plants. The most basic of these are the Happy Sunflowers, which spawn solar-points during daytime. Its mushroom counterpart, which is the Sun-shroom, sleeps during the day but produces solar-points at night. Instead of giving you solar-points, the Marigold flower gives you silver and gold coins.PlantDescriptionSun CostSunflowerThe Sunflower is essential for the player as it produces extra sun. It costs 50 solar-points and it produces one normal-sized piece of sun (worth 25 solar-points) every 24.3 seconds.50Sun-shroomThis analog to the Sunflower is less expensive, but starts out small, producing only 15 sun units until they grow to full size and produce 25. Like all mushrooms, sun-shrooms sleep during daytime levels.25MarigoldMarigolds periodically drop silver and gold coins. These plants are similar to the Sunflower, but they produce money instead of sun. Every 24 seconds, the Marigold drops a silver ($10) or gold coin ($50) which can then be used for purchases from Crazy Dave.50Offensive PlantsOffensive Plants attack the incoming waves of zombies. There are a large number of different offensive plants and only a few are listed below. In order to properly hold off the undead horde, one must use different offensive strategies depending on the situation.PlantDescriptionSun CostPeashooterThe Peashooter is basic line of defense. They shoot peas at attacking zombies. Peashooters are able to decapitate normal zombies in ten shots.100Cherry BombA one-time use weapon that will blast the zombies on whatever square it's planted on as well as adjacent squares. It has a very quick charge, but it causes no damage if eaten before it explodes.150Snow PeaA close relative to the Peashooter, this plant fires ice peas that freeze whatever zombie it hits, greatly slowing their forward progress. They do the same damage as a Peashooter and have the same firing rate, though they cost 175 sun.175ChomperChompers devour normal-sized zombies in one bite, but take plenty of time to chew their food at which point they are completely defenseless. They can attack one square ahead of them, so they do best planted behind another unit.150RepeaterAnother close relative of the Peashooter, but this one shoots two peas at once.200ThreepeaterThreepeaters shoot peas across three different lanes.325Split-PeasSplit Peas shoot peas forward and backwards, useful against digger zombies.125Puff-shroomThis is the weakest mushroom, being the first plant the player comes across with limited range (3 squares). On the other hand, the Puff-shroom is free to plant, making it useful during the night when sun is scarce.0Fume-shroomFires a burst of spores that passes through screen doors that zombies carry for defense. Their attacks act as area-of-effect, since all within range are hit by the spores.75Scaredy-ShroomScaredy-shrooms are long-range shooters that hide when enemies get near them.25Ice-shroomTemporarily freezes all zombies on the screen. The ice-shroom disappears after applying the freezing effect. Some special zombies are either unaffected or merely slowed by this attack.75Doom-shroomThe Doom-shroom is the most powerful of all exploding plants. It destroys all zombies in a large area and leaves a crater. The crater cannot be planted on but disappears in three minutes.125JalapeñoJalapeño deals heavy damage to an entire lane of zombies.125TorchwoodTorchwoods turn peas that pass through them into fireballs that deal twice as much damage. (Snow Peas that pass through Torchwood melt into regular peas.)175Sea-ShroomSea-shrooms are aquatic plants that shoot short ranged spores. The pool-based equivalent of a puff-shroom, they can be planted without use of a lily-pad.0StarfruitStarfruits shoot stars in 5 directions.125Cabbage-PultCabbage-pults hurl cabbages at the enemy, useful on roof levels where the angle makes using peashooters much less useful.100Kernel-PultThe Kernel-pult is an offensive lobbed-shot plant for the roof levels. It launches either light-damage kernels or normal-damage butter which temporarily stall zombies.100Melon-PultThe Melon-pult lobs watermelons at incoming zombies. The watermelons smash on impact, causing further damage to other nearby zombies.300Defensive PlantsDefensive plants act as supporting-plants, where they hold off or divert the attacking swarm long enough for the offensive plants to cause heavy damage. They are best used in conjunction with other plants to ensure home safety.PlantDescriptionSun CostWall-NutThese are useful when placed in front of other plants the player wants to protect.. The Wall-nut takes a great deal of damage before getting destroyed, allowing the player to damage tougher zombies without risking critical attack pieces. Advanced zombies are able to jump or fly over the Wall-nut.50Potato MineThis inexpensive fellow takes awhile to activate after being planted, but once he does, he'll blow up any zombie that steps on him, dealing instant death to all but the strongest units.25Hypno-shroomWhen eaten, it causes the eating zombie to turn around and fight for the player. Can only be consumed once and they cost 75 sun to plant.75Tall-NutTall-nuts are heavy-duty wall plants that can't be vaulted over. Ladder zombies are still able to climb over them and other advanced zombies can squish them. They can take 144 bites before being destroyed and they cost 125 sun.125SquashSquashes will smash the first zombie that gets close to it. They deal area-of-effect damage to all zombies that happen to be there when triggered.50PumpkinPumpkins do not take up a grid-space of their own, but are planted on other plants. They shelter that plant for the same number of bites as a wall-nut, though a number of zombie types can still vault over them.125Tangle KelpTangle Kelp are aquatic plants that pull the first zombie that nears them underwater.25BloverBlovers immediately blow away all balloon zombies on the field and also temporarily removes all fog from the map.100Grave BusterSingle-use plants that consumes a grave. During night-time levels, graves obstruct planting and serve as spawn points for zombies. It takes around five seconds for the Grave Buster to destroy the grave and the plant can still be consumed by zombies while working.75GarlicGarlic diverts zombies into other lanes.50Umbrella LeafUmbrella Leaves protect plants in a 3x3 square radius from bungees and catapults.100Magnet-shroomMagnet-shrooms remove metal objects from zombies within a circular radius. This serves a variety of purposes; helmets can be removed to lower defense, ladders can be eliminated as a threat, jack-in-the-box explosives can be neutralized, etc.100SpikeweedSpikeweeds cannot be eaten and hurt zombies walking on them. They also pop tires that attempt to drive over them, but then the spikeweed is destroyed in the process.100Utility PlantsThese plants don't fit well within the offensive or defensive categories, but are nevertheless essential for surviving the zombie apocalypse.PlantDescriptionSun CostLily PadLily pads let the player plant non-aquatic plants on top of them. This is used for levels in the backyard, where the player has a pool covering the majority of grid-squares.25Coffee BeanA mushroom pant is usually asleep during daytime levels, but each can be woken up by planting a coffee bean on it. Though mushrooms are cheap, Coffee Beans cost 75 sun, so the player must ensure that using the mushroom is economically efficient.75PlanternPlanterns light up an area, letting the player see through fog on levels in which it hides the identities of incoming zombies.25Flower PotFlower Pots let the player plant on the roof by placing other plants on them.25ImitaterImitaters let you use two of the same plant during a level, which means you do not have to wait for the plant to recharge. The Imitater can not imitate the so-called "Upgrade Plants", but only the regular plants that you do not have to buy from Crazy Dave. When you want to purchase a plant (using solar-points) using the Imitater, you will have to wait for about 2 seconds before the Imitator turns into that plant. The plants you bought using the Imitator will have a lighter shade (unless they got upgraded). You can purchase this item for $30,000 in Crazy Dave's shop.The Imitater is the only buyable plant that does not get more expensive after every purchase during the "endless survival mode".DependsUpgrade PlantsUnlike the other plants in the game, upgrade plants are purchased from Crazy Dave's Shop instead of being earned through the adventure mode. They are displayed on purple cards and regenerate slower than the other cards. They are each planted on and thus enhance a specific other plant type,PlantDescriptionSun CostGatling PeaUpgrades the Repeater.Gatling Peas fire four peas per reload cycle (as opposed to the two of the repeater). You can purchase this upgrade for $5,000 in Crazy Dave's shop.250Twin SunflowerUpgrades the Sunflower.The Twin Sunflower produces 50 sun each cycle instead of 25 sun per cycle. It is more expensive and requires more time between plantings than the normal sunflower, but allows double the space economy. You can purchase this upgrade for $5,000 in Crazy Dave's shop.150Gloom-ShroomUpgrades the Fume-Shroom.Gloom-shroom emits puffs of fumes in all directions when a zombie is nearby. You can purchase this upgrade for $7,500 in Crazy Dave's shop.150CattailUpgrades the lily-pad.The Cattail is a versatile attacker that targets the closest zombie. It can also shoot down air targets in any lane. You can purchase this upgrade for $10,000 from Crazy Dave's shop.225Winter MelonUpgrades the Melon-Pult.The Winter Melon deals an area attack that affects multiple rows of zombies and slows their movement. You can purchase this upgrade for $10,000 in Crazy Dave's shop.200Gold MagnetUpgrades the Magnet-Shroom.Gold Magnet attracts coins that get dropped in the level. You can purchase this upgrade for $3,000 in Crazy Dave's shop.50SpikerockUpgrades Spikeweeds.Spikerock upgrade Spikeweeds to inflict higher damage and become more durable. You can purchase this upgrade for $7,500 in Crazy Dave's shop.125Cob CannonUpgrades two Kernel-pults.The most devastating plant in the game. It destroys zombies in an area, then takes time to recharge. Because this plant uses two spots instead of one, it is not very space-economic and it cannot be protected by a Pumpkin. You can purchase this upgrade for $20,000 in Crazy Dave's shop.500ZombiesZombies are the evil menace whose sole task is to invade your home and eat your brains. Naturally, you want to keep your brain for your own use. However, zombies have devised cruel and foul ways to try fighting through your plant-ary (pun for planetary) defenses. A number of different zombie types are listed below. Which plants will you use to hold off the horde?ZombieDescriptionCommon-variety ZombieRegular Garden-variety ZombieFlag ZombieFlag Zombies marks the arrival of a huge pile or "wave" of zombies.Conehead ZombieHis traffic cone headpiece makes him twice as tough as normal zombies.Pole Vaulting ZombiePole Vaulting Zombie vaults with a pole.Buckethead ZombieHis bucket hat allows him to take five times as much damage as a normal zombie.Newspaper ZombieHis newspaper provides limited defense.Screen Door ZombieHis screen door is an effective shield.Football ZombieFootball Zombie makes the big plays.Dancing ZombieOriginally, this zombie resembled Michael Jackson in his Thriller music video, but was later patched to look like a disco dancer. Any resemblance between Dancing Zombie and person living or dead is purely coincidental.Backup Dancer ZombieThese zombies appear in sets of four whenever Dancing Zombie rocks out.Ducky Tube ZombieThe ducky tube allows this zombie to float on water.Snorkel ZombieSnorkel zombies can swim underwater.Balloon ZombieBalloon Zombies floats above the fray, immune to most attacks.ZomboniThe Zomboni applies ice, steam and pressure to your plants.Bobsled Zombie TeamThese zombies appear in sets of four.Bungee ZombieBungee Zombie attacks from above, descending from the sky to steal a plant or to drop a fellow zombie.Catapult ZombieCatapult Zombie operates heavy machinery and lobs basketballs at your plants.Digger ZombieThis Zombie digs tunnels underground to bypass your defenses and appears on the left side of the lawn.Dolphin Rider ZombieDolphin Rider Zombies use dolphins to exploit weaknesses in your pool defense by jumping over the first plant he runs into.GargantuarGargantuar is a gigantic zombie with a highly destructive appetite. He also throws imps off of his back.ImpImps are tiny zombies thrown off of the back of a Gargantuar into the middle of your plants.Jack In the Box ZombieThis zombie carries an explosive surprise.Ladder ZombieLadder Zombie climbs over obstacles.Pogo ZombiePogo Zombie hops to bypass your defenses.Dr. ZombossDr. Zomboss rules over all of the Zombies.Zombie YetiZombie Yeti is a rare and curious creature that runs away after a short while.You can only encounter this zombie when playing the adventure mode a second time.Trash Can ZombieThe Trash Can Zombie was added in the Xbox Live Arcade version of Plants Vs. Zombies. Trash Can Zombies use the trash cans for a shield so they will take more damage than a normal zombie. Trash Can Zombies can be found in the hard survival levels and well as Survival: Endless. The Trash Can Zombie is also a selectable unit in Vs. mode.Target ZombieThe Target Zombies only appear in the Vs. Mode. In Vs. Mode the plants player must destroy three of the Target Zombies in order to win.AlmanacThe almanac is an in-game guide that keeps track of the plants and zombies the player encounters, providing both gameplay information and humorous biographies. It can be accessed from the main menu, from the pause menu, and from the plant selection screen preceding each level.Mini-GamesA number of mini-games are unlocked over the course of the Adventure Mode. These include a bowling variant in which the player rolls defensive structures at zombies instead of building plants, and a more challenging variant of the main game where the zombie characters have a lot of the offensive capabilities that the player possesses, such as projectile attacks.The complete list of mini-games is:Beghouled TwistZombotany 1  2Wall-nut bowling 1  2Slot MachineIt's raining Seeds!BeghouledInvisi-ghoulSeeing StarsZomiquariumBeghouled TwistBig Trouble, Little ZombiePortal CombatColumn Like You See ThemBobsled BonanzaZombie Nimble, Zombie QuickWhack a ZombieLast StandPogo PartyDr Zomboss's RevengeHeavy Weapon (Xbox Live Arcade)Puzzle ModePuzzle Mode is unlocked after the completion of the Adventure Mode. Puzzle Mode include two different types of puzzles. The first requires the player to break open vases which can either include zombies or plants. The player must successfully break all of the vases and kill all of the zombies. There are 9 different finite levels and one endless. The second mode requires the player to play the role of the zombie and assault cardboard cutout plants. The objective is to break through the defenses and consume 5 brains on the other side of the plants. This also includes 9 different finite levels and one endless.Survival ModeSurvival mode sets the player up against multiple waves of zombies. The first five levels include each venue (Day, Night, Pool, Fog, Roof) and send five waves of zombies. The second set of five levels include the same five venues and ten waves of zombies. The final level provides an endless wave of zombies.StoreCrazy Dave's Twiddydinkies.The player can use coins collected during normal gameplay to purchase items. During the game's second chapter, a character named Crazy Dave will open his shop: Crazy Dave's Twiddydinkies. This allows the player to purchase extra items to make the game's demands a little easier on them. The most expensive items in the store are generally the extra seed slots, which allow the player to bring more types of seeds (and therefore have a bigger variety of plants) in a given level.Other upgrades include upgraded versions of items that must be planted over existing plants; for example, planting an upgrade onto Repeater plants will cause them to fire four shots at a time instead of two. The cheapest upgrades in the store are generally temporary; for $200, a rake can be purchased for the next three levels that will appear randomly on the map and kill the first zombie to step on it.Zen-GardenStarts with two Marigold flowers that need to be tended. Additional plants are collected by playing mini-game, puzzle, and survival modes. All plants require regular watering and fertilizer to grow. These activities reward the player with small amounts of money and a larger amount if the plant reaches its full size. Once full-grown plants also require bug-spray and music to remain happy for a day. Doing so nets the player a fairly large reward. Apart from the standard Zen-Garden a mushroom garden, aquarium, and the tree of wisdom are also provided. The mushroom garden allows mushroom plant types to grow further and the aquarium does the same for aquatic plants. The tree of life grows as tree-food is placed upon it, handing out advice for every growth spurt.VersionsXbox 360 VersionThe Xbox Live Arcade version was released on Sept 8, 2010 for 1,200 Microsoft Points. It features 50 levels alongside 21 mini-games and 7 different game modes. The retail version was made available on Sept 28, 2010 for $19.99 and includes two other games by PopCap: Zuma and Peggle.iPhone VersionNow Available on iPhones EverywhereThe iPhone version was released on the 15th of February 2010. Whilst the game is ultimately the same game with touchscreen controls, upon release it had several missing features such as the Zen garden, various mini games, and survival mode which would be unlocked upon completion. A summer/fall 2011 update has added in most of the missing modes, but requires in-game or micro-transaction currency to unlock mini games.Game of the Year EditionOn August 10th 2010 a game of the year edition of Plants Vs. Zombies was made available on Steam and as an automatic update to users of the regular edition. It added 20 new Steam achievements, support for Mac users, Steam Cloud support and a interactive zombatar tool which allows users to create their own zombies.Google Chrome EditionOn May 19, 2010 Google announced at their I/O conference that they would be launching an app store for their web browser, Chrome. A flash version of Plants vs. Zombies was confirmed to be among the launch titles priced at $3.99 according to preview screenshots. The store is expected to be open by the end of October 2010.Windows Phone 7 VersionOn May 18th, 2011 a version of Plants Vs. Zombies was released for the Windows Phone 7 platform. This version of Plants Vs. Zombies is essentially the original game with the inclusion of Xbox Live features such as leaderboards and achievements.PlayStation 3 VersionOn February 8th, 2011 the game was released on the PlayStation Network. This version is the same as the original game, including leaderboards and 12 trophies.Nintendo DS VersionOn January 18th, 2011 Plants Vs. Zombies was released on the DS. This version also includes the multi-player modes from the Xbox Live version and allows the player to play against another friend with a cartridge or to send a basic skirmish via Download Play. The game was also released on DSIWare on March 14th, 2011.SoundtrackSoundtrackThe game's soundtrack was composed by Laura Shigihara.Track NumberSong TitleLength1.Crazy Dave's Greeting00:082.Crazy Dave (Intro Theme)01:273.Choose Your Seeds00:184.Grasswalk02:285.Loonboon01:476.Moongrains02:257.Zen Garden01:008.Watery Graves (Slow)02:019.Watery Graves (Fast)01:5610.Ultimate Battle01:5511.Rigor Mormist01:5212.Cerebrawl01:5713.Graze the Roof03:0314.Brainiac Maniac01:4215.Zombies On Your Lawn02:3916.Zombotany (Unreleased Track)01:1717.Uraniwa ni Zombies ga!02:3918.Crazy Dave IN-GAME01:4519.Choose Your Seeds IN-GAME00:3120.Grasswalk IN-GAME05:0021.Loonboon IN-GAME02:0422.Moongrains IN-GAME03:1323.Zen Garden IN-GAME01:0924.Watery Graves IN-GAME03:4125.Ultimate Battle IN-GAME02:0926.Rigor Mormist IN-GAME03:5927.Cerebrawl IN-GAME01:5528.Graze the Roof IN-GAME03:4829.Brainiac Maniac IN-GAME01:59PC System RequirementsOperating System: Windows 2000 / XP / Vista / Mac OSXProcessor: 1.2GhzRAM Memory: 512 MBGraphics Card: 128MB of video memory, 16-bit or 32-bit colour qualityDirectX: 8 or higherHard Drive: 65 MB of free HD spaceSound: DirectX compatible sound</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22139">Desktop Tower Defense</game><game id="22801">Ninjatown</game><game id="12764">PixelJunk Monsters</game><game id="21064">Lock's Quest</game><game id="25000">Crystal Defenders</game><game id="23311">Defense Grid: The Awakening</game><game id="29428">PixelJunk Monsters Deluxe</game><game id="23102">South Park Let's Go Tower Defense Play!</game><game id="16164">Immortal Defense</game><game id="33408">Revenge of the Titans</game><game id="32495">Robo Defense</game><game id="34392">Castle Fall: Age of the Magogs</game><game id="34906">Valet Parking 1989</game><game id="35676">Two Worlds II Castle Defense</game><game id="35878">Army of Darkness Defense</game><game id="35869">Defender Chronicles: Legend of the Desert King</game><game id="36865">Zombie Misfits</game><game id="38214">Eden to GREEEEN</game><game id="41494">Garfield’s Defense: Attack of the Food Invaders</game><game id="21562">Zoombies - Animales de la Muerte</game><game id="43699">March on Oz</game><game id="44064">Zombie Zombie Zombie</game><game id="39738">Beware Planet Earth</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1514401-pvz_box.png</image></root>