<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25725</id><name>Saints Row: The Third</name><description>OverviewNo one man should have all this power.Saints Row: The Third is an over-the-top open-world action-adventure game developed by Volition and published by THQ for the Xbox 360, PlayStation 3, and PC on November 15, 2011. The third game in the Saints Row franchise, players take the leader of the 3rd Street Saints (which turned from a Stilwater street gang to an international multi-media empire) into a war against a legendary criminal organization (known as The Syndicate) in their turf: the city of Steelport. Things quickly go incredibly over-the-top, as players eventually must fight a futuristic military organization (known as the S.T.A.G., or Special Tactics Anti-Gang), hack into the online world of one of the Syndicate's leaders (a la Tron), and quell a zombie infestation (with help from the city's mayor, Burt Reynolds). Strap it on.Gangs and OrganizationsAs in the previous games, Saints Row: The Third features three rival gangs that the Saints must defeat in order to claim the city as their own. These gangs make up a powerful international criminal organization known as The Syndicate:Morning Star (Red)Led by the influential Phillipe Loren (who is also the leader of the entire Syndicate), these suit-wearing chain-smoking criminals focus on organized means of crime, especially human trafficking and prostitution. Loren's day-to-day affairs are manged by his two personal assistants, Kiki DeWynter and Viola DeWynter (both of which have important roles as the story progresses). Members of the Morning Star tend to drive four-door sedans (such as the Justice and the Infuego); though when they have to hunt down Saints, they make use of sniper assassins in Oppressor helicopters.The oldest pimp (with an autotuned voice box and well-known connections in the city's criminal underworld) in Steelport, Zimos, was an ally of the DeWynters before becoming imprisoned in their human trafficking ring. After being rescued by the Saints, he will join forces with the Saints and will assist them throughout the campaign. From the Morning Star, they will also rescue Oleg Kirrlov, a superhuman brute (with both incredible strength and superior intellect) who serves as the host to the clone of "Brutes" found throughout the campaign.Deckers (Blue)Led by the socially challenged cyber-criminal Matt Miller, the Deckers is a gang consisting of young British cyberpunk-inspired punks. They specialize in cybercrime and money laundering. While they are the most technologically sophisticated gang, they make arguably the poorest choice of vehicle usage, with their main staples being the Solar hybrid car, the Kayak SUV, and the Criminal. When hunting down Saints, they make use of rollerblading teenage girls that can travel at supersonic speeds and wield both submachine guns and a powerful shock hammer.A former intelligence agent for the FBI, Kinzie Kensington, crossed paths with the Deckers before (causing them to frame her for espionage). After being rescued by the Saints after being captured by the Deckers, she will join forces with the Saints and will assist them throughout the campaign.Luchadores (Green)Led by the hotheaded once-prominent wrestling star Killbane, the Luchadores is a gang consisting of violent, muscular men (wearing lucha libre masks). They specialize in drug dealing and organized gambling. When hunting down Saints, their specialist is a mighty luchador punk with a rapid-fire grenade launcher.The gang was once led by both Killbane and his former tag-team partner, Angel de la Muerte, before infighting led Killbane to unmask him (considered the greatest form of disrespect in lucha libre). Hungry for revenge, he will join forces with the Saints and will assist them throughout the campaign.Like Saints Row 2, the game features a powerful and futuristic police force/military organization that makes its appearance late in the game:Special Tactical Anti-Gang (S.T.A.G.)Led by Cyrus Temple, the STAG group were formed by the government after being proposed by Senator and former Stilwater mayor Monica Hughes to combat gang violence in Steelport. They are enemies to all gangs in the city, and used advanced weapons and vehicles such as the F-69 VTOL jet and the experimental Specter hover bike. Their weapons consist mainly of futuristic laser-based designs, and some of their vehicle designs share a resemblance to the designs used for Red Faction Guerrilla.Activities and RespectRespect is no longer used to unlock story missions like in the previous two games. Respect now acts as experience which you use to level up your character, unlocking upgrades and abilities for purchase. Activities now play a more prominent role in the game's world; completing them will have more effect on the war against Syndicate as a whole, rather than just supplying the player with more cash and respect.Insurance FraudThe fan-favorite from the preceding games makes yet another return. Given an unlimited amount of health, the player must literally throw himself in harms way in order to rack up as much fraudulent insurance money as possible. The Adrenaline meter also returns, allowing a player to throw themselves over extremely large distances and into bigger hazards to maximize their scoring potential.TraffickingTrafficking handles identically to the Drug Trafficking missions in the earlier games, with the protagonist riding alongside an AI controlled dealer, who is attempting to sell illegal goods while the police and gang presence escalates in their pursuit. Players will be given weapons and ammunition for these side missions, and depending on the difficulty, the quality of the items received will also increase accordingly.Heli AssaultFly around in an attack helicopter with heat-seeking missiles and protect your crew members down below. Alternate version has you protecting Kinzie instead of Pierce and you are given more control over the helicopter.EscortDrive a car with a prostitute who is entertaining a client in the back seat, while avoiding unwanted attention from news crews. Also includes a variation where the player must drive with a live tiger in the vehicle while attempting to not enrage the animal.SnatchTake out pimps and steal their prostitutes. Alternate version has you picking up captured FBI informants from gang members.Trail BlazingRide around on a flaming ATV and cause as much damage as you can in the allotted time. There's also a variant called "Cyber Blazing" where the player jumps into cyberspace and help Kinzie hack rival gangs' systems by racing through them in a Tron style lightcycle.Guardian AngelProtect a target from afar using weapons such as rocket launchers from a helicopter and a sniper rifle from a roof while they complete their objectives. When playing in co-op, both players will be protecting the AI, rather than one character manning the aircraft, as happened in Saints Row 2's Helicopter Assault side missions.Professor Genki's Super Ethical Reality ClimaxA super popular Japanese-style game show that pits contestants against other psychopath mascots in bizarre challenges. Complete with flame/electrical traps and bonuses obtained by shooting certain signs.MayhemUsing an array of explosive weapons at your disposal, rack up the most amount of dollars in damage to your surroundings as possible. Ammo is unlimited for certain weapons, and there are typically areas with more cars spawning to make causing havoc easier. Gangs and police are also eligible as targets for destruction.Tank MayhemMuch like the Mayhem activity, only this time you have a near indestructible tank at your disposal. Tanks in the game are extremely resistant to damage and with the limited time in Tank Mayhem, destroying a tank is nigh-on impossible. Tank Mayhem is one of the easiest side activities, since it normally has certain areas designated with huge numbers of enemies and vehicles, to boost your combo and kills.AssassinationFind and kill a list of assassination targets. There are thirty-six targets and each target has different criteria before they will spawn and can be killed. For example, one target requires you to park at a gas station in a muscle car. When they spawn you may kill them in any manner desired, as was the case for Saints Row 2, though not in the original, where you had to kill targets in a specific manner.Vehicle TheftSteal and deliver a list of desired cars. These cars can be found in certain areas of the city, though if you have one in your garage you can drive it into the area and then to the chop shop, barring a few exceptions. Some of the cars needed are specific and will spawn in fixed locations, allowing you to repeatedly attempt to find the car if it has been destroyed during a previous attempt."Whored" ModeWhored Mode is the games own take on Gears of War's Horde Mode survival-style gameplay. In Whored Mode the player has to survive as long as they can fighting multiple waves of enemies. Each wave has you fighting certain types of enemies with certain weapons and/or conditions. For example, waves can have you fighting against prostitutes with the Penetrator dildo bat, or against brutes in a tank.Genkibowl VIIGenkibowl is the first piece of DLC for Saints Row: The Third, released on January 17th, 2012. The DLC comes with 4 new Professor Genki challenges as well as new costumes, homies and vehicles.GenkibowlProfessor Genki is hosting the 7th annual Genkibowl, a violent sport competition where the contestant must murder mascots. Apocalypse Genki is similar to the core activity "Super Ethical Reality Climax", with the same power ups and objective (score enough money to open up the exit), except that the event happens in a jungle setting with shark infested waters.The second challenge is Super Ethical PR Opportunity, where the contestant must drive Professor Genki to an event while avoiding rabid fans and running over civilians in order to please Genki. Running over a large number of civilians triggers the vehicle's flamethrowers which fire both towards the front as well as on the sides. This car is known as the Genkimobile, and is a modified Danville from Saints Row 2.Sexy Kitten Yarngasm lets the player control a huge ball of yarn, crushing cars and keeping the combo going by creating as much destruction as possible. This mode handles similarly to Tank Mayhem, though Yarnie (the vehicle used) is able to travel in any direction and make faster turns, though at the cost of not having a main gun. Yarnie is, like tanks during Tank Mayhem, extremely difficult to destroy in the allotted time. Yarnie can be destroyed outside the mode, though, where it appears as a Homie and can be called to your location. Yarnie cannot be selected via the Garage or Helipad.Finally, Sad Panda Skyblazing has the contestant dress up as a sad panda who has special sky diving abilities (he can basically fly). In order to gain altitude, the player must hit (ethical and unethical) balloons and scores money by going through rings and killing mascots on rooftops with a chainsaw.The DLC ends with the contestant winning Genkibowl and giving an inspiring speech on TV to the kids at home. Completing the DLC lets the player call in the giant ball of yarn as a homie.Gangstas In SpaceThe second piece of DLC for the game came out on February 21st 2012. Unlike the Genkibowl VII DLC this came as a set of missions put together as a story. On completion a V-TOL style space-ship, a new alien hoverbike, two homies and a mind control helmet are unlocked.The DLC is based around the recording of a film named "Gangstas in Space". Throughout it the Protagonist is instructed to act out questionably violent scenes with his/her co-star Jenny Jaros involving the deaths of many actors. The director, Andy Zhen, is constantly rude to Jenny eventually leading to her crashing a space ship into him. Three new alien weapons were introduced but they are only available during the missions and cannot be accessed anywhere else.The Trouble With ClonesThe Trouble With Clones, like Gangstas In Space, is a story-based DLC for the game. It was released on March 30th 2012. It comes with a new vehicle and two new homies.It starts with Jimmy Torbitson, a nerdy fan of the Saints who wishes to clone Johnny Gat. When he does the clone is massively strong and promptly escaped, confused and stupid. The Protagonist and Pierce help Jimmy to find him and bring him back. They try disguising Pierce as Aisha and he sings awfully to bring Johnny Tag out and use another muscled clone of Aisha in an attempt to calm him down but the Aisha clone is killed. When the Protagonist is knocked out, he/she is given a special Saints Flow drink engineered by Jimmy to give him/her super powers. After a long fight with the army, Johnny Tag joins the Saints.The super powers provided by the Saints Flow only last for the some of the last mission and cannot be used in normal gameplay, the same goes for the bee gun used while Pierce pretends to be Aisha.WeaponsAs always, the character will have an enormous arsenal of weaponry at his fingertips, ranging from pistols and shotguns to satchel charges. Weapon customization is handled similar to how vehicles were handled in past games. Each weapon can be upgraded three times, affording new abilities such as a better zoom level, or more damage. They are permanently saved to a cache in your crib, much like your garage. Melee with most weapons results in a nutshot melee animation.MeleeStrap it onThe Penetrator: A giant purple dildo with flopping physics. The Penetrator was one of the first weapons shown in promotional material for the game, and was also known as the 'Dildo Bat' before clarification.Apoca-Fist: Boxing gloves that obliterate victims. They are one of the options available during the Murder Brawl XXVI mission, depending on how the player chooses to handle Killbane. The Apoca-Fist is an instant kill melee weapon resembling a set of boxing gloves.ChainsawBaseball Bat: A regular baseball bat which can be upgraded with nails for extra damage.Nocturne: A large sword, unlocked by defeating the Deckers gang. Nocturne handles similar to the Penetrator, giving roughly equal power in the form of a sword.Stun Gun: A regular stun gun. When an enemy is hit with a blast from the weapon their body will ragdoll and they will be temporarily incapacitated. This can also be used against other players in co-operative play.Pistols.45 Shepherd: The first pistol encountered in the game, the .45 Shepherd is large and powerful, getting even larger and more powerful as it is upgraded. The design seems to blend the Colt M1911 design with the infamous Desert Eagle pistol. It boasts explosive rounds when fully upgraded, giving each shot a small splash damage effect.KA-1 Kobra: Standard pistol used by police, with average initial performance. When fully upgraded the Kobra boasts a silencer and armor-piercing rounds, which can make it very useful.SMGsTEK Z-10: The first SMG encountered in the game, with a name similar to the stereotypical Tec-9. The Z-10 is initially weak though becomes very valuable when upgraded, receiving incendiary rounds.D4TH Blossom: The other main SMG of the game, used by law enforcement. It resembles the TDI Vector, and has a very high rate of fire along with armor piercing rounds when upgraded.Cyber Blaster: An SMG unlocked by defeating the Deckers, with a similar Tron-inspired design as their cars. Physically it looks similar to the D4TH Blossom, though it fires lasers with a pulse noise instead, requiring a cooldown instead of a reload.ShotgunsGrave Digger: A shotgun with a slow fire rate, resembling the Winchester Model 1887. When upgraded it receives additional barrels. When it is at Level 4 the Grave Digger boasts three barrels and incendiary shells, which can make it excellent for destroying vehicles, though it has a slower firing rate than the AS3.AS3 Ultimax: The main shotgun of law enforcement authorities in Steelport, the Ultimax is pump action initially. When upgraded it becomes automatic and similar in scope to the real-world USAS-12. The AS3 Ultimax edges the Grave Digger out in many regards due to its higher rate of fire.S3X Hammer: Futuristic shotgun design used by the STAG, firing laser pulses as opposed to conventional rounds. It does not need reloaded though can overheat if fired too rapidly.RiflesK8 Krukov: The basic assault rifle of the game. When upgraded it receives a grenade launcher, firing grenades in your inventory, and an LMG-styled box magazine. Due to this it can be a potent weapon for destroying cars and aircraft, since grenades fired from it explode on impact rather than on a timer.AR-55: A more powerful assault rifle, limited to firing in bursts of three rounds initially, though upgraded to bursts of five when fully upgraded. The AR-55 also receives a long-range scope.Viper Laser Rifle: A long range laser rifle used by STAG troops.ExplosivesAnnihilator RPG: An RPG-7 which can be upgraded with heat-seeking rockets.Satchel Charges: Placeable explosive device, that can be chosen during the "My Name is Cyrus Temple" mission.Mollusk Launcher (Professor Genki DLC pack): A mind-control launcher firing live octopi which can be manually detonated. When a target is hit they go insane, beginning to dance and perform other erratic actions.SpecialMcManus 2015: A long range, high-powered sniper rifleReaper Drone: A predator missile strike deployed through an overhead view of the battleSA-3 Airstrike: A precision jet airstrike designated by laser targetingRC Possessor: A device that overrides a vehicle's driver and allows the vehicle to be driven via remote control.Sonic Boom: A chargeable weapon that creates a large sonic force that obliterates anything too close.Cyber Buster: A Mega Man-style blaster fitted to the player's arm. Shoots unlimited explosive blasts.Radio StationsThere are eight radio stations in the game. Through the in-game phone, the player can also create a Mixtape as a ninth station and add any number of songs from any radio station to it. Unlike in previous games, adding music to a Mixtape does not require buying the music from a music store in-game.89.0 Generation XThe Black Keys – Next GirlBrooklyn – VolcanologyThe Dear Hunter – In Cauda VenenumDeftones – Diamond EyesDelphic – Clarion CallThe Do – Queen Dot KongDragonette – Stupid GrinFeeder – RenegadesHeavy Young Heathens – Sha La La LaHockey – Too FakeJustin Raisen – Lost DesireKing Khan and The Shrines – TortureThe Lines – El MatadorMiike Snow – AnimalThe Rassle – Born FreeSleigh Bells – Riot RhythmValencia – Stop SearchingWhite Denim – Paint Yourself95.4 KRhymeAmanda Blank – Gimmie What You GotThe Black Keys with NOE – Done Did ItFreeway – Throw Your Hands UpG-Eazy – My Life is a PartyKanye West – PowerK:B – Get It InKurupt and Problem – I'm BurntMedine – Don't PanikMickey Factz – ParadiseMos Def – Quiet DogPharoahe Monch – In the ZoneRob Roy – Fur in my CapSean Price – Boom Bye YeahSixx John – Push PlaySouthpaw Swagger – Can't Stop NowSum Kid – The CountdownTandem – 93 HardcoreTyler, The Creator – YonkersWale – MirrorsYelawolf – Good to Go97.6 K12Baobinga – State of Ghetto Jackin'Benny Benassi – SatisfactionThe Bloody Beetroots – 31 Seconds to Diedeadmau5 – A City in FloridaDigitalism – IdealisticDilemn – PitilessDivalola – WallflowerGrum – HeartbeatsJesse No – Double BubbleJesse No – Oh No U Don'tJokers of the Scene – Baggy Bottom BoysJunkie XL – Angry ElephantsKKS – Scrub DownMNDR – C.L.U.B.Ratatat – NeckbraceRusko – Woo BoostTugboat – Don't Break It102.4 KlassicJohann Sebastian Bach – Brandenburg Concerto No. 3: AllegroLuigi Boccherini – MinuetFrédéric Chopin – Waltz in D flat major, Op. 64, No. 1Antonín Dvořák – Humoresque, Op. 101 No. 7George Frideric Handel – Hallelujah from MessiahFranz Liszt – Hungarian RhapsodyFelix Mendelssohn – Spring SongWolfgang Amadeus Mozart – Serenade No. 13 in G for String Orchestra 1: AllegroWolfgang Amadeus Mozart – Serenade No. 13 in G for String Orchestra 4: RondoGioacchino Rossini – The Thieving Magpie OvertureGioacchino Rossini – The William Tell OvertureCamille Saint-Saëns – Carnival of the Animals: The FossilsJohn Philip Sousa – The Stars and Stripes ForeverJohann Strauss Jr. – Blue DanubeRichard Wagner – Ride of the ValkyriesÉmile Waldteufel – Skaters Waltz104.2 KabronAmbush – Este ReggaetonBlaster Chicks – Vamonos Hasta BajoCalle Cardona – Get DownChacka – FriendzDJ Genesis ft. Simola – Ella Prende GillaDon Omar – Diva VirtualFDK – LujoFDK ft. Pinky – Dejate LlevarFlama – Movimiento EspectacularMr. Kapri – Maria JuanaPitbull – Maldito AlchoholProphex – La TurbinaProphex ft. R-1 – Se Fue La LuzReggae Black – Sueltate Y TomaVakero – Ponte A TrabajarVillanosam – Todavia No Hay Na106.66 The BloodAfter the Burial – BezerkerAmon Amarth – Runes to My MemoryBetween the Buried and Me – ObfuscationThe Black Dahlia Murder – NecropolisBlack Veil Brides – Perfect WeaponChemlab – Suicide JagThe Dillinger Escape Plan – Farewell, Mona LisaDrowning Pool – Feel LIke I DoGoatwhore – Apocalyptic HavocJob for a Cowboy – Regurgitated DisinformationKMFDM – WWIIIMarilyn Manson – Arma-Goddamn-Mortherfuckin-GeddonMastodon – DivinationsMiss May I – Apologies are For the WeakOpeth – The Lotus EaterOTEP – Rise, Rebel, ResistShai Hulud – Misanthropy PureStrapping Young Lad – Love?Tugboat – Slow RevolutionYou Love Her Coz She's Dead – Engine Wrecker107.77 The MixAdam Ant – Stand and DeliverAldo Nova – FantasyBonnie Tyler – Holding Out For a HeroBush – MachineheadButthole Surfers – PepperFaith No More – EpicFrankie Goes to Hollywood – RelaxThe Icicle Works – Birds Fly (Whisper to a Scream)Joe "Bean" Esposito – You're The BestMark Morrison – Return of the MackMötley Crüe – Live WireMötley Crüe – Shout at the DevilRobert Tepper – No Easy Way OutRun DMC – My AdidasSocial Distortion – Ball and ChainSublime – What I GotTalk Talk – It's My LifeTone-Loc – Funky Cold MedinaWDDT CPDG Adult SwimBlack Mountain – Let Spirits RideCerebral Ballzy – Insufficient FairCheesburger – WinnerDanger Doom – Basket CaseDethklok – The Cyborg SlayersJ.G. Thirlwell – No Vacancy (The Venture Bros. Theme)Mike Bigga – The WarOdd Future – AnarchySchooly D – Aqua Teen Hunger Force Theme (Remix)Tim and Eric – Sports! (Sports Bar Remix)Unknown Hinson – Save Me From MyselfWavves – IdiotInitiation StationOn November 1, in advance of the game's release, an external character creation tool named the Saints Row Initiation Station was made available, allowing players to create their characters before playing the game. They are able to upload their character to the community site where they can share it with others, and download characters created by others. Early access to the Initiation Station was made available to those who pre-ordered Red Faction: Armageddon or purchased the Saints Row Double Pack on October 25th.Platinum PackThe collector's edition of Saints Row: The Third cost $99.99 USD and includes the following:A custom modeled Saints Row headset that auto-tunes your voice (The headset works with a 3.5MM audio input and smartphone devices; it does not work on Xbox Live and the Playstation Network, though can be made to work through an adapter).Saints Row: The Third Original Soundtrack.PC VersionThe PC version running on multiple monitorsThe PC version for Saints Row: The Third, like Red Faction: Armageddon was done in-house by Volition, promising a much better PC experience than Saints Row 2. The PC version adds a video record mode that allows you to record and save gameplay clips. It also features a much higher upper limit on the graphical presentation.Minimum Requirements:OS: Microsoft® Windows® XPProcessor: 2GHz Dual Core Processor (Intel® Core 2 Duo or AMD Athlon™ X2) or higherMemory: 2GB System RAM or moreGraphics: 320MB Video RAM GPU w/ Shader Model 3.0 support.NVIDIA® GeForce® 8800 series or better.ATI Radeon™ HD3800 series or betterDirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 10GBSound: 100% DirectX® 9.0C compliant sound card or equivalent onboard soundRecommended System:OS: Microsoft® Windows® 7Processor: Any Quad Core Processor (Intel® Core i5 or AMD Phenom™ II X4) or 3.0+ Dual Core CPUMemory: 4GB System RAM or moreGraphics: 1GB Video RAM GPU w/ Shader Model 4.0 support.NVIDIA® GeForce® GTX 400 series or better.ATI Radeon™ HD5000 series or betterDirectX®: 11Hard Drive: 10GBSound: 100% DirectX® 9.0C compliant sound card or equivalent onboard soundCo-op Play:NVIDIA® GeForce® 8800 cards or higher. Requirement of 640MB of Video RAM.ATI Radeon™ HD3800 cards or higher. Requirement of 1GB of Video RAM.PS3 Exclusive Content Mix-upTHQ had promised that the PS3 version of the game would have exclusive content at launch (a multiplayer game mode and a unique weapon). For reasons unknown, that could not be made available. So, to compensate, all North American users who purchased a new PS3 copy of the game and redeemed their online pass code before February 13, 2012, received a free digital copy of Saints Row 2.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20742">Just Cause 2</game><game id="17036">Grand Theft Auto: Vice City</game><game id="18163">Just Cause</game><game id="4065">Crackdown</game><game id="36765">Grand Theft Auto V</game><game id="38237">Gangstar Rio: City of Saints</game><game id="10593">Grand Theft Auto 2</game><game id="42241">Far Cry 3: Blood Dragon</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2058139-box_srow3.png</image></root>