<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25767</id><name>Six Days in Fallujah</name><description>Back StoryThe city of Fallujah lies about 43 miles west of Baghdad, in the  Iraqi province of Al Anbar. Before the war it had roughly half a million inhabitants. Insurgent forces gained strength following initial US occupation, and on March 31st, 2004, roughly one year after the start of hostilities, attacked a convoy escorted by US mercenaries from Blackwater Security Consulting, now known as Xe. The four Blackwater guards were killed, burned, and hung from a bridge, attracting global attention. US forces tried and failed to retake Fallujah four days later, and withdrew after a month of fighting, on May 1st. The city was successfully retaken by US and British forces during The Second Battle of Fallujah, during November and December of 2004.  The Game Six Days In Fallujah is based on the first days of the Second Battle of Fallujah, during which the heaviest fighting took place. A third-person shooter presented in a documentary style, the game is intended to impart greater understanding of the conflict, from the perspective of both coalition and insurgent forces. In developer  Atomic Games' words: It is intended to challenge perceptions about what a videogame can be.  Konami's Withdrawal In April 2009, roughly one month after Atomic's announcement of the game, Six Days in Fallujah lost funding from publisher  Konami, due to the growing controversy surrounding the project. Atomic admitted seeking consultants from both sides of the conflict, and some feared making a game about such recent events while the war was still ongoing would be disrespectful to the dead. According to Atomic Games, as of January 2011 they are still working independently on the game, and hope to release it in the future.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3715/948314-six_days_in_fallujah_pc_001.jpg</image></root>