<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25791</id><name>Pro Evolution Soccer 2010</name><description>FeaturesPES 2010 contains improved visuals, animations and moves, including live player expressions and movements that will change according to conditions on the field. Animations of dribbling and shots on goal, as well as individual skills, have all been reworked.Gameplay has been made more realistic to constantly test the player, requiring the player to have both strategic play and quick reactions, just like real life. This includes more versatile goalkeepers, greater control over penalties in terms of placing and accuracy, and intuitive zonal defending.There will be an enhanced online experience; a new development team is solely dedicated to improving online play and other aspects such as downloadable content. Previous versions of the game's online mode were plagued with lag, teleporting players and warping.AI has been improved thanks to Teamvision 2.0. Now midfielders and defenders will work together to cut out the attack more effectively. The player will also be able to move several players at once into any opening, resulting in a need for more strategic thinking.The match-day atmosphere has been improved to give a better taste of home or away crowds, which will react spontaneously to all the action on the pitch.360-degree control is introduced, available on the PS3, Xbox 360 and PC versions of the game via the analogue sticks on the respective controllers. The system will allow players to spread the ball with ease, opening up new attacking and defensive possibilities. PS3 owners will also benefit from this when using the Dualshock’s D-Pad, but the Xbox 360 and Wii D-Pads are limited to eight-directional control due to the hardware. Automatic tackling, which often lead to fouls, has now been removed.  Overhaul of the penalty system.  Goalkeepers now more intelligent and less prone to errors.  Konami ID is no longer a requirement for online play. Players "freezing" after taking  free kicks removed.  The master league has seen many enhancements; Real team budgets with real currency, The ability to play UEFA Champions League and Europa League matches during the season and you can skip matches. Licensing   Fully Licensed leagues  Ligue 1  Eredivisie  Serie A     Partially licensed or unlicensed leagues  Premiership  La Liga - 12 licensed teams  Bundesliga   Other leagues     Licensed clubs                                                      Liverpool                                                     Manchester United                                                    FC Barcelona                                                   Real Madrid Athletic BilbaoDeportivo La CorunaEspanyolAthletico MadridReal MallorcaSevillaValenciaVillarreal licensed   Licensed International TeamsCroatiaCzech RepublicEnglandFranceGermanyGreeceIrelandItalyNetherlandsNorthern IrelandPortugalScotlandSpainSwedenTurkeyCote D'IvoireGhanaArgentinaBrazilAustraliaJapanSouth KoreaTeams Confirmed AnderlechtClub BruggeStandard LiègeCroatia Dinamo ZagrebSlavia PragueSparta Prague BrøndbyCopenhagenFinland HJK HelsinkiAEK AthensOlympiacosPanathinaikosPAOK RosenborgWisła Kraków BenficaBraga PortoSporting CPCFR ClujDinamo BucureştiLokomotiv Moscow 3Spartak MoscowZenit St. PetersburgAberdeen CelticHearts RangersRed Star BelgradeAIKGöteborgHammarbyKalmar Boca Juniors River Plate Internacional BaselBeşiktaşFenerbahçeGalatasaraySivasspor Dynamo KyivMetalist Kharkiv Shakhtar Donetsk    International teams    Europe 34 teams                  Austria                BelgiumBosnia And HerzegovinaBulgariaCroatiaCzech RepublicDenmark                  EnglandFinland                   FranceGermanyGreeceHungryIrelandIsraelItalyMontenegroNetherlandsNorthern IrelandNorwayPolandPortugalRomania              Russia             Scotland           SerbiaSlovakiaSlovenia            Spain        Sweden         Switzerland          TurkeyUkraine               Wales     Africa (13 teams)    AngolaCameroonCote D'Ivoire       EgyptGhanaGuineaMali      MoroccoNigeriaSenegal    South AfricaTogoTunisia     The Americas (16 teams)                                        CanadaCosta RicaHonduras                                 Mexico                                     Trinidad And Tobago                                United StatesArgentinaBolivia                                      BrazilChileColumbiaEcuadorParaguay                                   PeruUruguay                                  Venezuela     Asia/Oceania (16 teams)                                   AustraliaBahrain                             China                              Iran                         Iraq                            JapanKuwait                          North KoreaOmanQatar                           Saudi Arabia                       South KoreaSyria                        ThailandUAEUzbekistan  Stadiums  # Stadium Country Team   1                       Anfield England  Liverpool   2                        Old Trafford England  Manchester United   3                      Wembley Stadium England  England   4  Camp Nou Spain  Barcelona   5  Santiago Bernabéu Spain  Real Madrid   6  Estádio do Dragão Portugal  Porto   7  Estádio José Alvalade Portugal  Sporting CP   8  Estádio da Luz Portugal  Benfica   9  Amsterdam Arena Netherlands  Ajax   10  El Monumental Argentina  River Plate   11  Saitama Stadium Japan  Urawa Red Diamonds   12  Stade de France France  France   13  Stade Louis II Monaco  AS Monaco   14  San Siro Italy  Milan and  Internazionale   15  Stadio Olimpico Italy  Roma and  Lazio   Soundtrack Pro Evolution Soccer 2010now features some licensed music played during menus. The player has the option to select which ones will be played and which ones won't. The list of the tracks along with the performers is the following.    * 10-FEET – "super stomper"    * The All American Rejects – "Dirty Little Secret"    * Andrew W.K. – "Party Hard"    * Black Kids – "Hurricane Jane"    * The Chemical Brothers – "Galaxy Bounce"    * The Chemical Brothers – "Midnight Madness"    * The Courteeners – "Not Nineteen Forever"    * David Holmes – "Holy Pictures"    * Delphic – "Counterpoint"    * Dj Shadow – "Artifact"    * The Durango Riot – "No Need for Satisfaction"    * gUiLLeMoTS – "Kriss Kross"    * gUiLLeMoTS – "Trains to Brazil"    * Hoobastank – "Sick of Hanging On"    * Kaiser Chiefs – "Never Miss a Beat"    * Kaiser Chiefs – "Ruby"    * Keane – "Again and Again"    * Keane – "Pretend That You're Alone"    * Klaxons – "Atlantis to Interzone"    * Klaxons – "Gravity's Rainbow"    * Ocean Colour Scene – "Up on the Downside"    * Paul Weller – "Come On/Let's Go"    * Paymoney To My Pain – "The Answer is Not in the TV"    * Stereophonics – "A Thousand Trees"    * Stereophonics – "Dakota"    * the telephones – "Wooo Hoooo"    * The Urgency – "Move You"Advertising  The in-game advertising firm Double Fusion will operate the in-game advertising in PES2010.  DemoThe PES2010 demo was released for the Xbox 360, PS3 and for Windows on Thursday, 17th of September.  The Demo is an older build of the game with a noticeable slow response time when compared to the latest build.   System Requirements Minimum system requirements Processor: Intel Pentium 4 with 2.5 GHz or comparable processorVideo card: Nvidia Geforce FX series or Ati Radeon 9700 series or better (128 MiByte, Pixel Shader 2.0)Memory: 1 GiByteHard Drive: 8 GBRecommended system requirementsProcessor: Intel core 2 Duo with 2.0 GHz or comparable processorVideo Card: Nvidia Geforce 7900 GT or Ati Radeon HD 2400 series or better (256 MiByte, Pixel Shader 3.0)Memory: 2 GiByteHard Drive: 8 GB</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="40">Soccer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21030">FIFA Soccer 09</game><game id="19350">FIFA Soccer 08</game><game id="37">FIFA Soccer 07</game><game id="2629">UEFA Euro 2000</game><game id="26702">FIFA 10</game><game id="15714">Total Club Manager 2005</game><game id="19086">Total Club Manager 2004</game><game id="1586">Total Club Manager 2003</game><game id="20798">UEFA Euro 2008</game><game id="9951">UEFA Champions League 2006-2007</game><game id="3517">UEFA Euro 2004 Portugal</game><game id="25382">Real Football 2009</game><game id="29895">2010 FIFA World Cup South Africa</game><game id="31651">FIFA 11</game><game id="30203">Pure Futbol</game><game id="27148">Let's Make a Soccer Team!</game><game id="29636">Real Soccer 2010</game><game id="34856">FIFA 12</game><game id="36166">FIFA Soccer 13</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2266531-box_pes10.png</image></root>