<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25834</id><name>Yu-Gi-Oh! 5D's Stardust Accelerator: World Championship 2009</name><description>IntroductionWelcome to Neo Domino City, once the playground to legendary duelist Yugi Moto, this sprawling metropolis has since been transformed into a futuristic society where dueling has kicked into overdrive. With recent technological advancements made by the Kaiba Coporation, dueling has undergone a metamorphosis that has revolutionized the make-up and pace of the game of duel monsters and changed it into a heart pounding, adrenaline filled, fuel injected competition where duelist ride supercharged hyper cycles called Duel Runners and battle it out in hi-octane contests called "Turbo Duels." Now the winners and losers aren't just separated by skill and strength... but by SPEED!GameplayThis game does let you do turbo duels as you play. some you just race. you can customize your duel runners color and it's speed once you get farther into the game. You have two separate deck edits. one for turbo duels and one for duels.You start out with a pretty bad deck but if you add some cards from your side deck you'll do pretty well against opponents5D's StoryYou start out as a guy who has amnesia and is from neo-domino city he wakes up and finds a guy named Rally (one of Yusei's friends). You find out that if you duel you remember things much quicker. Your first duel is against Rally. He's a pretty easy opponent if you've edited your deck. After the duel Rally tells you to go to his hangout with his friends. His friends obviously don't know you and the one who is protecting the entrance decides that if you duel him and win he will let you through</description><genres><genre id="13">Card Game</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9558">Magic: The Gathering Online</game><game id="36372">Pokémon Card Game: How To Play DS</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2210221-box_ygo5dssawc2k9.png</image></root>