<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25866</id><name>WarioWare D.I.Y. Showcase</name><description>OverviewWarioWare D.I.Y. Showcase (Asobu Made in Ore in Japan) is the WiiWare counterpart to the DS game WarioWare: D.I.Y., which lets players create and share their own WarioWare microgames. Although content cannot be created in Showcase it includes totally different preloaded microgames, comics and music than those found in WarioWare D.I.Y., and empty slots to store up to 72 of each content type imported from a DS, friends or the NinSoft Store.Playing Games (Wario-Man Super Store)72 pre-made microgames are included. As well as playing the Game Blender stages, single microgames can be played on a loop to get a high-scoreWario-Man SoftwareFour characters have pre-made microgame sets in Showcase. Rather than the stories of previous games, each character stage is based around a simple TV show and features no conclusive ending. A simple interactive animation is played following the Boss Stage. All four character stages are unlocked from the beginning. Wario-Man: "The Extraordinary Wario-Man" - While flying through the park Wario-Man sees some boys trying to get into the public restrooms, but the doors are jammed shut. After each Boss Stage, Wario-Man runs past a billboard for his movie. Dribble   Spitz: "Dribble  Spitz Rally!" - Dribble  Spitz enter the Diamond City Rally in their modified taxi cab. During the interval, an ad for their Taxi Company is shown. Again, you need to see it after a Boss Stage is beaten or failed. Kat   Ana: "Kat  Ana's Sky Patrol" - Kat  Ana jump off a cliff and fly through the skies using capes. The break shows them using their "ninjitsu" in a park and you can see it after each Boss Stage. 18-Volt: "Jet 18-Volt" - 18-Volt stars in his own 8-bit scrolling shooter very similar to  Xevious in design. At the end of the Boss Stage, 9-Volt appears in a spaceship to meet 18-Volt.There are also two Remix modes that incorporate all the Wario-Man Software microgames. Instead of a TV show theme, the remixes use differently-colored Wario TVs.Shuffle: Games start at normal speed and get progressively faster. Boss Stages appear, in the order they appear in the character stages. Unlocked by playing all 72 microgames at least once.Ultra-Hard!: The games start from a much higher speed. Unlocked by reaching 25 points on Shuffle.D.I.Y. GamesThere are four stages made up from downloaded and player-made microgames (imported from the DS game) labeled D.I.Y. Games 1-4, with 18 slots each. The Shuffle and Ultra-Hard! remix modes above also return but containing only the D.I.Y. sets.Mix AllThese remixes incorporate both the pre-made and player-made microgames in a single mix. All three are unlocked by scoring 10 points on Wario-Man Software: Ultra Hard!Shuffle: The games start at normal speed. Boss Stages appear, in the order they appear in the character stages.Ultra-Hard!: The games start at a much higher speed.Versus: The games can be played with up to 4 players. Each player takes a quarter of the screen and when their section lights up they play a microgame. Other players can interfere with each others games, and when each player loses their four lives, they're out. The last player standing wins.Sharing (Distribution Center)Exchanging GamesGames, music and comics can be sent to another Wii friend (via WiiConnect24) or to the DS game (via local wireless). Up to 72 of each type of content can be stored on the Wii. Wii-exclusive content can be transferred to DS, but DS-exclusive content cannot be sent to the Wii.In order to share games on Wii, players must switch on the D.I.Y. Friend Notification Switch, which will allow Showcase to check which friends in the console's Address Book own the game and if they're sharing anything. When sending to another Wii console, you can send out two members of staff per content type (games, music, comics) at one time. Each staff member can deliver one piece of content to up to 8 friends at once.Once a friend has received and played a game, they can rate it (out of five stars) and write a comment, which is sent back to the creator's Survey Box on the Main Menu.NinSoft StorePlayers can visit the "NinSoft Store" to get free downloads from Nintendo. The shop stocks 2 new Weekly Games from Nintendo each week, in addition to Big Name Games (by game developers) and contest-winning Theme Games . The same downloads are available for both the DS and Wii games.In North America, Big Name Games will be posted every week until July 26. In Japan, new Weekly Games releases have stopped at 100 (which took just under a year; it's likely that the same will be true for other regions) and Big Name Games are now being removed one year after their original release, with the exception of Sakurai and Sakamoto's games. Design Challenges continue to be posted, however. In Europe, the Big Name Games schedule differs from the American one, and the Weekly Games are being released around 4 and a half weeks after the NA versions.Music and Comics18 records and comics are included in the game, and like with microgames there's 72 slots for D.I.Y. content. Unlike the DS game, all 18 records and comics are unlocked from the start. Each of the six characters in the game has three comics and three records, released under the Wario-Man Records/Publishing brand.The music player is styled after Balloon Trip from Balloon Fight and allows the player to adjust tempo by dragging the character left or right in Listen mode. There's also a Play mode that plays like the aforementioned Balloon Trip, with the player collecting the notes in the sky. The comic viewer is almost identical to the DS version, with no features other than the ability to click though the pages.Pricing  AvailabilityWarioWare D.I.Y. Showcase is available from the Wii Shop Channel for 800 Wii Points. It launched day-and-date with the DS game in Japan and Europe, and the next day in North America (to line up with the Shop Channel's Monday update schedule). The download takes up 83 blocks in the Wii system memory (112 blocks for the Japanese and European versions).Complete Microgame ListingAll the preloaded microgames are listed below, in the order they appear on the Super Store shelves. Showcase includes 76 microgames (72 4 Boss Stages), which can be transferred to the DS game. The genres are the same as the original WarioWare, Inc., except 18-Volt who takes 9-Volt's genre (9-Volt has his own Nintendo set on the DS game). Downloadable microgames are listed on the WarioWare D.I.Y. page.Note: Since the game never displays the names of the Boss Stages, the names below aren't the "official" names.Wario-Man (Games Featuring Wario)Stamp OutWario 101Let's BounceIdol HandsOutta My WaySpearheadWardi GrasWanna Slice?Who Nose?Navel ForceGAME  WARIOWatched PotsOut With It!MechaWarioFlag WaverMoney HungryHow Old?Speed TrapBoss Stage: Pass the BombDribble  Spitz (Sci-Fi)Garden PestsMoon BalloonLeaf ThrowerOn Course1, 2, ROBOT!Space TrapTenderfootStop! Go!Spirit SpotDomino BlockBlocksmithSpring BotClock RocksHeat is OnShell GameOn-LineGun Vs NinjaWind FallBoss Stage: Oh Nose!Kat  Ana (Nature)Stripy SeaFish WhichBall  ChainCrypto ZooThe Lily CupOfficer K-9Bird-WatcherAnimal XingCritterificRed-HandedPork SortRabbit RiverCheese RunDoor DashOut of WaterWorm FoodEscape HatchDog CatcherBoss Stage: Giant Bug18-Volt (Nintendo)Mario KartDK 3Wario LandDuck HuntMario WorldDK CountryDonkey KongAdvance WarsPunch-Out!!Wild GunmanWreck, CrewMario Bros.Clu Clu LandMario SlotsKid IcarusMario Adv.BooZelda 2Boss Stage: Gyromite</description><genres><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2104/1283329-diyshowcase_logo.jpg</image></root>