<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25912</id><name>King's Bounty: Armored Princess</name><description>StoryRibbit!Set years after the first game in the series, the story follows the adventures of Princess Amelie, who was sent by her father to Teana via a magic portal, so she can find her mentor and savior from the first game, Bill Gilbert. As soon as she arrives, she is greeted by the ruler of the island of Debir, King Frederick, and receives The Stone of Courage. This proves that she is the chosen one, and her quest to find the other stones located on Teana, as well as finding Bill. Apart from the main storyline the heroine is confronted with dozens of side quests on numerous islands. Almost every character has their own backstory and unique character.GameplayThe style of the gameplay is a Turn Based Role Playing Game (TBRPG) ,in which the player controls only Princess Amelie on the overworld map. She can be either a warrior, a paladin or a mage. When you engage in combat, the game turns into a Heroes of Might and Magic style of game, with each type of creature having a set amount of action points, special ability, attack points, defense points, critical damage chance etc. The stats of your hero are added to the stats of the creature.The differences between the sequel and the original are:Fear the dragon's rage!Pet Dragon replaces the Box of RageInstant Travel to other islands on boat instead of portalsNew RaceNew SkillsMedals that work like Achievements, but add some skills to your hero.System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Windows XP / VistaProcessor: 2.6GHzMemory: 1GB of RAMGraphics Card: nVidia GeForce 6600 with 128 MB or equivalent ATIHard Drive: 5.5 GB of free spaceSound Card: DirectX-compatible soundcardRecommended:OS: Windows XP / VistaProcessor: 3 GHzMemory: 2 GB of RAMGraphics Card: nVidia GeForce 7950GT with 512 MB or equivalent ATIHard Drive: 5.5 GB of free spaceSound Card: DirectX-compatible soundcard</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1915">Heroes of Might and Magic V</game><game id="17108">Heroes of Might and Magic: Quest for the DragonBone Staff</game><game id="18414">Age of Wonders</game><game id="18279">Age of Wonders: Shadow Magic</game><game id="15976">Age of Wonders II: The Wizard's Throne</game><game id="22154">King's Bounty: The Legend</game><game id="32374">Might &amp; Magic Heroes VI</game><game id="12466">Heroes of Might and Magic II: The Succession Wars</game><game id="13989">Heroes of Might and Magic III: The Restoration of Erathia</game><game id="14391">Heroes of Might and Magic: A Strategic Quest</game><game id="33448">Vantage Master</game><game id="33450">VM Japan: Vantage Master - Mystic Far East</game><game id="40652">Frozen Hearth</game><game id="41470">Folk Tale</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/13692/1269370-kingsbountyarmoredprincess.jpg</image></root>