<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>25983</id><name>Torchlight</name><description>OverviewTorchlight is the debut game from Runic Games, and was released on October 27, 2009. It is an isometric view action RPG, very much in the vein of the successful famous classic Diablo franchise. Development of Torchlight was led by Max and Erich Schaefer, designers behind Diablo and Diablo II. An XBLA version was released March 9, 2011.A sequel, Torchlight II, was released September 2012.StoryThe story centers around a mysterious ore called Ember, which is the essence of magic and the keystone in alchemy. Word of Ember crossed the world, and the city of Torchlight was built. Miners dug deep beneath the streets of Torchlight, discovering ore richer than anyone had ever seen, but they were not the first to covet these mines. Buried along with the ore lays a buried past, a dangerous labyrinth of caverns and ruined civilizations, twisted creatures and the bones of those who came before. Evil bubbles up from the depths and threatens to overrun Torchlight as it has so many others. The heart of a villain has infused the Ember, and his darkness seeps through the veins. To survive, the townspeople must break the cycle of destruction; they need a champion who can destroy the evil at its root. Removing the source of the rot may purify the Ember, but it is a long and perilous journey. The champion must battle through rock and fire, through lost cities and ancient tombs, into the palace of the villain himself.GameplayFighting can get pretty messyTorchlight consists of one main dungeon, with the only outside area being the town of Torchlight. The main story takes place along the entire length of the dungeon, culminating in the end boss on the lowest floor of the dungeon. There is also a major boss fight every five floors, with a change in environment shortly after. The levels in the dungeon are randomized, but the game includes many handcrafted quests and unique bosses. After the player finishes the main game, they can also access an infinite dungeon, the Shadow Vault.Torchlight includes a total of five difficulty levels, ranging from Very Easy to Very Hard. Additionally, there is a hardcore mode where if the player's character dies, they are dead permanently. It is recommended that players familiar with this type of game start with at least the Hard difficulty.Character ProgressionLeft, Attributes. Right, Skill Tree.In Torchlight, players gain experience and levels by killing monsters and completing quests. With each level gained, the player gets five attribute points that they can spend on the four main attributes: Defense, Magic, Strength, and Dexterity. They are also rewarded with one skill point to apply to their Skill Tree upon leveling up.An auxiliary means of leveling in Torchlight is Fame. As players kill Boss Monsters or complete quests, they gain fame. For each level of fame, they are awarded one bonus skill point, and the maximum level of fame is twenty.Equipment and LootPlayers can find all kinds of valuable items while dungeon diving in Torchlight, either by defeating enemies, destroying barrels and other destructible wares scattered around in the dungeons, or in treasure chests. It can range from simple items like magical scrolls and potions, to rare, unique equipment that players can spend hours trying find. Each class can use any equipment they find; there are no class-specific weapons or armor. There is, however, attribute and level restrictions on many of the rarer equipment. A player has eleven equipment slots, much like most RPGs:Equipment ScreenHelmChest armorShoulder armorBeltBootsGlovesRings (two slots)AmuletLeft handed weapon/shieldRight handed weaponTorchlight has an item color classification to make the value and importance of an item easier to discern. This classification system was popularized by World of Warcraft, and is a key component of many loot-heavy games:White: An ordinary item. Scrolls and spells are also displayed in this color.Green: An enchanted item. This item possess a magical enchantment and usually sells for a higher price than ordinary items, and they usually come identified.Blue: A rare item. This item often possess a powerful enchantment or even several, different magical properties. When identified, this item sells well.Orange - A unique item. This is a one-of-a-kind item that rarely appears in the game and hold many powerful enchantments. If identified, this unique item can sell for a lot of gold.Purple - A rare or unique item that is part of a set. Collecting and equipping other armor or items in the same set adds additional powers. The number of items in sets varies but some include up to six distinct pieces.GemsGems in Torchlight are weapon or armor modifiers that can be placed into any empty Socket. Sockets can come either preexisting in weapon drops, or added to equipment by random enchantment at the Enchanter. They have different effects dependent on their type, their grade, and their placement into a weapon, an armor piece, or a trinket. Identical gems can be combined to form a higher grade gem of the same type at the Transmuter. There are ten grades to a gem, ranging from the poorest quality to the best:CrackedDullDiscoloredNormalCutPolishedStarFlawlessPerfectUltimate (Each type has their unique name)There are nine main types of gems in Torchlight.GemWeapon EffectArmor/Trinket EffectCold-EmberAdditional Ice DamageAdditional Ice ResistanceCore-EmberHealth Recovery per SecondStrength Attribute BonusDeep-EmberArmor Degraded per HitDexterity Attribute BonusFire-EmberAdditional Fire DamageAdditional Fire ResistanceFlow-EmberAdditional Electric DamageAdditional Electric ResistanceLife-EmberAdditional Poison DamageAdditional Poison ResistancePure-EmberAdditional DamageAdditional ArmorEyeballMana Stolen on HitMagic Attribute BonusSkullHealth Stolen on HitDefense Attribute BonusThere are also rarer chaos gems, with random magical bonuses.PetsThe Faithful DogThe pet is a player's only companion while exploring the dungeons of Torchlight. Two types of pets came with the game's original release: a wolfish dog, and a lynx-like cat. The retail release of Torchlight introduced a ferret pet, and the XBLA release made available a rather odd lizard creature called a Chakawary. These additional pets are not available in the original release except through modding.The pet will have the ability to fight along a player's side, and can hold items, and even sell loot back in town while the player remains in the dungeon. It is able to equip two rings and an amulet, and can learn up to two spells to cast. The pet cannot die, but will flee when it is out of health, putting it out of combat for a period of time.Players can feed fish, found in fishing spots in the dungeons, to their pets, changing it temporarily or permanently into other creatures (this also changes their own attributes accordingly). Other potions, capable of affecting only its attributes and not its appearance can also be found through fishing and exploration (see Potions below).Players can set just how aggressive their pets are during combat by setting its stance, using buttons located just below the pet's health and mana bars:Agressive Stance: The pet will always attack any nearby enemy and pursue them until either it has to flee or the enemy dies.Defensive Stance: The pet will only attack an enemy if it attacks the player first; it will also not pursue enemies.Passive Stance: The pet will not engage enemies, even those that attack the player.The DungeonThe entirety of Torchlight's gameplay takes place in a single, continuous huge dungeon beneath the game's only town, similar to the Diablo, but with more variations on level design. This dungeon comprises of all the levels in the game's main story. The monster sets in these levels are predefined and do not scale to the player's level.Floors 1 - 5: Orden MinesThe original mineshaft that most of the townsfolk work in to collect Ember, the town's most profitable resource, and the source of corruption.Floors 6 - 10: Tomb of the Awakened A necropolis with skeletons and zombies.Floors 11 - 15: Estherian RuinsA central hub of overgrown plants amid temple ruins. Three floors can be taken in any order to unlock the final floors in the area.Floors 16 - 20: Tu'tara CavernsA system of caverns on the verge of collapse.Floors 21 - 25: The Molten PrisonRuins of an old prison system with red-glowing lava flowing below.Floors 26 - 30: The Lost FortressAncient Dwarven ruins consisting of mechanical enemies and corrupt Ember beings.Floors 31 - 34: The Black PalaceThe final set of dungeons before meeting the game's villain. Naturally, these levels present the biggest challenges and tought enemies.Floor 35: Ordrak's LairThe ancient temple of the main dungeon's final boss, Ordrak, with dark energy waves and lightning special effects to set the properly ominous tone.The Shadow VaultThe Shadow Vault is a randomized dungeon, unlocked in the town's Crypt/Graveyard area after defeating Ordrak on any difficulty setting on any given character class. The dungeon floors are endless and randomized to use all sets of locations and monsters. The enemies in this never-ending dungeon scale to the player's level on all floors, providing a more challenging and rewarding experience for the player.The Shadow Vault has two quest givers; these NPC's are located in town, just outside the dungeon's entrance.CharactersPlayable ClassesThere are three classes in Torchlight, all of which are gender-specific. Each class has three unique skill trees, and skills are unlocked by the character's levels.ClassesThe Destroyer is a melee based class supplemented with special spiritual abilities. He is a Warrior-like class in its essence. You can range from a Tanky Juggernaut to a Duel-Wielding Beast. He gains 60 health and 5 mana per level and has the following starting attributes:Strength: 10Dexterity: 4Magic: 3Defense: 10Health: 300Mana: 20The Alchemist is a mage-like class that uses a special gauntlet on his left hand called the Focus Glove to shoot bursts of Ember energy. He gains 40 health and around 7 mana per level, and has the following starting attributes:Strength: 6Dexterity: 7Magic: 10Defense: 5Health: 200Mana: 30The only female class in the game, the Vanquisher is a ranged-focused character with rogue-like abilities. She is part of an elite military unit of the capital city sent to Torchlight, disguised as an adventurer seeking treasure. In reality, she is there to investigate strange occurrences in the mines beneath Torchlight. She gains 40 health and 5 mana per level, and has the following starting attributes:Strength: 5Dexterity: 10Magic: 7Defense: 6Health: 200Mana: 20Non-player CharactersThe Man Behind it AllTorchlight has a number of NPCs that the player can interact with:Syl: Brought to Torchlight by a note from her mentor, Master Alric.Brink: Companion and business partner to Syl.Master Alric: Mentor to Syl, and the one who taught her to use Ember.Kolos: A blacksmith that sells weaons.Tarn the Merchant: Sells general goods.Trill-Bot 4000: Aspiring Bard and One-Man Band.Triya: Sells socketable Gems.Goren: Enchants items.Duran, the Transmuter: Combines treasure to create new items.Vasman: Ember scholar.Gorn: Destroys items, recovering the gems inside.Furn: Destroys gems in socketed items.Duros the Blade: Sells unidentified items.Valeria: Gives quests related to the Shadow Vault.Gar: Gives quests related to the Shadow Vault.SkillsAlchemistSkillTierDescriptionLevel Required to UnlockEmber BoltArcaneBolts of ember energy seek out their target1Magic Weapons ExpertiseArcaneMastery of all wands and staves, and reduced requirements for rings and amulets.1IceshockArcaneHurl a crystal that detonates with a chilling blast, freezing nearby foes.5Critical StrikesArcaneIncreases the chance and improves the damage of all critical strikes.5AdventurerArcaneImproves the potency of potions, increases the rate of experience and fame gain, and reduces resurrection penalties.10Ember LightningArcaneBlasts foes with a bolt of ember energy.10Offensive Spell MasteryArcaneIncreases the level of all offensive magic spells. Spells can be found or bought, and fall under the spells tab in your inventory.10Ember LanceArcanePierces foes with a shaft of blistering energy.15PyreArcaneHurls a crystal filled with nether flames - burns foes over time.20Advanced SpellcastingArcaneReduces the level requirements of all spells and improves mana recharge rate.20Ember StrikeArcaneA bolt of burning energy from the sky strikes the target location.25Nether ImpLoreSummons Nether Imps from the dormant energies of corpses.1Thorned MinionsLoreYour minions are imbued with crackling energy that reflects the damage foes inflict on them.5Pet MasteryLoreYour affinity for animals increases your pet and minion's power and decreases the pet's town-travel time.5Summon Alchemic GolemLoreSummons an alchemical golem to attack your foes.10Charm Spell MasteryLoreIncreases the level of all charm magic spells. Spells can be found or bough, and fall under the spells tab in your inventory.10TerrorLoreCauses enemies within range to flee in mortal terror.15Ranged Weapons ExpertiseLoreMastery of bows, pistols, crossbows, and rifles.15Burning BlindLoreYour minions are enraged, resulting in improved damage and attack speeds.20Summon Beam GolemLoreSummons a golem to blast your foes with a beam of electricity.25Treasure HunterLoreIncreases the chance to find magic items, and potency of enchantments. Treasure hunters also find more gold.25Ember ShockBattleA gauntlet overload delivers a devastating charge to a single target. Power diffuses into nearby foes for lesser damage.1Armor ExpertiseBattleMastery of all forms of armor reduces requirements and improves armor absorption.1Ember ShieldBattleEnvelops you in ember energy, absorbing physical damage.5Martial Weapons ExpertiseBattleMastery of swords, axes, maces, and polearms.5InfuseBattleImbue your weapons with ember energy for increased damage.10Defensive Spell MasteryBattleIncreases the level of all defensive magic spells. Spells can be found or bough, and fall under the spells tab in your inventory.10FrailtyBattleEnfeebles Nearby enemies, reducing their armor and elemental resistances, and slowing their attacks.15Dual WieldingBattleImproves damage of all weapons when dual-wielding.15Ember PhaseBattlePhase to a new location dealing damage as you enter and exit nether space.20Block and ParryBattleIncreases the chance to block, either with or without shield.20Ember SentryBattleA sentry crystal blasts nearby enemies with a beam of ember energy.20DestroyerSkillTierDescriptionLevel Required to UnlockSlash AttackBerserkerAttacks all foes in front of you with all equipped weapons.1Dual WieldingBerserkerImproves damage of all weapons when dual-wielding.1StampedeBerserkerA brutal forward dash that damages all foes in its path.5AdventurerBerserkerImproves the potency of potions, increases the rate of experience and fame gain, and reduces resurrection penalties.10Offensive Spell MasteryBerserkerIncreases the level of all offensive magic spells.10Chain VortexBerserkerPhantasmal chains stun nearby foes.15Spectral EchoBerserkerWhile active, attacks cause a spectral echo to damage foes beyond their normal range.20Critical StrikesBerserkerIncreases the chance and improves the damage of all critical strikes.20Treasure HunterBerserkerIncreases the chance to find magic items, and potency of enchantments. Treasure hunters also find more gold.25DevastateBerserkerYou rush forward in a flurry of powerful attacks using all equipped melee weapons.25Soul RendTitanA powerful phantasmal blade cleaves your foes.1Titan StompTitanBlast all nearby foes with a shockwave that damages and knocks them back.5Martial Weapons ExpertiseTitanMastery of swords, axes, maces, and polearms.5Ranged Weapons ExpertiseTitanMastery of bows, pistols, crossbows, and rifles.10DoomquakeTitanStrike the ground, sending burning cracks outwards to pierce your foes.10Defensive Spell MasteryTitanIncreases the level of all defensive magic spells. Spells can be found or bough, and fall under the spells tab in your inventory.10Frost ShieldTitanA protective field absorbs physical and elemental damage, and freezes foes who strike it.15BarterTitanReduces the purchase prices at merchants, enchanters, and gamblers. Improves the sale prices of your own goods.20Block and ParryTitanIncreases the chance to block, either with or without shield.20Seismic BurstTitanA burst of energy crackles along the ground, flinging enemies from its path.25Shadow ArmorSpectralSummons a phantasmal which attacks nearby foes.1Entropic AuraSpectralEnemies near you are slowed, and sometimes interrupted. The aura lasts for two minutes. Only one aura may be active at a time.5Armor ExpertiseSpectralMastery of all forms of armor reduces requirements and improves armor absorption.5Magic Weapons ExpertiseSpectralMastery of all wands and staves, and reduced requirements for rings and amulets.5Shadow BowmanSpectralSummons a phantasm which attacks foes at range with a spectral bow.10Charm Spell MasterySpectralIncreases the level of all charm magic spells. Spells can be found or bough, and fall under the spells tab in your inventory.10Pet MasterySpectralYour affinity for animals increases your pet and minion's power and decreases the pet's town-travel time.15Aura of ThornsSpectralEnemies near you incur automatic damage over time. The aura last for two minutes.20Spectra DecaySpectralDisrupts the armor of nearby foes, amplifying the damage you deal to them.25Advanced SpellcastingSpectralReduces the level requirements of all spells and improves mana recharge rate.25VanquisherSkillTierDescriptionLevel Required to UnlockRanged Weapon ExpertiseMarksmanMastery of bows, pistols, crossbows, and rifles.1RicochetMarksmanFire a ricocheting projectile from the active ranged weapon.1Frost PilumMarksmanFire a piercing ice projectile from a ranged weapon.5Critical StrikesMarksmanIncreases the chance and improves the damage of all critical strikes.5AdventurerMarksmanImproves the potency of potions, increases the rate of experience and fame gain, and reduces resurrection penalties.10Seeking ShotMarksmanFires 3 projectiles that seek out nearby foes.10Offensive Spell MasteryMarksmanIncreases the level of all offensive magic spells. Spells can be found or bought, and fall under the spells tab in your inventory.10Explosive ShotMarksmanFire a projectile from any equipped ranged weapon that detonates on impact, dealing damage to foes within its range.15Block and ParryMarksmanIncreases the chance to block, either with or without shield.20Arrow HailMarksmanCall forth a hail of arrows to pierce your foes.25Needle ArcRogueFling an arc of darts that pierces foes.1StabRogueA brutal forward strike with two dirks.5Armor ExpertiseRogueMastery of all forms of armor reduces requirements and improves armor absorption.5Wind of JusticeRoguePushes nearby enemies away with a freezing force of righteousness.10Defensive Spell MasteryRogueIncreases the level of all defensive magic spells. Spells can be found or bough, and fall under the spells tab in your inventory.10Martial Weapons ExpertiseRogueMastery of swords, axes, maces, and polearms.15BarterRogueReduces the purchase prices at merchants, enchanters, and gamblers. Improves the sale prices of your own goods.20Venomous DirksRogueRelease a set of enchanted poison dirks which slowly seek out and pierces enemies.20Treasure HunterRogueIncreases the chance to find magic items, and potency of enchantments. Treasure hunters also find more gold.25HamstringRogueA swift dash which slices enemies with a pair of dirks, impairing their movement and inducing bleeding.25Lightning BombArbiterHurl a bomb that splits into electrical bolts on impact.1Dual WieldingArbiterImproves damage of all weapons when dual-wielding.5Flame TrapArbiterHurl a device that burns nearby foes with gouts of flame, devastating low resist enemies.5Charm Spell MasteryArbiterIncreases the level of all charm magic spells. Spells can be found or bough, and fall under the spells tab in your inventory.10Flechette TrapArbiterHurl a device that sprays foes with piercing flechettes.15Pet MasteryArbiterYour affinity for animals increases your pet and minion's power and decreases the pet's town-travel time.15Magic Weapons ExpertiseArbiterMastery of all wands and staves, and reduced requirements for rings and amulets.20Devouring TrapArbiterHurl a device that drains the armor of all nearby foes.20Shock TrapArbiterHurl a device that shocks nearby foes with bolts of lightning.25Advanced SpellcastingArbiterReduces the level requirements of all spells and improves mana recharge rate.25PotionsHealth PotionsPotionDescriptionHealth Potion400 Health recovery over four secondsBig Health Potion800 Health recovery over four secondsGiant Health Potion1200 Health recovery over four secondsSuper Health Potion1600 Health recovery over four secondsGrand Health Potion2000 Health recovery over four secondsMana PotionsPotionDescriptionMana Potion520 Mana recovery over four secondsBig Mana Potion1040 Mana recovery over four secondsGiant Mana Potion1560 Mana recovery over four secondsSuper Mana Potion2080 Mana recovery over four secondsGrand Mana Potion2600 Mana recovery over four secondsSpecial PotionsPotionDescriptionTime DurationAccuracy PotionAdds 20 to Critical Hit20 secondsLuck PotionAdds 100% Magic Find60 secondsArmor PotionAdds 100% Armor120 secondsPotion of RespecRefund all Skill Points-----Brom's Roughhide TonicAdds 2 Defense PointsPermanentOverseer's EyeAdds 25 Health / Hit PointsPermanentFish PotionsThese potions can only be fed to your pet and will obviously only take effect on him/her.FishDescriptionTime DurationOrdrake PolypAdds 25% to Magic Find for 3600 seconds3600 secondsMolten EelAdds 20% to Fire Damage dealt- 20% Fire Damage taken300 secondsMagmamouth BassAdds 1 point to StrengthPermanentLeviathan ToothAdds 100% to Knock Back Resistance3600 secondsGruefishAdds 20% to Poison Damage dealt- 20% Poison Damage taken300 secondsGlowsharkAdds 1 point to MagicPermanentEmberbright CodAdds 50% to Fishing Luck1200 secondsEmber Fish EyeAdds 20% to Experience Gain300 secondsElectric EelAdds 20% to Electric Damage dealt- 20% Electric Damage taken300 secondsBlind EelAdds 1 point to DexterityPermanentBearded FishAdds 25% to Armor300 secondsAxe RayAdds 1 point to DefensePermanentAncient GumfishAdds 20% to Ice Damage dealt- 20% Ice Damage taken300 secondsAlbino HalibutAdds 10% Chance to Block300 secondsEnemiesCommon EnemiesRock TrollVarkolynSlimeRatlinMimicConstructsFlesheatersGrave DiggersSkeletonsSpidersStabber PygmysPygmy ChantersTunnel SpidersThorned SpidersTu'TaraGoblin StabberGoblin HunterGoblinhoundCrazed GoblinGoblin ChanterGoblin HealerTrollTroll JuggernautBurrowerSpecterSoulless CutterDwarven WightEmber ThrallDeathwalker BattlemasterMechanical ConstructWatcher GeistCursed SwordCrawlerSkeletonBlood DiscipleDark ZealotEnslavedDragonkinFelwingDragonkinBossesBrink, the CorruptedThe OverseerEmber ColossusKragMedeaAlricOrdrakModdingOne key feature of Torchlight is its moddability. With the Torchlight editor, known as TorchED, players are able to create their own dungeon sets with a tile based editor, and edit damage, experience, monster, skill, and loot tables. Players can also create their own armors, skills, and even their own classes using their own character models and armor sets.MultiplayerAlthough there is no (official) multiplayer support in Torchlight, limited multiplayer (Direct IP) support is available through the use of a community developed mod. Available at http://code.google.com/p/tlmp/The sequel, Torchlight II, has multiplayer co-op out of the box.SoundtrackThe soundtrack is composed by Matt Uelmen, who is best known for the soundtrack of the Diablo series. It is also said that he will compose the soundtrack for the upcoming TorchLight MMO as well. The songs can be found in the game's audio directory, filed under alphabetical order. They are as follows:Song TitleRunning TimeBoss Anticipation01.09Boss Fight01.14Boss Resolution00.30Cavern05.00Crypt03.12Fortress03.37Lava03.54Mines04.46Ordraak Fight01.13Ordraak Resolution00.40Palace04.40Ruins03.43Title02.21Town02.55Town Fight00.13DistributionOriginally Torchlight was only going to be available via PC digital distribution platforms including Steam, Direct2Drive, and from Runic Games directly. The Steam version of the game now has cloud saves and achievements to go along with the update that added the infinite dungeon. However, Runic revealed that the game would be available on store shelves from publisher Encore. A physical copy for Torchlight was available in stores since January 5th, 2010. The boxed versions do not have any form of DRM, and also come with a 3rd pet, a Ferret (which can also can be unlocked with mods).Torchlight XBLAIn March 2010, Max Schaefer (CEO of Runic Games) was asked about porting the game to consoles, and he responded:"We're going to put some serious effort, pretty quick, into getting 'Torchlight' onto consoles. There's a lot of really cool things about the console world, too, that would work well with our game."Later, in August at Gamescom 2010, Runic Games revealed that they have been hard at work on the console port and are hoping to have the XBLA and PSN versions of the game out by Holiday 2010.At CES 2011, it was officially announced that an XBLA version of Torchlight would be coming sometime in February as part of an "XBLA House Party" promotion."Torchlight" (Runic Games Inc./Microsoft Corp.) E10 (Everyone 10 ) A highly regarded PC game with more than 800,000 units sold to date, "Torchlight" is now coming to Xbox LIVE. Combat is more exciting with revamped controls and mechanics, new armor and quests. There's even an exclusive new pet for your character. Send a select goodie or two to your friends on Xbox LIVE* to share the fun for the first time.Although previously announced to also appear on PSN, plans for that have been halted as Microsoft is publishing the XBLA version.There are many changes to this version from the original release:New art assetsOverhauled UINo item slots, instead players can hold up to fifty items, and ninety-nine potions and scrollsPotions auto select the best potion to heal or restore manaPlayers can map four active skills to the controller buttons. Two sets of four can be swapped between for a total of eight mapped skillsCharacter movement is executed with the left analog stick. Enemies are not targeted, as the character now strike any enemy in their rangeLoading times reducedNew animationsAutomapping system from Torchlight IIOne new armor set for each classNew questsA new pet: the ChakawaryThe price of the game in XBLA is 1200 MSP.System RequirementsPCOperating System: Windows XP SP3 or laterProcessor: Intel Pentium III 800 MHz processorRAM Memory: 512 MB (1 GB Recommended)Graphics: DirectX 9.0c compatible 3D graphics with at least 64 MB of addressable memoryHard Drive: 400 MBMacOperating System: OS X version Leopard 10.5.8, Snow Leopard 10.6.3, or laterProcessor: Intel MacRAM Memory: 1GB RAMGraphics: OpenGL 2.0 compatible video card with 256MB dedicated RAM (ATI Radeon X1600 or nVidia equivalent)Hard Drive: 800MB</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20803">Diablo III</game><game id="1119">Diablo II</game><game id="5985">Diablo</game><game id="8638">Titan Quest</game><game id="13762">Titan Quest: Immortal Throne</game><game id="5153">Sacred</game><game id="20901">Sacred 2: Fallen Angel</game><game id="21229">Mythos</game><game id="25290">Fate:  Undiscovered Realms</game><game id="4673">Fate</game><game id="19703">Darkstone</game><game id="11521">Record of Lodoss War</game><game id="20499">Too Human</game><game id="29421">Greed Black Border</game><game id="29823">Grim Dawn</game><game id="29893">Anrufen Online</game><game id="21633">Soma Bringer</game><game id="17752">Diablo: Hellfire</game><game id="30628">Pocket Legends</game><game id="31134">Hazen: The Dark Whispers</game><game id="21733">DeathSpank</game><game id="32378">Dimensity</game><game id="32085">Bastion</game><game id="32416">DeathSpank: Thongs of Virtue</game><game id="13293">Dungeon Siege: Legends of Aranna</game><game id="20718">Dungeon Siege III</game><game id="28914">Magicka</game><game id="32255">Torchlight II</game><game id="32562">Path of Exile</game><game id="32130">Darkspore</game><game id="33494">Dungeons &amp; Dragons Daggerdale</game><game id="35449">The Baconing</game><game id="35468">Crimson Alliance</game><game id="35560">Warrior's Lair</game><game id="37364">The Sewer Goblet: The Wu-Tang Clan and the Wu-Tang Baby</game><game id="37209">R.A.W.: Realms of Ancient War</game><game id="37649">Akaneiro Demon Hunters</game><game id="38760">Forge</game><game id="40652">Frozen Hearth</game><game id="37680">Dungeonland</game><game id="42053">Evoland</game><game id="38294">The Incredible Adventures of Van Helsing</game><game id="42722">Second Chance Heroes</game><game id="41416">The Mighty Quest for Epic Loot</game><game id="43290">Hand of Fate</game><game id="8590">Dawn of Magic</game><game id="43649">Diablo III: Reaper of Souls</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1099/1251559-torchlight.png</image></root>