<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26009</id><name>Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Double Agent</name><description>There is a Xbox 360, PC, and the PlayStation 3 version that can be reached here.OverviewCreated by Splinter Cell and Chaos Theory developer Ubisoft Montreal, this (as then) last-generation version of Splinter Cell: Double Agent was developed for the Xbox, PS2, Gamecube and Wii. Opposed to it's counterpart it focuses purely on light and shadow based stealth and reuses many assets from it's predecessor Chaos Theory.Although both versions conceptually feature several of the same missions and locales, as well as their own individual ones, the level and art design are drastically different from each other.The online gamemode from past iterations isn't present in this version, and is substituted by a four mission co-op campaign and six player Spies vs. Spies multiplayer.StoryThe story of Double Agent revolves around Sam Fisher's breakdown after the death of his daughter. Faced with this hardship, Sam takes up an assignment to infiltrate an American-based terrorist group known as the JBA.Much of the game's story is told in past-tense by the means of a phone call taking place between Fisher and Assistant Director Williams, an NSA executive hired to watch over Lambert and Third Echelon in an effort to keep things in line. These conversations play before or after missions, over a rudimentary collection of images and video. These scenes can vary slightly depending on particular actions taken in the game, and occasionally coincide with other pre-rendered cutscenes, several of which are featured in both games.One ending exists in this version of Double Agent. Although the result of both games is Sam Fisher being on the run from the NSA, leading into Splinter Cell: Conviction, the events immediately prior play out entirely different from each other.GameplayGameplay in Double Agent is very similar to former titles, with the addition of a trust system gauging relationships between the JBA and NSA. This results in a need to balance trust between the two groups by performing optional objectives or making decisions in favor of one alignment. The standing on the trust meter also influences the equipment received for each mission.At two intervals in the game, Sam is tasked with objectives inside of the JBA compound; unlike the higher-gen version, these missions are not timed, and instead feature a balaclava-clad Sam Fisher operating around the headquarters in the cover of night. In these segments Sam is equipped with a compact launcher, which uses non-lethal ammunition like rubber bullets and tranquilizers, alongside the more standard gadgets. Here JBA members can be interrogated, and can make an effort to apprehend Sam if discovered, resulting in a QTE.Differences between versionsWhile the primary version of Double Agent heavily trimmed the interface, this version goes back to showing text boxes and visually indicating light and sound levels on the HUD. Much of the general interface is identical to Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Chaos Theory.Contrary to the Xbox 360, PS3 and PC version, the levels almost always opt for indoor or nighttime environments.William's role in the story is significantly more important, and has a more defined antagonistic quality.Hisham Hamza plays a bigger part by acting as Fisher's teammate in Iceland, rather than John Hodge.Both games utilize a fairly different set of gadgets and equipment.Money Train: a plot conceived by the JBA to hijack and secure a train in effort to steal the gold being transported (much in the vein of Pandora Tomorrow), and Snowbound Rooftops: the game's finale in New York City, are mission entirely unique to this version.This version features a full co-operative campaign, similar to that of Splinter Cell Chaos Theory, which can be played online (no longer available) and split-screen.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2077">The Mark of Kri</game><game id="37494">Assassin's Creed III</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/30036/1324475-splintercelldagiantbomb.jpg</image></root>