<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2612</id><name>Marvel vs. Capcom 2: New Age of Heroes</name><description>OverviewCable with a combo on the low end of what's possible in MvC2.Marvel vs. Capcom 2: New Age of Heroes is a 2D tag-team fighting game developed and released by Capcom for the arcades (under the NAOMI engine) on February 24, 2000. The fourth installment of the Marvel vs. Capcom crossover series (and sequel to Marvel vs. Capcom: Clash of Super Heroes), the game doubles the roster of the previous installment while adding new 3-on-3 gameplay and simplified controls (two punch buttons, two kick buttons, and two assist buttons). The game brings back the classic "assist attack" system (sans "partners") while adding a new "snapback" attack (a close-ranged attack that, if hit successfully, swaps the opponent's character with another). These additions, along with the over-the-top action and crazy combos, help the game maintain a prominent role in the tournament scene in the 00's.It was released for the Dreamcast and later ported to both the PlayStation 2 and the Xbox. At first, the Xbox version was to have Xbox Live on it, but because of a contract conflict, which said they could not alter the game at all, they had to remove that.XBLA  PSN VersionsMarvel vs. Capcom 2 arrived to Xbox LIVE Arcade, as part of the "Summer of Arcade" campaign, on July 29, 2009. The game was released to the Playstation Network as well on August 13, 2009. The price is 1200 Microsoft points or $14.99 on PSN. The PS3 and 360 versions by Foundation 9 and are based on the Dreamcast code.New FeaturesIt now features an optional visual filter that smooths out the graphics and new online modes. It includes Ranked Matches and the Quarter matches found in Super Street Fighter II Turbo HD Remix, which allows up to 4 people to watch  chat while two others fight. It also has widescreen support with the gameplay in a 4:3 field.No characters have to be unlocked in the game. All 56 characters are available from the get go.An exclusive demo for the PlayStation 3 was released on April 30 with six characters playable, Iron Man, Wolverine, Spider-Man, Ryu, Chun-Li, and Strider-Hiryu. Only local VS. mode was available for the demo.The PS3 version is also available via retail and includes:* Redemption Code for the full game* 8 page color manual with artwork and moves list* 1 month free subscription to Marvel Digital Comics ($9.99 value)* 2000 Capcom-Unity pointsThe retail version is $14.99 and is a Gamestop Exclusive.Playable CharactersThe game includes 56 playable characters (28 characters from the Marvel side and 28 characters from the Capcom side) Unlike the two previous installments of the Marvel vs. Capcom franchise, Marvel vs. Capcom 2: New Age of Heroes contain no hidden alternate versions of certain fighters. The final, unplayable boss in the game is Abyss, an original demon who must be defeated three times (in three forms).Capcom CharactersCharacterOriginal FranchiseAkumaStreet FighterAmingoMarvel vs. CapcomAnakarisDarkstalkersB. B. HoodDarkstalkersCammyStreet FighterCaptain CommandoCaptain CommandoCharlieStreet Fighter AlphaChun-LiStreet FighterDanStreet Fighter AlphaDhalsimStreet FighterFeliciaDarkstalkersGuileStreet FighterHayatoStar GladiatorJill ValentineResident EvilJinCyberbotsKenStreet FighterM. BisonStreet FighterMega ManMega ManMorriganDarkstalkersRollMega ManRuby HeartMarvel vs. CapcomRyuStreet FighterSakuraStreet Fighter AlphaServbotMega Man LegendsSonSonSon SonStrider HiryuStriderTron BonneMega Man LegendsZangiefStreet FighterMarvel CharactersCharacterOriginal FranchiseBlackheartGhost RiderCableX-MenCaptain AmericaCaptain America, AvengersColossusX-MenCyclopsX-MenDoctor DoomFantastic FourGambitX-MenHulkHulk, AvengersIcemanX-MenIron ManIron Man, AvengersJuggernautX-MenMagnetoX-MenMarrowX-MenOmega RedX-MenPsylockeX-MenRogueX-MenSabretoothX-MenSentinelX-MenShuma-GorathDoctor StrangeSilver SamuraiX-MenSpider-ManSpider-ManSpiralX-MenStormX-MenThanosAvengersVenomSpider-ManWar MachineIron ManWolverineX-Men</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2760">Art of Fighting</game><game id="617">NeoGeo Battle Coliseum</game><game id="16793">Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors</game><game id="18484">Killer Instinct</game><game id="7751">Art of Fighting Anthology</game><game id="800">Guilty Gear XX Λ Core</game><game id="8492">Capcom vs. SNK 2: Mark of the Millennium</game><game id="13999">Kizuna Encounter: Super Tag Battle</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="22820">Red Earth</game><game id="12125">Capcom Fighting Evolution</game><game id="10574">X-Men: Children of the Atom</game><game id="7527">Marvel Ultimate Alliance</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="9542">Night Warriors: Darkstalkers' Revenge</game><game id="10126">X-Men: Next Dimension</game><game id="3965">X-Men: Mutant Academy 2</game><game id="8899">Marvel Super Heroes in War of the Gems</game><game id="22879">Mega Man 2: The Power Fighters</game><game id="5964">The King of Fighters '99</game><game id="27853">Justice League: Heroes United</game><game id="28102">Kabuki Ittou Ryoudan</game><game id="21930">Touhou 7.5 - Immaterial and Missing Power</game><game id="21325">Touhou 10.5 - Scarlet Weather Rhapsody</game><game id="27857">Touhou Hisoutensoku - Choudokyuu Ginyoru no Nazo o Oe</game><game id="29779">BlazBlue Calamity Trigger Portable</game><game id="30399">Spider-Man: Shattered Dimensions</game><game id="30558">Sunday vs. Magazine: Shuuketsu! Choujou Daikessen</game><game id="17631">Groove on Fight: Gouketsuji Ichizoku 3</game><game id="34082">Skullgirls</game><game id="32161">Street Fighter X Tekken</game><game id="25247">Iron Man 2</game><game id="36274">Persona 4 Arena</game><game id="36947">Ougon Musou Kyoku Cross</game><game id="37959">Project X Zone</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1856047-box_mvc2.png</image></root>