<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26401</id><name>Ashes Cricket 2009</name><description>OverviewAshes Cricket 2009 is a Cricket game for the Xbox 360, PlayStation 3, PC and Wii. The 360, PS3 and PC versions were developed by Transmission Games. The Wii version was developed by Gusto Games. It features licensed teams from the England  Wales Cricket Board, the Cricket Australia Board and Marylebone Cricket Club. It features the full England  Australia cricket teams.Grounds from all Test playing nations are available apart from Bangladesh, with all 5 2009 Ashes Series grounds included in this. All test playing nations as well as Ireland and Kenya are present with rosters of early 2009 players; though only England and Australia are licensed.Multiple game modes are included, to allow players to play in different modern day series's of cricket, including The Ashes, Test Cricket, One-Day-International's, and Twenty20. Online multiplayer is also available through Xbox Live, PlayStation Network and Nintendo WiFi. There is a historical mode called Legend Mode, where players can play famous cricket matches from history. A create a player, team and tournament modes are also available.Commentary is provided from well known ex-cricketers: Tony Greig, Ian Bishop, Shane Warne, Ian Botham  Jonathan Agnew are all featured in the game.Wii VersionThe Wii version is dramatically different to the other consoles, having been developed specifically for the Wii by Gusto Games. This version uses the Wii Remote to allow the player to play cricket shots which are recreated in the game.PC System RequirementsMinimumWindows XP/Vista. (if running Windows Vista SP1 or above is recommended)DirectX 9.0c2 Ghz Pentium or AMD™ equivalent1 GB RAMGraphics Card: GeForce 6800 / Radeon X1600 or above Shader 3.0 256MB RAM cardDirectX Compatible Sound CardDual layer DVD-ROM Drive2.5 GB Hard Drive SpaceRecommendedWindows XP/Vista. (if running Windows Vista SP1 or above is recommended)DirectX 9.0c3 GHz Pentium 4 or AMD™ equivalent and above1.5GB RAMGraphics card: GeForce 8800GS  above, or Radeon X1900 series  aboveSound Card: Creative Sound Blaster X-Fi Sound Card.Dual Layer Compatible DVD-ROM Drive3 GB Hard Drive Space</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="46">Cricket</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13032">Cricket 2005</game><game id="12363">Cricket 2000</game><game id="4431">Cricket 97</game><game id="25475">Cricket 97: Ashes Tour Edition</game><game id="21668">Super International Cricket</game><game id="501">Allan Border's Cricket</game><game id="34254">Cricket Revolution</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1099/1063961-ashes_cricket_2009_uk_cover_ps3.jpg</image></root>