<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26416</id><name>Money Puzzle Exchanger</name><description>OverviewThe game features 8 different types of "blocks": 6 types based on Japanese coinage and 2 special blocks. Coins of the same denomination can be chained to convert them to coins of higher value; for example, if you place two 5 yen coins next to each other they will become a 10 yen coin, while 5 10 yen coins will convert to a 50 yen coin. This pattern continues up to 500 yen coins; two five-hundred yen coins placed next to each other will disappear, helping to clear the player's side and pushing down the coins on the opponent's side. If at any time coins touch the bottom of the screen, the player loses. As an additional note, any extra coins of the same type included in a chain (say you use 7 10 yen coins, equaling a total of 70 yen) will simply vanish, and you will get a 50 yen piece in return; As this is worth a score bonus, this makes for efficient clearing and scoring! As a side note, there are apparently some gameplay differences between the versions with slightly different titles; in one version the characters are all identical in traits except appearance; in the other they push the opponent's pieces down in different manners, ala Magical Drop.Coins1 yen coin5 yen coin10 yen coin50 yen coin100 yen coin500 yen coinSpecial BlocksThere are also two types of special blocks that have special effects on the playing area.ER Block: ER stands for "erase", and this blue ball does exactly that. When grabbed and thrown, it will erase any of the same types of coinage it touches that are on the screen.RU: RU stands for "rank up". These greenish balls will turn all coins of the value it touches to the next value up (ex., 100 yen coins will all become 500 yen coins!). Play ModesThe game features three modes of play: Story Mode, Solo Play, and Versus Play. Story mode simply goes through a character's story as you beat opponents; solo play is an endless mode where the player simply tries to clear coins for as long as they possibly can. Versus play allows a player to challenge another player to a match.CharactersNote: Only Sakura and Asahi are playable in story mode. All the other characters (members of the "Money Sisterhood") are usable in vs. mode. Most of the character's names are references to forms of currency or famous Japanese banks.Mitsukoshi Sakura/Exchanger (Exchanger is her transformed name)Likes: Depositing money, her balanceDislikes: Manual labor, repaymentHobbies: Saving moneyShe is a 17 year-old second year student at Kisaragi Girl's High School and the daughter of a bank president. She, like a number of other characters in the game, is a parody of the "magical girl" genre, specifically sailor moon in this case.Takashima Asahi/Debtmiser (Debtmiser is her transformed name)Likes: Dogs, cats, and birds.Dislikes: Her own personalityHobbies: FinancingShe is Sakura's friend. She is shy and introverted, but is a good person who freely lends money to others. She is also secretly the pretty soldier Debtmiser.Bill Bank/CoquettybouncerThe youngest child of the Bank Concern. He is severely overworked by his older sister, Note Bank. For some inscrutable reason he's dressed as a dog. Unlike the other characters, he doesn't have a full profile. Lulula Franc/CherrybiterLikes: Plush toysDislikes: VegetablesHobbies: Deceiving peopleShe seems nice, but is a liar. She is also a student at Kisaragi Girl's High, and has bought out a toy shop named "Moneysaurus" for her own amusement.Arashizaki En/EveryworkerLikes: Training, sweat, and working hardDislikes: Weak peopleHobbies: Exercise and workingYet another student at Kisaragi High, she loves sports and is a hard worker. She's only really a member of the Money Sisterhood for convenience. She also works at a 24 hour convenience store, "Moneymart".Seshil Pound/EldylaborLikes: Solving problemsDislikes: insanity and whipsHobbies: Browsing the internetUnsurprisingly, a student at Kisaragi. She likes to study, and really doesn't like her transformation at all.Sakata Blibov/MackermocallyA half-Russian teacher at Kisaragi Girl's Highschool. He found out what the girls were up to and wanted in on the action, as he thought it looked fun; he transforms in to the hero for justice, Mackermocally! For some reason he develops a strong kansai-ben when he transforms.Note Bank/MightdealerLikes: JewelryDislikes: People who fail herHobbies: FashionThe leader of the Bank Concern and Bill's older sister. She plans to ruin the world's coin market for her own personal gain. She gets very angry when people overestimate her age (she's 20) and is in love with Blibov.HaniwaA character who is obviously one of the famous kofun era ceramic figurines. He's a reference to a number of earlier Face games which featured a haniwa as the protagonist, notably "Hani in the Sky". He appears in the training mode in home ports.</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3827">Magical Drop</game><game id="2285">Bust-A-Move 2: Arcade Edition</game><game id="26412">Critter Crunch</game><game id="14761">Astropop</game><game id="10224">Magical Drop III</game><game id="7667">Magical Drop II</game><game id="34236">Mushihime-tama</game><game id="35868">Magical Drop V</game><game id="42721">Super Puzzle Platformer Deluxe</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2579/1895767-tumblr_lo9tnog0st1qbfiiuo1_500.jpg</image></root>