<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26422</id><name>Lunar: Silver Star Harmony</name><description>GameA remake of the beloved classic,   Lunar Silver Star-- Lunar tells a story filled with love, betrayal, and redemption.  This remake includes updated visuals, an updated interface, remastered music, remastered cut-scenes, and new cut-scenes to fill in story gaps. Hailed by critics as one of the greatest RPGs of all time, Lunar masterfully crafts an engrossing story, cinematics, and cut-scenes to create an experience to be had by all.DemoA Demo is available on the    PSN Network. If you import a completed demo save to the final game you will receive a special bonus item.  At the beginning of the game Luna recieves a slingshot from Alex's dad, but if you import the completed demo save Luna will instead receive Silver Darts that everyone can use. This will give you a great advantage to start out with as the Silver Darts inflict extra damage to the enemy. You can acquire this weapon later on in the game, if you decide not to play the demo first, by paying 26,000 silver.  AvailabilityThe game is available both digitally via the     PSN Network, and as a stand alone retail game. The retail version is a Limited Edition including the following bonus items: a soundtrack CD and a set of 13  exclusive "bromide" collector cards highlighting the girls of Lunar</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19938">The Legend of Heroes: A Tear of Vermillion</game><game id="5278">The Legend of Heroes III: Song of the Ocean</game><game id="6859">The Legend of Heroes II: Prophecy of the Moonlight Witch</game><game id="25694">Ys I &amp; II Chronicles</game><game id="19349">Breath of Fire III</game><game id="21624">Mana Khemia: Alchemists of Al-Revis</game><game id="7281">Astonishia Story</game><game id="11771">Brave Story: New Traveler</game><game id="2094">Final Fantasy II</game><game id="17905">PoPoLoCrois</game><game id="27372">Narisokonai Eiyuuden: Taiyou to Tsuki no Monogatari</game><game id="27501">Hexyz Force</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2375805-box_lunarssh.png</image></root>