<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26465</id><name>Shatter</name><description>OverviewShatter is a brick-breaker game developed by Sidhe Interactive. It was originally released exclusively on the PlayStation Network on July 23, 2009 but was subsequently followed by a PC release through Steam (and in retail for certain countries) on March 15, 2010. It takes the traditional Arkanoid/ Breakout formula and implements the additions of the "Sucking" and "Blowing" mechanic, allowing the player to alter's the ball's trajectory as it's travelling.Shatter was received to both critical and commercial acclaim, both for the game's innovative gameplay and engaging soundtrack. The game currently holds an 86% rating on Metacritic and the soundtrack, sold independently on the Bandcamp website of composer Jeremiah Ross a.k.a Module, has won several awards including Giant Bomb's Best Original Soundtrack of 2009.ModesStory ModePlayers battle through 90 stages, divided between 10 worlds, which consist of 7 waves, a boss battle and a bonus level.Boss RushIn this mode, players have to defeat all 10 bosses as quickly possible. This mode is locked until story mode is completed. Time is a factor if the player also wants to collect a trophy for defeating all 10 bosses in under 10 minutes.Bonus ModeThe player has to survive 3 bonus round types for as long as possible to try to better their score. Once all 3 types have been encountered in story mode, this mode is unlocked. A trophy is earned if the player gains 10 million points in this mode.Shatter DLC ( PSN)The additions present in the PC version of Shatter have been confirmed for the PSN version, via the Playstation Blog. This includes Endless, Endless Co-Op, Time Attack, and Time Attack Co-Op modes. It is set to release in 2010.Story ModeThe game pits you as Bat 1137, a 'bat' that is trying to escape an unknown facility. There are multiple levels that the player goes through in Story Mode, each with it's own theme and soundtrack.SoundtrackReleased alongside the game at a minimum of $9.99, a price which is interestingly more than the game itself, Shatter's soundtrack was a key component in the critical success of the game. Jeramiah Ross composed and recorded much of the game's electronic rock and retro beats, mixing them together with epic guitar solos and spacey vibes to create a fantastic soundtrack that fits the game. The soundtrack can be downloaded via the Sidhe website, and on iTunes. A physical copy has also released.1. Kinetic Harvest (6:36)2. Aurora (7:28)3. Granular Extractor (6:31)4. Krypton Garden (6:29)5. Freon World (7:29)6. Amethyst Caverns (5:15)7. Neon Mines (6:02)8. Argon Refinery (8:50)9. Xenon Home World (6:18)10. The End of the World (6:45)11. Boss Music (3:01)12. Homelands (Credits Music) (5:17)13. Glass Halls (Menu Music) (2:51)Steam ReleaseShatter was released on Steam ( PC) on March 15, 2010. The PC version comes with controller support and Steam achievements. This new version contains four new modes of play: Endless, Endless Co-Op, Time Attack, and Time Attack Co-Op. The co-operative modes are local multiplayer only. These features were rumoured to be added in the PS3 version as a downloadable pack, but that hasn't happened yet.PC System RequirementsOS: Windows XP SP3 or higherProcessor: 2.0 GHz single-core or dual-core (any speed)Memory: 512 MBHard Drive: 250 MB of free spaceGraphics: 128MB dedicated graphics processor with Shader Model 2 support (e.g. NVIDIA GeForce FX 5600 or ATI Radeon 9600)Sound: DirectX 9.0c compatible audio cardDirectX®: 9.0c</description><genres><genre id="45">Block-Breaking</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13049">Breakout</game><game id="15107">Arkanoid</game><game id="11099">Geometry Wars: Retro Evolved</game><game id="793">Super Stardust HD</game><game id="13779">Krakout</game><game id="23747">Peggle Nights</game><game id="30059">Hyperballoid HD</game><game id="24912">Magic Ball</game><game id="1055">Super Breakout</game><game id="35666">Wizorb</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/13158/1080425-gb.png</image></root>