<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2652</id><name>Disgaea 2: Cursed Memories</name><description>OverviewDisgaea 2: Cursed MemoriesDisgaea 2 is the sequel to the cult classic Disgaea: Hour of Darkness. It's a Tactical Strategy RPG, which builds upon it's predecessor in every way. However, some would argue that the story does not quite live-up to the original. The one thing that most Players notice and may find odd, is that the Main Character is not a general Warrior-type like in most RPG's, but rather a Monk-type Character. Adell uses fisticuff weapons instead of wielding a sword. The one thing to most be said about Disgaea 2 and the whole Franchise, in general, is it's staggering amount of replayability and how far the Player can push the game's numbers. Getting to Level 9999 is the goal of many Disgaea enthusiasts.PlotThe Overlord, Zenon, curse the lands of Veldime many years ago, turning all of it's inhabitants from Humans to Demons... all that is, except for one. This lone young man is named Adell. Adell has vowed to destroy Zenon and undo the curse, so that it may turn his family back to their former Human selves. Adell and his "Mom", a crazy Witch Summoner Demon Lady, attempt to summon Zenon to their Village so that Adell can finish him off the easy way. Unfortunately the experiment may have failed, as they summon instead, what they think, is Overlord Zenon's Daughter instead. Her name is Rozalin, and she proudly states that she is in-fact "Overlord Zenon's only Daughter." Adell then decides to go on a Quest to bring her back to her father and kill him at the same time, because, "that's just his style."Multiple EndingsDisgaea 2 has multiple endings. Some of these endings reveal massive story elements. It is possible to get bad endings part way through.Character ClassesStory Character Classes Adell - Demon Hunter/ Archer Guards/ Prism Black  Rozalin - Zenon's Child  Tink - Dirty Frog  Hanako - Adell's Sister  Taro - Rozy's Slave  Etna - Beauty Queen  Yukimari - Kunoichi  Axel - Dark Hero  Fubuki - Ninja MasterHumanoid Classessamurai and female fighterMale Fighter Lady Fighter Mage Skull Cleric Thief Archer Gunner Ninja Kunoichi Samurai Heavy Knight Sinner Geomancer Beastmaster Rune Knight MajinMonster ClassesPrinny Spirit Undead Orc Marionette Flora Beast Feline Dragon Winged Roc Succubus Aqua Demon Wood Golem Mystic Beast Rifle Demon Holy Dragon Dragon ZombieCameo Character Classes Laharl - Overlord  Flonne - Fallen Angel  Prinny Kurtis - Defender</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="451">Makai Kingdom: Chronicles of the Sacred Tome</game><game id="3731">Phantom Brave</game><game id="21355">Soul Nomad &amp; the World Eaters</game><game id="12719">Advance Wars</game><game id="7522">La Pucelle: Tactics</game><game id="19701">Stella Deus: The Gate of Eternity</game><game id="21222">GrimGrimoire</game><game id="5255">Advance Wars 2: Black Hole Rising</game><game id="14506">Ogre Battle 64: Person of Lordly Caliber</game><game id="771">Front Mission 4</game><game id="20571">Rondo of Swords</game><game id="23082">Super Robot Wars R</game><game id="23083">Super Robot Wars D</game><game id="22607">Super Robot Wars Alpha 2</game><game id="21244">Super Robot Wars W</game><game id="7259">Arc the Lad</game><game id="23481">Front Mission 2089: Border of Madness</game><game id="22722">Disgaea DS</game><game id="22847">Eternal Poison</game><game id="24220">Fire Emblem: Shadow Dragon</game><game id="20112">Sakura Wars: So Long, My Love</game><game id="4834">Suikoden Tactics</game><game id="24207">Growlanser II: The Sense of Justice</game><game id="17786">Growlanser Generations</game><game id="23693">Cross Edge</game><game id="26556">Trinity Universe</game><game id="1885">Summon Night 4</game><game id="3048">Summon Night 3</game><game id="31138">Global Defence Force Tactics</game><game id="27861">Shin Megami Tensei: Persona 3 Portable</game><game id="33450">VM Japan: Vantage Master - Mystic Far East</game><game id="29872">Dokapon DX</game><game id="36104">Card Hunter</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1832911-box_disgaea2.png</image></root>