<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26550</id><name>Fatal Inertia</name><description>Race Craft TypesPhoenix Class - Well balanced all roundersAurora Class - Fastest of all classesMercury Class - Lighter class with superior handling compared to other classesTitan Class - More fire-power and armourWeapons and ItemsFatal Inertia lets you use a variety of weapons during a race. All weapons can be fired backwards but may have a different affect if you do this. Weapons work like Mario Kart so the good weapons are given to people at the back of the race while only magnets and smoke bombs are given to position 1Magnets - These stick to opposing craft and explode after a set period. The victim can shake these off with a barrel roll. If a player uses these while there is no target ahead, the magnets can sometimes come back and attach to the userCluster Magnets - Similar to magnets but is a small ball of magnets that when within range will stick to a victim. These can also be shaken off but require more barrel rollsRocket - This can either be used to propel you forward faster if you fire it backwards. It lasts for about 3-5 seconds. If fired forward, it will attach to a victim and make them unstable by having the rocket thrust them in a weird angle. If the rocket cannot find a victim, it may attach to the userForce Blast - a bomb of sorts. When fired forwards will make opponents within the vicinity fly off course and if fired backwards works like a boost.Smoke Bomb - a bomb that leaves a cloud of smoke after impactCable - This is a cable that can be attached to an opponent. One end attaches to an opponent and the other can attach to the level geometry. It is used mainly for anchoring opponents to terrain but if the spiked end of the cable is released first, then it will attach you to the groundForce Field - A shield which blocks all other power upsEMP - Crafts within the area will lose thrust and manoeuvring capabilities for a small period of timeTime Dilator - This slows opponents down while you move at normal speed</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21285">Rollcage Stage II</game><game id="21146">Fatal Inertia EX</game><game id="20610">WipEout HD</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2323859-box_fi.png</image></root>