<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26649</id><name>Marvel Super Hero Squad</name><description>GameplayMarvel Super Hero Squad the game is split into two parts. Adventure mode and Battle mode. Adventure mode is where the player gets to pick one of six original squad members. This could be Iron man, Falcon, Wolverine, Hulk, Thor, or Silver Surfer. However, it will only be certain levels in the story that the player will get to be one of the original members of the squad.    For example, it might be an Hulk mission, the player will not be able to have Wolverine on their side instead they will have a secondary member with them. This could be Storm, Nightcrawler, Invisible Woman, or Thing. The game features drop-in, drop-out co-op game play. When playing single player, the A.I will take over your secondary character. Battle mode is where the player and three other friends can join together to fight each other. They can do a team based game, or go against each other in an all out free-for-all battle. The player can use the bad guys in battle mode too. You can pick between good guy or bad guy.    Plot    Doctor Doom has all the infinity fractals to take over the world, it is up to the super hero squad to stop him. The squad may have destroyed the sword, but that won't stop him from getting the pieces again. You must work as a team to stop Doctor Doom from conquering the world, it is time for your squad to "Hero Up!"     Secret CharacterTo unlock the secret character for the game, the player must collect all six of the secret tokens. Once unlocked, the secret character turns out to be Spider-man. </description><genres><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13087">X-Men: Legends</game><game id="7527">Marvel Ultimate Alliance</game><game id="16327">Justice League Heroes</game><game id="21559">Marvel Ultimate Alliance 2</game><game id="7676">X-Men: Legends II - Rise of Apocalypse</game><game id="31852">Marvel Super Hero Squad Online</game><game id="30399">Spider-Man: Shattered Dimensions</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1982781-box_mshs.png</image></root>