<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26699</id><name>LEGO Indiana Jones 2: The Adventure Continues</name><description>Overview    A scene from Lego Indiana Jones and the Kingdom of the Crystal Skull.     Lego Indiana Jones 2: The Adventure Continues is the second              Lego Indiana Jones game from             Traveller's Tales and            LucasArts. The game was released for the           Wii,          Xbox 360,         PlayStation 3,        Nintendo DS,       PlayStation Portable, and      PC on November 17, 2009 in North America. The game includes many new features, including a level editor (which can be used to edit any levels, including completed story levels). The Adventure Continues contains levels from the first three films (completely new levels, no levels from the first Lego Indiana Jones), as well as levels from the latest film, Indiana Jones and the Kingdom of the Crystal Skull. Of note is the fact that the PS3 version of the game is compatible with PSP remote play. Also of note is LucasArts's message on   Twitter on November 23, 2009 stating that they are working on a patch for the PS3 and Xbox 360 versions of the game that would allow for online co-op.The game received fairly decent scores, with most critics praising the many levels the game offered, the diversity of the editor, the soundtrack, and the replay value. Criticisms included repetitiveness, lack of online features, lack of secrets, and the hub world. Lego Indiana Jones 2: The Adventure Continues (PS3/360 versions) respectively have a 70% and 71% on Metacritic and a 69% and 73% on Game Rankings.Gameplay    Cue theme song.     The majority of the gameplay remains largely similar to LucasArts's other     Lego games. Players control a Lego figure in a variety of levels based on the scene in the movie. Combat with other Lego figures is simple; each character has a weapon (or can pick up a weapon), which they then use to attack enemies. In addition to combat, there is a large focus on puzzle-solving and exploring the (mostly) linear levels. Puzzles take advantage of each characters unique abilities, including archeology, digging, pre-equipped weapons, etc. By exploring levels, it's possible to find collectibles which unlock other bonuses in the game.The largest new feature introduced in Lego Indiana Jones is the level creation (and editing) mechanic. As previously mentioned, after completing a story level, the option to freely edit it is opened up. In addition to that, there is a relatively wide level creation mode, allowing players to put a variety of blocks, enemies, and set up unique levels.  The new split-screen mode.     Another new feature of Lego Indiana Jones 2 is the way that split-screen play has been tweaked. Instead of forcing both players to be within a certain distance of one another, the game now seamlessly splits away when players get too far apart, and then merges when they get closer. Also changed is the hub world. Instead of having free access to all unlocked levels, players now have to find the pathways to the next level by doing certain tasks.  System RequirementsMinimum System RequirementsProcessor: Intel Pentium IV at 1.8 Ghz / AMD Athlon XP 2200 Video Card: 256 MB – Nvidia GeForce FX 5800GT / ATI Radeon X1300Memory: 256 MB for Windows XP / 512 MB for Windows VistaHard Drive: 5 GB of free Hard Disk SpaceOperating System: Microsoft Windows XP / Windows VistaSound Card: 9.0c Compatible sound cardDirect X: 9.0cOptical Drive: DVD-ROM Drive Recommended System RequirementsProcessor: Intel Pentium IV at 3.2GHz / AMD Athlon XP 3100 Video Card: 512 MB – Nvidia Geforce 9200M / ATI Radeon HD 3400 SeriesMemory: 512 MBHard Drive: 5 GB of free Hard Disk SpaceOperating System: Microsoft Windows XP / Windows VistaSound Card: 9.0c Compatible sound cardDirect X: 9.0cOptical Drive: DVD-ROM Drive </description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6781">The Simpsons Game</game><game id="26753">LEGO Harry Potter: Years 1-4</game><game id="32196">Marvel Super Hero Squad: The Infinity Gauntlet</game><game id="36898">LEGO Batman 2: DC Super Heroes</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2284686-box_legoij2.png</image></root>