<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26708</id><name>Dementium II</name><description>OverviewDementium II, originally developed by Renegade Kid and published by SouthPeak for the Nintendo DS is the second very well received horror FPS game in the Dementium franchise.A PC version was announced in August of 2012; it is being developed by Memetic Games with Digital Tribe Games taking over publishing duties. The PC versionPlotThe game begins five weeks after the events of the first game with William Redmoor. William awakes in the Bright Dawn Treatment center located in Michigan in the United States. William awakens after having brain surgery. Shortly after he is brought to his cell, the world shifts into an evil world. By traversing the evil world, he escapes his cell. Soon after, the world shifts again and this happens all throughout the game. He soon meets the Doctor who slowly reveals more of what happens but remains hostile to William throughout the game.WeaponsFlashlight - Not a weapon per say, but used to light the way and find hidden enemies in the dark hallways and can be carried at the same time as one handed weapons.Shank - A makeshift prison knife. This is the first weapon players encounter in the game.Revolver - A standard gun with a six shot clip size.Sledgehammer - A strong but slow melee weapon that can be used to clear away obstacles such as boarded up doorways, in addition to clearing away enemies.Shotgun - A double barrel shotgun with two shells chambered. It is more effective when it comes to close range targets.Assault Rifle - Capable of shooting multiple rounds for an effective attack.Flamethrower - this makeshift weapon is created when players combine an aerosol can and a lighter.Dynamite - Useful for taking out a large enemies or a group of enemies.Mysterious Relic - A powerful boomerang that returns to the player after each throw.Buzz Saw - A powerful medical saw.Changes from the First GameMelee weapons are able to break down barriers to places that where once blocked.The map shows where a player has been before and where barriers are.The Buzz Saw over heats.Players are now able to crouch and jump.Enemies do not respawn when a player leaves the room.Players are able to hold a one handed weapon with the flashlight.New weapons.There is a much larger selection of music.New enemies.A much higher polygon count.A much larger variety of environments.A much easier saving system, players can save manually.There is a survival mode.Players are now able to pick up medicine you find, rather then only using it immediately when they find it.ReceptionThe game has received very high reviews from many companies praising the games graphics, and gameplay. The biggest issue critics have with the game is replayability and how short the game is. It can supposedly take a seasoned First Person Shooter player less than 5 hours to beat the whole game. The battle music was also criticized because it is very short and loops, however the rest of the music is praised as being original and keeps to the games horror elements.PC System RequirementsOS: Windows XP, Vista, 7Processor: 2 GHzMemory: 512MBHard Disk Space: 150MBVideo Card: Shader Model 3.0 requiredDirectX®: 9.0cSupports Keyboard/Mouse and 360 Game Pad controls</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21507">Moon</game><game id="25713">C.O.R.E.</game><game id="27137">Nanashi no Game</game><game id="27214">Nanashi no Game Me</game><game id="42032">Cult County</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2120433-box_dem2.png</image></root>