<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26713</id><name>Sally's Salon</name><description>Overview Sally's Salon is a salon management game that plays similar to        Diner Dash. Sally's Salon was released on the Browser, Nintendo DS, and iPhone as well as an updated version titled Sally's Salon Luxury Edition for Windows Phone 7 and iPad.  Gameplay       Sally's Salon plays much like other time managing games such as: Diner Dash, Cake Mania, and Star Wars Cantina. Customers will walk through the door of Sally's Salon and want various services. These services desired will be displayed by a bubble above the customers head.  Services Provided Hair WashingHair StylingHair CuttingHair ColoringHair Drying Eyebrow StylingWhile customers are waiting to be served they will slowly lose their satisfaction which is displayed as a series of hearts. The more hearts the customer has remaining when they pay the more the tip amount will be. If the customer loses too many hearts they will get angry and leave the shop.  Upgrades   One of the various upgrades available     In between days working in the shop the player can apply various upgrades. There are different categories, such as: Waiting Room Additions - These additions will help keep the waiting customers happy.Station Additions - These can either be more stations or upgrades to current stations to make them work faster.Hire Assistants - Assistants can also be hired to help lighten the work load.Windows Phone 7 Release On June 24, 2011 Sally's Salon was released on the   Windows Phone 7 platform under the name Sally's Salon: Luxury Edition. There are some upgrades to this version such as enhanced graphics, new customer types, and five new locations. This version of Sally's Salon also contains  Xbox Live features such as achievements and leaderboards.</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17228">Cake Mania</game><game id="10315">Diner Dash</game><game id="22423">Wedding Dash</game><game id="24658">Burger Island</game><game id="38335">Dead Hungry Diner</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8257/1040515-sallys_salon_ds_ninte_r72456.jpg</image></root>