<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26777</id><name>Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 2: The Siege of Spinner Cay</name><description>Overview Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 2: The Siege of Spinner Cay is the second part of the Telltale's series of episodic Monkey Island games. It continues directly on from the first episode,  Launch of the Screaming Narwhal. It follows the adventures of  Guybrush Threepwood, Mighty Pirate™ Plot The story continues from where the previous episode left off with Guybrush Threepwood being held at sword-point by a mystery assailant, who is quickly revealed to be  Morgan Leflay, Mighty Pirate Hunter™   who has been hired by the  Marquis de Singe to obtain Guybrush's Pox infected hand. Morgan slices off Guybrush's hand, and leaves to collect her reward, while Guybrush replaces his hand with a hook.  An unfortunate mishap during the attack damaged the mast, and forced Guybrush and shipmate  Reginald van Winslow to dock at the Spinner Cay, of the Jerkbait Islands to complete repairs. Upon arriving he discovers his wife,  Elaine Marley overseeing an argument between  McGillicutty, a local pirate who has become infected by the Pox of LeChuck, and Chieftain Beluga, leader of the Vaycaylians, a race of mer-folk who hold the secret to curing the Pox of LeChuck.   Elaine explains that the Vaycaylians have three secret artefacts (the Wise Turtle, the Noble Seahorse and the Cranky Fish) that are the secret to locating La Esponja Grande, the cure to the Pox of LeChuck, and Guybrush must find these artefacts. She goes on to tell Guybrush that  LeChuck is a changed man, is no longer evil and will assist Guybrush in obtaining the items.  After obtaining the items, Guybrush discovers that McGillicutty has kidnapped Chieftain Beluga and is laying siege to the Jerkbait Islands. Elaine, Guybrush and LeChuck form a plan to rescue the MerLeader and execute it with precision. The Chieftain explains that the artefacts are used to summon sea creatures that guide ships to La Esponja Grande and Guybrush sets sail in order to follow these creatures. LeChuck decides to stay behind in order to rehome the monkeys from his ship, and Elaine stays with him to help.  While following the sea creatures, Guybrush is paid another visit from Morgan LeFlay, who has once again been hired by the Marquis, this time to capture and bring back Guybrush alive. Just as she is about bring Guybrush in, a giant manatee comes out of the water and swallows the ship whole.  PC Requirements Operating System: Microsoft® Windows® XP/Vista/Windows 7Processor: 2.0 Ghz or better (3 GHz Pentium® 4 or equivalent recommended)Memory: 512 MB RAM (1GB recommended)Hard Disk Space: 310 MBVideo Card: 64 MB DirectX® 8.1 compliant video card (128 MB recommended)Sound Card: DirectX® 8.1 sound deviceDirectX® Version: DirectX® Version 9.0c or better (DirectX updater included)Controller Support: Yes    No internet connection required to play         </description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6049">Sam &amp; Max Save the World</game><game id="27084">Strong Bad's Cool Game for Attractive People</game><game id="29474">Sam &amp; Max: The Devil's Playhouse</game><game id="30008">Sam &amp; Max Episode 301: The Penal Zone</game><game id="30370">Sam &amp; Max Episode 302: The Tomb of Sammun-Mak</game><game id="4889">Rent-a-Hero</game><game id="30372">Sam &amp; Max Episode 303: They Stole Max's Brain</game><game id="30373">Sam &amp; Max Episode 304: Beyond the Alley of the Dolls</game><game id="7344">Sam &amp; Max Episode 5: Reality 2.0</game><game id="32592">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 1: It's About Time</game><game id="33414">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 2: Get Tannen!</game><game id="33415">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 3: Citizen Brown</game><game id="33416">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 4: Double Visions</game><game id="33417">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 5: OUTATIME</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4938/1111403-talesofmi.png</image></root>