<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26786</id><name>Halo: Reach</name><description>OverviewThe player's companions, making up the rest of the elite Noble Team.Halo: Reach is a first-person shooter developed by Bungie and published by Microsoft for the Xbox 360 on September 14, 2010. It is a direct prequel to Halo: Combat Evolved and chronicles the destruction of Reach, a world used as headquarters for the United Nations Space Command, in the late summer of 2552. Players control the customizable Spartan-312, known as Noble Six, in an elite team of Spartan super-soldiers known as Noble Team.The game is built off of the same engine used in Halo 3 and Halo 3: ODST, having full feature parity while including new features and improving existing ones. A new ranking system allows players to earn "credits" (cR) by playing both single-player and multi-player games, which both tracks their rank and allows them to further customize their Spartan armor.Players who owned a copy of Halo 3: ODST were invited to a multiplayer beta of Halo: Reach, which ran from May 3, 2010 to May 20, 2010. (Though an internal group had access beginning on April 29, 2010) The beta included four maps (Boneyard, Overlook, Powerhouse, and Sword Base) and a variety of new and existing gametypes. Microsoft promoted Halo: Reach through viral marketing campaigns "Birth of a Spartan" and "Remember Reach". The game was also promoted by Mountain Dew and Doritos via a special sweepstakes, in which players win the game, Xbox 360, or promotional material such as a working replica Mongoose ATV.Halo: Reach is the last Bungie-developed game in the Halo franchise. Now 343 Industries holds the title, with their first original entry in the series being Halo 4.GameplayHalo: Reach remains very close in style to its predecessors in terms of movement and aiming. The combination of regenerating health (in which health regenerates up to the nearest third) and regenerating shields returns from Halo: Combat Evolved, requiring players to pick up health packs when needed. Unlike the previous Halo games, shields now must be fully depleted in order for players to take health damage (though certain attacks negate it). The ability to dual wield weapons has been removed altogether (though A.I. Elites sometimes akimbo Plasma Rifles).Armor AbilitiesNew to Halo: Reach is the concept of Armor Abilities, which grant skills that can be activated by pressing a certain button (left bumper by default). This is a general replacement of equipment from Halo 3, though the Bubble Shield returns as the Drop Shield Armor Ability. In Campaign levels, the player starts with the Sprint ability, and can only replace it by finding armor abilities throughout the level. In all other modes, the player's armor ability is determined by which loadout they use. Each armor ability have different cooldown timers that prevent the player from using the ability until it has recharged fully or to a specific percentage.Sprint - Causes players to run faster for a short period of time. However, this lowers their weapon, preventing them from firing from the hip.Evade - Causes players to perform a quick roll that breaks lock-on from certain weapons.Armor Lock - Causes players to become completely invulnerable (at the cost of being immovable and unable to fire weapons). Enemies close to the player have their shields removed from the EMP burst.Jet Pack - Propels player into the air (until it runs out of fuel/needs to recharge) .Active Camo - Makes the player nearly invisible. However, the faster they move, the more visible they are. Active Camo also disrupts enemy radar (along with the player's radar) with extra random blips. Audio becomes muffled as well.Hologram - Creates a hologram of the player which can be used to distract enemies. The hologram walks wherever the player has their reticle pointed at and disappears after being fired upon too much (or after a certain amount of time).Drop Shield - Creates a blue-tinted bubble shield around the player's location, blocking all weapon fire. The shield also heals the player and all teammates inside, and can be destroyed by taking too much damage.LoadoutsLoadouts in multiplayer and Firefight modes determine which armor ability, weapons, and grenades the player can start with. They can be switched during the respawn window or during the start of the match. Loadouts cannot be customized for matchmaking, as they are restricted into each gametype. Players can only choose from up to five loadouts at a time. In Invasion gametypes, Spartans and Elites can have their own loadout selection, which change according to how far the game has progressed. OPlayable ElitesUnlike Halo 2 and Halo 3, in which picking an Elite is a pure aesthetic choice, playable Elites in Halo: Reach are now faster, stronger, and bigger than Spartans. They do not need to use health packs, as their health fully regenerates. Because of these differences, Elites are only playable in Elite Slayer or Invasion (in the Elite team).AssassinationNew to Halo: Reach, holding down the melee button when attacking someone from behind triggers a third-person animation, depicting the player silently killing the enemy with a knife or plasma sword, depending on their species. Neither player is invulnerable during this animation, and quick players can either rescue those who are being assassinated or steal the kill by killing the player being assassinated. A assassination can change or not even happen if you aren't looking at the right angle.Weapon ReticlesAll weapons in Halo: Reach are now subject to reticle bloom. The reticle now gets larger as a weapon is repeatedly fired, showing their worsened accuracy. In order to maintain consistent accuracy, players must wait for the reticle to return to normal size after a short delay. Crouching reduces this bloom. Certain weapons also have a " ghost reticle", which assists players by showing how far ahead the player needs to aim to hit a target.Space CombatNew to Halo: Reach is the concept of space combat. In two sections of "Long Night of Solace", players pilot a YSS-1000 space craft (known as a Sabre), fighting Banshees, Seraphs, and Phantoms before disabling a Corvette. The Sabre is very mobile, similar to the Banshee, and have both regenerating health and shields. Players can choose between a machine gun cannon and homing missile launchers.WeaponsUNSC WeaponsDesignated Marksman Rifle (DMR) - A mid to long ranged single shot rifle. It takes 5 shots to kill a fully-shielded Spartan and 6 shots to kill an Elite. Essentially a superior version of the old Battle Rifle.M6C Magnum - Like its Halo:CE counter part it can be very lethal. Takes 5 shots to kill a spartan and 6 to kill an elite. This is a mid to close range weapon. It has a higher rate of fire than the DMR but it is less accurate and more subject to reticle bloom.MA5C Assault Rifle - Very similar to the model in Halo 3, except that it now has weapon bloom, and short bursts are more accurate at long range.M41 Rocket Launcher - Similar to Halo 3, yet the vehicle targeting from Halo 2 is back (only against ground vehicles). Also immune to shield pop.M45 Tactical Shotgun - Farther reach than the shotguns in previous Halo games as not all shots stay within the reticle, immune to the requirement of a shield pop at close range.M319 Grenade Launcher - If it hits its target it explodes. If it does not it bounces around like a frag for a short delay, then explodes. If you hold the trigger after you fire it will act as a remote detonation and explode when you release the trigger. The grenade also lets out a small EMP blast disabling jet packs, vehicles and the such.SRS99D Sniper Rifle - Appears the same as Halo 3, now has a weapon bloom effect that appears to be primarily as an indicator of when the next shot can be fired. Immune to the shield pop requirement.H-165 FOM (Target Locator) - After a charge time and orbital bombardment comes from the sky and destroys anything in its radius. Can be used to paint either a wide area or individual targets. Only available in Campaign or Firefight modes.Covenant WeaponsPlasma Repeater - The Covenant version of the assault rifle. It sends out a steady stream of plasma. Fire rate slows as it heats up but never overheats, as fire rate slows, accuracy increases. Pressing the reload button will cool it down and bring it back up to speed. Able to be partially cooled, and cooling can occur during melees and grenade throws.Plasma Launcher - It fires off 1 to 4 rounds of plasma bombs depending on how long you hold the trigger: The plasma will lock on to both people and vehicles with a similar lock on as a needler. The shots stick to people and vehicles like plasma grenades.Focus Rifle - If the beam rifle and the sentinel beam had a baby this would be it. It a zoomable laser that drains health and shields very quickly. At the current build, it takes about 1.5 seconds to kill a target.Needle Rifle - Covenant equivalent to the DMR. Fires very long needles, if three needles stick to an unshielded opponent, a super-combine explosion occurs like the needler, it is a one-shot headshot kill on an unshielded opponent as well. It is less inaccurate than the DMR when fired quickly, but does less damage with each individual shot.Plasma Pistol - Now carries an area of effect component that allows the charged shot to hit multiple targets. It takes from 7 to 10 shots to kill a fully shielded Spartan player.Needler - Improved tracking compared to it's Halo 3 version. Also features the "ghost reticle" effect. Shields must be down before a super combine will occur.Energy Sword - Similar to Halo 3, but it can now be countered by a normal melee strike.Concussion Rifle - An Elite equivalent of the Brute Shot, fires a large ball of plasma that explodes on impact.Plasma Rifle - The iconic Covenant weapon from all of the past Halo games returns in Reach.Gravity Hammer - No changes from Halo 3.Brute Spike Rifle (Spiker) - A returning weapon from Halo 3. No noticeable changes made. It is good in close range for taking down shields, though short, controlled bursts are recommended for medium to long range. Its projectiles have a slight arc, so you should aim higher when firing at longer ranged targets.Fuel Rod Cannon - Covenant equivalent to the rocket launcher. Fires 5 rounds before needing reloading. Its shots are capable of bouncing off of surfaces.VehiclesUNSC VehiclesWarthog: Classic Halo vehicle, mostly used for offensive maneuvers. It can carry one driver, a gunner and a passenger. It's armed with either a M41 12.7mm LAAG chain gun, a M68 25mm ALIM canon, or finally a M79 65mm MLRS rocket launcher. The chain gun now overheats after extensive use and has a speed reduction of 25 km/h.Scorpion: A tank that makes up in power what it lacks in speed. It disposes of a M512 90mm canon as well as M257 7.62mm secondary gun turret.Falcon: The UH-144 is a versatile, transverse-rotor multipurpose utility helicopter. Two Falcons can transport a fully-equipped infantry squad faster than any previous system, and provide overwhelming support fire, in most weather conditions.Mongoose: The high speed, light weight troop transport returns. With Forge, players can now change the base color of the Mongoose depending on which team color it spawns with.Pelican: Transports more soldiers than a Falcon (10 instead of 3) and has room for a vehicle. This bird doesn't have any sort of weapons.Sabre: A Space superiority fighter, it transports both a pilot and a radar expert and uses a heavy cannon and Medusa missiles.Longsword: The previous generation of space superiority fighter, can also serve as a bomber while in atmosphere.Covenant VehiclesGhost: Minor aesthetic revisions, but otherwise unchanged from Halo 3. Still equipped with 2 plasma canons with little protection for the pilot.Wraith: No changes from Halo 3. Fires plasma mortars and has a plasma canon. Its weakness is its backside.Banshee: Aesthetic overhaul, otherwise unchanged from Halo 3. A new Banshee, the space Banshee, can now go in space.Spirit: The original Covenant dropship. It is capable of carrying up to 30 infantry and 2 vehicles. It is armed with one heavy plasma auto-cannon.Revenant: A cross between the Ghost and a Wraith and about the size of a Warthog, this pink beast is fast and furious with mobile plasma artillery. A second seat is available, though there isn't anything for the passenger to do. Like the Ghost, the crew has very little protection.Seraph: A Covenant space superiority fighter that has great handling as well as powerful shields. It's armed with 2 heavy plasma cannons.MultiplayerA fight between a Spartan and an Elite onlineBungie has gone to great lengths to continue the evolution of the multiplayer gameplay expected from a Halo game. That evolution involves many of the changes detailed above. Halo: Reach multiplayer contains Armor Abilities that modify the Spartan or Elite armor allowing for different style of play from each player. Additionally, Reach brings back the idea of Halo 2's Y menu with the addition of Active Rosters. Most multiplayer maps were actually designed and then placed into campaign. Elites return to multiplayer with very different characteristics. Most noticeably, Elites are significantly bigger than Spartans - for example, in a crouched position, they are nearly as tall as a standing Spartan. In addition, Elites default run speed is almost as fast as a Spartan using the Sprint Armor Ability. Further differences from previous Halo games MP include, Spartan non-regenerative health, Elite regenerative health, and species specific Armor Abilities and Loadouts. Despite pre-release rumors, multiplayer is not strictly class based, however, the addition of Loadouts, granting players the ability to choose what Armor Ability and weapons they can start the match and re-spawn with, makes it very close to a class based system.Competitive Multiplayer MapsAnchor 9 (Noble Map Pack) - A small map set in a UNSC space station for refueling and rearming various ships. The outer portion of the map is actually in space and features reduced gravity compared to the rest of the map. It is optimized for 4v4 play and is reminiscent of Halo 3's "The Pit" map.Battle Canyon (Anniversary Map Pack) - A remake of the popular Halo 2 map Beaver Creek. While most of Battle Canyon is a faithful recreation of the previous incarnation of the map, there are some notable changes in the geometry. Tunnels have been added at either end of the creek in the center of the map, and small caves have been added behind each base.Boardwalk - A long map used in almost all matchmaking playlists for various gametypes.Boneyard - The map is specifically designed for the new Invasion gametype, which is speculated to be a 6v6 variant featuring one team of Spartans against one team of Elites. It is a large map that allows for areas to be progressively opened as the match progresses. The map is set around the construction yard of a UNSC space frigate.Breakneck (Anniversary Map Pack) - A remake of Headlong from Halo 2.Breakpoint (Noble Map Pack) - The largest of the first three DLC maps is set in a cliff-side UNSC research installation near a Forerunner artifact. It is designed around the Invasion gametype, but will also support Big Team Battle. The Invasion scenario puts the Spartans on defense against the Elites, which are on offense.Condemned (Defiant Map Pack) - A medium-sized indoor map set in a Human space station overlooking the battle of Reach from orbit. Best suited for Team Slayer and small-scale objective gametypes. Contains a zone of reduced gravity in the center of the map, similar to Anchor 9.Countdown - This symmetrical map is set in a UNSC base and features a shotgun, Concussion Rifle, and Energy Sword.Highlands (Defiant Map Pack) - A large-scale outdoor map set in a Spartan training facility on Reach. Used primarily in Big Team gametypes.High Noon (Anniversary Map Pack) - A remake of Hang 'Em High from Halo: CE.Penance (Anniversary Map Pack) - A remake of Damnation from Halo: CE.Powerhouse - A former hydroelectric station that has since been put to use by the UNSC military. Powerhouse is designed to support small-team games, such as Slayer. The default map variant features plenty of weapon variety. There are several DMRs, Magnums, Plasma Pistols, Needlers, and Needle Rifles scattered about the map. There are also some important power weapons available: a Gravity Hammer, a Focus Rifle, and a Rocket Launcher.Reflection - A remake of Ivory Tower from Halo 2.Ridgeline (Anniversary Map Pack) - A remake of Timberland from Halo PC.Solitary (Anniversary Map Pack) - A remake of Prisoner from Halo: CE. The new version of the map contains gravity lifts in place of ladders, and adds a few new corridors in the upper levels of the map for increased movement options.Spire - The game on Spire relies heavily on air combat. It has 16 player Invasion.Swordbase - With a design inspired by a pair of fan favorite maps from Halo: Combat Evolved, Prisoner and Boarding Action, this map is small and asymmetrical -- perfectly-suited for Slayer and one-sided Objective matches. There are three power weapons available for players to fight over: an Energy Sword, a Plasma Launcher, and a Sniper Rifle.Tempest (Noble Map Pack) - A mid-sized map, set on the Halo ring, that supports almost every gametype and size. It is reminiscent of Halo 3's Valhalla and features functional symmetry, vehicles and numerous power weapons.Zealot - A Covenant themed map drawing map/aesthetic design cues from Midship, though is significantly different in layout. The largest difference being the large third floor that takes place in space. This allows for zero-gravity combat and quick travel from one side of the map to the other.The ArenaRanked matches in Halo 3 were plagued with boosters - high level players who would create second accounts to start out at rank 1 and take advantage of poorer players on their way back up the ladder to level 50. To prevent that problem from happening in Reach Bungie has replaced ranked matches with a new playlist - the Arena.The Arena is broken up into month long seasons. Each season players can place within one of 5 divisions. The divisions are Onyx, Gold, Silver, Bronze, and Iron. The players division rank for each season will stay with their gaming history. In interviews Bungie has compared players divisional placement history to the stats on the back of a baseball card. This provides an incentive to stay with one account so not to lose that history. Moreover, divisional assignments are made rather quickly, so a high level player will be playing other high level players within just a few days of the start of a new season.To place in a division players will have to play a minimum number of matches over a minimum number of days. Players need to complete 3 Arena matches in a day in order to receive a Daily Ranking. The player is assigned to a division after receiving 3 daily rankings.The players daily ranking will be based on the three best matches they played during that day. And the seasonal ranking will be based on the players three best daily rankings throughout the month. Therefore, once your divisional assignment is complete, you can only climb in the rankings. Once your divisional assignment is made no amount of bad play can lower your ranking, but a day or two of great play can increase your ranking.The players ranking for each match will be based on how well they play as a member of a team. No longer will assists and K/D ratios be discounted in favor of pure kills. A player with 0 kills, 5 assists and 5 deaths will receive a higher ranking than the player who got 20 kills, no assists, and 20 deaths. Being on a winning team still matters, but now if you are the only player on the losing team that went positive, you’ll be rewarded and may even get a higher rating than some under performing members of the winning team.Forge 2.0Welcome to Forge WorldForge has seen significant changes from the forge mode in Halo 3. The mode remains purely an object editor without terrain editing. However, the built-in structures allow one to create much more complicated levels than Halo 3's Sandbox or Foundry. The most important new feature is the ability to change an objects physical property from normal (object is affected by gravity like Halo 3), fixed (object is not affected by gravity), and phased (object now has no collision detection and can be pushed through walls and other objects). Each piece has further useful settings such as increasing the effective radius and shape of a teleporter or changing the color of the object to match team specifications. Several of maps that come on disc are direct remakes of older Halo maps, and each shows the variety of maps that can be produced in the new Forge.On-disc Forge World Map VariantsHemorrhage - Coagulation/ Blood Gulch remake.Paradiso - Unique map created on The Island in Forge World.Pinnacle - Remake of Ascension from Halo 2.The Cage - A map originally intended for Halo: CE, The Cage is a precursor to Lockout and Guardian and features many of the same design elements, such as narrow walkways and long sight lines.Asylum - Remake of Sanctuary, a Halo 2 map.Grifball Court - A standard arena court for the popular community variant Grifball, built in the Coliseum section of Forge World.Patch added Forge World Map VariantsAtomCliffhangerMultiplayer MatchmakingArena - A set of playlists, such as Free-for-All and Team Slayer that are similar to the Ranked Playlists of the Halo 3. The Arena uses a new rating system that counts other factors than wins to rank the player in 5 divisions in month long seasons. Players can move up or down in the season divisions, and play players in their division. They are then ranked in their division, and to qualify for a "daily ranking" players can also play a certain number of matches in a day.Active Roster - Active Roster takes much of the information that was in the Halo 3 players' profiles under "Halo 3 Party" and puts it on the main menus. This tells the player his/her friends' current parties, games being played in, score and remaining time.Queue Joining - Allows the player to wait in a lobby for a friend, rather than wait for a match to end to join a friend, as in Halo 3, or actually join the match, as in Modern Warfare 2.Veto 2.0 - Gives the players three maps and gametypes to choose from in the lobby for the players to vote on.New Party-Up System - After a match, all players are kept in a lobby to move into the next match together, rather than looking for new players every time. There is an opt-out to still go into a brand new lobby.New Preferences System - The game now has a preferences system for Chattiness, Motivation, Teamwork, and TonePersistent StatsHalo: Reach improves upon the persistent experience of Halo 3.Experience SystemThe experience system used in Halo: Reach uses "Credits" (abbreviated to cR), which can be earned in a variety of ways in all game modes (after finishing the match):Game Completion - Completing the match (or exiting out of a non-matchmaking match) earns all players the same amount of cR. (Which varies according to game mode and match duration)Commendations - Commendations are given by earning medals (given under special circumstances) in the match. Players also earn cR through special awards (known formally as Commendations) that are tracked among all games the player has played on that mode (Campaign, Multiplayer Matchmaking, and Firefight Matchmaking).Challenges - Each day brings four new Daily Challenges, which gives players a specific task to perform (such as completing a Campaign level on a certain difficulty with certain skulls on or killing a certain number of players in Matchmaking). Each week also brings one Weekly Challenge, which gives a harder, more demanding challenge.Slot Machine - Matchmaking only. A random bonus is given to each player, usually around 100 cR.CreditsPlayers are ranked according to how much "Credits" they collect throughout their entire Halo: Reach career. Buying things from the Armory does not reduce the player's amount of experience or rank. Once players reach certain ranks, more gear is unlocked (or uncovered) in the Armory.CommendationsCommendations are special awards that players earn throughout their Halo: Reach career. Performing certain actions multiple times increase their Commendation's level. When the level gauge is filled, their Commendations upgrade and the player receives cR. The Commendations list in each player's service record is sorted by the most upgraded Commendation. There are six milestones in each Commendation, each with their own emblem. (Iron, Bronze, Silver, Gold, Onyx, and maximum Onyx) There is a total of 45 Commendations, split into three different categories: Campaign (green Commendations), Multiplayer Matchmaking (blue Commendations), and Firefight Matchmaking (red Commendations).Cannon Fodder (Campaign) / Target Practice (Firefight) - Kill an Infantry-class enemy.Close Quarters (Multiplayer) - Kill an enemy in close-quarters combat (Melee, Shotgun, Energy Sword, Gravity Hammer).Demon (Campaign) - Complete a Campaign mission.Downshift (Multiplayer) - Be the driver of a vehicle while a passenger on a mounted weapon kills an enemy.Flawless Cowboy (Campaign) / Perfectionist (Firefight) - Complete a Campaign mission (on Heroic or Legendary) or a Firefight Matchmaking round without dying.Jack of All Trades (Multiplayer) - Earn a specific medal. (Such as First Strike, Revenge, and Killjoy)Leadership Element (Campaign) / In Command (Firefight) - Kill a Leader-class enemy.Nice Arm (Campaign) / Grenadier (Multiplayer) / Pull the Pin (Firefight) - Kill an enemy with a frag or plasma grenade.Pinpoint (Campaign) / One Shot (Multiplayer) / Dome Inspector (Firefight) - Kill an enemy with a headshot.Precisely (Campaign) / Crack Shot (Multiplayer) / Longshot (Firefight) - Kill an enemy with a precision weapon (DMR, Needle Rifle, Focus Rifle, or Sniper Rifle)Rear Admiral (Multiplayer) - Perform an assassination on an enemy.Right of Way (Campaign) / Grounded (Firefight) - Blow up an enemy vehicle.Small Arms (Campaign) / Sidearm (Multiplayer) / Trigger Happy (Firefight) - Kill an enemy with a Magnum or a Plasma Pistol.SpecOps (Campaign) / Specialized (Firefight) - Kill a Specialist-class enemy.Splash Damage (Campaign) / Heavy Weapon (Multiplayer) / Get Loud (Firefight) - Kill an enemy with a heavy weapon (Rocket Launcher, Grenade Launcher, Plasma Launcher, Spartan Laser, Concussion Rifle, Fuel Rod Gun, or Target Locator).Standard Issue (Campaign) / Trigger Man (Multiplayer) / Riflin' Through (Firefight) - Kill an enemy with an automatic weapon (Assault Rifle, Needler, Plasma Rifle, Plasma Repeater, or Spiker).Super Soldier (Campaign) / Any Spree (Multiplayer) / Methodical (Firefight) - Earn any type of spree, (such as Killing Spree and Wheelman Spree).Support Role (Campaign) / Assistant (Multiplayer) / Backup (Firefight) - Earn an assist.Walking Tank (Campaign) / Multikill (Multiplayer) / Numbers Game (Firefight) - Earn a multikill.War Machine (Campaign) / Mobile Asset (Multiplayer) / Vehicular (Firefight) - Kill an enemy with a vehicle.RanksRecruit0 cRPrivate7,500 cR(+7,500 cR)Corporal10,000 cR(+2,500 cR)CorporalGrade 115,000 cR(+5,000 cR)Sergeant20,000 cR(+5,000 cR)SergeantGrade 126,250 cR(+6,250 cR)SergeantGrade 232,500 cR(+6,250 cR)Warrant Officer45,000 cR(+12,500 cR)Warrant OfficerGrade 178,000 cR(+33,000 cR)Warrant OfficerGrade 2111,000 cR(+33,000 cR)Warrant OfficerGrade 3144,000 cR(+33,000 cR)Captain210,000 cR(+66,000 cR)CaptainGrade 1233,000 cR(+23,000 cR)CaptainGrade 2256,000 cR(+23,000 cR)CaptainGrade 3279,000 cR(+23,000 cR)Major325,000 cR(+46,000 cR)MajorGrade 1350,000 cR(+25,000 cR)MajorGrade 2375,000 cR(+25,000 cR)MajorGrade 3400,000 cR(+25,000 cR)Lt. Colonel450,000 cR(+50,000 cR)Lt. ColonelGrade 1480,000 cR(+30,000 cR)Lt. ColonelGrade 2510,000 cR(+30,000 cR)Lt. ColonelGrade 3540,000 cR(+30,000 cR)Commander600,000 cR(+60,000 cR)CommanderGrade 1650,000 cR(+50,000 cR)CommanderGrade 2700,000 cR(+50,000 cR)CommanderGrade 3750,000 cR(+50,000 cR)Colonel850,000 cR(+100,000 cR)ColonelGrade 1960,000 cR(+110,000 cR)ColonelGrade 21,070,000 cR(+110,000 cR)ColonelGrade 31,180,000 cR(+110,000 cR)Brigadier1,400,000 cR(+220,000 cR)BrigadierGrade 11,520,000 cR(+120,000 cR)BrigadierGrade 21,640,000 cR(+120,000 cR)BrigadierGrade 31,760,000 cR(+120,000 cR)General2,000,000 cR(+240,000 cR)GeneralGrade 12,200,000 cR(+200,000 cR)GeneralGrade 22,350,000 cR(+150,000 cR)GeneralGrade 32,500,000 cR(+150,000 cR)GeneralGrade 42,650,000 cR(+150,000 cR)Field Marshall3,000,000 cR(+350,000 cR)Hero3,700,000 cR(+700,000 cR)Legend4,600,000 cR(+900,000 cR)Mythic5,650,000 cR(+1,050,000 cR)Noble7,000,000 cR(+1,350,000 cR)Eclipse8,500,000 cR(+1,500,000 cR)Nova11,000,000 cR(+2,500,000 cR)Forerunner13,000,000 cR(+2,000,000 cR)Reclaimer16,500,000 cR(+3,500,000 cR)Inheritor20,000,000 cR(+3,500,000 cR)NameplatesAlthough nameplate emblems (special icons that appear next to the player's emblem in multiplayer lobbies) have existed since Halo 2, they were only to show that the player is a Bungie.net member or a Bungie employee. While nameplates can still only be changed through a Bungie.net, they can be customized in one of 13 different options:Blank - Default.Septagon - Unlocked once the gamertag is linked to a Bungie.net account.DMR - Unlocked by subscribing to the Bungie Pro service.Marathon - Unlocked by playing the full version of the Xbox Live Arcade version of Marathon: Durandal.Halo 1 - Unlocked by entering a product key for the PC or Mac version of Halo: Combat Evolved.Halo 2 - Unlocked by playing the Xbox version of Halo 2 before April 14, 2010.Halo 3 - Unlocked by playing Halo 3.Halo 3: ODST - Unlocked by playing Halo 3: ODST.Assault Rifle - Unlocked by playing the Halo: Reach beta.HALO - Unlocked after earning the Halo 1, Halo 2, and Halo 3 emblems.Spartan Helmet - Unlocked after earning four of the following emblems: Halo 1, Halo 2, Halo 3, Halo 3: ODST, Assault Rifle.Star - Unlocked by participating in "Bungie All Star" community challenges on Bungie.net and having your entry chosen by the community manager.Bungie - Bungie employees only.Official GametypesHalo: Reach has 12 multiplayer gametypes and one gametype specifically made for Forge, each customizable in many ways. Some official Bungie gametypes are not built-in to the game and must be downloaded from either a search or by playing that gametype in Matchmaking. The VIP gametype from Halo 3 has been removed, as well as most gametype variations from previous Halo games.Only Slayer and Elite Slayer have indestructible vehicles. By default, players start with the Assault Rifle and Magnum and have five loadouts: Sprint, Armor Lock, Active Camo, Hologram, and Drop Shield.Slayer (originated in Halo: Combat Evolved)Slayer - Default deathmatch mode. Kill or be killed. Suicides and betrayals decrease your score. Active Camo is replaced with Jet Pack.Slayer Pro - Slayer for more hardcore players. Players choose one of two loadouts: Marksman (starts with the DMR and two frag grenades) or Warden (starts with the Needle Rifle and two plasma grenades). Players can only use the Sprint armor ability. Motion tracker is disabled. Vehicles are limited to Mongooses. All weapon locations are replaced with a special "Arena Standard" set.Classic Slayer - Slayer reminiscent of previous Halo games. No loadouts or armor abilities.Elite Slayer - Slayer with Elites only. All weapon locations are replaced with Covenant weapons. Players start with two plasma grenades (and a Plasma Pistol as a secondary weapon) and have access to five loadouts: Zealot (Evade with a Needle Rifle), Dark Assassin (Active Camo with a Needler), Deceiver (Hologram with a Plasma Repeater), Saboteur (Armor Lock with a Needler), and Ranger (Jet Pack with a Plasma Repeater).SWAT - Originally a custom gametype in Halo 2 and a special playlist in Halo 3, SWAT limits the players' arsenals to DMRs and Magnums. Grenades, motion trackers, shields, and loadouts are disabled. Players can only use the Sprint armor ability, have 200% damage resistance and have infinite ammo. This is announced in the beginning of the game as "SWAT" instead of "Slayer".Slayer DMRs (not included)Snipers (not included)Snipers Pro (not included)Big Team Slayer (not included)BTB Classic (not included)BTB Snipers (not included)Oddball (originated in Halo: Combat Evolved)Oddball - Players (or teams) must pick up and hold on to the Oddball to earn points. Players carrying a ball have 25% less speed, cannot drive vehicles, have a disabled motion tracker, and have a waypoint that's visible to everybody else.Hot Potato (not included)Capture the Flag (originated in Halo: Combat Evolved)Capture the Flag - 2-4 teams. Each team has a flag. Players must guard their team's flag while grabbing the flags of enemies and bringing them back to their base. Dropped flags take 30 seconds to respawn (or 15 seconds to return if an ally is standing on it). Players carrying a flag have 25% less speed, cannot drive vehicles, and have a waypoint that's only visible to allies. Teams must have their flags safe at their base in order to score.Multi Flag CTF - No difference.Neutral Flag CTF - Same as Capture The Flag, only instead of each team having their own flag, only one flag is placed in the middle of the map (which anybody can grab).One Flag CTF - Two teams. Each team take turns as Attackers and Defenders. Defenders have the flag and has three minutes to guard it. The round ends when the time is up or the flag is captured. Dropped flags take 30 seconds to respawn, regardless of whoever is near it.One Flag Pro (not included)One Flag Classic (not included)Two Flag Pro (not included)Two Flag Classic (not included)King of the Hill (originated in Halo: Combat Evolved)King of the Hill - A "hill" (essentially a marked area) is placed somewhere in the map. Players earn points by being the only player or team standing in the hill. Players cannot use their armor abilities while inside the hill.Crazy King - Same as King of the Hill, only the hill is moved to a random location every 30 seconds.Crazy King Pro (not included)Race (originated in Halo: Combat Evolved)Race - Players race Mongooses, Ghosts, Warthogs, or Banshees around a set of pre-determined zones. Going through all the zones count as a "lap". Land mines, which knock vehicles around, can be scattered throughout the course. Players who get off their vehicle have a Sprint ability and are nearly-invulnerable, but gets on a teleported vehicle after some time. There are no grenades or loadouts.Rally - Same as Race, only players earn points by being the first at a random location (which moves after a player enters it with a vehicle). Unlike Race, players can use grenades and can die like normal.Rocket Race (not included) - This gametype has a unique icon.Assault (originated in Halo 2)Assault - Two teams, each with their own bomb. Players must pick up their team's bomb, take it to the enemy's base (shown as a waypoint) and protect it until it detonates, all while protecting their own base from enemy bombs. Players carrying a bomb have 25% less speed and cannot drive vehicles. It takes 5 seconds for the bomb to arm, 10 seconds for the bomb to detonate, 5 seconds for the bomb to be disarmed by the enemy, and 30 seconds for dropped bombs to return.Neutral Bomb Assault - Same as Assault, only instead of each team having their own bomb, only one bomb is placed in the middle of the map (which anybody can grab).One Bomb Assault - Each team take turns as Attackers and Defenders. Attackers have the bomb and has three minutes to plant it. The round ends when the time is up or the bomb is detonated.Juggernaut (originated in Halo 2)Juggernaut - One player is randomly the Juggernaut, who has 200% damage resistance, twice the amount of shields (which cannot be recharged), immunity to assassinations, 50% faster speed, 50% greater jump height, three times the damage on melee attacks, and a Gravity Hammer with infinite ammo. However, they cannot use grenades, armor abilities, vehicles, or other weapons, and have a waypoint that everybody can see. New Juggernauts are invulnerable for 10 seconds. Killing an enemy gives the player 5 points, while killing an enemy as the Juggernaut gives the player 10 points. Players start with the Sprint ability, the Assault Rifle, the Magnum, and one frag grenade. There are no loadouts.Territories (originated in Halo 2)Territories -3-Plot Territories -Land Grab -Infection (originated in Halo 3)Infection - One player starts out as a Zombie (who has the Evade ability, an Energy Sword with double damage, no shields, an enhanced motion tracker that shows enemies at all times, 20% faster speed, 50% greater jump height, and cannot use vehicles) while the rest starts out with a Shotgun and a Magnum. Everybody has unlimited ammo, but cannot pick up weapons or use grenades. Once a Zombie kills a normal player, that normal player respawns as a Zombie. The last man standing has 50% more shields and 10% faster speed, but his location is visible to everybody else. Players who survive after four minutes gets an extra point.Safe Havens - Same as Infection, only there is now a special area on the map that, when normal players step into it, makes these normal players invulnerable. 15 seconds after a normal player steps on the special area, it moves to a random location on the map.Headhunter (new)Headhunter - Killing an enemy causes a flaming skull to pop out of their head (as well as the skulls they previously collected). Players must collect these skulls (unlike Oddball, they are automatically carried) and run to one of two special "Drop Points". After 30 seconds, a new random location for each drop point is chosen. Players that are carrying skulls have a waypoint (which also has the number of skulls collected) that is visible to everybody. Players who capture the maximum amount of skulls (ten) automatically wins the game, regardless of the current scoreboard. Active Camo is replaced with Jet Pack.Headhunter Pro - A mixture of Headhunter and Slayer Pro. Only headshot kills generate collectable skulls.Stockpile (new)Stockpile - 2-4 teams fight for four neutral flags that appear randomly throughout the map. Players must grab these flags and drop them off at designated control points. After each minute, all the flags in each team's control points are collected, giving them one point per flag. Players can also sabotage enemy control points and throw flags out of their points.Stockpile Pro (not included)Invasion (new)Invasion - Invasion pits Spartans versus Elites in a multi-tiered attack-and-defend style mode. Each map is structured largely the same, with territories to capture in order to unlock the next section of the map before retrieving and escaping with a data core. In a nutshell its a game of "territories, territories and finally CTF". After a round is over, the teams switches side, alternating between attacking and defending.Invasion Slayer - Invasion slayer plays very differently. Here, Spartans and Elites vie for control over territories that when captured will spawn that team a new vehicle or "Power Weapon". As the match progresses, more loadouts will be unlocked and the team that reaches 100 kills first wins. The second and third tier are unlocked at 25 and 50 kills respectively.Invasion: Boneyard - The Elites are on offense, trying to steal a datacore from a defunct UNSC military installation. The campaign mission "Pillar of Autumn" is loosely based on Boneyard.Invasion: Spire - The Spartans are on offense, trying to gain access to a large energy sphere and stealing a datacore. The campaign mission "Tip of the Spear" is very much based on Spire.FirefightFirefight returns in Reach from its introduction in Halo 3: ODST with a wealth of new options and features. The core concept remains the same, that being a set number of players fight against waves of AI enemies with increased difficulty through difficulty modifiers. The additions to Reach come in the form of improved matchmaking and network support, instead of the invite only nature of ODST. Furthermore, Firefight has been given a overhaul in terms of customization, allowing the user to tweak the mode to their liking. The player can change a multitude of options such as the weapon drops, types of enemies, the way in the which the enemies behave, and much more. The addition of new types of objective-based gametypes inside of Firefight adds more variety as well, such as the Generator Defense gametype (seen in the multiplayer beta) asks the players to defend a number of generators against Covenant forces.There is also the newly announced Versus Firefight which is a 2v2 gametype. 2 players are Spartans and there goal is to score as many points as possible in the allotted time frame, with a set number of lives. The other 2 players plays as Elites with Covenant reinforcements being dropped off just like regular Firefight, the Elite players' job is to kill the Spartans as fast as possible. The Elites score no points and have infinite lives to kill the Spartans, however the Spartans gain an extra life and point boost every time they kill one of the Elite's. When the round ends team switch sides and whoever scores the most points wins the game.Firefight MapsBeachhead - Set in a natural park in the metropolitan city of New Alexandria, on the planet Reach.Corvette - Set inside a Covenant cruiser in orbit above Reach, the combat on the map is focused inside a hangar bay.Courtyard - Wage war in a Courtyard outside an ONI building on Reach. Walkways, connecting rooms and plenty of cover make this a frantic space to fight in. It may not prove to be an effective weapon but feel free to jump behind the wheel of a Forklift if you feel inclined.Glacier - This map has been added in the latest patch. Glacier is an underground level where you defend the base from Covenant troops.Holdout - Set in the outside of an industrial factory, Holdout is a multi tiered level where you defend against the Covenant .Outpost - Set affront a massive Covenant AA gun.Overlook - Fight against the Covenant in this settler dwelling set amidst the rugged Reach countryside. Take advantage of turret emplacements to hold off the Covenant crossing the river but beware the occasional Wraith.Waterfront - A night based map set in a pumping station on the shores of a large body of water. It was the first Firefight map revealed during E3 2010.Language on ReachOccasionally citizens on Reach can be heard speaking a foreign language. This language is actually Hungarian.Limited Release SKUs:Much like its predecessors, Halo: Reach will come with two limited edition choices, as well as two specially themed accessories.Limited EditionLimited EditionGame disc housed in recovered ONI "Black Box".An exclusive Elite armor set for use in multiplayer modes.Artifact bag containing Dr. Halsey's personal journal and other classified documents and effects that unravel long held secrets from the Halo universe.Legendary EditionThe same as the limited edition release plus the following:Noble Team Statue crafted by McFarlane Toys.USNC themed custom packaging.An exclusive Spartan armor feature for use in multiplayer modes, a flaming helmet that was exclusive to Bungie employees in Halo 3.Exclusive downloadable video content.Xbox 360 BundleNew Xbox 360 "S" in limited platinum color which also features new sounds from the console, one for when you power up the 360 and one for the disc tray.Two platinum controllers.Halo Reach Game (Standard Edition).Japanese Xbox 360 S BundleA download code for the game was bundled with Monster Hunter Frontier, Fable III, and Gears of War 2 in a Japanese-exclusive "value" bundle.Halo: Reach Wireless ControllerLegendary EditionFeatures artwork created by Bungie, inspired by Halo: Reach, the blockbuster prequel to the award-winning Halo trilogy.Features all the functionality of the award-winning Wireless Controller while fitting in perfectly within the Halo: Reach mythology.Includes a token for a Banshee aircraft Avatar item.Halo: Reach Wireless HeadsetFeatures all the functionality of the Wireless Headset, a distinctive silver color and artwork created by Bungie that was inspired by Halo: Reach, the blockbuster prequel to the award-winning Halo trilogy.Avatar AwardsThe avatar awards are the helmets of the other members of Noble Team. It is unknown whether or not they will come via Halo: Reach or Halo: Waypoint which currently is used to unlock every other Halo avatar award. A Noble 6 Helmet and any Noble armor suit are not available as Awards. The armor for Jun, Jorge, Carter, Emile, and Noble 6 can be bought in the Avatar Marketplace. A Noble 6 helmet is available as a code giveaway to people lucky enough to get one.Carter's Helmet - Clear a Campaign mission on Legendary without dying.Emile's Helmet - Earn a Bulltrue medal in either multiplayer or Firefight Matchmaking.Jorge's Helmet - Earn a Killtacular in multiplayer Matchmaking.Jun's Helmet - Kill 100 enemies in a row without dying in either the Campaign or Firefight.Kat's Helmet - Avenge a teammate's death in multiplayer Matchmaking.The ArmoryThe Armory is a feature in Halo: Reach that the player uses to customize their Spartan solider to their heart's desire.The armor is split in to the following categories:HelmetLeft ShoulderRight ShoulderChestWristUtilityVisor ColorKnee GuardsArmor EffectFirefight VoiceEmblem  ColorsThe player uses Credits (accumulated by completing challenges, killing enemies and essentially playing the game) to purchase different pieces of armor. Some armor pieces may be locked (or not even viewable in the menu) until the player is of a higher rank. The Spartan that the player creates is used for Single player/ Co-Op Campaign, Firefight and Matchmaking.SoundtrackReach OST Front CoverThe Halo: Reach soundtrack was released on September 28th. It was once again composed by Martin O'Donnell, who said this about composing the soundtrack:I want it to be more visceral, to have a bigger sense of loss, a personal feeling of sacrificeTracks1: Overture - 4:462: Winter Contingency - 12:083: ONI: Sword Base - 8:274: Nightfall - 5:405: Tip of the Spear - 6:056: Long Night of Solace - 11:467: Exodus - 7:188: New Alexandria - 8:419: The Package - 6:5510: The Pillar of Autumn - 9:4011: Epilogue - 4:2912: From the Vault - 4:5913: Ashes - 2:4514: Fortress - 1:0715: We're Not Going Anywhere - 1:1316: At Any Cost - 2:2917: Both Ways (Remix) - 2:1718: Walking Away - 1:5319: Ghosts and Glass - 2:4120: We Remember - 2:05</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20699">Resistance 2</game><game id="593">Shadowrun</game><game id="13286">Unreal Tournament 2004</game><game id="17179">Starsiege: Tribes</game><game id="29021">Resistance 3</game><game id="34259">Knights: Spiral Islands</game><game id="32620">Section 8: Prejudice</game><game id="23708">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5150/1331572-reach.jpg</image></root>