<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2681</id><name>American McGee's Alice</name><description>OverviewAmerican McGee's Alice is a third-person action and platforming game, styled as a darker sequel to "Alice's Adventures in Wonderland" and "Through the Looking Glass". The game uses a heavily modified version of the  Quake III: Arena engine.PlotThe Cheshire CatThe game is set ten years after  Alice's previous adventures in Lewis Carroll's Story, "Alice's Adventures in Wonderland", with players taking the role of Alice. In the opening cinematic, Alice's house is burnt down by an accidental fire, killing her parents. As a result of her survivor's guilt, Alice attempts to commit suicide and is sent to the Rutledge Asylum. After years of unhelpful counselling, Alice is near catatonic until the  White Rabbit summons Alice to aid a radically altered Wonderland, now under the tyrannical rule of the  Queen of Hearts. The  Cheshire Cat serves as Alice's companion through the entire game, frequently appearing to guide her with cryptic riddles.Various famous characters from the books of "Alice's Adventures in Wonderland" and "Through the Looking Glass" make appearances in the game such as: The Mad HatterHumpty DumptyThe DormouseThe March Hare The Mock Turtle The Gryphon Tweedle Dee and  Tweedle Dum The Caterpillar The JabberwockThe Duchess The Queen of HeartsAll of these characters have however been horrifically twisted or reconstructed.GameplayAmerican McGee 's Alice is a third person action game, emphasizing heavy platforming and third person shooting elements. Gameplay also consists of large  puzzle elements, requiring Alice to traverse the environment and utilize her various weapons and powers obtained during the game. Using  id Software's Quake III: Arena engine, The game is displayed in fully 3-D environments with smooth character and environment textures and animations.CombatCombat takes place from a third person perspective, with various items related to Alice's journeys acting as weapons. A  deck of cards serve as a weak projectile type weapon, whilst a Jack-In-The-Box serves as a makeshift grenade. All weapons have a differentiated second function, often acting in new and different ways to the original function (i.e. Throwing Alice's Vorpal Blade, launching a barrage of cards at once). The varying effects of each weapon and its sub-function add a degree of depth and difficulty to combat. Other weapons include demon dice, a blunderbuss and the Jabberwock eye staff.ToysToys are what Alice uses to combat the malevolent forces of the Queen of Hearts; most have two distinct methods of operation, the ones that don't activate their primary fire when you push the alt fire button.ToyDescriptionPrimary AttackSecondary AttackVorpal BladeThis weapon, visually a butcher knife, is named after the sword used to kill the Jabberwock in the original poem. Primary fire slashes and stabs, alt fire throws it at enemies. The Vorpal Blade uses no Will, but throwing it causes it to disappear, and Alice will be unable to use it until it magically returns to her a few seconds later.SlashThrowDeck of CardsThe Deck of Cards fires slow-moving, target-seeking projectiles in the form of razor-sharp playing cards. Primary fire launches a steady stream of cards as long as you hold the button, and alt fire launches a short-ranged blast of cards with a shotgun effect.Card Throw16 Card BlastCroquet MalletPrimary fire swings the Mallet, and successful hits electrify enemies. This has a a slightly longer reach than the Vorpal Blade, and hits significantly harder, as well as using no Will. Alt fire consumes Will and launches an electrified croquet ball at your target from a distance.BashElectrified Croquet BallJack-in-the-BombPrimary fire tosses out the Jack-in-the-Bomb; it plays its jingle and then explodes with great force, like a grenade. Alt fire tosses it out as well, but this time it immediately begins to emit a powerful gout of flames in a slowly rotating blast, then explodes into a fireball once it runs out of power.ExplosionFlame-Thrower / ExplosionIce WandPrimary fire sends out a constant stream of frigid air that deals extreme damage to fire-based enemies, and heavy damage to most others. Killing an enemy with the Ice Wand causes them to freeze solid. Alt fire creates a small shield of ice directly in front of Alice that blocks enemy projectiles in theory, but given that in practice you really need to keep moving constantly, it's basically useless.Ice BlastWall of IceJacksPrimary fire launches out the spike-tipped Jacks, which seek out an enemy and pummel them without mercy or hesitation for a short time, then return to Alice. As long as the ball is bouncing next to Alice, the Jacks are doing their thing, but they cannot be used until they return. Alt fire throws out a handful of Jacks in a similar manner to the Cards' alt fire. It deals almost no damage, though, so stick with primary fire.Jack BarrageJack ThrowDiabolical DiceDepending on how many Dice you have, and what you roll, you can summon demons with these malevolent cubes. There are three types of demons that can be summoned, with this group destroying weapon, but be warned, summoning demons when no enemies are around will lead your summoned monsters to attack you.Small Demon -- uses ¼ of your Will meter; the demon is small and winged and has a mild electric beamMedium Demon -- uses ½ of your Will meter; the demon is snake-like, with both slashing and flame attacksLarge Demon -- uses ¾ of your Will meter; this is a large and mean demon, and it has electric and pounding attacksThrow Die/Dice-----Jabberwock's Eye StaffPrimary fire charges up for a few seconds before unleashing a purple death ray that causes extreme damage to whatever you care to point it at, and lasts until you run out of Will. Alt fire launches a number of purple projectiles into the sky, which soon come down in the direction Alice is looking.Eye BeamMeteor ShowerBlunderbussThis is the most powerful Toy in the game, it takes a full Will meter to use and kills every enemy in the area you fire it into. Only bosses can survive even a single blast from this devastating beauty. Unfortunately, it's hidden...Burst of Will-----Deadtime WatchThis watch will freeze time, giving you twenty seconds in a frozen world to do whatever you want, and it's always amusing to watch a group of enemies drop dead the second time starts again. Unfortunately, it has a very long cooldown.Time Freeze-----LevelsFortress of DoorsThe Pale RealmWater LoggedDementiaPandemoniumFortress of DoorsBeyond the WallFortress of Doors, pt. 2Skool DazeSkool's OutSkool Daze, pt. 2Pool of TearsHollow HideawayJust DessertsWholly Morel GroundDry LandingHerbaceous BorderRolling StonesIcy ReceptionFungiferous FloraCatterpillar's PlotPale RealmCastlingCheckmate In RedMirror ImageCrazed ClockworkAbout FaceBurning CuriosityJabberwock's LairCatterpillar's Plan, pt. 2Majestic MazeAirborne TerrorMystifying MadnessWater LoggedLabyrinthine RevengeMachinationsRoyal RageBattle RoyaleAscensionCastle KeepHearts of DarknessEnemiesCommon EnemiesYou'll see these guys a lotClub Card GuardsDiamond Card GuardBoojumMechanical LadybugArmy Ant SoldierSnarkArmy Ant GeneralMushroomPink RoseAntlionFire ImpLava ManPhantasmagoriaSpade Card GuardHeart Card GuardRed PawnRed KnightRed RookRed BishopClockwork GuardLantern SpiderFire SnarksJabberspawnBossesMad Hatter's Concept ArtThe DuchessThe CentipedeThe Red King Tweedle Dee and  Tweedle DumThe  Mad HatterThe  JabberwockThe  Queen of HeartsVoice TalentsSusie Brann -- Alice Jarion Monroe -- Catterpillar Roger Jackson -- Cheshire Cat / Jabberwock / The Dormouse Andrew Chaikin -- The White Rabbit / The Mad Hatter / The March Hare Anni Long -- The Queen of Hearts / The DuchessSoundtrackThe  soundtrack for American McGee's Alice was composed by the musician  Chris Vrenna.Track No.TitleRunning Time01Falling Down the Rabbit Hole01.2002Village of the Doomed03.3503Fortress of Doors03.5104Fire and Brimstone03.4605Wonderland Woods03.5906The Funhouse03.3907Skool Daze04.1008Time to Die03.5509I'm Not Edible03.0910Taking Tea In Dreamland03.4411Fungiferous Flora03.3512Tweedle-Dee and Tweedle-Dum03.4613The Centipede03.3114Pandemonium03.5515Floying On the Wings of Steam04.3516Late to the Jabberwocky03.1717Pool of Tears04.0818Battle of the Red Queen04.1119A Happy Ending03.4420Flying On the Wings of Steam (remix)04.03PC System RequirementsOS: Windows 98/ME/2000Processor: Pentium 2 @ 400 MHzMemory: 64 MBHard Drive: 580 MB FreeVideo Memory: 16 MBSound Card: DirectX CompatibleDirectX: 7.0TriviaThe game's release offered a pewter Cheshire Cat figurine (approx. 2 in. tall) as a Gamestop/EB Games pre-order bonus.An alternate front cover was attached to later releases of the game; it appears almost identical, but the Cheshire Cat is less bony and emaciated, and Alice is carrying the Ice Wand, not the  Vorpal Blade. A third cover was later attached which appears identical to the second one except that Alice is carrying the even less threatening Deck of Cards.At one point in development, the team considered casting  Marilyn Manson as the voice of the Mad Hatter, but decided against it.</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22565">American McGee's Grimm</game><game id="10533">Conker's Bad Fur Day</game><game id="24065">American McGee's Oz</game><game id="2770">Weird Dreams</game><game id="7353">Conker: Live &amp; Reloaded</game><game id="10746">Shadow Man</game><game id="10728">American McGee presents SCRAPLAND</game><game id="16258">The Vault of Darkness</game><game id="12788">Rule of Rose</game><game id="3457">MediEvil</game><game id="3438">MediEvil II</game><game id="42742">Alice: Otherlands</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4527/1816798-1.jpg</image></root>