<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26842</id><name>Gran Turismo</name><description>Gran Turismo is a driving simulator released for the PSP handheld system. It was released in UMD form in retail stores and as a digital download in the PlayStation Store. This iteration of the game introduced several new car manufacturers to the series, including Lamborghini and Bugatti. The game contains over 800 licensed cars and over 40 different race tracks. Gran Turismo for PSP released simultenously alongside the PSP Go system. (A smaller version of PSP.) Gran Turismo for PSP was forward compatible with Gran Turismo 5; players are allowed to transfer their Gran Turismo garage into their Gran Turismo 5 garage, even though Gran Turismo 5 was not yet released at the time.Data InstallData Install improves the experience by reducing load times, especially when browsing, purchasing, and tuning vehicles.Gran Turismo for PSP offers a data install option. This means that players who own the game on UMD disc rather than as a digital download are still able to install the game to their memory stick, reducing load times and eliminating disc reading. (Thereby eliminating disc read noise and marginally improving battery life.) However even when using data install, the game disc is still required to play.Save File RestrictionGran Turismo for PSP restricts your save file to whatever system it was created on. If you want to replace or upgrade your PSP, or play the game on Vita, you will not be able to carry over any of the vehicles or credits you've accumulated, nor your progress through the game. To play on a different PSP, you will have to create a new save file and start the game over from the beginning. (Which includes having to unlock the custom soundtrack option all over again.)Custom SoundtrackThis is block A. The player must complete at least 6 blocks to unlock custom sountrack. Each block contains 6 events.Gran Turismo for PSP offers the option to use a custom soundtrack, allowing the player to use any mp3 music files stored on their PSP system as the soundtrack during gameplay. (not menus) This feature must first be unlocked by completing the first set of driving challenges. This is relatively easy to do, as the player is only required to get at least a bronze on each event. Getting silvers or golds are not required.Two options are presented for custom soundtrack. The player can choose to have the game use all music stored in the Music folder on their PSP, or to only look at a specific folder within the Music folder that must be named "GTPSP". This allows the user to decide which music on their PSP to use in Gran Turismo.Enabling custom soundtrack option disables the default soundtrack entirely. (There is no way to use music from the default soundtrack while adding your own.) Even if you choose not to enable custom soundtrack, there is no way to disable specific music tracks from the default soundtrack. Likewise, the only way to disable a music track in your custom soundtrack is to exit the game and delete that music track.GameplayOpen-ended in design, the game allows players to play Gran Turismo without an ultimate goal. Unlike other games in the series, there is no career mode. In the single-player menu the player can choose between three options; Car Selection, Track Selection and Mode Selection (See Game Modes). This is aside from the Driving Challenge mode which is also included separately.In races, players earn credits based on the selected difficulty rank of the races they compete in as well as the place they finishes and the number of laps they raced. Races are competed in one of over 40 race tracks with three other computer controlled racers. As you completes races and thus increase in skill level, you gain the ability to increase the difficulty of the A.I. opponents (represented by a letter grade) until you achieve their highest difficulty rank of ''S''. The higher the difficulty rank, the higher the payoff for winning a race.Players can then use the credits they've earned to buy more cars for their garage. However, what cars the player is able to purchase changes every time a race is completed.Gran Turismo PSP contains an exhaustive Driving Challenge mode with over 100 challenges.Players can also take part in over 100 driving challenges that test the driving skills of the player. Gold, Silver and Bronze in-game trophies and credits are rewarded based on how well the challenge is completed.Connecting the PSP with others via Ad Hoc allows players to trade cars with each other or gift them.Game ModesSingle Race4 different viewpoints are offered: Bumper, cockpit, roof, and chase view. You can change views any time during gameplay.Race on any of the tracks from 1 to 120 laps with any car you have. The AI are given cars based on your selected car and selected difficulty. You can also choose whether to have all AI opponent drive an identical (except for color) car model as you, instead of different cars that are similar in performance level.Time TrialRacing against your ghost.Race on any of the tracks, race your ghost, and try to achieve your best lap time. The game records your top 10 lap times for each course. Unfortunately, no credits are awarded in this mode, and there is no online leaderboards or online ghosts.Drift TrialDrift Trial mode.There are two modes: sectional drift challenge, and full course mode. Sectional Drift has you drift a specific section of the course and records your drift score for that section. Full course mode has you drift the whole course and records your drift score for as long as you choose to play. You are awarded credits in both Drift Trial modes.Drift Trial can be played on any course, even dirt/snow.Driver ChallengeThe optional on-road guideline is available by default in races, time trial, and driving challenges.As mentioned earlier. Contains many different challenges and tests which teach and evaluate your driving ability and racing technique. Credits can be earned each time the player completes a challenge for the first time or when improving their record.Multiplayer Modes:(Ad-hoc only.)Party Race Mode - Multiplayer race mode where player start times vary depending on their skill levelShuffle Race Mode - Multiplayer race mode where players are given different cars based on skill levelTracksReal World Circuits:Cote d'AzurCircuit de ValenciaNurburgring NordschleifeMazda Raceway Laguna SecaTsukuba CircuitSuzuka CircuitSuzuka Circuit WestSuzuka Circuit EastInfineon Raceway (Sports Car Course)Fuji Speedway 2005Fuji Speedway 90sTwin Ring Motegi Road CourseTwin Ring Motegi Super SpeedwayTwin Ring Motegi East Short CourseTwin Ring Motegi West Short CourseCircuit De La Sarthe 2005Circuit De La Sarte IGran Turismo (Fictional) Circuits:Trial Mountain CircuitHigh Speed RingAutumn RingAutumn Ring MiniCitta di AriaCosta di AmalfiEl CapitanGrand Valley SpeedwayGrand Valley EastDeep Forest RacewayMid-Field RacewayApricot Hill RacewayTest CourseMotorlandBeginner CourseCity Courses:Tokyo R246Opera ParisNew YorkSeattle CircuitSeoul CentralDirt And Snow (Rally):Swiss AlpsGrand CanyonChamonixCathedral Rocks Trail ICathedral Rocks Trail IICathedral Rocks Trail IIITahiti MazeCar ListAlthough Gran Turismo PSP boasts an incredible number of cars, it is worth nothing that many of them are nearly identical to each other, with sometimes the only differences between two models of cars, seemingly, are negligible markings that are virtually unnoticeable unless you know where to look. Nonetheless, the car selection is certainly quite impressive even if one were to discount duplicate cars.Note: The below car list is incomplete, as not all manufacturers are listed.Acura:Acura CL 3.2 Type-S '01Acura CL 3.2 Type-S '03Acura DN-X Concept '02Acura HSC Concept '04Acura INTEGRA TYPE R '01Acura NSX '91Acura NSX '04Acura NSX Coupe '97Acura RSX Type-S '04Bentley:Bentley Speed 8 Race Car '03Bugatti:Bugatti Veyron 16.4 '09Chevrolet:Chevrolet Corvette Stingray L46 350 (C3) '69Chevrolet Corvette ZR1 (C6) '09Chevrolet Camaro IROC-Z Concept '88Chevrolet Camaro LM Race CarChevrolet Camaro SS '69Chevrolet Camaro SS '00Chevrolet Camaro Z28 302 '69Chevrolet Camaro Z28 Coupe '97Chevrolet Chevelle SS 454 '70Chevrolet Corvette C5-R (C5) '00Chevrolet Corvette Convertible (C1) '54Chevrolet Corvette Coupe (C2) '63Chevrolet Corvette GRAND SPORT (C4) '96Chevrolet Corvette Z06 (C2) Race Car '63Chevrolet Corvette Z06 (C5) '00Chevrolet Corvette ZR-1 (C4) '90Chevrolet Silverado SST Concept '02Chevrolet SSR '03Dodge:Dodge RAM 1500 LARAMIE Hemi Quad Cab '04Dodge VIPER GTS '99Dodge Charger 440 R/T '70Dodge Charger Super Bee 426 Hemi '71Dodge SRT4 '03Dodge VIPER GTS R Concept '00Dodge VIPER GTS-R Team Oreca Race Car '00Dodge VIPER SRT10 '03Ford:Ford GT '052000 Ford Falcon XR8Ford Escort Rally Car ‘98Ford Focus Rally Car ‘99Ford Focus RS ‘02Ford Focus ST170 ‘03Ford GT ‘02Ford GT (No Stripe) ‘05Ford GT LM Race CarFord GT LM Race Car Spec IIFord GT40 Race Car ‘69Ford Ka ‘01Ford Mustang GT ‘05Ford Mustang SVT Cobra R ‘00Ford RS200 ‘84Ford RS200 Rally Car ‘85Ford SVT F-150 Lightning ‘03Ford Taurus SHO ‘98Honda:Honda 1300 Coupe 9 S '70Honda ACCORD Coupe '88Honda ACCORD Coupe EX '03Honda ACCORD Euro-R '00Honda ACCORD Euro-R '02Honda ARTA NSX (JGTC) '00Honda BALLADE SPORTS CR-X 1.5i '83Honda BEAT '91Honda BEAT Version F '92Honda BEAT Version Z '93Honda Castrol MUGEN NSX (JGTC) '00Honda CITY Turbo II '83Honda CIVIC 1500 3door 25i '83Honda CIVIC 1500 3door CX '79Honda CIVIC SiR-II (EG) '91Honda CIVIC SiR-II (EG) '92Honda CIVIC SiR-II (EG) '93Honda CIVIC SiR-II (EG) '95Honda CIVIC TYPE R (EK) '97Honda CIVIC TYPE R (EK) '98Honda CIVIC TYPE R (EP) '01Honda CIVIC TYPE R (EP) '04Honda CIVIC TYPE R (EP, EU) '01Honda CR-X del Sol SiR '92Honda CR-X SiR '90Honda DUALNOTE Concept '01Honda ELEMENT '03Honda FIT W '01Honda Gathers Drider CIVIC Race Car '98Honda S2000 (EU) '99Honda S2000 (EU) '03Honda S2000 Type V (EU) '00Honda S2000 Type V (EU) '01Honda HSC "The 37th Tokyo Motor Show Concept Car" '03Honda INSIGHT '99Honda INTEGRA TYPE R (DC2) '95Honda INTEGRA TYPE R (DC2) '98Honda INTEGRA TYPE R (DC2) '99Honda INTEGRA TYPE R (DC5) '03Honda INTEGRA TYPE R Touring CarHonda JAZZ 1.4 DSi SE Sport '01Honda LIFE STEP VAN '72Honda LOCTITE MUGEN NSX (JGTC) '01Honda Mobil 1 NSX (JGTC) '01Honda MUGEN MOTUL CIVIC Si Race Car '87Honda N360 '67Honda NSX '90Honda NSX '93Honda NSX '95Honda NSX '97Honda NSX '99Honda NSX '01Honda NSX Type R '92Honda NSX Type R '02Honda NSX Type S '97Honda NSX Type S '99Honda NSX Type S '01Honda NSX Type S Zero '97Honda NSX Type S Zero '99Honda NSX-R Concept '01Honda NSX-R Prototype LM Race CarHonda NSX-R Prototype LM Road CarHonda ODYSSEY '03Honda PRELUDE Si VTEC '91Honda PRELUDE SiR '96Honda PRELUDE SiR S spec '98Honda PRELUDE Type S '96Honda PRELUDE Type S '98Honda RAYBRIG NSX (JGTC) '00Honda S2000 '99Honda S2000 '01Honda S2000 '03Honda S2000 (EU) '01Honda S2000 (US) '99Honda S2000 (US) '01Honda S2000 (US) '04Honda S2000 LM Race CarHonda S2000 Type V '00Honda S2000 Type V '01Honda S2000 Type V '03Honda S2000 Type V (US) '00Honda S2000 Type V (US) '01Honda S500 '63Honda S600 '64Honda S800 '66Honda S800 RSC Race Car '68Honda TAKATA DOME NSX (JGTC) '03Honda TODAY G '85Honda Z ACT '70Jaguar:Jaguar E-TYPE Coupe '61Jaguar S-TYPE R '02Jaguar XJ220 '92Jaguar XJ220 LM Race CarJaguar XJR-9 LM Race Car '88Jaguar XKR Coupe '99Jaguar XKR R Performance '02Lamborghini:Lamborghini Countach LP400 '74Lamborghini Countach 25th Anniversary '88Lancia:Lancia STRATOS Rally Car '77Lancia DELTA HF Integrale Evoluzione ‘91Lancia DELTA HF Integrale Rally Car ‘92Lancia DELTA S4 Rally Car ‘85Lancia STRATOS ‘73Mazda:Mazda 110S (L10A) '67Mazda 110S (L10B) '68Mazda 787B Race car '91Mazda Atenza Concept '01Mazda Atenza Sports 23Z '03Mazda Atenza Touring CarMazda Autozam AZ-1 '92Mazda BP FALKEN RX-7 (D1GP) '03Mazda Carol 360 Deluxe '62Mazda Cosmo Sport (L10A) '67Mazda Cosmo Sport (L10B) '68Mazda DEMIO GL-X '99Mazda DEMIO SPORT '03Mazda efini RX-7 Type R (FD) '91Mazda efini RX-7 Type R (FD) '93Mazda efini RX-7 Type RS (FD) '96Mazda efini RX-7 Type R-S (FD) '95Mazda efini RX-7 Type RZ (FD) '92Mazda efini RX-7 Type RZ (FD) '93Mazda efini RX-7 Type RZ (FD) '95Mazda efini RX-7 Type RZ (FD) '96Mazda Eunos Roadster (NA Special Package) '89Mazda Eunos Roadster J-Limited (NA) '91Mazda Eunos Roadster J-Limited II (NA) '93Mazda Eunos Roadster SR-Limited (NA) '97Mazda Eunos Roadster S-Special Type I (NA) '95Mazda Eunos Roadster VR-Limited (NA) '95Mazda Eunos Roadster V-Special Type II (NA) '93Mazda Familia Sedan Sport 20 '02Mazda KUSABI Concept '03Mazda Lantis Coupe 2000 Type R '93Mazda 323F '93Mazda Furai Concept '08Mazda2 '03Mazda6 5-door '03Mazda6 Concept '01Mazda6 Touring CarMazda Mazdaspeed Atenza '05Mazda MX-5 (NA) '89Mazda MX-5 1.8 RS (NB, J) '98Mazda MX-5 1600 NR-A (NB, J) '04Mazda MX-5 1800 RS (NB, J) '00Mazda MX-5 1800 RS (NB, J) '04Mazda MX-5 J-Limited (NA, J) '91Mazda MX-5 J-Limited II (NA, J) '93Mazda MX-5 Miata (NA) '89Mazda MX-5 Miata 1.8 RS (NB, J) '98Mazda MX-5 Miata 1600 NR-A (NB, J) '04Mazda MX-5 Miata 1800 RS (NB, J) '00Mazda MX-5 Miata 1800 RS (NB, J) '04Mazda MX-5 Miata J-Limited (NA, J) '91Mazda MX-5 Miata J-Limited II (NA, J) '93Mazda MX-5 Miata SR-Limited (NA, J) '97Mazda MX-5 Miata S-Special Type I (NA, J) '95Mazda MX-5 Miata VR-Limited (NA, J) '95Mazda MX-5 Miata V-Special Type II (NA, J) '93Mazda MX-5 SR-Limited (NA, J) '97Mazda MX-5 S-Special Type I (NA, J) '95Mazda MX-5 VR-Limited (NA, J) '95Mazda MX-5 V-Special Type II (NA, J) '93Mazda MX-Crossport Concept '05Mazda Protege '02Mazda Roadster 1.8 RS (NB) '98Mazda Roadster 1600 NR-A (NB) '04Mazda Roadster 1800 RS (NB) '00Mazda Roadster 1800 RS (NB) '04Mazda RX-7 GT-LIMITED (FC, J) '85Mazda RX-7 GT-X (FC) '90Mazda RX-7 GT-X (FC, J) '90Mazda RX-7 LM Race CarMazda RX-7 Spirit R Type A (FD) '02Mazda RX-7 Type R Bathurst R (FD) '01Mazda RX-7 Type RS (FD) '98Mazda RX-7 Type RS (FD) '00Mazda RX-7 Type RS-R (FD) '97Mazda RX-7 Type RZ (FD) '00Mazda RX-8 '03Mazda RX-8 Concept (Type-I) '01Mazda RX-8 Concept (Type-II) '01Mazda RX-8 Concept LM Race CarMazda RX-8 Type E '03Mazda RX-8 Type S '03Mazda SAVANNA RX-7 GT-Limited (FC) '85Mazda SAVANNA RX-7 INFINI III (FC) '90Mercedes-Benz:Mercedes Benz 300 SL Coupe '54Mercedes-Benz 190 E 2.5 – 16 Evolution II ‘91Mercedes-Benz A 160 Avantgarde ‘98AMG Mercedes 190 E 2.5 – 16 Evolution II Touring Car ‘92AMG Mercedes CLK-GTR Race Car ‘98Mercedes-Benz CL 600 ‘00Mercedes-Benz CLK 55 AMG ‘00Mercedes-Benz CLK Touring Car ‘00Mercedes-Benz E 55 AMG ‘02Sauber Mercedes C9 Race Car ‘89Mercedes-Benz SL 500 (R129) ‘98Mercedes-Benz SL 500 (R230) ‘02Mercedes-Benz SL 55 AMG (R230) ‘02Mercedes-Benz SL 600 (R129) ‘98Mercedes-Benz SL 600 (R230) ‘04Mercedes-Benz SL 65 AMG (R230) ‘04Mercedes-Benz SLK 230 Kompressor ‘98Mercedes-Benz SLR McLaren ‘03Mitsubishi:Mitsubishi 3000GT MR (J) '95Mitsubishi 3000GT MR (J) '98Mitsubishi 3000GT SL (J) '95Mitsubishi 3000GT SL (J) '96Mitsubishi 3000GT SL (J) '98Mitsubishi 3000GT SR (J) '95Mitsubishi 3000GT SR (J) '96Mitsubishi 3000GT SR (J) '98Mitsubishi 3000GT VR-4 (J) '98Mitsubishi 3000GT VR-4 Turbo (J) '95Mitsubishi 3000GT VR-4 Turbo (J) '96Mitsubishi 3000GT VR-4 Turbo (J) '98Mitsubishi AIRTREK Turbo-R '02Mitsubishi COLT 1.5 Sport X Version '02Mitsubishi CZ-3 Tarmac '01Mitsubishi CZ-3 Tarmac Rally CarMitsubishi ECLIPSE GT '95Mitsubishi ECLIPSE GT '06Mitsubishi ECLIPSE Spyder GTS '03Mitsubishi FTO GP Version R '97Mitsubishi FTO GP Version R '99Mitsubishi FTO GPX '94Mitsubishi FTO GPX '97Mitsubishi FTO GPX '99Mitsubishi FTO GR '94Mitsubishi FTO GR '97Mitsubishi FTO Super Touring CarMitsubishi GALANT 2.0 DOHC Turbo VR-4 '89Mitsubishi GALANT GTO MR '70Mitsubishi GTO SR '95Mitsubishi GTO SR '96Mitsubishi GTO SR '98Mitsubishi GTO Twin Turbo '95Mitsubishi GTO Twin Turbo '96Mitsubishi GTO Twin Turbo '98Mitsubishi GTO Twin Turbo MR '95Mitsubishi GTO Twin Turbo MR '98Mitsubishi HSR-II Concept '89Mitsubishi i Concept '03Mitsubishi Lancer 1600 GSR '74Mitsubishi Lancer 1600 GSR Rally Car '74Mitsubishi Lancer EX 1800GSR IC Turbo '83Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution GSR '92Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution Super Rally Car '03Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution II GSR '94Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution III GSR '95Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution IV GSR '96Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution IV Rally Car '97Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution V GSR '98Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution VI GSR '99Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution VI GSR TOMMI MAKINEN EDITION '00Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution VI Rally Car '99Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution VI RS '99Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution VI RS TOMMI MAKINEN EDITION '00Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution VII GSR '01Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution VII GT-A '02Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution VII RS '01Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution VIII GSR '03Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution VIII RS '03Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution VIII MR GSR '04Mitsubishi LEGNUM VR-4 Type V '98Mitsubishi MINICA DANGAN ZZ '89Mitsubishi MIRAGE 1400GLX '78Mitsubishi MIRAGE CYBORG ZR '97Mitsubishi PAJERO Evolution Rally Raid Car '03Mitsubishi PAJERO Rally Raid Car '85Mitsubishi STARION 4WD Rally Car '84Nissan:Nissan 180SX Type X '96Nissan 200SX '96Nissan 200SX (S14) '96Nissan 240RS Rally Car '85Nissan 240SX '96Nissan 240SX (S14) '96Nissan 240ZG (HS30) '71Nissan 300ZX 2by2 (Z32) '98Nissan 300ZX 2seater (Z32) '89Nissan 300ZX 2seater (Z32) '98Nissan 350Z (Z33, EU) '03Nissan 350Z (Z33, US) '03Nissan 350Z Concept LM Race CarNissan 350Z Gran Turismo 4 Limited Edition (Z33) '05Nissan 350Z Roadster (Z33, EU) '03Nissan 350Z Roadster (Z33, US) '03Nissan Be-1 '87Nissan BLUEBIRD 1600 Deluxe (510) '69Nissan BLUEBIRD Hardtop 1800SSS (910) '79Nissan BLUEBIRD Rally Car (510) '69Nissan CALSONIC SKYLINE (JGTC) '00Nissan CALSONIC SKYLINE GT-R Race Car '93Nissan CUBE EX (FF/CVT) '02Nissan CUBE X '98Nissan C-WEST RAZO SILVIA (JGTC) '01Nissan EXA CANOPY L.A.Version Type S '88Nissan Fairlady 2000 (SR311) '68Nissan Fairlady 240ZG (HS30) '71Nissan Fairlady Z 280Z-L 2seater (S130) '78Nissan Fairlady Z 300ZX (Z31) '83Nissan Fairlady Z 300ZX TwinTurbo 2seater (Z32) '89Nissan Fairlady Z 300ZX Version R TwinTurbo 2by2 (Z32) '98Nissan Fairlady Z 300ZX Version S TwinTurbo 2seater (Z32) '98Nissan Fairlady Z Concept LM Race CarNissan Fairlady Z Roadster (Z33) '03Nissan Fairlady Z Version S (Z33) '02Nissan Fairlady Z Version ST (Z33 Option Wheel) '02Nissan FALKEN GT-R Race Car '04Nissan GRAN TURISMO SKYLINE GT-R '01Nissan GRAN TURISMO SKYLINE GT-R (PaceCar) '01Nissan GT-R Concept (Tokyo Motor Show 2001)Nissan GT-R Concept LM Race CarNissan GT-R SpecV '09Nissan LOCTITE ZEXEL GT-R (JGTC) '00Nissan March 12c 5door '03Nissan March G# '99Nissan MICRA '03Nissan mm-R Cup Car '01Nissan MOTUL PITWORK Z (JGTC) '04Nissan OPTION Stream Z '04Nissan PAO '89Nissan PENNZOIL Nismo GT-R (JGTC) '99Nissan PENNZOIL ZEXEL GT-R (JGTC) '01Nissan PRIMERA 2.0Te '90Nissan PRIMERA 20V '01Nissan PRIMERA 20V (EU) '01Nissan R390 GT1 Race Car '98Nissan R390 GT1 Road Car '98Nissan R89C Race Car '89Nissan R92CP Race Car '92Nissan SILEIGHTY '98Nissan SILVIA (CSP311) '65Nissan SILVIA 240RS (S100) '83Nissan SILVIA K's (S13) '91Nissan SILVIA K's (S13) '88Nissan SILVIA K's AERO (S14) '93Nissan SILVIA K's AERO (S14) '96Nissan SILVIA Q's (S13) '88Nissan SILVIA Q's (S13) '91Nissan SILVIA Q's AERO (S14) '93Nissan SILVIA Q's AERO (S14) '96Nissan SILVIA spec-R AERO (S15) '99Nissan SILVIA spec-S AERO (S15) '99Nissan SILVIA Varietta (S15) '00Nissan SKYLINE 1500Deluxe (S50D-1) '63Nissan SKYLINE 2000GT-B (S54A) '67Nissan SKYLINE 2000GT-R (KPGC110) '73Nissan SKYLINE Coupe 350GT '03Nissan SKYLINE GT-R (R32) '89Nissan SKYLINE GT-R (R32) '91Nissan SKYLINE GT-R (R33) '95Nissan SKYLINE GT-R (R33) '96Nissan SKYLINE GT-R (R33) '97Nissan SKYLINE GT-R (R34) '99Nissan SKYLINE GT-R (R34) '00Nissan SKYLINE GT-R M-spec (R34) '01Nissan SKYLINE GT-R M-spec Nur (R34) '02Nissan SKYLINE GT-R N1 (R32) '91Nissan SKYLINE GT-R N1 (R33) '95Nissan SKYLINE GT-R Midnight Purple II (R34) '99Nissan SKYLINE GT-R Midnight Purple III (R34) '00Nissan SKYLINE GT-R V-spec (R32) '93Nissan SKYLINE GT-R V-spec (R33) '97Nissan SKYLINE GT-R V-spec (R33) '95Nissan SKYLINE GT-R V-spec (R33) '96Nissan SKYLINE GT-R V-spec (R34) '99Nissan SKYLINE GT-R V-spec II (R32) '94Nissan SKYLINE GT-R V-spec II (R34) '00Nissan SKYLINE GT-R V-spec II N1 (R34) '00Nissan SKYLINE GT-R V-spec II Nur (R34) '02Nissan SKYLINE GT-R V-spec LM Limited (R33) '96Nissan SKYLINE GT-R V-spec N1 (R32) '93Nissan SKYLINE GT-R V-spec N1 (R34) '99Nissan SKYLINE GTS25 Type S (R32) '91Nissan SKYLINE GTS-R (R31) '87Nissan SKYLINE GTS-t Type M (R32) '91Nissan SKYLINE GTS-t Type M (R32) '89Nissan SKYLINE Hard Top 2000 RS-X Turbo C (R30) '84Nissan SKYLINE Hard Top 2000 Turbo RS (R30) '83Nissan SKYLINE Hard Top 2000GT-R (KPGC10) '70Nissan SKYLINE Sedan 300GT '01Nissan SKYLINE Sedan 350GT-8 '02Nissan SKYLINE Sport Coupe (BLRA-3) '62Nissan STAGEA 25t RS FOUR S '98Nissan STAGEA 260RS AutechVersion '98Nissan XANAVI HIROTO GT-R (JGTC) '01Nissan XANAVI NISMO GT-R (JGTC) '03Subaru:CUSCO SUBARU ADVAN IMPREZA (JGTC) '03Subaru IMPREZA Coupe WRX typeR STi Version VI '99Subaru IMPREZA Premium Sport Coupe 22B-STi Version '98Subaru IMPREZA Rally Car '99Subaru IMPREZA Rally Car '01Subaru IMPREZA Rally Car '03Subaru IMPREZA Rally Car Prototype '01Subaru IMPREZA Sedan WRX STi '94Subaru IMPREZA Sedan WRX STi (Type-II) '02Subaru IMPREZA Sedan WRX STi spec C (Type-II) '04Subaru IMPREZA Sedan WRX STi Version (Type-I) '00Subaru IMPREZA Sedan WRX STi Version II '95Subaru IMPREZA Sedan WRX STi Version III '96Subaru IMPREZA Sedan WRX STi Version IV '97Subaru IMPREZA Sedan WRX STi Version V '98Subaru IMPREZA Sedan WRX STi Version VI '99Subaru IMPREZA Sport Wagon STi (Type-I) '00Subaru IMPREZA Sport Wagon WRX STi Version VI '99Subaru IMPREZA Super Touring CarSubaru IMPREZA WRX STi Prodrive Style (Type-I) '01Subaru LEGACY B4 2.0GT '03Subaru LEGACY B4 2.0GT spec.B '03Subaru LEGACY B4 3.0R '03Subaru LEGACY B4 Blitzen '00Subaru LEGACY B4 RSK '98Subaru LEGACY Touring Wagon 2.0GT '03Subaru LEGACY Touring Wagon 2.0GT spec.B '03Subaru LEGACY Touring Wagon 3.0R '03Subaru LEGACY Touring Wagon GT-B '96SUBARU 360 '58Toyota:Toyota 2000GT '67Toyota ALTEZZA AS200 '98Toyota ALTEZZA Gita AS300 '01Toyota ALTEZZA RS200 '98Toyota ALTEZZA Touring CarToyota ARISTO 3.0V '91Toyota ARISTO V300 '00Toyota ARISTO V300 Vertex Edition '00Toyota au CERUMO Supra (JGTC) '01Toyota bB 1.5Z X Version '00Toyota CALDINA GT-FOUR '02Toyota CARINA ED 2.0 X 4WS '89Toyota Castrol TOM'S SUPRA (JGTC) '00Toyota Castrol TOM'S SUPRA (JGTC) '01Toyota CELICA 1600GT (TA22) '70Toyota CELICA 2000GT-FOUR (ST165) '86Toyota CELICA 2000GT-R (ST162) '86Toyota CELICA GT-FOUR (ST205) '98Toyota CELICA GT-FOUR Rally Car (ST185) '95Toyota CELICA GT-FOUR Rally Car (ST205) '95Toyota CELICA GT-FOUR RC (ST185) '91Toyota CELICA GT-R (ST183, 4WS) '91Toyota CELICA SS-II (ST202) '97Toyota CELICA SS-II (ZZT231) '99Toyota CELICA XX 2800GT '81Toyota COROLLA LEVIN BZ-R '98Toyota COROLLA LEVIN GT-APEX (AE86) '83Toyota COROLLA Rally Car '98Toyota COROLLA RUNX Z AEROTOURER '02Toyota DENSO SARD SUPRA GT (JGTC) '00Toyota GT-ONE Race Car (TS020) '99Toyota ist 1.5S '02MINOLTA Toyota 88C-V Race Car '89Toyota MR2 1600 G '86Toyota MR2 1600 G-Limited Super Charger '86Toyota MR2 G-Limited '97Toyota MR2 GT-S '97Toyota MR2 Spyder '99Toyota MR2 Spyder (6MT) '02Toyota MR-S S Edition '99Toyota MR-S V Edition (6MT) '02Toyota PRIUS G (J) '02Toyota PRIUS G Touring Selection (J) '03Toyota RSC '01Toyota RSC Rally Raid CarToyota SERA '92Toyota SOARER 2.5GT-T '97Toyota SOARER 430SCV '01Toyota SPORTS 800 '65Toyota SPRINTER TRUENO BZ-R '98Toyota SPRINTER TRUENO GT-APEX (AE86 S. Shigeno Version) '00Toyota SPRINTER TRUENO GT-APEX (AE86) '83Toyota STARLET Glanza V '97Toyota SUPERAUTOBACS APEX MR-S (JGTC) '00Toyota SUPRA 2.5GT Twin Turbo R '90Toyota SUPRA 3.0GT Turbo A '88Toyota SUPRA RZ '97Toyota SUPRA SZ-R '97Toyota Tacoma X-Runner '04Toyota 7 Race Car '70Toyota VITZ F '99Toyota VITZ RS 1.5 '00Toyota VITZ RS Turbo '02Toyota VITZ U Euro Sport Edition '00Toyota VOLTZ S '02Toyota WEDSSPORT CELICA (JGTC) '03Toyota WiLL VS '01Toyota WOODONE TOM'S SUPRA (JGTC) '03Toyota Yaris F (J) '99Toyota Yaris RS 1.5 (J) '00Toyota Yaris RS Turbo (J) '02Toyota Yaris U Euro Sport Edition (J) '00TOYOTA MODELLISTA CELICA TRD Sports M (ZZT231) '00TVR:TVR Cerbera Speed 12 '00TVR Cerbera Speed 6 '97TVR Griffith 500 '94TVR T350C '03TVR Tamora '02TVR Tuscan Speed 6 '00TVR V8S '91</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5881">Forza Motorsport 2</game><game id="17599">Forza Motorsport</game><game id="17872">TOCA Race Driver 3 Challenge</game><game id="531">TOCA Race Driver 2</game><game id="23808">Race Driver 2006</game><game id="24995">Forza Motorsport 3</game><game id="42693">Forza Motorsport 5</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1794107-box_gtpsp.png</image></root>