<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26869</id><name>Wii Fit Plus</name><description>OverviewFeatures lots of fun interactivitiesWii Fit Plus is a fitness game developed by Nintendo for the Wii. The game is an updated version of Wii Fit and was originally announced at Nintendo's E3 2009 media briefing.New features include calorie burning counter, users can now create custom fitness regimes or choose from specialized routines to follow as well as create profiles for pets and babies. New improvements have been made to game UI to allows users to switch between activities easier.The game features 15 new activities to choose from.ReleaseWii Fit Plus was released on October 1, 2009 in Japan and October 4, 2009 in the US. The game is sold bundled with a Wii Balance Board as well as separately for people who already own a Wii Balance Board.As of April 2012, Wii Fit Plus has sold 20.48 million units worldwide.ActivitiesYogaDeep BreathingHalf-MoonWarriorTreeSun SalutationStanding KneePalm TreeChairTriangleDownward-Facing DogKing of The DanceCobraBridgeCrocodile TwistShoulder StandSpine ExtensionGateGrounded VMuscle WorkoutsSingle Leg ExtensionPress-up  Side StandTorso and Waist TwistsJack-knifeLungeRowing SquatSingle Leg TwistParralel StretchTricep ExtensionArm  Leg LiftSingle Arm StandBalance BridgeSide LungeSingle Leg ReachPress-up ChallengeJackknife ChallengeStretch ChallengeAerobic ExercisesHula HoopStep basicsJoggingSuper Hula HoopStep Plus2P JoggingRythm BoxingFree StepFree JoggingBalance GamesHeadingSki SlalomSki JumpTable TiltTightrope TensionBalance BubblePenguin SlideSnowboard SlalimZazenTraining PlusPerfect 10CyclingRhythm Kung FuDriving RangeSegway® CircuitBird's-eye Bull's-eyeSnowball FightObstacle CourseTilt CityRhythm ParadeBig Top JugglingSkateboard ArenaTable Tilt PlusBalance Bubble PlusJogging Plus</description><genres><genre id="44">Fitness</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="24481">EA Sports Active</game><game id="24302">Gold's Gym: Cardio Workout</game><game id="26537">Daisy Fuentes Pilates</game><game id="28433">The Biggest Loser</game><game id="31711">Your Shape Fitness Evolved</game><game id="31743">Zumba Fitness</game><game id="31748">Pilotwings Resort</game><game id="32357">EA Sports Active NFL Training Camp</game><game id="36440">Billy's Bootcamp</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5911/1136186-wiifit.jpg</image></root>