<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26880</id><name>Flight Control</name><description>Overview There are currently five levels, all accessible from the beginning, available in the game:  Standard airfieldBeach airfield (with two helipads)Aircraft carrierAustralian OutbackWindy airfield  There are 4 types of aircraft involved. From slowest to fastest they are: Helicopter Propeller PlaneSmall JetFast Jet   Players drag the aircraft to the designated color landing zones. The Helicopter and Propeller Plane each have their own zone. The Small Jet and Fast Jet share a single zone. In the newest level, Australian Outback, the Royal Flying Doctor Service appear. These special planes are not controlled by the player and fly on a preset path to a runway.    MultiplayerThe game also features a two player cooperative mode where players share air controller duties. Both players are missing a colored landing zone and must send those aircraft to the other player's screen. This mode is playable over local Wi-Fi or Bluetooth connection.  The latest update also patched in support for Apple's              Game Center platform with new achievements and leaderboards. The existing Cloudcell service support (used for uploading high scores and leaderboards for you geographic area) is still intact. PlayStation 3 Version The game was released on September 15th, 2010 on the European PSN, under the title Flight Control HD.  This PS3 version features the following enhancements: 1080p resolution  3D technology PlayStation Move support4 player drop-in/drop-out cooperative playAn exclusive "Metropolis" map with changing day/night cycleOn September 12, 2010, just days before the PlayStation Move launch, it was          confirmed by Firemint that there would be no North American release of the game:  We  are very sad to confirm that unfortunately we do not expect Flight  Control HD for PlayStation®Move to be available in North America. We  would love to make it available everywhere but unfortunately at this  point we have exhausted all avenues for making it happen. We’d like to  thank everyone who has asked for your interest, we wish we could shed  more light on this but all we can say is that sadly, the stars just  haven’t aligned!  The PSN version was still released in the UK, Australia, and Europe.  Steam ReleaseFlight Control was released for Steam on November 18th, 2010 for $4.99/€3.99. The game is available for both PC and Mac, and has achievements, as well as Steam Cloud support.   Flight Control HD has been especially redesigned for PC  and Mac, with  updated graphics and an even tougher new challenge – the  Steam exclusive  Stunt map where you can increase your score by flying  through the gates  before landing!   This version has a total of 9 maps. This version however does not have co-op or online capabilities, except for the online leaderboards. PC System Requirements   OS: Windows XP (SP3), Vista and 7Processor: 1GHzRAM : 512MBGraphics: 64MB, DirectX 9Hard Drive: 90MBSound: Directx 9 compatible card     Mac System Requirements   OS: OS X  Leopard 10.5.8, Snow Leopard 10.6.3, or later.Processor: 1GHz (Intel Only)RAM : 512MBGraphics: 64MBHard Drive: 90MB   </description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="27158">Dock'em</game><game id="30682">Stop and Go</game><game id="6285">Locomotion</game><game id="28336">Harbor Master</game><game id="39903">Aero Porter</game><game id="42542">Men's Room Mayhem</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3699/1831629-flight_control.jpg</image></root>