<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26928</id><name>NBA 2K10</name><description>NBA 2K10 FeaturesNBA Today - Real world matchups, news and stats are automatically streamed right into the game. Also roster updates that reflect the current NBA season (trades, injuries, player ratings).My Player Mode - Players can create their own basketball player and guide him through his career. Starting as an undrafted rookie in the Summer Circuit, players will have to work their way up into an NBA team’s training camp, or in the D-League.Signature Play - New signature player styles, tendencies, dribble packages, dunk packages, and facial expressions.Reworked Gameplay - New easy-to-use dribbling and post game controls. New Stamina system.Deeper Association - The Association now incorporates the NBA Development League, the ability to control all 30 NBA teams at once, restricted free agency, real-time practice, an all-new player progression system, and a host of other enhancements.Shut Down D - Shut down teams with new defensive controls that allow you to shadow your opponent’s every move, deny position off-ball, and even select how you want to contest shots.Improved Create-A-Player Mode - Players can now customize their player's facial styles, tattoos, and shoes. Also included are new dunk packages, dribble packages, signature leaners, floaters and post moves.Save  Quit - A new gameplay feature that allows you to save a game right where you are and come back to it later to the point where you saved it.Anniversary EditionAlong with the standard edition of the game, an Anniversary edition will be available which includes:NBA 2k10 video gameNumbered 2k Sports game storage locker with combination lockExclusive McFarlane Kobe Bryant figurineExclusive 2k Sports Kobe Bryant posterNBA 2k10 10th Anniversary video exploring the history of the NBA 2k franchiseAccess to the Gold Room, NBA 2k10's VIP online lobbyThe Anniversary Edition will be available on Ps3 and 360 versions. NBA 2K10 Soundtrack Ace Hood- Top of the WorldAdam Tensta- My Cool  Akala- The Edge  Al Kapone- Rock ThisChali2na- Lock it Down (Instrumental)Chali2na– International (feat. Beenie Man)  Donnie Bravo- Run AwayDuo Live- Shootin  Flo Rida- ROOTS Iglu  Hartly- In this CityIllinois - Hang On  Izza Kizza- They’re Everywhere K’naan- Wavin’ the Flag  Kanye West- Amazing Kenan Bell - Like ThisMatisyahu - One Day Metric - Help I’m Alive  Metronomy - Radio Ladio  MGMT- Electric FeelMiike Snow- Black  Blue Naïve New Breeders- Can’t Choose Ratatat - Falcon Jab Ratatat- Mirando  Santogold- Unstoppable Saul Williams- List of Demands (Reparations)Spotrushaz- IronThe Game- Champion (Exclusive and original track)  The Moog - Joyclad ArmiesVincent Van Go Go- Do You KnowSystem RequirementsOS: Windows Vista, XP, or 2000Processor: Pentium 4 2.4 Ghz Single Core processor or equivalent (2.8 Ghz for Vista)Memory: 512 MB or more (1 GB for Vista)Graphics: Video card with 128 MB or more memory and one of the following chipsets is required: ATI x1300 or greater | NVIDIA 6600 or greater | DirectX 9.0c compatible card with Shader Model 3.0 supportDirectX®: DirectX 9.0c compatibleHard Drive: 10.5 GB or more free spaceSound: DirectX 9.0c compatible</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="22">Basketball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="27022">NBA Live 10</game><game id="28122">NBA 10 The Inside</game><game id="31439">NBA 2K11</game><game id="31438">NBA Elite 11</game><game id="2860">Fronte del Basket 2007/2008</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1810930-box_nba2k10.png</image></root>