<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26923</id><name>Trials HD</name><description>OverviewTrials HD was released as part of Xbox Live's Summer of Arcade on the 12th of August 2009 for 1200 Microsoft Points. It is an addition to the popular Trials games available on PC, and is developed by RedLynx Ltd.Trials HD is a physics-based motorcycle racing game with over 50 tracks consisting of several unique modes. Race mode emphasizes skill, balance, and control, played out on a 2D plane. Players have the ability to accelerate and brake while using the left analog stick to control the riders posture and lean backwards or forwards. There are 5 difficulty modes in all: beginner, easy, medium, hard and extreme. There are bronze, silver, gold and platinum medals to earn in each track. Medals are awarded for a mixture of time, and number of faults - the lower of each, the better.Other ModesTournament ModeTournament mode takes several of the race mode tracks and requires players to play through all consecutively. Medals are given for minimal restarts and quick completion.Skill GamesSkill Games focus more on extreme stunt tracks where explosions, crashes, and injuries are part of the game. From the get-go there are 3 games to play including ski jump and ring of fire, and a further 9 can be unlocked by clearing portions of the game. 12 more are unlocked by purchasing the Big Pack DLC. Just like other modes, medals are given for passing certain parameters. All 24 are as follows:Inside the BallPlayers are put in a metal ball and required to stay on their bike for as long as possible.Pinball Pit (DLC)Same as Inside the Ball, but the metal ball is flung around by pinball flippers.Ski JumpPlayers launch off a ski-ramp, bail out mid-air, and try to land as far down ramp as they can.Extreme Skiing (DLC)Same as Ski Jump, but the ski-ramp flicks upward as players go off to give more air time.Ring of FireFlying through rings that propel players like rockets.The Burning Eye (DLC)A much more challenging Ring of Fire course.DeliveryUsing a special bike, players must tow a bomb as far as possible without hitting bumps that will set that sucker off.The 2nd Package (DLC)A different course for the Delivery mini-game.Down the StairsPlayers bail down a large staircase in order to break their rider's bones.Pain! Again! (DLC)Another bone-breaking course.In FlamesYou are on fire and only speed can quench it.Run of Doom (DLC)A harder fire course.Target HuntBreak as many floating targets in two minutes.Paddle Wizard (DLC)A giant pinball machine with targets just waiting to be broken.Hill ClimbClimb a steep incline as far as you can.Mountain Climb (DLC)Climb an insanely steep incline as far as you can.Outside the BallRiding outside the metal ball instead of inside.Down the Mines (DLC)An intense version of Outside the BallInfernal PinballGet flung by pinball flippers to reach as high a point in the level as possible.Flugtag (DLC)Fly a rocket ship as high as possible.Flip HunterFlip your bike over and over to win.Turbo Flip (DLC)A faster, crazier version of Flip Hunter.Loose Screw!Your front tire is loose and will fall off unless you do a wheelie. Go as far as you can.Extreme Torque (DLC)A harder course for Loose Screw!Trials HD also features a level editor, allowing the player to create and share their tracks with friends. Players can also download user created tracks, but this is limited to only those on their friends list.Redlynx recently announced the Track Creator Challenge. This is a contest in which players are asked to create and submit their track. Prizes include cash ($5,000 for first place), tee-shirts and flags. The top 10 tracks will be used in the upcoming Big Thrills pack.Miscellaneous Features:Rider CustomizationUnlockable bikesGlobal rankings for each raceTop ranked replaysDLCThe following DLC has been released for Trials HD over XBL:Big Pack - Released on 23rd December 2009 for 400 MS points.Includes 35 new tracks12 new skill games5 new tournaments50 new track editor objectsThree new achievements worth 50 pointsBig Thrills Pack - Released on December 1st, 2010 for 400 MS points.Includes 40 new tracks from publisher Red Lynx10 new tracks from users3 new achievement worth 50 gamer scoreTrivia• On September 2009, Trials HD was reported to have sold over 300,000 copies since its launch.• According to Xbox LIVE users, Trials HD was the best XBL Arcade game of 2009. It also was the most innovative.• The voice overs for the game are provided by Art Webb, Brandon DiCamillo and Rake Yohn who all appear in the CKY videos made famous by Bam Margera.• There is a small Easter egg after the credits that appear to be the ramblings of a crazy developer. Unlockable Gamer PicturesThere are two unlockable gamer pictures in Trials HD.Getting the "Full Throttle" achievement will earn you the gamer pic with the guy riding with no hands. Beating all the extreme tracks will earn you the gamer pic with the devil who has handlebars for horns.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="335">Kikstart: Off-Road Simulator</game><game id="15042">Kikstart 2</game><game id="12765">Elasto Mania</game><game id="15025">Excitebike</game><game id="15429">Excitebike 64</game><game id="30055">Pixel Boarder</game><game id="28484">Joe Danger</game><game id="29109">Excitebike World Rally</game><game id="32533">MotoHeroz</game><game id="33114">Doritos Crash Course</game><game id="31798">Swarm</game><game id="32914">Old School Racer</game><game id="36129">Joe Danger 2: The Movie</game><game id="36705">Trial Xtreme</game><game id="11810">Wheelie</game><game id="37488">Toy Stunt Bike 2</game><game id="38573">Bike Race</game><game id="42716">Element4l</game><game id="40679">Urban Trial Freestyle</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1841455-box_thd.png</image></root>