<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2693</id><name>Hover Strike</name><description>Hover Strike was released onto the Atari Jaguar platform in early 1995. It is similar in build and game play action to Cyber morph, which was released as a free game bundled with the Jaguar console. The game features a high level of strategy, and also has a tough learning curve.In-game shot.The game is set in dystopian future where the federation (the good guys) are at war throughout galaxy against Terrakian pirates (the bad guys), who have taken over control of a distant colonial planet. They have slaughtered many and have enslaved the whole populace (as bad guys usually do), and they must stop. A federation rescue armada has been assembled, but are kept at arms length by a Terrakian atmospheric cannon and a highly sophisticated defense matrix.A secrete plan is hatched using the new highly advanced HS709 armored hover tank, which will be dropped behind enemy lines. It will be up to you, as the pilot of the strike craft to destroy all Terrakian installations and ground vessels, as well as to disable the atmospheric cannon. Eventually allowing for the federation armada to attack, re-take the planet and free the surviving colonists. There are 30 levels within the game, set over various terrains and differing visual conditions. These missions are divided into sub groups of six. You can upgrade you hover craft by Finding power-ups through out the levels. The game features reasonable graphics and sound for the Atari Jaguar, using texture mapping and shading throughout, with night missions featuring an impressive use of  flare source-lighting effects. Though at times the frame rate can slow up a bit and interfere slightly with the game play.Kill the Terrakian!Overall the game is quite challenging and varied with enough interesting missions to keep you playing. It was definitely one of the better games to be released for the Jaguar system in its lifetime. </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2059552-hover_strike_front.jpg</image></root>