<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26957</id><name>Wangan Midnight Maximum Tune 2</name><description>SummaryWangan Midnight Maximum Tune 2 is the second game in the Maximum Tune series once again pitting players against CPU or against eachother in the streets of tokyo and the rural mountain passes. Once again it features cross-cabinet multiplayer in which players race competitively with their own customized car. The game allows players to upgrade their car and store that data on amagnetic card, much like the first. As well as multiplayer, the game features a single player story and time attack mode as well as a brand new mode known as 10-out-run. The arcade cabinet retains the same hardware features of the first game featuring a gear input, pedals and a steering wheel.This game has a variety of different tracks from the first which the player can choose to race on either the day or night variationNew FeaturesNew mode single player, 10-Out-Run: The player must overtake 10 opponents each catagorized by a grade ranking system.Different track variation featuring new tracks.More car tuning detailsTechnical DetailsThis game used the Sega Chihiro type arcade system.The game ran on the RenderWare engineThe game features magnetic cards.MusicThe game features a multitude trance tracks by composerYuzo Koshirowhich are played whilst the player races. The games popularity justified the release of an official sound track disk much like the first.01 Overdrive Neurotransmitters02 Maximum Acceleration03 Stream Of Tears(more tranced remix)04 Feel the Passion05 Beyond The Horizon06 Upbeat Gas Junkie07 Fun-Loving Spirit08 Speed Fenatic09 Driver's Delight10 Decoration For The Dement11 Ghost in the Resonance12 Stream Of Tears13 Total Terror14 Smoldery Guest15 Atheist On The Highway16 This is My Destiny17 Unlawful Temptation18 Acid Runner19 Nothing Lives Forever20 Destination Blackout21 Blue Blazes22 Another Dimension23 Holy Land Anthem</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21657">Initial D: Extreme Stage</game><game id="21830">Initial D: Street Stage</game><game id="12805">Initial D: Special Stage</game><game id="5732">Initial D: Mountain Vengeance</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/12621/1047601-untitled_1.jpg</image></root>