<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>26958</id><name>Wangan Midnight Maximum Tune 3</name><description>SummaryWangan Midnight Maximum Tune 3 is the 3rd installment of the  arcade tokyo street racing game. Again it features cross-cabinet multiplayer support in which players race competitively with their own customized car. The game allows players to upgrade their car and store that data on a  magnetic card, a feature which was well recieved in the previous installments. As well as multiplayer, the game features a single player story and time attack mode, additionally a ghost battle mode is added. The arcade cabinet features a gear input, pedals and a steering wheel.The game has a variety of tracks which the player can choose to race on either the day or night variation On March 4th, 2010, a DX Plus version of the game was released.New FeaturesNew variety of tracks to race onGhost battle mode: Race against ghost drivers which were recorded from previous players goes. Ghosts are calculated on their skill level and like 10-out-run mode are seperated into class grades.More extensive tuning regarding car visualsUpdated graphic engine.Technical DetailsThis game used the System N2 type arcade system still featuring the standard car racing input methods.The game ran on the System N2  engine, providing improved graphics over the previous installments.The game features  magnetic cards.MusicLike the previous 2 games in the series, this game also features a variety of trance tracks by composer  Yuzo Koshiro. The games popularity justified the release of another official sound track disk.01  Overdrive Neurotransmitters02  Maximum Acceleration03  Stream Of Tears(more tranced remix)04  Feel the Passion05  Beyond The Horizon06  Upbeat Gas Junkie07  Fun-Loving Spirit08  Speed Fenatic09  Driver's Delight10  Decoration For The Dement11  Ghost in the Resonance12  Stream Of Tears13  Total Terror14  Smoldery Guest15  Atheist On The Highway16  This is My Destiny17  Unlawful Temptation18  Acid Runner19  Nothing Lives Forever20  Destination Blackout21  Blue Blazes22  Another Dimension23  Holy Land Anthem</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21657">Initial D: Extreme Stage</game><game id="21830">Initial D: Street Stage</game><game id="12805">Initial D: Special Stage</game><game id="5732">Initial D: Mountain Vengeance</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/12621/1047602-untitled_1.jpg</image></root>