<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27028</id><name>Mirror's Edge</name><description>OverviewMirror's Edge is a reboot of the first game with the same name, again starring the "runner" Faith and her struggle against the oppressive government agents in a dystopian future. It has been described as an "open-world action adventure" built on Frostbite.Rumors, Leaks,  RevealOn July 12, 2009 a Mirror's Edge game was confirmed by President of EA Games Europe Patrick Soderlund as being considered for development, saying"You will see another Mirror's Edge for sure. It's just a matter of when that time is and what we do with it. We have a small team on it and I'm excited about what we do...Mirror's Edge was a risky move. It was a bold move, a very innovative and inspiring move. The game wasn't perfect by any means. We would have liked the game to sell better, even though the game has sold better than most people think."In a February 2011 interview with Vicachu, Soderlund revealed that development work on Mirror's Edge 2 had stalled in favor of other projects, again citing the lack of Mirror's Edge sales as a disincentive for continuing work on the title.On November 22 2012, Ben Cousins, the former executive producer of the Battlefield series, mentioned on twitter in regards to DICE working only in the Battlefield games that: "It is general knowledge in the Stockholm dev scene that Mirror's Edge 2 is in production as DICE."In May 2013, listings for the game briefly appeared on a few European Amazon websites, which were quickly removed. On May 30th, 2013, it was noticed that a help page for Mirror's Edge 2 existed on the EA website itself, but was promptly deleted later that same day.AnnouncementThe game was officially announced on June 10th, 2013 at EA's E3 Press Conference. Some gameplay was revealed of Faith fighting masked agents, intercut with her receiving a tattoo on her arm (a tattoo she already has in the original game, suggesting the game is a prequel). The game was announced for PC, Xbox One, and PS4, with no release date given, only that it will come "when it is ready."On June 12, 2013, Patrick Söderlund explained in an interview that the game will be different compared to the first game. The original game received criticism on how it handled combat situations. Söderlund addressed this by saying: "The first game was a lot about running away from things and, even though you want to have sections with that, you also want Faith... she's a powerful character and you want her to take control. You'll see a little bit more of that in this game.'' At the same time, he made sure to explain that the game will not become a shooter saying: "Again, we're not going to turn this into a shooter. On the contrary, in fact. But we are going to evolve Faith and the story. Once we show more of this people will be genuinely excited. I am personally extremely excited about it."</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2840/2495671-mirrors_edge_wallpaper_2.jpg</image></root>