<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27065</id><name>Macross Ultimate Frontier</name><description> OverviewMacross Ultimate Frontier is the sequel of Macross Ace Frontier, which itself is derived from the Gundam Battle series by developer Artdink.  While Ace Frontier merely covered the six most well-known series in the Macross franchise, Ultimate Frontier delves into spin-offs and side-stories, including the ill-received Macross II (which receives its first video game representation in over 15 years). Several new subsystems are added in this game, including Support Characters and Antii-Missile attacks.Featured Macross SeriesSuper Dimensional Fortress MacrossSuper Dimensional Fortress Macross: Do You Remember Love?Super Dimensional Fortress Macross: Flash Back 2012 (new)Super Dimensional Fortress Macross II: Lovers Again (new)Macross PlusMacross 7Macross 7 Dynamite (new)Macross FrontierMacross Zero       Macross VF-X 2 (new)       Macross M3 (new) Macross II, Flash Back 2012, M3, and VF-X 2 are not given full-fledged campaigns.  Starting Characters Pilot Yuuto KaguraGary MardockLewis Fernando (new)Miyuki ShirakawaHilda V. BelgenYui Hoshimura (new) Operator Yuu AkimizuClaire StanfordItsuki YamashiroBinon Collette (new)Misa HayaseNew Features-Scenes from the various anime.  -Support Character. A third character that is created at the start of the game, the Support Character holds the player's skills. All pilots can become Support Characters, and some characters that cannot become pilots normally (such as Lynn Minmay) can also serve as Support characters. -Auto Skill. A new type of skill that is somewhat similar to the skill system of     Gundam Battle Universe. These skills are constantly active.-Missile Alert. A system that allows the player's machine to automatically target and shoot down enemy missiles. This new ability is restricted by the "Anti" gauge.  - Real Flight. A new type of control option; when in Fighter Mode, the unit's controls resemble that of a flight sim.-Special equipment such as FAST packs are equipped onto preexisting units, as opposed to the combined unit becoming a separate unit of its own. The armor can be detached with sufficient damage or manually.  -Custom Soundtracks are introduced.-A new shop system is introduced, which allows players to unlock features easier (they can still be unlocked by earning high ranks in missions).</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22918">Macross Ace Frontier</game><game id="23091">Gundam Battle Universe</game><game id="29686">Gundam Assault Survive</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/16207/1060456-muf.jpg</image></root>