<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27103</id><name>The Polynomial: Space of the Music</name><description>Developed independently by Dmytry Lavrov.GameplayPolynomial generates abstract worlds with fractal arts based on music or mic input from the player. The game is essentially a shooter set in these worlds and scores players based on 1, 5, 20 or 60 minutes of gameplay. There is a survival mode which scores players based on all their actions without dying.Fractals!Players can also turn the difficulty down to "none" and simply explore the worlds and collect flowers or warp through wormholes.The player can import any music file playable in Windows Media Player to play in the game. The game can also recognize play-lists in the .m3u format, but they must be placed in a specific directory. Unlike similar games like Audiosurf, there is no length limit imposed on the music file, so the player can also play Podcasts like the Bombcast.Development  ReleaseThe game has been in beta since 2009 and was known as just "Polynomial" during development. Initially, the game accepted random variables to generate it's fractal art. In 2010, the beta versions started supporting music  mic input. The game was renamed to The Polynomial: Space of the Music and released for PC and MAC through Steam on Oct. 15, 2010. Notably, the developer has also personally optimized the game for use in WINE on Linux, and it functions perfectly on the platform. As of the end of December 2012 Polynomial released on Steam for Linux as a native client.System RequirementsWindows System RequirementsMac System RequirementsOS: Windows XP / Vista / 7 / 7 , 32 or 64-bitProcessor: Pentium IV 1.5GHzMemory: 512MBGraphics: 256MB video memory, 512MB or more recommendedVideo: OpenGL: 2.1 , GLSL: 1.2Hard Drive: 100MBOS: OS X Snow Leopard 10.6.3, or later.Processor: Intel Mac 1.5GHz or betterMemory: 512MBGraphics: 256MB video memory, 512MB recommended.Video: OpenGL: 2.1 , GLSL: 1.2Hard Drive: 100MBLinux System RequirmentsOS: Ubuntu 12.04 LTS, fully updatedProcessor: Intel Core 2 1.8GHz, AMD Athlon 2GHz, or betterMemory: 1GB RAMGraphics: NVIDIA® GeForce® 7600 or better, ATI Radeon®HD 2000 series or better, with 256MB video memory (512 MB recommended).Intel HD cards may hang up or have very low framerate.Hard Drive: 100MB    </description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21167">Geometry Wars: Retro Evolved 2</game><game id="11099">Geometry Wars: Retro Evolved</game><game id="16151">Geometry Wars: Galaxies</game><game id="29407">Beat Hazard</game><game id="9436">Audiosurf</game><game id="7271">Space Giraffe</game><game id="30472">Turba</game><game id="32141">Rhythm Zone</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3661/1560435-header_292x136.jpg</image></root>