<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27148</id><name>Let's Make a Soccer Team!</name><description>OverviewLet's Make a Soccer Team! (known in Japan as "Pro Soccer Club o Tsukurou! Euro Championship") is a football management game where the player creates and manages a football club to the top of their particular country. The game differs from other football management sims as the player is both the chairman and the creator of their club. The game was not released in North America but it was released in Europe and Japan.PremiseA look at the game's tactics screen.At the beginning of the game, the player must first choose a nation to create their club in. Once the nation is chosen, the design and colour of the club's kit, the team's playing style, and the club's secretary are chosen. A history of football is then shown. The game then begins at the last three games of the 2005/2006 season. A wealthy businessman, Mr. Leonard, is threatening to take over the team and strip it of all of it's assets. The player must then win promotion so they can build their squad in order to try gain promotion to the country's top division. The game then officialy begins at the play-offs for the Second Division. If the player is knocked out of the tournament, it is a " Game Over".The main goal for the player is to make their way to the top division and to win it. The game also have a number of conditions for a "Game Over". These include:If the player's club becomes financially bankrupt and runs out of funds.If the player places last in the Second Division for two years in a row.If the player can not field 16 fit players for a match.The game then continues on until the player reaches the top. A series of cut scenes and dialogue take place throughout the game's story.LocationsThe player can choose to build a club from a number of European nations. They are:EnglandFranceSpainItalyThe NetherlandsGermanyScotlandWalesRepublic of IrelandNorthern IrelandMonacoReceptionPlayers during a training session.Let's Make a Soccer Team was met with a mixed critical reaction when the game was released in Europe. Some reviewers enjoyed their experince but many slated the game. The game was given praise for it's decent 3D graphics engine and originality. Other reviewers critiqued the game's poor UI and how the game's story and main gameplay takes some time to get into full swing.TriviaThe former Italian footballer Roberto Baggio endorsed the Japanese version of this game.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="40">Soccer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21030">FIFA Soccer 09</game><game id="26702">FIFA 10</game><game id="20959">Pro Evolution Soccer 2009</game><game id="13165">Pro Evolution Soccer 2008</game><game id="23498">Football Manager 2009</game><game id="20784">Football Manager 2008</game><game id="10269">Championship Manager 2006</game><game id="10275">Championship Manager: Season 00/01</game><game id="29209">FIFA Manager 10</game><game id="27814">Football Manager 2010</game><game id="25791">Pro Evolution Soccer 2010</game><game id="38712">Soccer Tsuku DS: World Challenge 2010</game><game id="38713">Soccer Tsuku DS: Touch and Direct</game><game id="38714">J-League Pro Soccer Club o Tsukurou! 7 Euro Plus</game><game id="38721">J-League Pro Soccer Club o Tsukurou! 5</game><game id="38727">J-League Pro Soccer Club o Tsukurou!</game><game id="38728">J-League Pro Soccer Club o Tsukurou! 2</game><game id="38858">Virtua Pro Football</game><game id="39259">J-League Pro Soccer Club o Tsukurou! 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1099/1065100-256px_let_s_make_a_soccer_team_.jpg</image></root>