<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>272</id><name>Gaelic Games: Football 2</name><description>Gaelic Games: Football 2 is the sequel to the bestselling Gaelic Games: Football. It was developed by Transmission Games and was published by Sony Computer Entertainment Europe.  It contained new features and improvements over it predecessor. The game was criticized for its continued lack of official players and poor graphics. Though the game is known as fairly better than the original.  New AdditionsNew Career Mode:  Pick from one of 32 counties and take part in a GAA season. You can take part in the National League and the All-Ireland Championships. New Clubs:You could pick from all new county clubs. Mission Mode: Play old GAA games from the past. Each with it's own objective New Tactics Selection: Newstrategiesand formations can be applied, for more in-depth gameplay. Edit Mode: Can change kit, badge etc. of each club in the game. Training: This allowed players to adjust to the game and help increase their skills  New Controls: An all new control system to give more control to your players  ClubsSeveral new teams are in Gaelic Games Football 2. They are as follows:The graphics have improved since the first gameMunsterKerry Cork Waterford Clare Tipperary Limerick  ConnachtSligo Roscommon New York Galway London Leitrim Mayo  UlsterTyrone Armagh Donegal Monaghen  Cavan Down Fermanagh Derry Antrim  LeinsterDublin Kildare Louth Laois Carlow Kilkenny Wexford Longford Wicklow Meath Westmeath Offaly  StadiumsAll the stadiums from the first game returned in this version. Not every stadium used in the GAA championships are in the game due to licensing rights.  Here they are listed along with the counties they are in:Croke Park, Co. DublinCroke Park Parnell Park, Co. Dublin  Casement Park, Co. Antrim Pairc Ui Chaoimh* (O'Caoimh Park), Co. Cork O'Moore Park, Co. Laois Gaelic Grounds, Co. Limerick Pairc Taitleann*, Co. Meath St.Tiernach's Park, Co. Monaghan Pearse Stadium, Co. Galway FitzGerald Stadium, Co. Kerry Dr.Hyde Park, Co. Roscommon  (*)= Names in Irish</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="40">Soccer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21612">90 Minutes: European Prime Goal</game><game id="17382">Gaelic Games: Hurling</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14452/783251-gaelic_games_football_2_box_art.jpg</image></root>