<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27204</id><name>Gods Eater Burst</name><description>StorySet in an apocalyptic future, you play as a custom user created main character who has just been accepted into the ranks of the Gods Eaters. The Gods Eater are an elite group of humans who serve as humanities last defense against the Aragami, a mysterious and powerful species that threatens the extinction of mankind. Nobody knows where the Aragami came from, they just appeared from nowhere one day. They have no brains or hearts, as they are actually a colony of hundreds of thousands of oracle cells (single celled organisms) which means they cannot be harmed by conventional weapons.It is for this reason the Gods Eaters created the God Arcs, an advanced type of bio-weaponry embedded with oracle cells to stop the fusing of the Aragami cells.GameplayThere are over 100 missions to complete in the game. Gods Eater will let you customize your weapons based on materials you find during missions. You have to team up with three other God Eaters, NPC's or human players through wi-fi, to defeat the Aragami.PS Vita CompatibilityDespite not being in the official compatibility list, Gods Eater Burst can be played on the PS Vita. To do this, the user must first download the game to the PS3. From there, go to Content Transfer on the PS Vita and select the game for transfer. Once complete, the game will show up on the Vita's menu.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20887">Phantasy Star Portable</game><game id="13822">Monster Hunter Freedom</game><game id="20223">Monster Hunter Freedom 2</game><game id="25935">Monster Hunter Freedom Unite</game><game id="25694">Ys I &amp; II Chronicles</game><game id="21447">Kingdom Hearts: Birth by Sleep</game><game id="21108">Star Ocean: First Departure</game><game id="21464">Star Ocean:  Second Evolution</game><game id="21441">Tales of Destiny 2</game><game id="595">Tales of Eternia</game><game id="1335">Tales of Destiny</game><game id="255">Tales of Phantasia</game><game id="11703">Tales of Rebirth</game><game id="28428">Exorsister</game><game id="25133">.hack//Link</game><game id="27657">Phantasy Star Portable 2</game><game id="24309">Dynasty Warriors: Strikeforce</game><game id="30378">Dynasty Warriors: Strikeforce 2</game><game id="24944">Monster Hunter G</game><game id="30580">Monster Hunter Portable 3rd</game><game id="32630">Lord of Arcana</game><game id="33334">White Knight Chronicles: Origins</game><game id="36432">Lord of Apocalypse</game><game id="38047">Soul Sacrifice</game><game id="39200">God Eater</game><game id="36422">Ragnarok Odyssey</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2213159-box_geb.png</image></root>