<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27218</id><name>Two Worlds II</name><description>StoryContinuing the story of the first Two Worlds, the game sees the return of the player character from the first game still trapped in prison, slowly having the life energy sucked out of him by Lord Gandohar which he uses to keep the players sister Kyra imprisoned while he continues his experiments on her.Shortly afterwards the player character is broken out out prison by the orcs and since having the life drained out of him, has lost all of his powers. The rest of the games story is comprised of regaining his lost powers and continuing his battle against Gandohar.SettingOne of the islands of Antaloor.Taking place in the same territory as the original, the kingdom of Antaloor has undergone some changes since it was last seen. Boasting over 60 square kilometers of open world area to explore, Two Worlds II's world consists of two large islands and a number of smaller ones that players can travel to by sail boat or by teleport.These island can range from vast, open savannas populated by cheetahs, rhinos and warthogs to dense jungles all of which can be explored by the player.GameplayCombat in Two Worlds II.The Combat of Two Worlds II is greatly improved over its predecessor adding 4 attacks and multiple special moves for each weapon in the game. There is also crafting which can be used by placing stones into various pieces of equipment. Also new to the game is pick pocketing which can range from simply picking someone's pocket to full-on store robberies.Your also able to fully customize your equipment (colors, symbols etc.), however, this requires a special profession. The player even has the ability to start his own small factories where you can hire certain Non Player Characters to work and make items for you. Paying them more than average helps them make better items while paying them less than average will decrease the quality of the items.Much of the gameplay revolves around dungeon exploration with mainly standard fetch quests. Like similar open world RPGs, it is easy to wander into areas for which the player character is under-leveled.ReceptionCritically, Two Worlds II received mixed reviews with IGN scoring the game a 6.0 out of 10 and saying "An inventive spell system and multiplayer element don't make Two Worlds II good, unfortunately" and Gamespot scoring the game a 7.5 out of ten and saying " This role-playing sequel's big world and seemingly countless quests make it easy to overlook it's wrinkles".PC System RequirementsMinimum SpecificationsProcessor: Intel Pentium 4 @ 2.0 Ghz / AMD Athlon 2400+RAM: Windows XP - 1 GB / Windows 7 or Vista - 2 GBOS: Windows XPGraphics Card: 256 MB - Pixel / Vertex shader 3.0Sound Card: DirectX 9 compatibleHard Drive Space: 8 GB2x DVD-RomKeyboard, MouseRecommended SpecificationsProcessor: Intel Core 2 DUO @ 2.6 Ghz / AMD Athlon 64 X2 4200+RAM: 4 GBOS: Windows Vista / 7Graphics Card: 512 MB - Pixel / Vertex shader 4.0Sound Card: DirectX 9 compatibleHard Drive Space: 8 GB8x DVD-RomKeyboard, Mouse</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20238">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion</game><game id="7753">Gothic 3</game><game id="21846">Gothic 3 : Forsaken Gods</game><game id="24057">Demon's Souls</game><game id="33129">Divinity II: The Dragon Knight Saga</game><game id="23796">Arcania: Gothic 4</game><game id="14759">Two Worlds</game><game id="27878">Fable III</game><game id="28178">The Witcher 2: Assassins of Kings</game><game id="33149">Risen 2: Dark Waters</game><game id="43607">Fable Legends</game><game id="42844">Fable Anniversary</game><game id="35539">Fable: The Journey</game><game id="20514">Fable II</game><game id="3264">Fable</game><game id="41484">The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt</game><game id="10473">The Witcher</game><game id="35398">Dragon Age: Inquisition</game><game id="30995">Dragon Age II</game><game id="20738">Dragon Age: Origins</game><game id="38206">The Elder Scrolls Online</game><game id="33394">The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim</game><game id="17367">The Elder Scrolls III: Morrowind</game><game id="1129">The Elder Scrolls II: Daggerfall</game><game id="7513">The Elder Scrolls: Arena</game><game id="40798">Dark Souls II</game><game id="32697">Dark Souls</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1828917-box_tw2.png</image></root>