<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27256</id><name>Kenka Bancho: Badass Rumble</name><description>Badass OverviewKenka Bancho: Badass Rumble is the North American localized version of Kenka Bancho 3: Zenkoku Seiha.Takashi, being a badass.Badass Rumble stars Takashi Sakamoto, a particularly badass high school senior (the badassest at his high school), on an unbearably boring school trip to the historical and cultural mecca of Kyouto (not to be confused with Kyoto). As luck would have it, 47 other badass banchos are in Kyouto as well, sent by their serendipitously like-minded high schools, with each bancho being the toughest representative from their region.With a week to spend in Kyouto, players control Takashi with the primary goal of proving that he is the toughest hombre in town, and by extension Japan, by means of "serving knuckle sandwiches at the all-you-can-eat buffet."Takashi, taking full advantage of being a bancho.Gameplay revolves around being able to "fight practically anyone" in the city, with the aim being to beat the other banchos to earn their loyalty, territory, and special moves over the course of a week. However, the game is open-ended and allows the player to wander the city and do as they please.Though the player is a bancho, they are not specifically a bully or a criminal, participating primarily in consensual brawls. Attacking bystanders, destroying property, using weapons, and being a wimp are frowned upon.The player can customize Takashi's hairstyle, clothing, facial hair, and fighting style over the course of the game. The game also features two-player ad-hoc co-op.North American LocalizationKenka Bancho 3 was localised for North America by Atlus USA. The name Kenka Bancho: Badass Rumble was chosen by the Atlus Faithful who voted for the name in an online survey. The number was removed from the title as it is the first in the series to be officially released outside of Japan.The list of prospective names was:Kenka BanchoBadassBadass RumbleKenka Bancho: Badass RumbleTurf WarsKenka Bancho: Turf WarBancho RoyaleFist of the BanchoRise of the BanchoFurther ReadingThe official website has more information, including an explanation of what a bancho is and is not.</description><genres><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16206">The Warriors</game><game id="6608">River City Ransom</game><game id="25040">Tokyo Beat Down</game><game id="5888">God Hand</game><game id="7180">Yakuza</game><game id="13147">Yakuza 2</game><game id="10281">Bully</game><game id="5092">Bully: Scholarship Edition</game><game id="22304">Yakuza 3</game><game id="31243">Kurohyou: Ryu ga Gotoku Shinshou</game><game id="27487">Yakuza 4</game><game id="37804">Kurohyou 2: Ryu ga Gotoku Asura-hen</game><game id="39057">Kenka Bancho Bros.: Tokyo Battle Royale</game><game id="8163">Shodai: Nekketsu Kouha Kunio-kun</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1836589-box_kbancho.png</image></root>