<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>2726</id><name>Star Wars: Episode I - Jedi Power Battles</name><description>OverviewStar Wars Episode I: Jedi Power Battles was released on the Playstation on March 31, 2000 and later on the Dreamcast. It takes place within the events of Episode I: The Phantom Menace. The game is an action with platforming elements.The game is set on the worlds of Naboo, Tatooine, Coruscant, and a Trade Federation Battleship. There are a number of playable characters including Obi-Wan Kenobi, Qui-Gon Jinn, Mace Windu, Adi Gallia, and Plo Koon.Made by LucasArts, Jedi Power Battles was released shortly after the direct movie tie-in; "Stars Wars Episode One; The Phantom Menace". Unlike this previous game, the focus is almost entirely on action, and the game's 10 levels take the form of memorable battles that are loosely based on locations and events from the film. The game also has a basic leveling system, based on how many points you're able to amass playing each level. You're able to upgrade both your health, and the amount of force power energy you have.CharactersThe game lets the player take control of five Jedi from the era of episodes 1-3, each with their own special Force abilities. These Jedi, and their starting special abilities are as follows:Qui-Gon Jinn - Shockwave: Qui-Gon releases the power of the Force in a 360-degree attack.Obi-Wan Kenobi - Saber Dash: Obi-Wan races forward, cutting down enemies in his path.Mace Windu - Saber Shield: Mace causes his lightsaber to spin around him for quick protection.Adi Gallia - Mesmerize: Adi lulls nearby enemies into a trance.Plo Koon - Saber Cyclone: Plo whirls around in a 360-degree spin with his lightsaber.You can also unlock more characters to play as:Darth Maul - Complete the game as Qui-Gon Jinn.Captain Panaka - Complete the game as Obi Wan Kenobi on the Dreamcast, or Plo Koon on the Playstation.Battle Droid - Complete the first level as all five starting characters. (Dreamcast only)Queen Amidala - Complete the game as Adi Gallia on the Dreamcast, or Obi-Wan on the Playstation.Ki-Adi-Mundi - Complete all seven training levels, then save the game. (Dreamcast only)Most of the characters have a lightsaber as their primary weapon (the exceptions being Amidala and Panaka). As the game is more action based than the official movie game, the combat system is made paramount. The player can lock onto an enemy, and then use combo attacks to defeat them. Lasers can also be deflected using the lightsaber by timing the block button just as the blast is about to hit you.Levels01 Trade Federation BattleshipPoints EarnedBonus Level8,000Combo Bonus16,000Energy Bonus24,000Extra Life Bonus02 Swamps of NabooPoints EarnedBonus Level7,000Combo Bonus14,000Energy Bonus21,000Force Bonus03 City of TheedPoints EarnedBonus Level10,500Energy Bonus21,000Combo Bonus31,500Attack Bonus04 Theed PalacePoints EarnedBonus Level14,000Energy Bonus26,000Combo Bonus39,000Defense Bonus05 TatooinePoints EarnedBonus Level12,000Combo Bonus23,000Energy Bonus34,000Force Bonus06 CoruscantPoints EarnedBonus Level17,000Combo Bonus34,000Energy Bonus51,000Attack Bonus07 RuinsPoints EarnedBonus Level20,000Energy Bonus25,000Combo Bonus30,000Defense Bonus08 Streets of TheedPoints EarnedBonus Level2,550Extra Life Bonus5,100Combo Bonus7,650Energy Bonus09 Palace CliffsPoints EarnedBonus Level5,000Extra Life Bonus9,000Energy Bonus14,000Combo Bonus10 Final BattlePoints EarnedBonus Level4,000Combo Bonus8,000Energy Bonus12,000Attack BonusBoss Fights01 Trade Federation Battleship - Loader Droid / Starfighter Droid02 Swamps of Naboo - Slaatik Hagworm03 City of Theed - Turret Droid04 Theed Palace - Plasma Droids05 Tatooine - Armored Krakkiss / Darth Maul06 Coruscant - Thug Boss07 Ruins - Gungan Security Chief08 Streets of Theed - N/A09 Palace Cliffs - N/A10 Final Battle - Darth MaulEnemiesBattle Droid (100 Points)Pilot Droid (50 Points)Security Droid (150 Points)Rifle Droid (100 Points)Commander Droid (200 Points)Grapple Droid (350 Points)Flame Droid (350 Points)Plasma Droid (350 Points)Stap (200 Points)Destroyer Droid (300 Points)Tusken Raider (150 Points / 200 Points)Jawa (50 Points)Probe Droid (100 Points / 150 Points)Coruscant Thugs (100 Points / 150 Points)Kreetle (100 Points)Carnivorous PlantGungans (100 Points)Dreamcast VersionThe original PlayStation release was for the most part received fairly negatively by critics, but it should be noted that the Dreamcast version was a much more refined version of the original game, going beyond being a simple port. The Dreamcast version featured improved graphics, a new front-end menu, a competitive multiplayer mode that allowed you to play as nearly every character in the game (including enemies), as well as alterations in gameplay to moderate the difficulty level.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14541">Star Wars: Episode I - The Phantom Menace</game><game id="251">LEGO Star Wars: The Video Game</game><game id="9631">LEGO Star Wars II: The Original Trilogy</game><game id="18331">Star Wars: Episode II - Attack of the Clones</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1787602-box_swe1jpb.png</image></root>