<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27410</id><name>Punch-Out!!</name><description>OverviewPunch-Out!! is an arcade boxing title released by  Nintendo, in Japan in 1983 and North America in 1984. It was the debut title in the long-running Punch-Out!! franchise and featured the first appearance of many characters who have remained featured in the series since then.GameplayThe player controls an unnamed green-haired boxer who is displayed from a behind-the-back view as a green wire-frame during gameplay - this was done to allow the player to see the opponent more easily. The player can throw high and low / right and left punches using two buttons in combination with the joystick, as well as press a third, larger button that is used for a "super punch" - either an uppercut or hook - when the player fills an on-screen meter via landing multiple normal punches. The player must quickly react to visual cues from the opponent in order to block or dodge incoming punches.The player works his way through a series of opponents until they earn the right to face the world champion, Mr. Sandman. Like many arcade games from the same era, Punch-Out!! does not have a true ending. If you progress through all of the boxers and manage to win the world title, the game starts you over at the first opponent again. The second time through your green wireframe character is yellow, and the opponents have different colored attire and display more complex and dangerous techniques.Unlike the later home games in the Punch-Out!! franchise, there is only one round per fight. The player must KO his opponent within that one round. If the time expires it goes to a "decision" which results in a loss for the player. Although there is technically no TKO win condition in the game, three knockdowns (either to the opponent or player) will result in a knockout.OpponentsIn order of appearance: Glass Joe Piston Hurricane Bald Bull Kid Quick Pizza Pasta Mr. Sandman (champion)Technical InformationThe Punch-Out!! arcade cabinet was somewhat unique in that it used two monitors - one in the standard arcade cabinet position for the field of play and another monitor above it that displayed game data like player/opponent portraits as well as health meters.Punch-Out!! also featured digitized speech that served multiple purposes, an announcer introduced the opponents before a fight as well as called the action on the fly during a bout (ie "Right! Right! Left! Bodyblow! He's down for the count!") and gave an audio cue to the player when their super meter was full ("Put him away!" or "Knock him out!"). The announcer also encourages the player to "Come on, stand up and fight!" after a defeat. Other brief samples were used for boxer voices, mainly just grunts when the player was hit by an opponent and a laugh that would be heard when the player was knocked out by the computer opponent.LegacyPunch-Out!! spawned several home console titles bearing the Punch-Out!! name with a similar (although not identical) gameplay style, had an arcade sequel ( Super Punch-Out!!) , and even had a spin-off  Arm Wrestling arcade title (which featured Bald Bull as a masked opponent named Mask X). Punch-Out!! is generally regarded as one of the original iconic Nintendo franchises, although not at the level of Mario or Zelda titles.Other FactsDuring gameplay, iconic Nintendo character  Donkey Kong can be seen sitting in the audience.The title screen music is the "Gillette Look Sharp March," originally used in Gillette radio and television ads, and later used for the Gillette Cavalcade of Sports television program in the 1950's.</description><genres><genre id="20">Boxing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26552">Arm Wrestling</game><game id="19968">Champion Boxing</game><game id="36496">Heavyweight Champ</game><game id="34475">Hajime no Ippo: The Fighting!</game><game id="44162">KO Punch</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4527/1084842-punchout_arcade_1.jpg</image></root>