<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27495</id><name>Naruto Shippuden: Ultimate Ninja 5</name><description>Ultimate Ninja 5 spans from episodes 1-53 of the Naruto Shippuden anime, i.e. the beginning of the Rescue Gaara arc to the end of the Sasuke pursuit arc.   New gameplay additions to Ultimate Ninja 5 include the introduction of assist characters, which can be called during battle to deal extra damage to the opponent. Up to two assist characters can be summoned, where selecting specific characters will allow the player to carry out special team based jutsu and ougis.    Also for the first time, Ultimate Ninja 5 grants the player the ability to boost character stats as well as add equipment and upgrade Jutsus.  Ultimate Ninja 5 will also allow players to free-roam the Leaf Village and interact with the villagers and surroundings as they progress through the game's story mode; "Master Mode".   The game was released in Japan on December 20th 2007. A European release is planned for November 27th 2009, with Australian an release scheduled for December 3rd of 2009. Sadly, North America never released the game.Playable Characters      Naruto Uzumaki Sasuke Uchiha  Sakura Haruno  Kakashi Hatake  Rock Lee  Neji Hyuga  Tenten  Might Guy  Shikamaru Nara  Choji Akimichi  Ino Yamanaka Asuma Sarutobi  Shino Aburame  Kiba Inuzuka  Hinata Hyuga  Kurenai Yuhi  Gaara  Kankuro  Temari  Chiyo  Itachi Uchiha  Kisame Hoshigaki  Deidara  Sasori (true form and Hiroku) Sai  Yamato  Jiraiya  Tsunade  Shizune  Orochimaru  Kabuto Yakushi  Jirobo  Kidomaru  Sakon and Ukon  Tayuya  Kimimaro  First Hokage  Second Hokage  Third Hokage  Fourth Hokage  Hanabi Hyuga  Konohamaru Sarutobi  Anko Mitarashi  Haku  Zabuza Momochi</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5206">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai</game><game id="15234">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai 2</game><game id="13129">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai 3</game><game id="20500">Dragon Ball Z: Burst Limit</game><game id="21720">Bleach: Blade Battlers</game><game id="22231">Bleach: Blade Battlers 2nd</game><game id="1499">Dragon Ball Z: Shin Budokai - Another Road</game><game id="22285">Dragon Ball Z: Shin Budokai</game><game id="22569">Bleach: Heat the Soul</game><game id="21981">Bleach: Heat the Soul 2</game><game id="22974">Bleach: Heat the Soul 3</game><game id="21378">Bleach: Heat the Soul 4</game><game id="21917">Bleach: Heat the Soul 5</game><game id="25378">Bleach: Heat the Soul 6</game><game id="20486">Bleach: Shattered Blade</game><game id="2154">One Piece: Grand Battle</game><game id="30786">Naruto Shippuden Ultimate Ninja Heroes 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2215077-box_narutoun5.png</image></root>