<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>275</id><name>GT Legends</name><description>GT Legends features man famous real life tracks and cars. The track layouts are based on their current (or current as the game's release), unlike Grand Prix Legends which included historic cars and the historic track layouts. The stock tracks (not counting user made mods) areAnderstorp GPAnderstorp NorthAnderstorp SouthDijon-Prenois GPDijon-Prenois ShortDonington GPDonington NationalHockenheim GPHockenheim NationalHockenheim ShortImola GPMagny-Cours ClubMagny-Cours GPMagny-Cours NationalMondello Park IntermediateMondello Park InternationalMondello Park NationalMondello Park ShortMonza GPMonza JuniorNürburgring GPNürburgring MüllenbachNürburgring SprintSpa-Francorchamps GPZolderGT Legends also includes many historic race cars, the stock game includes theseAbarth 1000TCAC CobraAlfa Romeo GTAAustin-Healey 3000Austin Mini Cooper SBMW CSLChevrolet CorvetteDe Tomaso PanteraFerrari 275 GTB/CFord Capri RSFord Escort RSFord FalconFord GT40Ford MustangJaguar E-TypeJaguar MK 2Lotus CortinaLotus Elan 26RLotus EliteMercedes 300SLPorsche 906Porsche 911RSRPorsche 914-6Renault Alpine A110Shelby Daytona CoupeShelby GT350TVR Griffith 400System RequirementsMinimumOS: Microsoft Windows XP/Vista/SevenProcessor: 1.3 GHz Intel Pentium III or AMDMemory: 512 MB RAMGraphics: DX8.1 comp. video card/64 MBDirectX®: 8.1Hard Drive: 3 GB HD spaceSound: DX8.1 comp. sound cardRecommendedProcessor: 2 GHz Intel Pentium IV or AMDMemory: 1 GB RAMGraphics: DX9.0c comp. video card/256 MBDirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 3 GB HD spaceSound: DX9.0 comp. sound card</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14858">GTR 2: FIA GT Racing Game</game><game id="6347">Grand Prix Legends</game><game id="19522">Live for Speed</game><game id="25225">Need for Speed: SHIFT</game><game id="19563">Sports Car GT</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/29460/893200-250px_gt_legends_video_game_pc_cover_scan.jpg</image></root>