<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27568</id><name>Skwug</name><description>OverviewSkwug is a platformer developed for the Xbox 360 using XNA. It is a community game created by Jeremy Verchick. It was available for purchase on July 27th, 2009 for 200 Microsoft points.Gameplay  Skwug is a platformer that makes use of a Teleportation mechanic. Skwug is capable of performing three teleports while in midair, he then needs to land before he can teleport again. He can teleport through most obstacles, but cannot pass through the ground, or unopened doors which litter some levels. The game makes use of this mechanic by presenting many obstacles that are impassible without teleportation suspended in mid-air, requiring perfect timing to pass in the limit of three teleports. There are a total of fifty levels in the game. Each level is comprised of a short set of challenges that concludes in an opening that returns the player to the over world. Each level also has three unlockables, one is given for beating the level on the hard difficulty, one for beating the par time on that level, and one that is given for retrieving the hypercube on that level. The over world is represented as the five worlds that make up the game, arranged directly next to each other on an island. The game features four powerups, each represented by a different colored wormhole. The first is the green wormhole that restores one teleport, even if in mid-air. The second is the yellow wormhole that restores all teleports, even if in mid-air. The third is the blue wormhole that increases the range of the next teleport Skwug performs. The final powerup is the red wormhole that instantly transports Skwug from one red wormhole to another. Skwug includes an in game achievement-like system that is referred to as unlocks, some of which are linked to new visual themes that can be applied to the games levels.  </description><genres><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/36674/1093344-boxartz.jpg</image></root>