<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27767</id><name>Soul of the Ultimate Nation</name><description>OverviewSoul of the Ultimate Nation (S.U.N. or simply SUN) is a free to play MMORPG developed by Korean publisher WebZen. Like WebZen's other titles, and most other free to play MMOs, SUN offers an item shop where players may purchase in-game items with real currency.Character CreationThe avatars available during character creation.The player can choose one of five available avatars, each with his own set of accessible class selections. Upon selecting an avatar and its class, the player can proceed with minor customization of appearance (face, hair, height). Finally, the player is allowed to try on some armor sets to see how they look on current character.Currently, there are five classes. Some of them used to be gender-restricted (for example, Berserker used to be male only, Valkyries female only, etc.), but that no longer seems to be the case. Each class has its own skill tree that branches out into two different directions and allows the player to customize their character to suit their playstyle.Classes and StatsThe class choice determines your appearance, skill tree and requisite stats (Strength, Agility, Vitality, Intelligence and Spirit). The available classes are:Berserker - a melee fighter optimized for frontal combat and a focus on Strength and Vitality. Their "Mana Pool" is always empty and can be replenished by fighting or using certain utility skills. Berserker skill tree branches out into: Defender skills that deal a moderate amount of damage, in addition to various other effects, such as provoking the enemy to attack the Berserker, weakening them or strengthening the Berserker; Berserk skills focus towards dealing a large amount of damage to multiple enemies and crowd control effects such as pushing, tripping and stunning.Shadow - a mixed fighter/caster for various roles in group. They focus on Strength, Intelligence and Agility. Shadows lack area-of-effects skills in early game. Their Skill tree branches into Cursed (misc caster) skill tree and Dark (melee ambusher) skill tree.Dragon Knight - an off-tank class with good defense, buffs, debuffs, and decent melee damage.Elementalist - a mage class who can do ranged magical damage, or use healing abilities.Valkyrie - a ranged damage class who use bows and crossbows, as well as summoning pets.</description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10796">EverQuest</game><game id="20701">World of Warcraft: Wrath of the Lich King</game><game id="9705">Lineage II: The Chaotic Chronicle</game><game id="22994">Shaiya</game><game id="21308">Aion: Ascension</game><game id="29190">Twelve Sky 2</game><game id="29189">Twelve Sky</game><game id="30084">Aika Online</game><game id="26770">Rift</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1992/1102473-suna2mifh0873e7___.jpg</image></root>