<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27792</id><name>Sheriff</name><description>An arcade shooter released by Nintendo in 1979, this was the first video game ever co-designed by their most famous producer Shigeru Miyamoto, who assisted the more experienced (at the time) lead designer Genyo Takeda.OverviewIn the game, the player controls a county sheriff who must defend the town and rescue his lover from bandits. It was an early run-and-gun multi-directional shooter that featured dual-stick controls, with one joystick for movement and the other for aiming, and a large number of enemies shooting many bullets, paving the way for later dual-stick shooters such as Robotron and Geometry Wars as well as many bullet hell shooters.Miyamoto and Takeda combined the Wild West setting and on-foot movement of Gun Fight with the single-player horde-based action gameplay and high score mechanic of Space Invaders to create Sheriff, making it possibly the first run-and-gun shooter ever produced.Sheriff also anticipated some of the gameplay elements that Miyamoto would later popularize with Donkey Kong, including the damsel in distress plot and the use of cutscenes to progress the game's simple plot. Sheriff was possibly the first game to use cutscenes, predating Taito's much more popular Space Invaders Part II by a month.It was also one of the first video games to feature concepts such as a romance theme, bonus points, and continuous chiptune background music (predating Namco's more popular Rally-X by a year).  </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="31">Dual-Joystick Shooter</genre><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1034">Asteroids</game><game id="354">Space Fury</game><game id="32574">Gun Fight</game><game id="11233">Robotron: 2084</game><game id="5099">Space Invaders</game><game id="11099">Geometry Wars: Retro Evolved</game><game id="17576">Front Line</game><game id="19413">Space Dungeon</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/7667/1103485-slide04.jpg</image></root>