<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27816</id><name>Greed Corp</name><description>GameplaySet in the Mistbound universe, the game takes place on a board made of hexagon shaped tiles that are stacked up to 6 layers tall. Each match revolves around 2-4 identically equipped factions trying to eliminate all of their enemies. It is designed to be both simple and deep such as Chess.Win ConditionsA faction is eliminated when they have no tiles or they are all empty (no units or buildings). Victory is obtained by being the last remaining faction on the board. When a player eliminates an opposing faction, the player is awarded all of that faction's remaining credits, tiles, and carriers.TurnsEach player has only 60 seconds to complete each turn. At the beginning of each turn credits are awarded for all controlled harvesters as well as a separate lump sum of credits. This sum is the same for all players and starts low. The fewer tiles that remain, the larger this lump sum.TilesA sample game board.Hexagon shaped.Every tile has a height in Layers.A tile can be between 1 and 6 Layers tall.Cannons and harvesters can destroy a tile's layers.When a tile's height becomes 0 Layers, it is destroyed and falls off the game board, taking all units and buildings that occupy the tile with it.When a tile's height is 1 Layer, it is considered a Critical Tile. It will appear cracked and ready to fall away, as well have special properties involving chain reactions with other critical tiles.A tile's height is indicated by the number of dots around the cursor as it is hovered over the tile.UnitsWalkersBasic attack and defense unit. Up to 16 can be stacked on a single tile together.They can move to any adjacent neutral or enemy tile during a turn, or up to three tiles through player controlled territory.When walkers engage in combat with each other, the outcome is determined by the difference between attackers and defenders. They cancel each other out on a 1:1 ratio: If the attacker's numbers exceeds those of the defender, or the numbers are equal, the attacker claims the tile. If the defender has the larger number of walkers, the defender retains control of the tile. In both cases the winner of the engagement has the number of enemies subtracted from the remaining forces. (ex. 16 defenders vs. 8 attackers: 8 defenders remain on the tile no attackers remain)CarriersOne time use unit that must be purchased separately the turn before its use.It carries any number of walkers on a given tile to any other tile. If the destination is occupied by enemy walkers it will be handled like any other engagement.Players can stack at least 3 carriers at a time.BuildingsHarvestersA tile with a harvester plummeting into the mist.Can be placed on any controlled tile.At the start of a player's turn, all controlled harvesters will destroy one layer on the tile they occupy and the immediately surrounding tiles. If a tile is destroyed through this process, the units and buildings on that tile will be lost.Every layer a harvester destroys awards 2 credits to the controlling player.Harvesters can be captured by other players but not destroyed. They will destroy tiles every turn until their own tile plummets into the mist.Self-Destruct: during a turn, a player can choose to self-destruct a controlled harvester. The harvester will completely destroy the tile it is on and lower adjacent tiles by one layer. All connected critical tiles will also be destroyed in a chain reaction. No credits will be awarded.ArmoryCan be placed on any controlled tile.Are necessary to produce walkers and summon carriers.Can only produce 8 walkers in a single turn.Can be captured.CannonsCan be placed on any controlled tile.Are stationary and have a limited range of 2 to 5 tiles.Ammo must be bought for the cannons separately at least a turn before they are fired. A cannon can hold up to 9 rounds.Cannons can fire multiple times in one round if they have the ammo.When a cannon is fired, the target tile will be lowered one layer and 5 walkers on the tile will be destroyed. If the target tile is a critical tile, all connected critical tiles will be destroyed in a chain reaction.Can be captured. Ammo in a captured cannon stays in the cannon for the capturing player to fire.PC System RequirementsOS: Windows® XP (SP3), Windows Vista® (SP1), Windows 7®Processor: Pentium 4 3GHz or comparableRAM Memory: 1 GBGraphics Card: DirectX® 9-compatible graphics adapter with 128 MB RAM (ATI® X700 or better / NVIDIA GeForce® 6100 or better)DirectX®: DirectX®9.0cHard Drive: 1 GB free spaceSound Card: DirectX® 9.0c-compatible</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21010">Catan</game><game id="20580">Sid Meier's Civilization Revolution</game><game id="18595">Tom Clancy's Ruthless.com</game><game id="3749">Hexxagon</game><game id="19556">Hexxagon 2</game><game id="17086">Carcassonne</game><game id="30076">Carcassonne DS</game><game id="21969">Starship Catan</game><game id="10687">Risk</game><game id="29748">RISK: Factions</game><game id="18399">Risk II</game><game id="374">RISK: The Game of Global Domination</game><game id="22821">Axis &amp; Allies</game><game id="16099">Axis &amp; Allies</game><game id="34423">Gatling Gears</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/31/1268250-greedcorp_packshot_pc.jpg</image></root>