<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27859</id><name>Just Dance</name><description>What is  Just Dance?  Just Dance is a party game by    Ubisoft that requires you to follow on-screen prompts and a professional dancer in order to score points. It features highly stylised, rotoscoped graphics. Despite the obvious suggestion of the title, it does not actually contain the Lady GaGa song "Just Dance".   Tracklist     Just Dance offers 32 song for the players to dance on. These songs are:   Acceptable in the 80's – Calvin Harris A Little Less Conversation (JXL Remix) –  Elvis Presley Vs.  JXL Bebe – Divine Brown Can't Get You Out of My Head – Kylie Minogue Cotton Eye Joe – Rednex Hot n' Cold (Chick Radio Mix) – Katy Perry* Dare – Gorillaz Eye of the Tiger (theme from Rocky) –  Survivor Fame – In the style of Irene Cara (cover) Funplex CSS – The B-52's Girls and Boys – Blur Girls Just Want to Have Fun – Cindi Lauper Groove is in the Heart – Dee-Lite  Heart of Glass – Blondie I Get Around – The Beach Boys I Like to Move it – Reel To Real Jerk it Out – Caesars Jin Go Lo Ba – Fat Boy Slim Kids in America – Kim Wilde Le Freak – Chic Louie Louie –         Iggy Pop Lump – The Presidents of the United States of America Mashed Potato Time – Dee Dee Sharp Pump up the Jam – Technotronic Ring My Bell – Anita Ward Step by Step – New Kids On The Block Surfin' Bird – The Trashmen That's the Way (I Like it) – K.C.  The Sunshine Band U Can't Touch This – MC Hammer Wannabe – Spice Girls Who Let the Dogs Out? – Baha Men Womanizer – In the style of  Britney Spears (cover)* This version of Hot N' Cold is a radio edit which replaces the minor swear word "Bitch" with "Chick" Critical Reception The reception for  Just Dance has been fairly negative with some reviewers stating that the cover tracks in the game are mediocre and the presentation of the game being "simple, plain  uninspiring". The setlist has also been subject to criticism, with most of the songs not even fitting the party dancing feeling the game attempts to create, with song such as "Dare", "Who Let The Dogs Out?"  "Eye Of The Tiger" not really songs one would dance to. The game has been put under the microscope by dancers and choreographers  and they found the dances to be simple but not always fitting to the songs. Popularity  Despite the frosty critical reception,  Just Dance has inexplicably become a popular game for parties especially in the UK.</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23508">Helix</game><game id="29507">Fame</game><game id="31705">Dance Central</game><game id="31787">SingStar Dance</game><game id="32238">Gold's Gym: Dance Workout</game><game id="31724">Michael Jackson: The Experience</game><game id="32856">Kidz Bop Dance Party! The Video Game</game><game id="32865">Dance Paradise</game><game id="31801">DanceMasters</game><game id="34611">Country Dance</game><game id="35532">Dance Central 2</game><game id="35638">Everybody Dance</game><game id="34784">DanceDanceRevolution</game><game id="29420">Dance Dance Revolution X2</game><game id="36861">Nickelodeon Dance</game><game id="35754">Let's Dance with Mel B</game><game id="42433">K-Pop Dance Festival</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2331123-box_jd.png</image></root>