<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27873</id><name>I MAED A GAM3 W1TH Z0MBIES!!!1</name><description>OverviewAs you begin A GAM3 the music starts to roll and you are treated to a song that is itself about the game you are playing. The song's chorus summons larger waves of enemies in addition to changing the playing arena in some way. Although the song is the main draw of the game, it continues after the song ends, ending rather unceremoniously once they've destroyed all the waves of monsters, approximately 15 minutes after the game begins, cutting right to a black 'enter initials' screen. While fighting zombies, snakes (literally from the game Snake hence the ASCII happy face that appears on the box art), green blobs, and others, you will be rewarded with useful weapons such as flamethrowers, shotguns, and laser guns to help keep the hordes at bay. It includes four-player multiplayer on a single console so you may enlist the help of your friends.The Xbox Live Marketplace description for the game reads "This video game product represents a culmination of years of intensive psychological research, bleeding edge engineering, and artistic collaboration by over two dozen internationally recognized art houses, using such technologies as the HYPERMAGIC 3.0 engine to power never-before-seen eye candy with the MEGACORE X parallelization processor for smooth-as-glass presentation."EnemiesThe player will experience entire hordes of zombies across the game, here's a small list:Normal ZombieThese guys walk at a normal speed and kill the player if they get too close, they are killed in one shot (from the infinite AK) .Fat ZombieThese guys walk slowly and are almost twice the size of other zombies, they take around five to six shots (infinite AK).Green Amorphous blobTheses guys are giants, and they duplicate themselves into smaller blobs when shot or if left alone.They take about the same amount of damage as a Fat Zombie, but when they die a large horde of 'baby blobs' are released upon the player, these babies take one shot each.AsteroidNot really a zombie, but these things just fly around, usually aimed at the player.They are easy to dodge, but each time they are hit they split into smaller and faster asteroids (like the game!), making them challenging in hordes.BomberThese guys run quickly and have bombs strapped to them, they take a couple of shots and release a small explosion, rarely killing other enemies.DiamondThese guys will appear out of nowhere and fly quickly at the player, they only take one shot, but when they spawn in massive hordes.Demon squareThese guys have come straight from hell and they're out to kill the player. They are just a large box with a face on it, the face alternates between red and black to white and black, usually in time to the ambient music. They move the fastest and have a small chunk of health. About three to four shots can kill them, but like the Diamond, they spawn in massive numbers, usually off screen to surprise the player.Success since releaseSince launch, the game has been both critically acclaimed and met financial success. The game has been highly praised by both gamers and game video games sites through out the Internet. Luke Plunkett of disreputable gaming site Kotaku said that he would pay a dollar just for the song. Hamza CTZ Aziz of Drestructoid calls the song "I MAED A S0NG W1TH Z0MBIES!!!1" this year's " Still Alive", the song from Portal. Xav de Matos of Joystick said the game was "filled to the brim with awesome."As of March 2, 2010, I MAED A GAM3 W1TH Z0MB1ES!!!1 has sold about 200,343 since release.He made a game, with zombies in it.By popular demand, on August 29, 2009 Ska Studios released "I MAED A S0NG W1TH Z0MBIES 1N 1T!!!1", the theme song to I MAED A GAM3 W1TH Z0MBIES!!!1, through their website. The site updated the files two more times for quality issues and file issues. The vocals can be described as a resemblance to "The Smashing Pumpkins" Billy Corgan with the growling described as gibberish. The song can be downloaded here: http://www.ska-studios.com/2009/08/26/download-i-maed-a-s0ng-w1th-z0mb1es-1n-it1/</description><genres><genre id="31">Dual-Joystick Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11099">Geometry Wars: Retro Evolved</game><game id="24547">BIOLOGY BATTLE</game><game id="21167">Geometry Wars: Retro Evolved 2</game><game id="27866">Dead Nation</game><game id="28042">Nation Red</game><game id="20775">Mutant Storm Empire</game><game id="5218">Mutant Storm</game><game id="20774">Mutant Storm Reloaded</game><game id="24253">Burn Zombie Burn!</game><game id="25841">Zombie Apocalypse</game><game id="27196">Death by Cube</game><game id="26344">ZSX4 Guitarpocalypse</game><game id="26343">ZP2K9</game><game id="31207">Murky Horizon</game><game id="29991">Age of Zombies</game><game id="31639">JoyJoy</game><game id="34067">Square Off</game><game id="34069">TwinStick: This Ain't No Picnic</game><game id="30144">The Dishwasher: Vampire Smile</game><game id="35593">Zombie Apocalypse: Never Die Alone</game><game id="36004">Dead Horde</game><game id="11758">Crimsonland</game><game id="37142">Z0MB1ES (on teh ph0ne)</game><game id="39485">The Border Lands</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/4/41471/1109636-zomb1es.jpg</image></root>