<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27936</id><name>ArmA II: Operation Arrowhead</name><description>Operation Arrowhead takes place three years after the events of ARMA II. A new situation has occurred in the fictional central Asian republic of Takistan, and the US Army is deployed.This expansion adds a whole new style of terrain, inspired by Afghanistan, as well as introducing new units and vehicles from the US Army, UN, Czech Republic and the OpFor side as well. In addition to this, the developers are also adding several updates to the ARMA 2 engine such as the inclusion of FLIR and flashlights, and also several back end changes.Throughout the pre-release period, Bohemia Interactive have been updating AAN World News with information relating to the situation in Takistan. These articles also include information of future releases in the ARMA 2 series, with British Army units appearing in one article.System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Windows XP or Windows VistaProcessor: Intel Core 2.4 GHz or AMD Dual-Core Athlon 2.5 GHzMemory: 1GBGraphics: Nvidia Geforce 8600GT or ATI Radeon 3650 or faster with Shader Model 3 and 512 MB VRAMDirectX®: DirectX 9.0cHard Drive: 10 GB free spaceRecommended:OS: Windows 7Processor: Intel Core i5 or AMD Athlon Phenom X4 or fasterMemory: 2GBGraphics: Nvidia Geforce GTX 260 or ATI Radeon HD 5770 or faster with Shader Model 3 and 896 MB VRAMDirectX®: DirectX 9.0cHard Drive: 20 GB free space</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5333">Operation Flashpoint: Cold War Crisis</game><game id="19649">Operation Flashpoint: Elite</game><game id="32243">Operation Flashpoint: Red River</game><game id="21665">Operation Flashpoint: Dragon Rising</game><game id="2590">Operation Flashpoint: Resistance</game><game id="18992">Operation Flashpoint: Gold Upgrade</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5774/1774479-arma_2_operation_arrowhead_box_art.jpg</image></root>