<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>27966</id><name>Zombie Master</name><description>OverviewZombie Master is a mod based around a hybrid of multiple genres used in a survival horror environment. The majority of players are survivors who are trying to escape a level or withstand a horde of zombies that can be spawned by a lone enemy player named the "Zombie Master." The survivors are played in a first person shooter perspective where they must gather weapons, ammo, and objects that can help them against the waves of zombies. The "Zombie Master" plays the game in a real-time strategy perspective in which the player can spawn different types of zombies within red orbs and level specific traps within yellow orbs.  GameplayWhen a player enters the game, he or she is entitled to prefer either being a human or being the "Zombie Master." Picking the latter wont make the player be the "Zombie Master" immediately or by the end of the round as it can vary with other players who would prefer to be the ZM.  Maps will contain objectives including escaping an area, blowing up a complex, or surviving until the round ends. The maps can contain objects that are vital to completion including explosives and vehicles.  When a human dies from the round, they are not able to respawn and would have to wait until either the humans or the "Zombie Master" wins.   HistoryConceived by modder "Angry Lawyer," Zombie Master originally began as a hybrid game based around spawning   Combine forces as the RTS element but was later scrapped. "Angry Lawyer" then replaced the Combine with zombies which would later be the main part in creating Zombie Master. On April 15, 2007, the first version of the mod was released to the public. On January 5, 2009 with the release of version 1.2.1, "Angry Lawyer" announced that the version will be the final update to the mod and will no further updates will be made. Zombies In Zombie Master, there are four different kinds of zombies: Shambler-your standard zombie, they move very slow but their strength is in their numbers, and they usually do about 25 damage per hit, so try not to get surrounded by them.Banshee-very fast, and they jump very far, but they are very weak and pretty easy to killHulk-the powerhouse zombie, they are huge and move very slow, but their damage output is massive, and they have the most health out of all the zombiesDrifters-floating zombies that have about the same health as a banshee or a shambler, they move at a medium speed, and they attack by spitting acid at a medium range, which when it hits a human, causes their screen to shake, disorienting them WeaponsAt the start of the match, every human starts out with only their fists unless they find a weapons of many including.   WeaponDescriptionSpeedDamageAmmo Fists Standard, you always have them. fast low infinite Crowbar none needed medium medium infinite Sledgehammer primary fire hits target with handle, secondary fire swings hammer slow very high infinite Pistol regular pistol medium low 20 loaded, 80 spare Revolversecondary fire fans the hammer, firing off all the shots loaded (think western movies)  varies high 6 loaded, 36 spare Shotgun standard shotgun, obviously best at close range medium high at close range, diminshes further from target 8 loaded, 24 spare Rifle bolt-action rifle slow depends on where target is hit, headshots help 11 loaded, 20 spare Mac10 submachine gun, it eats up ammo very high low, but high rate of fire compensates for this 30 loaded, 60 spare Barrelsbarrels that explode when shot  none very high depends on how many you can find Paint can like barrel, but smaller, harder to shoot none very high depends on how many you can find MapsThere are a large number of maps in Zombie Master.  The following are most of the maps in the game, but not necessarily all of them. 4d tetrisairalphasiteasylumbackwoodsbastardbathroombigbadtrojanblackmesablockadebluevelvetcagefightcaptivitycoutrytraincrocodiledeathballdeathrundefencediamondshoalsdocksofthedeaddonkeyexodus dawnexodus rusefactoryfailtrainforestroadgasdumpgilmanhouseholdhousejumpropelabescapelonelylostintentionsmadnessmallmalum canalmine shaftminerincovenienceminesweepernoodlenuklearobstacleonesmallshamblepinball snowpeakplatformsplundergroundspoweroutagesurviveprisonbreakprojectnightmarerainynightravenholmrazor prored horrorredmesaredqueenrunrunawayrunofdeathsafezoneshipsomething texturedspoffydefensespookhousesunnytownsuper marioundeadhouseurban escapeurban underworldvaultwarehousezombiefort</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20690">Left 4 Dead</game><game id="24358">Zombie Panic: Source</game><game id="26782">Left 4 Dead 2</game><game id="28907">Situation Outbreak</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/36971/1126775-snapshot0000.jpg</image></root>