<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>28029</id><name>We Sing</name><description> The first karaoke game exclusively for the Wii        The singing game featuring four mics and four singers has arrived. Thirty chart topping tunes from a wide range of musical tastes. Fun for young and old singers, and a party piece for the whole family. Exclusively for the Wii!    The first game featuring four mics  four singers… together! 30 chart topping songs from a mixture of leading artists, including  original videos Broad range of music for a variety of tastes Solo, Party and Karaoke modes Party Mode includes We Sing, Versus, Group Battle, Pass The Mic, and First to 5000 Up to 4 players can sing along together in any Party Mode Karaoke mode – for the purists Easy, Medium or Hard, with short or full length song modes Playlist feature – line up your favourite songs  Customisable interface – change your look to fit your mood Easy, simple and clean menu to allow quick access to songs Choose your singer if there is more than one artist Integrates with a USB 4 port hub, for 4 microphones Fully compatible with Logitech® USB Microphones from Sing It, High School Musical 3, Guitar Hero and Rock Band Song list   Amy Winehouse - Tears Dry On Their OwnAqua - Barbie GirlBlondie - One Way Or AnotherCharles and Eddie - Would I Lie To You?Chesney Hawkes - The One And OnlyColdplay - Viva La VidaCulture Club - Karma ChameleonDuffy - Mercy Duran Duran Hungry Like The WolfElton John with Kiki Dee - Don't Go Breaking My HeartJames Morrison  Nelly Furtado - Broken StringsJohn Denver - Take Me Home, Country RoadsKaiser Chiefs - I Predict A RiotKylie Minogue - Loco-MotionLady GaGa - Poker FaceLily Allen - The FearMadness - Our HouseMeatloaf - I'd Do Anything For LoveMoloko - Sing It BackOne Republic Featuring Timbaland - ApologizePussycat Dolls - Don't ChaRoxette - It Must Have Been LoveShampoo - TroubleSpice Girls - WannabeSugababes - GirlsTasmin Archer - Sleeping SatelliteThe Automatic - MonsterThe Police - Every Breath You TakeTom Jones - DelilahUB40 - Red Red Wine  </description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21171">Lips</game><game id="26636">Lips: Number One Hits</game><game id="20462">SingStar</game><game id="1641">SingStar</game><game id="31218">Singstar: The Wiggles</game><game id="31283">We Sing Encore</game><game id="32213">We Sing Robbie Williams</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14741/1155849-ws.jpg</image></root>