<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>28094</id><name>Silent Hunter V: Battle of the Atlantic</name><description>OverviewSilent Hunter V:  Battle of the Atlantic is the fifth instalment in the submarine simulator franchise                Silent Hunter, developed by Ubisoft Romania and published by Ubisoft.   Players assume the role of a German submarine captain in a first-person perspective to command their crew throughout the single-player campaign. The campaign is set in the Atlantic Ocean and Mediterranean Sea during World War II.    Key Features: Ability to walk through all of the submarine in first-person view.Direct crew interaction and a simulation of the tension and fear of the crew.A new objective-driven dynamic campaign modeAllied ships respond to players advances and new locations, upgrades and resupply alter the campaign dynamically.A brand-new user interface supporting a beginner mode and a mode where the player can control the whole submarine on their own.Improved graphics and realism. Collectors Edition:Silent hunter 5 : Battle Of the Atlantic PC DVD-Rom Silent Hunter 5 Collector's Edition  Game manual  Official guide, containing all   in-game details  Authentic map of the Battle Of the Atlantic  SH5 original Soundtrack7 unique submarine  enemy ship skinsOne iron box     Uplay Uplay is a service where you earn points and use them to unlock bonus items. Here is a list of Actions (achievements) and Rewards for this game.  ActionsPointsTutorial missionComplete the tutorial and first macro objective, "Invasion of Poland". 10UFinish 1st campaignFinish 'Total Germany' campaign. 20UFinished 4th campaignComplete "Battle of Mediteranean" OR "Operation Drumbeat" OR "Arctic Convoys". 30UComplete career modeComplete 'Black May' Campaign. 40U RewardsCostSilent Hunter 5 WallpaperHigh resolution wallpaper. 10USubmarines skinsTwo popular camouflage skins which were used by german Uboats during their campaign in Atlantic. 20U Royally SunkWhile on her way to Gibraltar the fleet carrier HMS Ark Royal is attacked and sunk by U-81. 30UChance of a LifetimeA lucky Uboat captain has found himself a dream target: the ocean liner Queen Mary. 40U PC Version DRMUbisoft requires that all of their PC games need an "always-on" internet connection, as part of a new DRM and online services platform. All announced Ubisoft PC games will include the online services, whether sold online, or from brick and mortar stores.   If you get disconnected while playing, you're booted out of the game. All your progress since the last checkpoint or savegame is lost, and your only options are to quit to Windows or wait until you're reconnected.  This happens even if the game  loses its connection to Ubisoft's 'Master servers' on their end.  This DRM was very negatively received by the PC gaming community, and the servers have       come under attack by hackers in protest of the DRM policy.  System Requirements OS: Windows® XP (Service Pack 3), Windows Vista® (Service Pack 2), Windows® 7Processor: Intel® Core™2 Duo E4400 2 GHz / AMD Athlon™ 64 X2 4000  2.1 GHz or higher (Intel Core™2 Quad Q6600 2.4 GHz / AMD Athlon 64 X2 5200  2.6 GHz or higher recommended)Memory: 1 GB (Windows XP) / 2 GB (Windows Vista, Windows 7) (2 GB recommended)Graphics: 512 MB DirectX® 9.0c-compliant video card(*see supported list)DirectX®:Hard Drive: 10 GB (15 GB recommended)Sound: DirectX 9.0c-compliant sound cardPeripherals Supported: Windows-compliant mouse, keyboardInternet Connection: 256 kbps Broadband connection (512 kbps connection or better recommended)*Supported Video Cards at Time of Release:NVIDIA GeForce 8800GT / 9 / GTX 200 seriesATI Radeon HD 2600 / HD 3000 / HD 4000 / HD 5000 seriesNVIDIA SLI  ATI Crossfire</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="30639">Naval Assault: The Killing Tide</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/13692/1292448-silent_hunter_5_61087.jpg</image></root>