<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>28125</id><name>Legend of Mir 2</name><description>OverviewThe Legend of Mir 2 Four Heroes is an early 2D Isometric MMORPG looking similar in style to Ultima Online. The official European server was shut down, early 2009, but has been relocated elsewhere on an F2P basis. Despite the closed servers The Legend of Mir 2 is still very much alive. CharactersThe Legend of Mir 2 consists of four character classes:  Warrior      A Warrior's                            strength lies in their ability to fight tough monsters                            with their high strength and large amount of health.                            Warriors are able to hunt monsters easily because of                            their excessive strength and health.       Wizard Wizards are favored for their large variety of spells and special effects. Not only does it require extra effort from the mind, but one must be born with these special talents to become a Wizard. Some thought that it is possible to become a Wizard without these special talents born to you, but no one has yet obtained the powers of a Wizard without being born with them.       Taoist  Through great amounts of mental training and study, Taoists have a masterful knowledge of astrology, geography, and health. Although Taoists may not have the strength of a warrior, Taoists have a variety of sword techniques at their disposal.       AssassinAssassins are born for one purpose-total and complete elimination of a chosen target. They use exceptional agility and deadly magical arts to overwhelm foes in the blink of an eye. Assassins learn ageless magical skills through constant study. By mastering these magical skills, the assassins strengthened their magic defense. Additionally, Assassins use their magical skills to hallucinate and weaken monsters.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18547">EverQuest II</game><game id="22850">Myth of Soma</game><game id="1119">Diablo II</game><game id="15589">Diablo II: Lord of Destruction</game><game id="5767">Ultima Online</game><game id="743">Astonia 3</game><game id="3634">Redmoon</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/18403/1139270-legend_of_mir.jpg</image></root>