<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>28138</id><name>AI War: Fleet Command</name><description>OverviewAI War: Fleet Command is an original space-based RTS with a focus on co-op play, management of many thousands of units, and a blend of the quick, decisive elements of real time strategy and the long-term planning of a grand strategy game. Games can end up lasting days, weeks or even months. Published by indie developer Arcen Games, it is primarily developed by Chris Park.Visually it is rendered in 2D, which allows for a huge unit count, relatively low system requirements, and simple unit management (not to mention ease of development). The stated focus of the game is on a tough, adaptive AI that responds on how much of a threat the player signifies. Discretion, scouting, wise timing and strong macromanagement are highly encouraged to the player. Almost no micromanagement is required.Unlike most RTS games, a player-vs-player mode is not included; only co-op, which is one of the main features of the game, is available along with single player. It uses emergent Artificial intelligence along with scaling difficulty to allow for a wildly different experience each playthrough if so desired.ExpansionsThere are currently five expansions available with a sixth scheduled for release in late 2013.The Zenith Remnant (featuring large additions to the AI, new units and new game mechanics.)Children of Neinzul (charity micro expansion.)Light of the Spire (featuring a more directed, event-driven story that unfolds procedurally within a standard game. Also introduces a multitude of new ship types and methods of resource gathering.)Ancient Shadows (features champions you or another human player can control alongside your main fleet.)Vengeance of the Machine (adds new AI types along with new map types, guardian types, and two new optional AI plots.)System RequirementsPCOS: Windows 2000 or later, 32 or 64 bitProcessor: 1.6Ghz CPU (2.4 Ghz recommended, Dual Core strongly recommended for Host)Memory: 1 GB RAM (2 GB recommended)Graphics: Graphics card must support 1024x1024 textures (most 32MB and up graphics cards do), 1024x768 or greater (32 bit color recommended)DirectX®:9.0cHard Drive: 300MBMultiplayer: Broadband Internet Connection or LAN required for multiplayer.MacOS: OS X version Leopard 10.5.8, Snow Leopard 10.6.3, or later.Processor: 1.6Ghz CPU (2.4 Ghz recommended, Dual Core strongly recommended for Host)Memory: 1 GB RAM (2 GB recommended)Graphics: Graphics card must support 1024x1024 textures (most 32MB and up graphics cards do), 1024x768 or greater (32 bit color recommended)Hard Drive: 300MB</description><genres><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/6/68766/1192334-aiwar.png</image></root>