<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>28188</id><name>Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War II: Chaos Rising</name><description>Campaign ModeChaos Rising takes place mere months after the event of Dawn of War II on planet Aurelia, the home world of the Blood Ravens, which was pushed out of orbit by the warp storm a thousand years ago and was thought to be lost forever. Aurelia has inexplicably returned, bringing with it the Chaos Marines, a group of insane, mutated space marines hellbent on destroying the Space Marines and all they stand for. Now the Blood Ravens must fight to reclaim their lost planet or fall forever to the corruption of Chaos.Corruption MechanicDawn of War II: Chaos Rising contains a new corruption meter. As your squads progress through the campaign, they have the chance to be able to become more corrupt. Having impure squads doesn't hinder the gameplay or stop you from progressing through the story. Instead, the corruption mechanic allows the player to unlock new Chaos abilities and gear for his/her squads, and depending how corrupt the squads become changes the outcome of the game as a whole.New Squad LeaderJonah the LibrarianJonah the Librarian joins your team in Chaos Rising as the newest squad leader. He's a powerful psychic caster, a dynamic the developers felt the player didn't have access to in the original Dawn of War II campaign. Jonah can equip spells in the same way other squad leaders equip accessories. By equipping different Focus Items, the player can change the way a spell functions. For example, Jonah can equip the "psychic hood" which transforms his otherwise normal fireball attack into the Ignite Soul ability: if the fireball kills a target then the target itself explodes, causing area of effect damage.Multiplayer ModeChaos Rising makes a number of additions to Dawn of War II's traditional mutliplayer game mode. A new faction, the Chaos Space Marines, is now available along, with new units and squads for each of the four original factions. In addition, all extra content to the old races will be free for owners of Dawn of War II. Also, all previous races have been rebalanced and outfitted with new upgrades.New Race: Chaos Space Marines"Impurity shall be our armor. Hate shall be our weapon. Immortality shall be our reward."CommandersChaos LordChaos LordPrimarily a melee class using powerful attacks and health draining abilities to fight enemies directly. Cannot be suppressed. Choosing this Commander will align your heretics with Khorne, causing their shrines to summon temporary Bloodletters.Plague ChampionA long-range specialist with abilities equivalent to both an apothecary and a techmarine on the SM side. He can build turrets, repair mechanical things, and also acquire items that allow him to heal allies or poison enemies. Choosing this Commander will align your heretics with Nurgle, and their shrines will increase the regeneration rate of any allies nearby.Chaos SorcererA fragile magic-user who uses powerful spells to teleport around the map and disrupt enemy formations. Choosing this Commander will align your heretics with Tzeentch, and their shrines will cloak any nearby allies and fire damaging bolts of energy at nearby enemy units.Tier 1Chaos Space MarinesChaos Hereticsa basic meat-shield unit, but these units can build shrines to their dark god of choice, surround a unit and suicide bomb it with Doomblast, or even acquire grenade launchers to damage enemy infantry at long range.Chaos Space MarinesA tough, basic, long-range unit. Can be upgraded to have plasma guns under Tzeentch or get battle axes with the mark of Khorne.Chaos HavocsA powerful tier-one suppression unit. Can later be upgraded through Khorne to increase their rate-of-fire with each kill or through Tzeentch to get an anti-vehicle laser.Tier 2Chaos DreadnoughtBloodlettersA powerful hit-and-run melee unit granted by Khorne that can teleport through the warp or phase shift to avoid taking damage. Carries flaming swords.Chaos DreadnoughtRequires a lot of power to produce, but a unit to be reckoned with. Can be upgraded under Khorne to have a second melee claw and the Blood Lust ability, or under Tzeentch to attach a missile launcher.BloodcrusherA single bloodletter riding atop a mighty beast with light vehicle armor. Used to break suppression or otherwise harass an enemy without any tier 2 tech.Chaos Plague MarinesA unit of four heavy Chaos Marines, one of which comes with a rocket launcher for anti-vehicle support. When any Plague Marine dies, they leave behind a pile of filth that heals nearby allies and damages nearby enemies.Tier 3The Great Unclean OneChaos PredatorA powerful tank that can be upgraded to take on either heavy infantry or attach an anti-tank laser.The Great Unclean OneCosts a large amount of money, but its powerful attack and incredible regeneration rate makes the GUO nearly unkillable.New UnitsSpace MarinesLibrarianLibrarianSpace Marine "Psyker" unit capable of powerful damage and support spells. Inspires surrounding marines when killing in melee.New UpgradesThe Predator Tank gets a lascannon upgrade. Effective against vehicles but weaker against infantry.The Force Command terminator armor gets a claw upgrade. A melee weapon effective against Heavy and light infantry.Devastator Heavy Bolter squads now revice a lascannon upgrade. Effective against vehicles but squad loses suppuration.EldarWraithguardWraithguardSlow moving short range heavy infantry, they move more quickly with a warlock nearby but are stunned if the warlock dies.OrksWeirdboyWierdboyThe Weirdboy is a long range support unit and caster. Charge his energy by putting him near da boyz and having them shout. His attacks will damage both enemies and allies if they are too close together.TyranidsTyrant GuardTyrant GuardA large durable melee unit, moves faster in synapse. Can use the Shieldwall ability which regenerates health and reduces incoming damage.Genestealer BroodAn elite melee unit that infiltrates after staying still for enough time. Adrenal Rush ability grants increased speed, lifesteal and increased damage.Free-For-All Multiplayer ModeChaos Rising adds a new multiplayer mode to Dawn of War II. Free-For-All is an every-man-for-himself style mode that supports at least 6 players. Like the normal ranked match game play, Free-For-All requires sustained control of Victory Points spread across the map to win. Unlike normal ranked matches however, players start with 0 points and must collect 500 for victory. Additionally, Victory Points can be destroyed. A destroyed Victory Point can be repaired for a "cost".Last Stand ModeChaos Rising features two new heroes for Dawn of War II's Last Stand DLC mode: the Tyranid Hive Tyrant and the Chaos Sorcerer.Tyranid Hive TyrantHive TyrantThe Hive Tyrant is a slow but powerful hero with the ability to summon and support Tyranid minions.ArmorPoison CystsPoison Cysts - Acquired at level 1. Carapace riddled with small poison cysts used to excrete clouds of toxic miasma. Grants the ability to launch an area of effect, damage over time poison attack and makes the wearer immune to suppression and knockback. Armor Rating: 160Bonded Exoskeleton - Acquired at level 6. Heavily thickened carapace which signals a hive evolution that makes all minion creatures more resilient. Makes the wearer immune to knockback. Armor Rating: 134Reinforced Chitin - Each attack on this chitin triggers a hardening of resinous mucus increasing its armor value. Makes the wearer immune to knockback. Armor Rating: 98WeaponsHeavy TalonsHeavy Talons - Acquired at level 10. Grants the ability to knock down/back enemy infantry with regular attacks and makes user's minions immune to knockback.High-Toxin Venom Cannon - Heals user's minions on hit.AccessoriesSeismic RoarSeismic Roar - Acquired at level 1. Grants the ability to stun nearby enemies with a roar.Genestealer Nest - Acquired at level 1. Allows the Hive Tyrant to call Genestealer minion creatures. Genestealers wield Rending claws that reduce enemy armor.Warrior Nest - Acquired at level 7. Grants the ability to summon a Tyranid Warrior.Psychic Scream - Grants the ability to weaken enemy squad's damage and armor within a given range.Ravener Nest - Grants the ability to summon a Tyranid Ravener.Commander ItemsEvolutionThornback- Acquired at level 5. Grants the ability to charge in a straight line, knocking over everything in the path.Synapse - Reduces cost of of all abilities by 50%.Evolution - Acquired at level 20. Gives the wearer 2.0 health regeneration. Gives wearer's minions 50 health, 2.0 health regeneration, 25% movement speed and 25% melee and ranged damage.AchievementsChaos Rising features a full set of achievements, totalling at 1000 points. However, there is not a separate achievement set. The achievements are instead added into Dawn of War II's original achievement set, bringing the total to 2000 points.System RequirementsMinimum Requirements:OS: Windows XP SP2 / Windows Vista SP1Processor: P4 3.2 GHz (single core) or any Dual Core processorMemory: 1 GB RAM (XP), 1.5 GB RAM (Vista)Video Card: 128MB (Shader Model 3) - Nvidia GeForce 6600 GT / ATI X1600, or equivalentHard Drive: 5.5 GBNetwork: Online play requires log-in to Games For Windows - LiveRecommended Requirements:OS: Windows XP SP2 / Windows Vista SP1Processor: AMD Athlon 64x2 4400 or any Intel Core 2 DuoMemory: 2 GB RAM (XP and Vista)Video Card: 256MB (Shader Model 3) - Nvidia GeForce 7800 GT / ATI X1900, or equivalentHard Drive: 5.5 GBNetwork: Online play requires log-in to Games For Windows - Live</description><genres><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="27130">Command &amp; Conquer 4:  Tiberian Twilight</game><game id="31544">Company of Heroes Online</game><game id="24708">WorldShift</game><game id="38224">Company of Heroes 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2022691-box_wh40kdow2cr.png</image></root>