<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>28226</id><name>KIRAKIRA</name><description>OverviewKiraKira was first developed and released in Japan for the PC by Overdrive on November 22, 2007. It was later translated and released in English by MangaGamer on June 24, 2009. M-trix later released it for the iPhone in both Japanese and English languages on November 20, 2009 and for the Android platform on May 4, 2011. An all-ages version was released for the Playstation 2 only in Japan on February 26, 2009 by PrincessSoft and for the PC by MangaGamer on July 1, 2010.PlotShikanosuke Maejima is a student at the Missionary school, Oubi Academy. He doesn't attend his club, he doesn't put much effort in his studies, all he does is show up at his part time job; in short, his life could be better. One day, he meets a strange girl, Kirari Shiino, at work and before he knows it, they've formed a punk band.The band consists of Shikanosuke, Kirari, his childhood friend Chie Isurugi, and a rich but weak young lady by the name of Sarina Kashiwara. The four of them are members of the Second Literature Club (daini bungeibu, shortened to d2b), which has hardly any active members and is already scheduled to be disbanded. This band is their chance to stand out and give one final farewell at the Culture Festival.The challenge was foolhardy, but after eccentric training they managed to succeed and rock out the peaceful Oubi Academy with their debut performance. That should have been it.They were satisfied.They should have returned to their normal lives.However, their final performance at a local Live House became a hit on the Internet and requests for their performance start flying in from far and wide.One problem: exams are coming up and their parents are opposed to the band!Who cares!The four of them embark on their final adventure, a long tour of Japan, armed with their dreams and their instruments, all aboard a rickety van that could fall apart at any moment."First stop, Nagoya!"Main CharactersShikanosuke MaejimaShikanosuke MaejimaShikanosuke is the protagonist of KiraKira. He used to be a tennis player and plays doubles with Murakami but he quit due to health issues. At the beginning of the story, Shikanosuke was dumped by his girlfriend.Shikanosuke met Kirari at the Taishou Restaurant where he was working at and she invited to form the Second Literature Club band. He plays the bass guitar and cross-dresses and plays as Shikako.Kirari ShiinoKirari ShiinoKirari is the oldest child of an impoverished family. Her cheerful and energetic personality hides her hardship. Kirari is exceptionally intelligent and is attending school under scholarship. Her intelligence also makes it difficult for her to mix with her peers.Kirari met Shikanosuke on her first day at her new job at the Taishou Restaurant and she invited him to form a band. Initially, she wanted the drums but Chie convinced her to be the vocalist. Kirari proved to have a powerful singing voice.Chie IsurugiChie IsurugiChie is Shikanosuke's childhood friend and is close to his family. She is actually a year older than him but she had to repeat her third year of high school due to family issues. Chie is the president of the Second Literature Club and invited Shikanosuke to the club after he quit the tennis club.Chie is the unofficial leader of the band and is the voice of reason for the group. She hides her shy nature with a mature personality. Chie plays the drums.Sarina KashiwaraSarina KashiwaraSarina is the only child of a rich family. She has a weak constitution and her grandfather's strict upbringing caused her to have very few friends and very little exposure to the outside world. Kirari is her best friend and she often visits Sarina's home.Sarina is mild-mannered and lady-like but has a strong will and can be stubborn. She is the lead guitarist of the band and she obtained her electric guitar from her uncle.GameplayKiraKira is heavy on narrative, with the occasional choice of 2 or 3 options. The choices will determine the player's relationship with the three girls and the band's reputation. There are several checkpoints throughout the game that will lead to a game over if the band's reputation at that point is insufficient.The first half of the story focuses on the band's adventure. The story then branches at a specific point where the band will have their final performance then focuses on one of the girls. The true ending, which is considered canon, is unlocked after clearing all the girls' paths.Original Sound TrackKira Kira - game's theme song and opening themeToo Fast to Live, Too Young to Die - STAR GENERATION's songLet's Jump - d2b's song during the school festivalTo be by your side - d2b's song first performed at Osaka, ballad-styleLike a Life, Like a Live - song produced by KirariA song for... - song produced by Shikanosuke, performed by Happy Cycle Mania on Kirari's normal ending and ending themeO.H.B.I. - rearrangement of the school's anthemTraveler - Sarina's ending themeGo on a Trip - Chie's ending themeLead You to Dream - Kirari's first single with Shikanosuke's accompaniment on Kirari's true ending and ending themeSystem RequirementsRequired CPU:Pentium III 800MHzRecommended CPU:Pentium 4 1.4GHzRequired Memory:256MBRecommended Memory:384MBRequired Resolution:800x600Required Colors:16bit colorsRecommended Colors:24bit colorsRequired Graphics:4MB VRAMRecommended Graphics:32MB VRAMRequired HDD Free Space:2GBDirectX:DirectX 8.1, Direct3DCreditsProducerHiroshi "bamboo" TakeuchiOriginal Character DesignerShinji KatakuraScenarioRen Shinya SetoguchiComposermilktub / Second Literature Club bandMovieIris Motion GraphicDirectorNarazaki Sun</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="41370">Deardrops</game><game id="31181">KiraKira Curtain Call</game><game id="41420">A Profile</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/33017/1141783-kirakiracover.png</image></root>