<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>28310</id><name>The Settlers 7: Paths to a Kingdom</name><description>Story Princess ZoéThe story of the game takes place in the land of Tandria, where you take  the role of         Princess Zoé,  attempting to free Tandria from its corrupt rulers, thieves and  bandits. Throughout the majority of the story you are accompanied by an  adviser, Bors, whose guidance is crucial to your success in early  levels. The story takes you through various locations on Tandria and  features a colorful cast of characters, allies and enemies alike, such  as Ramírez, Raspun, Dracorian, Rovyn, Lord Wolvering, Bishop Matheusz,  Field Marshall Ludowig, King Konradin and King Balderus.  Gameplay Campaign map     The campaign of the game consists of 12 levels, some of which also act as a tutorial for various mechanics of game, ranging from basic economy to more advanced tactics. In early levels only military victory is available, but later when Victory Points come in play the possibilities of varying tactics open up. The map consists of sectors that are either neutral, yours, ally's or enemy's. Each sector holds a single military outpost, but can also be upgraded to place palisades and stone towers next to roads. You can take over neutral sectors with brute force, use your traders to bribe them, or proselytize them with novice clerics. You can freely travel through sectors owned by your allies, but only military strength will help you take over sectors from your enemies. The logistics of the game's economy is divided into 4 classes, military, church, trade, and building. Each class have their own queue displayed, where you can prioritize, halt and resume objects. Additionally you can also prioritize a whole class over another. Technology research is done with your clerics of varying levels, and are generally used to boost part of your economy and military by reducing production times, providing more resources, or just making your units faster. Establishing trade routes is useful if you are short on a particular resource, but have plenty of something else. Establishing routes requires traders of varying levels. Prestige pointsPrestige Points are used to unlock upgrades,  mostly for your buildings, but also for stone roads and forest  clearance. Prestige Points are automatically awarded for conquering new  sectors, researching new advancements and establishing trading routes.  You can also build small, medium and large prestige objects of varying  price to quickly raise your prestige level.  Victory pointsVictory pointsVictory Points are the main deciding factor on  who wins the map. While pure military victory is possible by simply  wiping your enemies of the map, it's much more likely that the victory  is received by Victory Points. There are two kinds of victory points,  dynamic and permanent ones. Dynamic points are only yours as long as you  can hold them. They are generally awarded for holding a certain special  sector on the map, having most sectors, having the largest army, having  the most money, having most research and most trade routes and other,  similar things. You only hold the point as long as you qualify.  Permanent points are different in the way that they are generally harder  to get, but once you get one, it's yours for the rest of the match.  Permanent points are gained by doing certain quests, researching the  most expensive technology or establishing special trading routes.  Buildings Most of  the construction in the game is divided into  the 5 class of buildings, each of which have 3 adjacent building slots  reserved for work yards. Farm: Farms need a lot of space  for their work yards.Grain BarnPiggeryShepherdStable       Windmill  Mountain Shelter: For various mining related operationsCoal MinerIron MinerGold MinerIron SmelterQuarryCoking Plant Lodge: Your main building for  various gatherers.FisherHunter      SawmillWoodcutterForester Residence: Raises your maximum population,  your basic living quarters.Paper MillWeaving MillBrewery, BakeryWheelwrightToolmaker Noble  Residence: Bigger and fancier houses.BookbinderMint      BlacksmithGoldsmithTailorButcher Work yards of Farm, Mountain Shelter, Lodge and basic Residence work  without food, but it's possible to food boost them to work more  efficiently. Work yards of Noble Residence requires basic food just to  work, but is also possible to boost with Fancy Food. It's possible to  upgrade both residences twice to hold more people.Special buildings  StorehouseYour basic storage  building, but also contains the units that move your resources around  the map. Bunch of well placed storehouses are a key to a good economy.  Basic storehouses can only support 20 of each resource, upgrading will  raise the cap to 50, and second upgrade will remove the cap entirely.  StrongholdThe building for Military Branch. From this building  you will train your military units. Can be upgraded twice to train more  advanced units. ChurchTrains Clerics of various levels,  depending on the level of the Church. The only building with three  upgrades. Export OfficeHeart of your Trade Branch, trains  traders. ConstructorEssential to your kingdom, this  building is the home of your constructors. Basic constructor holds only  one person, but the building is upgradeable to hold 3. WellYou guessed it. Offers endless supply of water. In most of the maps you will start with a fully upgraded storehouse, a  fully upgraded constructor and a tavern. Tavern acts as a place to hire  mercenaries (Pikemen and Musketeers), hiring Generals to lead your  troops, and to do small trading. UnitsAside from the various automated workers, you also have access to military, church and trade units.  Military Pikemen Basic melee unit, available from both  the tavern and from level 1 stronghold. MusketeersBasic  long range unit, available from the tavern and level 1 stronghold.   CavaliersAdvanced melee unit, available only from level 2 and  higher stronghold. CannonsAdvanced long range unit,  available only from level 3 stronghold. Standard BearerSupport unit, army with him will fight more effectively. Available only  from level 3 stronghold.  Church Technology mapClerics come in three tiers, Novices, Brothers and  Fathers. While novices can also be used to take over neutral sectors,  the main use of all the cleric units is technology research. Clerics can  also be used to boost the health of your military by sending them to  military outposts in your sectors. Traders      Trade MapTraders also come in three tiers, Hawkers, Salesmen and  Merchants. You can use Hawkers to take over neutral sectors with  bribery, but the main use of traders is to trade and establish trading  routes. Multiplayer, online  DRM  The game has your basic multiplayer modes such as         skirmish against AI and         online multiplayer against other players. The gameplay is the same as it is in later campaign missions, victory points being the main path to a victory. Settlers 7 is also one of the first games to contain         Ubisoft's controversial “always online”         Digital Rights Management solution, that requires the player to have a constant internet connection available even during singleplayer campaign missions. If connection is lost on either the player's side or Ubisoft's side, the game will pause and wait for a reconnection. If connection can not be reestablished, the session will be locally saved and the game will quit to the menu. The saved games are also synchronized in “the cloud” on Ubisoft's servers, so the player can continue their game on another computer in another location.   Map Forge Map Forge allows you to customize the maps you play in, by changing the amount and type of Victory points, mining resource locations, event locations, and other details of the map. Castle Forge In Castle Forge you can customize the look of your castle for both the singleplayer campaign as well as skirmish and online multiplayer. Various objects that you can add are walls, flags, towers, windows and ornaments. You can also purchase more objects with your         UPlay points as well as in-game reward currency that is accumulated during all your matches. Achievements Settlers 7 has         achievements that are directly related to your Ubisoft / UPlay account and UPlay points.  Uplay Uplay is a service where you earn points and use them to unlock bonus items. Here is a list of Actions (achievements) and Rewards for this game.  ActionsPointsKing of my CastleDefine your own castle at the Castle Forge and use it in game. 10UAgainst the OddsWin 1 skirmish match in single player mode with a minimum of 3 AI opponents. 20UHeat of the BattleFinish 5 matches at the SETTLERS Empire. 30UHero of TandriaComplete the campaign of The Settlers 7. 40U RewardsCostThe Settlers 7 WallpaperGrants you the exclusive Uplay Wallpaper for The Settlers 7. 10UEnormous AdvantageThe "enormous" option is available for resources and start condition at the Map Forge. 20U Castle ElementsUse an exclusive set of decorations for your castle at the Castle Forge. 30UThe Crushed MirrorGet your hand on this 4 player map to prove your skills against the AI or in multiplayer matches. 40U  DRM Settlers uses Ubisoft's custom DRM that requires an online connection at all times.System Requirements OS: Windows XP, Windows Vista, Windows 7Processor: 2 GHz Intel Pentium 4 / AMD XP 2600  or better (Intel Core 2 Duo / AMD Athlon 64 X2 recommended)Memory: 2 GB (4 GB recommended)Graphics: 256 MB DirectX 9.0c-compliant, Shader 3.0-enabled video card (512 MB recommended)(*see supported list)DirectX®: DirectX 9.0cHard Drive: 8 GBSound: DirectX 9.0c-compliant sound cardPeripherals Supported: Windows-compliant keyboard and mouseInternet Connection: Broadband Internet connection with 128 kbps upstream or fasterSupported Video Cards at Time of Release:NVIDIA GeForce 7900 / 8 / 9 / GT / GTS / GTX seriesATI Radeon X1900 / HD 2000 / HD 3000 / HD 4000 / HD 5000 series</description><genres><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23459">Dawn of Discovery</game><game id="23547">Anno 1701: Dawn of Discovery</game><game id="6724">1602 A.D.</game><game id="21454">Majesty 2: The Fantasy Kingdom Sim</game><game id="6645">Caesar III</game><game id="19170">Caesar IV</game><game id="8546">Age of Empires III</game><game id="6161">Serf City: Life is Feudal</game><game id="30640">Patrician IV</game><game id="34703">Anno 2070</game><game id="36344">Castle Empire Online</game><game id="8460">Diggles: the Myth of Fenris</game><game id="18721">Cultures</game><game id="2859">Cultures: Die Saga</game><game id="5457">Cultures: Die Abenteuerbox</game><game id="19132">Cultures 2: The Gates of Asgard</game><game id="14638">Northland</game><game id="1489">8th Wonder of the World</game><game id="3009">Immortal Cities: Children of the Nile</game><game id="10942">The Nations</game><game id="12474">Black &amp; White 2</game><game id="738">Black &amp; White 2: Battle of the Gods</game><game id="16757">Tropico: Paradise Island</game><game id="32326">Tropico 4</game><game id="24458">Tropico 3</game><game id="7965">Tropico 2: Pirate Cove</game><game id="11466">CivCity: Rome</game><game id="5652">Caesar II</game><game id="12757">Tropico</game><game id="30573">Tropico 3: Absolute Power</game><game id="4102">Emperor: Rise of the Middle Kingdom</game><game id="36949">Majesty 2: Battles of Ardania</game><game id="17680">Pharaoh</game><game id="6210">Populous</game><game id="10562">Populous II: Trials of the Olympian Gods</game><game id="5211">Zeus Official Expansion: Poseidon</game><game id="3769">Zeus: Master of Olympus</game><game id="3144">Cleopatra: Queen of the Nile</game><game id="625">Alien Nations</game><game id="8592">Caesar</game><game id="18623">Black &amp; White</game><game id="14823">Black &amp; White: Creature Isle</game><game id="18490">Majesty: The Northern Expansion</game><game id="11751">Majesty: The Fantasy Kingdom Sim</game><game id="29811">Majesty 2: Kingmaker</game><game id="31820">Majesty 2: Pocket Kingdom</game><game id="36948">Majesty 2: Monster Kingdom</game><game id="15035">SimCity</game><game id="4736">SimCity 4</game><game id="13760">SimCity 2000</game><game id="10733">SimCity 3000</game><game id="18443">SimCity 3000 Unlimited</game><game id="14865">SimCity 4: Rush Hour</game><game id="38867">Total War: Rome II</game><game id="40887">Towers of Oz</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/880/1868695-settlers7.jpg</image></root>