<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>28974</id><name>Auditorium</name><description>OverviewIn Auditorium, you manipulate a stream of rays which are called "The Flow" by setting up points of movement and expanding or minimizing their area of effect. These points vary from a simple direction to creating a swirling vortex which will steer the Flow in a variety of strengths depending on the radius of the control points. The object is to use these control points so the Flow hits "Audio Containers", which are squares that emit a sound when hit by the Flow, eventually building to a harmonizing melody. Speed, trajectories, and colors must be constant enough to sustain the melody before the level is cleared.At first, players begin with a single color, but as the game progresses, the Audio Containers have several different colors and the Flow will have to pass "Color Spheres" of different colors to match the Audio Containers.For example: One level will have you start with a yellow Flow, but only a red Audio Container. There will be a red Color Sphere which will change the color, but you will have to manipulate the Flow so it passes through the red Color Sphere to change it's color, but still hit the red Audio Container.Auditorium HDThe PlayStation 3 version of the game contains the original 72 levels of Auditorium, plus 78 all new levels, PlayStation Move integration, and 3D support.PC System RequirementsOS: Windows XP/Vista/7Processor: 1.2 GHz Dual-Core or higherMemory: 2GB or higherHard Disk Space: 65MBMac System RequirementsOS: OS X version Leopard 10.5.8, Snow Leopard 10.6.3, or later.Processor: 1.2 GHz Dual-Core or higherMemory: 2GB or higherHard Disk Space: 15MB</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9436">Audiosurf</game><game id="22034">Rez HD</game><game id="5057">Lumines: Puzzle Fusion</game><game id="37318">AVSEQ</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/6/63119/1635008-auditorium_splash.jpg</image></root>