<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29027</id><name>Arkedo Series - 01 JUMP!</name><description>Overview The goal of JUMP! is to collect each bomb before the timer runs out.     Arkedo Series - 01 JUMP! is a            platform game where the player takes control of Jumpman. The story begins with a giant Iron Crab dropping bombs onto the planet and Jumpman must collect all the bombs before they explode. The game was made by a team of two men, Aurélien Régard and Dimitri Péan, and the entire game took 35 days to create from start to completion.  Gameplay Each stage begins littered with bombs and each bomb has an individual timer. The bombs must be collected before the timer reaches zero or they will detonate and the level will be failed. Sometimes bombs are encased inside Piggy Banks, and must be unlocked by collecting the required amount of $. Currency appears in the form of coins, gems and treasure chests. Once all the bombs have been collected the door is unlocked. Jumping into the door completes the level.  Jumpman The main character of  Arkedo Series - 01 JUMP! is jumpman, a small man with a green shirt and brown hat and trousers. Jumpman will die if he touches an enemy or dangerous object, for example fire or spikes.  Enemies The critters out to get you in Arkedo Series - 01 JUMP!  include:   Crabs    Bats     Snakes      Skeletons  Objects and Weapons Jumpman can occasionally collect weapons, such as  knives, which can be thrown at enemies using the X button.   Game DesignArkedo Series - 01 JUMP! uses the "retro evolved" pixelated style used in games like                  Space Invaders Extreme and                 Pacman Championship Edition. Objects have been simplified and are depicted using groups of coloured squares with bold outlines.  Completing a level in Arkedo Series - 01 JUMP! rewards the player with a screen displaying the word "YEAH" and a small caption. Collecting Hearts will reward the player with an extra life, but if jumpman runs out of lives then it's game over - there are no continues and the player must begin the game from the beginning. Apparently "Retro games didn't have continues!"   There are a list of bonus challenge levels that can be unlocked by progressing through the adventure.</description><genres><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12914">Flicky</game><game id="19726">Mario Bros.</game><game id="29331">Dreams of Witchtown</game><game id="10014">Pitfall!</game><game id="12877">Pitfall II: Lost Caverns</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2345917-box_arkedo1.png</image></root>