<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29122</id><name>Stellar Dawn</name><description>MechScapeJagex started working on a game which they called MechScape back in 2006. They didn't release much information to the public about the game, other than that they were continuing to work on it. On June 14, 2010, Jagex announced that the MechScape project had been scrapped, but they were taking several concepts, and other bits of work, to develop a new game called Stellar Dawn. According to Jagex, the MechScape project was canceled because they didn't feel it was up to their standards, as it was nearing its release. The question is if the MechScape developments did really stop, or that it was just given a new name: Stellar DawnOverviewStellar Dawn is a combat-driven, sci-fi MMORPG. Very little is known about the game right now, although Jagex is slowly revealing new bits of information as the release date nears. Like RuneScape, Stellar Dawn will have both a free-to-play version, and a premium version available for a small monthly fee. The premium version will have a lot more content, and will receive regular content updates.There will be a set of skills to train up, much like in RuneScape, however, progressing through those skills will be a lot different. Jagex hasn't explained what they mean by this, but they have said their aim is to cut down on the constant skill-grinding and the use of macros and other cheats.Closed BetaJagex is planning to host a closed beta sometime before the release of the game, although no details have been announced yet. You can apply for the beta on the game's official website. There is no firm date for the beta to begin.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22099">MechScape</game><game id="2268">RuneScape</game><game id="34461">Transformers Universe</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/12806/1179114-stellardawn_logo_1_.jpg</image></root>