<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29147</id><name>Magic: The Gathering - Tactics</name><description>Overview Magic: The Gathering - Tactics is a free to play free to download microtransaction game that lets players duel each other in an online environment. It was released for the PC on January 18, 2011, with a later date scheduled for the PS3. Players take the role of a Planeswalker and will have access to all five color decks. They can then take their decks and duel each other or participate in the single player campaign. Players start with access to the first chapter of the PvE campaign, but need to spend real money (via stationcash) to purchase additional chapters. The starting deck depends on what color you select when you create your avatar and consists of 40 cards, the minimum required to create a playing deck. Additional cards are gained by completing mission in the PvE campaign, or by spending cash to buy boosters. Gameplay The gameplay in Tactics deviates markedly from the original card game. The playing field is divided into grids, creatures move around on the playing field, can only melee attack adjacent enemies, need line of sight to use ranged attack or special abilities etc. Large creatures can occupy more than 1 grid. Each creature has, in addition to the usual attack/defence stats, the following 3 stats that are used for the new system:Movement: How many spaces the creature may move. Flying creatures may fly over obstacles, but not end their turn on them. There are also spectral creatures that may move through obstacles.Initiative: How often the creature gets a turn. In normal MtG player 1 and all his creatures take a turn, then player 2 etc. In Tactics every creature (including the player's avatar) is kept track of individually, and the higher their initiative, the more often they act.Range: The number of spaces the creature can attack. Enemies that are far away take less damage.System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows XPProcessor: Intel Pentium 4 3.0 GHz, AMD Athlon FX-53Memory: 1 GBHard Disk Space: 2.16 GB Free SpaceVideo Card: NVIDIA GeForce 8600 or ATI Radeon HD2900Additional: Broadband Internet ConnectionRecommendedOS: Windows XP, Vista, 7Processor: Intel Core2 Duo or AMD Athlon FX-60Memory: 2 GBHard Disk Space: 2.16 GB Free SpaceVideo Card: NVIDIA GeForce 8800 or ATI Radeon HD2900</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="33448">Vantage Master</game><game id="33450">VM Japan: Vantage Master - Mystic Far East</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/573/1184600-magic_tactics.jpg</image></root>