<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29215</id><name>Dangerous Dave</name><description>OverviewDangerous Dave is a 1988 Computer game by John Romero. It was developed for DOS and Apple II.  There are 4 Dangerous dave games.   Dangerous Dave is platformer game. You will get an extra life if you get 10000 Points in score.  The object of the game was to collect gold cups, but the main goal is to get the Shiny trophy to move on to the next level. There's total of 10 levels.   Game uses 16-color (16 color port of the 1988 original)          Weapons/ItemsThats your GUN. It is obtainable in some levels by jumping on it. and the ammo is infinte and thats your big bullet .With GUN you can´t shoot multiple times, you must wait until the 1x bullet is out of the screen so you can re shoot.Jetpack, used to fly over big distances. You must save the fuel you got as it is not infinte.   Score items and ItemsPurple dot - Gives you 50 score.Blue gem - Gives 100 score.Red gem - Gives you  150 score.   Ring - Gives you 200 score.Crown - Gives you 300 score.Green Stick or Orb  - Gives you 500 score.  Trophy - The key to finish the level using door.Door - used to finish the level.   MonstersSpider - The very first boss you will meet , Moves usually in cyrcles, shoots one bullet at the time. Red dot -  Red dot that also moves kinda fast and will one shot you.Blue dot - Blue dot that also moves fast and will one shot you. Landscape/ObjectsHarmless.Blue block - Blue block since level 2 Dark Blue block -Block that is used in some levels and in the level end ´´video´´ Red Block - Same as the blue block,used in level 1 and other levels. Light brown block / Dirt - Used in many levels.Purple Bricks - Used as stairs. Pipe-Enterence to new level. Dangerous/Objects Water - Blue thing with dots that kills you.  Fire - Red sparks that will also instant kill you when touch.  Purple Roots - Roots that kill you.  Stars-Used as ladder.Tree- Used as ladder.</description><genres><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/6/62608/1189208-dangerousdave.jpg</image></root>