<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29221</id><name>Call of Duty: Modern Warfare Reflex Edition</name><description>Call of Duty 4The game is a complete port of the original.Originally, Call of Duty 4: Modern Warfare was released for the PC, Xbox 360, Playstation 3, and the Nintendo DS. Unlike previous games in the series, Modern Warfare leaves the WWII setting for a modern day setting. The game went on to be the most successful Call of Duty game ever made, selling well over 10 million copies, receiving high scores from many game journalist publications.For more information on the game, please visit our page for the original game.DevelopmentUsing only a small budget, the game was completely rebuilt from the ground up for the Wii.Because the engine in which Call of Duty 4 ran was not compatible with the Wii, Treyarch had to completely remake the engine for it to run on the console.Because the Wii's RAM was lower than the other consoles, the game could not load full levels at one time like the HD versions did. Treyarch instead segmented the levels so that different parts could "stream in" as the player progressed through the level.Real-time lighting was dropped in favor of pre-baked lighting effects, using colored textures and polygonal shadows to create the illusion of real-time lighting to both save on budget and time. Wii Speak support was also not added, although the game's full online multiplayer mode remains intact. Using inspiration from games like The Conduit, the Wii remote controls are now fully customizable.ControversyA scene from Call of Duty 4 running on Wii.After Treyarch completed development of Call of Duty 5, rumours started to appear talking about Infinity Ward's unhappiness about other developers handling their games. In the past, Infinity Ward has usually made the numbered Call of Duty games, while Treyarch handled the ports to consoles, which the number was removed for a subtitle, to differentiate the games from Infinity Ward's titles.After debating the issue, Infinity Ward convinced Activision to rename Call of Duty 5 into Call of Duty: World at War, dropping it's numbered moniker. Infinity Ward was also not pleased with Call of Duty 3, which they also didn't develop, getting a numbered title. In fact, the PC version of Call of Duty 4's executable file for starting the game has the name of Call of Duty 3.After development of Call of Duty: World at War ended, Treyarch began working on the port of Call of Duty 4 for the Nintendo Wii. Activision, who published Infinity Ward's Modern Warfare 2 the same year, did not do any press for the game, and only released a handful of pre-alpha screens, much to Treyarch's dismay. Treyarch's logo was also removed from the opening of the game, allegedly at Infinity Ward's request.The release of the game was a surprise to many, who did not know the game existed prior to it getting an official press release a couple days before it was scheduled to be released.ReceptionPeople were somehow surprised when a Wii game wasn't as good as its seventh-gen counterpart.Upon announcement and release, although a technically proficient port for it's budget, the game was bashed by critics for being a low quality port, citing graphical, feature, and control shortcomings to other Wii games in the genre.Although the original game was intact, the graphics were downgraded to sub-Wii levels, leading journalists to criticize the game for having dated graphics in comparison of other Wii games. The game also doesn't make use of Wii Speak, which also brought up complaints from players and critics.Some reports of crashing when the game connected to the internet were also reported, but the incidents were rare. The game uses the Wii remote, along with the nunchuk, the former of which is usually talked about as a faster and more intuitive way of playing first person shooters, and featured an extremely customizable control scheme, but it's complexity turned many gamers off to using the default schemes, which were criticized for "not feeling right".Upon release, the game received minimal market advertisement and presence, with only a few ads and posters placed in stores, along with coverage on the Nintendo Channel. It sold 81,000 units on it's first month on North American retail, with an average playtime of 24 hours and 55 minutes.Golden WeaponsIf anyone playing Call of Duty: Modern Warfare Reflex and thought they saw people with golden camouflage, your eyes were correct. Getting golden camouflage is very simple. For each weapon group you can get one golden weapon, here are a list of the weapons that you may get the golden camouflage for:Golden AK-47Complete all Assualt Rifle ChallengesGolden Desert EagleReach Level 55 CommanderGolden DragunovComplete all Sniper ChallengesGolden M1014Complete all Shotgun ChallengesGolden M60E4Complete all LMG ChallengesGolden Mini-UziComplete all SMG ChallengesSingle Player CheatsWhen you complete the campaign for the first time on any difficulty, you unlock the cheats menu, heres a list of each cheat and how they're unlocked:A Bad YearFind 15 IntelCluster BombsFind 10 IntelCoD NoirFind 02 IntelInfinite AmmoFind 30 IntelPaintballFind 08 IntelPhoto-NegativeFind 04 IntelSlow-Mo AbilityFind 20 IntelSuper ContrastFind 06 IntelOnline Multiplayer UnlockablesHere is a list of unlockables, on multiplayer mode, attain the required level to unlock the reward, perk, or gun.3x Frag (Perk Slot 1) - Level 41AK-47U - Level 28Bandolier (Perk Slot 1) - Level 32Barret .50 Cal - Level 49Bomb Squad (Perk Slot 1) - Level 14Boot Camp Challenges 1 - Level 09Boot Camp Challenges 2 - Level 15Boot Camp Challenges 3 - Level 18Clan Tag - Level 12Claymores - Level 23Create-a-Class - Level 04Dead Silence (Perk Slot 3) - Level 44Demolitions Class - Level 02Desert Eagle - Level 43Double Tap (Perk Slot 2) - Level 29Dragunov - Level 22Eavesdrop (Perk Slot 3) - Level 35Elite Challenges - Level 51Elite Challenges 2 - Level 53Elite Challenges 3 - Level 54G3 - Level 25G36C - Level 37Golden Desert Eagle - Level 55Gun Challenges - Level 05Humiliation Challenges 1 - Level 42Humiliation Challenges 2 - Level 45Humiliation Challenges 3 - Level 47Humiliation Challenges 4 - Level 48Humiliation Challenges 5 - Level 50Iron Lungs (Perk Slot 3) - Level 26Killer Challenges 1 - Level 30Killer Challenges 2 - Level 33Killer Challenges 3 - Level 36Killer Challenges 4 - Level 39Last Stand (Perk Slot 3) - Level 08M1014 - Level 31M14 - Level 46M1911 - Level 16M21 - Level 07M4 Carbine - Level 10M60E4 - Level 19Martyrdom - Level 17Mini-Uzi - Level 13MP44 - Level 52New Playlists - Level 06Operations Challenges 1 - Level 21Operations Challenges 2 - Level 24Operations Challenges 3 - Level 27Overkill (Perk Slot 2) - Level 38P90 - Level 40Prestige Mode - Level 55R700 - Level 34Sleight of Hand (Perk Slot 2) - Level 20Sniper Class - Level 03UAV Jammer (Perk Slot 2) - Level 11</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2600">Halo: Combat Evolved</game><game id="20601">Killzone 2</game><game id="15048">Killzone</game><game id="20655">Battlefield: Bad Company</game><game id="21646">Battlefield 2: Modern Combat</game><game id="21121">The Conduit</game><game id="7712">Red Steel</game><game id="30544">Conduit 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1784889-box_codmwre.png</image></root>