<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29238</id><name>Allods Online</name><description>Factions and RacesAllods Online has 2 playable factions which the player has to chose when he creates a new character. The 2 factions are called The League and The Empire.The LeagueThe League is a democratic society which uses a election and voting system. While they let their people vote to solve simple issues they depend on The Council of Deputies to make important that will impact on the lives of all League citizens.There are 3 league races that players can chose if they pick the League over the Empire.The Kanians are an ancient human race that had has to adjust to the Astral quickly.Champions (Warrior)Crusaders (Paladin)Rangers (Scout)Clerics (Healer)Druids (Warden)Magicians (Mage)The Elves are the oldest of the races, they have watched from a distance and watched to other develop after a long battle with the Orcs and the Xadaganians they signed up with the league.Templars (Paladin)Priests (Healer)Archmages (Mage)Demonologists (Summoner)The Gibberlings are a race of small furry creatures, Gibberlings come in a "sprout" of three who live, travel, fight and die as a unit. With their homeland destroyed they joined the league while looking for a new place to call home.Brawlers (Warrior)Tricksters (Scout)Animists (Warden)Seers (Psionicist)The EmpireThe Empire is a totalitarian state ruled by an enormous bureaucratic system. They rule with discipline and keep everyone in order with a strong military. There are 3 empire races that players can chose if they pick the empire over the league.The Xadaganians are a human race that has one goal in mind complete domination of the Astral. Their children are trained from birth to become the ultimate war machine. They build huge city's that host Xadaganian.Vanquishers (Warrior), Avengers(Paladin), Stalkers(Scout), Inquisitors(Healer), Defilers(Summoner), Mentalists(Psionicist)The Orcs are strong and mighty creatures that live in the places that are inhospitable to other races. Their inhuman strength makes them capable of destroying almost anything that is in their path.Brutes (Warrior)Reavers (Paladin)Marauders (Scout)Shaman (Warden)The Arisen are undead humans, that keep them self alive with machinery and mistycal.Heretics (Healer)Sorcerers (Mage)Savants (Summoner)Occultists (Psionicist)ClassesIn Allods Online there are 6 main classes. Each race has a unique racial ability in each of their classes.WarriorPaladinHealerScoutMageWardenSummonerPsionicistOpen Beta is as of 1st of March 2010 still ongoing.PC System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows XP / VistaCPU: 1.5 GHz Pentium 4 or better.RAM: 512 MBHDD: 3 GB FreeGraphics Card: ATI Radeon 9600+ VGA CardRecommendedOS: Windows XP / VistaCPU: 2 GHz Pentium 4RAM: 1024 MB (1GB)HDD: 3 GB FreeGraphics Card: Nvidia 6600 VGA Card</description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20701">World of Warcraft: Wrath of the Lich King</game><game id="18603">World of Warcraft: The Burning Crusade</game><game id="30193">Forsaken World</game><game id="40598">Maestia</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2352/1190933-allods_online_logo.png</image></root>