<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29247</id><name>Sacraboar</name><description>OverviewSacraboar is an RTS game that requires players to capture their opponent's boar trophy and then bring it back to the player's base. The complexity of the game is intended to be casual friendly with an easy to manage resource system, fast-paced, arcade-like combat, and simple technology and construction phases. Adding some strategic element to the game is the player's choice of which type of towers to build, which augment the player with spells or passive effects.The game offers common RTS features such as replays, tutorials, and multiplayer.GameplayObject of the GameThe object of a game of Sacraboar is to capture the opponent's pig trophy. The player commands units, using basic RTS controls, to both defend their own trophy and attempt to capture the opponent's trophy. The game works exactly like capture-the-flag, where the player must secure the opponent's trophy and then bring it back to their base to score. The enemy may stop the player by either killing the captor or by stealing the player's pig—preventing the player from capturing the enemy's trophy until they have retrieved their own. A pig trophy may be reacquired by killing the captor and touching the trophy, which teleports it back to its stand.ConstructionEach player starts the game with a set number of credits to build a starter army. Military units can be produced at the start of the match, which allows for quick skirmishes to happen within the first minute of the game. Each time a unit is killed, the player gets money back to spend again. This makes it imperative to keep units flowing and to not store credits. The amount of credits that the player has can be increased by building specific towers.UnitsThere are seven types of units: six fighters and one builder. The fighters have various strengths and weaknesses that must be managed depending on the location and the enemy's tactics. The builders are unarmed and cannot carry or return a pig. They transform into towers that give the player unique bonuses and augmentation.TowersA builder unit can transform into one of the follow five towers, each imbuing the player with unique abilities:TowerDescriptionResourceIncreases the amount of credits a player can use.SpeedGives the player access to speed spells that accelerate player units and slow down enemy units.NeutralizeCan freeze the enemy's units, block the enemy from using skills, or despell the player's units.ProtectionHeal player units or make them invulnerable for a period of time.DamageIncreases the damage of the player's units, block shots from the enemy, or transform a unit into a bomb.SingleplayerThe single player portion of the game consists of 89 missions with three difficulty levels: Bronze, Silver, and Gold. There is not a story weaving the missions together. The game offers six tutorial missions, not included in the 89 mission figure, that familiarize the player with the mechanics of the game.There are various types of single player modes such as League mode and Cup mode, each offering various missions and difficulty levels. Quick matches can be done using the skirmish mode, which offers a wide variety of difficulty and customization.The game offers achievements through Steam.MultiplayerSacraboar has support for LAN and internet games. The only mode of play is the traditional "capture-the-trophy" type. Players can share their replays and modules that enhance the game.System RequirementsOS: Windows XP/Vista/7Processor: 2.2 GHz CPU (Intel Pentium 4 or Athlon 64 XP) or betterMemory: 1 GBGraphics: 256 MB DirectX™ 9 compatible graphics card (NVidia 7600, ATI X1600) or betterDirectX®: 9.0Hard Drive: 350 MBSound: 100% DirectX™ 9 compatible sound card</description><genres><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="32887">Dota 2</game><game id="14073">Warcraft III: The Frozen Throne</game><game id="20103">Warcraft II: Tides of Darkness</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/11/110676/1908344-sacraboar.jpg</image></root>