<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29287</id><name>Final Fight: Double Impact</name><description> GameplayFinal Fight: Double Impact contains a remake of the original 1989 arcade release Final Fight together with the side-scrolling fantasy game Magic Sword.Both games feature online modes complete with leaderboards and drop-in co-op as well as achievements. Each game can be played with enhanced graphics or the original arcade graphics. The game can also be played in an arcade cabinet mode, which will distort the screen to make it look like you're playing it on an original arcade machine. Plot The story revolves around a street gang known as Mad Gear kidnapping Jessica, who is Haggar's daughter and Cody's girlfriend. Instead of giving in to the gang, Haggar, Cody, and Cody's ninja friend, Guy, take to the streets to destroy the gang and rescue Jessica. GameplayThe game has a total of six stages and two bonus stages. The bonus stages take place in a gas station, where the player is to destroy a thugs car within the time limit, and a glass panes factory, where the player is to destroy all of the glass panes in the factory within the time limit. ExtrasFinal Fight: Double Impact comes with a host of unlockable extras earned for completing challenges in both Final Fight and Magic Sword. Most of the unlockables consist of official artwork and fanart of their respective games. However, it is also possible to unlock "Final Fight", an episode of the Street Fighter cartoon that aired on the USA network in the mid-1990s that featured the Final Fight characters in a prominent guest appearance.</description><genres><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4325">Magic Sword</game><game id="21228">Battletoads</game><game id="2536">Altered Beast</game><game id="13315">Bad Street Brawler</game><game id="12187">Last Battle</game><game id="20754">Double Dragon Advance</game><game id="18122">Streets of Rage 2</game><game id="38381">Sega Vintage Collection: Streets of Rage</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1841436-box_ffdi.png</image></root>