<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29286</id><name>Castlevania: The Adventure ReBirth</name><description>Overview Castlevania: The Adventure ReBirth (known in Japan as Dracula Densetsu ReBirth, translated to Dracula Legends ReBirth) is a 2D action horror platformer developed by M2 and published by Konami for the Wii (via WiiWare for 1000 Wii Points) on December 28, 2009.The third game in Konami's ReBirth trilogy (after Gradius ReBirth and Contra ReBirth), Castlevania: The Adventure ReBirth is a re-imagining of the 1989 Game Boy game Castlevania: The Adventure, combining gameplay elements of many traditional Castlevania games while including synthesized rearrangements of previous Castlevania soundtracks.The game is set in 1576, nearly a century after the events of Castlevania III: Dracula's Curse and nearly a century before the events of Castlevania. Players control Christopher Belmont, a mighty vampire hunter brandishing the Vampire Killer whip, as he sets out to destroy the resurrected Count Dracula.Gameplay Unlike most 2D Castlevania games of the decade, which take their inspiration from the "Metroidvania" style of Castlevania: Symphony of the Night, Castlevania: The Adventure ReBirth plays like a traditional Castlevania game. Players guide Christopher through six stages, increasing their score by defeating enemies and collecting money (dropped by defeated enemies and scenery scattered throughout each stage).There are four options for controlling Christopher: Wii Remote, Wii Remote with Nunchuck accessory, Wii Classic Controller, and Gamecube Controller. Regardless, players use the control stick (or D-pad) to move Christopher left and right (as well as making him crouch and making him move up/down stairs), a jump button, and an attack button. As a bonus option, players who use the Wii Remote with Nunchuck accessory can also swing using the Wii Remote to attack, giving the impression that players are using the Vampire Killer whip.SoundtrackWith the exception of the mini-boss theme, all of the soundtrack in Castlevania: The Adventure ReBirth is re-arranged from older Castlevania games. Each track is rendered in a synthesized fashion similar to older Konami arcade games.Title Screen: Start BGM (from  Castlevania: The Adventure)Demo: Map (from  Castlevania: Dracula X)Stage 1: Reincarnated Soul (from  Castlevania: Bloodlines)Stage 2: A Lullaby Sent to the Devils (from  Haunted Castle)Stage 3: New Messiah (from  Castlevania II: Belmont's Revenge)Stage 4: Load BGM (from  Castlevania Chronicles)Stage 5: Aquarius (from  Castlevania III: Dracula's Curse)Stage 6: Vampire Killer (from  Castlevania)Mini-Boss: GauntletBoss: The Final Battle (from Haunted Castle)Final Boss: Riddle (from Castlevania III: Dracula's Curse)Stage Clear: Stage Clear (from Castlevania)Game Clear: Stages Clear (from  Super Castlevania IV)Ending: The End of the Day (from Castlevania II: Belmont's Revenge)Player Death: Player Out (from Castlevania: Dracula X)Game Over: Game Over (from Castlevania: Dracula X)All of those tracks appeared in the original soundtrack, which also included the soundtrack to Contra ReBirth and two unused tracks:Battle of the Holy (from Castlevania: The Adventure)Lost Painting (from  Castlevania: Symphony of the Night)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="29413">Mega Man 10</game><game id="29979">Blaster Master: Overdrive</game><game id="26376">Contra ReBirth</game><game id="23658">Gradius ReBirth</game><game id="40803">Street Fighter X Mega Man</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1733778-castlevaniaadventurerebirth.jpg</image></root>