<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29408</id><name>Chou Jikuu Yousai Macross: Scrambled Valkyrie</name><description>OverviewKnown also as Super Dimension Fortress Macross: Scrambled Valkyrie, this is the second game in the Macross series. It is based off of the film The Super Dimension Fortress Macross: Do You Remember Love? Scrambled Valkyrie was developed by Winky Soft and published by Zamuse.GameplayThe player can freely switch between the three forms.In terms of gameplay, Super Dimension Fortress Macross: Scrambled Valkyrie is a traditional side-scrolling shooter. The player is able to choose between three different characters: HIkaru, Max, and Millia, Each of these three character have three different forms they are able to use: Fighter, Gerwalk, and Battroid. Each of these three forms has three levels of firing capability, as each form powers up independently.Upon getting hit by enemy fire, the player loses health and one level of the currently equipped weapon. Physically hitting an enemy or an environmental obstacle solely causes health loss. Weapon power can be restored by picking up "P" power-ups (for the weapon level), while "S" power-ups boost the score. There are also items for 1-UPs and health. Additional power-ups picked up past level three will only add to the points total.Fetuses are clearly the ultimate evil overlords.Along with three power-up levels for each of the three modes on each of the three pilots' three Valkyries, Scrambled Valkyrie features an enemy-capture mechanic. If the player stops shooting, their fighter will begin to glow. Approaching many of the game's enemies while glowing will cause that enemy to fight for the player (presumably because of culture). If you attempt to capture a non-capturable enemy, you will lose any enemy you have under your control at that time. Only one enemy may be captured at a time.TriviaSuper Dimension Fortress Macross: Scrambled Valkyrie is a prime example of the Fetus as a Final Boss concept.The game features many pieces of music from the anime, including a brief song by Lynn Minmay as the player flies past one of her concerts in the back half of the game.If the difficulty is set to "Easy," it is impossible to die by being shot by any enemy or colliding with smaller enemies. Running into walls or large bosses is still instant death.</description><genres><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7617">Gradius III</game><game id="16642">U.N. Squadron</game><game id="3458">R-Type III: The Third Lightning</game><game id="20364">Zero Wing</game><game id="6619">Earth Defense Force</game><game id="8261">Rendering Ranger: R2</game><game id="34393">Eliminate Down</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/7465/1738122-575468_16528_front.jpg</image></root>