<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29474</id><name>Sam &amp; Max: The Devil's Playhouse</name><description>Overview The Devil's Playhouse is an episodic series which consists of five episodes. They are:Episode 1:  The Penal ZoneEpisode 2:  The Tomb of Sammun-MakEpisode 3:  They Stole Max's BrainEpisode 4:  Beyond the Alley of the DollsEpisode 5:  The City That Dares Not SleepEach episode was released monthly by Telltale starting with          The Penal Zone in April 2010 and ending with         The City That Dares Not Sleep in August 2010.Collector's DVDOn August 31st, 2010, Telltale detailed the bonus content available on the Collector's DVD. It includes:PC and Mac versions of all five gamesPackage art by       Steve PurcellTrailersScreen shotsWallpapersConcept artOuttakesA highlight reel with developer commentaryFuture Vision TV Commercials     Skun-kap'e's Secret OriginGamepro's "History of Sam  Max" video series The Collector's DVD is available for free (plus shipping costs) to anyone who purchases the full season from Telltale's website.System RequirementsPC System Requirements OS: Windows XP, Windows Vista, or Windows 7Processor: 2.0 GHzMemory: 1 GBGraphics: 128MB DirectX 8.1-compliant video cardDirectX: Version 9.0c or betterSound: DirectX 8.1 sound deviceMac System RequirementsOS: Mac OSX 10.5 or laterProcessor: Intel Core 2 DuoMemory: 256MBGraphics: Not recommended for Macs with integrated graphics</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26779">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 4: The Trial and Execution of Guybrush Threepwood</game><game id="26778">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 3: Lair of the Leviathan</game><game id="26780">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 5: Rise of the Pirate God</game><game id="26777">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 2: The Siege of Spinner Cay</game><game id="32796">Tales of Monkey Island</game><game id="32592">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 1: It's About Time</game><game id="29176">Big Brain Wolf</game><game id="33414">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 2: Get Tannen!</game><game id="38889">Back to the Future: The Game</game><game id="26608">Case Closed: The Mirapolis Investigation</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2413492-600full_sam___max__the_devil_s_playhouse_cover.jpg</image></root>