<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29483</id><name>Dead or Alive: Paradise</name><description>HistoryIn December 2009's Famitsu magazine, Tecmo announced a new Dead or Alive title coming to the PSP titled Dead or Alive: Paradise. Not many details were given, except that it would focus more on the relationship and minigame aspect of 2006's Dead or Alive: Xtreme 2. Tecmo also announced that a new Dead or Alive character would be making her debut in Paradise. This also marks the first release of a Dead or Alive game on a PSP or any other portable.It's not surprising that Dead or Alive: Paradise was criticized for being "creepy" and "cheesy" by the video game industry for its subject matter, including "stalking" the DOA women and taking pictures of them for a photo album.In an interview with Eurogamer, Tecmo Koei representative Yoshinori Ueda said otherwise. He stated that the game is not softcore pornography, but rather a game that shows that "women are beautiful characters.""From our perspective, we're trying to make beautiful women, that has been the focus. We want our characters to be beautiful. The DOA characters are strong and that they look the way they do is based on trying to bring out the beauty of women..We're certainly not trying to degrade women, They have beautiful bodies. We're trying to show off the beauty of their bodies but we're not trying to be degrading about it - we're trying to show that they are beautiful characters."GameplayThe gameplay in Dead or Alive: Paradise is similar to 2006's Dead or Alive: Xtreme 2. You choose a Dead or Alive female character to play as, and do various activities and making friends with the other girls for more Zack Dollars. With your Zack Dollars, you can buy new swimsuits and other unlockables.Paradise also features a photo album. The game encourages you to go around and take pictures of the other girls. These photos are assembled into an album, where you can view them and create your own album. DOA Paradise seems to be a little more focused on this feature than the gambling or minigames.Limited EditionsThe Kasumi figure that comes included with the limited edition.There are two limited editions of Dead or Alive: Paradise.The Dead or Alive: Paradise "Paradise's Secret Box" edition contains:A Dead or Alive "Secret Photo Collection"Live Voice  Soundtrack CDDead or Alive: ParadiseAlternate bikini for Kasumi figure.All contents are in a special Kasumi box, and the whole bundle retails for 7,329 Yen (roughly 81 US dollars).The Kasumi Figure edition of the Secret Box contains a Kasumi figure. This bundle retails for 15,729 Yen (175 dollars). The figure also includes a changeable bikini.CharactersDead or Alive's all-female cast makes a return.AyaneAyane: Age: 16Nationality: JapaneseHobby: Beauty TreatmentsFavorite Food: Marrons GlacesFavorite Color: Dark PurpleChristieChristie: Age: 24Nationality: BritishHobby: DrivingFavorite Food: Tomato JuiceFavorite Color: BlackHelenaHelena: Age: 21Nationality: FrenchHobby: Walking her dogFavorite Food: Blanc MangerFavorite Color: Pearl WhiteHitomiHitomi: Age: 18Nationality: GermanHobby: CookingFavorite Food: SachertorteFavorite Color: Sky BlueKasumi: Age: 17Nationality: JapaneseHobby: Fortune TellingFavorite Food: Strawberry MillefeuilleFavorite Color: Milky PinkKokoroKokoro: Age: 17Nationality: JapaneseHobby: PianoFavorite Food: Japanese Fruit CocktailFavorite Color: OrangeLei FangLei Fang: Age: 19Nationality: ChineseHobby: Aroma TherapyFavorite Food: Almond TofuFavorite Color: Lemon YellowLisaLisa: Age: 21Nationality: AmericanHobby: SurfingFavorite Food: Cherry PieFavorite Color: Crimson RedTinaTina Armstrong: Age: 22Nationality: AmericanHobbies: Sports Games, Cycling, Video GamesFavorite Food: SeafoodFavorite Color: Sapphire BlueRioDead or Alive: Paradise also features a guest character. "Rio" from Tecmo's "Super Blackjack" series makes an appearance in this game.Dead or Alive: Paradise released in Japan on April 2, 2010, two days after the North American release date of March 30, 2010.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="29245">Queen's Blade: Spiral Chaos</game><game id="24115">Ikki Tousen: Eloquent Fist</game><game id="29281">Akatsuki no Amaneka to Aoi Kyojin: Pashiate Bunmei Kenkyuukai Koubouki</game><game id="31524">Rio Blackjack</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1791091-box_doap.png</image></root>