<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29539</id><name>Naughty Bear</name><description>StoryNaughty Bear has long been the black sheep and scapegoat for the Teddies of the Island of Perfection, but Naughty had always taken it well - more or less. However, when the teddies neglect to invite the shabby stuffed psychotic to the big birthday party, Naughty Bear finally loses it. The game follows Naughty Bear on his mission to seek retribution through the relentless and systematic execution of every other bear on the Island of Perfection. What a naughty,A Very Naughty Bearnaughty bear.The game starts off with Naughty getting ready for Daddle's party. However, the game's narrator tells Naughty that he hasn't been invited despite the fact that he's already bought a present. This sends Naughty into an infuriating rage which makes him throw the present away and grab his knife. He plows through all of Daddle's friends whom he kills in horrible ways and ultimately, makes Daddles pay.In the second episode it's discovered that a politician by the name of Chubby promises to kill Naughty if he's elected. The other bears of Perfection don't seem to have a problem with that, however Naughty does. Naughty kills most of Chubby's voters before killing Chubby himself.In the third episode, Naughty is woken up early in the morning by a weird bird at his window. The bird seems to have a camera on its head. Naughty investigates and realizes that the Paradise Island military are using the birds to spy on him to make sure he's not doing anything naughty. Not standing this, Naughty bear kills all the birds and teaches the military a good lesson about privacy.In the fourth episode, Naughty Bear is once again not invited to something, this time to Nibbles's cooking lessons. As the other bears arrive and Nibbles starts catering to them, he accidentally opens the wrong cooking book, a book that when opened releases Zombears. This annoys Naughty who decides that Nibbles must be punished and among the chaos of zombies and soldiers he dishes out sweet punishment to Nibbles.In the fifth episode, Trembles has come back to the island as a successful oil baron. He wishes to look for oil on the island and the first place he'll be looking is where Naughty's house is. Naughty finds out that Trembles wants to wreck his house and kill him with his elite SWAT unit B.E.A.R.S. Naughty decides to kill Trembles and put a stop to his search for black gold.In the sixth episode, Fluffy is building a giant robot as well as a robot army. Said army is going to take over the world. To make matters worst, he's using a special type of technology that will rip the universe apart! Naughty isn't going to sit around and let this happen. He quells the robot revolution and brings a stop to Fluffy's dreams of world domination.The entire game is narrated by a British sounding narrator. He speaks in very simple language, using vocabulary that you would usually find in children books, to describe Naughty Bear's violent actions. After an execution, he usually makes up funny puns like massive "defuffication" and always sounds super pumped, like a game show host.GameplayGameplay requires the player to lead the single minded and sociopathic Naughty Bear on his personal quest to bring about hilariously brutal revenge against his elitist teddy neighbors. What follows can only be described as the cheeriest mass murder since the Telephone music video.Naughty Bear starts each level at his shack where he must score a certain number of Naughty points to advance to the main level. Naughty points are awarded for anything and everything you do. The game gives you a multiplier bar. Said multiplier bar multiplies your points and lets you do mad combos (you can multiply your score all the way to 100) . The multiplier rises when you do feats of Naughtiness and the game lets you know when it is rising or falling. The only way to score a high score is to constantly keep the multiplier high. When you start a level, the game also gives you a precise set of objectives, like kill all the bears in the area, don't let any of them escape or make a specific bear eat it. The game also gives you random collectibles to search out (these are optional) such as presents or cursed pages. By finding and destroying these, you keep your multiplier high. You also can pick up a freeze bonus, which freezes your multiplier, stopping from going down for a set period of time but also letting boost it. Naughty Bear isn't invincible and has a life bar situated on the top left corner of the screen right under your score. Once you lose all of it or fail an objective, its game over and all the surviving bears laugh at you. You can replenish your health by finding cake. In the load screens the developers hint at the fact that you can play better when eating cake.Its' Giggles, Cuddles and Fluffy... now you KILL THEM!!Naughty Bear has different tools at his disposal to terrorize and kill the bears of Paradise Island. Naughty can find loads of weapons scattered all around the levels such as clubs, knives and sticks. He can also shoot a gun. He has the choice between a magnum revolver or a machine gun. When aiming, the camera takes an over the shoulder view for increased precision. Naughty can also place traps (bear traps and land mines). The bear traps work as expected, trapping a bear as where, when a bear steps on a land mine, he also traps himself since if he takes his foot off it it blows up. But Naughty's most powerful weapon is his growl. He scares innocent teddies with his mighty yell that is a key part of the gameplay. It serves to scare the other bears, lure them into a trap or make them run away. But this is only the beginning of the naughtiness.There are over 250 crimes and misdemeanors for Naughty Bear to commit on his rampage across the Island of Perfection. The naughtiness ranges from the likes of graffiti to gangland executions and includes altogether more sinister acts, such as domestic sabotage and using the desperate cries of trapped teddies to lure out the more altruistic bears, creating plenty of easy targets. The bears have a knack for fixing things and by sabotaging instead of destroying, they'll come and try to fix what you've done, leaving them vulnerable. You can also wound the bears at which point they're unable to walk correctly. This usually happens after a trap. This means that Naughty can execute an ultimate kill. Ultimate Kills just require you to go up to the bear, squeeze the right trigger at which point Naughty will conduct a brutal execution. The execution is different according to the situation and the weapon Naughty is holding. For example, if Naughty executes an Ultimate Kill on a bear who's trying to fix a phone, Naughty will take the phone, bash the bear in the face with it then stick it down its throat. You can also to Ultimate Scares. These work kind of like the Ultimate Kills except that the bear must first become insane. You can do this on multiple occasions and once he is insane, he'll walk around the level aimlessly with bubbles floating over his head, telling you that it's time to push them over the edge. One final kill will make them commit suicide, taking whichever weapon they have in their hand and killing themselves with it.However, the NPC's don't let themselves get driven off their rocker so easily. They're organized. Usually each group has a leader (the one with the hat). They investigate on suspicious behaviors such as the power cutting out. The barricade themselves in, try to make a run for it by car or by boat (both of which can be destroyed by Naughty) and can call in the cops, ninjas and the military. They wield guns and other weapons which they find on the ground, in the fridge and in picnic baskets. They can fix things and run after you. Observing the day to day business of the NPC's and setting suitable traps early on in the level will cause the greatest carnage in the least possible time and buff the score multiplier. Once this happens and all hell breaks loose amongst the local teddies the multiplier will start soaring and it will then be left to Naughty Bear to get to work. You have to act quickly to catch all the bears trying to run away or call in "the fuzz," but there are thankfully no shortage of bludgeoning, pyrotechnic or environmental methods of murder littered around each stage. By hurting or making a bear go insane, the other bears see this and it alarms them, making you get even more points.The game's HUD tells Naughty Bear where to go. The green arrow pointing from Naughty's feet indicate where his main objective is. Usually this arrow appears after having accomplished all the level's objectives, telling you where the exit is. The red arrow appears when one of the other teddies is doing something (escaping, calling for help, etc). The arrow appears so you can know where they are and stop them. When an NPC is doing something that deserves your attention, a little pop up window showing you the bear and if it has something to do with calling for help or escaping, a timer appears.Naughty PointsNo matter how you torture the other bears you will earn naughty points and you will increase your multiplier and these point are a testament to how naughty you have been (or rather how varied and skill full  creative you are). The best thing I found about naughty point is that the top players best score is away on screen which give you incentive to keep a high multiplier and to try out new things in order try new method of naughtiness in order to beat that players score.CostumesNaughty likes to dress up. By winning cups such as bronze, silver, gold and platinum cups or completing levels you can unlock costumes. These costumes have different effects on Naughty. Some just boost his statistics like strength or speed. Others make him disguise himself as an ally, giving him more time to sabotage things. He can also disguise himself as certain characters, like cop Gordon. Some costumes come with weapons.List of CostumesNaughty the Party AnimalMayor NaughtyPeacekeeper NaughtyCordon Bleu NaughtyProspector NaughtyDoctor NaughtyConspiracy NaughtyCop NaughtyAdept NaughtyGeneral NaughtyZumbo-Jumbo NaughtyTactical NaughtyTech-NaughtyAstro-NaughtySheriff NaughtyMaster NaughtyCaptain NaughtyZombear NaughtyN.O.T.Y.R0B0-N4UGH7YXnotyCop GordonMaster MiyagiColonel KetchupZombear OodooE.L.I.T.E. MahoneyR0B0-PR1M3Emperor XoonNaughticornChallengesEach chapter has a set number of challenges, making you replay the same level but with new conditions.FriendlyIn this challenge, you mustn't hit or use any weapons on the bears. This means you have to use scare tactics to drive them insane so they commit suicide and use traps at your advantage. The level ends once all the bears are dead.InsanityYou must drive the bears insane. No bears must escape and you may only kill them once insane. This means you have to once again resort to scare tactics, sneaking up behind bears to scare them and sabotaging their things.InvisibilityYou must run around the map without being seen more than five times. This type of challenge demands stealth and quick kills.KillerHere the objective is simple: Kill all the bears anyway you want without letting a single one escape.Speed RunYou must go through a level before time runs out. To do this you must be quick and deadly as the timer is for the entire level, not just the individual areas.UntouchableYou mustn't get hit once while taking out the bears or else its game over.Different types of BearsThe game sports a variety of bears that each have their own characteristics:Fluffy, Stardust, Twinkles, and Sunbeam.These are the regular bears. They chase after you with weapons such as clubs and ham. You can scare them and make them go insane pretty easily and they're easy to hide from since they can't go into the forest. When they call for help, they call for the cops.Bears with Hats:These bears usually where a party hat or a top hat. This distinguishes them from other bears. Usually these bears are the bears that you must eliminate to complete the level. They usually sport guns and give out orders.The Fuzz.The Fuzz:The cops only appear when called upon by other bears. The cops carry guns and are lead by cop Gordon. Like the other bears, they can't go into the woods and they can call for reinforcements.Army Bears:They're the most powerful bears, sporting automatic weapons and greater health. They can't go through the woods but can call in more army bears, forcing Naughty to stay on his toes. When the Zombears attack, they're the ones who respond.Zombears.Ninja Bears:These bears are quick and stealthy. They run after you with their blades even through the woods. They often hide in closets and can call more ninjas as reinforcements.Zombears:Zombears (or The UN-Ted) are bears who've come back from the dead thanks to an ancient curse found in a cook book. They attack other bears with their bone and can chase Naughty through the forest. They don't call for reinforcements instead new Zombies spawn from the ground.MultiplayerNaughty Bear features an online multiplayer that supports up to 4 players. The multiplayer is known so far to offer mode such as The Golden Cup Cake (King of the Hill), The Golden Ooze (Capture the Flag) and Assault the unibear statue (Search and Destroy).Multiplayer lets you wear all the costumes that you've unlocked in single player. You can also unlock badges. Badges give Naughty special abilities in multiplayer.List of BadgesThe Bulky Bear Badge - 75 health.The Brawny Beacer Badge - 25% to melee damage.The Skilled Squirrel Badge - 25% to range damage.The Miasmatic Muskrat Badge - 25% to duration of traps' effects on enemies.The Brainy Bunny Badge - 25% to repair and sabotage speed.The Flourishing Ferret Badge - 25% to life regeneration from cakes.The Cordial Cardinal Badge - 25% to healing capabilities speed.The Bountiful Buck Badge - 25% to power-ups duration.The Misleading Mongoose Badge - 15% to hiding capabilities.The Bold Badger Badge - 15% to blocking capabilities.The Legendary Badge of Pronounced Obviousness - 25% Bonus Points but hiding capabilities disabled.The Legendary Badge of the Accommodating Weaknessiveness - 50% Naughty Points but weapons damage is halved.The Legendary Badge of Cheese and Moose Sausage - 50% Bonus Points but cakes make you lose health and Power ups are disabled.The Legendary Badge of Discombobulated Awesomeness - 75% Bonus Points but permanent spore effect.ReceptionNaughty Bear has received mediocre or poor reviews. The Metacritic average for the game is a 42 for the PS3 and a 44 for the XBox 360, making it one of the top 20 worst reviewed games for the PS3 and one of the top 50 worst games for the XBox 360. The game has received criticism for a number of reasons, mostly it's repetitive nature and poor combat mechanics.DLCPre-OrderJason Voorhees Pre-Order Bonus.By Pre-ordering the game at GameStop also at Game in the UK, you can get the Slasher DLC code, letting you download two exclusive costumes. One costume is a Jason Voorhees one and another is a costume of Freddy Krueger. These codes can be bought off E-Bay for 99 cents. These costumes at present are 2 of the games more powerful and best costumes.Further DLCThe game's box and its loading screens indicate that more free DLC is on the way in the form of levels and costumes. A recent trailer for the first piece of DLC is a costume that turn naughty bear in to a superhero. There will also be another piece of DLC which sees Naughty Bear take on a bunch of pirates (this DLC will not be free but instead will cost 400 MSP).</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6108">Manhunt</game><game id="18777">The Club</game><game id="22008">Raze's Hell</game><game id="22715">Fur Fighters: Viggo's Revenge</game><game id="21258">Manhunt 2</game><game id="31391">Bloody Good Time</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/6087/1368736-1256634_xb360_boxart.jpg</image></root>