<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29690</id><name>Tatsunoko vs. Capcom:  Cross Generation of Heroes</name><description>OverviewTatsunoko vs. Capcom: Cross Generation of Heroes is a Japan-exclusive fighting game released both in arcades and on the Wii in December of 2008.  The game is a part of Capcom's                                             Versus series of crossover fighting games and pits a variety of Capcom characters against famous characters from a number of anime series produced by the animation studio Tatsunoko.  Like other Versus games, battles are tag team affairs, allowing the player to switch between two fighters with separate health gauges on the fly or allow them to team up for powerful combination attacks.  Due to the scattered legal rights to the Tatsunoko characters in territories outside of Japan, it was assumed by many that the game would never be able to see an official release in western markets.  However, Capcom managed to accomplish this feat, securing the rights to the majority of the Tatsunoko characters in the game's roster; the lone exception being                                            Hakushon Daimao.  As a result, Capcom went back and revamped the game, adding features and adjusting character balance.  New characters were also added to both the Capcom and Tatsunoko character rosters.  This revised version of the game is titled                                           Tatsunoko vs. Capcom:  Ultimate All Stars and was released in North America on January 26, 2010, with releases in Japan and Europe following shortly after.   Mini gamesTatsunoko VS Capcom comes with a set of mini games, one different game for every character of the game making the number of mini games 22 exclusive to the Wii version of the game. Most of the mini games use the wii remote its motion sensor as input devise and the game will not allow you to play them with a classic controller or with the nunchuk. All of the mini games can be played with 4 players, most of them simultaneously. A small number of the mini games will be unlocked from the start but most of them will have to be bought from the in game shop. By playing the different minigames you unlock new items to buy in the shops and gain actual Zennies to spend there. The different mini games are: Tatsunoko Minigames: Ken the Eagle (initially unlocked) Ken's mini game is a shooting gallery, you shoot using the A button and reload by pointing the Wii remote's IR pointer outside of the screen and shoot. On screen will be 2 rows of pods out of these pods will pop enemies and some of the playable characters whenever you hit one of the enemies you get 500 points but when you hit one of the playable characters you will get minus 500 points. After a while a small flying creature from the Science Ninja Team Gatchaman series will start to fly around on screen shooting him will grand you 2000 points. Once shot a new area behind the rear row will open, in there will be the antagonist of the series running around, when ever shot you gain 1000 points. The player with the most points at the end of the round wins.  Casshan (initially unlocked)Casshan's mini game is a dog race in which by pressing the A button as fast as possible your dog will run faster up to 200 KM/H (Which converts to FAST in miles) the first player whose dog reaches the finish wins. Tekkaman (initially unlocked)Tekkaman is standing on his flying pod/mecha and you will have to make it go as fast as possible on a runway by shaking the Wii remote as fast as possible for a short period than when his pod gets at a certain point the runway its color will change and that is the cue to press the B button. If done correctly Tekkaman will throw his lance in a boomerang like fashion destroying enemies with it, the faster the pod went when he launched his lance the more enemies will die. The winner is the one who will have killed the most enemies.    Hurricane Polimar (500 Zennies)Polimar’s mini game is a race. Swing the wii remote in a circle to make Polimar’s drill move forward, you have 10 seconds to try and get further than the other drills.    Yatterman 1 (500 Zennies)This minigame has you take control of Yatter-Wan. Yatter-Wan will race through a stadium and it is your job to stop it by pressing A before the finish line without going over. The closer you get the better your score.   Doronjo (500 Zennies)Doronjo's minigame is like the end credit sequence. You take control of Doronjo and her henchmen on a bike and with three tries you have to try and collect as many coins as possible. There are numerous pits to jump over and bombs dropping from the sky to avoid.  Ippatsuman (500 Zennies)Ippatsuman’s minigame consists of him throwing a baseball at a numbered board. Two meters will appear that determine where the baseball will be thrown. Pressing A to decide the length and swinging the wii remote to decide which height. You then have 10 baseballs to try and get as high a score as possible.  Jun the Swan (500 Zennies)Jun the Swan's minigame is her free falling through the air. Using the dpad on the wii remote you have to direct Jun over the score bubbles to get points. You have 30 seconds to try and accumulate as many points as possible.   Hakushon Daimaou (500 Zennies)Hakushon Daimaou's minigame is a math game. Simple math sums will be shown on screen and using the wii remote you select the answer from a list of numbers. You have 30 seconds to try answer as many questions as you can. Karas (500 Zennies)This mini game is somewhat comparable to Capcom's Soki mini game, during 15 seconds ghostly enemies will advance towards Karas the player will have to slash them all by doing a slashing motion with the Wii remote, the player who managed to slash the most enemies wins the round.  Gold Lightan (500 Zennies) Gold Lightan's minigame consists of you cleaning separate parts of him. You have 2 seconds to swing the wii remote and clean his arm, his leg, his chest and his head, the cleaner each section the higher points you will receive.Capcom Minigames: Ryu (initially unlocked)Ryu's mini game consist of throwing fireballs at objects, the fireballs are thrown by doing a stabbing motion with the wii remote. On the left hand side of the screen is a meter that fluctuates at variable speeds, the goal is the launch the fireball when the meter is at its top, the higher the meter the stronger the fire ball. Once an object destroyed another object will take its place. The object Ryu has to destroy vary from tree logs to submarines. The player who destroyed the most objects with the most powerful fire ball wins. Chun-li (initially unlocked)In Chun-Li's mini game you mash the A button as fast as possible to make Chun-Li do her lighting kick on a rock to sculpt a stone ryu out of it, the player who sculpted the most statues wins. Batsu Ichimonji (initially unlocked)Batsu's mini game is a memory game that in order to play you hold the Wii remote like a classic NES controller. A code will appear on screen (made out of the four direction of the D-pad and the 1 and 2 button of the Wii remote) and it is up to you to copy it as fast as possible before the time runs out, did you happen to put in the wrong code or did not manage to input the code in time you lose one of your tree lives. The faster you input the code the more point you earn. As the game progresses the codes get longer reaching up to 6 digits. The player with the most points wins. Morrigan Aensland (500 Zennies)Morrigan will have (?) grabbed around the waist and its your goal to fly Morrigan as high up possible and to then slam (?) on a taget on the ground. You fly Morrigan by pressing "A" when a circle that comes from the left hits a bar on the right somewhat like a rhythm game. After a certain time Morrigan will dive towards the ground preparing to slam (?) on the target in order to hit the target you will have to time a button press. The score will be determined by the height Morrigan rose and if the target was hit. The player with the highest score wins the game.  Alex (500 Zennies)Alex's mini game is basically the hammer throw. Alex will have to pick up a car by pressing B, once the car is picked up you swing the wii remote to build momentum and release by pressing B to throw the car across the screen. Soki (500 Zennies) Objects will be thrown at Soki and it is up to you to swing the Wii remote when the object is just about to hit him to slash your sword at it, the player who manages to destroy the most objects wins.   Viewtiful Joe (500 Zennies)Viewtiful Joe's minigame consists of you trying to take a picture of him. He will run by quickly and you have three attempts to snap a picture when he enters the reticle on screen, the better the picture the higher the score you will receive.  Mega Man Volnut(500 Zennies)Mega Man Volnut's minigame is a memory game. Little servbots will run in and out of your coloured box and at the end of each of the three rounds you must memorise how many servbots are in your coloured box. Roll (500 Zennies)Roll's minigame is bacially her running forward and you trying to avoid different obstacles such as boxes and moving servbots using the left and right buttons on the wii remote dpad, getting as far as possible will get you points as will cleaning up dirty spots on the floor. You have three tries to accumulate as many points as possible.Saki Kanebou (500 Zennies)Saki Kanebou's minigame is a shooter. Using the wii remote to direct the crosshair and the A button to fire you need to shoot down as many rocks that fly towards you as possible, when your gun runs out of power you shake the wii remote to regain it. You have 60 seconds to get as many points as possible, sometimes gaint robots will fly towards you shooting them down will get you minus points. A gaint pig(?) will also fly towards you, shooting this down will grant you alot of points  Kalin no Soki (500 Zennies)Soki's mini game is somewhat comparable to the Karas mini game, fireball type enemies will advance towards Soki and it's up to the player to slash them all by doing a slashing motion with the Wii remote, you have three tries to score as many points as possible. PTX-40A Ivan (500 Zennies)PTX's minigame is set in the Lost Planet universe, it is a scrolling shooter where players face off against the Akrid. You control PTX from an overhead view using the dpad to move and 1 and 2 buttons to fire, it has been expanded upon on the recently released     Tatsunoko vs Capcom: Ultimate All Stars.Playable CharactersTatsunoko                                                     Ken the Eagle  (Science Ninja Team Gatchaman)                                                                                                      Jun the Swan (Science Ninja Team Gatchaman)          Yatterman 1 assisted by                                Yatter-Wan in his ultra attacks(Yatterman)                                                                                                     Doronjo accompanied by both                                                 Boyacky and                                                Tonzura (Yatterman)                                                                                                      Casshan (Neo-Human Casshan)                                                                                                      Tekkaman (Tekkaman: The Space Knight)                                                                                                      Gold Lightan (Golden Warrior Gold Lightan)                                                                                                    Ippatsuman (Gyakuten! Ippatsuman) - Unlockable via in-game shop after beating arcade mode with three Tatsunoko characters                                                                                                      Hurricane Polimar (Hurricane Polimar)                                                                                                      Karas (Karas)                                                                                                      Hakushon Daimao (Hakushon Daimao) Unlockable via in-game shop after beating arcade mode with one Tatsunoko character   Capcom                                                                                                     Ryu (                            Street Fighter)                                                                                                      Chun-Li (                           Street Fighter II: The World Warrior)                                                                                                      Alex (                          Street Fighter III: New Generation)                                                                                                       Mega Man Volnutt (                         Mega Man Legends)                                                                                                       Roll (                        Mega Man)                                                                    Batsu Ichimonji (                       Rival Schools: United By Fate)                                                                                                       Morrigan Aensland (                      Darkstalkers)                                                                                                      Kaijin no Soki (                     Onimusha: Dawn of Dreams)                                                                                                      PTX-40A Ivan (                    Lost Planet: Extreme Condition)                                                                                                      Viewtiful Joe (                   Viewtiful Joe) - Unlockable via in-game shop after beating arcade mode with three Capcom characters                                                                                                      Saki Kanebou (                  Quiz Nanairo Dreams) - Unlockable via in-game shop after beating arcade mode with one Capcom character                                                                                                    Yami (                 Okami) - Final Boss of the story mode who is unplayable Non-playable CameosA number of unplayable Capcom and Tatsunoko characters make cameo appearances in the game.  On the Capcom side, some of the appearances include                                     Arthur from the Ghosts n' Goblins series In Kaijin no Soki's ending,                                      Dr. Light in Roll's ending, and                                       Silvia in Viewtiful Joe's ending.  The Capcom character                                   Devilot plays a prominent role in Doronjo's ending.</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="28437">Super Street Fighter IV</game><game id="21519">The King of Fighters XII</game><game id="39253">Versus Hero: Kakutou Ou e no Michi</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2452917-box_tvccgoh.png</image></root>