<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29717</id><name>E.Y.E: Divine Cybermancy</name><description>OverviewYou play as a spy who has infiltrated the E.Y.E, a group of Warrior-Monks made up of two warring factions. These factions have been fighting constantly to see which one gains power over the whole organization. The E.Y.E serve the Secreta Secretorum, which is a company dedicated to overthrowing the Federation and is the company you work for. The Secreta Secretorum ordered you to infiltrate the E.Y.E and uncover a traitor to the cause as well as watching the internal actions of E.Y.E.The player, traveling through a solo campaign in which FPS and RPG mechanics combine, must fight the returning Metastreumonic Force, but also help the Federation take control again. This campaign will also be an occasion for the player to discover an obscure conspiracy and a large amount of rivalries and manipulations for power. During his journeys, the player will meet many other characters with whom he will create a friendship, will collaborate, or will fight against. With most of them, conversations are possible via a multiple choice dialogue interface.BackstoryThe developers of E.Y.E have spent a long time writing a rich back story for the world in which E.Y.E is set, creating a dark background of corporate takeover and war in history.PastThe history of the Earth remains a mystery because of the many wars and catastrophes it underwent. We only know that it's during this dark period (before 2116) that psychic abilities were studied and admitted by science, initially by the army (in the 1890's), then by civil science (1970). We also know that the consortium of Mega-corporations was created, at the same time as the first Martian colony.In 2116, the space colonization began alongside the discovery of inter-dimensional space. Then Mars proclaimed its independence and launched an offensive against the Earth with equipment unknown to the human race. This flash attack decimated 2/3 of the human race. The surviving countries formed an alliance - the Federation - in order to better counter Mars, but almost all their military equipment had been destroyed. The megacorporations, having their own war weaponry, proposed to help the Federation, hoping to extend their power and influence.During this war, the Federation used telepathic soldiers. These new troops were called the parapsychic Legion. Its role was mainly to inform, misinform, torture, spy, search for and find traitors. At the end of the war, the legion became the Federation's "inquisition", constantly gaining power and influence. It was renamed federal parapsychic army, and was separated from military command in order to keep its autonomy, but remains under Federal control.NowSecreta Secretorum, taking full account of the Federation's coercive measures, decides to attempt a coup d'état. E.Y.E troops stand at the ready, rallied to win by desperation to get out from under federal rule.It's in this chaos that the creatures of the metastreumomic will reappear, launching fast and devastating attacks over all of the Federation, including New Eden.The Federation hardened the laws prohibiting access to high-end war equipment such as the energy weapons. The whole market is in shortage. Secreta Secretorum launches its own research programs to counter it.E.Y.E is in its worst possible position. Officially, the structure no longer exists. Covertly, it takes actions through Secreta Secretorum to fight the metastreumonic Force, but the enemies of the group as well. E.Y.E is still divided into two groups, Culter Dei and Jian Shang Di which with time, become rivals and hostile towards each other. The equipment difficulties that both groups share are undoubtedly not foreign to these tensions.E.Y.E must also be partly financed by itself. It employs beginners wishing to integrate the structure and sends them on badly equipped missions to intercept important valuable cargoes. These warriors parade as galactic plunderers. E.Y.E, like many, knows a serious shortage in high-end military and cybernetic equipment.During this time the elite troops of E.Y.E achieve capital missions in the anti-Metastreumonic and anti-Federal fight, exterminating the threat even on the farthest colonies, recovering artefacts on inhospitable worlds, protecting civilians from besieged cities.The co-habitation is rather well tolerated by federal authorities who take into account E.Y.E successful missions against the Force. There are sometimes even Federal Forces and the members of the organization shoulder to shoulder, defending their hearths from the mysterious enemy raids.The invasion by the Metastreumonic force increases each day, and the war against the Federation ravages whole worlds every second.This is where the games plot begins.Game ModesSingle player: a multi-chapter campaign featuring a dynamic storyline.Cooperative campaign: 2 players play through the same campaign that is in the single player game.Cooperative missions: up to 32 players taking on standalone missions with a set of objectives to complete.Teamplay: players are split into two opposing teams, competing to complete mission objectives.Character AttributesEvery player character is described by a set of attributes, which include the following:Strength - affects maximum carrying weight and melee attack damage.Psi Force - affects strength of Psi powers and Psi resistance.Endurance - affects maximum health and stamina, as well as resistance to hemorrhaging.Hacking - affects hacking bonus and resistance.Accuracy - affects gun damage and chance to cause hemorrhaging.Mental Balance - affects resistance to mental shock.Medicine - affects efficacy of first aid.Agility - affects character movement speed and melee attack rate.On level up, a player earns three additional attribute points that can be spend in any of the above categories.Weapons and ItemsE.Y.E features futuristic and cyberpunk styled weaponry, including swords and guns. Some more details can be found below.Melee Weapons - Two varieties of swords (of Japanese-inspired design) and a hammer.Pistols - Three semi-automatic handguns with varying trade-offs between damage, rate of fire, accuracy, and option to dual-wield.SMGs - Two SMGs that are small and one handed, firing many shots at the cost of accuracy and damage.Shotguns - Three shotguns--one sawed off and two semi-automatic--all of which require engagement at close range to be effective, but are capable of obliterating enemies.Assault Rifles - There are 4 assault rifles each with varying characteristics but generally they hold a balance between range and strength.Special Weapons - Miniguns, sniper rifles, rocket launchers and more falls into this category. These weapons tend to all be very powerful and specialized.Grenades - After being throw, they will explode on impact with enemies or can be remotely detonated.Med Kit - A syringe that can be used to restore one's own or an ally's health. More health is restored the longer the syringe is allowed to 'charge up'.HackingHacking can used against many types of targets, including enemies, stationary defenses, ATMs, oneself, and more. There are four kinds of hacks that can be attempted on a target:Possess - gives limited control over the target. For example, an enemy can be made to clumsily move around and hesitantly open fire on nearby targets, such as other enemies.Hack - generally makes the target friendly to the hacker, such as by causing enemies to become allies and ATMs to dispense money.Destroy - causes the target to be destroyed, killing living targets, frying the circuitry of electronic ones, and bypassing obstacles like sealed doors.Steal - takes energy from the target and gives it to the hacker.After choosing the type of hack to attempt, the hacker engages in a symmetrical hacking minigame battle against the target. Both parties have a set of hacking stats (Attack, Defense, and HP), which are loosely derived from a combination of their respective levels and Hacking attributes. Whichever party depletes the others hacking HP first wins the hack and inflicts the effects of the type of hack on the loser. There are four actions available during a hacking battle:Attack - reduces the opponent's hacking HP by the amount of the user's Attack stat minus the defender's Defense stat.Mask - reduces the opponent's Attack stat.Scan - reduces the opponent's Defense stat.Shield - increases the user's Defense stat.Charge - raises the user's Attack stat at the cost of a lesser reduction in the user's Defense stat.PsiPsi powers cost energy to cast and produce a variety of offensive, defensive, and utility effects. Many aspects of the efficacy of Psi powers are determined by the user's Psi attribute.SoundtrackThe original score for E.Y.E.: Divine Cybermancy was composed by Olivier Zuccaro aka MaX and is available for free at the game's official website.System RequirementsMinimumRecommendedOperating System: Windows® 7 32/64-bit / Vista 32/64 / XPProcessor: Pentium 4 3.0GHz, Athlon 64 3000+ or betterRAM Memory: 1 GB for XP / 2GB for VistaHard Disk Space: At least 6 GB of free spaceVideo Card: : DirectX 9 compatible video card with 128 MB, Shader model 2.0. ATI X800, NVidia 6600 or betterDirectX®: 9.0cSound Card: DirectX 9.0c compatible sound cardAdditional: Internet Connection required for multiplayerOperating System: Windows® 7 32/64-bit / Vista 32/64 / XPProcessor: Intel core 2 duo 2.4GHz or AMD Athlon 64 X2 4600+RAM Memory: 1 GB for XP / 2GB for VistaHard Disk Space: At least 6 GB of free spaceVideo Card: : DirectX 9 compatible video card with Shader model 3.0. NVidia 7600, ATI X1600 or betterDirectX®: 9.0cSound Card: DirectX 9.0c compatible sound cardAdditional: Internet Connection required for multiplayer</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9989">Hellgate: London</game><game id="17533">Deus Ex</game><game id="8870">System Shock 2</game><game id="13948">System Shock</game><game id="9883">Deus Ex: Invisible War</game><game id="21358">Deus Ex: Human Revolution</game><game id="3183">Neocron</game><game id="593">Shadowrun</game><game id="18133">Omikron: The Nomad Soul</game><game id="30734">Syndicate</game><game id="15632">CyberMage: Darklight Awakening</game><game id="38456">Cyberpunk 2077</game><game id="36172">Remember Me</game><game id="42021">Deus Ex: Human Revolution Director's Cut</game><game id="42241">Far Cry 3: Blood Dragon</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2275989-box_eye.png</image></root>