<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29745</id><name>VVVVVV</name><description>OverviewVVVVVV (pronounced "the letter V six times", or just "V" in context) is an indie 2D puzzle platformer developed and published by distractionware for the PC and Mac on January 10, 2010.The game is deliberately retro, using simplistic graphics and chiptune audio (both reminiscent of old Commodore 64 games). Players control Captain Viridian, leader of the D.S.S. Souleye, who has the ability to invert his personal gravity while on the ground or ceiling (at the cost of not being able to jump). As the spaceship becomes affected by interference from another dimension, the crew escapes through a teleporter in the ship, only to be scattered randomly around the ship. It's up to Viridian to explore the dimension and rescue each of his crew members. (Doctor Violet, Doctor Victoria, Officer Vermilion, Professor Vitellary, and Chief Verdigris).The original game was developed in Adobe Flash and was distributed (via a Flash projector application) through the developer's website. A trial version of this version was made playable online (via Kongregate) and offline (via the developer's website). The game was later ported into native C++, released as version 2.0 (alongside a level editor) for the PC, Mac, and Linux on July 2011 (coinciding with Humble Indie Bundle 3). This version was later distributed to various digital distribution services (such as Steam, GamersGate, and Impulse). The game was later published for the Nintendo 3DS (via the eShop) by Nicalis on December 29, 2011. It was announced on August 30, 2013 that Nicalis will be publishing the PlayStation Vita version soon.GameplayAll six members of the D.S.S. Souleye ROCKIN' OUT!In VVVVVV, the player only has access to three distinct buttons: move left, move right, and flip (which inverses the player's personal gravity). There are no jump buttons (standard in most platformers) present. In order for the player to progress through the game, he must complete puzzles by moving around and using the flip button at the right time while avoiding obstacles (primarily spikes). The game's increasing difficulty, made slightly easier by numerous checkpoints scattered around the levels, remains a consistent challenge, but never to the level of the deliberately unfair games in the so-called "masocore" sub-genre.The game includes several main areas, four of which can be accessed in any order. These main areas are separated by vast space, which must be explored in a Metroidvania style. (Though teleporters scattered around the dimension can make progression faster) The cameras in most screens are static, only changing when the player enters a new area from any direction. This can increase difficulty, as the player leaps blindly into another screen, only to get hit by spikes. (As an example, a screen titled "What Lies Below?" is above a screen titled "Spikes Do!")Extras and UnlocksWhile the player progresses through the game, he encounters special "shiny trinkets" (20 in all), which can be collected to unlock music and game modes. Game modes can also be unlocked by completing the game or doing well in other game modes.Time Trials Mode (unlocked by progressing through the game and finding trinkets) - Players start at the beginning of the chosen level and must beat the level as fast as they can while collecting trinkets and trying not to die. The player is judged based on the following: they beat the level's par time, if they collect all the level's trinkets, and if they didn't die. Failing all objectives earns a B-rank, completing one objective earns an A-rank, completing two objectives in one run earns a S-rank, and completing all three objectives in one run earns a V-rank.Space Station 1 (rescue Violet and find 3 trinkets)The Laboratory (rescue Victoria and find 6 trinkets)The Tower (rescue Vermilion and find 9 trinkets)Space Station 2 (rescue Vitellary and find 12 trinkets)The Warp Zone (rescue Verdigris and find 15 trinkets)The Final Level (complete the game and find 18 trinkets)Intermission Mode (unlocked by completing both intermission levels) - Play through the two intermission levels (when the player finds the first and third crew member) whenever you like with whoever you like.No Death Mode (unlocked by achieving a S-rank or above in four of the six time trial levels) - Go through the entire game (with or without cutscenes) with no checkpoints. One death means game over.Flip Mode (unlocked by completing the game) - Enabling this option flips the dimension vertically, making it feel like a brand new dimension! Can be enabled alongside the other extra game modes.Ship Jukebox (unlocked by finding trinkets) - Find trinkets to unlock music to play at the ship.Secret LabAfter collecting all trinkets and then talking to Victoria, a humorous cutscene plays. The trinket room is blown apart and, in place of the trinkets, a huge teleporter stands in the middle of the room leading to a secret laboratory. (Which can be accessed through the mode selection menu). Inside is a trophy room (that shows off the player's achievements) and Super Gravitron, a special mini-game similar to the one found in the second intermission level (only endless and much more difficult).There are 19 trophies to collect, including beating the game with Flip Mode or No Death Mode enabled, clearing the game under a certain number of deaths, surviving a certain amount of time in Super Gravitron, and earning V-ranks on each time trial levels.SoundtrackPPPPPP Cover ArtReleased in January 2010, the VVVVVV soundtrack, entitled PPPPPP, was composed by Magnus "SoulEye" Pålsson. The quasi-retro soundtrack is a mix of fast and slower tempo melodic chiptunes to accompany the game's pacing. All but one track included in PPPPPP start with the letter "P".In mid-2011 "Pressure Cooker" and "Positive Force" were made available for download for the Rock Band Network.Track #Song TitleDuration1."Powerup"0:032."Presenting VVVVVV"2:403."Pause"0:084."Pushing Onwards"3:405."Path Complete"0:096."Passion for Exploring"2:527."Positive Force"2:498."Predestined Fate"2:189."Phear"0:1710."Potential for Anything"3:4311."Pressure Cooker"3:2712."Plenary (Game Complete Jingle)"0:2213."Pipe Dream"2:2214."Popular Potpourri"6:0915."Positive Force Reversed"2:4916."Waiting for VVVVVV"0:56Remixed soundtrackOn March 2011 SoulEye released a Remixed version of VVVVVV soundtrack called: PPPPPPowerup!PC System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Windows XPProcessor: 2 GHzMemory: 256MBGraphics: Direct X9.0c Compatible CardDirectX®: DirectX® 9.0cHard Drive: 42MBSound: Standard audioMac System RequirementsMinimum:OS: OS X version Leopard 10.5.8, Snow Leopard 10.6.3, or laterProcessor: Intel Mac 2 GHzMemory: 256MBHard Drive: 42MBSound: Standard audio</description><genres><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12296">Metal Storm</game><game id="13373">N</game><game id="20773">N+</game><game id="12900">M.C. Kids</game><game id="31633">Eversion</game><game id="25716">And Yet It Moves</game><game id="31213">Hero Core</game><game id="32612">Platformance: Castle Pain</game><game id="29952">Tower of Heaven</game><game id="33114">Doritos Crash Course</game><game id="34060">Antipole</game><game id="34068">The Deep Cave</game><game id="33566">Bunny Must Die</game><game id="34903">Soul Brother</game><game id="36324">A Flipping Good Time</game><game id="35743">Continuity 2</game><game id="35147">LaserCat</game><game id="36870">Stealth Bastard: Tactical Espionage Arsehole</game><game id="36940">A Walk In the Dark</game><game id="40930">KRUNCH</game><game id="38285">You Have to Win the Game</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14982/1244604-v.jpg</image></root>