<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29753</id><name>Armored Core V</name><description>OverviewMassive battle between both sides.FromSoftware's fifteenth game in the Armored Core series brings more mecha action, similar to other titles in the series. The game is set to be released first in Japan on January 26, 2012. Publisher Namco Bandai will be exporting the game to North America on March 20, 2012, and Europe three days later.Armored Core V is not a sequel to Armored Core 4 or Armored Core: For Answer, but a reboot to the series. The game setting is the same as the first game in the franchise which saw humanity fighting over world resources in a global catastrophic event. The most notable changes to the series are the Armored Core (AC), instead of being 10 meters as in previous titles, the scale has been reduced down to 5 meters. The game also features new weapons called "Overed Weapons" which are powerful weapons that can destroy an AC with one shot.GameplayArmored Core V has major changes to gameplay elements like smaller AC, three different types of weapons, and the addition of "Overed Weapons", but From Software keeps the same customizable ACs that all Armored Core fans love and enjoy.Overed WeaponsThe game introduces Overed Weapons, powerful weapons that can destroy any type of unit in a single blow. Taking up both hanger weapon slots on your AC. They are extremely difficult to use and they cannot be purged (detached). Once the Overed Weapon are activated, the AC generator disable its limits and pushes its output to dangerously high level.DevelopmentArmored Core 5Armored Core V was announced at Armored Core Championship Tournament event in 2010. At the end of the Japanese event, series producer Toshifumi Nabeshima took the stage and announced "Armored Core 5". After his speech, he revealed a teaser trailer showing some major changes to the game. Not much detail was given after the announcement, but From Software said that they will give more information about the game on January 14 from their official website. They stated that the concept of AC5 will be more mayhem-like action to this game.SoundtrackArmored Core V OST Front CoverThe Armored Core V Original Soundtrack was released on Janunary 25, 2012. The soundtrack for Armored Core V was composed by long running composer Kota Hoshino, and other composer like Yoshikazu Takayama, Tsukasa Saitoh, and Hideyuki Eto.Disc 1Track #Song TitleRunning Time1.V2:322.Begin In Your Coming2:533.V Computer Are Talking0:434.Lament Over The Howling Age4:275.Vulture3:066.Cadence Call1:487.Just Tuned0:548.Obsession3:389.Lithium3:3510.Acheron3:0411.In A Day4:2912.Why Don't You Come Down3:4113.OK, Stay  Go1:2714.Operation Room3:0515.Mercenaries1:3416.Force3:4217.Mars2:5418.Black Out3:14Disc 2Track #Song TitleRunning Time1.12 Steps3:362.Private Machine1:093.Meteor3:254.Strive3:285.On the Corner1:236.Frozen Area1:287.Conservation3:218.Made in Haven3:139.Birthday3:1510.Inversus4:0511.Mech Dinosaur3:4012.The Predator1:2013.Choral2:5914Stain4:3715.Halo2:5516.Protrude2:0817.The War Has Begun0:1318.Why Don't You Come Down (Instrumental)3:5219.Scientist3:14</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13931">MechWarrior</game><game id="11350">Zone of the Enders</game><game id="19719">Chromehounds</game><game id="22133">Armored Core: for Answer</game><game id="26008">Front Mission Evolved</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2129480-box_acv.png</image></root>