<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29790</id><name>Deadliest Warrior: The Game</name><description>OverviewDeadliest Warrior: The Game is a 3D weapon-based fighting game developed and published by Pipeworks for the Xbox 360 (via Xbox Live Arcade) on July 14, 2010 and for the PlayStation 3 (via PlayStation Network) on October 5, 2010. It's based on the Spike TV show Deadliest Warrior, where information on historical or modern weaponry are used to determine which of two warriors is the "deadliest".The game comes with eight characters and five stages (with the Fight Lab from the show being an unlockable stage). Each character comes with three weapons (short-ranged, mid-ranged, and long-ranged) and an armor set, each with alternate weapons/armor that must be unlocked via the arcade mode. A downloadable content pack, sold for $5 (400 msp), was released for the PlayStation Network on February 22, 2011 and the Xbox Live Marketplace on February 24, 2011. This pack includes three new characters, each with new weapons and armor, a new game mode (Skirmish Mode), new taunts for all characters, and the inclusion of a replay system. (A free version of this pack was available, so players without the pack can fight against the new characters online).The game's sequel, Deadliest Warrior: Legends, was released a year later, focusing on specific individuals (such as Vlad the Impaler and Alexander the Great) while including new game modes and mechanics. Having a save file of this game grants you extra weapons in Deadliest Warrior: Legends.The Xbox Live Arcade version contains two unlockable avatar awards:Samurai Outfit - Complete any fighter's campaign.Samurai Helmet - Complete all fighters' campaigns on the Deadliest difficulty.The Xbox Live Marketplace also sells costumes (helmets, armor, and both) and shield props for avatars related to other characters from the game, including the alternate versions of the Knight and the Samurai.GameplaySimilar to the Bushido Blade franchise, the length of fights in this game can be short (due to the great damage done by most attacks) or long (due to the freedom of movement around the stage).The control scheme uses three buttons for melee attack (high, mid, and low), one button for projectile attacks, one button for a "signature move" attack (such as a shield bash or a crouched horizontal slice), one button for switching melee weapons (between short-ranged and mid-ranged), and one button for taunting. The left control stick moves the fighter around the arena while the right control stick is used for a quick dodge maneuver. The left and right triggers are used to block.The core melee of this game revolves around stringing combos of two-to-four melee attacks. By combining blocking and the right melee button (mimicking the opponent's attack button) at the right time causes the player to parry. Each player has a "stamina bar" along with their health bar which depletes while guarding and attacking. Attempting to attack with a depleted stamina bar causes the attack to be slow and open for counter-attack. Blocking or parrying with a depleted stamina bar causes a guard break, which leaves you open for counter-attacks.Certain attacks, if landed on an enemy, can hinder their movement, reduce their attack and defense capabilities, or can instantly kill them. Fighters who lose an arm can still fight (similar to Time Killers and BloodStorm), however they slowly bleed out. Each fighter also has a unique finishing move animation, similar to fatalities from the Mortal Kombat franchise. These "finishing blows" are done by doing the character's special weapon attack (a two-button combination) when the opponent is at critical health.Game ModesThe game features a traditional arcade mode, where the player must defeat all eight warriors in succession. This is the only mode that allows you to unlock the alternate weapons and armor for each character. After the second battle, you play a minigame called "Target", where you must cut down pig carcasses from hooks. If you succeed, you unlock the alternate short-ranged weapon. The fifth battle is always a mirror match, and winning that earns you the alternate armor set. After the seventh battle, you play another minigame called "Slice", which is a short fight where each hit can result in the loss of a limb. If you succeed, you unlock the alternate mid-ranged weapon. Beating the game with that character unlocks its alternate long-ranged weapon.After beating the game with all characters, you unlock Challenge mode, which is a set of special modes. The "Target" and "Slice" modes are selectable, as well as both a survival mode and a unique mix of survival mode and "Slice". (called "Survival Slice") After beating ten opponents in survival mode, you unlock the Fight Lab stage.The game also features both local and online multiplayer modes, including an online asynchronous tournament mode (in similar vein to Street Fighter IV's championship mode). Both ranked and tournament matches attribute to a "battle rating" system for each gamertag similar to the Elo rating system. (most commonly used in chess)CheatsDeadliest Warrior: The Game also features cheat codes, which is done from the title screen, that change major gameplay mechanics in any offline game mode (and cannot be used online or to get achievements and unlockables). These include God Mode for either player (which gives them infinite life and resistance to dismemberments), Sudden Death Mode (in which both players start with critical health), Slice Mode (similar to the "Slice" and "Survival Slice" challenge modes, where each hit has a very high chance of dismemberment), and a unique Zombie Mode, where players have infinite life and can survive decapitations and most dismemberments (the only way to win is to amputate both legs). These cheats can be combined, creating unique experiences such as Zombie Slice Mode.Characters The eight characters included in the game are from season one of the TV show with the exception of the Roman Centurion (which is season two). The roster is split into three categories: Champion, Guerilla, and Berserker. Champions are well-armored and have a good balance of offense and defense. Guerillas and Berserkers are unarmored and rely either on rapid attacks (Berserkers) or evasive maneuvers (Guerillas).After online polls on Spike TV's official website to help determine which warriors might show up as Downloadable Content (which included the Aztec Jaguar, Zande, Rajput, Shaolin Monk, Persian Immortal, Gladiator, Maori, and the Celtic Warrior, as well as specific warriors like William Wallace, Attila the Hun, Sun Tzu, and Vlad the Impaler), they released three warriors for $5 (400 msp) on February 22, 2011 for the PlayStation Network version and on February 24, 2011 for the Xbox Live Arcade version: Shaolin Monk, Zande Warrior, and Rajput. Apache  Warrior Type: GuerillaShort-ranged Weapons: Stone War KnifeIron War KnifeMid-ranged Weapons:Iron Blade TomahawksHorse Jaw TomahawksLong-ranged Weapons: Bow (Iron Arrows)Bow (Poisoned Arrows)Special Weapon: War ClubArmor Types: Hand PaintWar PaintCenturionWarrior Type: ChampionShort-ranged Weapons: GladiusSpathaMid-ranged Weapons: LanceaHastaLong-ranged Weapons:PlumbataPilumSpecial Weapon:FalxArmor Types: Lorica SegmentataLorica Hamata Knight Warrior Type: ChampionShort-ranged Weapons: BroadswordMaceMid-ranged Weapons: PoleaxeHalberdLong-ranged Weapons: Light CrossbowHeavy CrossbowSpecial Weapon:Morning StarArmor Types: Maximillian FullplateCoat of Plates Ninja Warrior Type: GuerillaShort-ranged Weapons: NinjatoWakizashiMid-ranged Weapons: KusarigamaKyoketsu ShogiLong-ranged Weapons:ShurikenBlow GunSpecial Weapon: Black EggArmor Types: Shinobi ShozokuTatami-Do Pirate Warrior Type: BerserkerShort-ranged Weapons: CutlassDaggerMid-ranged Weapons: Boarding PikePikeLong-ranged Weapons: Flintlock PistolBlunderbussSpecial Weapon: Grenado Armor Types: Leather CoatPrivateer JacketRajput (DLC)Warrior Type: BerserkerShort-ranged Weapons: KhandaGrujMid-ranged Weapons: TabarBhujLong-ranged Weapons: ChakramQuoitSpecial Weapon: KatarArmor Types: Coat of 10,000 NailsChahar-Aina Samurai Warrior Type: ChampionShort-ranged Weapons: KatanaNodachiMid-ranged Weapons: YariNaginataLong-ranged Weapons: Yumi (Hankyu)Yumi (Daikyu)Special Weapon: Kanabo Armor Types: Do-maru ArmorNimaido ArmorShaolin Monk (DLC)Warrior Type: GuerillaShort-ranged Weapons: JianDaoMid-ranged Weapons: Hook SwordsChicken SicklesLong-ranged Weapons Flying KnifeSleeve ArrowSpecial Weapon: Emei PiercersArmor Types:Monk RobesBuddhist RobesSpartanWarrior Type: ChampionShort-ranged Weapons: XiphosXyeleMid-ranged Weapons: DorySarissaLong-ranged Weapons: Light JavelinHeavy JavelinSpecial Weapon: FalcataArmor Types: Bronze CuirassLinothorax Viking Warrior Type: BerserkerShort-ranged Weapons: Viking LongswordSkeggoxMid-ranged Weapons: Viking Great AxeAtgeirLong-ranged Weapons: SpearDouble Spear ThrowSpecial Weapon: LangsaxArmor Types: ChainmailLamellar ArmorZande Warrior (DLC)Warrior Type: GuerillaShort-ranged Weapons: MakrakaZande Fighting KnifeMid-ranged Weapons: Light MakriggaHeavy MakriggaLong-ranged Weapons KpingaBotto and PimaSpecial Weapon: Zande SwordArmor Types: Zande Battle WearCeremonial Headress</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6399">Bushido Blade</game><game id="25453">Pirates, Vikings and Knights II</game><game id="30428">BloodStorm</game><game id="12411">Soulcalibur</game><game id="6226">Bushido Blade 2</game><game id="22940">Kengo: Master of Bushido</game><game id="26611">Tournament of Legends</game><game id="20831">Castlevania Judgment</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1424148-dwarrior_box.png</image></root>