<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29879</id><name>Tiger Woods PGA Tour 11</name><description>While little is known about the specifics of this game, on the first day of the Game Developers Conference EA revealed that Tiger Woods PGA Tour 11 would utilise the upcoming PS3 Move motion controller and would feature The Ryder Cup as a playable tournament.    GameplaySeveral key gameplay changes have been made to the higher difficulty levels. One such change is the addition of "True aim" which will replace the old circle aiming system with simply the general direction the shot will go. Also gone is the camera following the ball flight.  This will now be a stationary camera that remains behind the golfer showing only what would normally be seen on the golf course. The Ryder Cup has been added to the game as well featuring the typical setup seen in the real world with 12 vs.12 team play.   Playstation Move Now that Move has shipped, PGA Tour 11 has received an update making it compatible with Move. Move allows for 1:1 swings and tilting the controller lets you change the way you take your shot. A demo of Tiger will is available on Move's demo disk. Golfers Male    Tiger Woods   Rory Mcilroy   Chris DiMarco   Luke Donald   Jim Furyk   Retief Goosen   Colin Montgomerie   Ian Poulter   Justin Rose   Adam Scott   Vijay Singh   Mike Weir   Michael Campbell   Camilo Villegas   Darren Clarke   Paul Casey   Nick Dougherty   Anthony Kim   Rocco Mediate Stephen Ames Danny Lee Boo Weekley   Female    Paula Creamer   Cristie Kerr   Morgan Pressel   Natalie Gulbis Suzanne Petterson   Fantasy   Raczilla Angus MacLeary Travis Knox Elsa Bjorklund Bobbie Leigh Xbox 360  PS3 Course List    TPC Sawgrass  Turnberry  St. Andrews  Bethpage State Park  Oakmont CC  Wentworth    Pebble Beach  TPC Boston  Hazeltine  East Lake  Torrey Pines  Wolf Creek  Celtic Manor Resort  Liberty National  The Greenbrier  TPC Scottsdale  Whistling Straits   DLC Courses for Xbox 360  PS3   Pinehurst™ No. 2  Sheshan Golf  CC  Harbour Town Golf Links  Gary Player Country Club Course  Bay Hill Club  Lodge®  TPC Blue Monster at Doral®  Cog Hill Golf  CC™  Banff Springs  Firestone CC  Spyglass Hill® Golf Club  Riviera CC (Gamestop Pre-order Bonus) The Predator  Highlands  River Course at Blackwolf Run  Emerald Dragon Wii Course List  Celtic Manor Resort (The Twenty Ten Course)  The Greenbrier (The Old White Course)  Liberty National G.C.  Whistling Straits (Straits Course)  The Predator (Fantasy Course)  Banff Springs (Stanley Thompson 18)  Bay Hill Club  Lodge  Bethpage (Black)  Cog Hill Golf  CC (Dubsdread Course)  Doral (Blue Monster)  East Lake C.C.  Gary Player C.C.  Harbor Town Golf Links  Hazeltine National C.C.  Kiawah Island Golf Resort (Ocean Course)  Oakmont C.C.  Pebble Beach Golf Links  Pinehurst (Course #2)  Sheshan Golf Club  Saint Andrews Links (Old Course)  The K Club Golf Resort  Torrey Pines G.C. (South Course)  TPC Boston  TPC Sawgrass  TPC Scottsdale  Turnberry (Ailsa Course)  Wentworth (West Course)  Wolf Creek G.C. </description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="28">Golf</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20598">Hot Shots Golf: Out of Bounds</game><game id="22203">Super Swing Golf</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2269435-box_twpgat11.png</image></root>