<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29886</id><name>Dino D-Day</name><description>OverviewDino D-Day is a multiplayer-oriented class-based  World War II first-person shooter developed and distributed by  800 North and  Digital Ranch for the  PC (via  Steam) on April 8, 2011. Originated as a one-map single-player "prototype" game  modification for  Half-Life 2 (released on November 11, 2009) and powered by  Valve's  Source Engine, the game introduces an  alternate history where  Nazi scientists have found a way to breed killer  dinosaurs, creating a powerful raptor army serving the Third Reich. Players are thrown into conflicts (Team Deathmatch, King of the Hill, and Objectives) in North Africa as one of 16 unique playable classes (9 human classes, 5 regular dinosaur classes, and 2 special dinosaur classes).Factions and ClassesDino D-Day pits players as one of two factions: the Allies and the Axis. Each faction has direct access to seven playable classes each. In some maps, the Axis can have access to one of two special dinosaurs (the Tyrannosaurus Rex and the Styracosaur).Allied Classes (Hardgrave's Team)Captain Jack Hardgrave American paleontologist turned battle-hardened dinosaur hunter, who sometimes need to feed the urge to punch dinosaurs in the face.Weapons:  M1 Garand,  Colt .45,  MK2 Frag Grenade,  Fists Special Ability (Berserk): After killing three enemies in a single life, the player can make Hardgrave go berserk by pressing the special ability key. While berserk, he is only able to use his fists, but he can absorb a greater amount of damage taken.Corporal Joe Spencer American former track star and the Allied forces' agile "scout" class, equipped with powerful sticky grenades and artillery strikes.Weapons:  Thompson SMG, Colt. 45,  Sticky Grenades, FistsSpecial Ability (Artillery Strike): By holding the special ability key, a targeting reticle appears on the position the player is facing at. Pressing the primary attack button then dispatches an artillery strike at that location (after ten seconds).Captain Nigel Blithe-Crossley British expert paleontologist, who uses a pump-action shotgun for close-quarters combat and the PIAT anti-tank weapon against certain armored dinosaurs.Weapons:  Trench Gun,  PIAT,  Smoke Grenade, FistsIlona Vike Latvian partisan and skilled sniper seeking revenge for the dinosaur destruction of her village, also carries a trap for a specific breed of dinoasur.Weapons:  Mosin-Nagant, Nagant Revolver, FistsSpecial Ability (Rabbit Trap): In the weapon slot normally reserved for grenades contain one dead jack rabbit, which can be thrown to lure in  velociraptors.Camille Brun French partisan, who was trained as a combat nurse during the French Resistance.Weapons:  Sten Gun,  P38, FistsSpecial Ability (Healing): Camille has two methods of healing friendly players: throwing health kits and direct healing (in similar vein to the Left 4 Dead series). In the weapon slot normally reserved for grenades contain 5 health kits, which can be thrown to teammates to create a range-of-effect area that heals friendly players for 20 seconds. She can also directly heal players by holding the special ability key near an injured teammate (with no cost to her throwable health kit supply). Injured players are shown at all times with a pulsing red outline.Jakob Frank German Jew and a powerhouse force for the Allies.Weapons:  BAR, Flechette Gun, MK2 Frag Grenade, FistsTrigger Added in the July 28, 2011 update, it is a Protoceratops rejected by the Nazis (due to a birth defect in its back leg) and taken care of by Hardgrave's team. It is equipped with a powerful .30 cal machine gun on its back (which tends to overheat) and can knock enemies down by ramming them. Weapons: .30 Cal MG, Ramming attackAxis Classes (Dinosauriergruppe)Hptm. Kurt Streicher Accomplished painter and "perfect assault soldier" recruited from an elite unit of the  Wehrmacht.Weapons:  Mauser K98,  MP-40,  Stick Grenade,  KnifeOLt. Karl Hissman Skilled falconer and outdoorsman, who uses both his sniper rifle and his army of  kamikaze  pterosaurs to take out enemies from afar.Weapons: Mauser K98 (with Scope),  Luger, Stick Grenade, KnifeSpecial Ability (Kamikaze Pterosaur): By holding the special ability key, a targeting reticle appears on the position the player is facing at. Pressing the primary attack button then dispatches a pterosaur strapped with a 80mm mortar at that location. The reticle can also be locked on to an enemy player, in which the pterosaur will chase the target before exploding.HptFw. Wolfgang von Graff Veterinarian and Combat Medic, who can heal dinosaurs on the front lines just as well as human soldiers.Weapons:  MP-44, Luger, KnifeSpecial Ability (Healing): Graff has two methods of healing friendly players: throwing health kits and direct healing (in similar vein to the Left 4 Dead series). In the weapon slot normally reserved for grenades contain 5 health kits, which can be thrown to teammates to create a range-of-effect area that heals friendly players for 20 seconds. He can also directly heal players by holding the special ability key near an injured teammate (with no cost to his throwable health kit supply). Injured players are shown at all times with a pulsing red outline. Velociraptor  Fast and agile carnivores with an incredible leaping ability, who can pounce on enemies for a speedy kill (as long as there are no delicious dead rabbits lying around).Weapons:  ClawsSpecial Ability (Pounce): Jumping at an enemy while holding down the secondary attack button causes the player to latch onto the victim for an instant kill.Special Ability (High Jump): Jumping directly after crouching sends the player soaring high through the air, allowing the player to reach higher places.Desmatosuchus A walking reptilian  tank who can shell enemies from afar while being able to easily absorb bullet barrages.Weapons: 20mm Gun, Lunge attackDilophosaurus One of the earliest known theropod dinosaurs, it can pick up its prey (both fallen Allied humans and  goats) by its mouth and throw them at its enemy.Weapons: ClawsSpecial Ability (Head-butt): By pressing the primary attack button while sprinting, the player can knock down enemy humans, leaving them helpless for a short period of time.Special Ability (Victim Throw): By pressing the secondary attack button at a knocked-down enemy human, the player can pick up the corpse for an instant kill. The player can also (within five seconds) throw the corpse at other enemies to also kill them. The player can also pick up goats scattered throughout the map and throw them at enemies to kill them.Stygimoloch Added in the July 28, 2011 update. Similar to Trigger, it carries a powerful back-mounted machine gun (that tends to overheat) and can knock enemies down by ramming them.Weapons: MG34, Ramming attack Tyrannosaurus RexAdded in the July28, 2011 update. System RequirementsOperating System: Windows XP / Vista / 7Processor: Pentium 4 3.0GHzGraphics Card: 128 MB, Shader model 2.0, ATI 9600, NVidia 6600 or betterRAM Memory: 1 GBHard Disk Space: 5 GBDirectX: 9.0cSound Card: DirectX 9.0c compatiblePeripherals: Keyboard and Mouse</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16121">Day of Defeat: Source</game><game id="28916">Jurassic: The Hunted</game><game id="11051">Turok</game><game id="21119">Wolfenstein</game><game id="29981">Primal Carnage</game><game id="37216">Depth</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/880/1839580-untitled2.jpg</image></root>