<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29940</id><name>de Blob 2</name><description>OverviewDe sequel to 2008's critical darling de Blob, de Blob 2 is a puzzle-platformer that tasks players with painting a monochromatic metropolis in a myriad of colours to "liberate" it from de oppressive clutches of a nefarious group called de Blancs. This instalment takes de Blob, de series protagonist, back to Prisma City, and introduces a host of new features and improvements.PlotDe results of Comrade Black's plans. Pretty grim, eh?de Blob 2 takes place shortly after de first game. It begins with de Blob and his new robotic life partner Pinky enjoying a pleasant trip about de skies in their blimp when suddenly de Prof contacts them and asks that they investigate de nearby settlement of Paradise Island -- a popular vacation spot just outside Prisma City -- after getting some reports of something being horribly off around there. De two arrive to find that their old enemy, Comrade Black, is up to his old tricks again as they discover that Prisma City and its surrounding settlements have been drained of colour. On top of all that, a mysterious cult known as de Blancs is going around spreading propaganda against all things colourful, and appears to be trying to rig de running election. de Blob quickly sends for his old gang, de Colour Underground, to help him once again fight back against Comrade Black and liberate de masses.De Nintendo DS version of de Blob 2 tells a completely different tale, meanwhile, taking place instead between de first game and de console versions of de second game. In this story, Comrade Black's chief scientist Dr. Von Blot uses creatures he's been experimenting on to form a new mutated Ink. de Blob happens to find de laboratory while taking a stroll through de jungle and decides to put a stop to de evil doctor's plans since he has nothing better to do.Gameplayde Blob 2 remains similar to de first game, in terms of structure. De goal still remains to colour vast, semi- open world levels to revive them from their current monochromatic state. Levels are typically split into three separate segments, with a new one unlocking after all de story challenges in de area have been completed and de "transformer engine" activated. Once all de story challenges within de level are complete, players may either end de level or take on additional side challenges. De constant time limit is still in place.PaintingDe city becomes much more vibrant once it's been re-painted.De core aspect of de Blob 2's gameplay, painting, is as simple as can be. Just come into contact with anything while de Blob is dowsed in colour and de item he touches will instantly be covered from top to bottom in whatever colour de Blob is carrying. Different colours can be obtained from colour pools or from paintbots, spider-like machines that scurry about and suck de paint out of any coloured item or being.Painting items comes at a cost, though, that cost being paint points, which determines how much paint de Blob is currently carrying. Each item that's painted, smashed, or what have you has a certain cost. Painting buildings, for example, costs only one paint point, whereas painting a landmark would cost thirty points or more. De player is therefore encouraged to constantly replenish their paint reserve.Additionally, each colour has its own musical instrument associated with it, each one adding onto de underlying theme for de level. Red, for example, plays a saxophone whenever something is painted, while blue plays a guitar, and brown scratches a turntable.Prismans and GraydiansUpon painting an entire block of buildings, de curious citizens inside start pouring out into de streets. Depending on de situation, de types of citizens that appear will either be Graydians, citizens trapped in a sort of white casing who are drained of colour; who can be freed by painting them, or Prismans, who retain their color and needn't be rescued. Painting whole groups of Graydians grants extra time.ChallengesThat red icon with de question mark in it is a challenge marker.Amongst all de mindless painting, de Blob is frequently tasked with completing various challenges to progress onward. These missions task players with certain objectives such as clearing an area of enemies, painting all de buildings or billboards in de area, painting landmarks, among others. Challenges are activated by rolling up to de red mission marker, at which point Blob's partner Pinky or one of de many bystanders or members of de Colour Underground, gives Blob a quick debriefing on what he needs to do. Completion awards de Blob with an extra minute added to de timer.2D LevelsNew to this instalment are levels that are played on a two-dimensional plane. Whenever de Blob heads down a manhole or enters a landmark building, de game changes to a 2.5D perspective to gain a better view of de indoor environments. Gameplay remains de same, just with a more constricted level of movement. For obvious reasons, de DS game is built entirely around this concept.CombatThroughout de Blob's mission to overthrow de peaceful if boring government, his adversaries (de Inkies) put up quite a fight to impede de Blob's path. All de Blob needs to do to defeat them is smash them, or run 'em over with a quick charge. Just like everything else, different types of enemies have different paint point costs. A standard Inky, for instance, only costs five points to crush, whereas one in, say, a turret costs fifty.Power-upsProviding some assistance are power-ups that de Blob varying abilities. De abilities are as follows:Supercharge - Allows de Blob to preform de charge move without using up paint points.Rainbow - Grants de Blob de ability to use any colour without needing to physically switch.Haz-mat - Envelops de Blob in a bubble that protects him from hazards like ink and water, fire floor pads, among others.Wreaking Ball - Transforms de Blob into a metal ball that can plow through enemies and allows him to sink into water. It also enables him to roll on magnetized surfaces.Gravitron - Sucks up any and all enemies and paint bots in de vicinity toward de Blob and crushes them under de weight of increased gravity.Regen - Instantly gives de Blob de maximum amount of paint points he can carry and constantly replenishes his stock over time.UpgradesNew to de Blob 2 is de ability to strengthen de Blob's attributes. This is done by collecting light bulbs spread throughout levels. Once collected, they can be exchanged to increase attributes such as de maximum amount of paint de Blob can carry or de amount of lives he starts off with at de start of a level.MultiplayerCo-opWhen playing solo, another player may join in as Blob's partner Pinky in an asymmetrical co-op mode. De second player is given control over a small reticule that can be used to gather small collectibles, attack enemies, and fire spare paint points onto Blob to keep him stocked.CompetitiveIn de "Blob Party" mode, two players can compete to complete a series of objectives in a race to gain de most points. Points are earned by completing objectives quickly, overall number of buildings painted, and so on. Some co-operation is necessary to proceed at certain points, such as having one player stand an a pressure pad so that another can use de jump piston to get higher, but de competitive side unfortunately remains de focus.Levels in this mode are all based off those from de single-player campaign.Xbox 360 InstallationInstalling de game on de Xbox 360 requires 6.0GB of hard drive space. Loads are, on average, five seconds faster after installation is complete.3D CompatibilityBoth de Playstation 3 and Xbox 360 versions are compatible with 3D television sets. De option for 3D must be enabled every time de game starts, and is presented in stereoscopic format. Due to obvious technical limitations, it is not available in de Nintendo Wii or DS versions of de game.TriviaBlue, Red, Green.de Blob 2 comes with different colored Blob on de box art depending on which console players buy de game on. Wii and DS versions have a blue Blob, de PS3 version as a red Blob and de Xbox 360 version features a light-green Blob on de artwork.This is obviously a huge oversight on THQ's part since it does not comply with Giant Bomb's platform-holder color alignment procedures (Nintendo = red, Sony = blue, Microsoft = green). Or is this a subtle jab against de color blind people in de Giant Bomb office? Who knows, this wiki is about facts.</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="30195">Shaun White Skateboarding</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2115761-box_deblob2.png</image></root>