<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29990</id><name>Major League Baseball 2K10</name><description>Noteworthy FeaturesImproved Pitcher vs. Hitter ExperienceThe theme of MLB 2K10 is the improved pitcher vs. hitter experience. The feeling of control as you throw pitches and hit balls was one of the developers key focuses while developing MLB 2K10. You now have greater control over the ball's direction as it comes off the bat, or more precise pitching on breaking balls, etc.My Player ModeThe feature that started in NBA 2K10 has made it's way over to 2K's MLB series. The basic goal of this mode is similar to those found in games like Madden for a few years now. The player starts with an up and coming baseball player and has to basically role play his career and turn that player into a Hall of Famer. You increase your player's attributes through both practice drills throughout the season as well as achieving goals given to you during games . The player controls only his/her single player throughout games and the rest of the players are CPU controlled.MLB TodayThis is another extension on an NBA 2K10 feature. The idea of this is to bring game commentary to life by detecting all kinds of stats from previous real life MLB games and incorporating them into the in-game commentary. For example, an announcer may bring up how the team you are playing as have won the previous two games in a series and what it could mean record-wise if they were to sweep the series. If you are playing a quick game, the stats will be pulled from real life games. However if you are playing a custom franchise mode, it will pull stats from fictional games within your franchise mode.$1,000,000 Challenge and Fathead OfferWinner of the million dollar challenge.The MLB 2K10 creators issued a challenge to be the first to pitch a perfect game. The first player to purchase MLB 2K10 and record a prefect game won $1,000,000.The winner of the million dollar challenge was Wade McGilberry from Alabama, who completed the challenge on the first day after only 7 tries. McGilberry used Atlanta Braves pitcher Kenshin Kawakami for his no hitter attempt.If you buy either the 360, PS3, or Wii versions of the game there will be a Fathead token inside to redeem at www.fathead.com/mlb2k10. You can choose from 8 different players including Evan Longoria, this years cover athlete.Avatar AwardsMLB 2K10 has several avatar awards.2K Sports Jersey - Win a game in any mode.MLB 2K10 Jersey - (Achievement: The Call) Get called up to the majors in My Player mode.Evan Longoria Jersey - Win the "best fielder" award in Franchise or My Player modes.MLB 2K10 Batting Helmet - Hit a Grand Slam in any game mode.MLB 2K10 Bat and Ball (prop) - Either win the batting title in Franchise or My Player modes or hit 150 home runs.SoundtrackThe Full soundtrack consists of 16 tracks:(note: Pearl Jam's "The Fixer" will only be included in the 360 and PS3 versions of the game)Hotel St. George - "It's the Blues"Social distortion - "Bad Luck"Tantric - "Down and Out"Black Crowes - "Go Faster"Iggy Pop - "Lust For Life"Sugarhill Gang - "Rapper's Delight"Phoenix - "Lisztomania"Black Eyes - "Your Touch"LCD Soundsystem - "Time To Get Away"Cage The Elephant - "Judas"Daughtry - "Every Time You Turn Around"Jet - "Start The Show"Boss Martians - "Hey Hey Yeah Yeah"Ryan Adams - "Magick"Black Sheep - "The Choice Is Yours"Pearl Jam - "The Fixer"PlatformsMLB 2K10 was released on the 360, PS3, Wii, PC, PS2, DS, and PSP. Every version had the same release date of March 2nd, 2010.</description><genres><genre id="34">Baseball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="24101">MLB Front Office Manager</game><game id="29485">MLB 10: The Show</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2146371-box_mlb2k10.png</image></root>