<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>29992</id><name>LEGO Star Wars III: The Clone Wars</name><description>OverviewThe game will include all the characters from both seasons of the hugely popular animated television series, Star Wars: The Clone Wars, as well as some characters from the theatrical Star Wars Saga. The game will feature brand new battle modes, giving players head-to-head combat and an upgraded level builder, allowing the creation of customized bases and in-game battlefields.Play either as a Jedi or Separatist with new character abilities, such as Squad command, Lightsaber slicing, Lightsaber jumps, long distance Jedi attacks and Grapple Tie-Ups, all within a new hub. The game will be the most action-oriented game in TT's LEGO series, and will be set to release around March 2011.ImprovementsVisualLego Star Wars III is one of the first Lego games to bolster Traveller's Tales' new graphics engine that was only previously featured in Lego Indiana Jones 2: The Adventure Continues. It features improved lighting features which make them game look more impressive, but still manages to keep the Lego vibe. It also adds more depth of field elements which make it easier to play in some minor aspects.The game also features a new scene swap addition which has the player switch to characters in completely different parts in a level at any time once available. Examples are switching from a droid in one part of the level, to a Jedi in another part in order to solve a puzzle.GameplayA few new gameplay improvements have been made in order to capture the fluidity of large scale battles. One of the features includes a new way to land space ships and continue to fight on land.Another improvement is the ability to build bases and defend them against droids.Also, the hub world has been changed from a cantina to a republic space cruiser called the Resolute.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="31415">Scooby-Doo! and the Spooky Swamp</game><game id="32196">Marvel Super Hero Squad: The Infinity Gauntlet</game><game id="35461">Disney Universe</game><game id="36898">LEGO Batman 2: DC Super Heroes</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1676369-box_legosw3.png</image></root>