<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30003</id><name>NCAA Football 11</name><description>Cover AthleteOn April 8th, 2010,                                       EA Sports announced that former University of Florida quarterback and 2007 Heisman Trophy Winner Tim Tebow would grace the cover of NCAA Football 11.  This also broke the two-year trend of having a different player on the cover for different platforms.  Two weeks later, the cover art was revealed for the game with different covers for the                                          PlayStation 3 and                                         Xbox 360 versions.  FeaturesIn an article that ran on ESPN.com on February 26, 2010, the first features were revealed.   These included: On-field                                        referees with avoidance logicPro-Tak gang-tackling engine                                     Auto-save featureAuto-loading rostersFormation substitutionsNew player equipmentSingle bowl seasonDynamic conference logosNumbers on                                     helmets (for teams such as the University of Alabama) Beginning on March 4, 2010,                                  EA Sports began adding                                 screenshots of new                                    mascot models that would be included in the game to their Facebook page every week.  Examples include the University of Oregon, Texas Tech University, Stanford University and many more.  On March 25, 2010,                                EA Sports designer                               Russ Kiniry released an article detailing the revamped lighting system implemented in NCAA Football 11.  Using linear lighting, the development team was able to achieve natural skin tones, as well realistic                          reflections on jerseys and                        helmets.  A week later, on April 5, 2010, an article was posted on                       EA Sports' blog with revealing a revamped locomotion engine.  This new engine was to be momentum-based and involved any actions a player made involving running, turning, and cutting.  While previous iterations of                      NCAA Football placed a heavy emphasis on a given player's speed rating, this new engine placed more weight upon a player's agility and acceleration ratings, giving players with a lower top speed more utility.  A larger motion capture facility also enabled the development team at                     EA Tiburon to create more natural run cycles.  For the first time in the                   series, full ESPN integration was to be included for the in-game presentation.  Previous entries included live updates from ESPN's Sportscenter and a news ticker, but NCAA Football 11 was the first to include ESPN College Football theme music, as well as in-game graphics.  The updated in-game UI included the ESPN game clock, stat banners and                 replay wipes.  The main menu was also updated with an ESPN look and the best recruits are tagged with the ESNPU Top 150 tag.  In late April, NCAA Football 11 Associate Designer Mike Scantlebury revealed the improvements made to general gameplay, dubbed               Real Assignment AI.  These improvements were largely made to the AI blocking schemes in the gameplay engine.  This allowed for the gameplay design team to create realistic blocking assignments for more complicated running schemes, with specific mentions of read option, triple option, stretch and draw plays.  It was also announced that running AI for the CPU would be greatly improved from past versions of the game.   It was later announced that there would be a number of              team-specific stadium entrances, adding to the in-game presentation in a way never seen in the current generation of consoles.  Teams announced to have received this treatment include Clemson, Florida, Florida State, Miami, Nebraska, Notre Dame, Tennessee, Texas, Virginia Tech and more.  There are rumored to be 30  teams in all to have specific stadium entrances. In a video that was released later, it was also revealed that there will be fan-specific          cutscenes and chants for a number of teams.   Dual-Analog Stick ControlsNew this year is a new Dual-analog stick controls which gives you control over both lower and upper body of the ball carrier for example if you have a fast agile runner and lean away from a defender and you setup a easy spin move to get out of the tackle.  Other features added to the game include: Game speed sliderMore challenging Hit Stick   Auto-Turbo optionNew onside kick camera   EA Team BuilderLike NCAA 10, NCAA 11 allows you to go    online and create a  school to use in the game. You can customize the logo, uniforms, fields,  mascots, programs, and rosters of the team and when the game is  released you can download the team to the hard drive and play.    Online DynastyNCAA 11 allows users to establish an online dynasty with the ability to have friends play as the opposing teams.  Either in-game or online via the     NCAA Football 11 website, a dynasty commissioner can control the flow and settings of the franchise, as well as provide weekly news stories to breathe some extra life into the fun.    In order to participate or establish an online dynasty, an individual must have used the Online Pass code that came with a new purchase of the game, or purchased one via the  EASports website.          </description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="21">Football</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25614">NCAA Football 10</game><game id="20848">NCAA Football 09</game><game id="25241">Madden NFL 10</game><game id="21706">NCAA Football 07</game><game id="21951">NCAA Football 08</game><game id="13671">NCAA Football 06</game><game id="6811">NCAA Football 2005</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2250727-box_ncaafb11.png</image></root>