<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30057</id><name>Sid Meier's Civilization V</name><description>OverviewCivilization V is the latest game in the Civilization franchise, developed by Firaxis Games and published by 2K Games. It was released on September 21, 2010 on the PC, and November 23, 2010 on the Mac. It makes a significant departure from the previous games in the franchise, adopting a hexagonal grid (instead of a square grid), and limiting units to one per tile. Some gameplay elements from Civilization IV, like religion and espionage, have been removed, while new elements like city states and limited strategic resources were added.Gods  Kings, an expansion pack, was released on June 19, 2012 in America, and June 22, 2012 worldwide. It adds 9 new civilizations, 3 new scenarios, as well as religion and espionage in the game. The second expansion, Brave New World, will be released July 9, 2013 in America, and July 12 worldwide. It revamps the Cultural and Diplomatic victories, and adds new trade route mechanics. This wikipage is reflective of the mechanics as employed in the base game.GameplayHex Grid in ActionIn Civilization V, the player chooses a civilization and manages its cities and units, trying to achieve victory. The game usually begins in the Stone Age, although players can choose a pre-determined age to start off from, and will progress through the ages to the Future Era. Throughout the game, the player will encounter other civilizations, and can form relations and become strong allies, or crush them to smithereens. Players can win through having the highest score, capturing all enemy capitals, being the first to reach Alpha Centauri, winning the United Nations vote, or even being the most culturally affluent of all the civilizations and building the Utopia Project.CombatRanged CombatThe combat system has been completely overhauled in Civilization V. Unit stacking from previous games has been removed, replaced with a one military unit-per-tile system. Ranged units also make a return to the franchise. They can attack units from a distance, allowing them to take potshots at invading armies. However, they are weak in melee combat and require good positioning or a melee defender to avoid from being destroyed.Sieges in Civilization V are different from the previous games, as cities are now able to defend themselves. All cities possess hit points--if this reaches zero, the city will fall under the attacker's control. Garrisoning units and building defensive buildings will increase a city's defense rating. Cities can also fire at sieging units, softening them up for a counterattack. After a city has been conquered, it can be: razed, annexed, or transformed into a puppet state.Naval movement and combat has also been changed, as any land unit can "embark", entering a water tile and automatically turning into a transport ship. Embarked units are defenseless, and will require protection from enemy vessels. All ships are ranged units in Civilization V, although Gods  Kings adds melee naval units that can take cities. Ships can also blockade trade routes and bombard cities and units on land.CitiesThe City ScreenBuilding a city is one of the pillars of Civilization gameplay, and cities can be settled by settler units in any suitable place on the world map. City boundaries can grow, one tile at a time, to a maximum of 3 tiles outwards, favoring food oriented tiles like grasslands over production based tiles like forests. The player can also buy specific tiles, speeding up the rate at which a city expands. Cities generate production, money, culture, and science for their civilization, and players can choose which building they wish to build and what units they wish to train.City-StatesCity-states are one city civilizations controlled by AI, unable to expand, and cannot win the game. There are 3 types of city-states - Cultured, Maritime and Militaristic - each providing culture points, food, and military units respectively. Civilizations will have to vie for influence over the city-states, performing quests for them or giving them monetary gifts. Being friendly with a city state provides bonuses based on the type, and allying with one will provide a greater amount of bonus. Gods  Kings adds 2 more types of city-states: Religious and Mercantile.The United NationsA city-state can only ally itself with one civilization at a time. That city-state will provide all its resources to its ally, and will join its ally in war. It will also vote its ally in the United Nations, for the Diplomatic Victory. If a city-state is conquered by a civilization but then liberated by another, it will also vote for the liberator in the United Nations. Some examples of city-states in the game are Singapore, Rio de Janeiro, and Venice.Social PoliciesSocial Policy TreesSocial Policies replaces Civics from Civilization IV, and are civilization-wide bonuses that are unlocked with enough culture points. There are 10 Social Policy trees - each with 5 policies, opener, and finisher abilities - and are unlocked in various eras. Some policy branches are mutually exclusive. Players can still switch to a conflicting branch, but only at the expense of all the policies of the previous one, and a period of anarchy. If 5 trees are fully completed, the Utopia project is unlocked, allowing for Cultural Victory to be achieved. The 10 social policies are, as follows: Liberty, Tradition, Honor, Piety, Patronage, Commerce, Rationalism, Freedom, Autocracy and Order.Science and EconomyScientific VictoryScience is an important part of Civilization V, as it controls how fast technology is unlocked. Science is generated at 1 per population unit, and can be increased through scientific buildings, science specialists, or Social Policies. Trading technologies between civilizations has also been removed. Instead, two civilizations can enter a research agreement (for a nominal sum) where they work together to provide a huge boost to their research. But if they go to war, the agreement is cancelled.A civilization's economy is reflected by the amount of gold they generate. Gold can be used in a vast array of things, from the maintenance of units, buildings, and roads, to buying and upgrading units. Gold can also be used in diplomacy to improve relations with other civilizations or city states, or used as a bartering tool. Gold is generated from tiles such as coastlines or rivers, and the trading post improvement can be built to generate further income. Luxury resources, trade routes, pillaging tiles, capturing cities, and disbanding extra units will also provide gold.HappinessHappiness is a factor that determines how willing a civilization's citizen are to work and cooperate with their leader, and how well they fight in their armies. Unlike previous games, happiness is now a civilization-wide value. The larger a civilization gets, the more unhappy their citizens become. The number of cities in a civilization and the population of those cities negatively affect happiness, and annexed cities compound the issue. If unhappiness is not resolved, rebel units will eventually rise up in the civilization's territory and attack the civilization.Happiness is generated through the presence of luxury resources, the construction of entertainment buildings, and the discovery of Natural Wonders throughout the world. Several Social Policies and Wonders also help to alleviate unhappiness. Positive happiness will eventually build up into a Golden Age for a civilization, granting them additional gold and production (and culture in Gods  Kings) for 10 turns.Great PeopleGreat People are special units generated by Great People points. These units can build a special Great Person tile improvement, activate a special action unique to that type of Great People, or can be used to generate a short Golden Age. Great People points are generated from their corresponding specialists and from certain Wonders, except Great Generals, who gain points from land combat.NameActivated AbilityTile ImprovementGreat ArtistCulture Bomb: Tiles around the Great Artist immediately belong to the civilization, regardless of previous ownerLandmark: +6 CultureGreat EngineerHurry Production: Provides a great amount of production to the building or Wonder in the city's queueManufactory: +4 Production, +5 with ChemistryGreat GeneralCombat Boost (passive): Increases the combat ability of land units within 2 tiles of the Great GeneralCitadel: Defensive boost, 3 damage to enemies around itGreat MerchantConduct Trade Mission: Grants a large amount of gold and boosts city state influenceCustoms House: +4 Gold, +6 with EconomicsGreat ScientistDiscover Technology: Instantly discover any technologyAcademy: +6 Science, +8 with Scientific TheoryResourcesThere are 3 types of resources in Civilization V: strategic resources, luxury resources, and bonus resources. Strategic resources unlock different units and buildings that rely on them, such as Iron for Swordsmen. These resources can be acquired by building the appropriate improvement upon them like mine or a well. Strategic resources had a huge overhaul in Civilization V, and there are now limited quantities of a resource per source. If the source is depleted no further units or buildings that require that resource can be built. In addition, if a civilization loses the resource, their units will suffer a severe combat penalty. The strategic resources are: horses, iron, coal, oil, aluminum, and uranium.Luxury resources are rare resources like spices, whales, or gems. These resources often provide gold boost to the tile it is on, and more importantly, happiness to a civilization. Each unique luxury resource a civilization holds grants it 4 happiness points, and extra luxuries can be traded for gold or more luxuries. Additional luxury resources, such as citrus and truffles, were added in Gods  Kings.Bonus resources like cows or fish can help a civilization grow bigger. These types of resources provide additional food or production to tile, and can be improved by tile improvements. A city working a tile with the bonus resource will get the full benefit of that resource, and many bonus resources can be further improved with specific buildings.WondersHagia Sophia in the Reveal TrailerWonders are special one-time buildings any civilization can build, and provides massive bonuses to the builder. There are 2 types of buildable wonders in Civilization V: World Wonders and National Wonders. World Wonders can only be built once in any game, and cannot be rebuilt if destroyed. All civilizations can built it when they meet its prerequisites, but once a civilization finishes it, all other attempts fail and gets turned into gold. National Wonders, on the other hand, can be built by every civilization once they fulfill its prerequisites, and each civilization can have their own National Wonder.There are 28 World Wonders and 8 National Wonders in Civilization V, and the Wonders of the Ancient World DLC adds 3 additional World Wonders to the game.Natural Wonders are a tile feature added in Civilization V. They are magnificent natural features that can be found around the world, and provides 1 happiness point to a civilization when discovered. The number of Natural Wonders in a game is limited by the size of the map. Natural Wonders provide tile yields greater than normal terrain, and Spain gets additional bonuses from Natural Wonders due to their special ability. There are a total of 10 Natural Wonders in Civilization V:Cerro de Potosi: 10 GoldEl Dorado: 5 Culture, grants the first civilization that finds it 500 GoldFountain of Youth: 10 Happiness, grants units near it extra health regenerationKrakatoa: 5 ScienceMt. Fuji: 1 Gold, 5 Culture (2 Gold, 3 Culture, 3 Faith in Gods  Kings)Old Faithful: 2 Science, 3 HappinessRock of Gibraltar: 2 Food, 5 GoldThe Barringer Crater: 2 Gold, 3 ScienceThe Grand Mesa: 2 Production, 3 GoldThe Great Barrier Reef: Occupies 2 tiles, 2 Food, 1 Production, 1 Gold, 2 ScienceCivilizationsWashingtonThere are 25 civilizations currently in Civilization V, shipping with 18 and the rest as DLCs. Unlike the previous games, each civilization now gets a special ability that is unique to them. they also either get two unique units, or a unique unit and a unique building or tile improvement. These special abilities give them specific advantages that somewhat reflects the civilization's history. Each civilization is either controlled by a player or AI, and goes through the various eras until achieving victory or is defeated.When a civilization is encountered, their leader will speak in their traditional language. Bismarck will speak in German, while Elizabeth will speak in English. This gives each of the leaders their own distinctive personalities, though subtitles are also provided to help clarify what is being said to the player.AmericaLeader: George WashingtonUnique Ability (Manifest Destiny): All land military units gain +1 to sight. Gold cost of Tile Purchasing reduced by half.Unique Unit (Minuteman): Replacement for Musketman (Renaissance Era). Immediately granted the Drill promotion. Ignores all terrain movement penalties.Unique Unit (B-17 Bomber): Replacement for Bomber (Modern Era). Immediately granted the Siege and Evasion promotions.ArabiaLeader: Harun al-RashidUnique Ability (Trade Caravans): Each Trade Route increases Gold production by +1. Double production of all mined Oil resources.Unique Unit (Camel Archer): Replacement for Knight (Medieval Era). Changes to Ranged unit (trading -44% base Combat Strength for +15 base Ranged Strength with a range of 2 tiles).Unique Building (Bazaar): Replacement for Market (Medieval Era). Doubles production of each mined luxury resource near the City.AztecsLeader: MontezumaUnique Ability (Sacrificial Captives): Gains Culture from each enemy unit killed.Unique Unit (Jaguar): Replacement for Warrior (Ancient Era). Unit automatically heals 2 HP after killing an enemy unit. Adds +50% to Combat Strength while in a Jungle tile. Doubles movement speed in Forest tiles.Unique Building (Floating Gardens): Replacement for Water Mill (Ancient Era). Gold upkeep cost of building reduced by half. Increases Food production by +15%. Adds +2 Food production to all worked Lake tiles.ChinaLeader: Wu ZetianUnique Ability (Art of War): Combat bonus from Great Generals increased by 15%. Birth rate of Great Generals increased by 50%.Unique Unit (Chu-Ko-Nu): Replacement for Crossbowman (Medieval Era). Immediately granted the Logistics promotion. Reduced base Ranged Strength by -27%.Unique Building (Paper Maker): Replacement for Library (Ancient Era). No Gold maintenance. Adds +2 Gold production.EgyptLeader: Ramesses IIUnique Ability (Monument Builders): Production towards Wonder construction increased by +20%.Unique Unit (War Chariot): Replacement for Chariot Archer (Ancient Era). No longer requires one Horse resource per unit. Increased movement speed by +1 tile.Unique Building (Burial Tomb): Replacement for Temple (Classical Era). No longer requires a Monument building. No Gold maintenance. Trades some Culture production (by -1) for Gold production (by +2). If the City is captured, the amount of Gold plundered is doubled.EnglandLeader: ElizabethUnique Ability (Sun Never Sets): Changed in the Gods  Kings expansion.Unique Unit (Longbowman): Replacement for Crossbowman (Medieval Era). Immediately granted Range promotion.Unique Unit (Ship of the Line): Replacement for Frigate (Renaissance Era). Increased base Ranged Strength by +13%. Reduced production cost (-8% Production or -6% Gold). Increased upgrade cost (to Destroyer) by +8% Gold. Made obsolete by the Electricity tech rather than the Combustion tech.FranceLeader: Napoleon BonaparteUnique Ability (Ancien Régime): Adds +2 Culture production per City. Made obsolete after discovering the Steam Power tech.Unique Unit (Musketeer): Replacement for Musketman (Renaissance Era). Increased base Combat Strength by +25%.Unique Unit (Foreign Legion): Replacement for Infantry (Industrial Era). Adds +25% to Combat Strength while in foreign territory.GermanyLeader: Otto von BismarckUnique Ability (Furor Teutonicus): Reduces Gold upkeep cost of land units by -25%. Upon defeating a Barbarian unit inside a Barbarian Encampment, there is a 50% chance that you earn 25 Gold and they join your side.Unique Unit (Landsknecht): Replacement for Pikeman (Medieval Era). Reduced production cost (-50% Production or -41% Gold). Increased upgrade cost (to Rifleman) by +32% gold.Unique Unit (Panzer): Replacement for Tank (Industrial Era). Increased base Combat Strength by +20%. Increased movement speed by +1 tile.GreeceLeader: Alexander the GreatUnique Ability (Hellenic League): City-State Influence degrades at half the normal rate and recovers at twice the normal rate.Unique Unit (Hoplite): Replacement for Spearman (Ancient Era). Increased base Combat Strength by +29%.Unique Unit (Companion Cavalry): Replacement for Horseman (Classical Era). Increased base Combat Strength by +20%. Increased movement speed by +1 tile.IndiaLeader: GandhiUnique Ability (Population Growth): Unhappiness from number of Citizens is halved, while unhappiness from number of Cities is doubled.Unique Unit (War Elephant): Replacement for Chariot Archer (Ancient Era). Increased base Combat Strength by +50%. Increased base Ranged Strength by +14%. Reduced movement speed by -1 tile. Increased production cost (+25% Production or +19% Gold). Reduced upgrade cost (to Knight) by -19% Gold.Unique Building (Mughal Fort): Replacement for Castle (Classical Era). Increases City Strength by +2, adds +2 to Culture production. Provides gold after the Flight tech.IroquoisLeader: HiawathaUnique Ability (The Great Warpath): All land military units ignore terrain penalties in Forest and Jungle tiles on friendly territory. Upon researching The Wheel tech, Forest and Jungle tiles on friendly territory can be used to establish Trade Routes.Unique Unit (Mohawk Warrior): Replacement for Swordsman (Classical Era). No longer requires one Iron resource per unit. Adds +50% to Combat Strength while in a Forest or Jungle tile.Unique Building (Longhouse): Replacement for Workshop (Medieval Era). Trades +10% increase to City Production with +1 City Production increase from each worked Forest tile.JapanLeader: Oda NobunagaUnique Ability (Bushido): All military units fight at full strength, regardless of their current HP.Unique Unit (Samurai): Replacement for Longswordsman (Medieval Era). Immediately granted the Shock promotion.Unique Unit (Zero): Replacement for Fighter (Industrial Era). Adds to Ranged Strength against Fighters.OttomansLeader: Suleiman the MagnificentUnique Ability (Barbary Corsairs): Changed in the Gods  Kings expansion.Unique Unit (Janissary): Replacement for Musketman (Renaissance Era). Increased base Combat Strength by +14%.Unique Unit (Sipahi): Replacement for Lancer (Renaissance Era). Increased movement speed by +1 tile. Pillaging enemy Cities cost no movement points.PersiaLeader: Darius IUnique Ability (Achaemenid Legacy): Golden Ages last 50% longer. During a Golden Age, all military units have increased movement speed (by +1 tile) and a +10% bonus to their Combat Strength.Unique Unit (Immortal): Replacement for Spearman (Ancient Era). Adds +14% to Combat Strength while attacking. Healing rate is doubled.Unique Building (Satrap's Court): Replacement for Bank (Renaissance Era). Adds +2 to Happiness and +2 to Gold production.RomeLeader: Augustus CaesarUnique Ability (The Glory of Rome): Increases Production towards any buildings that already exist in the Capital City by +25%.Unique Unit (Ballista): Replacement for Catapult (Classical Era). Increased base Ranged Strength by +27%.Unique Unit (Legion): Replacement for Swordsman (Classical Era). Increased base Combat Strength by +18%. Can construct Roads as well as Fortresses (only non-builder unit able to do so).RussiaLeader: Catherine the GreatUnique Ability (Siberian Riches): All Strategic Resources provide +1 Production to their nearest Cities. Double production of all Horse, Iron, and Uranium resources.Unique Unit (Cossack): Replacement for Cavalry (Renaissance Era). Adds +50% to Combat Strength against damaged units.Unique Building (Krepost): Replacement for Barracks (Ancient Era). Reduced cost of purchasing tiles for the City.SiamLeader: Ram KhamhaengUnique Ability (Father Governs Children): Changed in the Gods  Kings expansion.Unique Unit (Naresuan's Elephant): Replacement for Knight (Medieval Era). Increased base Combat Strength by +22%. Reduced movement speed by -1 tile.Unique Building (Wat): Replacement for University (Medieval Era). Trades +2 Science production bonus in Jungle areas for a +3 increase in Culture production.SonghaiLeader: Askia MuhammadUnique Ability (River Warlord): Changed in the Gods  Kings expansion.Unique Unit (Mandekalu Cavalry): Replacement for Knight (Medieval Era). Ignores Combat Strength penalty against Cities.Unique Building (Mud Pyramid Mosque): Replacement for Temple (Classical Era). No Gold maintenance. Adds +1 to Culture production.DLC CivilizationsCivilization / LeaderUnique 1Unique 2Special AbilityBabylonNebuchadnezzarBowmanWalls of BabylonIngenuity:Receive a free Great Scientist when you discover Writing. Earn Great Scientists 50% faster.Mongolia (Free)Genghis KhanKeshikKhanMongol Terror:Units fighting City States receive a +30% combat bonus. All mounted units receive +1 movement.IncaPachacutiSlingerTerrace FarmGreat Andean Road:Units ignore terrain costs when moving into any tile with Hills. No maintenance costs for improvements in Hills; half cost elsewhere.SpainIsabellaTercioConquistadorSeven Cities of Gold:Gold bonus for discovering a Natural Wonder (bonus enhanced if first to discover it). Culture, happiness, and tile yields from Natural Wonders doubled.PolynesiaKamehamehaMaori WarriorMoaiWayfinding:Can embark over ocean tiles immediately. +1 sight for embarked units. +10% combat strength when within 2 tiles of a Moai.DenmarkHarald BluetoothBerserkerNorwegian Ski InfantryViking Fury:Embarked units have +1 movement and pay just 1 movement point to move from sea to land. Melee units don't spend movement points when pillaging.KoreaSejongHwachaTurtle ShipScholars of Jade Hall:+2 Science from all specialists and GP Tile Improvements. Science boost each time a science building or wonder is built in the capital.Downloadable ContentKorea DLCCivilization V is the first game in the franchise to introduce DLC. Currently, there are 6 civilizations available as purchasable DLCs, and all of them (except Babylon) come with their own relevant scenarios, and have their own Steam achievements. Mongolia was added after the game's release as a free DLC and all players get the civilization for free.4 Cradle of Civilization map packs were initially only available separately as pre-order bonuses from different online and brick and mortar retailers. Each pack includes a single fixed size map inspired by real-world Asia, the Americas, the Mediterranean and Mesopotamia. The maps were later made available as paid DLC.The Explorer's Map Pack was released alongside the Denmark DLC. It includes 5 real world location: the British Isles, main island of Japan, the Caribbean, the Bering Strait and Eastern North America. It also added 3 new map generation scripts (Amazon, Donut, Sandstorm) as well as enhanced versions of the Continents and Pangaea scripts.The Wonders of the Ancient World scenario pack was released alongside the Korea DLC, and can be bought together as a combo pack. It adds 3 new World Wonders to the base game: the Temple of Artemis, the Statue of Zeus, and the Mausoleum of Halicarnassus. It also comes with a Ancient World scenario where players race with other civilizations to built the most World Wonders to win the game.Inspired by the "Brave New World" scenario "Scramble for Africa" a "Scrambled Contintents" map pack was released alongside the fall 2013 balance patch. It includes map scripts with real world continent outlines but random interiors. A thawed Antarctica and a whole world map are included, as well as some improvements on other map scripts like "Small Continents".Special EditionsThe special retail edition includes:5 metal figurines based on units from Civilization V manufactured by Reaper Miniatures2-disc CD soundtrack of game score selections“Behind-the-Scenes at Firaxis on Civilization V” DVD176-page hardcover art bookThere were no in-game bonuses in the Special retail edition.The Digital Deluxe edition also came with the soundtrack and the behind the scenes footage, but lacked the figurines and the art book. Instead, the Babylonian civilization and a Cradle of Civilization map pack came with the edition.The GOTY edition was released September 27, 2011, and comes with all 4 Cradle of Civilization map packs, the Explorer's Map Pack, the official soundtrack, and 4 DLC civilization packs: Babylon, Spain and Inca, Polynesia, and Denmark.Gods  KingsOfficial Box ArtOn February 16, 2012, the first full-on expansion to Civilization V was announced. In contrast to the "Civilization and Scenario" DLC packs, Gods  Kings also included major gameplay changes. Amongst them are two heavily fan-requested features: Religion and Espionage. Furthermore, the combat system was reworked, putting a bigger emphasis on a balanced army composition and introducing naval melee units. Other additions and changes include 27 new units, 13 new buildings, 9 new wonders, and 9 new playable civilizations, as well as 3 new scenarios including a steampunk-inspired one.The expansion pack was released June 19, 2012 in North America, and June 22, 2012 worldwide. It costs US$19.99 on Steam, and a demo (which requires Civilization V to be installed) is available. Gods  Kings is not included in the Game of the Year Edition copy of the game, and must be purchased separately.Brave New WorldBrave New World BoxartThe second full-on expansion for Civilization V focusses on tweaking the culture game and diplomacy. To this end several new mechanics were introduced, like archaeology and player-managed international trade routes. The culture has been complemented with tourism - tourism being the offensive part of culture, while conventional culture-points defend against tourism of other Civs. The social policies have been greatly expanded and gained multi-tiered Ideologies, which play a greater role in international diplomacy. The World Congress makes a return from previous Civ games, allowing Civs to vote on various resolutions, like the ban of nuclear weapons or a world ideology.Furthermore the add-on includes 9 new civilizations, 8 new wonders, 20 new units and 2 new scenarios. It includes the gameplay changes of Gods  Kings.Steam Integration2K Games announced that the game will use Steamworks. It will be used to provide Steam achievements, auto updating, DLC, multiplayer matchmaking and Steam Cloud support. This means that Steam will be installed regardless of how the game is obtained, despite the fact that it is purchasable through other digital distribution services (such as Direct2Drive). Steam will also be the DRM solution, requiring a one time activation. Steam AchievementsAchievementDescriptionA Magnificent VictoryBeat the game on any difficulty setting as Suleiman.A Righteous VictoryWin the Korean Scenario on Immortal (requires Korea DLC)A Woman's WorkBeat the game on any difficulty setting as Wu Zetian.Age of EmpireBeat the game on any difficulty setting as Darius.All Aboard the Orient ExpressDiscover a route to the Orient in the New World Scenario. (requires Spain/Inca DLC)All Roads Lead to RomeBuild a road with a Roman Legion.All-Achieving ZeusWin the Wonders Scenario on Deity (requires Wonders DLC)Amongst the Catacombs of Nephren-KaBeat the game on any difficulty setting as Ramesses II.Arab TraderTrade a luxury resource to another Civ that you earned through a city with a Bazaar.Arabian KnightsBeat the game on any difficulty setting as Harun al-Rashid.Au in the EUReturn a Treasure to Europe in the New World Scenario. (requires Spain/Inca DLC)Baby StepsBeat the game on the Settler difficulty level.Barbarian WarlordAs Bismarck, convert the Barbarians from 10 camps to your side.Barbary PirateAs Suleiman, accumulate a navy with 10 Barbarian naval units.Battlefield EarthBeat the game on an Earth-type Map.Blood and IronBeat the game on any difficulty setting as Bismarck.BollywoodAs gandhi, win a cultural victory with 3 or fewer cities in your empire.Bolt and ArrowBuild Statue of Zeus and Temple of Artemis in the same city (requires Wonders DLC)Book 'em Danno!Find Hawaii in a random map game in the Paradise Found Scenario. (requires Polynesia DLC)Bora! Bora! Bora!Win as Tahiti in the Paradise Found Scenario. (requires Polynesia DLC)Bright-Eyed AthenaWin the Wonders Scenario on Immortal (requires Wonders DLC)By the Waters of BabylonBeat the game on any difficultly setting as Nebuchadnezzar II. (requires Babylon DLC)Charming. Really.Beat the game on the Prince difficulty level.City of GoldDevelop a city to produce more than 100 gold per turn.City of LightsDevelop a city to produce more than 100 culture per turn.City of ScienceDevelop a city to produce more than 100 science per turn.ConnoisseurRate a Mod.Conquest of the WorldAs alexander, defeat every known player by 350 bc.Death Before ShameFully Explore the Honor Policy Track.Diplomacy by Other MeansFully Explore the Autocracy Policy Track.Do you have a little Captain in you?Encounter Captain Cook in the Paradise Found Scenario. (requires Polynesia DLC)Do You Want to Super Size That?Beat the game on a Large Map.Dr. Heidegger's ExperimentFind the Fountain of Youth (requires Spain/Inca DLC)Dragon EmperorWin the Korean Scenario on Emperor (requires Korea DLC)Eighty-Eight Miles per HourFully Explore the Rationalism Policy Track.Emperor Fu ManchuWin the Korean Scenario as Manchu (requires Korea DLC)Empire of the EastBeat the game on any difficulty setting as Ramkhamhaeng.EngineerBuild a Wonder.Enlightened RulerUnlock all Social Policies, across any number of playthroughs.Epic GilgameshWin the Wonders Scenario as Gilgamesh (requires Wonders DLC)ExpansionistDownload a Mod.ExperimenterPlay a game with a Mod.Exterminate! Exterminate!Win a Domination Victory.Far-Shooting ApolloWin the Wonders Scenario on Emperor (requires Wonders DLC)Fear the TurtleWin the Korean Scenario as Korea (requires Korea DLC)Fetchez la Vache!Build a motte and bailey improvement in the Viking Scenario (requires Denmark DLC)First in the Hearts of Your CountrymenBeat the game on any difficulty setting as Washington.First of the MohicansBeat the game on any difficulty setting as Hiawatha.Flawless StrategyBeat the game on the Deity difficulty level.Flying FortressBomb an enemy city with a B-17.Forty-NinerBuild 1000 mines, across any number of playthroughs.Freedom Isn't FreeFully Explore the Freedom Policy Track.From Archaemennid to SafavidAs Darius, start 5 Golden Ages in a single game.Gardens of Lake TexcocoBuild a Floating Garden in a city with a lake tile in its radius.Genghis KhanBeat the Mongol scenario on the Deity difficulty level.Give Peace a ChanceBeat the game on any difficulty setting as Gandhi.Go Boldly Where No Man Has Gone BeforeWin a Space Victory.God Is GreatConstruct 1000 Temples, across any number of playthroughs.Going It Old SchoolBeat the game on a Pangaea-type Map.Gotta Catch 'Em AllBeat the game on all standard map types and sizes.Great KhanBeat the Mongol scenario on the King or harder difficulty level.Grecian FormulaWin the Wonders Scenario as Alexander (requires Wonders DLC)Hands Free to Victory!Beat the game on any difficulty setting as Harald Bluetooth (requires Denmark DLC)Harder, Better, Faster, StrongerUpgrade a Unit.He Threw a Car at My Head!Have any city ransomed by Barbarians.Head and Shoulders Above the RestWin as Samoa in the Paradise Found Scenario. (requires Polynesia DLC)Heads Up!Find Easter Island in a random map game in the Paradise Found Scenario. (requires Polynesia DLC)Here Ends the Noble SavageRaze 100 Barbarian camps, across any number of playthroughs.Honoring the AncestorsWin the Korean Scenario on Deity (requires Korea DLC)Huitzilopochtli's ArrowWin the New World Scenario as the Aztecs. (requires Spain/Inca DLC)I Can Has Nukes?Drop a Nuke on another Civ.I Need More Elbow RoomBeat the game on a Tiny Map.I'm on a Boat!Embark a Unit.Island HoppingBeat the game on an Archipelago-type Map.It satrap!Win the Wonders Scenario as Darius I (requires Wonders DLC)It's Just You and Me, KidBeat the game on a Duel Map.It's Standard IssueBeat the game on a Standard Map.It's Super EffectiveDestroy an enemy unit in just one hit.Kamikaze AttackKill an enemy unit attacking with a Japanese unit with just 1 HP remaining.Khaaan!Run out of time to beat the Mongol scenario.KhanBeat the Mongol scenario on any difficulty.King of the MountainBeat the game on any difficultly setting as Pachacuti. (requires Spain/Inca DLC)Know Thy EnemyConsult the Oracle 2 times in a single game in the Wonders Scenario (requires Wonders DLC)Kublai KhanBeat the Mongol scenario on the Immortal or harder difficulty level.Land BaronPurchase 1000 tiles, across any number of playthroughs.Last Man StandingWin any Multiplayer Match.Law of the Splintered PaddleBeat the game on any difficulty setting as Kamehameha. (requires Polynesia DLC)League of Extraordinary HoyanehsWin the New World Scenario as the Iroquois. (requires Spain/Inca DLC)Living in SmallvilleBeat the game on a Small Map.Lux Perpetua Luceat EisFully Explore the Piety Policy Track.Macho PicchuWin the New World Scenario as the Incas. (requires Spain/Inca DLC)MagellanProve that the world is round by uncovering a connected loop of tiles around the circumference of the world.Marco PoloBe the first to explore and uncover 1000 tiles, across any number of playthroughs.Master of the HouseFully Explore the Tradition Policy Track.Master of the UniverseBeat the game on any difficulty setting with each leader.Merchant KingTrade 100 resources, across any number of playthroughs.Model of a Modern Major-GeneralTrain all Units, across any number of playthroughs.Money Doesn't Grow on TreesFully Explore the Commerce Policy Track.Montezuma's Revenge...Beat the game on any difficulty setting as Montezuma.Moving on UpEarn a Unit Promotion.My Little PonyAs Catherine, research Horseback Riding before any other Civ.Neighborhood BullyAnnex a previously puppetted City State.Ngata ChanceWin as Tonga in the Paradise Found Scenario. (requires Polynesia DLC)Nobody Expects the Spanish InquisitionBeat the game on any difficultly setting as Isabella. (requires Spain/Inca DLC or Gods  Kings expansion)Odin's Chosen WarriorWin as Denmark (any difficulty) in the Viking Scenario (requires Denmark DLC)Odysseus the Great TacticianWin the Wonders Scenario on King (requires Wonders DLC)One to Rule Them AllBeat the game on any difficulty setting with only one city.Panzer "Shafernator" GeneralSpawn over 100 Great Generals, build an army of over 100 standing units, and beat the game 100 times.Party in hattUSAWin the Wonders Scenario as Muwatallis (requires Wonders DLC)Paul BunyanChop down 1000 forest tiles, across any number of playthroughs.Peace and ProsperityBegin a Golden Age.People of the LonghouseBuild a longhouse in a city with at least 4 unchopped forests in its radius.Pillage, Then BurnPillage 9 Farms on the same turn in the Viking Scenario (requires Denmark DLC)Plate TectonicsBeat the game on a Continents-type Map.Purple People EatersWin as Norway (any difficulty) in the Viking Scenario (requires Denmark DLC)Ra's Mighty TruthWin the Wonders Scenario as Ramesses II (requires Wonders DLC)Raleigh's Road to RichesDiscover El Dorado (requires Spain/Inca DLC)Rest in Gold PiecesGain 1000 gold from expended Great People with the Mausoleum of Halicarnassus across any number of playthroughs (requires Wonders DLC)Reverse EngineerGain possession of 3 wonders by conquering cities in a single game in the Wonders Scenario (requires Wonders DLC)Riddle of the SphinxRush a wonder as Egypt with a Great Engineer.Rising SunBeat the game on any difficulty setting as Oda.Ruler of the SeasAs elizabeth, sink and destroy 357 enemy naval units, across any number of playthroughs.Ruler of the Twelve ColoniesBeat the game on a Huge Map.Samurai DelicatessenWin the Korean Scenario as Japan (requires Korea DLC)Say Hello to My Little FriendReach Ally Status with a City State.Searching for the PreciousFind New Zealand in a random map game in the Paradise Found Scenario. (requires Polynesia DLC)Second CityFound a second city.Seoul PowerWin the Korean Scenario before 100 turns as any power (requires Korea DLC)Seriously?!?Have another Civ beat you to completing a Wonder 10 times.Siglo de OroWin the New World Scenario as Spain. (requires Spain/Inca DLC)Star of the NorthBeat the game on any difficulty setting as Catherine.Sun Tzu's Art of WarAs Wu Zetian, earn a Great General through battle.Supreme KhanBeat the Mongol scenario on the Emperor or harder difficulty level.Surviving DomesdayWin the Viking Scenario on Immortal (requires Denmark DLC)Surviving RagnarokWin the Viking Scenario on Deity (requires Denmark DLC)Surviving the MarquesasWin as Hiva in the Paradise Found Scenario. (requires Polynesia DLC)Taekwon-DOH!Lose the Korean Scenario as Korea (requires Korea DLC)Taking off the Training WheelsBeat the game on the Chieftain difficulty level.Tea and Crumpets for EveryoneWin the New World Scenario as England. (requires Spain/Inca DLC)Team PlayerFully Explore the Patronage Policy Track.The African KingBeat the game on any difficulty setting as Askia.The AlexmanBeat the game on the Warlord difficulty level.The Appian WayBuild 1000 roads, across any number of playthroughs.The Best State of a RepublicWin a Cultural Victory.The Choson OneWin a game as Korea (requires Korea DLC)The ExplorerDiscover 100 natural wonders.The Golden HordeBeat the game on any difficultly setting as Genghis Khan.The Golden PathBeat the game on the Emperor difficulty level.The Man Who Would Be KingBeat the game on any difficulty setting as Alexander.The Once and Future KingBeat the game on the King difficulty level.The Pen is MightierWin a Diplomatic Victory.The Wonder YearsBuild all the Wonders, across any number of playthroughs.The World Is a Mess, and I Just Need to Rule ItBeat the game on the Immortal difficulty level.This isn't KansasFind Australia in a South Pacific map game in the Paradise Found Scenario. (requires Polynesia DLC)This was their Finest HourWin as Anglo-Saxon England (any difficulty) in the Viking Scenario (requires Denmark DLC)Thoughtful TelemachusWin the Wonders Scenario on Prince (requires Wonders DLC)Three MusketeersKill a unit with a French Musketeer when two other Musketeers are providing flanking bonuses.Time to Stitch a TapestryWin as Normandy (any difficulty) in the Viking Scenario (requires Denmark DLC)To Stand the Test of TimeBeat the game with all victory conditions.Tomb RaiderPillage gold from an Egyptian city with a burial tomb in it.Tout le Monde Francophone?Win the New World Scenario as France. (requires Spain/Inca DLC)Treasure HunterDiscover an ancient ruin.Turtle PowerSink an Ironclad with a Turtle Boat (requires Korea DLC)Two Men Enter, One Man LeaveCompletely defeat another Civ and remove them from the game.Veni, Vidi, ViciBeat the game on any difficulty setting as Caesar.Video et TaceoBeat the game on any difficulty setting as Elizabeth.Vivre La RevolutionBeat the game on any difficulty setting as Napoleon.War Canoe AttackAs askia, conquer a city on another continent.We Have the TechnologyFully explore the Tech Tree.Where's the Biathlon?Enter a snow tile with the Norwegian ski infantry in the Viking Scenario (requires Denmark DLC)With an Iron FistFully Explore the Order Policy Track.With Liberty and Justice for AllFully Explore the Liberty Policy Track.WonderwallBuild 3 wonders in the same city in the Wonders Scenario (requires Wonders DLC)You The ConquerorWin the Viking Scenario on Emperor (requires Denmark DLC)Yow Ming!Win the Korean Scenario as China (requires Korea DLC)ZeupiterAs Rome, conquer a city with the Statue of Zeus (requires Wonders DLC)System RequirementsPC MinimumPC RecommendedOperating System: Windows® XP SP3/ Windows® Vista SP2/ Windows® 7Processor: Dual Core CPUMemory: 2GB RAMHard Disk Space: 8 GB FreeDVD-ROM Drive: Required for disc-based installationVideo Card: 256 MB ATI HD2600 XT or better, 256 MB nVidia 7900 GS or better, or Core i3 or better integrated graphicsSound Card: DirectX 9.0c-compatible sound cardDirectX®: DirectX® version 9.0cOperating System: Windows® Vista SP2/ Windows® 7Processor: 1.8 GHz Quad Core CPUMemory: 4 GB RAMHard Disk Space: 8 GB FreeDVD-ROM Drive: Required for disc-based installationVideo Card: 512 MB ATI 4800 series or better, 512 MB nVidia 9800 series or betterSound Card: DirectX 9.0c-compatible sound cardDirectX®: DirectX® version 10 or 11Mac MinimumOperating System: 10.6.4 (Snow Leopard)CPU Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo (Dual-Core)CPU Speed: 2.4 GHzMemory: 2 GB RAMHard Disk Space: 8 GBVideo Card (ATI): Radeon HD2600Video Card (NVidia): Geforce 8600Video Memory (VRam): 256 MBMedia Required: DVD-ROM (Physical, boxed copies only)Useful LinksCivilization V HomepageCivilization V Digital Manual</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12379">Sid Meier's Alpha Centauri</game><game id="21592">Galactic Civilizations II: Twilight of the Arnor</game><game id="21663">Galactic Civilizations II: Dark Avatar</game><game id="19549">Freeciv</game><game id="30640">Patrician IV</game><game id="7419">Master of Orion 3</game><game id="14956">Master of Orion II: Battle at Antares</game><game id="11342">Master of Orion</game><game id="32963">Balance of Power: 21st Century</game><game id="19887">Rome: Total War</game><game id="33464">Fate of the World</game><game id="31531">Total War: Shogun 2</game><game id="5646">The Corporate Machine</game><game id="35071">8 Realms</game><game id="7281">Astonishia Story</game><game id="37248">Warlock: Master of the Arcane</game><game id="38447">Nobunaga's Ambition</game><game id="39681">Neo Scavenger</game><game id="6210">Populous</game><game id="374">RISK: The Game of Global Domination</game><game id="41503">Age of Wonders III</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1777728-box_civ5.png</image></root>