<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30064</id><name>Virtua Fighter 5 Final Showdown</name><description>OverviewVirtua Fighter 5: Final Showdown is a 3D fighting game developed by SEGA-AM2 and released by Sega for Japanese arcades on July 29, 2010. The second major revision of Virtua Fighter 5 (following Virtua Fighter 5 R), Virtua Fighter 5: Final Showdown brings more customizable costumes, new and improved arenas, a new soundtrack, and various gameplay tweaks. It was released worldwide as a downloadable title for the PlayStation 3 (via PlayStation Network) on June 5, 2012 and Xbox 360 (via Xbox Live Arcade) on June 6, 2012.StoryAll of the sought after invitations for the Fifth World Fighting Tournament have been sent and now the 19 best fighters in the world begin their final phases of preparation. They must learn from their prior mistakes and perfect every aspect of their mind, body, and soul - for there is no room for mistakes in this competition. Little do they know that J6, the organization funding the tournament, has sinister ulterior motives for the contest and the company's top secret Dural program is already well underway. In the organization's quest for world domination, the scientists at J6 are creating the ultimate fighting machine with human features. Their first model was defeated in the Fourth World Fighting Tournament, which drove them to kidnap Vanessa. She was able to escape with the help of an insider, but not before they captured her combat data and transferred it to the new advanced Dural model named V-Dural.J6 is determined to find out who the inside traitor is that released Vanessa and more importantly, if V-Dural is indeed ready to defeat the world's best fighters. The Fifth World Fighting Tournament will reveal both - let it begin.[taken from the manual to Virtua Fighter 5]CharactersCharacterFirst AppearanceFighting StyleStoryAkira YukiVF1Bajiquan (Hakkyoku-ken)Despite strong performances in previous tournaments, Akira still seeks to earn the approval of his ever-critical grandfather.Aoi UmenokoujiVF3Aikido (Aiki Ju-jutsu)Akira's childhood friend who seeks to reconnect with him, and find out the truth behind Brad's advances.Brad BurnsVF4: EvoMuay ThaiA rich Italian playboy who entered the tournament to prove his skills and to hit on the female competitors.EileenVF5Monkey Kung Fu (Kou-ken)A young girl who entered the tournament to meet Pai Chan.El BlazeVF5Lucha LibreA masked luchador who seeks to beat Wolf in a match to prove he can defeat heavyweight wrestlers as easily as lightweight ones.Goh HinogamiVF4: EvoJudoAn assassin sent by J6 to destroy Akira among others in the tournament. Having failed his first attempt, he seeks to complete his job this time.Jacky BryantVF1Jeet Kune DoHaving fully recovered from his accident and rescuing his sister, Jacky now seeks to confront the mysterious J6 organization behind everything.Jean KujoVF5: RKarateAfter Goh's failure, J6 sent Jean to finish the job. Jean is especially interested in killing Lion, without remembering their childhood friendship together.Jeffry McWildVF1PankratiumEntered the previous tournaments to earn enough money to find and catch the mysterious "Satan Shark," only to discover that J6 has captured the shark for some unknown purpose. Entered now to find out why J6 wants his shark.Kage-MaruVF1Hagakure-ryu Ju-jutsuThe tenth generation "Kage-Maru" ninja from the Hagakure village. His mother was kidnapped, experimented on and turned into the cyborg known as Dural by J6. She then burned down Hagakure and killed everyone there as Dural. Kage entered the tournament to free her and destroy J6.Lau ChanVF1Tiger Swallow Fist (Koen-ken)A master martial-artist and talented chef, Lau has been suffering from an incurable disease as he seeks an apprentice to pass on his style. Unfortunately, his last student nearly killed him, so Lau has decided to seek out Pai before his death.Lei-FeiVF4Shaolin Kung FuA Shaolin monk from a long-forgotten order in China that sought to destroy other martial artists. Lei-Fei entered the tournament to learn Lau's Koen-ken and then kill him with it. Unfortunately, Lei-Fei was too impatient and Lau escaped his grasp. He enters the tournament to face him again in a final showdown.Lion RafaleVF2Praying Mantis Kung FuThe son of a powerful French arms dealer, Lion seeks to win freedom from his father in the tournament.Pai ChanVF1Mizongquan (Ensei-ken)A Hong Kong action film star, Pai Chan blames her father Lau for her mother's death. However, her anger has cooled over time and she even managed to save him from Lei-Fei during the last tournament. She now enters to make amends with her father.Sarah BryantVF1Martial ArtsBrainwashed by J6 to kill her brother Jacky. She managed to break free with her brother's help, and has re-entered the tournament to save her friend Vanessa.Shun DiVF2Drunken Fist (Zui Quan)A drunken kung-fu master from northern China who joined the second tournament on a lark, but continued returning when he found that one of his students was being held captive by J6Taka-ArashiVF3Sumo WrestlingA hot-blooded sumo wrestler yokozuna who seeks to prove his strength to the whole world.Vanessa LewisVF4Vale TudoWhen she was a child, Vanessa's parents were killed and J6 kidnapped her to train her into a soldier for them. She was rescued by another soldier named Lewis, but Lewis was later killed by J6. Vanessa enters to protect Sarah and find Lewis's killer, but her body was used to make a new version of Dural called V-Dural.Wolf HawkfieldVF1Pro WrestlingA powerful woodsman and hunter from the wilds of Canada who was scouted by a sports agent, Wolf soon became a famous pro wrestler. He enters the tournament to find the truth behind strange visions of a world in flames that haunt his dreams.DuralVF1??????At first Dural was a cyborg version of Kage's mother, herself a kunoichi from his village. At the end of the third tournament, Kage managed to free his mother, but she needed more cyborg technology just to stay alive. J6 simply kidnapped Vanessa and used her for an upgraded Dural model. Even though she escaped, they acquired enough data to create the V-Dural, and now seek to use this tournament to test its capabilities.GameplayGameplay ModesSingle PlayerArcadeScore AttackLicense ChallengeSpecial ChallengeDojoPracticeCommand TrainingFree TrainingOnlineRanked MatchPlayer MatchRoom MatchThe game contains multiple single-player modes that allow a player to test his mettle against AI opponents. There is arcade mode, which lets a player run through a gauntlet of enemies until eventually fighting the evil Dural in a bonus stage. There is a variant called Score Attack, which tests the player's ability to clear one of three selected sets of AI enemies both quickly and brutally.There is a license challenge mode, which challenges players to not only win the match, but clear a certain condition first while they fight. Conditions can range from simply "win the match" to "prevent enemy from dodging 7 attacks." After fighting through a set of five enemies, players upgrade their "license." Finally, for those who have all the DLC, there is a special challenge mode unlocked. Like the "Shadow Battles" from MvC3, these fights pit the player against a set of customized enemies, and the player must beat them all one-on-one to clear the set.The "Dojo" allows players to practice their moves with any character on any stage against either a human or AI opponent. Normal training mode lets them practice for as long as they want. Command Training allows the player to run through the command list of any one character to find the one that suits them. And free sparring removes all of the excess HUD except for a simple health bar and a box showing damage and frame data, useful for plotting your own combos and techniques.As for online, players have the option of jumping into a game immediately in either Ranked Matches or unranked Player Matches. Players with DLC can also take their customized character online, but those without DLC can still play against normal-looking opponents. In ranked matches, a loss nets the player 1-2 points while a win nets 4 points. Also, each player is ranked in a martial arts-styled ranking system, letting them progress from 10th Kyu to 1 Kyu, then 1 Dan to 10 Dan, and then a special ranking if they clear 10th Dan depending on their win %. To discourage any intentional disconnecting or gaming of the W/L system, the only things noticeable during ranked match selection are the rank, number of games played, rank points, and likelihood of disconnection.The game also offers Room Match mode, where rooms of up to 8 players (including host) can either spectate or pick their preference for the 1P or 2P slot. Before each match, the top players to pick the 1P and 2P slots on the list in the room after a 30 second timer has passed will be the ones to battle each other. The loser will be sent to the bottom of the list, but the lowest member can still technically play if no one above decides to enter.Changes from Virtua Fighter 5 RCertain evasive maneuvers (such as dodges and back dashes) are riskier (as counter-attacks against these maneuver deal more damage) but more rewarding (such as successful dodges always granting side-attacks and successful back-dashes moving faster).Throws are now restricted to three groups: joystick towards, joystick away, and joystick neutral. This gives a 1/3 chance of a throw escape command succeeding (either P+G, towards P+G, or away P+G).Knocking an opponent into destructible walls only destroys the wall during or after a K.O., instead of randomly during the round.Faster jump speed.Downloadable Content (DLC)SEGA released several packs of content that allows the player to customize their character with a wide variety of different costume pieces that can be accessed and modified through the "Terminal" menu. Players who wish to buy custom packs for an individual character must pay $5 (400 MSP) to be able to customize their respective character. Alternatively, players can buy up to two "Customization Pack Bundles" that contain costume pieces for 9 or 10 characters (respectively) at $15 (1200 MSP) each.The costume pieces themselves have no good or bad side effects in game, though some of them can trigger a new end-game victory celebration at random if the character wins.If the player without the custom packs plays someone who has them, then the characters will only be seen through their default costume.If the player has all custom packs, then Special Challenge mode is unlocked in the single-player menu (see Gameplay).</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20689">Tekken 6</game><game id="7792">Dead or Alive 4</game><game id="36412">Dead or Alive 5</game><game id="32716">Tekken Tag Tournament 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2213192-box_vf5fs.png</image></root>