<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30063</id><name>Mobile Suit Gundam Extreme VS.</name><description>OverviewMobile Suit Gundam: Extreme VS. is the eighth game in the Gundam VS series. It is the first HD entry in the franchise, running on Namco's PS3-based System 357 arcade board (the same board used by Tekken 6).Gameplay ChangesExtreme Burst works similarly to the Awaken systems of earlier games in the series: after the EX gauge is filled, the player can press ABC to activate a power-up for a limited time. Additionally, NEXT Dash (now Extreme Action) can no longer cancel melee. The ability to call a Mobile Assist is now character-specific. A new cost tier, 2500, has been added.Featured MSMobile Suit GundamGundam ( Amuro Ray) - 2000Char Custom Gelgoog ( Char Aznable) - 2000Zeong ( Char Aznable ) - 2000Acguy (Akahana) - 1000Mobile Suit Gundam MS Igloo [NEW]Zudah (Jean-Luc Duvall) - 1000Hildolfr (Demeziere Sonnen) - 1000Mobile Suit Gundam: The 08th MS TeamGundam Ez-8 ( Shiro Amada) - 1000Gouf Custom (Norris Packard) - 1000Mobile Suit Gundam Side Story: The Blue DestinyBlue Destiny Unit-1 ( Yuu Kajima) - 2000Mobile Suit Gundam 0080: War in the PocketZaku Kai (Bernard Wiseman) - 1000Gundam Alex ( Christina Mackenzie) - 1000Mobile Suit Gundam 0083: Stardust MemoryGP-01Fb Zephyranthes Full Vernian ( Kou Uraki) - 2000GP-02 Physalis (Anavel Gato) - 2000Mobile Suit Zeta GundamZeta Gundam ( Kamille Bidan) - 2500The O ( Paptimus Scirocco ) - 2500Hyaku Shiki ( Quattro Bajeena) - 2000Messala ( Paptimus Scirocco) - 2000Mobile Suit Gundam ZZFull Armor ZZ Gundam ( Judau Ashta) - 2500Quebeley ( Haman Karn) - 2500Quebeley Mk.II Red ( Puru Two) - 1000Mobile Suit Gundam: Char's CounterattackNu Gundam ( Amuro Ray) - 3000Sazabi ( Char Aznable) - 2500Mobile Suit Gundam: Char's Counterattack - Beltorchika's Children [NEW]Hi-Nu Gundam ( Amuro Ray) - 3000Mobile Suit Gundam UnicornUnicorn Gundam ( Banagher Links) - 3000Kshatriya ( Marida Cruz) - 2500Sinanju ( Full Frontal) - 2500Delta Plus (Riddhe Marcenas) - 2000Mobile Suit Gundam F91Gundam F91 ( Seabook Arno) - 2000Berga Giros (Zabine Chareux) - 1000Mobile Suit Crossbone Gundam [NEW]Crossbone Gundam X-1 Kai ( Kincaid Nau) - 2500Crossbone Gundam X-2 Kai (Zabine Chareux) - 2500Mobile Suit Crossbone Gundam Steel Seven [New]Crossbone Gundam X-1 Full Cloth ( Tobia Arronax) - 3000Mobile Suit Victory GundamV2 Gundam ( Uso Ewin) - 3000Gottrlatan ( Katejina Loos ) - 2500Gun-EZ (Junko Jenko) - 1000Mobile Fighter G GundamGod Gundam ( Domon Kasshu) - 2500Dragon Gundam (Sai Saichi) - 2000Master Gundam ( Master Asia) - 3000New Mobile Report Gundam Wing: Endless WaltzWing Gundam Zero Custom ( Heero Yuy) - 3000Gundam Heavyarms Custom ( Trowa Barton) - 2000Gundam Deathscythe Hell ( Duo Maxwell) - 2500Tallgeese III ( Milliardo Peacecraft) - 2500After War Gundam XGundam Double X ( Garrod Ran) - 3000Gundam Virsago Chest Break (Shagia Frost) - 2000Turn A GundamTurn A Gundam ( Loran Cehack) - 3000Turn X ( Gym Ghingnham) - 3000Gold Sumo (Harry Ord) - 2000Mobile Suit Gundam SEEDStrike Gundam ( Kira Yamato) - 2000Providence Gundam ( Rau Le Creuset) - 2000LaGOWE (Andrew Waltfeld) - 1000Forbidden Gundam (Shani Andras) - 2000Mobile Suit Gundam SEED Astray [NEW]Astray Red Frame ( Lowe Gear) - 2000Astray Blue Frame Second L (Gai Murakumo) - 2000Mobile Suit Gundam SEED DestinyGunner ZAKU Warrior ( Lunamaria Hawke) - 2000Strike Freedom Gundam ( Kira Yamato) - 3000Infinite Justice Gundam ( Athrun Zala) - 2500Destiny Gundam ( Shinn Asuka) - 3000Mobile Suit Gundam 00Gundam Exia ( Setsuna F. Seiei) - 200000 Gundam ( Setsuna F. Seiei) - 3000Gundam Dynames ( Lockon Stratos) - 2000Cherudim Gundam ( Lockon Stratos) - 2500Arche Gundam ( Ali Al-Saachez) - 2500Susanowo ( Mr. Bushido) - 2000Mobile Suit Gundam 00 - A Wakening of the Trailblazer [NEW]00 Quan[T] ( Setsuna F. Seiei) -3000Raphael Gundam ( Tieria Erde) - 2500</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/16207/1275397-image37.png</image></root>