<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3007</id><name>R-Type Delta</name><description>Introduction R-Type Delta is a shooter game for the          PlayStation released in 1998 by         Irem Software Engineering. It is the fourth installment in the        R-Type series and the first to make use of full 3D graphics. Other innovations include a variety of selectable fighters and the Delta Weapon.Fighters The game features three different fighters, including an unlockable fourth fighter. R-9A Delta R-9A DeltaCharged shot: Wave CannonBurst shot: Diffuse Wave CannonForce: StandardDelta weapon: Nuclear Catastrophe  R-X Albatross  R-X AlbatrossCharged shot: Burst Shock Wave CannonBurst shot: High Compression Wave CannonForce: TentacleDelta weapon: Negative Corridor  R-13 Cerberus  R-13 Cerberus Charged shot: Lightning Shock Wave CannonBurst shot: Over LightningForce: AnchorDelta weapon: Hysteric Dawn   Pow Armor Unlockable FighterForce:      BydoDelta weapon: Bydic Dance  Delta Weapon Dose Delta Weapon    Dose is built up gradually when the Force device comes in contact with an enemy or enemy fire.  Dose Break When the Dose meter reaches its maximum, the Force reaches a condition called Overdose, which both raises the player's score and enables the invocation of the Delta Weapon.Delta Weapon This weapon can be fired while in Overdose mode. It drains the Force device of its Dose, doing critical damage to all enemies on the screen in the process.Stages There are a total of seven stages in R-Type Delta, numbered in the game as 1st Contact,  2nd Contact, etc.1st Contact "Lethal Weapon" (狂機) 1st ContactBoss: Moritz G  An unnamed Asian city, likely Japanese. One of the mid-bosses for this stage appears almost immediately, but its laser fires only in a straight line, making it not that great a threat.  2nd Contact "Deformation" (異形) 2nd Contact Boss: Dust Nate Cocoon, Dust Nate Worm A flooded energy reactor. This stage crawls with organic types of Bydo. The background music changes when the player submerges in or surfaces from the water.  3rd Contact "Gigantic Attack" (巨襲) 3rd ContactBoss: Geitz A military base in the snow-capped mountains. In this level, rather than a giant space ship, the enormous four-legged Geitz chases from behind. The player has to fly through the space between its legs and finally assault the core at its top.  4th Contact "Invasion" (侵食)4th ContactBoss: Q.T. Cat  Set in the space fortress Aegis in orbit of planet earth, this stage scrolls upward. In the latter half of the stage, the player has to navigate a maze of moving pillars. Also, inside the boss, Q.T. Cat, is the first generation R-9. 5th Contact "Evil" (邪悪)5th Contact Boss: Gondolan, Gommander, Green Inferno The interior of some mysterious organism. Throughout the stage, enemies from earlier se ries appear, and bosses from the original appear in succession. Later in the level, the player faces a difficult battle inside a spinning pipe. All sections of the stage are based on the original game. 6th Contact "Awakening" (覚醒) 6th Contact Boss: R-9, Patrol Spinners (2),       Dobkeratops  The headquarters of the R-fighter development project has suffered a fiece Bydo attack. Half-way through the level, the player's skills are again challenged as a Nozari creeps up from behind and other enemies rain down from above. The bosses included the infested R-9 and a resurrected Dobkeratops.  Last Contact "Life" (生命)Last ContactBoss: Bydo CoreAn alternate dimension created by the Bydo Core. Human architecture and genetics are the theme of this stage. Once the membrane of the Bydo Core is destroyed, the Core steals the player's Force device, however it can be defeated using the Delta Weapon. Part of this stage makes another appearance as a hidden level in R-Type Final.    Playstation NetworkThe game is available on the American Playstation Store for $5.99.</description><genres><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="119">Söldner-X: Himmelsstürmer</game><game id="21799">Blazing Star</game><game id="13960">Life Force</game><game id="5536">Defender</game><game id="15508">Gradius</game><game id="3623">Gradius II</game><game id="10201">Gradius V</game><game id="12069">Ikaruga</game><game id="20772">Omega Five</game><game id="7617">Gradius III</game><game id="13714">Last Resort</game><game id="5412">Darius+</game><game id="15999">Darius Twin</game><game id="22600">Homura</game><game id="11627">Lightening Force: Quest for the Darkstar</game><game id="11684">Contra: Shattered Soldier</game><game id="19750">R-Type II</game><game id="23462">Gradius Gaiden</game><game id="30856">Dorapan</game><game id="28120">Söldner-X 2: Final Prototype</game><game id="32758">Gaia Seed</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2303992-box_rtyped.png</image></root>