<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30105</id><name>Batman: The Brave and the Bold: The Videogame</name><description>OverviewBatman: The Brave and the Bold - The Videogame is a 2D side-scrolling action-adventure game developed by WayForward and published by WB Games for the Wii and Nintendo DS on September 7, 2010. Based on the Batman: The Brave and the Bold animated television series, players team up as either Batman or one of his trusty superhero allies (which differ depending on the chapter being played) to foil the plans of a series of supervillains. Each playable character has a series of upgradable gadgets and a superhero assist attack (known as "Jump-In" characters, which must be chosen prior to the level from a group of unlockable heroes, including Black Canary, Booster Gold, Aquaman, Black Lightning, Red Tornado, The Flash, Green Arrow, Plastic Man, Captain Marvel, Green Lantern and Proto Bot). Players with the Nintendo DS version can join in with players with the Nintendo Wii version as Bat-Mite, where they move around with the touchscreen and drop objects on enemies (sometimes dropping health for the players).Each of the game's unrelated chapters are split into "episodes", structured in the same fashion as the animated series (an "introduction" level, prior to an animated opening sequence, and ten main adventure levels):The Case of the Siamese Diamond! - Location: Gotham City. Teammate: Robin. Introduction Villain: Two-Face. Main Villains: Catman, Catwoman.Monkey Think, Robot Do! - Location: Science Island. Teammate: Blue Beetle. Introduction Villain: Copperhead. Main Villain: Gorilla Grodd.Over the Underworld! - Location: London, England. Teammate: Hawkman. Introduction Villain: Clock King. Main Villains: Gentleman Ghost, Astaroth.Green with Anger! - Location: Outer Space. Teammate: Green Lantern. Introduction Villains: Captain Cold, Heat Wave, Weather Wizard. Main Villains: Mongul, Starro.GameplayThe game takes a casual approach to beat-em-up. You can play every level as Batman or switch and play as his partner. Batman is joined by a different DC hero every level which opens up 2 player co-op and 3 player co-op if another person has a DS version of the game, at which point this person plays as Bat-MiteThe game lets you kick, punch and use gadgets on enemies. Batman can also summon a DC character, which you select at the beginning of every level, to inflict additional damage on his foes. Batman also has special attacks that take up the entire screen and kill all enemies. The gameplay also involves some platforming where you can use the Batgrapple to swing from ledge to ledge in the search of finding hidden collectibles.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="32156">Green Lantern: Rise of the Manhunters</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2303968-box_btbatbtvg.png</image></root>