<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30373</id><name>Sam &amp; Max Episode 304: Beyond the Alley of the Dolls</name><description>StoryCrazy as everFollowing the events of They Stole Max's Brain, Sam and Max lose the Devil's Toybox and flee into Stinky's Diner. They discover another secret tunnel inside that leads them to a room filled with cloning equipment used to make the clones of Sam. They find Momma Bosco's ghost and she tells them if they can get her a new body, she can take control of the clones.Sam and Max then visit Anton Papierwaite's office and find the weaken elder god Yog-Soggoth. He tells them where to find the Cthonic Destroyer, a Toy o Power which will let them get rid of thing from the Dark Dimension and let them use the cloning machine. He also warns them that if they gather the Toys of Power and the Devil's Toybox in the same place, it could weaken the fabric of reality and let his grandson Junior into the world and wreak havoc.Sam and Max retrieve the Cthonic Destroyer and make a new body for Momma Bosco. She seizes control of the clones and order them to find their master. Sam and Max follow the clones to the docks and enter a building where the Devil's Toybox is being held. Max gets out Charlie Ho-Tep but discoveres that Charlie is actually alive and the one controlling the clones. He captures Sam and Max and takes the Toys of Power.Now at the Statue of Liberty, Charlie is going ahead with his plan to summon Junior so they can play together again. Norrington distracts Charlie by pointing out that Junior actually hates Charlie, and this lets Sam change Charlie's piano music (which was keeping everyone captive) and allows Max to climb up and save them.Just as Charlie is about to complete the ritual, Yog-Soggoth appears and, with the last bit of his energy, fully unlocks Max's psychic powers so he can use them without the toys. He tricks Charlie into blasting the Devil's Toybox, halting the summoning and destroying everything around from the Dark Dimension, including Charlie. Max falls and lands on the Liberty's torch (the previous focus of the ritual) and accidentally eats the demon seed left there. Max begins to undergo a transformation and becomes a hulking monstrosity. He begins marching towards the City while Sam watches....PC System Requirements:Operating system:Windows XP / Vista / Windows 7Processor:2.0 GHz (3 GHz Pentium 4 or equivalent rec.)Memory: 1GBSound: DirectX 8.1 sound device Video:128MB DirectX 8.1-compliant video card(256MB rec.) DirectX(TM): Version 9.0c or betterMac System Requirements:Operating Systems: Mac OS X 10.5 or newerProcessor: Intel Core 2 Duo processorNot Recommended For:Macs with integrated graphics</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26778">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 3: Lair of the Leviathan</game><game id="21670">Wallace &amp; Gromit's Grand Adventures Episode 1: Fright of the Bumblebees</game><game id="25467">Wallace &amp; Gromit's Grand Adventures Episode 2: The Last Resort</game><game id="25468">Wallace &amp; Gromit's Grand Adventures Episode 3: Muzzled</game><game id="25469">Wallace &amp; Gromit's Grand Adventures Episode 4: The Bogey Man</game><game id="10528">Monkey Island 2:  LeChuck's Revenge</game><game id="3019">The Secret of Monkey Island</game><game id="26776">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 1: Launch of the Screaming Narwhal</game><game id="26777">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 2: The Siege of Spinner Cay</game><game id="26779">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 4: The Trial and Execution of Guybrush Threepwood</game><game id="26780">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 5: Rise of the Pirate God</game><game id="10505">Bone: The Great Cow Race</game><game id="10837">Bone: Out from Boneville</game><game id="20587">Strong Bad's Cool Game for Attractive People Episode 1: Homestar Ruiner</game><game id="23066">Strong Bad's Cool Game for Attractive People Episode 2: Strong Badia The Free</game><game id="24203">Strong Bad's Cool Game for Attractive People Episode 4: Dangeresque 3: The Criminal Projective</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8169/1444951-episode4.jpg</image></root>