<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30381</id><name>I'm Not Alone</name><description>Story I'm Not Alone's  story, centers around Patrick Weber, an exorcist who possesses the ability to see into the daemon world, where he can see restless spirits and hostile presences. The title comes from the fact that this ability has left him painfully aware of the fact that he is "never alone". Patrick is called to a mansion in the Austrian mountains by its new owner, an elderly woman named Caroline, to free said mansion of demons, ghouls, and all things scary. The house was originally owned by a musician named Lilian Von Gruber, who was infamous for murdering dozens of people, including all of his servants and staff, before mysteriously disappearing. Now, the house is haunted, and Caroline has been cursed to be unable to leave the premises, fearing for her life from the numerous monsters and demons. As can be expected, these demons are none too pleased to have an exorcist in their home, and so Patrick must use his abilities to rid the mansions of all things evil. The player can use his psychic powers so that Patrick can see the daemon world, allowing him to fight the demons using a pair of magical daggers and a crossbow that fires two kinds of magical bolts.  A journal found early in the game describes von Gruber's descent into madness after the death of his mother, whom he was obsessed with. In an attempt to resurrect her, he became a priest of the demon lord              Baphomet, murdering innocent people as sacrifices to the demon. However, even after the dozens of murders required to appease him, Baphomet betrayed the human and while Von Gruber's mother's  body was reanimated, her  soul remained in the afterlife. Instead, Thamiel, a powerful demon minion of Baphomet's, was allowed to possess the old woman's corpse, intending to destroy the world through her new avatar. However, the journal ends with Von Gruber believing that he is himself becoming possessed by the demon, and regretting all his evil deeds.  At the end of the game, Patrick kills all the reanimated servants (along  with a few hundred Crawlers), unlocks the many, many puzzle seals, and  confronts and defeats Von Gruber, who is horribly mutated into a  tentacled thing. However, after the boss fight, Von Gruber reveals the  truth: the seals and guardians he placed around himself weren't placed  there to protect evil from the righteous, they were placed there to  protect the world from evil. After his mother's body was possessed by  Thamiel, he attacked it, and was accidentally possessed by half the  demon's power. Although this cost him his humanity, it also left  Thamiel, still in his mother's body, without enough power to destroy the  world. Von Gruber used his new found power to seal the demon inside his  home, and himself inside a tomb, sealed by a series of elaborate puzzle  locks and protected by the reanimated corpses of his unfortunate  victims. He reveals that his mother was Caroline, and that the old woman  who hired Patrick was in fact Thamiel in Caroline's body, hoping that  Patrick would kill Von Gruber, returning Thamiel's power to her, making  her strong enough to finally carry out her mission for Baphomet and  bring about the end of humanity. After this, Von Gruber slips through  what appears to be a portal to            Hell.  Patrick is then attacked by Thamiel, who thanks him for his services  and makes a super villain monologue, and after a long battle, Patrick  defeats Thamiel, who is pulled into hell by one of Von Gruber's  tentacles. The game's ending then depicts Patrick wishing he had a  cigarette before he too is apparently killed by a tentacle.     WeaponsPatrick has access to exactly two types of weapons: a pair of daggers and a crossbow.  The two daggers have two different magical effects. The SOLVE dagger (the one bound to the left mouse button) refills Patrick's health with every successful attack on a monster. The COAGULA dagger (the right mouse button) fills up a "Panic Bar" with each attack, which, when full, triggers "Over Panic" mode. In Over Panic mode, Patrick's attacks become stronger and more precise. The combat tutorial also states that "When the Over Panic Bar lights up, you will be able to launch a double power attack", whatever that means. Both daggers deal the same amount of damage to the enemy. The crossbow is Patrick's ranged weapon, and does more damage than the daggers, at the cost of being slower to attack. The crossbow can fire SOLVE bolts and COAGULA bolts at any time, despite there clearly being only one bolt loaded in at any given time, and just like the daggers, they refill Patrick's health and fill up his Panic Bar, respectively. There is no ammunition so Patrick never runs out of bolts. EnemiesAll of Von Gruber's many victims have been reanimated as monsters that Patrick must face in his struggle against evil. The majority of them are  Crawlers, the murdered spirits of young men who actually do not crawl, instead sort of shuffling towards Patrick before trying a melee attack, that is unless he kills them first with his powerful crossbow. Crawlers come in three flavors: small, big (which act identically to small ones except for having more health and dealing more damage) and a third variety which looks like the small ones but have a ranged attack.  Another variety are  Virgins, the spirits of innocent virgins drowned in the backyard swamps by Von Gruber as part of his dark ritual. They also walk up to you and use a melee attack. The females have a unique model, but the males are essentially small Crawlers with different sound effects.  Other than Crawlers and Virgins, Von Gruber's many murdered servants have been reincarnated as bosses, such as a pair of twin maids armed with steak knives, a butcher armed with a large cleaver, and a gardener armed with a scythe. </description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20475">Alone in the Dark</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/176/1415884-im_not_alone_box.jpg</image></root>