<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30389</id><name>Nexuiz</name><description>OverviewNexuiz (not to be confused with the freeware title of the same name) is an arena-based first-person shooter developed by Illfonic and published by THQ for the Xbox 360 (via Xbox Live Arcade on February 29, 2012), and the PC (via Steam on May 3, 2012). A PS3 version was originally announced, but was delayed and is unlikely to ever be released since THQ's closure. Made partially by some of the original Nexuiz team, this game is restructured with the CryEngine 3, including 4v4 Team Deathmatch and Capture The Flag twitch combat set in futuristic Victorian-influenced alien battlefields.The game introduces the concept of "Dynamic Mutators", which temporarily alter the gameplay rules (from over 100 different rules, such as lowering the gravity, giving the team a full arsenal, and giving everybody jetpacks) by either collecting a special power-up scattered around maps, getting a killing spree, or capturing the enemy flag.The lore of Nexuiz involves a fragile truce between the red-armored Kavussari and the blue-armored Forsellians, in which their combat turns from a centuries-old war to a never-ending arena spectacle (The Nexuiz Competition).The 360 version never saw any updates, but the PC version got additional maps, game modes (such as classic deathmatch) and support for Steam Workshop for user created content after launch. The player cap was also increased from 16 to 32, and an alternate client, titled Nexuiz Stupid Mode was released, allowing for much higher quality shaders and other graphical effects, at the cost of performance - primarily meant for benchmarking and screenshots. Due to THQ's bankruptcy, the game servers for the Xbox 360 version of Nexuiz was discontinued (and the game delisted from the Xbox Live Marketplace) on February 27, 2013.Illfonic originally stated that the PC version wouldn't be affected by THQ's closure, as Illfonic hosted the PC servers themselves, but a few weeks later the master server for the PC version, as well as the nexuiz.com website, disappeared without notice. The game remains playable online using the LAN mode (but without matchmaking, the built in server browser or player rankings).WeaponsThere are nine weapons to use in Nexuiz, each with their own primary and secondary attacks. Headshots using these attacks deal massive damage. Players can also melee enemies with any weapon, dealing heavy damage (instantly killing them when smacking them from beind).Certain mutators grant a "super" version of the weapon, giving them enhanced attacking properties and infinite ammo (as long as the mutator is still in play). Once the mutator is over, the weapon turns back into its normal form.Shotgun(Weapon switch key: 1) Each player's starting weapon with infinite ammo. Each faction has their own unique shotgun appearance (though these shotguns do not differ in functionality).The Super Shotgun vastly increases the rate-of-fire for both attacks.Primary Fire - Fires a cluster of bullets over a wide spread. Good for close-range combat.Secondary Fire - Fires a tight cluster of bullets focused in the center, for use in longer ranges. Slower firing speed and harder aim than Primary Fire.Crylink(Weapon switch key: 2) Uses Cell (blue) ammo. An energy shotgun that fires glowing balls of energy (that bounces off surfaces, similar to the Flak Cannon primary attack in Unreal Tournament games). This power can be focused into a continuous beam of energy (similar to the Pulse Gun secondary attack in Unreal Tournament games).The Super Crylink changes the attack to a "telefrag gun". By aiming at an enemy for a short period of time while firing, the user teleports at the enemy's position, instantly killing the enemy.Primary Fire - Fires a cluster of energy shells that bounce off surfaces.Secondary Fire - Fires a continuous stream of energy.Electro(Weapon switch key: 3) Uses Cell (blue) ammo. An energy rocket launcher. The energy can also be fired as weaker sticky bombs.The Super Electro changes the attack to fire large area-of-effect balls of electricity that dissipates over a short amount of time, causing continuous damage to anyone inside it.Primary Fire - Fires a high-damage explosive energy projectile that detonates upon impact. Uses a large amount of Cell ammo per shot.Secondary Fire - Fires a small ball of energy that bounces off surfaces and sticks to enemies. Less damage than the primary fire, but uses less ammo and has a faster firing rate.Nex(Weapon switch key: 4) Uses Cell (blue) ammo. Standard railgun. Can be zoomed in like a sniper rifle.Attacks using the Super Nex are one-hit-kill (no matter where it hits on the bodies of enemies), similar to the Instagib Rifle from the Unreal Tournament games.Primary Fire - Fires an instant pinpoint-accurate rail of energy. Uses a very large amount of Cell ammo per shot.Secondary Function - Toggles the weapons scope, zooming in for a better view at long range.Hagar(Weapon switch key: 5) Uses Munitions red) ammo. A rapid-fire mini-rocket launcher. Mini-rockets can either detonate upon impact or bounce along surfaces before detonating.The Super Hagar changes the mini-rocket to a shrapnel grenade, detonating upon impact while dealing larger area-of-effect shrapnel damage.Primary Fire - Fires a rapid-fire stream of mini-rockets that detonate upon impact.Secondary Fire - Fires a rapid-fire stream of mini-rockets that bounce upon walls before detonating.Clancutter(Weapon switch key: 6) Uses Cell (blue) ammo. An energy machine gun that fires accurate bullets of energy (similar to the Pulse Gun primary attack in Unreal Tournament games). Multiple energy bullets can also be fired in a spread.The Super Clancutter changes the attack to a powerful beam weapon (similar to the Crylink's secondary fire).Primary Fire - Rapidly fires fast, accurate energy bullets.Secondary Fire - Fires a wide burst of energy bullets, similar to the Crylink's primary fire. (With a wider spread and no bouncing).Mortar(Weapon switch key: 7) Uses Munitions (red) ammo. Rocket launcher that fires missiles in an arcing trajectory. Not as powerful as the Rocket Launcher, but has a faster rate of fire and less ammo count. Missiles can either detonate upon impact or detonate after a short amount of time.The Super Mortar changes the missiles into proximity mines, exploding when an energy or teammate is near. Once the mutator is over, all proximity mines explode for total carnage.Primary Fire - Fires an arcing missile that detonates upon impact.Secondary Fire - Fires an arcing missile that detonates after a few seconds.Rocket Launcher(Weapon switch key: 8) Uses Munitions (red) ammo. The standard rocket launcher. Rockets can be remotely guided and remotely detonated in mid-air.The Super Rocket Launcher increases the amount of missiles fired at a time while automatically homing to the target on the user's crosshair.Primary Fire - Fires a powerful missile. Holding onto the Primary Fire button (while moving or aiming) guides missiles towards the crosshair.Secondary Function - Detonates rockets already in mid-air.Ravager(Weapon switch key: 9) Uses Munitions (red) ammo. The standard sub-machine gun. Can be fired at two firing speeds: fast and inaccurate, or slow and accurate. Uses a small amount of Munitions ammo per shot.The Super Ravager makes the attacks acts like secondary fire, but turns the bullets into poison bullets (dealing continuous damage to hit enemies over time).Primary Fire - Fires a rapid-fire stream of bullets. Fast, yet inaccurate.Secondary Fire - Fires a rapid-fire stream of bullets. Slow, yet accurate.LevelsTeam DeathmatchCrashRefinerySanctuaryStationStrengthTensionCapture the FlagOverlookVertigoVigor</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3874">Quake III Arena</game><game id="17448">Unreal Tournament</game><game id="13286">Unreal Tournament 2004</game><game id="21388">Quake Live</game><game id="34424">Tribes Ascend</game><game id="10955">Unreal Tournament 3</game><game id="36015">Xonotic</game><game id="11233">Robotron: 2084</game><game id="40478">Red Eclipse</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2104765-box_nexuiz.png</image></root>