<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30383</id><name>DiRT 3</name><description>OverviewFollowing in the tracks of the critically acclaimed Dirt 2, Dirt 3 is an off-road racing game with a variety of events to complete. There are over hundred events to participate in, and drivers will race in many different environments around the world, including African plains, mountainous Aspen, Monaco and Norway. The player will work as a team with other drivers to win races. Developer Codemasters described it as their "biggest racing game" yet. On the 10th May, the game was submitted to Microsoft and Sony for certification.DevelopmentChangeable weather conditionsThere is a new scoring system in place that takes into account how close the driver comes to various obstacles, similar to the "near miss" bonus in the Burnout franchise. Multiple In-game replays, of 30 seconds in duration, can now be uploaded directly to YouTube (to DiRT3 community channel and the personal channel) to share with others. The graphic engine also got an upgrade with more varied weather effects, better lighting and damage model for the cars. Varying track conditions also make a return featuring rain and snow.The car handling will be more realistic than DiRT 2 as cars will drift differently based on whether they are front/rear/four-wheel drive. The car's weight distribution will affect the amount of traction available in corners. The cars also have independent suspensions that shift its balance and center of gravity while drifting. The Gymkhana cars are setup differently but use the same physics and handling model that the game uses throughout. The damage modeling has been updated to take into account where exactly the car got hit and the handling will change accordingly. The game has a system that allows the player to get punctures. If one drives on, the tyre will eventually shred off the rim.User InterfaceThe developers have moved away from the first-person menus of DiRT 2 to what they only describe as a "more stylized" 3D menu system. The game also shuns its Xtreme elements from DiRT 2 in favor of a more slick and minimalistic presentation. There will be a garage area where one will be able to view the cars. The loading screens will show the car which will be driven.LicensingDiRT 3 is the first game in the series since Colin McRae 2005 to feature the important World Rally Championship license. Along with the more dynamic environment model, it marks a bigger focus on rally. This shift coincides with the series' current figurehead, Ken Block, joining WRC in 2010. Block's famous Gymkhana will also make its first appearance. It's a stunt event, focused on extreme acceleration and executing tight drifts in confined spaces. In addition, DiRT 3 will retain the X-Games license. The game will feature Ken Block, Tanner Foust, Kris Meeke, Liam Doran and Sebastien Ogier.Game ModesThe single player campaign, named DiRT Tour, takes place over 4 seasons. Within each season there are 4 championships with multiple events in different disciplines and challenges that test the players driving skills with races and various gymkhana events.Returning modes from DiRT 2Rally - Standard rally mode, which will carry the WRC branding this time.Rallycross - DiRT's form of a standard race, usually on a closed-looped circuit.Trailblazer - Standard rally format with a twist. All cars are on the track at the same time and the player has no co-driver to help with the turns.Raid - Off-track racing with large all-terrain vehicles.CompoundDiRT's version of the GymkhanaAn open-ended playground to improve one's skills in the new Gymkhana mode. The Multiplayer party modes will be held at this Compound. The obstacle courses are based on Ken Block's Gymkhana videos. The compound is designed after the Battersea Power Station in the UK. It will be divided in 3 areas, namely:DepotPower StationParking LotParty ModesParty modes are being introduced to the multiplayer portion of the game. Cat 'n' Mouse, Invasion, Outbreak and Transporter are the available party modes. DiRT 3 also marks the return of split-screen multiplayer, which was absent from the previous game.X-GamesThe Season two X-Games will be held at LA Coliseum whereas the Winter X-Games at Aspen.Vehicle ListWith the newly acquired WRC license, DiRT 3 will feature a number of classic cars from the different eras of rallying. So far, the following cars have been confirmed:1960s Rally ClassMini Cooper SLancia Fulvia HRenault Apline A110 1600 S1970s Rally ClassOpel Kadette GT/E 16VFiat 131 Abarth1980s Rally ClassFord Sierra Cosworth RS500Opel Manta 400Renault 5 TurboGroup B Rally ClassAudi Sport Quattro RallyeMG Metro 6R4Ford RS2001990s Rally ClassLancia Delta HF IntegraleFord Escort RS CosworthToyota Celica GT-FourS2000 ClassPeugot 207 S2000Abarth Grande Punto S2000Open Rally ClassSubaru Impreza WRX STI SRT USASubaru Impreza WRX STI N12Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution XColin McRae R4Ford Fiesta Open ClassPro Rally Class (WRC)Ford Focus RS WRCCitroen C4 WRCFord Fiesta RS WRCMini Countryman Rally EditionRallyCrossSubaru Impreza WRX STI GR RallycrossMitsubishi Lancer Evolution XPeugot 207 T16 4X4MG Metro 6r4 RallyXFord RS200 RallyXFord Fiesta RallyCrossTrailblazer ModernBMW Z4 M Coupé MotorsportMonster Sport SX4 Hillclimb SpecialRhys Millen Racing PM580Ford Fiesta OMSE Hillclimb SpecialTrailblazer ClassicAudi Quattro S1 Pikes PeakPeugot 405 T16 Pikes PeakToyota TacomaGymkhanaSubaru Impreza WRX STI GD GymkhanaSubaru Impreza WRX STI GR GymkhanaFord Fiesta Gymkhana 3Mitsubishi Lancer Evo X JUNLandrushStadium TruckStadium BuggyLocationsThe game will feature about 100 tracks; but with different weather conditions involved, one will visit each track about 3-4 times in the game with each time being at a different time of day and weather.The following is the complete list of locations featured in the game:Kenya, LA Coliseum, Monaco featuring dry terrain.Aspen, Norway will feature snow.Finland, Michigan and Smelter featuring wet terrain.Event wise listing of Locations:Rally and Trailblazer in Kenya, Norway, Finland and Michigan.Rallycross in Aspen, Monaco, LA Coliseum and Smelter.Landrush in Aspen and Smelter.Head-to-Head in Monaco.As for Gymkhana, there will be4 routes in Monaco (in the DiRT3 Tour)4 in LA Coliseum (in the DiRT3 Tour)3 areas in Battersea CompoundOnline passLike many games it will have an online pass in new copies to enable online play and YouTube uploads. As with Mortal Kombat the online modes were made free for all PSN users during the PSN Store downtime while codes were not redeemable. The Online pass also comes with 5 cars:Colin McRae R41995 Subaru Impreza WRX STIFord Sierra Cosworth RS500Peugeot 405 T16 Pikes PeakHummer H3Sound  MusicThe audio engineers made a special effort to record the effect of gravel  mud hitting the underside of the car. They went out with Rally and Rallycross drivers and recorded the sound effects from inside the car as it was driven at speed.The 49 track, dominantly hip-hop and rock soundtrack was revealed via the game's Facebook page, and was compiled by Kerrang DJ Christian Stevenson, the same music consultant that was used for DiRT2:ArtistSong Name  Featured ArtistsDuration65DaysOfStaticCrash Tactics3:48Aceyalone  RJD2All For U3:28Alter BridgeIsolation4:13AtmosphereThe Waitress3:00Biffy ClyroThat Golden Rule3:50Black SpidersWhat Good's A Rock Without A Roll?4:30Chase  StatusBlind Faith feat. Liam Bailey3:54ChromeoDon't Turn The Lights On4:33CrocodilesMirrors5:32Dan Le Sac vs. Scroobius PipCauliflower (Does It Offend You, Yeah? Remix)2:30Danny ByrdJudgement Day feat, Cyantific  I-Kay5:04Danny ByrdWe Can Have It All3:47David E. SugarKeep It Simple3:57Deaf HavanaSmiles All Round2:48Dinosaur Pile-UpWheels TurningDrive AAre You Blind3:04Everything EverythingSuffragette Suffragette4:06Fort Knox FiveInsight feat. Asheru (A. Skillz Remix)4:30Fort Knox FiveInsight feat. Asheru (The Nextmen Remix)3:56Fort Knox FiveUptown Tricks feat. Mustafa Akbar  Shunda K. (Shimon's Trix Radio Mix)3:58FuryonDisappear Again3:47Glamour of the KillFeeling Alive3:29Grafitti6Stare Into The Sun3:57HarlemFriendly Ghost3:01Hudson MohawkeFuse3:11LeftfieldStorm 30005:44LornCherry Moon3:38Manchester OrchestraI've Got Friends4:58MolokoFun For Me5:09People Under The StairsTrippin' At The Disco4:12PhonatGhetto Burnin'4:40PhonatGhetto Burnin' (Mmmathias Mix)5:05PhonatIntimate Confessions3:37RJD2Good Times Roll Pt. 24:57Run DMCPeter Piper3:23Scott NixonThe WedgeScott NixonResolutionSkreamListenin' To The Records On My Wall3:28South CentralDemons5:08StarkeyNew Cities feat. Kiki Hitomi4:06StarkeyOk Luv4:00StarkeyPleasure Points4:54Tek-OneLHC BluesThe Gap BandBurn Rubber On Me (Why You Wanna Hurt Me)5:36The Gaslight AnthemThe Spirit Of Jazz3:13The Go! TeamT.O.R.N.A.D.O.2:10UNKLEThe Answer feat. Big In Japan (Baltimore)4:41We Are ScientistsRules Don't Stop2:19Young GunsCrystal Clear3:30Spoken Audio Names and NicknamesBoys (Eng)Girls (Eng)Nicknames (Eng)AaronAbiAceAdamAliceAngelAlanAmandaBabeAlexAmberBig DogAndyAmyBJAntAngieBootsAshAshleyBossBarryBeckyBunnyBenBethBusterBlakeBritannyButterflyBradBrookeBuzzBrandonCaptainBrettCarnageBrianChampCallumCaitlinCheesemongerCarlCharlotteCherryCarlosChelseaChiefChadChloeChunkChrisClaireColonelCliveCourtneyCowboyColeCrashColinCupcakeConnorCutieCoreyDoctorCraigDollDanDanielleDonutDaveDudeDazDukeDeanFatsDylanFlashEdEmFoxyEricFrostyGavGemFuzzy NutsGazGeorgiaGhostGeorgeGnasherGraemeGonkGrantGonzoGregHannahGooseHarryHeatherGreat OneIanHollyHairsprayJackJadeHawkJacobJenHoneyJakeJessHotstuffJamesHot RodJasonHunterJeffIceJesusJacknifeJezJawboneJoeJesterJoelKidJohnKittenJordanKnucklesJoshLadyJustinLegendKenKateLightningKevKelseyLollipopKieranKimMagicKyleKirstyMamaLeeLauraMateLewisLaurenMaverickLiamLisaMcLovinLukeLizMissyMarkLouiseMongooseMartLucyMonkeyMattMaddiMooseMaxMeganMuffinMikeMelNitroMitchMichelleOmeletteMoPinkyNathNataliePistonNicNicolePrincessOliPumpkinOscarRangerPatRazorPaulRedPeteRookiePhilScoobyRandyRachShadowRayShortieRichSidelineRickSilkRobSix StringRodSkippyRonSmokeyRossSnakeRussSpankyRyanSparkySamSarahSpiderScottSophieSpoonSeanStephStalkerShaneSugarSiSweetySteveT-BagStuTexTannerTinaThumperTimTroubleTomTurboTravisWheelsWillVickyWolfZachWoodySupported controllers and steering wheels (PC)KeyboardKeyboard ControlsControl PadsDiRT 3 can be configured to use almost any PC controller, however it is recommended to use one the following controllers for the best experience:Xbox 360 Controller for WindowsLogitech Rumblepad 2Thrustmaster Run'n'DriveRun'n' Drive Rumble ForceThrustmaster T-Mini 3-In-1Dual Trigger 3-In-1Thrustmaster Dual Analog 3 (ensure official Thrustmaster drivers are installed)Steering wheelsDiRT 3 provides default configurations for all of the below, meaning that you should be able to plug-and-play, without tweaking.For some wheels (e.g. Logitech MOMO, Fanatec Porche) it is important that the pedals are on separate axes, rather than combined. From the Windows Control Panel, choose 'Controllers' and click 'Properties' for the wheel you will be using. Click 'Settings' and ensure that the 'Combined' or 'Single Axis' setting is unticked.Xbox 360 Wireless Racing WheelLogitech G25 WheelLogitech G27 WheelLogitech Formula Force EX Force Feedback WheelThrustmaster T500RS Racing WheelThrustmaster Ferrari 430 Force Feedback Racing WheelThrustmaster RGT F/F ProSystem RequirementsMinimumOS: Microsoft Windows XP, Vista or Windows 7Processor: AMD Athlon™ 64 X2 2.8GHz, Intel Pentium® D 2.8GhzMemory: 2GBHard Disk Space: 15GBVideo Card: AMD Radeon™ HD 2000 256MB, NVIDIA® GeForce® 8000 Series 256MBDirectX®: DirectX® 9Sound: DirectX® compatible soundcardController: Keyboard, Microsoft Wireless Racing Wheel or Xbox 360 controllerRecommendedOS: Windows Vista® or Windows® 7Processor:AMD Phenom™ II or Intel® Core™ i7Memory: 3GBHard Disk Space: 15GBVideo Card: AMD Radeon™ HD 6000 Series, NVIDIA® GeForce® DirectX® 11 based cardsDirectX®: DirectX® 11Sound: DirectX® compatible soundcardXbox 360 Game InstallationInstalling this game to the Xbox 360 hard drive requires 6.1GB of memory.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8944">RalliSport Challenge</game><game id="31982">WRC: FIA World Rally Championship</game><game id="20132">Sega Rally Revo</game><game id="24793">MotorStorm</game><game id="15931">Richard Burns Rally</game><game id="34427">Sega Rally Online Arcade</game><game id="6499">RalliSport Challenge 2</game><game id="28040">Sega Rally 2006</game><game id="2162">Sega Rally Championship</game><game id="16191">Sega Rally 2</game><game id="34757">Test Drive V-Rally</game><game id="37323">Insane 2</game><game id="36993">Project CARS</game><game id="37743">F1 2012</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1891340-box_dirt3.png</image></root>