<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30566</id><name>Sniper: Ghost Warrior</name><description>OverviewThis is the second sniping-dedicated game from  City-Interavtive, as a follow up to  Sniper: Art of Victory. Sniper: Ghost Warrior is a budget title, originally retailing for 39.99 USD. Its release date was repeatedly pushed back, leading Vinny to question the multiple times it showed up in the 'new releases' section of the bombcast.PlotA United States Government run Uranium mine has fallen into the hands of terrorists. It is up to Sgt. Tyler Wells and his Delta Force squad to inflitrate the compound and stop a potential nuclear crisis. Snipers are very effective in mines and large industrial areas.GameplayKey FeaturesA ballistic system that takes distance falloff and environmental effects such as wind, fog and rain into account.The realistic need to manage your breathing for increased accuracy of shots and to cooperate with your spotter. Bullet Cam mode, which will enable you to see your bullets strike the enemy with pin-point accuracy.12-Person multiplayer with 6 maps.RealismSniper: Ghost Warrior is an attempt at making a sniping simulator. It goes as far as to not only factor in environmental factors such as rain and wind, but also implements a breathing and heart rate system that affects accuracy.Arsenal4 types of sniping rifles:  AS50, MSG90,  SR25 and  SVD Dragunov Claymore mines C4 Throwing knivesGrappling hookSilenced PistolTrip WireCombat knifeLevelsOne Shot, One KillNo Man Left BehindDangerous GroundsTake Down the RigsAn Alliance to Save RodriguezWeaken the RegimeOn Your OwnA Simple RendezvousSteal From Under Their NosesThe End is NearThe Hunt is OnSteal From Under Their Noses Part 2A Marksman At His BestGuardian AngelThe ShowdownSeek And DestroySpecial EditionOn August 12th, GAME.co.uk listed that a special edition of Sniper Ghost Warrior was going to be released. While it was not stated what was going to be in this "special edition" it was priced up at a some what discounted £29.99. Closer to it's release date of August 19th it was soon dropped to £19.99. The game was then pushed back to a more generic September 2011 release window.Included in this "extended edition" of the game are four additional singleplayer maps, a new multiplayer mode (capture the flag), as well as extra two weapons for the games singleplayer.PC System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows® XP (SP3) / Vista™ (SP1) / 7Processor: 3.2 GHz / AMD Athlon 64 3500Memory: 1GB for XP / 2GB for Vista and 7Graphics: Nvidia 6800 or ATI X1650, 256 MB RAM, Shader Model 3.0DirectX®: DirectX® 9.0cHard Drive: 6GBSound: Compatible with DirectX® 9.0c</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17853">Sniper Elite</game><game id="32249">Sniper: Art Of Victory</game><game id="8835">Sniper: Path of Vengeance</game><game id="13970">World War II: Sniper - Call to Victory</game><game id="24772">The Sniper 2</game><game id="30280">Sniper Assault</game><game id="26423">Call of Duty: Black Ops</game><game id="2133">Call of Duty 4: Modern Warfare</game><game id="24713">Modern Warfare 2</game><game id="25246">Battlefield: Bad Company 2</game><game id="4402">Line of Sight: Vietnam</game><game id="33002">Sniper: Ghost Warrior 2</game><game id="37516">Snipers</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1373126-sniperbox.png</image></root>