<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30598</id><name>Another Century's Episode R</name><description>Overview Another Century's Episode R is the fourth game in the                       Another Century's Episode series, a series that, in essence, is an action-oriented take on                      Super Robot Wars. It is developed by From Software, best known for the                     Armored Core series. However, while Armored Core features a slower-paced, "heavier" take on robot combat, ACE R is a lighter, faster game that places emphasis on aerial fights.  Unlike  Super Robot Wars, which often scales the robots to approximately the same height, ACE is faithful to each robot's official stats. This means that Aquarion towers over the Gundams, which in turn are much larger than the other robots such as the Nightmare Frames, Arm Slaves, and Overmen.  The developers have admitted that ACE R will sport a smaller roster than previous games due to the transition to the PS3 hardware. Despite this, there are still more than three dozen playable mecha.   ACE:R's theme song is Re:birth by Acid Black Cherry.Featured Characters and MachinesMobile Suit Zeta GundamZeta Gundam (                        Kamille Bidan) Hyaku Shiki (                        Quattro Bajeena)Dijeh (                        Amuro Ray) Zeta Gundam Type 3 (Amuro Ray)Mobile Suit Gundam: Char's CounterattackNu Gundam (Amuro Ray) Hi-Nu Gundam (Amuro Ray)Mobile Suit Crossbone GundamCrossbone Gundam X1 Kai (                        Kincaid Nau)Crossbone Gundam X1 (Kincaid Nau)Crossbone Gundam X3 (                        Tobia Arronax) Crossbone Gundam X1 Full Cloth (Tobia Arronax) (Pilots from the above three series are interchangeable) Mobile Suit Gundam SEED DestinyDestiny Gundam (                        Shinn Asuka)Strike Freedom Gundam (                        Kira Yamato)Infinite Justice Gundam (                        Athrun Zala) Super Dimension Century OrgussOrguss (                        Kei Katsuragi)Orguss II (                        Olson D. Verne)Nikick (                        Athena Henderson) Overman King GainerKing Gainer (                        Gainer Sanga)XAN (Gainer Sanga)Dominator (                        Cynthia Lane) Genesis of AquarionSolar Aquarion (Apollo)Aquarion Luna (Silvia de Alisia)Aquarion Mars (Sirius de Alisia) (Reika, Tsugumi Rosenmeier, Jun Lee, Pierre Viero, and Rena Rune are available as alternate pilots)Full Metal Panic!Arbalest (                        Sousuke Sagara)Gernsback Sousuke Custom (Sousuke Sagara)Gernsback Mao Custom (       Melissa Mao)Gernsback Kurz Custom (        Kurz Weber)Bonta-kun Macross ZeroVF-0A Phoenix (Shin Kudo) VF-0S Phoenix (Shin Kudo)Macross FrontierVF-25F   with option of Super or Armored Pack (                        Alto Saotome)VF-25S   with option of Super or Armored Pack (Ozma Lee)VF-25G   with option of Super Pack (Michael Blanc)RFV-25   with option of Super Pack (Luca Angelloni)Queadluun-Rea (                        Clan Clang)Armored Clan (Clan Clang)Konig Moster (Canaria Berstein)Macross QuarterCode Geass: Lelouch of the Rebellion R2Lancelot Conquista (          Suzaku Kururugi)Lancelot Albion (Suzaku Kururugi)Lancelot (Suzaku Kururugi)Guren Aerial Type (  Kallen Kozuki)Guren S.E.I.T.E.N. 8 Elements (Kallen Kozuki)Guren Mk-II (Kallen Kozuki)Shinkirou (                        Zero)Akatsuki Command Model C.C. Custom (                        C.C.) Lancelot Frontier (C.C.) Super Robot Wars Original GenerationCybuster (                 Masaki Andou)ART-1 (                Ryusei Date)Alteisen Riese (               Kyosuke Nanbu) Armored Core: Master of Arena Nineball Seraph (N/A)    OriginalAlpha Heart (Autumn Four) </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11350">Zone of the Enders</game><game id="10225">Zone of the Enders: The 2nd Runner</game><game id="17675">Armored Core 4</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/16207/1469078-acer.jpg</image></root>