<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>306</id><name>Gangsters 2</name><description>Gangsters 2 is a Strategy game developed by Hothouse Creations in 2001. It Lets you control a gangster by the name of Joey Bane who is out to revenge his fathers death by killing the mob boss Frankie 'Hammer' Constantine. Throughout each mission the player must assist Joey to 'whack' important mob leaders who were involved in his fathers murder. To do so the player must set up illegal businesses and hire more gangsters and muscle to protect these businesses and in doing so, take over increasing areas of the map. Each gangster hired can have a total of four more muscle assigned to them and the weapons of these muscle can be improved, from pistols up to the classic 'tommy' gun. Once Joey has enough support the target can be taken out an the mission is completed. There are also many other ways of controlling the town, through kidnapping, the bribing of officials and bank robbery.Although a inprovement on the Original Gangsters game it only received mediocre success with critics.PC RequirementsWindows 95/98/Me/XP (Home Edition);Pentium II 266 MHz (Min.), Pentium III (Rec.);4x CD-ROM drive (Min.), 8x CD-ROM (Rec.);64 MB RAM (Min.), 128 MB (Rec.);4 MB DirectX 7 compatible graphics card (Min.), 16 MB (Rec.);DirectX 7 compatible sound card.Critical ReceptionGame Informer gave the review scores of 4 and 5 out of ten. Matt, who gave the higher score wrote, "...The premise of running a mafia outfit is a great one, but the developers haven't done much more than come up with a good concept here. There doesn't seem to be much depth to this game, which is good in a way, because the extremely clumsy interface and horrid AI will keep most people from wanting to play this for more than half an hour".</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9701">Hooligans: Storm Over Europe</game><game id="18461">Gangsters: Organized Crime</game><game id="22965">Chicago Enforcer</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/17557/1133827-gangsters_2_front.jpg</image></root>