<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30609</id><name>WonderKing Online</name><description>GameplayThe game plays very similarly to MapleStory with the exception of Double Jumps, Dashing, and overall faster Game play. Player versus Player is also a notable differenceClassesUpon creating a character the player can choose from the following four classes, each with 2 further class advancements.SwordsmanThe swordsman is the general melee class which can advance to either the Warrior or the Knight at level 30 then at level 80 to their respective class Berserker and Paladin.Warrior- The Melee focused branch of the Swordsman, they specialize in two handed weapons. Advances to Berserker.Knight- The Defense focused branch of the Swordsman, they specialize in a shield and sword combo. Advances to Paladin.MageMage's are the spell casting class of WonderKing, they can advance to either the Priest or Wizard at level 30 then at level 80 to their respective class the Saint and Warlock.Priest- The Healing focused branch of the Mage. Advances to Saint.Wizard- The Offensive Magic focused branch of the Mage. Advances to Warlock.ThiefThe agile and speed focused class, they can advance to either the Rogue or Ninja at level 30 then at level 80 to their respective class Knave and Assassin.Rogue- The dual weilding and more melee focused branch of the Thief. Advances to Knave.Ninja- This branch of the Thief focuses on using a Combination of Ninja Stars and Ninjutsu. Advances to Assassin.ScoutThe general ranged combat class which can advance to either the Gunner or Archer at Level 30 then at level 80 to their respective class Gunslinger and Ranger.Gunner- The Gun focused branch of the Scout. Advances to Gunslinger.Archer-The Bow focused branch of the Scout. Advances to Ranger.</description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21958">MapleStory</game><game id="22520">Latale</game><game id="12569">Grand Chase</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/28820/1839967-foto_wonderking_online.jpg</image></root>