<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30611</id><name>Fractured Soul</name><description>OverviewEndgame's Fractured Soul started its life as a Nintendo DS retail title. The game is a platformer/shooter that is designed around dual screen gameplay similar to Chronos Twin where you control the same character on both screens at the same time and have to switch control according to the requirements of the level design.After a long development time of more than two years, Fractured Soul was released exclusively via the Nintendo 3DS eShop on September 13, 2012. The game was approved by Nintendo of America on August 21st, 2012.StoryThe game takes place in the deep and cold parts of outer space. The main character Jake Desaul, a rogue who travels between planets, finds himself stuck in this hellish part of space. In order to escape the space station he must confront his inner demons from his past. Not much is known about Desaul as a character, rather he is a man with a very mysterious past. While in the space station, Jake must use his curiously handy ability to split into two physical bodies in order to solve the various puzzles that are in store for him.GameplayFractured Soul is mainly focused around shooting, platforming, and puzzle gameplay. The game has jumping and timed bases mechanics like every other platformer. However in the game Desaul also has a blaster to kill his foes, and he also has a jet-pack used for various height and puzzle purposes in the game. One thing that separates Fractured Soul from most 3DS games is it's use of bottom screen for gameplay, instead of just putting a map there. On both the bottom part and the top part of the screen the player must control Desaul in as he progresses through the space station. The game, however, limits the enemies to one screen per a time. Fractured Soul features 20 levels, with 5 different environments: inverted gravity, water, wind, ice, and damage.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2844">Chronos Twin</game><game id="27069">Chronos Twins DX</game><game id="39484">Giana Sisters: Twisted Dreams</game><game id="44033">Giana Sisters: Twisted Dreams - Rise of the Owlverlord</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/82063/2260942-599961_356196561116262_1095132181_n.jpg</image></root>