<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30637</id><name>Lucha Libre AAA Heroes del Ring</name><description>Overview The game  is based on a Mexican wrestling federation known as AAA (Asistencia Asesoría y Administración; Spanish for "Assistance, Consulting, and Administration") ,  and have both English and Spanish audio commentary. Heroes Del Ring is billed by its creators as:  "The first ever            lucha libre wrestling  game released in North America and that it will allow gamers to partake  in acrobatics, key moves, and over the edge action  gimmicks that  will make this spectacle unique for all viewers."  The Xbox 360 and Playstation 3 versions of the game were developed by a firm called Immersion Games Studio using            Unreal Engine 3. Sabarasa Studios followed it up with Wii, DS, and PSP versions.~ An Excerpt From The Official Press Release  The teaser of the first ever video game featuring Mexican wrestlers will be announced in the event Triplemania XVII this weekend. The new game, unlike others featuring wrestling, is directed for the first time at the Hispanic market. It successfully reflects the essence and feeling of the shows organized by the AAA in Mexico, with commentary in Spanish, the opportunity to choose the best known wrestlers and their masks, become involved in the throws, holds and locks and be completely involved in the fight, as well as connecting with the public. This game is published by Slang, a company dedicated to promoting the creativity and innovation of Hispanic culture on world class platforms. The game is designed on Unreal Engine 3, one of the most powerful of new generation game consoles, such as XBOX 360 and PLAYSTATION 3, both created by Immersion Games Studio. It should be available commercially at the end of 2009 and, at a later date, versions created by Sabarasa Studio for Wii, Nintendo DS and PSP, will be launched.  Pre-Orders Lucha Libre will gave those who pre-ordered the game one of four Lucha Libre wrestler masks. These are real Lucha masks that the owner can wear. As mentioned there are four different masks, however it is not know if this offer is available at every retailer or if it is a select few. The masks offered were:          Rudos/Heel   Chessman Dark Cuervo Dark Ozz Dark Scoria  Dr. Wagner jr El Brazo El Zorro Electroshock Espectro jr Kenzo Suzuki Killer ClownKonnan Psicosis Silver King Zombie Clown   Tecnicos /face Abismo Negro Alan Stone Apache Charly Manson Cibernetice  El Elegido El Mesias Extreme Tiger Gronda Jack Evans  La Packa Marco Corleone Octagon Superfly Vimpiro Canadiense </description><genres><genre id="10">Wrestling</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20469">TNA iMPACT!</game><game id="26888">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2010</game><game id="20680">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2009</game><game id="12592">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2008</game><game id="15815">WWE SmackDown! Here Comes the Pain</game><game id="1696">WWF Smackdown! Just Bring It</game><game id="17814">WWF SmackDown! 2: Know Your Role</game><game id="7552">WWE SmackDown! Shut Your Mouth</game><game id="13393">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW</game><game id="10338">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2006</game><game id="17436">WWF SmackDown!</game><game id="11394">WWF No Mercy</game><game id="3213">WWF Wrestlemania</game><game id="20723">WWE Legends of WrestleMania</game><game id="3667">WWF Wrestlemania 2000</game><game id="8027">WWF WrestleMania: The Arcade Game</game><game id="16435">WWF Attitude</game><game id="7485">WWF In Your House</game><game id="18801">WWF War Zone</game><game id="10775">WWF Royal Rumble</game><game id="22247">WWF Wrestlefest</game><game id="6945">ECW Anarchy Rulz</game><game id="8647">ECW Hardcore Revolution</game><game id="18320">WCW/nWo Revenge</game><game id="10286">WCW Backstage Assault</game><game id="14786">WCW vs. nWo: World Tour</game><game id="22273">WCW Superbrawl Wrestling</game><game id="775">WCW: World Championship Wrestling</game><game id="1204">WCW Mayhem</game><game id="7908">WCW Nitro</game><game id="1873">WCW/nWo Thunder</game><game id="29222">TNA iMPACT: Cross the Line</game><game id="25903">TNA Wrestling</game><game id="2308">WWE Day of Reckoning</game><game id="21620">WWE Day of Reckoning 2</game><game id="13445">WWE Raw 2</game><game id="4155">WWF Raw</game><game id="1299">Legends of Wrestling</game><game id="7556">Showdown: Legends of Wrestling</game><game id="7951">Legends of Wrestling II</game><game id="18086">Rumble Roses</game><game id="12635">Rumble Roses XX</game><game id="13440">Backyard Wrestling: Don't Try This at Home</game><game id="31640">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2011</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14741/1558094-lucha_libre_aaa.jpg</image></root>