<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30700</id><name>MapleStory DS</name><description>MapleStory DS is an adaptation of the free-to-play MMORPG by the name of      MapleStory, for the PC.  It will not feature any MMO aspect to it, but it has been said it will have some multiplayer capabilities.  Announcements and confirmations AnnouncementsThe game was originally announced at E3 2006, said to be released in September 2007.  After a long wait, Nexon announced that the Korean release was to be set sometime in 2009 and, later on, January of 2010.    Later, in February 2010, the game was announced to be released on April 15th, 2010 in Korea.  Apparently, there will no longer be any delays as        Nexon Corporation and       Nintendo of Korea have revealed a large amount of new media (commercials, screens, interviews...) concerning the game recently.  This date is the exact same date the         Nintendo DSi will be launched in Korea.  No plans to release MapleStory DS have been announced in any  other region thus far.  ConfirmationsMapleStory DS will not be an MMORPG in any way.  In an interview from December 2009, it has been said by the manager of international business development at Nexon (Stephen Lee) that the game's focus is on single player, with limited multiplayer functionality.  MapleStory DS will not support WiFi.  GameplayLike its PC counterpart, MapleStory DS is a side-scrolling, 2D RPG.  Players start by selecting one of four characters: an archer, a magician, a warrior or a thief.  Each of these characters have their own storylines. Players kill various monsters with basic attacks or special skills.  Killing these monsters rewards the player with experience points, that increases the level of the player, loot and/or money.  When players increase in level, they in turn distribute their gained attribute points and skill points to make their character more powerful.  The skill points are used in a skill tree.   The game also features several platforming aspects such as timed jumps  on platforms, double jumps, sprinting, and climbing ladders.  Differences from the PC MapleStory are: any class of character can sprint by tapping twice in one direction and any class of character can jump twice by double tapping the "jump" button. EquipmentPlayers also choose to equip equipments, that have various properties, via an item menu.  There are 6 varieties of equips: a hat (helmet, headband...), an overall (kimono, suit...), footwear, earrings (usually with magical properties), a one-handed or two-handed weapon (hammer, sword, staff...) and a ring.  Many of these equipments have level and class restrictions.   MultiplayerSupposedly, a player can choose to join the game of another with his or her character.  Not much has been said about it except for the promotional videos demonstrating some of it.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21958">MapleStory</game><game id="2411">Sorcerian</game><game id="21400">Valkyrie Profile: Covenant of the Plume</game><game id="11602">Valkyrie Profile</game><game id="2889">Valkyrie Profile 2: Silmeria</game><game id="255">Tales of Phantasia</game><game id="9235">Odin Sphere</game><game id="14787">Popful Mail</game><game id="9245">Wonder Boy in Monster World</game><game id="38903">Buddy Rush</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/33880/1327592-maplestory_ds.jpg</image></root>