<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30740</id><name>Gang Garrison 2</name><description>About the Game  Gang Garrison 2 is a parody of    Valve's    Team Fortress 2. The game allows users to play as 9 different classes that mimic classes in    TF2. The game is presented in an 8-bit style with 2D graphics. The game is free to download and play, and uses a GNU General Public License.    8-bit Parody             Concept Two feuding, quasi-legal freelance security and espionage firms endlessly square off against each other in treacherous battlegrounds in an attempt to acquire each other's deepest secrets. A demake of a 3D game in 8-bit, side-scrolling style. Multiplayer Gang Garrison 2 is multiplayer only. Players are given a chance to create their own servers with several options to choose from including player limit, time limit, auto balancing, etc. Players can also join a game directly via IP address and port (similar to    Soldat) or join a lobby in which they can choose which game to join. They will then choose which team they want to be on (Red or Blue) and which class they will play as. Many options are available in game, including changing teams or classes.  Classes There are 9 classes in Gang Garrison 2. They are detailed below as listed in the game's readme file.    The Runner Hit Points: 100 Weapon: Scattergun (8 damage per shot, shoots 6 bullets)Special Abilities: Double-Jump       The Firebug Hit Points: 120 Weapon: Flamethrower (90 damage per second) Special Abilities:  Airblast, Afterburn        Rocket Man Hit Points: 175 Weapon: Rocket Launcher (55 damage per shot) Special Abilities: Rocket-Jump        Overweight Hit Points: 200 Weapon: Chaingun (120 damage per second) Special Abilities: Manvich        Detonator Hit Points: 120 Weapon: Minebomb (25-50 damage per mine) Special Abilities: Detonate Mines        Healer Hit Points: 120  Weapon: Needlegun (3 damage per shot) Special Abilities: Healing, Superburst, Needlegun        Constructor Hit Points: 120 Weapon: Shotgun (6 damage per shot, shoots 4 bullets) Special Abilities: Autogun        Infiltrator Hit Points: 100 Weapon: Revolver (25 damage per shot) Special Abilities: Cloak, Stab, Passive Invisibility        Rifleman: Hit Points: 120 Weapon: Sniper Rifle (35 unscoped, 25-85 when scoped) Special Abilities: Charge, Scope-InCommunityGang Garrison 2 is supported by the community. All of its maps are created by supporters, and most of which are re-imagined     Team Fortress 2  maps. Utilities are available and linked below. The game is continually being updated by the community. LinksGang Garrison 2 Homepage:      http://www.ganggarrison.com/Garrison Builder - Map Editor:      http://www.ganggarrison.com/forums/index.php?topic=176.msg2291#msg2291 The Independent Gaming Source Bootleg Demakes Competition:     http://www.tigsource.com/features/demakes/</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18162">Team Fortress 2</game><game id="13773">Soldat</game><game id="4561">Team Fortress Classic</game><game id="29994">Pixel Force: Left 4 Dead</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/83904/1330256-header.png</image></root>