<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30765</id><name>AlphaBounce</name><description>AlphaBounce combines the classical brick-breaking arcade concept with RPG features, offering you the chance to explore an endless universe with millions of levels!You have been taken prisoner by an evil intergalactic mining corporation which exploits the galaxy's mineral resources. Take your only chance to escape and blast your way through the bricks back to Earth! Amass a huge collection of equipment, and use it to modify the rules of the game.AlphaBounce is a game which is exclusively available for download from the Nintendo DSi Shop and has been created and developed by Mad Monkey Studio and Motion Twin. GameplayAlphaBounce is similar to other hybrid games with "RPG elements", such as Puzzle Quest, in that the main gameplay mechanic originates in a completely different genre. In this case, it takes gameplay from titles such as Breakout, Arkanoid, Shatter and other such games and envelopes it in map exploration and "character" growth.  In this instance, it's your paddle that gets upgraded through various brick-breaking stages containing parts that you can attach to it. The main map, which is simply outer space broken up into tiles, shows areas with upgrades or other special events. You can move your paddle one tile at a time, but in order to progress further in any given direction, you need to "play" the tile--i.e. break yourself some bricks. You can move along through any tile you've previously played without having to stop, making backtracking to a space way across the map much less of a hassle than it could have been.  </description><genres><genre id="45">Block-Breaking</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15107">Arkanoid</game><game id="24062">Arkanoid Live!</game><game id="21608">Arkanoid DS</game><game id="26619">Arkanoid Plus!</game><game id="17164">Arkanoid: Doh It Again</game><game id="14325">Arkanoid 4000</game><game id="8962">Arkanoid 2000</game><game id="14886">Arkanoid: Revenge of DOH</game><game id="13049">Breakout</game><game id="838">Breakout 2000</game><game id="1055">Super Breakout</game><game id="1457">Breakout in Space</game><game id="22819">iBreakout</game><game id="18406">Breakout 3000</game><game id="20567">Puzzle Quest: Galactrix</game><game id="29289">Puzzle Quest 2</game><game id="24934">Puzzle Quest Chapter 1: Battle of Gruulkar</game><game id="21177">Neopets Puzzle Adventure</game><game id="28329">Gyromancer</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/13157/1333571-alphabouncecover.jpg</image></root>