<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30786</id><name>Naruto Shippuden Ultimate Ninja Heroes 3</name><description>OverviewNaruto Shippuden: Ultimate Ninja Heroes 3 is a PSP exclusive title that will launch in May. The storyline will follow the animes same core story.  Fighting ModesUltimate Master RoadThe player wil be experiencing a linear 2D side scroller when in story mode accomodated by special mission conditions as well as occasional battles for money and characters. when playing against a CPU or friend,  the battle style is embelished allowing stage shifts with a great charater roster and well done animations for specials. The story takes  a few hours due to branching missions for special items and can sometimes get repetitive repeating the stages but all will be forgiven when enterig the battle field with friends or a computer unleashing devestating moves upon your opponents. Players will love this agme as it deeply explores the shippuuden arc revealing many unknown characters to american viewers and when that is mixed with fun gameplay fans will not be disappointed. newcomers will also be welcomed to this sequel as the story is explained in the dialogue4 Player Battle-RoyaleThis mode allows you to fight three of your friends simultanously somewhat like the Super Smash Bros games.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="27495">Naruto Shippuden: Ultimate Ninja 5</game><game id="21007">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja Heroes 2: Phantom Fortress</game><game id="20903">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja Storm</game><game id="21720">Bleach: Blade Battlers</game><game id="22231">Bleach: Blade Battlers 2nd</game><game id="25378">Bleach: Heat the Soul 6</game><game id="22569">Bleach: Heat the Soul</game><game id="21981">Bleach: Heat the Soul 2</game><game id="22974">Bleach: Heat the Soul 3</game><game id="21378">Bleach: Heat the Soul 4</game><game id="21917">Bleach: Heat the Soul 5</game><game id="20486">Bleach: Shattered Blade</game><game id="5206">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai</game><game id="15234">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai 2</game><game id="13129">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai 3</game><game id="20500">Dragon Ball Z: Burst Limit</game><game id="22285">Dragon Ball Z: Shin Budokai</game><game id="1499">Dragon Ball Z: Shin Budokai - Another Road</game><game id="2154">One Piece: Grand Battle</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2215080-box_narutounh3.png</image></root>