<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30836</id><name>Touhou 12.5: Double Spoiler</name><description>OverviewDouble Spoiler is the second photography-based game in the  Touhou Project series and was released in Japan on March 14, 2010. It plays similar to  Shoot the Bullet in that  you must take pictures of various bosses and their bullet patterns while also avoiding them.    GameplayDouble Spoiler inherits the system of its prequel Shoot the Bullet, where players cannot shoot projectiles at enemies; instead the main character must take photographs to clear the screen of bullets and take down bosses. Scores are determined by the aesthetics of each photograph taken, such as colours and bullet density, and the risk taken to take these pictures. For each "scene", the player is only given one life to complete the objective -- to take a certain number of pictures of the boss without being hit in a limited amount of time.       Standard gameplay in Double Spoiler.   To take pictures, the film must be fully loaded into the cameras (100%). The player can move at three speeds, the normal         speed, the focused speed, and a super-focused speed which also allows for high speed film loading. When taking pictures, the player can hold the shoot button to control the viewfinder while the picture frame shrinks -- this can be used to zoom in on the boss. During this time, all bullets on screen are slowed down and the player cannot move. If the shoot button is held for too long, the film will get exposed and the player will have to reload the film. The player can also press the shoot button once without holding it to take a snapshot around the player character. For every picture taken, the player will need to reload the film from 0% again before they can take another picture. Only photos that contain an image of the boss ("Success" pictures) will be taken into account when tallying up the score.  New to Double Spoiler is the option to change the orientation of the shot between landscape to portrait, and the angle of the shot is automatically adjusted depending on where the player is in relation to the boss.    CharactersThere are two playable characters to chose from in Double Spoiler. The player decides which character to play at the beginning of the game.  Playable characters Aya Shameimaru: A tengu reporter of the Gensokyo newspaper Bunbunmaru Shinbun. She was the heroine and sole playable character of Shoot the Bullet.   Hatate Himekaidou: The second playable character in Double Spoiler. She is also a tengu reporter that makes a newspaper called Kakashi Nenpo .    BossesLevel 1:  Minoriko Aki,  Shizuha AkiLevel 2:  Parsee Mizuhashi,  Hina KagiyamaLevel 3:  Yamame Kurodani,  Kogasa Tatara,  KisumeLevel 4:  Nitori Kawashiro,  Momiji InubashiriLevel 5:  Ichirin Kumoi,  Minamitsu MurasaLevel 6:  Yuugi Hoshiguma,  Suika IbukiLevel 7:  Shou Toramaru,  NazrinLevel 8:  Rin Kaenbyou,  Utsuho ReiujiLevel 9:  Satori Komeiji,  Koishi KomeijiLevel 10:  Tenshi Hinanai,  Iku NagaeLevel 11:  Kanako Yasaka,  Suwako MoriyaLevel 12:  Byakuren Hijiri,  Nue HoujuuLevel EX:  Reimu Hakurei,  Marisa Kirisame,  Sanae KochiyaLevel Spoiler: Hatate Himekaidou, Aya Shameimaru  </description><genres><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="32099">Akai Katana</game><game id="34712">Koumajou Densetsu 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/4/48222/1340021-th125cover.jpg</image></root>