<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30858</id><name>XS Junior League Dodgeball</name><description>General Information XS Junior League Dodgeball  has a tournament mode and a versus mode. You can select from 8 different team leaders with their own specialties, and lead your team to be the champion of the school. Each team has 7 people: the leader and teammates on the inside of the field, and 3 on the outside. Each player has a         health bar, once the bar goes to zero, they are knocked out. The team who knocks out the other team first wins.  Each player can use power shots, and the team leader has their own Magic  Shot.       A player being removed after being knocked out.            Special Abilities Power ShotsEvery player in the inside court can use a power shot. To use a power shot, a player must start running, and then throw the   ball on their 5th step. As long as you have the timing right, there is no limit on how many times you can use it. Every player on a team has their own Power Shot, and there are many various types.  Globetrotter Shot- Shot that goes high in the air, circles the world, and comes crashing down.  Trick Shot- The thrown ball goes straight for the enemy, then stops midair, then continues its path.Ghost Shot- Shot disappears mid-flight, reappears in front of enemy. Rising Shot- Shot travels along the ground, then rises up quickly Triple Shot- Ball multiplies by 3 Hover Shot- Ball reaches it's target, then floats around the area. Corkscrew Shot- Ball follows a spiral path Hook Shot- Ball is thrown towards the side of the court, then comes towards the opponent from the side.  Magic ShotEach team leader has their own Magic Shot. The Magic Shot can be used when the      magic bar is filled by either catching thrown balls or hitting the opponent. To activate the Magic Shot, the team leader must run and then jump, at the highest point of their jump, they must throw. The shot is accompanied by an animation, and will reduce all opponents life bar to 1. The only exception to this is Jim, his Magic Shot heals all of his teammates.  Items Items will randomly float over the arena and can be grabbed by jumping. There are four items in this game.    Drink Bottle- Fully heals the teammate that grabs it.  Doughnut- Partially fills up the magic bar Bird- Reduces your opponents magic bar Angel- Revives one teammate that was previously knocked out.Team LeadersAprilSchool: Eastbrook HighHeight: 5' 6"Weight: 105 lbs Special: Tidal Wave  Jim School: Eastbrook High Height: 5' 10" Weight: 135 lbs Special: Healing  Becky  School: Lakeside High  Height: 5' 8"  Weight: 115 lbs  Special: Lightning  RyanSchool: Lakeside High Height: 6' 1" Weight: 150 lbs Special: Ice   JulieSchool: Alpine Cove High Height: 5' 6" Weight: 109 lbs Special: Lava Explosion  AlexSchool: Alpine Cove High Height: 6' 0" Weight: 134 lbs Special: Meteor  ChrisSchool: Oakwood High Height: 5' 11" Weight: 150 lbs Special: Fireball  TashaSchool: Oakwood High Height 5' 9" Weight: 120 lbs Special: Galaxy Whirlwind</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="38107">Battle Dodgeball</game><game id="38108">Battle Dodgeball II</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9253/1336474-xsjldodgeball_us_ps_front.jpg</image></root>