<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30866</id><name>Piposh</name><description>The GameHezi Piposh is the Israeli actor that played Elimelech Egoz, the main character in                                         Guillotines first game: In The Midst of Rating.     Hezi Piposh After gaining no fame and no fortune from appearing as the failed detective Eliemlech Egoz, the failed actor wishes to try his luck in Hollywood. He orders a cruise from Israel to Hollywood, but goes on the wrong ship. Aboard this ship are a cavalcade of odd characters: The ships captain - Capitolomihu Krupnic, the ship mechanic Henry Steam, the ship maid Brigett, a crazy German doctor Fritz Fon Bzzz, and many more. Also on board, is a murderer that has been knocking off people every day. It is Piposh's role to find the killer and save the ship.           Characters ListHezi Piposh     The cast of characters on Captain Krupnik's shipCaptain Krupnik  Henry Steam Brigitte  Fritz Fon bzzzEfi the Lulu Pustema  Pustema's Crystal Ball Tzutzik Marjury Kol-Raam Yeshurun Bar-sehel The Bentley Couple Captain Dubi Nahs  Mechanics Piposh  is a humorous adventure game in the likes of the famed                                         Monkey Island series. The player will navigate Hezi Piposh on the cruise ship that is broken into sections and rooms. You'll talk to the other guests and crew, pick up objects and use them to solve puzzles, in your goal to capture the murderer on board. The game also features a number of                                         mini games that are unrelated to the story line. Among them are an arcade room, a casino, a wrestling ring, a hot-tub and more.   Bonus MaterialPiposh came with an audio CD that included songs and skits that were in the game. In the game, the player also collected Travel and Ancient cards that could be printed into a card collection booklet.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12259">Piposh 2</game><game id="30867">Piposh in: A Dream Come True</game><game id="30868">Piposh 3D: The Revolution</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/33972/1337383-piposh1.jpg</image></root>