<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3090</id><name>Fatty Bear's Birthday Surprise</name><description>OverviewFatty Bear's Birthday Surprise was the second offering from the Ron Gilbert (The Secret of Monkey Island, Maniac Mansion) founded Humongous Entertainment. Built around a streamlined version of the SCUMM engine the game was targeted at a young audience. First released in 1993, Fatty Bear is the only Humongous Entertainment protagonist to not appear in any sequels. PlotStarring an anthropomorphic teddy bear clad in red overalls. It is up to Fatty Bear to save Kayla's birthday from disaster. Throughout the game the player is charged with gathering ingredients for a cake, catching a rogue puppy, and decorating Kayla's room. Set in and around Kayla's house, Fatty Bear travels all around to find the necessary items. Featuring an early version of Humongous Entertainment's soon-to-be standard path changing feature the game changes slightly each time it is played.Design/GameplayFatty Bear's Birthday Surprise runs on a streamlined version of the SCUMM engine. Instead of having to pick an action to interact with an object the player only needs to point-and-click for the action to be processed. This modified engine makes the game ideal for younger gamers who can't yet read.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="8">Educational</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14441">Pajama Sam 2: Thunder and Lightning Aren't so Frightening</game><game id="8430">Pajama Sam: No Need to Hide When It’s Dark Outside</game><game id="7900">Pajama Sam 3: You Are What You Eat From Your Head To Your Feet</game><game id="14961">Pajama Sam: Life is Rough When You Lose Your Stuff</game><game id="2373">Freddi Fish and the Case of the Missing Kelp Seeds</game><game id="15666">Freddi Fish 2: The Case of the Haunted School House</game><game id="9720">Freddi Fish 3: The Case of the Stolen Conch Shell</game><game id="10911">Freddi Fish 4: The Case of the Hogfish Rustlers of Briny Gulch</game><game id="7662">Freddi Fish 5: The Case of the Creature of Coral Cove</game><game id="931">Putt-Putt Travels Through Time</game><game id="11177">Putt-Putt Joins the Parade</game><game id="3785">Putt-Putt Saves the Zoo</game><game id="10431">Putt-Putt Joins the Circus</game><game id="3136">Putt-Putt and Fatty Bear's Activity Pack</game><game id="13134">Putt-Putt Goes to the Moon</game><game id="15183">Putt-Putt Enters the Race</game><game id="17824">Pajama Sam's SockWorks</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4938/617675-fatty_bears_b_day_fb.jpg</image></root>