<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30913</id><name>The Next Big Thing</name><description>OverviewThe digital version of the game is currently available on Steam. Both retail and digital versions were released on April 21st, 2011.A demo of the game is also currently available for download here.An iOS version of the game came out in December of 2012, under the name Hollywood Monsters (not to be confused with this game's predecessor of the same title). A lite version is available as of March 12th, 2013.PlotThe story revolves around a couple of charismatic heroes: Dan Murray and Liz Allaire, who become involved in an incredible adventure, full of interesting characters and moments full of comedic action.GameplayThe game bears many similarities with Péndulo Studios' earlier works, such as Runaway's unique graphics style and animation. It is a point and click adventure. It will run in full 1080p. The Next BIG Thing also boasts an intricate story, funny and charismatic characters, wacky mysteries, puzzles, and a modern adult tone.There are three levels of difficulty; the easiest level will give players the option to get hints on how to solve puzzles and the ability to highlight points of interaction in the game.System RequirementsPCOperating System: Microsoft Windows XP SP2, Vista SP1 or 7Processor: Intel/AMD 2.0GHZ equivalent, or higherRAM Memory: 1GB (XP) / 2GB (Vista/7)Hard Disk Space: 8GBVideo Card: : 256 MB 100% DirectX 9 compatible, ATI Radeon X800/Intel GMA 3000/Nvidia GeForce 6800 or HigherDirectX®: 9.0Sound Card: DirectX 9 compatibleMacOperating System: Mac OSXProcessor: Intel/AMD 2.0GHZ equivalent, or higherRAM Memory: 1GBHard Disk Space: 8GBVideo Card: 256 MB ATI Radeon X800/Intel GMA 3000/NVIDIA GeForce 6800 or Higher</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11221">Runaway 2: The Dream of the Turtle</game><game id="22496">Runaway: A Twist of Fate</game><game id="2426">Dreamfall: The Longest Journey</game><game id="8759">The Longest Journey</game><game id="16965">Syberia</game><game id="1975">Syberia II</game><game id="29132">Syberia III</game><game id="21914">A Vampyre Story</game><game id="1014">Runaway: A Road Adventure</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1306/1738123-pack2d_tnbt.jpg</image></root>