<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30924</id><name>Zen Bound 2</name><description>OverviewZen Bound 2 is a puzzle game developed by Secret Exit. The game requires you to tie rope around different wooden structures by spinning the structure around. The game is meant to be relaxing as it features minimal music and no time limit or pressure.GameplayOne of the simpler structures.Zen Bound 2 has you spinning rope around a wooden structure. The player does not directly control the rope, instead he rotates the object that is already attached to a piece of rope. By tying the rope around the structure, each piece of rope that touches the structure colors a part of said structure. This is where the game becomes a puzzler as you must try to color 100% of the structure. This requires you to weave the rope through structures of varying difficulty which can go from a hippo to more abstract shapes which require careful thinking in order to succeed.The game gives you a certain number of flowers depending on how much of the structure you have colored. 70% equals 1 rose, 85% equals 2 roses and 99% equals 3 roses. To make things slightly more challenging, you have limited amount of rope to work with and to complete a puzzle, you must rap your rope around a shining white nail. Progression is done on a sort of tree where you unlock more levels according to the amount of roses you have unlocked.PC System RequirementsOS: Windows XP SP3 or laterProcessor: 1.6+ GHzMemory: 512 MBGraphics: OpenGL 2.0 with shader model 3 required, ATI Radeon X1300 or better, Nvidia 6000-series or betterHard Drive: 250 MBMac System RequirementsOS: OS X version Leopard 10.5.8, Snow Leopard 10.6.3, or later.Processor: Any Intel CPUMemory: 512 MBGraphics: Intel GMA 950 or betterHard Drive: 250 MBController: Multi-Touch trackpad or Magic Trackpad recommended</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6136">QIX</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3699/1837850-zen_bound_2.jpg</image></root>