<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>30997</id><name>Ketsui: Kizuna Jigoku Tachi Extra</name><description>Ketsui: Kizuna Jigoku Tachi Extra is an updated version of Cave's arcade bullet hell shoot 'em upKetsui: Kizuna Jigoku Tachi. The porting was handled by 5pb. Pre-orders for the game included a guidebook. The Limited Edition features a 2-disc soundtrack with music from Ketsui and DoDonPachi Dai Ou Jou.On March 18, 2013, 5pb announced that a Playstation 3 version was in development and will be available July 25. StoryWe have the year 2054 and we are in the middle of a War. An Evil Company by the name EVAC is making massive Profit by, illegally, Producing and selling Weapon Systems. The United Nations discovered EVAC's doings and asked them to immediately stop all actions and to Destroy all Facilities. EVAC refused to take any action and now the United Nations started a preventive War against the evil Company.ScoringThe Basic Scoring in Ketsui is by  CAVE standards very simple. Kill an Enemy at close Range and a little 1 till 5er Box will Pop Up. When switching to the Laser Shoot afterwards (with Auto Lock-on) all killed Enemies will also produce 1-5er Box. When flying close by those boxes they will be auto sucked in.ShipsFighter Type-A | AH-Y72 TIGER SCHWERT Weapon: Spread Diffusion GunSpeed: SlowLock-on: Fast Fighter Type-B | FH-X4 PANZER JAEGER Weapon: Narrow Discharging GunSpeed: FastLock-on: Slow  CharactersAlice Blackbarn - Age 23Lloyd Evans Mann - Age 26Yuuma Nanase - Age 18Steel Yureku - Age 26TriviaThe Evil Company's name EVAC is the word CAVE spelled backwards. Also is the name of an Autobot in the Transformers Series who transforms into an helicopter.</description><genres><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="216">Dodonpachi Dai-Ou-Jou</game><game id="21705">DoDonPachi</game><game id="26433">DoDonPachi Dai Ou Jou Black Label EXTRA</game><game id="30001">Espgaluda II Black Label</game><game id="26366">Espgaluda II</game><game id="17644">Espgaluda</game><game id="32344">DoDonPachi Resurrection</game><game id="34001">Crimzon Clover</game><game id="34268">Mushihime-sama Futari Black Label</game><game id="37401">DoDonPachi Maximum</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2291759-box_kkjte.png</image></root>