<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>310</id><name>NASCAR Rumble</name><description>OverviewNascar Rumble is a arcade racing game based on the three top NASCAR racing series, developed and published by Electronic Arts. Nascar Rumble was released for the PlayStation on February 3, 2000. It is a unique game as It impliments a power up system that can aid or hurt the players vehicle, much like the items in the Mario Kart series. The game includes NASCAR Winston Cup, Craftsman Truck series drivers and legends.The game features a commentator who makes comments based on things that are happening in the race.Game ModesSingle Race - A standard race against five opponants.Showdown - A one lap head to head race against the players choice of opponant.Time Trial - The player has four laps to beat the previous best lap time or track time.Championship - The story mode of Nascar Rumble. In Championship mode the player competes in different areas unlocking trophies and legend modes for each area.DriversWinston CupSteve ParkRusty WallaceDale EarnhardtTerry LabonteBobby HamiltonMichael WaltripMark MartinDale Earnhardt Jr.Ricky RuddJeremy MayfieldKevin LepageTony StewartBobby LabonteWard BurtonJeff GordonWally DallenbachJohnny BensonKenny Irwin Jr.Mike SkinnerKen SchraderErnie IrvinSterling MarlinJoe NemecheckJohn AndrettiKyle PettyAdam PettyKenny WallaceGeoff BodineDarrell WaltripDale JarrettBill ElliotChad LittleJeff BurtonCraftsman TruckMike WallaceRick CarrelliRon HornadayJack SpragueScott HansenStacy ComptonLegendsAlan KulwickiCale YarboroughDavid PearsonBobby AllisonDavey AllisonRichard PettyBenny ParsonsPower-upsNitro- Increases top spead by 20 miles per hour.Bold tires - Improves handling by 2x.Oil Slick - Decreases handling by 2x.Bad Gas - Reduces speed and acceleration.Joker - Activates either nitro, bold tires, oil slick and bad gas.Tornado - Shoots out a tornado that sucks up the cars in front of you.Storm - Sends a storm cloud to the driver in front of you decreasing his vision.Big Rumble - Adds a red bumber to the front of your vehicle bouncing any opponants car out of the way that you hit.Invincible - Disables bad power-ups.Freeze - Freezes the opponant ahead of you.** The Number of power-ups can be determined by the player.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6196">Crash Team Racing</game><game id="21405">Crash Tag Team Racing</game><game id="8469">Shrek Smash N' Crash Racing</game><game id="18757">Mario Kart: Double Dash!!</game><game id="16769">Mario Kart: Super Circuit</game><game id="2278">Crash Nitro Kart</game><game id="20645">Mario Kart Wii</game><game id="15990">Diddy Kong Racing</game><game id="12967">Rumble Racing</game><game id="10170">Monster 4x4: World Circuit</game><game id="11174">LEGO Racers</game><game id="15429">Excitebike 64</game><game id="6368">Mickey's Speedway USA</game><game id="24733">NASCAR Kart Racing</game><game id="25961">Blur</game><game id="36537">NASCAR Unleashed</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2210277-box_nascarr.png</image></root>