<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31011</id><name>Desktop Dungeons</name><description>OverviewEach game or round consists of one dungeon floor, randomly created, that you must navigate through, gaining levels until you can defeat the boss.  As you move more of the dungeon is revealed, allowing you to find hidden treasure or power ups.  Once you have defeated the boss, a score screen is shown and any game rewards are given to you.  These rewards include new game modes, classes, or races.  There is only a single floor to each dungeon, and no persistent characters from dungeon to dungeon.  Long term progression in the game comes in the form of collecting gold and unlocking new game elements, which can open up new strategies. Although the game superficially resembles a roguelike, each level is actually more akin to a tactical puzzle game. The primary way for the player to regain health and mana is by exploring squares; if one uses up this resource recklessly, it is easily possible to lock oneself out of being able to defeat the level's boss. More difficult levels often require more complex strategies, such as targeting monsters of much higher level than the player, or carefully timing a level up to take best advantage of the free health and mana restoration associated with it. VersionsAfter the initial freeware release of the alpha version, QFC Design  turned their efforts toward an enhanced, full version of the game, which they have rewritten in the Unity Engine. The developers state that the full version will eventually run on PC, Mac, web, iOS, and Android, although the beta currently only runs through their website. The full version is commercial software; customers who pre-order the game gain access to the closed beta, which currently in development. The beta features enhanced graphics and expanded gameplay. It uses a world map with multiple dungeons, and each of these dungeons contain distinguishing features, such as different level layouts and different selections of monsters. This provides a much expanded selection compared to the level types available in the alpha. The player undertakes a series of quests to unlock new dungeons, as well as items, classes, races, altars and other features. Dungeons may now include sub-dungeons, branches that often contain rewards or puzzles. A "preparation" system was introduced in the beta, which allows the player to spend gold in exchange for certain advantages at the start of a dungeon run. The preparation system includes item banks, which allow the player to store items they have found and reuse them in later dungeons.   Due to extensive rebalancing, some gameplay elements including class abilities and gods now operate quite differently in the full version, compared to their counterparts in the freeware version.AvailabilityThe alpha version of the game is freeware and is currently available for download at  desktopdungeons.net.The beta version is available for pre-order at the same site.RacesNameDescription Unlocked at...    Human  +10% Damage Bonus  Start of game   Elf  +2 Maximum Mana  Start of game   Dwarf  +1 Max Health per level*  Start of  game   Halfling  +1 Healing Potion  Start of game   Gnome  +1 Mana Potion  Start of game   Goblin  +10 gold  Defeating the  Crypt dungeon with any race    Orc  +5 experience  Defeating the  Library dungeon with any race  ClassesNameDescriptionUnlocked at...Class Tier  Fighter Can see monsters of equal or lower level to the player on the map Gains 1 additional XP point per monster kill Survives 1 killing blow for freeStart of game  1 Thief  First attack on all monsters deals 30% more damage Map contains 33% more items HP and MP potions act as both in one Start of game 1 Priest  Bonus of 2 HP per level HP potions heal 100% HP Deals 200% damage to Undead Start of game  1 Wizard  Can see all glyph locations -1 MP cost to use glyphs -25% to own melee damage Map created with 1 extra glyph slotStart of game 1 Berserker  30% more damage vs higher level monsters -50% magic damage taken 30% more damage at all times Adds 2 MP cost to all glyphs Defeating normal dungeon using Fighter  2 Rogue  First Strike enabled at all times 20% base dodge rate 50% more damage at all times -5 HP per level up Defeating normal dungeon using Thief  2 Monk  Melee damage done of -50% Magic and physical damage taken of -50% HP regeneration from exploration is doubled Defeating normal dungeon using Priest  2 Sorcerer  Heals 2 HP per 1 any MP spent Begins with 5 additional MP Does 1 magic damage to monster per character level when hit Defeating normal dungeon using Wizard  2 Warlord  Begins with CYDSTEPP (cheat death) glyph 30% more damage when HP is below 50% Drinking MP potions gives a 30% damage on the next hit Defeating normal dungeon using Berserker  3 Assassin  Begins with APHEELSIK (poison) glyph Exploring all squares  around monsters enables First Strike 1 hit KO on all lower level monsters Defeating normal dungeon using Rogue  3 Paladin  Begins with HALPMEH (heal) glyph Killing the Undead restores 50% HP -25% physical damage taken Defeating normal dungeon using Monk  3 Bloodmage  Begins with BLUDTUPOWA (HP to MP) glyph MP potions give 100% refill (at the cost of 6 HP per level) Heal 15% HP from blood pools Defeating normal dungeon using Sorcerer  3 Transmuter  Begins with ENDISWAL (break wall) glyph Gains 2 HP per level for wall destruction ENDISWAL costs 1 MP, no HP regeneration Defeating    Snake Pit with any character  Special Crusader  Monster kills give 10% damage bonus on next hit (can chain up to  100%) Immune to Poison and Mana Burn Deals 300% attack damage to type of monster  that killed the player Defeating    Factory with a Wizard  Special Tinker  Map created with 6 extra shops 20% item discount Gold for monster killsDefeating    Factory with any character  Special Gorgon  Starts with ENDISWAL glyph -50% damage at start 50% physical  resist Poison attack Death Gaze immunity Adds 2 MP per kill Petrifies  defeated enemies 10% to death gaze Converts glyphs to additional 5% death gaze Defeating    Snake Pit with a Monk  Special Half Dragon  200% health at start Magical attack Increased sight radius BURNDAYRAZ prohibited 20% knockback damage Converts glyphs to 20%  additional knockback damage Defeating    Library with a Warlord  Special Vampire  7 damage per level -1 HP per tile explored First Strike Poison immunity Mana burn immunity Sense monster locations Spells use  health instead of mana Restore 10% health from blood pools 5% life  steal Converts glyphs to additional 5% life steal Defeating    Crypt with an Assassin  Special  Glyphs  Name Mana Cost Description     APHEELSIK5 Inflicts poison status on a monster, preventing it from  regenerating HP while you explore.  The effect will wear off if attack  anything. The Undead are immune to this glyph  Unlocked by completing a normal game as an        Assassin       BLUDTUPOWA0 Switches health regeneration for mana regeneration on one undiscovered tile Unlocked by completing a normal game as a        Bloodmage       BURNDAYRAZ6 Throws a fireball at a monster, causing 4 points of damage per each of the player's levels      BYSSEPS2 Player gets an additional 30% damage bonus during the next physical attack     CYDSTEPP10 Rather than dying, the player will be protected from the next fatal blow and will be reduced to 1 HP instead Unlocked by completing a normal game as a        Warlord       ENDISWAL8 Destroys a section of wall      GETINDARE3 First strike status is enabled in the next physical attack      HALPMEH3 Restores 3 HP per player level and cures any poison status  Unlocked by completing a normal game as a        Paladin       IMAWAL5 Transforms a monster into a section of wall.  It will not grant the player with any XP points, nor will it trigger any kind of reward/punishment from deities, however      LIMMISI3 Fully reveals 3 random unexplored tiles, awarding the player the usual HP and/or MP bonus for revealing a new tile     PISORF10 Teleports a monster to any random empty tile in the map     WEYTWUT6 Teleports the player to any random empty tile in the map     WONAFYT6 Teleports a random monster of the same level as the player's to any random  empty tile next to the player's characterEnemies Name Attack Health AbilitiesBoss Name     Animated Armour 160% Always 1 Death protection (1 point per level)  ---     Bandit 70% 80% Poison attackMana burn Nine Toes      Dragonspawn 100% 125% Magical attack Matron of Flame      Goat 100% 75% 25% Magical resistance Gharbad the- whoah!      Goblin 120% 100% First strike Lord Gobb      Golem 100% 100% 50% Magic resistance The Iron Man      Goo blob 100% 100% 50% Physical resistanceTower of goo      Gorgon 100% 70% First strikeDeath gaze (when the player's health is lower than 50%) Medusa      Imp 100% 80% Blinks  ---     Meat man 65% 200%  ---Super Meat Man      Naga 100% 100% Weaken attack  ---     Serpent 100% 100% Poison attack Jormungandr      Vampire 100% 100% UndeadLife steal upon discovery (brings the hero's health down to 60% of his current maximum HP)  ---     Warlock 135% 100% Magical attack Aequitas      Wraith 100% 75% UndeadMagical attackMana burn30% Physical resistance Tormented One      Zombie 100% 150% Undead Frank the zombie Stores  Store ItemsStores are placed randomly at the beginning of each dungeon and are revealed whenever you uncover the tile next to it.At the early stages of the game, only Items from ranks 1 to 5 will be available to purchase in any shop. From then on, for each  of the tiers 1 to 3 character classes that the player completes the game with, the Item Rank limit  will increase by 2. Finally, for every class that completes the  Library Challenge, the Item Rank limit will increase by 1.    RankNameGold Cost *Effect  1 Pendant of health 25 Adds 10 to maximum health   2 Pendant of mana 20 Adds 2 to maximum mana   3 Fine sword 25 Increases base damage by 5   4 Health potion 12 Restores 40% of your health (100% for Priests)Cures poison   5 Mana potion 12 Restores 40% of your mana (100% for Bloodmages)Cures mana burn   6 Bloody sigil 10 Adds 10 to maximum healthReduces damage bonus by 10%   7 Viper ward 25 Grants immunity to poison   8 Soul orb 30 Grants immunity to mana burn   9 Troll heart 10 Adds 1 extra health every time you gain a level   10 Tower shield 35 Grants additional 10% to the physical resistance   11 Mage helm 32 Grants additional 10% to the magical resistance   12 Scouting orb 21 Increases your sight radius (tiles 2 away from you are now semivisible)   13 Blue bead 22 Offers 1 extra mana after every kill   14 Stone of seekers 26 Reveal the location of all monsters.   15 Spoon 1 Increases base damage by 1   16 Stone sigil 45 Grants immunity to death gaze   17 Badge of courage 20 Provides death protection   18 Talisman of rebirth 52 Instantly restores health to maximumCures poison   19 Sign of the spirits 62 Instantly restores mana to maximumCures mana burn   20 Bonebreaker 29 Adds a 30% damage bonus to your next attack only   21 Stone heart 31 Restores 2 health whenever a wall is destroyed   22 Fire heart 38 Restores 10 health whenever an undead creature is destroyed   23 Platemail 50 Grants additional 20% physical resistance   24 Mage plate 45 Grants additional 20% magical resistance   25 Venom blade 55 Regular attacks do poison damage   26 Flaming sword 35 Attack damage counts as magical damage   27 Dancing sword 44 Grants first strike   28 Zombie Dog 1 Provides death protection   29 Dwarven gauntlets 60 Additional 20% attack bonus2 HP bonus   30 Elven boots 65 Additional 20% dodge bonus2 MP bonus   31 Keg o' health 55 3 health potions   32 Keg o' magic 55 3 mana potions   33 WEYTWUT glyph 50 Creates the WEYTWUT glyph   34 HALPMEH glyph 50 Creates the HALPMEH glyph   35 BLUDTUPOWA glyph 50 Creates the BLUDTUPOWA glyph   36 Crystal ball 50 Regenerates your mana twice as quickly   37 Agnostic's collar 10 Allows you to safely renounce your current deity   38 Vampiric sword 65 Adds 20% life steal   39 Spiked flail 80 Adds 50% knockback   40 Alchemist's scroll 72 Drinking a potion adds 6 max health permanently   41 Ring of the battlemage 90 Adds an additional 50% to the fireball damage   42 Wicked guitar 70 Increases base damage by 10Reduces life steal by 20%   43 Berserker's blade 120 Increases damage bonus by 50%Reduces maximum mana to 1   44 Magician's moonstrike 120 Adds 15 to maximum manaReduces base damage to 1   45 Terror slice 120 Increases damage bonus by 100%Reduces maximum health to 1   46 Amulet of Yendor 115 Grants 50 bonus experience points   47 Orb of Zot 120 Temporarily sets all monsters to 50% health * Note: keep in mind that the Tinker class gets a 20% discount on store prices. TriviaDesktop Dungeons won the "Excellence in Design" award at the  2011 Independent Games Festival.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="30676">Dungeon Crawl Stone Soup</game><game id="24999">Spelunky</game><game id="22309">Rogue</game><game id="32060">Shoot First</game><game id="33311">Epic Dungeon</game><game id="35423">Dungeons of Dredmor</game><game id="140">NetHack</game><game id="37313">Hack, Slash, Loot</game><game id="35899">The Binding of Isaac</game><game id="42828">Rogue Legacy</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/13280/1349632-dd_splash.jpg</image></root>