<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31010</id><name>DarkStar One: Broken Alliance</name><description>Overview  Darkstar One is a spaceflight combat and trading game with RPG elements. The RPG side of the game is centered on the player's spaceship (the  DarkStar One). The player alter the DarkStar One through the course of the game by  finding artifacts, and choosing which areas of the ship they want to upgrade. The story takes players through 300 solar systems, encountering six races: the Terran, the Mortok, the Raptor, the Oc'to, the Arrack, and  the Thul. Each race has unique ships, weapons, space stations, and  battle tactics. While DarkStar One's story is linear, the player can choose to ignore the story at any point to trade, pirate, or run missions. Different perks and penalties can be accrued by spending time pirating or killing pirates, running cargo or smuggling goods, and various other tasks.  CharactersKayron Jarvis - Pilot of the DarkStar One Eona - Mysterious woman that joins Kayron as a co-poilot Robert - Friend of Kayron's father Kayron's Father - Creator of the DarkStar One. Was killed and gifted the DarkStar One to Kayron.</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9503">Project Sylpheed: Arc of Deception</game><game id="5565">Freelancer</game><game id="22771">X3: Terran Conflict</game><game id="16484">Space Rangers 2: Rise of the Dominators</game><game id="18775">Space Rangers</game><game id="22157">Space Rangers 2: Reboot</game><game id="10309">Descent: Freespace - The Great War</game><game id="12541">Freespace 2</game><game id="19585">Descent: Freespace: Silent Threat</game><game id="8415">Independence War: The Starship Simulator</game><game id="12111">Independence War 2: Edge Of Chaos</game><game id="3929">Independence War Deluxe</game><game id="11767">Deep Space</game><game id="14447">EVE Online</game><game id="10902">Elite</game><game id="4830">Colony Wars</game><game id="4544">Colony Wars: Vengeance</game><game id="36681">Fusion: Genesis</game><game id="37043">X3: Albion Prelude</game><game id="16330">Frontier: Elite II</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1825082-box_dsoba.png</image></root>