<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31265</id><name>Scourge of War: Gettysburg</name><description>Scourge of War: Gettysburg is the creation of NorbSoftDev, an independent game developer who specializes in Civil War simulation games.The game itself is solely focused on the Battle of Gettysburg, which took place July 1st through 3rd 1863 in Gettysburg, Pennsylvania. The battle is split up into a twenty mission campaign representing actual skirmishes and battles that took place over the three days. The scenarios can be played in any order; however if you play in the order given, the results from the previous battle will carry over to the next.The missions are split into four different map regions for which the player will battle on. Each map is accurate to scale of the real battlefield, giving the player an immense amount of space to maneuver. The order of battle in each scenario is also accurate to actual events, meaning the correct units and officers are present on the battlefield. Each scenario varies in the players importance, certain missions may ask you to command only a few divisions of infantry, while others may give you the command over the whole field.There is also a "Sandbox", or open play, feature that allows you a nearly infinite variety of "what ifs". Choose your side, choose your brigade, division, or corps. There are an incredible number of options to modify play and many mods and new maps coming out all the time. A very active and talented community. Scourge of War supports multiplayer with at least 16 players.Orders and messages are transported by couriers in real-time, and the couriers can be shot down. Since the release, four expansions have been released; Scourge of War: Pipe Creek, Scourge of War: Antietam, Scourge of War: Chancellorsville and Scourge of War: Brandy Station. On June, 26th, 2013 the 150th anniversary edition was released, containing Scourge of War and all expansions.</description><genres><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25284">Take Command - 2nd Manassas</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/268/1370885-scourge_of_war_gettysburg.jpg</image></root>