<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31451</id><name>The Book of Unwritten Tales</name><description>StoryThe gremlin archaeologist Mortimer MacGuffin has finally discovered the whereabouts of an artifact of untold power; one that could affect the ongoing war between good and evil. Having sent his assistant Berry to contact the human Arch-Mage, Mortimer worries that the message may have been intercepted. Sure enough he is captured by the Orc mage Munkus and his henchman. As Mortimer is taken away on a dragon, passing wood-elf princess Ivo, clambers onto the dragon to free him. She cuts Mortimer's cage free so it can fall on some snow, right in front of the young gnome Wilbur Weathervane. Mortimer passes Wilbur a ring and tells him he must reach the human Arch-Mage to warn of Mortimer's capture.With this news Wilbur endeavours to leave his snowy home in search of the Arch-Mage and adventure. During his journey he will meet up with Ivo, the treasure hunting sea captain Nate, become a wizard and defeat death itself.HumorThe Book of Unwritten Tales has many jokes and digs at videogame conventions, specifically with RPG games even going so far as to have to NPC characters addicted to an "online" game. The game in question allows the players to escape the everyday fantastical world for a world off parking tickets and tax returns. At one point Ivo remarks that she should be the main character of the game, rather than the diminutive gremlin archaeologist. Captain Nate points out how a head on a stick would affect the game's PEGI rating.There's also plenty of pop-culture references to movies like Full Metal Jacket, Star Wars, Snow White and the Seven Dwarves and Indiana Jones.PC System RequirementsMinimumOS:Windows XP SP 3 (32bit) / Vista SP 2 / Windows 7 SP 1Processor:Pentium IV 2 GHz / Athlon 2.4 GHzMemory:2 GB RAMGraphics:Direct-X 9c compliant video card with 128 MB RAM, PixelShader 2.0DirectX®:9.0cHard Drive:6 GB HD spaceRecommendedOS:Windows XP SP 3 (32bit) / Vista SP 2 / Windows 7 SP 1Processor:3 GHzMemory:4 GB RAMGraphics:Direct-X 9c compliant video card with 256 MB RAM, PixelShader 2.0DirectX®:9.0cHard Drive:6 GB HD spaceMac System RequirementsMinimumOS:Mac OS X 10.6/Mac OS X 10.7Processor:1.4GHz Intel Mac Core DuoMemory:1500 MB RAMGraphics:Intel GMA-950-Grafikkarte with 64MB VRAM or betterHard Drive:6 GB HD space</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3019">The Secret of Monkey Island</game><game id="10528">Monkey Island 2:  LeChuck's Revenge</game><game id="25513">Ceville</game><game id="12260">Simon the Sorcerer</game><game id="161">Simon the Sorcerer II: The Lion, the Wizard and the Wardrobe</game><game id="37503">The Dark Eye: Chains of Satinav</game><game id="40544">Louisiana Adventure</game><game id="42346">The Raven</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3948/1386456-bout300.jpg</image></root>