<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31463</id><name>Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Blacklist</name><description>OverviewSam Fisher's return as the head of Fourth Echelon sees the return of the series' cinematic mood, with mechanics such as Mark and Execute. While the E3 stage demo showed the return of familiar characters such as Anna Grimsdottir, Sam is noticeably not voiced by Michael Ironside. Among the new gadgets in Sam's arsenal are electrocuting bolts, as demonstrated by Sam firing into a puddle to incapacitate two guards.The new game will incorporate Kinect voice controls for the Xbox 360 version to allow the player to attract a guard's attention or call an airstrike. Sam will now also be able to customize his weapon loadout and mix and match different pieces of armor to allow for a more custom gameplay experience. The mark and execute feature from Splinter Cell: Conviction will return and is now improved by allowing the player to stay mobile during the execution phase.FeaturesReturning FeaturesSplinter Cell: Conviction removed a lot of features that had always been present in previous Splinter Cell games. Splinter Cell: Blacklist has brought some back.Dragging bodiesNon-lethal TakedownsMultiple paths that allow multiple playstylesCustom loadouts from Splinter Cell Chaos TheoryNight Vision GogglesSide ObjectivesThermal Vision (sort of, it apears to be sonor goggles with a color pallet swap)Zip-liningRapellingUsing the knife to cut through fabricInverted takedownsSticky ShockersSleeping GasAirfoil Rounds, now called Noise BoltsCloser Than Ever Animation (CTE)Hacking, but without the minigameNew FeaturesPerfectionist Mode, this removes the ability to see through walls with sonor vision and thermal vision, it also enhances the AI and prevents CQC attacks from the front. Sam also dies after being shot once.Over 90 CQC animationsSam can hang from ledges even when there is no wall to support his feetFlying recon droidCrossbowAn animation that bridges the gap between normal movement and CTEUnconscious enemies can be woken upPC System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows® XP (SP3) / Windows Vista® (SP2) / Windows® 7 (SP1) / Windows® 8Processor: 2.53 GHz Intel® Core™2 Duo E6400 or 2.80 GHz AMD Athlon™ 64 X2 5600+ or betterMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: 512 MB DirectX® 10–compliant with Shader Model 4.0 or higherDirectX®: 10Hard Drive: 25 GB HD spaceSound: DirectX 10–compliant DirectX 9.0c–compliantAdditional: Peripherals Supported: Windows-compatible keyboard, mouse, headset, 3D glasses, optional controller (Xbox 360 Controller for Windows recommended)RecommendedProcessor: 2.66 GHz Intel® Core™2 Quad Q8400 or 3.00 GHz AMD Phenom™ II X4 940 or betterMemory: 4 GB RAMDirectX®: 10Hard Drive: 25 GB HD spaceSound: (5.1 surround sound recommended)Other Requirements: Broadband Internet connection</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26095">Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon: Future Soldier</game><game id="39575">Metal Gear Solid: Ground Zeroes</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/82063/2554367-blacklist.jpg</image></root>