<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31481</id><name>NHL Slapshot</name><description>OverviewOutdoor Greatness.     NHL Slapshot is EA's first hockey game for the Wii, and it seems to be aimed towards a younger audience. It will feature "Peewees to Pros" mode, a variation of the main NHL series' Be A Pro mode and a hockey stick peripheral. Wayne Gretzky will be on the cover, as well as be prominently featured in the game.  Judging from promotional materials, the game seems to be running on a modified version of the engine used for EA's NHL games on the previous generation of consoles (PS2, Xbox) as well as the PC.  The producers have claimed that the game will run at a smooth 60 frames per second.Stick PeripheralSpeak softly and carry a small stick.       Every copy of the game includes a 21 inch (53 centimeter) stick peripheral that holds the Wiimote and Nunchuk and can accurately detect wrist and slap shots, poke checks, and cross checks. The stick is not WiiMotion Plus compatible as the Nunchuk serves the purpose of the WiiMotion Plus. The analog stick on the Nunchuk is used for skating and triggers are used for pass and deke modifiers.  Creative director and former NHL goaltender David Littman designed the prototype stick peripheral by sawing down a real hockey stick and duct taping the Wiimote and Nunchuk to it.      FeaturesPeewee to Pro Anachronistic Greatness.     Similar to the Be a Pro mode found in the main NHL series as well as EA's FIFA games, Peewee to Pro allows players to take Wayne Gretzky, a created player, or an existing NHL star (like Sidney Crosby or Roberto Luongo) from the ranks of Peewee hockey (which is played three-on-three and in outdoor rinks) all the way through the junior and professional levels (both of which are regular five-on-five action).  If the user doesn't control Wayne Gretzky, the Great One will act as a coach as the player progresses through their career.  The game will feature a CHL license just like NHL 11 and players can be signed, traded, and experience all of the other key features from the Be a Pro mode found in the other NHL games. Mini-GamesOne of the mini-games in NHL Slapshot is Shooter Versus Goalie, a one-on-one, split-screen multiplayer mode where one player fires pucks at the goalie, who is controlled by the other player.  The Free 4 All mode found in EA's previous-generation NHL titles also returns, allowing four players to play at once as they control NHL stars and try to score on a CPU goaltender.  Other Modes The game will also allow players to play through a single NHL season or just a single Stanley Cup Finals series, like the Battle for the Cup mode found in the Xbox 360 and PS3 versions of the game.  Soundtrack NHL Slapshot features a licensed soundtrack as many officially licensed sports games do.  Both of EA's 2010-released hockey titles feature a remarkably authentic playlist, as many of the songs in the game are often played at real-life hockey games.  NHL Slapshot will have all of the following songs (which are also found in NHL 11):   Danko Jones - Full of Regret - Below The Belt2 Unlimited - Twilight Zone - Get Ready!Black Box - Strike It Up - DreamlandBlack Rebel Motorcycle Club - Mama Taught Me Better - Beat The Devil’s TattooBouncing Souls - ¡Olé! - Hopeless RomanticDarude - Sandstorm - Before The StormDropkick Murphys - Shipping Up To Boston (Live) - Live On Lansdowne, Boston MAEurope - The Final Countdown - The Final CountdownFoxy Shazam - Unstoppable - Foxy ShazamRamones - Blitzkrieg Bop - RamonesThe Black Keys - Howlin’ For You - Brothers</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="39">Hockey</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="30340">NHL 2K11</game><game id="29997">NHL 11</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1795335-box_nhlslap.png</image></root>