<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31526</id><name>Dance On Broadway</name><description>Overview A spin-off of Ubisoft's casual music/rhythm series,    Just Dance, Dance on Broadway replaces the typical dance tunes with broadway showtunes and features a single mode of play for up to four players. Like the original, lyrics to each of the songs can be displayed on the screen. It was released for the Wii on June 22, 2010, and for the PS3 (with Move support) on March 15, 2011. Gameplay  Presentation To play, users simply hold the Wii remote and mimic the dance moves of their on-screen character. The game uses some mysterious motion tracking algorithm to judge the accuracy of the player and issue points but there is never any way to fail or lose points. Unlike Just Dance and its sequel which use heavily filtered full motion video of live dancers, Dance on Broadway's characters are polygonal models. Depending on the song their appearance, costumes, backgrounds and other on-screen displays change to mimic those of the chosen song or source material. Characters performing 'All that Jazz', for example, wear flapper-esque dresses while they sport make-up, garter belts, and studded leather clothes during 'Time Warp'.   Dance on Broadway also introduces choreographed dances for multiple players with specific moves alternating in direction and timing depending on the song. 'I Just Can't Wait to be King' features unique routines for players as two represent Simba and the other two represent Rafiki. More diverse backgrounds and animations have been added over the original Just Dance including dramatic set changes and effects set in time with the lyrics and even non-player characters. 'Time Warp' sees a bumbling boy and girl who are supposed to represent Brad and Janet mingling with the player characters while other songs feature background dancers. All stages begin as the camera flies through a crowded theater and the red curtain parts.Tracklist A total of 20 songs are included in Dance on Broadway on the Wii, all covers of the original songs:  'All that Jazz' from Chicago'Roxie' from Chicago'Dreamgirls' from Dreamgirls'Time Warp' from The Rocky Horror Picture Show'You Can't Stop the Beat' from Hairspray'Good Morning Baltimore' from Hairspray'Let the Sunshine In/Aquarius' from Hair'Cabaret' from Cabaret'My Favorite Things' from The Sound of Music'Lullaby of Broadway' from Unspecified source recording'Fame' from Fame'Little Shop of Horrors' from Little Shop of Horrors'Thoroughly Modern Millie' from Thoroughly Modern Millie'Bend and Snap' from Legally Blonde'Money, Money' from Cabaret'One Night Only' from Dreamgirls'Luck be a Lady' from Guys and Dolls'I Just Can't Wait to be King' from Lion King'Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious' from Mary Poppins'We're in the Money' from Gold Diggers of 1933 The PS3 version includes 5 additional songs, including:"Ease on Down the Road" (The Wiz)  "There's No Business Like Show Business" (Annie Get your Gun)  "Out Tonight" (RENT) "Diamonds Are a Girl's Best Friend" (Gentlemen Prefer Blondes)"Rich Man's Frug" (Sweet Charity)</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="32238">Gold's Gym: Dance Workout</game><game id="31724">Michael Jackson: The Experience</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2331126-box_jddob.png</image></root>