<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3157</id><name>The Simpsons: Hit &amp; Run</name><description>OverviewVisit Iconic Simpson LocationsThe Simpsons Hit and Run is an open world action/adventure game based on the hit cartoon series  The Simpsons. The game was developed by  Radical Entertainment, published by  Vivendi Universal and released for the  Nintendo GameCube,  Xbox,  PlayStation 2 and  PC on September 16th in North America and October 24th in Europe. The voice cast of the television series all reprise their roles as the residents of  Springfield. The game received generally positive reviews upon release, with experts commending its fun gameplay and visual representation of the Simpsons universe.The game is entirely  backward compatible with the  Xbox 360, with emulation only suffering from slight "screen tearing" at times.StoryThe story was penned by the writers of the television series. You can take control of five different characters including  Homer,  Marge,  Bart,  Lisa and  Apu. You are tasked with discovering the root of the mysterious events happening in Springfield; as a swarm of robot wasps are unleashed upon the city.GameplayThe game employs an 'open-world' style of play, with many play elements borrowed from the  Grand Theft Auto games, albeit with significantly more family friendly overtones. For example, instead of car jacking, the player simply gets in the vehicle with the driver.CollectiblesCostumesOver the course of the game, the player collects coins that can be spent in a variety of ways. One way of throwing these away is to buy outfits for the different characters, many of which are referential to specific episodes of the show.Don costumes from to the show HomerHomer CasualHomer Muumuu (King-Size Homer, Season 7)Homer normalHomer Chosen One (Homer the Great, Season 6) BartBart Tall (Radioactive Man, Season 7)Bart NinjaBart NormalBart Football (Bart Star, Season 9) LisaLisa Cool (Summer of 4ft 2, Season 7)Lisa Floreda ($pringfield, Season 5)Lisa Hockey (Lisa on Ice, Season 6)Lisa Normal MargeMarge NormalMarge Classy (Scenes from the Class Struggle in Springfield, Season 7)Marge Police (The Springfield Connection, Season 6)Marge Intimate ApuApu ArmyApu American (Much Apu About Noting, Season 7)Apu B-Sharps (Homer's Barbershop Quartet, Season 5)Apu NormalBart AgainBart's Good Twin HugoBart CadetBartmanHomer AgainHomer DirtyEvil HomerDonut-Headed HomerVehiclesLike the clothing, many of the vehicles in Hit  Run can be purchased using coins. However, others are unlocked by winning races and completing missions.Level 1You will see vehicles new and old to the Simpson universeFamily SedanElectaurusDuff TruckSurveillance VanPlow King (Mr. Plow, Season 4)Pickup TruckLevel 2Honor Roller (Saturdays of Thunder, Season 3)SedanLimoFire TruckMr. Plow (Mr. Plow, Season 4)WWII VehicleLevel 3Malibu Stacey Car (I Love Lisa, Season 4)Book Burning MobileNerd CarDonut TruckSchool BusPrinciple Skinner's SedanLevel 4Canyonero (The Last Temptation of Krust, Season 9)Clown CarKrusty's LimoCuratorTractorKremlinLevel 5LonghornEl Carro LocoCola TruckPolice CarCar Built For Homer (Oh Brother, Where Art Thou?, Season 2)Hover CarLevel 6Ferrini Red36 Stutz BearCatArmoured TruckChase SedanGlobex Super Villain Car (You Only Move Twice, Season 8)BanditLevel 770's Sports Car (The Way We Was, Season 2)Open Wheel Race CarHearseHover Bike (Lemon of Troy, Season 6)Zombie CarMr. Burns' Limo</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3563">Wreckless: The Yakuza Missions</game><game id="6731">Grand Theft Auto: Liberty City Stories</game><game id="17036">Grand Theft Auto: Vice City</game><game id="20679">Saints Row 2</game><game id="10264">Grand Theft Auto: Vice City Stories</game><game id="5618">Saints Row</game><game id="39985">Archie's Riverdale Run</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2276098-box_tshar.png</image></root>