<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31633</id><name>Eversion</name><description>OverviewThe original version of EversionEversion is an indie 2D platformer created by Zaratustra Productions for the PC. The concept was to create a game that would start working against the player by slowly introducing bizarre and frightening elements over the arc of its progression, more than implying that dark forces are beginning to take over. The game was originally produced for a TIGSource competition in late 2008 inspired by H.P. Lovecraft's Commonplace Book, from which Eversion uses the quote: "sounds - possibly musical - heard in the night from other worlds or realms of being."Eversion was originally released in November 2008 on Zaratustra's web site, and has been patched multiple times since its release to improve playability. On June 7th, 2010, an improved version (formerly called Eversion HD) was released for the Steam gaming platform for $4.99, which adds higher-resolution graphics, controller support, achievements, leaderboards for time trials, support for custom levels on time trials, and an exclusive hidden third ending.GameplayEversion is a 2D platformer where players take control of Zee Tee, a wide-eyed walking flower, on his quest to rescue the Princess of the Flower Kingdom from the Ghulibas of the North. The player heads right to a flag at the end of the level, jumping on enemies' heads and collecting gems. Along with side-to-side movement and a jump button, the player has control of an "evert" button.Aside from being used to navigate menus, the "evert" button initially appears useless; however, guiding your character into a certain spot and pressing that button takes you to a different version of the game world (called "eversion layers"). Many elements are in the same place, but their characteristics have changed -- music and colors change; enemies walk at slower or faster speeds; bricks become breakable; clouds become solid (or immaterial); shrubs become solid (or even deadly); and new entities are added. There are a total of eight eversion layers, each with their own characteristics:NormalDeceptionErosionDesolationConfusionApprehensionCommotionInductionThe game contains seven levels, each with a set of gems to collect. Collecting all 240 gems in the game unlocks the Induction layer in the seventh level. Completing the level in that eversion layer gives you access to a final, eighth level. Completing that level gives you the good ending. (While completing the seventh level in any other eversion layer gives you the bad ending) Completing level 7 or level 8 (via a hidden exit) in the "Desolation" layer gives you a secret ending.PC System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Windows XP or laterProcessor: Single core 1GHz+Memory: 64MB or moreGraphics: 640 x 480 resolution or higherDirectX®: N/AHard Drive: 20 MBSound: Required</description><genres><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20716">Braid</game><game id="21868">The Misadventures of P.B. Winterbottom</game><game id="25716">And Yet It Moves</game><game id="29745">VVVVVV</game><game id="25681">Cocoron</game><game id="15544">Super Mario Bros.</game><game id="22737">Yume Nikki</game><game id="40513">Irisu Syndrome</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/347/1396987-evboxart.png</image></root>