<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31640</id><name>WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2011</name><description>New FeaturesA new physics engine has been built for the game. When a Superstar goes through a table, the area and force of impact will change the animation. The table will also crumble in line with the impact. Such as if the opponent is thrown through the side of the table the table in buckle and fall instead of breaking.A new weapon system is in place. Weapons will break depending on where it is impacted. Weapons can also be used in new ways; for example, a chair can now be thrown at an opponent.Players no longer have to grind levels for their created Superstars. All points will be available as soon as you create your Superstar.The most requested match upgrade has finally been addressed. The Hell in A Cell match now has a larger cage similar to its real life counter part and you now have the ability to use weapons within the match. You are also now able to send your opponent through the cell which will also use the new physics engine. The door from the cell is gone with only way out being to do a "Cell Finisher" in which you throw your opponent through the cell.WWE Universe Mode. Gone is the Career mode of old. In its place is the living WWE Universe mode. When turned on, the game will automatically create a show with a match card based on the rivalries and friendships that you have in place, in which you can adjust to your liking. The game will remember your changes for future shows. It also plays cutscenes before, during and after your matches. These cutscenes are based on many factors such as if you have a rivalry with an opponent, a title mach coming up, etc. This mode can be turned off.In Ladder and Money in the Bank Ladder matches, instead of waiting for the belt meter to empty, the player will engage in a minigame which requires in pulling the right thumbstick in a certain direction. Also winning this match in WWE Universe mode will allow you to cash in the contract at any time for a title match.Road to  WrestleMania has been greatly overhauled, allowing you to play as one of these WWE Superstars:  John Cena,  Rey Mysterio,  Christian,  Chris Jericho, or  the Undertaker . Road to WrestleMania now allows you to roam backstage and interact with other WWE Superstars and pick fights at will. But when you enter the ring, it takes the same form as previous years with matches and story segments happening in front of the crowd.Match TypesOne on OneNormal MatchInferno MatchFirst BloodHell in a CellIron ManLadderLast Man StandingSubmissionSteel CageTableTLCBackstageExtreme RulesTwo on TwoTag TeamTornado TagMixed TagHell in a Cell Tornado TagLadder Tornado TagSteel Cage Tornado TagTable Tornado TagTLC Tornado TagElimination TagBackstageExtreme RulesTriple ThreatNormalHell in a CellLadderSteel CageTableTLCExtreme RulesFatal-4-WayNormalBattle RoyalHell in a CellLadderSteel CageTableTLCExtreme Rules6-ManBattle RoyalNormal TagElimination TagElimination ChamberArmageddon Hell in a CellLadderHandicapGauntletOne on Two TornadoOne on Two TagOne on Three TornadoOne on Three TagTwo on Three TagRoyal Rumble10-Man Royal Rumble20-Man Royal Rumble30-Man Royal RumbleChampionship ScrambleChampionshipsActive (Can only be defended in WWE Universe Mode)WWE ChampionshipWorld Heavyweight ChampionshipIntercontinental ChampionshipUnited States ChampionshipUnified WWE Tag Team ChampionshipWomen's ChampionshipDivas ChampionshipUnlockable (Can be defended in Exhibition Mode)WCW ChampionshipECW ChampionshipHardcore ChampionshipCruiserweight ChampionshipMillion Dollar ChampionshipRosterRAW Batista Chris Jericho David Hart Smith Edge Evan Bourne Ezekiel Jackson Goldust John Cena John Morrison Mark Henry Primo R-Truth Randy Orton Santino Marella Shawn Michaels Sheamus The Miz Ted DiBiase Triple H Tyson Kidd Vince McMhaon Vladimir Kozlov William Regal Yoshi Tatsu Zack RyderSmackDown Big Show Chavo Guerrero Chris Masters Christian CM Punk Cody Rhodes Dolph Ziggler Drew McIntyre FinlayHornswoggle Jack Swagger JTG Kane Kofi Kingston Luke Gallows Matt HardyMike Knox MVP Paul Bearer Rey Mysterio Shad Shelton Benjamin The Undertaker Vance ArcherWWE Legends "Stone Cold" Steve Austin The Rock Bret Hart Jimmy "Superfly" Snuka Jake "The Snake" Roberts Ricky "The Dragon" Steamboat Rob Van DamDivas Alicia Fox Beth Phoenix Brie Bella Eve Torres Gail Kim Kelly Kelly Maryse Melina Natalya Michelle McCool Mickie James Nikki BellaDownloadable ContentFan Axxess (released October 26, 2010)FeaturesAll UnlockablesWWE Superstar Attribute EditorCustomizable Leaderboard Fan Axxess BadgePre-payment for all future downloadable contentOnline Axxess (released October 26, 2010)FeaturesOnline Multiplayer UnlockedWWE Community CreationsWWE Discount Pack 1 (released October 26, 2010 -- free with all new copies of the game)Superstars/DivasChris MastersAlternate Ring Attire Rey Mysterio (Day of the Dead) Kelly Kelly (Sexy Devil)WWE Discount Pack 2 (released December 21, 2010)Superstars/Divas Wade Barrett Justin Gabriel David Otunga The British Bulldog Lex Luger LaylaAlternate Ring Attire Shad Shawn Michaels (WrestleMania VIII)ArenasNXT (Season 1 stage)WWE Discount Pack 3 (Early 2011)Alternate Ring Attire John Cena (Purple and Yellow shirt) Undertaker (Big Evil "American Bad Ass") CM Punk (Straight Edge Society mask)ArenasWCW NitroBret Hart DLC (Early 2011)Previously a Best Buy exclusive,  Bret Hart is now able to be purchased by all users.Pre-order BonusesBest BuyReceive Bret Hart as a playable characterToys 'R' UsReceive The Undertakers Ministry of Darkness alternate attireAmazon.comReceive "The Viper pack" containing 3 alternate attires for Randy Orton (Referee, Suit, alternate shirt)Receive $10 off a future video game purchase with Amazon.Wal-MartReceive the Tribute to the Troops arenaGameStop/EBgamesReceive $20 off either WWE Survivor Series (11/21/10) or WWE Tables, Ladders  Chairs (12/19/10)Special UK-Exclusive Editions (360 and PS3)Hit Man EditionBret Hart Themed BoxBret Hart Art CardBret 'Hit Man' Hart: Best There Is, Best There Was, The Best There Ever Will Be DVDExclusive Bret Hart DLC CharacterAvailable from GAME and GamestationLord of Darkness EditionThe Undertaker Themed BoxThe Undertaker Art CardUnforgiven 2007 DVDUndertaker Ministry Attire UnlockAvailable from Play.comViper EditionRandy Orton Themed BoxRandy Orton Art CardNo Mercy 2007 DVDRandy Orton Three-Attire Pack (T-Shirt, Suit and Referee)Available from TescoXbox 360 InstallationThe amount of memory it takes to install this game is 5.3 GB.Known glitches/bugsUser created crowd signs will cause the to Wrestlemainia campaign to freeze.</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre><genre id="10">Wrestling</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20469">TNA iMPACT!</game><game id="29222">TNA iMPACT: Cross the Line</game><game id="31641">WWE All Stars</game><game id="20723">WWE Legends of WrestleMania</game><game id="18333">Backyard Wrestling 2: There Goes the Neighborhood</game><game id="13440">Backyard Wrestling: Don't Try This at Home</game><game id="6945">ECW Anarchy Rulz</game><game id="8647">ECW Hardcore Revolution</game><game id="30637">Lucha Libre AAA Heroes del Ring</game><game id="14786">WCW vs. nWo: World Tour</game><game id="1204">WCW Mayhem</game><game id="7908">WCW Nitro</game><game id="775">WCW: World Championship Wrestling</game><game id="3213">WWF Wrestlemania</game><game id="28430">WWF Royal Rumble</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1886645-box_wwevsraw11.png</image></root>