<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31643</id><name>Hydorah</name><description>OverviewHydorah is a freeware indie shoot-em-up with gameplay similar to Gradius and R-Type. There are sixteen levels with branching paths and multiple endings.Weapons and Power-Up SystemAt the beginning of the game, the ship has a default forward firing railgun and missiles which requires ammunition to fire. After beating a stage, a new weapon will usually be granted. Weapon loadouts can be freely selected and swapped around between stages. Eventually, there will be fifteen weapons to choose from: Five main gun types, five subweapons, and five power weapons. Generally, main weapons are forward firing and subweapons are bombs that are launched above and below the ship. Weapons in the power slot require ammunition and consist of things like temporary invincibility and screen-clearing bombs..Many of the weapons which can be obtained are close approximations of weapons in the Gradius series: The Laser, Twin Missile, and Option are all represented here, among others.There are two main power-up types: Green/Red and Yellow/Blue. The color of the power-up determines what is received: Green powers up the main gun, while red powers up the subweapons. Yellow provides ammunition for the weapon in the power slot and blue increases the speed of your ship. After appearing as one color, they will switch colors after a few seconds.SoundtrackAll songs are made by Gryzor87, except 'Shinobi Stage 1' and 'Game Over' by Sega.Track No.TitleRunning Time01Shinobi Stage 102:1002The Windancer03:1303Moving Phase02:1404NGC (Ninja Gambling Club)02:5805Walk and Watch02:3006The Silent Wind04:2007Bay Area02:5908Reflected Soul02:4609Ninjatech Corporation03:5110Assassins’ Lair05:4111Kosugi is Back04:0812Mission Twelve01:5713Game Over00:33</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15508">Gradius</game><game id="7617">Gradius III</game><game id="10201">Gradius V</game><game id="13745">R-Type</game><game id="22998">R-Type Dimensions</game><game id="25236">Super Darius</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/31700/1396233-hydorah_01.jpg</image></root>