<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31651</id><name>FIFA 11</name><description>FIFA 11 is the newest football game in the long-running FIFA franchise by EA Sports. It was released on September 28 in North America and October 1 in Europe. The game covers the 2010/2011 football season. It has a number of new features and gameplay changes. The Japanese league will again not appear in FIFA, due to the teams exclusive contract with the Japanese developed game series Pro Evolution Soccer.GameplayFIFA 11 benefits from some few gameplay upgrades. A brand new passing mechanics, dubbed Pro Passing gives total control of the ball to the player. Players feel heavier and a bit slower than in previous versions. Suddenly changing direction will require more time and effort from your virtual player, making counter attacks harder. 360 degree Fight for Possession is also added to the mix when two players battle it out for a mid air ball.The ball's physics have been revamped making for a more realistic type of game. Passes are now harder to make and must be gauged accordingly. The game also reduces chip shot effectiveness. The shot will now have to be made from a slower, composed state. Once again, the gamer must watch out for his player's stamina and make substitutions accordingly. Defense is tighter and there has been made an overall improvement to slide tackling. The penalty system is the same as in FIFA World Cup.Refs now occupy a bigger part in the game. They come out of the locker rooms with the players, can be seen during replays, and are mentioned by the commentators. Handball is now an option.CareerIn the career mode, you can play or as a football player, as the manager or as both for 15 full seasons. As the player, you wish for global glory by partaking in multiple cups both in leagues and national teams. As the coach, you must manage your team. You can select which players play the next match by looking at who's got penalty cards, who's tired and injured. You make the team and choose their tactics (offensive, defensive...). You must also manage the club's budget by buying ans selling players. By winning cups, your superiors will be proud and won't start thinking about replacing you."Personality " is a new feature in FIFA 11 that makes each player stand out from the other. Each football player has 36 different attributes andXbox 360 Version57 characteristics that make them different from their other team mates. This also applies to real world players, making the game seem more realistic. For example, when Cristiano Ronaldo misses a ball, he starts protesting like in real life. Lissandro goes for every single ball, like on the real pitch. Of course, you can create your own characters thanks to the game's character creator ("Creation Center"). You can also create your own team, creating its own stadium with its own logo. You can create all this through the game's website and share your creation online. You can also put your face on a player and create your own chants.You can make your own slomo of your finest moments and post them online. During a match, the game also saves all the best moments (plays, goals, head butts) and saves them. Once the match is done, like on TV, the game makes a little montage out of all these fine moments.As always, FIFA 11 has all the official teams and leagues with over 600 teams, 30 championships and 1500 licensed players. The teams take into account all last years transfers including ones that happened just weeks before the game went gold (such as Gourcuff going to Lyon). To stay up to date, the game offers "Season Live" mode for the following leagues: Leugue 1, Barclay's Premier League, Liga BBVA, Bundesliga and Seria A. Season Live automatically updates every player of a chosen league every week. For example, if a player is injured in the real world, he will be too in FIFA 11. The mode starts you off with a free 5 day trial and then charges you 2.50$ for a league and 10$ dollars for all of them.Playing as the KeeperFor the first time ever in the FIFA franchise, you can play as the keeper. This available online and off and introduces the brand new 11 vs 11 mode. Note that when you're playing as the keeper, you can't control the rest of your team. The game helps you with your job as number 1: youGoalkeepers will be playable for the first time in the series' historyget a line showing you where the ball is going, the A.I. gives you advice on where to go and you can organise your team mates. Like in real life, you can puch the ball out of the air, challenge attackers in daring one-on-ones and make amazing saves.Chelsea FC and Czech Republic goalkeeper Petr Cech has been signed as the spokesperson for Be A Goalkeeper and will be featured in advertising, marketing and promotional campaigns.MultiplayerLike other EA multiplayer games, FIFA 11 requires an online pass to play online. You'll find the 1 vs 1 mode where each player chooses a team and 11 vs 11 where each player takes the role of a virtual football player."Next-Gen" PC VersionThe PC version of FIFA 11 will be much improved from previous FIFA games on PC. The last few installments of the series have been PS2 ports with slightly updated graphics and features. However, this year the series is finally moving to the "next-gen" engine seen in the PS3 and Xbox 360 versions of FIFA. On PC the game will use the next-gen engine from FIFA 10, with some improvements from 2010 FIFA World Cup.LeaguesThere are 31 available leagues this year with the new addition of the Russian league.AustraliaAustriaBelgiumBrazilCzech RepublicDenmarkEngland ( Premier League - Football League 2 )France ( Ligue 1 2 )Germany ( Bundesliga 1 2 )Rep. of IrelandItaly ( Seria A  B )KoreaMexicoNetherlandsNorwayPolandPortugalRussia ( NEW! )ScotlandSpain ( La liga  Secunda Division )SwedenSwitzerlandTurkeyUnited States (MLS)Social NetworkingThe PC, 360 and PS3 demos for FIFA 11 also featured connectivity with the Facebook app 'FIFA Superstars', unlocking certain features for the demo such as the ability to play with Arsenal or in Emirates Stadium, as well as bonuses for the app for various feats done in the demo such as scoring a goal. The full version of the game doesn't currently feature the same level of interaction.Playable DemoEA Sports released the demo on the 15th of September. It features the following playable teams: Barcelona, Bayern Leverkusen, Chelsea, Real Madrid, Lyon and Juventus. The demo is played in Real Madrid's stadium Santiago Bernabeo with each half lasting 3 minutes. As with the previous demo users can upload replays to the EA Sports website. By winning five matches in the demo Arsenal FC gets unlocked and becomes a playable team. The Emirates Stadium can also be unlocked by simply playing 10 matches. After restarting the demo Arsenal and the Emirates Stadium will still be unlocked.SoundtrackThe soundtrack for FIFA 11 features 33 songs from various artists around the world:Ana Tijoux – 1977Adrian Lux – Can’t SleepCaribou – OdessaCharlotte Gainsbourg – Trick PonyChromeo – Don’t Turn The Lights OnChoc Quib Town – El BomboDan Black – WonderDapuntobeat – :0 (Dos Punto Cero)Dum Dum Girls – It Only Takes One NightEbony Bones – W.A.R.R.I.O.R.Gorillaz – Rhinestone EyesGroove Armada – Paper RomanceHowl – ControllerJonsi – Around UsJump Jump Dance Dance – White Picket FencesLadytron – Ace of HzLCD Soundsystem – I Can ChangeLinkin Park – BlackoutLocnville – Sun In My PocketMalachai – SnowflakeMaluca – El TigerasoMark Ronson feat. Simon Le Bon and Wiley – Record CollectionMassive Attack – Splitting the AtomMGMT – Flash DeliriumRam Di Dam – FlashbacksScissor Sisters – Fire With FireThe Black Keys – Tighten UpThe Pinker Tones – SampleameTulipa – EfemeraTwo Door Cinema Club – I Can TalkWe Are Scientists – Rules Don’t StopYeasayer – O.N.E.Zemaria – The Space Ahead</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="40">Soccer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25791">Pro Evolution Soccer 2010</game><game id="20959">Pro Evolution Soccer 2009</game><game id="13165">Pro Evolution Soccer 2008</game><game id="19165">Sensible World of Soccer</game><game id="31217">Pro Evolution Soccer 2011</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2266508-box_fifa11.png</image></root>