<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31661</id><name>Trine 2</name><description>OverviewThe sequel to 2009's physics based co-operative action-platformer Trine was announced at E3 2010 and was released in December 2011.The sequel sees the return of the first game's original three protagonists:Zoya the ThiefThe Thief makes her way up to rooftops and over walls with her trusty grappling hook. Zoya is not so concerned about family or duty, but she is content to be a hero of the Trine, for she loves adventure.Zoya's love for treasure, however, often leads her astray.Zoya uses a bow as a weapon to kill enemies and uses it to solve puzzles.Pontius the KnightThe Knight is an eager champion of the kingdom, the protector of the common man with a great sense of justice. Armed with his sword, his shield and the powerful Storm Hammer, he's a formidable fighter.Pontius's great weakness is food. This shows around his waist.In the game Pontius is the tank. He has the most hit points and always attacks his enemies from up close. He can use his weight to solve puzzles.Amadeus the WizardDespite his ongoing research for finally learning the Fireball spell, the Wizard's talent is for conjuring peculiar boxes, and occasionally even planks. He can also levitate small inanimate objects.Amadeus is married to a lady by the name of Margaret. They have three children, all of whom know the Fireball spell.By using his levitate spells Amadeus is able to solve puzzles and drop objects on enemies. The fireballs he has at his disposal are also good for eliminating his foes.The game continues the story of the first game, adding new environments, new puzzles, new abilities for the three main characters and new types of enemies that will force the player to use their new abilities wisely. The game also features three-player online co-op, the previous Trine had co-op but was offline only.MultiplayerTrine 2 allows all story levels to be played co-op with up to 2 additional players, either online or local. Individual level progress does not matter in multiplayer, as any level can be played even if a participant hasn't reached it yet in single player. Each player will have to play as Amadeus, Zoya, and Pontius.Goblin Menace DLCFrozenByte announced a six-level DLC campaign at GamesCom 2012 which was released in September 2012. Entitled Goblin Menace, the add-on includes new environments, enemies, and character abilities (the latter of which will also be usable in the original levels as well).Director's Cut VersionTrine 2: Director's Cut was released as a launch title for Wii U's eShop on November 18, 2012. This version includes the Goblin Menace DLC pack. An additional new mode called Magic Mayhem with new levels featuring new gameplay concepts designed around the Wii U GamePad was originally planned but had to be scrapped to make the system's launch. This mode appearing as DLC is still a possibility but not very likely, according to a Frozenbyte statement from January 2013.The Director's Cut also features optional touch screen controls and Off-TV Play as well as a post launch patch that adds support for the Wii U Pro Controller.SoundtackThe original soundtrack was created by the Finnish composer and musician Ari Pulkkinen.Tracklist:Trine 2 Main Theme — 02:33The Story Begins — 02:57The Mighty Warrior Pontius — 01:38The Mighty Warrior Pontius Part II — 01:38Thieves Guild — 01:45Mudwater Dale — 03:01Waltz of the Temple Forest Elves — 03:45Goblins! — 01:12Mosslight Marsh — 03:31Snake, Oh It’s a Snake! — 01:29Petrified Tree — 03:40Goblins! Part II — 01:19Shadowed Halls — 03:45The Lost Court of Mushroom Caves — 03:12Hushing Grove — 03:43For the Kingdom! — 01:29Searock Castle — 04:49Eldritch Passages — 03:46Icewarden Keep — 04:01The Giant Dragon — 02:56Trine 2 Main Theme Storybook Version — 01:30System RequirementsPC RequirementsOS: Windows 7 / Vista / XPProcessor: 2.0 GHz CPU (Dual Core recommended)Memory: 1 GBHard Disk Space: 1.5 GBVideo Card: ATi Radeon HD 2400 or NVIDIA GeForce 7600 or better (Shader Model 3.0 needs to be supported)DirectX®: 9.0cSound: DirectX 9.0c compatibleMac RequirementsOS: OS X version Snow Leopard 10.6, or laterProcessor: Intel MacMemory: 1 GB RAMHard Disk Space: 1.5 GBVideo Card: NVIDIA GeForce 8600M or better / ATi Radeon 2400 or betterLinux RequirementsMinimum:OS: Ubuntu 12.04 LTSProcessor: 2.2 GHz CPUMemory: 1 GBGraphics: ATI Radeon HD 2400 or NVIDIA GeForce 7600 or better (OpenGL 2.1 needs to be supported)Hard Drive: 2.5 GBOpenGL: 2.1Recommended:OS: Ubuntu 12.04 LTSProcessor: 2.2 GHz CPUMemory: 1 GBGraphics: ATI Radeon HD 2400 or NVIDIA GeForce 7600 or better (OpenGL 2.1 needs to be supported)Hard Drive: 2.5 GBOpenGL: 2.1Additional: Trine 2 runs best with proprietary drivers and may not function correctly with open source drivers.</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5429">The Lost Vikings</game><game id="4134">Norse by Norse West: The Return of the Lost Vikings</game><game id="38390">The Cave</game><game id="5269">Oddworld: Abe's Oddysee</game><game id="37756">A-Men</game><game id="39484">Giana Sisters: Twisted Dreams</game><game id="37971">Party of Sin</game><game id="40876">Shadow of the Game</game><game id="44033">Giana Sisters: Twisted Dreams - Rise of the Owlverlord</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2478708-box_trine2.png</image></root>