<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31698</id><name>Need for Speed: Hot Pursuit</name><description>OverviewNeed for Speed: Hot Pursuit is a racing game that launched November 16, 2010. Criterion Games considers it a return to the series' roots. Criterion Games is responsible for the PlayStation 3, Xbox 360 and PC versions while Exient Entertainment is responsible for the Wii version. The game was well-received both critically and commercially, selling more than 5 million units.GameplayCat-and-mouse gameplayThe game takes place in an open world environment that spans over 100 miles of high-speed road. What sets this game apart from recent Need For Speed games is the ability to play as a police officer as well as a street racer, with full career modes for both. The racer's career mode is all about driving really fast, racing and outrunning the cops, while the police officer's career mode is all about chasing down the racers and busting them. The career mode for both racers and cops consists entirely of events, with no plot or story.Specifically, the police officer will have to ram or otherwise damage the racer's vehicle until its energy bar is depleted. The racer, on the other hand, will have to escape and avoid destruction. This mechanic is similar to that in the game's predecessors, such as Most Wanted or Carbon.The game is set in the fictional location Seacrest County. Players are able to race in a wide array of settings, including desert, forest, seaside and mountainous regions, both on-road and off in the form of shortcuts.Game ModesWhile playing through the offline "Career" mode, players will unlock various events which each adhere to a specific set of rules depending on the mode.Police ModesHot Pursuit - The player must attempt to shutdown a race in progress by wrecking the racers or using weapons against them. The number of racers, the number of "busts" required, and the weapons available change from event to event.Interceptor - This is a 1v1 gametype in which the cop must bust the racer before he is able to escape. The opposing racer is not limited to a track and is able to take any road in sight and may also turn around when the player least expects it. The weapons available change from event to event.Rapid Response - Essentially a time trial in which the player can pick from any car unlocked in the available class in an attempt to finish within a certain time.Preview - Another time trial variant in which the player is given a specific car and must finish within a certain time.Racer ModesRace - The player must beat opposing A.I. in a flat out race where any unlocked car within the given class can be chosen. No cops are present during these races and no weapons or abilities are present.Hot Pursuit - The player attempts to finish the race in first place as well as surviving cop pressure. Weapons are available and vary from event to event.Preview - Time trial variant in which the player is given a specific car and must finish within a certain time.Time trial - Any car can be used within the given class and the race must be finished within a certain time.Gauntlet - Another time trial variant, this time with police pressure and weapons available.Duel - Simply a 1v1 race to the finish.Weapons / AbilitiesRacersThe racers have different special abilities which they unlock as the race progresses, each mapped to a button on the d-pad. They include:Spike Strip - Disables the vehicle (as it spins and comes to a complete halt) for a short while. It will also do some damage to the vehicle.Jammer - Briefly disables the GPS of opponents, will jam the HUD of the chaser, and will also prevent the Cop from calling in any help (Spikes, Heli, Road Block, EMP). In addition, the Jammer stops EMP lock ons and disables deployed Spike Strips.Turbo - A more powerful nitrous boost. The entire screen of the racer will warp as the player activates this ability.EMP - Causes long range damage, as well as slightly slowing down the opponent and affecting handling.CopsThe cop will also be able to use different special abilities to bust the racer, each mapped to a button on the d-pad. They include:Spike Strips - Disables the vehicle (as it spins and comes to a complete halt) for a short while. It will also do some damage to the vehicle.Helicopter - The chopper will track down racers and thus increase the radius of the search area. It will also be able to lay down spike strips as the ability is upgraded to a higher level.Road Blocks - Sets up police cars to block the road ahead. If the racer or cop hits the road block they will take damage, but there is also a small area which racers may escape.EMP - Causes long range damage, as well as slightly slowing down the opponent and affecting handling.For both Racer and Cop, the abilities receive upgrades based on player progress. For example, the police chopper may not initially be able to lay down spike belts early in the game. As the player progresses, however, the chopper will be able to do such things. In addition, spike strips increase from 1 to 2 dropped at one time.The majority of cars have police variants. Some cars are exclusive to racers, while some are exclusive to the police. It is also worth noting that police variants of cars available in the game are generally slightly faster than the normal ones. The handling of cars in game is also much more similar to that in the early Burnout series games.Multiplayer ModesRace - 8-player races, no Cops.Hot Pursuit - 4 Racers vs 4 Cops.Interceptor - 1 Racer vs 1 Cop, free-roam.Most Wanted - Open world Cops vs Racers. The Cops must take down a specific racer, and the racers must protect them. (via Armed  Dangerous DLC)Arms Race - A race with weapons. (via Armed  Dangerous DLC)The game uses bounty as a form of experience points and it is universal for both players playing as police officers and street racers. The match options will be rated according to difficulty and carry a corresponding bounty payoff.AutologThe game's multi-player mode is brought together by Autolog. Autolog lets you keep track of your friend's times by pushing your friend's times, telling you on which track he did the time and how much you must do to beat it. Once you've beaten it, your time will be pushed back to your friend's console who'll be able to directly try to beat your new time. It also allows you to challenge them to pursuits, where one person plays as the cop while the other plays as the fugitive who's on the run. Autolog recommends ways to play the game depending on what the player's friends have been doing, and keeps track of your progress as you win bounty to unlock new cars.iPhone AppOn December 15, 2010, EA released a free iPhone Autolog app. The name of the app is "Need for Speed Autolog." As of November 8, 2011 the app has 15 ratings for an average score of 3/5 stars. Features of the app include:View Wall postsReply to Wall postsYou can see Dreamshots taken by friends, even save them to your deviceChange your profile photoSee all Autolog recommendations waiting for you in the game.Android AppA playable mobile version of the game. Features of the app include:AchievementsRequires Android OS 2.0 or later.Limited EditionOn August 17, 2010, it was announced that a Limited Edition of Need For Speed: Hot Pursuit would be released on all platforms (PS3, 360, PC) and will be the same price as the regular edition. It would include exclusive access to the Alfa Romeo 8C Competizione and the Ford Shelby GT500. It would also include early access to the Audi TT RS Coupe, the Chevrolet Camaro SS, Porsche Cayman S, and the Dodge Challenger SRT. Non-Limited Edition purchasers will have to earn those cars normally or buy from the NFS Store (built-in Marketplace).Loyalty RewardsUnlock an extra 500 Racer bounty and 500 Cop bounty if you meet the requirements of playing prior EA racing games:Burnout Paradise (360 | PS3 | PC)Need For Speed SHIFT (360 | PS3 | PC)Need For Speed World (PC)To redeem your rewards, you must login to the same account that both the prior racing game and Hot Pursuit share. Then from Settings  Loyalty Rewards and they will unlock for you.Base CarsA total number of 66 cars appear in the game. The following list states all cars featured in the retail edition of Hot Pursuit:1. Alfa Romeo 8C Competizione2. Alfa Romeo 8C Spyder3. Aston Martin DBS4. Aston Martin DBS Volante5. Aston Martin One-776. Aston Martin V12 Vantage7. Audi R8 5.2 FSI quattro8. Audi R8 Spyder 5.2 FSI quattro9. Audi TT RS Coupé10. Bentley Continental Supersports11. BMW M3 E9212. BMW M6 Convertible13. BMW Z4 sDrive35is14. Bugatti Veyron 16.415. Bugatti Veyron 16.4 Grand Sport16. Carbon Motors E717. Chevrolet Camaro SS18. Chevrolet Corvette Grand Sport19. Chevrolet Corvette Z0620. Chevrolet Corvette ZR121. Dodge Challenger SRT822. Dodge Charger SRT823. Dodge Viper SRT1024. Dodge Viper SRT10 ACR25. Ford Crown Victoria Police Interceptor26. Ford GT27. Ford Police Interceptor Concept28. Ford Shelby GT50029. Ford Shelby GT500 Super Snake30. Jaguar XKR31. Koenigsegg Agera32. Koenigsegg CCX33. Koenigsegg CCXR Edition34. Lamborghini Gallardo LP550-2 Valentino Balboni35. Lamborghini Gallardo LP560-436. Lamborghini Gallardo LP560-4 Spyder37. Lamborghini Gallardo LP570-4 Superleggera38. Lamborghini Murciélago LP 640-439. Lamborghini Murciélago LP 670-4 SV40. Lamborghini Reventón41. Lamborghini Reventón Roadster42. Maserati GranCabrio43. Maserati GranTurismo S Automatic44. Maserati Quattroporte Sport GT S45. Mazda RX-846. McLaren F147. McLaren MP4-12C48. Mercedes-Benz SL65 Black Series49. Mercedes-Benz SLR McLaren 722 Edition50. Mercedes-Benz SLR McLaren Stirling Moss51. Mercedes-Benz SLS AMG52. Mitsubishi Lancer EVOLUTION X53. Nissan 370Z Coupe54. Nissan 370Z Roadster55. Nissan GT-R SpecV (R35)56. Pagani Zonda Cinque57. Pagani Zonda Cinque Roadster58. Porsche 911 GT3 RS59. Porsche 911 Targa 4S60. Porsche 911 Turbo S Cabriolet61. Porsche 918 Spyder (Concept Study)62. Porsche Boxster Spyder63. Porsche Carrera GT64. Porsche Cayman S65. Porsche Panamera Turbo66. Subaru Impreza WRX STIDownloadable Content PacksSCPD Rebel PackWith this pack, the following Cop cars are made available to the Racers.Maserati Quattroporte Sport GT SAston Martin DBSAudio R8 5.2 FSI quattroMercedes-Benz SLR McLaren 722 EditionLamborghini ReventonBugatti Veyron 16.4Chevrolet Corvette Z06Version 1.1 / One Million Views YouTube ChallengeBentley Continental Supersports ConvertibleLamborghini Murciélago LP 650-4 RoadsterDodge Viper SRT10 Convertible Final EditionSuper SportsAdds 13 new Race and Pursuit events, as well as new achievements.Porsche 911 GT2 RSGUMPERT Apollo SBugatti Veyron 16.4 Super SportArmed  DangerousAdds two new games modes and achievementsMost Wanted - Open world Cops vs Racers. The Cops must take down a specific racer, and the racers must protect them.Arms Race - A race with weapons.Lamborghini Untamed10 new events, and 4 achievements/trophiesDiablo SVCountach LP5000 QVSesto ElementoPorsche Unleashed10 new events, and 4 achievements/trophiesPorsche 911 Turbo 1982 EditionPorsche 959911 SpeedsterSoundtrack30 Seconds to Mars - "Edge of the Earth" (featured in the Demo)Bad Religion - "The Resist Stance"Benny Benassi feat. Garry Go - "Cinema"Black Rebel Motorcycle Club - "Conscience Killer"Chiddy Bang - "Opposites of Adults"Deadmau5 feat. Sofi - "Sofi Needs A Ladder"Does It Offend You, Yeah? - "Being Bad Feels Really Good" (Titled "All the Same" to avoid offensive material)Funeral Party - "Giant Song"Greenspeaker - "Live like You Wanna Live"Hadouken! - "Bombshock"Killa Kela - "Get A Rise"Klaxons - "Echoes"Klaxons - "Twin Flames"Lazee feat. Dead by April - "Stronger"Lemonade - "Big Weekend"Lupe Fiasco feat. Matthew Santos - "Shining Down"Maximum Balloon feat. Theophilus London - "Groove Me"M.I.A. - "Born Free"New Politics - "Yeah Yeah Yeah"Pendulum - "Watercolour"Pint Shot Riot - "Nothing from You (Redenka Remix)"Plan B - "Stay Too Long (Pendulum Remix)"Teddybears - "Devil's Music"Travie McCoy - "Superbad (11:34)"We Have Band - "Divisive (Tom Starr Remix)"White Lies - "Bigger Than Us"Weezer - "Ruling Me"DemoThe Demo was released on October 26th, 2010, and will be available for download until November 9th, 2010 for the Xbox 360 and PS3. It consists of 2 events. The first accessible event is a Hot Pursuit event called Dark Horse, where Players play as a cop. They must attempt to stop 4 other A.I. racers before they reach their destination. To help with this, the player has 2 weapons at his disposal. The first is a Spike Strip that drops directly behind the player's car. The second is a road block that is setup in front of the player. The more racers taken out before the end of the race the more bounty players receive. Bounty is a form of XP that is used to level up either the cop or the racer. Players can choose between the Nissan 370Z and the Ford Crown Victoria.The second event is only accessible if the player has someone on their friends list that has also played the demo. It is a race event called Roadsters Reborn. It's a simple point to point race with 5 other A.I. racers and no cops. The player is rewarded more bounty the better they finish. The cars to choose from are the Nissan 370Z Roadster, BMW Z4 sDrive35is and Porsche Boxster Spyder.The Demo features only two songs: Pint Shot Riot's "Nothing from You (Redenka Remix)", and 30 Seconds to Mars' "Edge of the Earth" (which is also featured at the title screen). Both the 360 and the PS3 play game soundtrack in the Race Event only, there is no music in the Hot Pursuit event. Custom soundtracks on the PS3 and 360 are limited to saved playlists only. On the PS3, this effectively limits the player to locally-stored music, while the XBOX 360 allows for playlists saved on a media server.E3 2010The game was first shown during E3 2010. It was revealed during the EA press conference which opened with the game's reveal trailer. The game was then demoed on stage (where the people demoing the game had a slight technical problem with a loading screen) where the developers revealed the game's chase mechanics and explained Auto-Log.PC RequirementsMinimum SpecsOS: Windows® XP SP 3 (32-64 bits) / Windows Vista® (32-64 bits) / Windows 7® (32-64 bits)CPU: Intel Core® 2 Duo 1.8 GHZ or AMD Athlon X2 64 2.4GHZRAM: 1.5 GB Windows® XP / 2 GB Windows Vista® – Windows 7®DISC DRIVE: DVD-ROM, 8 speedHARD DRIVE: 6.5 GBVIDEO CARD: 256 MB DirectX® 9.0 compliant card with Shader Model 3.0 or higherSOUND CARD: DirectX 9.0 –compliant sound cardCOMPATIBLE VIDEO CARD CHIP SETS: ATI® RADEON® X1950, HD 2000/3000/4000/5000 series NVIDIA GeForce® 7/8/9/100/200 seriesONLINE: 2 – 8 players, 512 Kbps or faster</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5648">Burnout Paradise</game><game id="357">Burnout 3: Takedown</game><game id="16492">Burnout Revenge</game><game id="13514">Burnout 2: Point of Impact</game><game id="20484">Burnout</game><game id="25961">Blur</game><game id="9112">Crazy Taxi</game><game id="31634">Driver: San Francisco</game><game id="20927">Midnight Club: Los Angeles</game><game id="13281">Chase H.Q.</game><game id="17224">Chase H.Q. II: Special Criminal Investigation</game><game id="25523">Split/Second</game><game id="5977">Need for Speed III: Hot Pursuit</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1828913-box_nfshp.png</image></root>