<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31709</id><name>Ryse: Son of Rome</name><description>OverviewMarius and VitallionRyse: Son of Rome is a game developed by Crytek exclusively for the Xbox One. First revealed at Microsoft's E3 2010 press conference under the name of Codename: Kingdoms, Ryse is an action game taking place during Roman Empire, developed by Crytek. The initial version of the game focused heavily on the use of Kinect and was meant to be an Xbox 360 exclusive. After its announcement not much was heard about the property in the media.Footage of the game resurfaced at E3 2013. Most of the Kinect features had been dropped (with the exception of some voice commands) in favour of a more standard controller based action game. The game will be the first game to showcase Crytek's latest CRYENGINE (4th Generation). With Crytek's latest engine more than 100 characters can be on screen at any given time. Character models are indistinguishable in cut-scenes and while in combat The facial capture in RYSE is truly next generation.PlotSet in ancient Rome circa 68 A.D, the story follows roman solider Marius Titus. After barbarians kills his family, Marius will rise and build a army to take revenge against the barbarian horde.GameplayGladiator: Blood Brothers [Cooperative]Battle in the ColosseumRYSE will feature a coop mode set in a Colosseum. The Gladiator: Blood Brothers mode will pit two players against hordes of barbarians. Players must survive waves of enemies and complete the given objective. Enemy varieties are randomized with every match. The usual match will last between 10 to 30 minutes.Kinect IntegrationWith Kinect a player can give optional voice commands to units in the battlefield, launch fire suppressing arrows, or hold off incoming attacks.Smartglass Integration Smartglass will give the player the ability to manage inventory, to strategize when in battle and give you access to character upgrades. Users can track friend's games progress, share video clips with friends, and smart match with friends in multiplayer. Hints and in game tips are given to the player, with achievement integration. Your collectible progress will be tracked along with a player's campaign progress.ReleaseStandard Edition [$59.99] Day One Edition [$59.99] Limited ReleaseAs part of Xbox One's launch lineup, Ryse is participating in the Day One Edition program along with Dead Rising 3 and Forza Motorsport 5. A Day One edition will give access toLegionnaire's Trust Exclusive Sword - From the brotherhood of Metalworkers high in the Swiss Alps, this well crafted hammered blad that includes bonus in-game attributes.Ruins - Columns of an abandoned temple, Ruin will pit players against hordes of barbarians. Day One owners can invite friends who own the standard edition.</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3699/2571196-ryse+-+son+of+rome+-+cropped.jpg</image></root>