<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31713</id><name>Battlestar Galactica Online</name><description>StoryTakes place during Season 2 of the television series, where most of the space battles of the series happened.. While it will line-up with storyline elements seen in the show, there will be parts that fill-in-the-gaps for game-play purposes. GameplayThird-person space flight and on-foot action.Main weapons will auto-fire on lock (target), but missles will be player controlled. Either can be customized for playFeaturesPlay as Cylon or Human 15 ships are available on each side, among them the Cylon Raider and the Human ViperUp to 1500 simultaneous players per serverPvP and PvE environmentsBoth on and off-ship environmentsWill have out of cockpit experiences and quests to perform Likenesses from the television series:  Human William "Admiral" Adama portrayed by Edward James Olmos Kara "Starbuck" Thrace portrayed by Katee Sackhoff Lee "Apollo" Adama portrayed by Jamie Bamber Galen "Chief" Tyrol portrayed by Aaron Douglas  CylonNumber Six portrayed by Tricia HelferNumber Eight portrayed by Grace ParkNumber One (John Cavil) portrayed by Dean StockwellNumber Two (Leoben Conoy) portrayed by Callum Keith Rennie E3 2010 TrailerDepicts a scene where a Cylon Raider discovers a Colonial mining ship, and alerts a Cylon Base Star. The Base Star jumps in and launches Raiders and Heavy Raiders. A large number of Colonial Vipers counterattack the Cylons' strike craft, and the Galactica begins trading blows with the Base Star. The Vipers are seen fighting alongside some sort of new, heavier, Colonial craft. The Vipers' protection of the mining vessel could indicate the presence of escort missions in this game.   TechnologyThe game uses the Unity Engine and is  compatible with Mozilla Firefox and other browsers with the Unity plug-in. It is free to play and already released and live. Register is possible via battlestar-galactica.bigpoint.com </description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="40575">Dark Orbit</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/4/46619/1402230-bgo.png</image></root>