<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31729</id><name>GoldenEye 007</name><description>OverviewGoldenEye now updated for 2010.GoldenEye 007 is a first-person shooter developed by Eurocom and published by Activision for the Nintendo Wii and Nintendo DS on November 2nd, 2010. Released in tandem with James Bond 007: Blood Stone (for the other seventh-generation consoles), GoldenEye 007 is a re-imagining of the 1997 Nintendo 64 Rareware classic of the same name (as well as a looser re-imagining of the 1995 movie GoldenEye). Much of the original game's story and gameplay mechanics have changed, including the portrayal of Daniel Craig as James Bond, switching the setting from the post- Cold War 1990's era to a modern late 2000's setting (in similar vein to other James Bond films starring Daniel Craig), and re-doing the multiplayer component, including online multiplayer for up to eight players (complete with a persistent experience system with unlocks and achievements) as well as the classic four-player split-screen multiplayer.The game was ported to the Xbox 360 and PlayStation 3 and released a year later as GoldenEye 007: Reloaded, revamping the controls and graphics engine while boosting the player limit of online multiplayer to 16 and adding a special challenge mode known as "MI6 Ops Missions".MultiplayerGoldenEye supports four-player local split screen multiplayer and online play. The online mode supports up to eight players and features a full experience system complete with unlocks and achievements. In local multiplayer, characters from other James Bond films including Francisco Scaramanga, Jaws, and Oddjob are all playable.CharactersThe game includes the following characters from GoldenEye and other James Bond films as playable characters in local multiplayer:OddjobDr. NoErnst BlofeldJawsFrancisco ScaramangaBaron SamediRosa KlebbRed GrantJames BondNatalya SimonovaXenia OnatoppGeneral OurumovDmitri MishkinAlec TrevelyanZukovskyAs in the Nintendo 64 version, there is a long list of playable minor characters and minions such as: Slav, Hazmat, Soldier, Pilot, Security, Sky Briggs, Red-one, Red-four, Red-five, Red-nine, Pvt. Gurov, Pvt. Harkov, Pvt. Shkadov, Pvt. Kozmin, Jones, Davis, Smyth, Adams, Two-Two, Two-Four, Two-Six, Two-Seven, Sgt. Glebov, Sgt. Baikov, Sgt. Chzov, Sgt. Drashev, Five-One, Five-Two, Five-Three, Five-Four, Vincent, Boris, Allonso, Sgt. Morozov, Sgt. Zotkin, Sgt. Udalov and Sgt. Shubkin.ControlsThe Wiimote and Nunchuk control scheme is fully customizable and the Classic Controller control scheme allows for dual analog First Person Shooter controls. The Gamecube Controller is also usable, also allowing dual analog movement.Bundle with Gold Classic Controller ProGold Classic Controller Pro BundleA special edition gold Classic Controller Pro is bundled with the game in certain regions. This particular controller colour is exclusive to the bundle and not available separately, except on eBay. The gold colour of the Classic Controller Pro is a tribute to the Golden Gun from the 1974 Bond film The Man With the Golden Gun which inspired a special weapon and classic multiplayer mode in the original GoldenEye 007 Nintendo 64 title.GoldenEye 007 Bundle includes:GoldenEye 007 GameGolden Classic Controller ProAt initial release in certain regions the bundled edition was the only release available.</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1974390-box_ge007.png</image></root>