<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31755</id><name>Paper Mario: Sticker Star</name><description>OverviewPaper Mario: Sticker Star sees the first appearance of the Paper Mario series on the Nintendo 3DS. The game eschews the real-time combat of Super Paper Mario, returning to the turn-based combat system that defined earlier games in the series. It also introduces new gameplay mechanics including the titular stickers which Mario uses to attack enemies.StoryThe story starts off in the Mushroom Kingdom, during the yearly Sticker Fest. An event much similar to the Renaissance Festival, except instead of artisans, people craft stickers which contain magical powers that come from the 3-D world around them. Bowser, angry that he was not invited to the event, thinks it would be fun to play a prank on everyone during the festivities. But something goes wrong during Bowser's joke and Six Royal Stickers ended up becoming attached to Bowser and his minions, giving them new powers. It's up to Mario and a Sticker faerie named Kersti to set off and get the stickers and bring them back to the Mushroom Kingdom.Mario will travel to many new places, particularly new areas that deal with nature, such as snowy mountains and fiery volcanoes. As he retrieves the stickers he will gain new powers that he can use in combat and also to help him solve puzzles in the world around him. Eventually in the game Mario will even be able to create his own unique blend of stickers that can give players the certain edge they need.GameplayThe gameplay mechanics have returned to its turned-based style and sidescrolling platformer-style from the first two games, leaving out the action adventure themes and 3D platforming from Super Paper Mario.Paper Mario: Sticker Star will have the Jump and Hammer commands just like the previous games, this time it will have a redesigned layout for the 3DS , as well as a proper party system, with Mario accompanied by a single "partner" at a time. Some screenshots show characters such as Chain Chomp or Wiggler will be used as partners, rather than them being replaced by Pixls in the previous installment. Another screen shot shows an outlined object, suggesting that players will be able to use the stylus to certain object`s around the area to solve puzzles.According to the Official Nintendo Magazine in Europe, stickers are a major part of the gameplay. These objects appear in the form of stickers, and they will also have the ability to give power ups to Mario, such as the Frog Suit. They will also help solve puzzles in certain situations. There will also be a new Battle Slot Machine mechanic very similar to the Bingo mechanic in Paper Mario: Thousand Year Door.Confirmed CharactersHere are some protagonists and enemies visually seen to appear in the game.MarioLuigiUn-named Chain ChompUn-named WigglerCrowned Monty MoleConfirmed EnemiesGoombasRed Koopa TroopaGreen Koopa TroopaPokeysWhompsWigglersMonty MoleBob-ombHammer BrosDownload VersionBlock size: 4,199 blocks</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19929">Paper Mario</game><game id="7481">Paper Mario: The Thousand-Year Door</game><game id="12739">Super Paper Mario</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/82063/2338170-8054165432_e127819445_o.png</image></root>