<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31758</id><name>Pro Zombie Soccer</name><description>Playing as Jax, a wash out, homeless “Awesome” soccer star who has suddenly found himself in the midst of a zombie apocalypse the user must fend off waves of incoming zombies who want nothing more than to eat Jax’s brains. Working his way across the city Jax must face waves of zombies that range in from the normal slow moving stereotypical zombie, a more fast-paced running zombie, and some boss-type zombies that take multiple hits of your powered-up soccer ball in order to kill them. In all, there are 9 levels with 3 stages a piece in them for a total of 27 levels.The game is wave based, where the zombies move from right to left, there is a digital button the player uses to power up their kicks. Using that same finger that powered up the ball, the player can also aim the ball at the on-coming zombies with a simple up and down motion.Once the player has killed a zombie, the player is rewarded with points, if the player ends up scoring a headshot or a “nutshot” then he/she is rewarded with a bonus amount of points, headshots can be chained in order to create a multiplier, the higher the headshot count, the higher the multiplier becomes.After enough successful zombie kills, a meter at the top left-hand corner of the screen fills up and the player is able to choose from three different power-ups including: a piercing soccer ball that is able to go through any amount of zombies and stops once it hits the right-hand side of the screen, a slow-motion bullet time feature where the player is able to pull-off many shots, and a power-up where Jax kicks the soccer ball into the atmosphere and hits a satellite that is then able to shoot down a blast killing any zombie in its AOE. The first two power-ups are time based and can be used in a 15 second window, while the satellite is one use.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="40">Soccer</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/37007/1405395-pzs.jpg</image></root>