<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>31787</id><name>SingStar Dance</name><description>Overview This is really all you need to see SingStar Dance retains the familiar karaoke interface of the series but squishes things to the left a bit for the addition of a live action dancer. Similar to Ubisoft's      Just Dance, players holding the      PlayStation Move controller follow along with the dancer, mimicking their moves which are in turn pantomimes of the moves in the original music videos. Judging by video footage the Move moves do not follow the original music videos or dance routines exactly and throw in generic moves and poses for the sake of timing and player stamina. Interestingly, players cannot sing and dance at the same time as Players One and Two are assigned to the microphones and Players Three and Four to the Move controllers. This doesn't make it impossible to sing and dance at the same time but holding a wired microphone and a motion sensing wand is probably not endorsed by Sony. Sony does, however, encourage all players to "spice up your video playbacks and enhance your dance moves with cool special effects" by using the Move controller, implying that some post-processing effects can be added before saving and/or uploading performances.  Since dance routines must be filmed and synced with each song it is not likely that SingStar Dance will be immediately backward compatible with previous disc-based or downloadable tracks. This is why SingStar Dance will be a separate release and not just a feature add-on to the current SingStar on PlayStation 3, though Sony promises it will be able to connect to the      SingStore for new non-Move song downloads on day one.  Soundtrack *NSYNC - Bye Bye ByeThe Backstreet Boys - Everybody (Backstreet's Back)Black Eyed Peas - Shut UpBlondie - Heart of GlassChris Brown - With YouCyndi Lauper - Girls Just Wanna Have FunDiana Ross and the Supremes - Baby LoveGloria Gaynor - I Will SurviveGos2 ip - Standing in the Way of ControlGwen Stefani - What You Waiting For?The Jackson 5 - I Want You BackJamiroquai - Cosmic GirlKC  The Sunshine Band - That's the Way (I Like It)Kid Cudi vs. Crookers - Day 'N' NiteKool and the Gang - CelebrationLa Roux - BulletproofLady Gaga - Poker FaceMC Hammer - U Can't Touch ThisNew Kids on the Block - Hanging ToughOutKast - Hey Ya!Paula Abdul - Straight UpPitbull - I Know You Want Me (Calle Ocho)The Pussycat Dolls - Don't ChaReel 2 Reel feat. The Mad Stuntman - I Like to Move ItRicky Martin - Living La Vida Loca Run DMC vs. Jason Nevins - It's Like ThatSalt N' Pepa - Push ItShaggy - BoombasticSir Mix a Lot - Baby Got BackSoulja Boy - Crank That The following tracks have been confirmed as future downloadable content for the game:Britney Spears - Baby One More TimeP!nk - So WhatWhitney Houston - I Wanna Dance with Somebody</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="27859">Just Dance</game><game id="31705">Dance Central</game><game id="31801">DanceMasters</game><game id="27944">Karaoke Revolution</game><game id="3738">Boogie</game><game id="21171">Lips</game><game id="31347">Just Dance 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/6/63119/1550012-5061544806_213f2bfc72_b.jpg</image></root>