<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3185</id><name>ClayFighter 63 1/3</name><description>OverviewClayFighter 63⅓ is a 2D fighting game developed and published by Interplay for the Nintendo 64 on October 27, 1997. The third game in the ClayFighter series (and the sequel to ClayFighter 2: Judgement Clay), ClayFighter 63⅓ continues the stop-motion clay-based sprite style of the previous games (with higher quality for the next-generation system) while adding a combo system, Super Combos, Claytalities, Parries and multi-layered arenas.Along with several characters from the first two installments, the game introduces four new characters: Kung Pow (a Chinese chef/martial artist and a racist Asian stereotype), Houngan (an evil Jamaican witch doctor), Sumo Santa (a clone of Santa Claus who happens to be a sumo wrestler), and Dr. Generic Kiln (a mad scientist and the game's main villain). Two other Interplay characters, Earthworm Jim and Boogerman guest star as playable fighters. Michael Buffer voices the game's announcer.The game started life under the title Clayfighters 3 for the ill fated M2 console. After the cancelation of M2 the game was seperated into two versions: One, 63 1/3 for the N64 and another titled Clayfighter Extreme for the Playstation. The Playstation version was canceled for unknown reasons, however given the dismal review scores of 63 1/3 PS gamers may of dodged a bullet.During development a host of characters and some stages were dropped from the game. Specificly Nintendo had a problem with one character named Hobocop who was a booze drinking crime fighting hobo. Nintendo adimently refused to allow the character in the game and so he was cut. The reason for the other fighters being cut is unknown, although it was probably done to save time.An enhanced version of the game, with the removed character (minus the aformentioned Hobocop), titled ClayFighter: Sculptor's Cut, was released on May 1, 1998 as a rental-only exclusive for Blockbuster Video shops. Its limited distribution made it one of the rarest North America Nintendo 64 games of all time.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8279">Mortal Kombat Trilogy</game><game id="10614">Killer Instinct Gold</game><game id="8161">Street Fighter II Turbo: Hyper Fighting</game><game id="20456">Street Fighter IV</game><game id="1615">Street Fighter III: 3rd Strike</game><game id="1328">Street Fighter Alpha 3</game><game id="243">Street Fighter II: The World Warrior</game><game id="8680">Street Fighter Alpha 3 MAX</game><game id="1251">Super Street Fighter II Turbo</game><game id="19134">Street Fighter Alpha 2</game><game id="14078">Primal Rage</game><game id="8021">Eternal Champions: Challenge from the Dark Side</game><game id="16444">Eternal Champions</game><game id="2178">Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3</game><game id="15743">Mortal Kombat</game><game id="4652">Mortal Kombat Gold</game><game id="1434">Mortal Kombat 3</game><game id="2760">Art of Fighting</game><game id="8867">Art of Fighting 3: The Path of The Warrior</game><game id="13327">Art of Fighting 2</game><game id="449">The King of Fighters 2001</game><game id="4124">The King of Fighters '97</game><game id="4249">The King of Fighters '94</game><game id="6452">The King of Fighters: Dream Match 1999</game><game id="1167">Virtua Fighter Kids</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="16793">Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="18484">Killer Instinct</game><game id="20678">Soulcalibur IV</game><game id="10476">War Gods</game><game id="21277">Ultimate Mortal Kombat</game><game id="36652">Fight 'N' Jokes</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2345120-box_cf64.png</image></root>