<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32017</id><name>Realm of the Mad God</name><description>OverviewCreated for an Assemblee competition, Realm of The Mad God makes no effort to hide its roots, this game is intentionally retro. Using the famous Oryx sprites, this game presents an art style almost never seen anymore in the MMORPG scene. There is no PVP. Instead, the game focuses on teamwork, battling many Gods and Monsters that can't be fought alone.This game is deliberately simple, there are no NPCs, it's just you, monsters, and whoever else is online. Stats are assigned for you, and equipment is straightforward to choose.The NexusInitially the only class available to you is the wizard. Once you take the wizard to level 5 you unlock the priest, and when your priest hits level 5 you unlock the ranger and so on. All classes shoot to attack (even if they are melee). How far and how much damage is dealt is based on the class, additionally, every class has a special ability. There are five weapon types in the game, swords, bows, daggers, staves and wands. There are rings useable by every class. Spells, armor, helmets, cloaks, robes, seals, and other equipment are also available, and usually have a class specific special ability tied to them.Generally, the game is free roam. After the initial short tutorial, you're allowed to freely explore the world and fight monsters. There are no towns, NPCs, or quests. Maps are typically islands, which are safe on the shores, but dangerous as you go in to them. Typically, the shore is safest, forest is second safest, deserts are dangerous, and mountains are very dangerous, with gods usually present there. There are no real "safe zones" on the map, monsters can go anywhere, anytime, but usually stay in their designated area unless they follow somebody. If the area is "safe enough," that is, there are no monsters in your radar, you can pause and be invulnerable, but not able to do anything until you un-pause, anyone pausing is shown in Grey-scale. Maps are server wide, and are chosen from a pool of twenty. Maps switch after Oryx is killed. There are dungeons to explore that are accessed by keys which open portals to them.The "objectives" are typically as follows:- Get to a respectable level (max is 20)An Adventurer In the Woods- Maybe acquire a few stat boosting potions, which after level 20, are the only way to raise your stats.- Destroy the Event Gods.- Kill quest monsters to unlock Oryx.- Challenge Oryx and kill him.All of which can only be completed with the cooperation of other players.Fighting Oryx is actually a unique mechanic, as everyone on the server is transported to his lair. His lair is the only map in the game that's guaranteed to be the same map every time. It's a giant arena with a few pillars and Oryx in the center, with countless powerful minions surrounding him. It's typically a very tough fight, requiring every player to stick together and devise a plan. There's usually a lot of focus fire, stat boosting, and clerics healing people.Much like a rouge-like, if you die, that's it, game over. You have to create an entirely new character with all your equipment gone and you begin at level one again. This makes it very important to fight alongside another player, for if you die, they can pickup your stuff and give it to you when you respawn as equipment doesn't have level requirements. Experience is area of effect, so if one enemy is killed, and one person gets 15 exp, then everyone around him gets 15 exp too. This discourages kill stealing greatly.Welcome to Scenic Bullethell, Wish You Were HereEveryone knows lone wolf tactics are the easiest way to die. Though this doesn't mean you can't solo the game, it does mean that the only way to get to maximum power is to work together, as stat boosting potions and high leveled equips are hard to come by. Trading and free give-aways are commonplace, if one just so happens to run by an equip that someone else would want.ClassesThe first layer classes may seem very similar, on closer inspection they are all quite different. Although most attack the same, their stats aren't, and neither are their equips or special abilities. Here are all the classes.WarriorFocused On: Raw PowerRange: LowHealth: HighWeapon: SwordEquips: Heavy Armor, Helmet, RingSpecial Ability: Rage Mode: Increased power and rate of attack. It is area of effect so it can be used on allies too.Unlock Requirements: A level 5 RogueRogueFocused On: Quick AttacksRange: MediumHealth: MediumWeapon: DaggerEquips: Cloak, Leather Armor, RingSpecial Ability: Hide In Shadows: Can't be detected by enemies but still receives damage.Unlock Requirements: A level 5 ArcherArcherFocused On: Long RangeRange: Very LongHealth: MediumWeapon: Bow and ArrowEquips: Quivers, Leather Armor, RingSpecial Ability: Power Shot: A single shot that damages any enemy greatly, and either slows or stuns him, depending on the quiver.Unlock Requirements: A level 5 PriestWizardFocused On: Mob Control (Attacking while they can't attack him)Range: HighHealth: LowWeapon: StaffEquips: Robe, Offensive Spell, RingSpecial Ability: Offensive Spell: Shoots in all directions of where it was cast.Unlock Requirements: None, starting classPriestFocused On: Support, healing himself and others.Range: HighHealth: LowWeapon: WandEquips: Robe, Healing Spell, RingSpecial Ability: Heal: Heals all people, including the Priest, in the area of effect.Unlock Requirements: A level 5 WizardKnightFocused On: TankingRange: LowHealth: High, with a ton of defense.Weapon: SwordEquips: Heavy Armor, Shield, RingSpecial Ability: Shield Stun: Sends out a quick wave of power that stuns anyone in range including gods.Unlock Requirements: A level 20 WarriorPaladinFocused On: Being the jack of all trades, mix of a warrior and a priest.Range: LowHealth: HighWeapon: SwordEquips: Heavy Armor, Seal, RingSpecial Ability: Recovery: Area of effect ability that makes all players in the area regenerate health, at the highest level it also increases damage.Unlock Requirements: A Level 20 Priest and Level 20 KnightAssassinFocused On: Hit and RunRange: MediumHealth: MediumWeapon: DaggerEquips: Poison, Leather Armor, RingSpecial Ability: Poison: Poisons an enemy, deals a high amount of damage over a set amount of time, great for throwing from behind cover.Unlock Requirements: A Level 20 Wizard and Level 20 RogueHuntressFocused On: Setting Up TrapsRange: LongHealth: MediumWeapon: Bow and ArrowEquips: Trap, Leather Armor, RingSpecial Ability: Trap: Sets up a trap that will explode if an enemy walks over it.Unlock Requirements: A Level 20 Archer and Level 20 RogueNecromancerFocused On: Draining EnergyRange: MediumHealth: LowWeapon: StaffEquips: Skull, Robe, RingSpecial Ability: Drain: Sucks the life out of a group of enemies and transfers it to the Necromancer and those around him.Unlock Requirements: A Level 20 Wizard and Level 20 PriestMysticFocused On: Dividing The EnemyRange: MediumHealth: LowWeapon: StaffEquips: Orb, Robe, RingSpecial Ability: Stasis: Freeze's a group of enemies -- they cannot move, attack, or be attacked -- until the effect wears off.Unlock Requirements: A Level 20 Huntress and Level 20 NecromancerTricksterFocused On: Creating DiversionsRange: MediumHealth: MediumWeapon: DaggerEquips: Prism, Leather Armor, RingSpecial Ability: Decoy: Create a decoy adventurer who distracts enemies and forces them to attack it.Unlock Requirements: A Level 20 Assassin and Level 20 PaladinSorcererFocused On: Ranged damageRange: LongHealth: LowWeapon: WandEquips: Scepter, Robe, RingSpecial Ability: Chain Lightning: A blast of lightning that jumps between 3-8 enemies within range, dealing moderate damage.Unlock Requirements: A level 20 Necromancer and level 20 AssassinPC System RequirementsOS:Windows XP or laterProcessor:2.33GHz or faster x86-compatibleMemory:1 GB RAMDirectX®:dx50Hard Drive:100 MB HD spaceMac System RequirementsOS:Mac OS X v10.6 or laterProcessor:Intel Core™ Duo or fasterMemory:1 GB RAMHard Drive:100 MB HD space</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21958">MapleStory</game><game id="27860">3D Dot Game Heroes</game><game id="8594">Gauntlet</game><game id="37665">RPG World Online</game><game id="39485">The Border Lands</game><game id="44338">Gangs of Space</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15063/2252688-tumblr_m5vla440sk1rozl4to1_r1_500.jpg</image></root>