<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32099</id><name>Akai Katana</name><description>Akai Katana is a horizontal bullet hell shoot 'em up developed by Cave and released in 2010. An enhanced Xbox 360 port, Akai Katana Shin, was released in 2011. MechanicsThe game allows the player to choose between three different ships, each with two characters (one pilot and one gunner/ninja) and an option. Once a meter fills it becomes possible to enter ninja mode, in which the ship transforms into the ninja character and its two shot types (spread and focused) are replaced by an offensive and a defensive mode. In offensive mode, the character fires an extra powerful shot. In defensive mode, all bullets get reflected when they come close enough, and enter a state in which they continuously home in on the player character until Ninja Mode is deactivated or the enemies that fired them destroyed. If said enemies are destroyed before Ninja Mode is deactivated, the bullets turn into gold that circles the player until the end of Ninja Mode, when the ship absorbs them and the player's score is boosted.     A special edition PCB was released three months after the original's release. It brought a number of tweaks and changes including the elimination of the option for coin-operated play, the removal of circling gold in order to reduce slowdown, the addition of a stage select feature, and a new, extra hard mod called Red Mode.Links Official Site for Arcade VersionOfficial Site for Xbox 360 Version Promo Video - Xbox 360 Version</description><genres><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21325">Touhou 10.5 - Scarlet Weather Rhapsody</game><game id="21928">Touhou 06 - The Embodiment of Scarlet Devil</game><game id="21877">Touhou 08 - Imperishable Night</game><game id="21289">Touhou 09 - Phantasmagoria of Flower View</game><game id="27857">Touhou Hisoutensoku - Choudokyuu Ginyoru no Nazo o Oe</game><game id="21930">Touhou 7.5 - Immaterial and Missing Power</game><game id="21327">Touhou 11 - Subterranean Animism</game><game id="21326">Touhou 10 - Mountain of Faith</game><game id="21757">Touhou 9.5 - Shoot the Bullet</game><game id="21929">Touhou 07 - Perfect Cherry Blossom</game><game id="21805">Touhou 01 - Highly Responsive to Prayers</game><game id="21882">Touhou 04 - Lotus Land Story</game><game id="21867">Touhou 02 - The Story of Eastern Wonderland</game><game id="25577">Touhou 12 - Undefined Fantastic Object</game><game id="30836">Touhou 12.5: Double Spoiler</game><game id="21883">Touhou 03 - The Phantasmagoria of Dim.Dream</game><game id="21874">Touhou 05 - Mystic Square</game><game id="29280">Mushihime-sama Futari</game><game id="34238">Deathsmiles IIX: Makai no Merry Christmas</game><game id="27064">Deathsmiles II: Makai no Merry Christmas</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/12/122378/2021146-akai_katana_shin_artwork_1.jpg</image></root>