<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32129</id><name>The Sims 3: Late Night</name><description>OverviewThe Sims 3: Late Night lets players explore the vibrant night life of The Sims 3. Players can become a celebrity, bartender, director, or a musician and worktheir way up the social ladder. Alternatively, Sims can discover the secrets of becoming a vampire. Rampant behavior will not go unchecked. If the player's Sim acts out of line they will be refused to enter the best clubs in the city and shunned by other Sims. The expansion pack is due Fall 2010 for PC and Mac. For this first time the Sims get hotter and alternately better as for the new features...New Features:*New Muscle Sliders and Shading Detail*New Breast Sliders and Stomach Detail*Unique Clubs*Improved Items for your Sims' Home*New Town called Bridge Port*Celebrities Sims*Vampire Sims*New Jobs/Work*Mixologist Skills*Moonlighting Abilities*New Music/InstrumentsDive Bars:Dive Bars are rather self explanotory, they are Local Hang Outs as for Real-Life Bars, where you will often find Exclusive Bar Games, Paparazzi, Reviewers, Celebrities, and Vampires. Also this is were the Mixologist Skill is involved, or Moonlighting...High-End Lounges:High-End Lounges, which are scattered all over BridgePort, Feature in'High-End' Rooftop Views with Mini-Bar Tables and usually Hot Tubs, another New Feature to the The Sims 3 Series...Dance Clubs:Similar to Bars, The Bar Tables and Mixologists return, However Dance Clubs are literally filled with Strode Lighting and Performers, were your Sim can dance as long as they want. Also, if your Sims own a Band, you may be invited to Perform at Gigs at a particular Club for a certain time...System RequirementsPC System Requirements:OS: XP SP2 / Vista SP1 / Windows 7Processor: For XP 2.0 GHz P4 processor or equivalent; For Windows Vista and Windows 7 2.4 GHz P4 processor or equivalentMemory: For XP 1 GB RAM / Windows Vista and Windows 7 1.5 GB RAMGraphics: 128 MB Video Card with Pixel Shader 2.0 support.Hard Drive: At least 500 MB of free space with at least 1 GB of additional space for custom content and saved games.Sound:Supported Video Cards: Nvidia GeForce series: FX5900 or better, and all NVidia G, GT, GTS, and GTX video cards. ATI Radeon™ series card 9500 series or better, X300, X600, X700, X800, X850, X1300, X1600, X1800, X1900, X1950, 2400, 2600, 2900, 3450, 3650, 3850, 3870, 4850, 4870, 4890 series or better; Intel® Graphics Media Accelerator (GMA): GMA 3-Series, GMA 4-Series For NVIDIA ION™ computers, the game requires at least 2.0 GB RAM. 9.6 GB of hard drive space if installing with The Sims 3. Please note that the GeForce 6100 and 7100 cards are not supported. The NVIDIA GeForce FX series is unsupported under Vista.Digital download is PC-compatible onlyMusicThere are 20 new songs in simlish added to the Late Night expansion pack. A new genre, Hip-Hop, is also added to the radio station selection.Dr. Dre - Under Pressure3OH!3 - Double VisionBryan Rice - There for YouChiddy Bang - Here We GoElectrolightz - Miss Outta ControlEliza Doolittle - RollerbladesFoxy Shazam - UnstoppableHadag Nahash - Lo MaspikHadouken! - M.A.D.Jessica Mauboy - Saturday NightJunkie XL - Live WiredKellis - BraveKelly Rowland - Rose Colored GlassesKing Fantastic - All Black Ying Yang (The Party Song)My Chemical Romance - Na Na Na (Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na)Nikki  Rich - Next Best ThingThe Ready Set - More Than AliveRise Again - SaviorSoulja Boy - Speakers Going HammerTravie McCoy - Need You</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9850">The Sims 2: Nightlife</game><game id="20581">The Sims 3</game><game id="27663">The Sims 3: World Adventures</game><game id="33372">The Sims 3: Outdoor Living Stuff</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/16/160705/2264380-ts3lnboxart.jpg</image></root>