<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32141</id><name>Rhythm Zone</name><description>Rhythm Zone is the new revolution in music gaming! Play using YOUR OWN MUSIC and get into the Rhythm Zone of your favorite indie, electronica, metal, rock, hip hop, and pop songs. Every game session is as different as the songs you choose and is matched to awesome and surreal changing backgrounds that are generated by your music. Experience falling-note beat-matching gaming in a dynamic new dimension while using your keyboard or any USB based plug and play controller. Rhythm Zone will also feature free monthly featured song updates and a multiplayer/challenge mode that is coming soon.Key FeaturesPlay Your Music: Regardless of your taste in music, you can play your favorite songs. Rhythm Zone supports a wide variety of file types and will identify most common songs against our database.Online Leaderboards: Compare your scores to your friends and check out who is the best in the world.Achievements: Earn over 50 Steam achievements by playing your music.Focus Power: Hit note streaks to earn score multipliers and the ability to unleash your inner rock star.Visualizers: Dynamic background visualizers that are based on your music and performance; create a unique game experience each time you play!Updates: But wait - there's more! Downloadable song packs and content updates on the horizon.PC System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Windows XP 32 BitProcessor: Pentium IV / Athlon XP 2.0ghz or higherMemory: 1GB system ramGraphics: Geforce 5 / ATI Radeon X100 / Intel 965 onboard graphics or higherDirectX®: DirectX 9.0 or laterHard Drive: 550MB space freeSound: DirectX 9.0 compatible sound cardRecommended:OS: Windows 7Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo 2.4ghz processor or higherMemory: 2GB system ramGraphics: Nvidia 7600/ATI x1600 or betterDirectX®: DirectX 9.0c or laterHard Drive: 550MB space freeSound: DirectX 9.0c compatible sound cardSteam Features67 Steam AchievementsSteam LeaderboardsSteam Stats</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9436">Audiosurf</game><game id="9860">Rock Band</game><game id="20714">Rock Band 2</game><game id="27919">Rock Band 3</game><game id="6311">Guitar Hero</game><game id="31632">Guitar Hero</game><game id="14916">Guitar Hero II</game><game id="30472">Turba</game><game id="27103">The Polynomial: Space of the Music</game><game id="29407">Beat Hazard</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/4/46795/1444381-header.jpg</image></root>