<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32238</id><name>Gold's Gym: Dance Workout</name><description>Overview Gold’s Gym Dance workout is a Fitness Dance game exclusively for the Nintendo Wii, Developed by Rocket Company  Published by Ubisoft Entertainment. Dance Workout was developed with fitness and dance exporters, dedicated to fitness and weight lost.   Gameplay Gold’s Gym offers of variety of dance workout   Cardio boxing workouts ranging from beginner to advance difficulty. Players can  build there own workout circuits programs or let the game randomly choice one for them. Circuit Programs are extended dance sessions and mini games up to 30 minutes. The game also features your own personal instructor that shows you new dance moves, gives you advice, and increases the intensity of your workout based on your personal performance. After each workout the game will record how many calories you burned during that session and will keep track of it. The game History will keep track of every workout, game time, calories burned, and body mass index(BMI) via the Wii Balance board. The game also offers a Practice mode for each work out. It beaks down the workout section by section letting you view the dance movements. You can rewind, loop, and view the dance movements in 3 different camera angles. Gold’s Gym Dance workout also comes with mini games, including the follow:MarathonJump RopeBoxingKarateMatadorBull RidingCanoeing SwordsMultiplayerGold’s Gym Dance Workout offers 2 player multiplayer, which lets you exercise with a friend.  Soundtrack Dance and burn those calories to hit songs from the following Lady Gaga - Just Dance Gloria Gaynor - I Will Survive Beach Boys - Good Vibrations C  C Music Factory - Everybody Dance Now Right Said Fred - I'm Too Sexy Madonna - Material Girl Kanye West - Stronger Pussycat Dolls - Jai Ho Santana - Smooth Chayanne - Salome Santana - Oye Come Va Jamiroquai - Cosmic Girl Blondie - Heart Of GlassBritney Spears  - Stronger  Jennifer Lopez - Waiting for TonightRight Said Fred - I'm too sexyEmiliano Almeida -  Empujalo Marky Mark  - Good Vibrations Chris Brown -  Forever  Wolfgang Gartner - For The Love of Girls  Plus additional original custom mixes.</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre><genre id="44">Fitness</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="27859">Just Dance</game><game id="31347">Just Dance 2</game><game id="31526">Dance On Broadway</game><game id="32856">Kidz Bop Dance Party! The Video Game</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5150/1466232-61mddjyffml._sl500_.jpg</image></root>