<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32243</id><name>Operation Flashpoint: Red River</name><description>OverviewBetween Afghanistan and China, the world’s next flashpoint is about to erupt.Operation Flashpoint: Red River takes place in the not too distant future in the real location of Tajikistan, close to China, Afghanistan, and Pakistan. Afghan insurgents make their way into the country with US forces trying to control the situation, while at the same time the Chinese People's Liberation Army, fearing a US breach into the country's soil, also gets involved.The story of the game is told from the perspective of Bravo Squad, and the soldiers that make up the squad use colorful language throughout, most noticeably between deployments while riding in the Humvee listening to an assortment of popular Metal music.ClassesDuring the single player campaign or the 4 player drop-in drop-out coop campaign you can play as 4 different :GrenadierScoutRiflemanAutomatic RiflemanExperience points will be persistent between  and multiplayer. These points allow the player to select different perks and skills between missions. These perks and skills, however, add to weapon stability and running speed/duration, rather than any unrealistic perks in games such as the recent Call of Duty franchise entries.During mission intervals, you can also edit and change your weapons, adding attachments, changing equipment and adding "Soldier Perks" to increase things like XP gained and increased healing ability.MultiplayerThere are 4 mutliplayer modes in Red River:Rolling Thunder- The team of up to 4 friends have to protect a travelling convoy through a scenario where there are a number of threats. At the start of the mode the team have two humvees to ride and protect the convoy.Last Stand- A defensive mode where you have to protect an area for as long as you can while collecting point, from enemies that increase in size and damage. To finish the mode the surviving members of the squad have to board the helicopter waiting for them, if this isn't done and all players die the team get zero points.Combat Sweep- The team have to go through an area and clear it of all enemies. There is a secondary objective where the team can destroy supply crates in the area.Combat Search and Rescue- The team scouts the area for a crashed helicopter to rescue two pilots and bring them back to the helicopter waiting for them.System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Windows XP / Vista / Windows 7Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo @ 2.4 Ghz / AMD Athlon 64 X2 5200+Graphics Card: 256 MB Graphics Memory - NVIDIA GeForce 7800 / ATI Radeon X1800Sound Card: DirectX 9 CompatibleDirectX: Version 9Memory: 1 GB of RAMHard Disk Space: 6 GBRecommended:OS: Windows XP / Vista / Windows 7Processor: Intel Core 2 Quad @ 3.0 GHz / AMD Phenom II X4 @ 3.4 GHzGraphics Card: 512 MB Graphics Memory - NVIDIA GeForce 8800 / ATI Radeon HD 3800 (or better)Sound Card: DirectX 9 CompatibleMemory: 2 GB of RAMDirectX: Version 9Hard Disk Space: 6 GB</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="30196">SOCOM 4: U.S. Navy SEALs</game><game id="27006">Battlefield 3</game><game id="24699">America's Army 3</game><game id="20476">America's Army: True Soldiers</game><game id="35432">Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon Online</game><game id="27936">ArmA II: Operation Arrowhead</game><game id="35383">ArmA III</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1789968-box_opflrr.png</image></root>