<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32253</id><name>SHIFT 2: Unleashed</name><description>OverviewShift 2: Unleashed is a sequel to the 2009 racing game Need for Speed: SHIFT. Developed by Slightly Mad Studios , Shift 2: Unleashed expands on the original Shift by adding several new features including GT1 World Championship racing, night racing, a helmet camera and Autolog, which first appeared in Criterion's Need for Speed: Hot Pursuit.DevelopmentShift 2 was officially announced on the release day for Need For Speed: Hot Pursuit (November 16, 2010) with a teaser trailer that was also included with that game. The game was officially released on March 29. 2011 for North America, March 31 for Australia and Europe and April 1 for the United Kingdom.Limited EditionA Limited Edition of the game was also available as a pre-order, featuring slightly different packaging, instant access to three exclusive cars (Nissan Silvia spec.R Aero S15, Alfa Romeo Giulietta QV and Lamborghini Murcielago LP640) and 40 bonus racing events.Need for Speed VIPIn addition to the Limited Edition content, the game also features the Need for Speed VIP program, which awards bonuses to players of previous Need for Speed titles. Having a Hot Pursuit save in the player's memory will award the player $10,000 in-game cash, 1000 XP, a special orange Pagani Zonda Cinque Roadster and a special Police version of the Lamborghini Reventon, a Shift save will award the player $20,000 in-game cash and 2000 XP and an Undercover save will award the player $10,000 in-game cash and 1000 XP.Career ModeIn Career Mode, the goal is to earn enough money and experience points (XP) through races to win the FIA GT1 World Championship. Players will compete in events across a wide variety of disciplines, including retro and muscle cars, Drifting, Endurance, Time Attack, Eliminator and Circuit Racing. Each discipline features coaching from a number of real-life professional drivers, such as Vaughn Gittin Jr. (Drifting), Tommy Milner (American Le Mans Racing), Chris Rado (Time Attack), Jamie Campbell-Walter (GT1), Patrick Soderlund (GT3) and "Mad Mike" Whiddett (Works Championship). These pros then become Rivals and the player can win their car by beating each Rival in their respective discipline. Players can also compete in Invitational races and win higher level carsExperience Points (XP)The experience points system has undergone some notable changes from the first game. The game no longer keeps separate point scores for Precision and Aggression moves and all "Aggressive" moves from the original no longer earn XP and the experience system now has only 20 levels instead of 50. Additionally, the "stars" system has also been completely replaced, with players unlocking events and disciplines by earning XP and levelling up. Individual race goals are still present, but now earn additional XP instead of stars.BadgesBadges are still present in Shift 2, but are no longer divided into Bronze, Silver, Gold and Epic. Race tasks such as Perfect Starts still earn XP but no longer count towards their own badges.Car Performance and TuningCars are now separated into Classes instead of Tiers for performance with each car having a performance score (similar to Forza Motorsport). Cars can be moved up and down classes by adding or removing upgrades. Once a car has been sufficiently upgraded, it is eligible for Works conversion into a full race car. Unlike Shift, performance upgrades are no longer grouped into levels and players do not have to install all previous level parts before installing the next or before performing a Works conversion.MultiplayerShift 2 features a number of multiplayer modes. The Driver Duel Championship Shift 2 is also part of EA's Project Ten Dollar program, so a code is included with each new copy of the game that allows players to play online as well as allowing Limited Edition owners to redeem their bonus content. PC System RequirementsOS: Windows XP (SP3) / Vista (SP2) / 7Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo 2.0 GHz / AMD X2 1964 2.4 GHzMemory: 2 GB of RAMVideo Card: 512 MB ATI HD 3XXX series / NVIDIA GeForce 8XXX (or better)Sound Card: DirectX compatibleHard Disk Space: 7 GBSupported Steering WheelsPC:Logitech G27 Racing WheelLogitech G25 Racing WheelLogitech Driving Force GTLogitech Formula Force EXLogitech Driving ForceLogitech Driving Force EXLogitech Driving Force RXLogitech Driving Force ProLogitech MOMO ForceLogitech MOMO RacingThrustmaster RGT FFB Pro ClutchThrustmaster Ferrari GT ExperienceThrustmaster Ferrari 430Fanatec Porsche 911 Turbo SPS3:Nascar Racing WheelLogitech Driving ForceLogitech Driving Force EXLogitech Driving Force ProLogitech G25 Racing WheelLogitech G27 Racing WheelLogitech Driving Force GT – full support for all buttons and dialThrustmaster F430 FFBThrustmaster RGT FFB ClutchXbox 360:Microsoft Force Feedback WheelFanatec Porsche 911 Turbo</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="24995">Forza Motorsport 3</game><game id="20729">GRID</game><game id="16220">GTR: FIA GT Racing Game</game><game id="14858">GTR 2: FIA GT Racing Game</game><game id="23526">GTR: Evolution</game><game id="33400">Forza Motorsport 4</game><game id="21790">Gran Turismo 5</game><game id="25485">Test Drive Unlimited 2</game><game id="20130">rFactor</game><game id="36993">Project CARS</game><game id="34542">F1 2011</game><game id="36977">RACE Injection</game><game id="27298">rFactor 2</game><game id="42693">Forza Motorsport 5</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1897546-box_nfss2u.png</image></root>