<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32295</id><name>EverQuest: House of Thule</name><description>Story     In the land of Norrath many important figures have fallen into dream-induced comas. Healers are incapable of waking them from their sleep so something is clearly wrong in the world of dreams.   In Feerrott jungle, a mysteriously sinister place, the overlords of Thule battle for power. Cazic, Terris, and Morell, the Lord of Dreams, are the deities of Thule and their violent fighting has caused massive upheaval in the world of Norrath. Reality becomes illusion, dreams and nightmares become reality. Nothing is held back by intangibles. Dreams and nightmares are no longer restricted to one's mind and take physical form. The overlords of Thule must be stopped before the entire world of Norrath is destroyed by the power of dreams.   New Additions in House of ThuleAdded 5 levels to cap making level 90 max.More than 800 AAs making powers and abilities stronger than they were beforeIn-game housing so players can display their itemsNew Housing Trophy System where trophies can be displayed and receive statistical benefits.Hundreds of housing items to decorate the player's house.18 raids full of loot.13 Zones to be added to the world of Norrath.450  spells to add to caster classes.17 missions to explore and experience lore.120 quests to gather loot.Inventory increase Purchasing OptionsEverQuest: House of Thule will be available for digital download at $39.99.  Pre-Order Bonuses Get House of Thule and all previous expansionsTopiary Mount16 slot bag2 extra bag slotsWailing Contract MercenaryHouse of Thule key art in-game painting    Pre-order Digital Collector's Edition Bonuses House of Thule and all previous Expansion packsTopiary Mount"Dead" Topiary MountGnoll Pup LeashSword of Truth template20 slot bag2 extra bag slotsWailing Contract MercenaryDiscordant Contract MercenaryHouse of Thule key art in-game paintingHouse of Thule in-game painting     Ordering Digital Download from Direct 2 Drive, Amazon, Steam House of Thule and all of its expansions.Topiary Mount16 slot bag2 extra bag slotsHouse of Thule in-game art painting.System SpecificationsWindows XPPentium II 400 or higher256 megabytes of RAMATI Radeon 7500/GeForce 1 or betterDirect X compatible sound card28k Internet Connection4x Speed DVD-ROM500 MB hard drive space or 8 gigs depending on how many expansions are installed.Direct X 9.0Everquest Subscription Recommended Specs  Windows 7, XP SP2, or VistaPentium 4 or higher1 gig of RAMNVidia GeForce FX 5700/ATI Radeon 9500 or betterDirect X compatible Sound card56.6k Internet connection or faster8X DVD-ROM10 gigs of Hard Drive SpaceDirect X 9.0</description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11142">Final Fantasy XI Online</game><game id="26847">Final Fantasy XIV Online: A Realm Reborn</game><game id="12376">The Lord of the Rings Online: Shadows of Angmar</game><game id="16511">Dungeons &amp; Dragons Online: Stormreach</game><game id="33226">The Lord of the Rings Online: Rise of Isengard</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/11660/1462077-eq_hot_keyart_final_small.jpg</image></root>