<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32306</id><name>Run!</name><description>Gameplay   In Run!, you control a stick man. The movement is automatically controlled but you can make him jump, slide, punch, or shoot rockets. Some enemies are only vulnerable to rockets, while some are only vulnerable to punches. If you jump and then punch, you do a flying kick. Every 200 points, either a new obstacle appears or your character speeds up. It alternates each time. There are also power-ups you can collect. There are four in total. Power Gear allow to to punch or kick things that are usually invulnerable to punches and kicks. The Golden Rocket Launcher allows you to shoot rockets at things that are usually invulnerable to rockets, the Shield makes you invincible, and the Laser Sword allows you to shoot a laser every time you punch. There is also a combo system where you get more points if you destroy obstacles in quick succession. You start with three lives but can pick up more as you go along. When you die, the game ends and your score can be added to an online leader board. Modes  Normal Mode - The default mode. Each level alternates between speeding up and adding new obstacles.   Quick Mode - All obstacles are in play from the beginning. Each level speeds the player up.    Custom Mode  - This mode allows you to choose which obstacles are in play. It also allows you to change your character's movement speed and object spacing.  Minute Mode - In this mode you have 60 seconds to score as many points as possible. You have unlimited lives, and can slide to run faster.    Obstacles Brick WallSteel WallZombieWalrusSpringSharkSaw BladeBoulderSpikesMeteor  BombWizardHelicopterUFO</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15544">Super Mario Bros.</game><game id="2465">Sonic the Hedgehog</game><game id="10014">Pitfall!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/4/49304/1462887-img_0049.png</image></root>