<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32311</id><name>Cabela's North American Adventures</name><description>Overview Cabela’s North American Adventures introduces fresh touches that hunters will appreciate, including a custom gun builder that allows players the ability to create thousands of gun options with a variety of receivers, stocks, barrels, and scopes. For the first time in franchise history, up to four friends can hunt together online at once (Xbox 360 and PlayStation®3). Once the hunt is done, friends can share their scores through online leader boards for bragging rights.   TV ShowThe game capitalizes on the popularity of hunting shows and online videos by adding a cameraman. By hunting well, you can be the next big star of the Hunting TV Show.  The cameraman follows the hunter around and you get to choose your shooting angle and camera angles for your video. Your camera man indicates good shooting angles and you get a grade for making a nice video. The TV show aspect of the game is only reserved to single player.   MultiplayerMultiplayer is a brand new feature never before seen in the franchise that makes its first appearance in Cabela's North American Adventures. You and four other friends can compete online to see who's the best at hunting.   The multi-player features perks, score bonuses and the possibility to grief your opponents. The online component of the game is only available on PS3 and 360.   Wii Version The Wii version doesn't support online multiplayer instead focusing on split screen competitive multiplayer. The Wii version also offers an exclusive shooting gallery and the game is compatible with the Wii Top Shot peripheral.        </description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6866">Cabela's African Safari</game><game id="2602">Cabela's Sportman's Challenge</game><game id="27870">Cabela's Outdoor Adventures</game><game id="26429">Cabela's Big Game Hunter</game><game id="24905">Cabela's Dangerous Hunts: Ultimate Challenge</game><game id="19528">Cabela's Dangerous Hunts</game><game id="19014">Cabela's Big Game Hunter</game><game id="24904">Cabela's Dangerous Hunts 2</game><game id="10877">Cabela's Big Game Hunter III: The Next Harvest</game><game id="6895">Cabela's Ultimate Deer Hunt</game><game id="20890">Cabela's Trophy Bucks</game><game id="24906">Cabela's Outdoor Adventures</game><game id="3837">Cabela's Big Game Hunter II</game><game id="19309">Cabela's Grand Slam Hunting: North American 29</game><game id="14225">Cabela's Big Game Hunter II: Open Season</game><game id="23865">Cabela's Legendary Adventures</game><game id="14196">Cabela's Big Game Hunter 2004</game><game id="11231">Cabela's Ultimate Deer Hunt 2</game><game id="11905">Cabela's Big Game Hunter 6</game><game id="22676">Deer Hunter Tournament</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2360868-box_cnaa.png</image></root>