<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32314</id><name>Dustforce</name><description>OverviewDustforce is an action-platformer developed by Australian developer Hitbox Team depicting the adventures of a team of ninja janitors known as Dustforce. Rather than collect coins or destroy enemies, characters dust and sweep the environments, which are full of dirt, leaves, and other debris. Characters are able to double jump, wall run, and perform combos in their quest for clean.A demo was released on August 1, 2010 for the PC. It includes a tutorial, two maps, and a level editor, allowing players to create their own maps.GameplayThe main gameplay in Dustforce consists of navigating Super Meat Boy-esque levels while avoiding hazards and cleaning debris off of the environment either by running over a dirty area or using attacks to knock the offending detritus off of wild animals; being covered in garbage has made the animals scared and hostile, and will attack Dustforce members until they are cleaned off.Cleaning the level fills up a meter which, when full, lets you use a full-screen attack that defeats all of the currently visible enemies. This is generally useful for saving until the end of a given level as most levels end in a "boss fight" of some sort, but it resets your mid-air jumps so it may also be useful in crossing very wide gaps.Upon completion of a stage, the player is given a rank in both Completion and Finesse. Completion measures the percentage of refuse cleaned in a level. Finesse reflects how high of a combo you were able to maintain. If both of these conditions are S-Ranked, the player is awarded with a key to unlock additional levels. Unfortunately, this means that levels must be perfected before the player can advance beyond a certain point.Cleaning all of the debris in the level is usually as simple as working out the most fluid path to hit all of the dirty surfaces. Getting an S-Rank in Finesse means that the player must build up their combo by cleaning things with a less than five-second gap between, otherwise the combo resets to zero. A perfect run involves clearing all of a level's debris and defeating all the enemies while maintaining a single combo.Members of DustforceDustman (Blue): Wields a broom. The most balanced character.Dustgirl (Red): Wields a pushbroom. Has the biggest attack range but is the slowest character.Dustkid (Purple): Dual-wields pom-pom dusters. Fastest and can triple jump but has a very small attack range and her jumps are quite low.Dustworth (Green): Wields a power vacuum cleaner. Has the highest jump and the furthest glide.MultiplayerThe game features a local-only multiplayer component. Up to 8 players containing teams of 4 can play (4v4). One team takes on the role of cleaning a stage as members of the Dustforce while the other team leaves dust everywhere they go and are tasked with making the stage as dirty as possible.Level EditorThe level editor was released on May 1, 2012 as part of a large update which also brought the game to the Mac. Created levels can be uploaded and shared on Atlas, the official Dustforce level sharing community.LeaderboardsThere is an in game list of fastest runs for each stage sorted by rank and clear time. A replay of each entry in the list is able to be viewed in game, but only after you have completed the level once yourself.EnemiesAn orb enemy in a Forest level.Dustforce has a wide variety of enemies. Enemy type and behavior varies depending on a level's theme, though the 'orb' enemy is common to all. AchievementsDustforce has only one Steam Achievement named "Double S+" with no accompanying description. This is obtained by achieving an S rank in Completion and Finesse on all levels.It is assumed that this single achievement is only a placeholder and that more achievements are forthcoming.Fastfall (Dustforce OST) by Lifeformed (Terence Lee)OST Cover Art.No.Track TitleTrack Time1Cider Time2:5929-Bit Expedition3:003Elvish Piper Academy2:484Fifty FPS Forest1:165Swimming While It Rains2:406The Magnetic Tree4:287Electric Relic1:558It's Not Supposed To Be Snowing2:379Pillars of Pepper3:3710Frozen Hot Sauce2:1311Sepia Tone Laboratory3:0312Upside Down Stalagmite3:3313Baryogenesis3:2214A Safe Place to Sleep2:3415Introduction0:30There are also three additional bonus tracks if the soundtrack is purchased.No.Track TitleTrack Time1Your Favorite Color1:522Light Pollution3:413Dream Salvage2:48System RequirementsPCOS: Windows XP, Vista, 7Processor: Core 2 Duo 2.0 GHz or equivalentMemory: 1GBHard Disk Space: 400MB Free SpaceVideo Card: Dedicated graphics card with Shader Model 2.0 supportDirectX®: 9.0cMacOS: OS X version Leopard 10.5.8, Snow Leopard 10.6.3, or later.Processor: Core 2 Duo 2.0 GHz or equivalentMemory: 1GBHard Disk Space: 400MB Free SpaceVideo Card: 256MB RAM with Shader Model 2.0 supportOpenGL: Version 2.1</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20773">N+</game><game id="13373">N</game><game id="22845">I Wanna Be The Guy</game><game id="35887">They Bleed Pixels</game><game id="5269">Oddworld: Abe's Oddysee</game><game id="24739">Trine</game><game id="30380">Limbo</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2334968-dust.png</image></root>