<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32317</id><name>BioShock Infinite</name><description>OverviewElizabeth - the game's AI companion.BioShock Infinite is the third installment in the BioShock franchise. Infinite is set in the all-new city of Columbia, a creation of an America transforming from a regional agrarian collection of states into a world power with global reach. The game is also primarily set in 1912; this is in contrast to the much later dates of the previous two games which took place during the '60s. Despite the departure from the series' usual setting, the game still retains some of the previous games' gameplay hooks, such as super human powers and first person shooting.The game was released on March 26 2013 for PlayStation 3, Xbox 360, and PC via Steam. A Mac version of the game is set to be released via Steam later in the year. In North America, the PlayStation 3 version of the game comes bundled with the original BioShock.SettingA 360° panorama of Columbia.BioShock Infinite takes place in the majestic floating city of Columbia, circa 1912. Engineered by the American government, Columbia was initially intended to be a floating symbol of American ingenuity and ideology at a time when the United States was just emerging as a prominent "world power." After being developed and completed the floating city was subsequently dispatched to distant shores with great admiration by a beguiled public as a herald for the new technological age.Notwithstanding, what began as a groundbreaking venture to promote prosperity and goodwill suddenly and abruptly goes horribly awry, after a major international incident within China affects the floating city profoundly. In addition to the international incident's already profound effects, it also reveals to the citizens of Columbia and to the rest of the world the floating metropolis' true nature: that in contrast to its Utopian exterior, the interior contains a heavily armed aerial warship of massive proportions.A scene from Battleship Bay - a beach in Columbia.The incident also created a rift between leadership in Columbia and the United States, which causes it to be immediately disavowed and subsequently leads to the city's disappearance shortly thereafter; it vanished among the clouds in a world that wasn't equipped with the modern technology to track it.Since its disappearance, civil war has suddenly erupted within the city, which split its citizens into two prominent factions with drastically different ideological beliefs. The more prominent of the two, The Founders, are a group of ultra-nationalists, religious fanatics and xenophobes who believe in American Exceptionalism and very little else outside of the concept. The opposition to The Founders' ultra-nationalist ideals is the internationalist, anti-capitalist, Marxist group coined only as the Vox Populi, Latin for "the voice of the people." The game echoes the conflicts in BioShock 2 between Ryan (who was a hard boiled capitalist similar to the Founders) and Lamb (who had communist ideals much like the Vox Populi).Story"The Songbird," Elizabeth's jailer.Players take on the role of Booker DeWitt, a former Pinkerton agent who ended up deep in debt to the wrong kind of people. In order to wipe his debt clean, he is given the task of retrieving Elizabeth from Columbia and bringing her back to New York.Finding Elizabeth will be easy enough, but escaping from a city ten thousand feet in the air won't be quite as simple. Players travel throughout Columbia with the goal of seeking out the residence of Z.H. Comstock, leader of The Founders, who Elizabeth must see before they can escape (Comstock is the only person in all of Columbia that can help Elizabeth realize and take control of her powers fully). In the process, their secondary goal is to find a viable escape route from the warring floating city. Elizabeth acts as a companion to the player, providing support during combat, as well a helping to progress the story as DeWitt's relationship with her deepens. This is another departure from traditional BioShock gameplay, as the player took on the role of silent protagonists that discovered their history as the game progressed.Elizabeth is also being chased by the Songbird, a mysterious monster hell-bent on keeping her from escaping. It is unclear why the Songbird wants to keep her imprisoned; it seems that this was what it was initially tasked to do when it was brought to Columbia.Allusions to Other MediaThe floating city of Columbia is regarded as steampunk, and has been compared to Gulliver's Travels, Hayao Miyazaki's Castle in the Sky, and Steamboy. Elements of the city have also been compared to Star Wars (Bespin cloud city and Death Star) as well as the airships of Final Fantasy settings.As well as this, the game shares many overt resemblances to The Wizard of Oz (both the novel and the movie). This is outlined in an article by Rock, Paper, Shotgun.GameplayAn in-game advertisement illustrating the effects of the 'Devil's Kiss' Vigor.Just like previous games in the franchise, the game is played from a first person perspective, with the right hand firing guns and the left hand firing powers. These powers are referred to as "Vigors", and are the equivalent of Plasmids from the previous games in the series. Continuing BioShock 2's improvements on the Plasmid system, Infinite allows players to fire guns and powers simultaneously, without having to switch between them. Players can make use of powers such as fire, lightning, and even a murder of crows to attack enemies.Elizabeth has the power to manipulate "tears" - windows in space and time. DeWitt can ask her to open these tears at any time during battle; these tears can bring in objects  weapons in from another dimension.Columbia also features an intricate series of "Sky-Lines," a rail system that connects the different pieces of the city. Players can leap onto these rails using the Sky-Hook, a magnetized tool that allows for quick travel around the environment. These rails can also be useful in battle, as players can perform jumping melee attacks onto enemies.Motion ControlCreative Director Ken Levine announced during Sony's 2011 E3 conference that the game will offer optional Move support. Players can play through the entirety of the game using the PS Move and Navigation controller.1999 ModeUpon completion of the game for the first time, 1999 mode is unlocked. This mode increases the difficulty of combat significantly through tweaks to damage and ammunition. The game's resurrection system has also been tweaked for the mode; if players do not have the required death penalty fee, the player will be reverted back to a previous save game.In its originally announced incarnation, 1999 mode was intended to expand the role-playing systems of the game by making equip-able items permanent. This would create the semblance of a class-based system focused on player choice and specialization. This version of 1999 mode was removed as changes to the equipment system made it untenable.This mode can also be unlocked without completing the game by entering in the Konami Code (Up, Up, Down, Down, Left, Right, Left, Right, B, A).MusicScoreLike Bioshock and Bioshock 2 the score was composed veteran composer Garry Schyman. However, unlike Bioshock where they went out of their way to not have dynamic music, they found that for Bioshock Infinite it would be too difficult to follow in Bioshock's footsteps, so thus Infinite does have a dynamic soundtrack. The soundtrack even features stingers when the players score head-shots or critical hits and it has a dynamic outro that plays to let the player know that combat is over.Period SongsBioshock is well known for using period music to create mood. However, as authentic recordings from the period are hard to come by, some recordings of period songs including After You've Gone (which plays at several points during the game and over the start menu) were made specifically for the game and produced to sound like they are from the era.Anachronistic SongsColumbia claims to have the songs of tomorrow today. A tear showing songs from the future appears before musician Albert Fink and he repurposes the songs to make them period appropriate. These versions can be heard at different points throughout the game and certain songs appear in their original forms via tears the player encounters. The anachronistic songs included in the game are:Song/Original ArtistRepurposed StyleRepurposed LocationOriginal Version Tear LocationGod Only Knows by The Beach BoysBarbershop QuartetIntroduction to Columbia/End CreditsNoneEverybody Wants to Rule the Word by Tears for FearsNoel CowardPhonograph at Albert Fink's House in Memorial GardensMonument TowerGirls Just Want to Have Fun by Cyndi LauperCalliope InstrumentalBattleship BayMemorial GardensFortunate Son by Creedence Clearwater RevivalAcapellaShantytownPlaza of ZealTainted Love by Gloria Jones/ Soft CellBluesGraveyard Shift Bar in ShantytownNoneShiny Happy People by R.E.M.Big-BandExiting Gondola to Comstock's HouseNoneDownloadable ContentThree DLC packs are to be released, with a Season Pass available for players to purchase all of it at a discount.Clash in the CloudsThe first DLC pack was released on July 30, 2013; it is set in Columbia and features wave-based survival gameplay. It features fifteen waves of enemies spread across four different locations. The DLC also features a number of additional Voxaphone recordings from Rosalind Lutice. The four playable maps are:Raven's DomeThe OPS ZealDuke and Dimwit TheaterEmporia ArcadeBurial at SeaBurial at Sea spans across two DLC packs; episode one will be released on November 12, 2013. It will feature both Booker and Elizabeth within Rapture, set just prior to the events of the first BioShock game (December 31, 1958). Players will continue to play as Booker in the first Burial at Sea DLC; during the second DLC, players will play as Elizabeth.Steam Trading CardsThe game now supports Steam Trading cards. There are a total of 7 cards to collect by playing the game.Also included as a result of getting the cards, is a badge called "Slate's Trooper", worth 100 XP.Development and Pre-Release"Name in the Game" contestThe winner's in-game advertisement.On April 8, 2011, Irrational Games' Community Manager Chris Remo posted a contest on the Irrational website, titled "Get Your Name in the Game," offering fans the opportunity to have their name in BioShock Infinite. Fans simply had to enter their full names and email addresses for a chance to appear as the "namesake of a building, a character, a business–whatever [their] artists come up with" in the game. Touted as the "ultimate bragging right," the Get Your Name in the Game Contest entry period ended on April 13.The lucky winner of the contest was Payton Lane Easter, and Irrational's Mike Swiderek created an advertisement for Payton Lane Easter  Sons Premium Automated Stallions.E3 2011 demoThe demo of the game shown at E3 2011 was shown to the public during an episode of GTTV, featuring a lengthy interview between Creative Director of Infinite Ken Levine and GameTrailers intrepid Geoff Keighley. Subsequently, the 15-minute demo was made available to the rest of the media. Ken Levine later revealed that the demo was not from the actual game but a general target for how the team envisioned the entire experience. This forced them to raise the bar in terms of their ambitions and, according to Ken, ultimately pushed them to create a better game.At Sony's E3 Creative director Ken Levine appeared on stage and announced that there would be a Playstation Vita version of Bioshock Infinite that mirrored the experience of the console and PC version. This version of the game was also supposed to feature cross play. In an interview with Joystiq in 2013 Ken Levine said that the deal with Sony still had not been worked out with publisher 2K Games. He also stated that it was something that he was still interested in doing but needed money to be started.BioShock Infinite: Industrial RevolutionAn example of a puzzle from BioShock Infinite: Industrial Revolution.Industrial Revolution is a standalone browser-based puzzle game that was made available exclusively to players that pre-ordered BioShock Infinite. The game was developed by Lazy 8 Studios, and features gear-based puzzles, similar to those found in Lazy 8's previous game, Cogs. Industrial Revolution was first made available on October 21, 2012, and will remain playable until August 26, 2013.The game yields rewards that can be unlocked in BioShock Infinite - these include extra money, extra lockpicks, and additional gear. As well as this, the game rewards players that complete all puzzles with images that can be used on Facebook and Twitter.System RequirementsPCMinimumOS: Windows Vista Service Pack 2 32-bitProcessor: Intel Core 2 DUO 2.4 GHz / AMD Athlon X2 2.7 GHzMemory: 2 GBHard Drive: 20 GB freeVideo Card: DirectX10 Compatible ATI Radeon HD 3870 / NVIDIA 8800 GT / Intel HD 3000 Integrated GraphicsVideo Card Memory: 512 MBSound Card: DirectX CompatibleRecommendedOS: Windows 7 Service Pack 1 64-bitProcessor: Quad Core ProcessorMemory: 4 GBHard Drive: 30 GB freeVideo Card: DirectX11 Compatible, AMD Radeon HD 6950 / NVIDIA GeForce GTX 560Video Card Memory: 1024 MBSound Card: DirectX CompatibleMacMinimumOS: 10.8.4 (Mountain Lion)Processor: 2.2 GHz Intel Core 2 Duo (Dual-Core)Memory: 4 GB RAMHard Disk Space: 30 GBVideo Memory: 512 MBVideo Card: ATI Radeon HD 3870 / NVidia Geforce 640MSupported Video Cards: NVIDIA GeForce® 640M, 650M, 660M, 675MX, 680MXATI Radeon HD 3870, HD 4850, HD 5670, HD 5750, HD 5770, HD 5870, HD 6750, HD 6770, HD 6970 Intel HD Graphics 4000RecommendedOS: 10.8.4 (Mountain Lion)Processor: 2.2 GHz Intel Core 2 Duo (Dual-Core)Memory: 4 GB RAMHard Disk Space: 30 GBVideo Memory: 512 MBVideo Card: ATI Radeon HD 3870 / NVidia Geforce 640MSupported Video Cards: NVIDIA GeForce® 640M, 650M, 660M, 675MX, 680MXATI Radeon HD 3870, HD 4850, HD 5670, HD 5750, HD 5770, HD 5870, HD 6750, HD 6770, HD 6970 Intel HD Graphics 4000</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8870">System Shock 2</game><game id="21144">Singularity</game><game id="1539">Half-Life 2</game><game id="35850">Dishonored</game><game id="20555">Ōkami</game><game id="26513">The Last Guardian</game><game id="32696">The Ico &amp; Shadow of the Colossus Collection</game><game id="6522">Shadow of the Colossus</game><game id="9638">ICO</game><game id="28006">Okamiden</game><game id="27266">999: 9 Hours, 9 Persons, 9 Doors</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4344/2379677-bioshockinfinite_boxart.jpg</image></root>