<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32356</id><name>Microsoft Flight</name><description>OverviewMicrosoft Flight is a free-to-play flight simulator developed and published by Microsoft for the PC (via Games For Windows - Live) on February 27, 2012 (and for the PC, via Steam, on April 3, 2012). A lighter reboot of the Microsoft Flight Simulator franchise, Microsoft Flight features a smaller scale experience, including a limited number of planes and easier flying assistance for beginners. Players fly around Hawaii and Alaska in aircraft ranging from amphibious light-sport monoplanes to World War II biplanes, participating in various activities including landing challenges, delivery/sightseeing jobs, and finding hidden collectibles (known as Aerocaches).The game features a free-to-play business model. The core, free game comes with two planes (the Icon A5 and Model 75), and gives the player access to the Hawaii mainland. Additional landmasses and planes can be purchased through either Games for Windows - Live or Steam.The game makes use of Games For Windows - Live functionality, including online multiplayer, achievements, and bonus aircraft/locations as paid downloadable content.GameplayMicrosoft Flight features a much smaller scale experience than previous entries in the Flight Simulator series. The game takes entirely in Hawaii and its surrounding islands (as well as the state of Alaska with added DLC), whereas Flight Simulator X featured several dozen high-quality cities and some level of coverage for the entire globe.The flying has also been simplified from previous entries in the series, offering an easier difficulty for newcomers that allows them to bypass most of the complex parts of take-off and landing, as well as making the actual act of flying a bit easier. All of this assistance can be turned off if desired, providing a much more of a traditional flight simulator experience. Besides the standard mouse and keyboard controls Microsoft flight also features gamepad and joystick support, as well as support for TrackIR.AircraftThe game's aircraft are split into two categories: Basic and Deluxe. Only Deluxe version have functional cockpit views and associated interactive instruments and checklists. The aircraft are then put into further different categories, restricting the choice of aircraft for most missions, most commonly due to cargo or passenger capacity. All planes have at least two paint schemes though some need to be unlocked. Some aircraft have unique features (such as an-cockpit 'GPS' map or the ability to land on water) corresponding to their real-world models.All purchasable aircraft have a bonus preview option (as free DLC), which only shows the plane's model in the hangar.Icon A5 (Deluxe) - Included with the base gameBoeing-Stearman Model 75 (Deluxe) - Unlocked by signing in to Games For Windows - LiveVans RV-6A (Deluxe) - Included with the "Hawaii Adventure Pack" DLC ($19.99)Maule M-7-260C (Deluxe) - Purchasable as DLC ($14.99)North American P-51 Mustang (Basic) - Purchasable as DLC ($6.99)Mitsubishi A6M2 Zero (Basic) - Released on 3/27/2012 as DLC ($6.99)Curtiss P-40B Warhawk (Basic) - Released on 4/24/2012 as DLC ($6.99)Vought F4U-1D Corsair (Basic) - Released on 5/30/2012 as DLC ($6.99)"RED TAILS" North American P-51 Mustang (Basic) - Cross-promotion with the DVD/Blu-Ray release of the movie Red Tails. Released on 6/27/2012 as DLC (Free)Cub Crafters Carbon Cub (Basic) - Included with the "Alaskan Wilderness Pack" DLC ($14.99)Cub Crafters Carbon Cub (Deluxe) - Purchasable as DLC ($14.99)C-46 (Basic) - Purchasable as DLC ($6.99)LocationsThe Alaskan Wilderness"Big Island" (Hawai'i) - Included with the base game.Hawaiian Islands - Included with the "Hawaii Adventure Pack" DLC ($19.99)Alaska - Included with the "Alaskan Wilderness Pack" DLC ($14.99)System requirements:Minimum System RequirementsOS: WinXP SP3CPU: Dual Core 2.0 GHzGFX: 256 MB card capable of shader 3.0 (DX 9.0c compliant)RAM: 2.0GBHDD: 10 GB Hard Disk Drive spaceRecommended System RequirementsOS: Win7 SP1 64-bit operating systemCPU: Dual Core 3.0 GHzGPU: 1024 MB ATI Radeon HD 5670 or 1024 MB NVIDIA GEFORCE 9800 GT or equivalentRAM: 6GBHDD: 30 GB hard drive spaceCancellationMicrosoft Flight was canceled on July 25th, 2012 after Microsoft shut down the Vancouver studio responsible for its development. The C-46 was near completion at the time and was released after this date, and some features such as "Aerocache of the Day" continue to be updated.</description><genres><genre id="24">Flight Simulator</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15530">Pro Pilot '99</game><game id="14727">Pilotwings</game><game id="108">Pilotwings 64</game><game id="31748">Pilotwings Resort</game><game id="40332">Aerofly FS</game><game id="43063">FlightGear</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2140359-box_mflight.png</image></root>