<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32381</id><name>Pink Sweets ~Ibara Sorekara~</name><description>Pink Sweets ~Ibara Sore Kara~ is a vertical bullet hell shoot 'em up developed by Cave and released in 2006. It is a sequel to   Ibara. The game's main programmer was   Shinobu Yagawa, the man behind   Battle Garegga. MechanicsThe game allows players to choose between four ships piloted by the Rose sisters, the bosses from Ibara. When the player doesn't shoot, a shield forms in front of the ship and a special attack called rose cracker starts charging. When charged, the rose cracker can be fired by pressing the regular shot button. Options called rose hips can be collected throughout the game, and placed in five different formations.The game has seven stages, a second loop, and a rank system that increases difficulty as the player shoots, collects items and goes long stretches without losing any lives. There's also a trick allowing players to gain infinite lives (initially mistaken for a bug, but later confirmed by Cave to be an intended feature).  Muchi Muchi Pork!  Pink SweetsAn   Xbox 360 port compilation that includes, in addition to Pink Sweets,   Muchi Muchi Pork! as well as a number of extra content (arrange modes, new music and, for buyers of the first print, Muchi Muchi Pork! Matsuri Version, a special version of Muchi Muchi Pork! that includes the bosses from Pink Sweets) was announced at the Cave summer festival of August 2010. The port is free of region protection, and will be released February 24 2011.</description><genres><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26433">DoDonPachi Dai Ou Jou Black Label EXTRA</game><game id="21705">DoDonPachi</game><game id="22919">Battle Garegga</game><game id="29280">Mushihime-sama Futari</game><game id="22393">Mushihime-Sama</game><game id="33885">Muchi Muchi Pork!</game><game id="33917">DoDonPachi Daifukkatsu Black Label</game><game id="34237">Ketsui: Kizuna Jigoku Tachi</game><game id="34001">Crimzon Clover</game><game id="34268">Mushihime-sama Futari Black Label</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/12/122378/1737852-pink_sweets.png</image></root>