<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32426</id><name>Super Robot Wars L</name><description>OverviewSuper Robot Wars L is the seventh Super Robot Wars game for the Nintendo DS and the third traditional, anime-based game. Many of the anime featured in this game appeared in the previous three traditional GBA/DS games; however, the developer claims that the animations for those returning series will be improved upon. Like Super Robot Wars K, the roster is primarily new-school; the only series predating the '00s are Endless Waltz, Combattler V/Voltes V, and the debuting Iczer OVAs.Featured SeriesA list of the anime series that are featured in the game. Anime that debut in this game are marked with "(new)".Shinji Ikari makes his handheld SRW debut.New Mobile Report Gundam Wing: Endless WaltzMobile Suit Gundam SEEDMobile Suit Gundam SEED DestinyMazinkaiser (OVA version)Mazinkaiser vs. The Great General of DarknessSuper Electromagnetic Robot Combattler VSuper Electromagnetic Machine Voltes VFight! Iczer One (new)Iczer Reborn (new)Shinkon Gattai Godannar!!Shinkon Gattai Godannar!! Second SeasonGaiking: Legend of Daiku MaryuKotetsushin JeegRebuild of Evangelion (new)Dancougar Nova (new)Macross Frontier (new)Linebarrels of Iron (new)Gameplay ChangesPartner Battle SystemEach unit has a "Partner Bonus" which raises the stats of its team.Partners can be swapped between teams by moving adjacent to another unit."Individual Attack" allows the Main unit to attack the enemy's Main unit and the Sub unit to attack the enemy's Sub unit. (Similar to Super Robot Wars Z's Wide Formation)If a Main unit and its Sub unit attack and the Main unit is destroyed, the Sub unit continues to attack. (In previous games, battle ends once a Main unit is destroyed).OtherClassic-style Support returns for single units. (In K, it was impossible for anyone except a Partner Unit to Support)For the first time since Super Robot Wars 2G, there are no equipable items.For a sizeable portion of the game, unit upgrades are limited to 5 points each. Eventually this will rise to the standard 10.The 'favourite series' system is not making a return.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/16207/1531547-srwl_boxart.jpg</image></root>