<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32513</id><name>Pinball FX2</name><description>OverviewPinball FX 2 is a free downloadable shell (for downloadable pinball tables) developed by Zen Studios first released for the Xbox 360 via Xbox Live Arcade on October 27, 2010. Along with all the gameplay features of the previous installment, the game includes split-screen simulatenous multiplayer, a new physics model, new special effects, a new system for achievements, global persistent stats, timed "trial modes" for each table, and the option to import all purchased tables from Pinball FX for free. A Windows Phone version is currently under development.Each table in Pinball FX2 includes three achievements (worth 5, 15, and 30 gamerscore) based on the difficulty of that achievement (which involves a specific goal to perform in that table). Some achievements also have an alternate goal of having a higher score than a certain number of players in the player's Friends List. (3 Friends for 5g, 5 Friends for 15g, and 10 Friends for 30g) The game itself also has avatar awards, which unlock as the player reaches milestones for the "Wizardscore" system (5,000 points for a t-shirt with the game logo on it, and 100,000 points for a male wizard robe and female sorceress dress).GameplayPinball FX 2 features both online and offline modes, players can play each table in single player where the main goal is to get the highest score possible by activating the bumpers, ramps, spinners and playing through the table specific Game modes such as the Secrets of the Deep tables Galleon exploration.The single player mode allows players to add their personal high score to the online leader boards as long as the operator settings are set to default.There are several multiplayer modes for online and offline play, offline players can play either hot seat mode in which each player takes turns sequentially or split screen in which both players play simultaneously on the same screen which is a first for pinball simulators.The online mode allows players to play in a ranked or player match over Xbox Live. The ranked mode pits you against a similarly skilled opponent based on your trueskill ranking while player match allows you to either find a random opponent or play against a Friend.In multiplayer players have infinite balls and must aim to get the highest score either within a set time frame or be the first player to achieve the target score, with the exception of ranked online play which uses a standard rule set, the multiplayer mode allows you to tweak the method of determining the winner.Superscore and WizardscoreWithin Pinball FX 2 there is a persistent scoring system called Superscore, this is determined by adding together your highest score on each table and rounding it down to the nearest million, so if you had a combined table score of 292,124,201 your Superscore would be 292.There is also a second scoring system which unlocks rewards as you progress called Wizardscore, Wizardscore is calculated by adding your Superscore to your friends combined Superscore and multiplying this value by the number of tables you have set a high score on. For instance if you have a Superscore of 300, your friends have a combined Superscore of 700 and you own 10 tables your wizard score would be 10,000.TablesWhile the game itself does not include any full versions of the tables (with the exception of the PC version, which includes the Mars table for free), tables can be purchased as collections (including four tables at a cost of 800 msp, or $10) or individual tables (at a cost of either 240 msp/$3 or 200 msp/$2.50). The PC version of Pinball FX 2 does not include collections and all tables must be individually purchased.Any table that can be purchased also includes a free trial version, which can only be played towards a set time limit and does not include achievements, leaderboards, local high scores, or game configurations. Trial versions are not available in the PC version.Pinball FX2 CoreReleased alongside Pinball FX2, the Pinball FX2 Core collection includes four tables for 800 msp ($10). Trial versions were included with the Xbox 360 version of Pinball FX2.Biolab - Comical "mad scientist" theme.Pasha - Persian theme.Rome - Roman legion theme.Secrets of the Deep - Underwater exploration theme.Pinball FX ClassicReleased alongside Pinball FX2, the Pinball FX Classic collection includes the three tables included with the original Pinball FX, along with the DLC table Buccaneer. These tables must be purchased in a bundle for 800 msp ($10). The bundle is free for owners of the original Pinball FX and is not available for the PC version of Pinball FX2.Speed Machine - Based on illegal street racing and car-tuning culture.Extreme - Based on extreme sports and skateboarding.Agents - Based on secret agents and action movies.Buccaneer - Pirate theme.Marvel PinballReleased on December 8, 2010 for 800 msp ($10), the Marvel Pinball collection includes four tables based on franchises from the Marvel license. Also available as a standalone game for other platforms and as a downloadable pack for Zen Pinball 2. On the PC version of Pinball FX2, all tables are sold separately.Spider-ManIron ManBladeWolverineMarvel: Vengeance and VirtueReleased on December 14, 2011 for 800 msp ($10), the Marvel: Vengeance and Virtue collection includes four tables also based on franchises from the Marvel license. Also available as a downloadable pack for Zen Pinball 2 and Marvel Pinball. On the PC version of Pinball FX2, all tables are sold separately.Ghost RiderThorMoon KnightX-MenMarvel: Avengers ChroniclesReleased on June 20, 2012 for 800 msp ($10), the Marvel: Avengers Chronicles collection includes four tables (one based on a recent Marvel film and three based on Marvel crossover comic book storylines). Also available as a downloadable pack for Zen Pinball 2 and Marvel Pinball. On the PC version of Pinball FX2, all tables are sold separately.The Avengers - Based on the 2012 film Marvel's The Avengers.Fear Itself - Based on Marvel's Fear Itself comic book storyline.The Infinity Gauntlet - Based on Marvel's The Infinity Gauntlet comic book storyline.World War Hulk - Based on Marvel's World War Hulk comic book storyline.Zen ClassicsReleased on December 12, 2012 for 800 msp ($10), the Zen Classics collection includes the four tables that was originally included with Zen Pinball. Also available as downloadable tables for Zen Pinball 2.El Dorado - A hunt for the city of gold.Shaman - Supernatural-themed table based around a witch doctor performing miracles.Tesla - Based on the inventor Nikola Tesla.V12 - Automobile theme.Star Wars PinballReleased on February 27, 2012 for 800 msp ($10), the Star Wars Pinball collection includes three tables based on the Star Wars franchise. Also available as a downloadable pack for Zen Pinball 2.Star Wars Episode V: The Empire Strikes BackStar Wars: The Clone WarsBoba FettIndividual TablesThese tables are not part of any collection and must be downloaded separately for 240 msp ($3) each.Mars - Released on April 20, 2011. Based on a futuristic expedition of the planet Mars. Also available as a downloadable table for Zen Pinball and Zen Pinball 2. Full version included with the PC version of Pinball FX2.Fantastic Four - Released on May 18, 2011. Based on Marvel's Fantastic Four franchise. Also available as a downloadable table for Zen Pinball 2 and Marvel Pinball.Captain America - Released on June 29, 2011. Based on Marvel's Captain America franchise. Also available as a downloadable table for Zen Pinball 2 and Marvel Pinball.Ms. Splosion Man - Released on August 31, 2011. Based on the video game Ms. Splosion Man. Not available for the PC version of Pinball FX2.Sorcerer's Lair - Released on October 12, 2011. Kids fantasy horror theme. Also available as a downloadable table for Zen Pinball and Zen Pinball 2.Paranormal - Released on October 26, 2011. Based on paranormal activity and investigations. Free to download between October 26, 2011 and November 1, 2011. Also available as a downloadable table for Zen Pinball and Zen Pinball 2. Not available for the PC version of Pinball FX2.Epic Quest - Released on February 15, 2012. Comical fantasy medieval table with RPG elements and a persistent experience point system. Also available as a downloadable table for Zen Pinball and Zen Pinball 2.Plants vs. Zombies - Released on September 5, 2012. Based on the video game Plants vs. Zombies. Also available as a downloadable table for Zen Pinball 2. Not available for the PC version of Pinball FX2.Civil War - Released on November 21, 2012. Based on Marvel's Civil War comic book storyline. Also available as a downloadable table for Zen Pinball 2 and Marvel Pinball.Individual Tables (Pinball FX)Released alongside Pinball FX2, these tables are the downloadable tables from the original Pinball FX (with the exception of Buccaneer, which is included in the Pinball FX Classic collection). Each table must be downloaded separately for 200 msp ($2.50) each.Nightmare Mansion - Horror themed. Not available for the PC version of Pinball FX2.Rocky and Bullwinkle - Based on the 1950s cartoon The Rocky and Bullwinkle Show. Not available for the PC version of PinbalL FX2.Street Fighter II Tribute - Based on the Street Fighter II franchise. Not to be confused Gottlieb's Street Fighter II pinball machine. Also available as a downloadable table for Zen Pinball and Zen Pinball 2. Not available for the PC version of Pinball FX2.Earth Defense - A sci-fi horror theme based on alien invasion. Features a giant robot toy with fluid movement. Also available for Zen Pinball and Zen Pinball 2.Excalibur - Fantasy medieval table based on the legend of King Arthur. Not to be confused with Gottlieb's Excalibur pinball machine. Also available for Zen Pinball and Zen Pinball 2.System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows XP/Windows Vista/Windows 7/Windows 8 Processor: Single Core CPU @ 1.6GHz Memory: 512 MB RAM Graphics: GeForce 6600 / Radeon 9800 DirectX®: 9.0 Hard Drive: 1200 MB HD space Sound: DirectX compatible sound card RecommendedOS: Windows XP/Windows Vista/Windows 7/Windows 8 Processor: Dual Core CPU @ 2.00GHz Memory: 1024 MB RAM Graphics: GeForce 8800 / Radeon HD 3850 DirectX®: 9.0c Hard Drive: 1500 MB HD space Sound: DirectX compatible sound card Other Requirements: Broadband Internet connection</description><genres><genre id="30">Pinball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="36777">The Pinball Arcade</game><game id="37942">Zen Pinball 2</game><game id="15088">Pro Pinball: Big Race USA</game><game id="40892">Capcom Arcade Cabinet</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1839026-box_pfx2.png</image></root>