<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32560</id><name>Puddle</name><description>OverviewA physics based puzzle game in which you guide a series of liquids from one point to another in varying maps and environments. Tilting the levels is the only way to get the liquid through and you'll encounter new obstacles as well as new liquids to control which you must get through to the end. Puddle was released for both Xbox Live Arcade and six days later for PlayStation Network. A Wii U version is currently in the works.After winning a 2010 IGF award for student projects the game was picked up by Konami to become polished enough to appear on XBLA and PSN.GameplayOne of the tree environmentsThrough tilting of the world you must guide your liquid from the beginning of the level to the end without losing too much of it through a series of obstacles in the game environment. You'll control different types of liquid each with their own set of physics as well as different environments with different hazards that may evaporate, burn off, or get left behind. A combination of speed and strategy is required to get enough of your liquid past dangerous obstacles. You'll also have items, such as leaf bulbs, that you need to carry and place around the level.Each level will award you medals, bronze, silver, and gold, depending on your performance. Levels in include sewers and drains, plant life and nature, laboratory,The game also included a small sandbox level editor to mess around with the fluid dynamics of the game.Wii U VersionMove puddles on Wii UThe Wii U eShop version of the game will support gameplay in full 1080p with 60 frames per second, Off-TV Play, online leaderboards and optional motion control comparable to the PSVita version. Certain levels have been tweaked with the help of collected player data to improve playability and remove potentially frustrating elements.PC System RequirementsMinimumOS:Windows XP 32bits SP3Processor:2 Ghz Dual CoreMemory:1024 MB RAMGraphics:Nvidia Geforce 8600 GT, ATI Radeon 4650, Intel HD Graphics, 512 MB Shader Model 3DirectX®:9.0cHard Drive:650 MB HD spaceSound:DirectX 9 compatibleRecommendedOS:Windows Vista, Windows 7 or 8Processor:2 Ghz Dual Core and aboveMemory:2048 MB RAMGraphics:Nvidia Geforce 8800, ATI Radeon 4800, Intel HD Graphics 512 MBDirectX®:9.0cHard Drive:1024 MB HD spaceSound:DirectX 9 compatible</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="32485">Fluidity</game><game id="24715">I-Fluid</game><game id="9410">LocoRoco</game><game id="24884">Rolando</game><game id="25643">Rolando 2: Quest for the Golden Orchid</game><game id="31678">Tales from Space: About a Blob</game><game id="1710">Mercury Meltdown</game><game id="35903">The Splatters</game><game id="39542">Fluidity: Spin Cycle</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2151657-box_puddle.png</image></root>