<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32598</id><name>Monster Maulers</name><description>Overview: The game  focuses on 1 on 1 battles versus giant enemies (like e.g. in         Red Earth) with a srcrolling beat 'em up section during the last level. Monster Maulers features 3 playable characters controlled with the 3 button attack scheme. Playable characters:   Character selection screen.  Anne     - Anne (quick but physically the weakest)   Nationality: British   Age: 22   Height: 5'8''   Weight: 125 lbs.   Hobbies: yoga, cooking   Profile: her whip-like punches and kicks are strong enough to beat any man.   Eagle     - Eagle (the strongest        Haggar type fighter)   Nationality: American   Age: ?    Height: 6'7''    Weight: 215 lbs.    Hobbies: pro-wrestling   Profile: his past is shrouded in mistery, but his perfect body can inflict huge damage on his enemies.   Kotetsu         - Kotetsu (a balanced warrior bearing a slight resemblence to       Ryu)   Nationality: Japanese    Age: 29    Height: 6'8''     Weight: 165 lbs.     Hobbies: haiku, meditation    Profile: he has combined various oriental martial arts to become a killing machine.  Bosses:   Moai              Moai (intro) Codename: MoaiStage: BrazilDescription: A fearsome god from a mysterious land.          Brainy  Brainy (intro)           Codename: Brainy Stage: Kenya Description: Red terror! A gleaming orb.        Centaur  Centaur (gameplay)    Codename: CentaurStage: IraqDescription: Is it a god? A devil? A shadow lurks in the shrine.       Diablo          Diablo (intro) Codename: DiabloStage: ChinaDescription: Roaring thunder! A demon who summons storms.       Fungus  Fungus (gameplay)   Codename: FungusStage: BermudaDescription: A terrifying sea and a strange life-form.       Dragon  Dragon (gameplay)   Codename: DragonStage: NorwayDescription: An evil trap! A creature from the depth.</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22820">Red Earth</game><game id="42703">Metamoqester</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/10/106662/1507437-monster_maulers_logo.jpg</image></root>