<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32632</id><name>Fastar!</name><description>OverviewFastar! (Fight Angry Squares: The Action RPG!) is an incredibly unique action RPG game that follows the adventures of a nameless protagonist in a blue tuxedo and blue slacks (which can be customized with different colors as he runs across 2D landscapes battling squares of various sizes and colors while visiting villages along the way.  Gameplay      The main character is controlled using the accelerometer; by tilting the iPhone left or right, the character will run in those directions. Attacks are controlled by merely tapping the screen and tilting the device quickly. Special powers which are selected before starting a game can be activate by tapping on their icons in the top right of the screen. The square enemies hop wildly, push forward and literally roll around as they attempt to hurt you. Defeated enemies drop coins which can then be used to purchase upgrades at shoppes. All of the modes are timed and these times are posted on global and local leaderboards which display the time to completion of a level and the stats of your character upon completion as well as your chosen spell. The game also features three alternate control schemes which include swiping, a virtual gamepad and one handed swipe controls.  Game ModesNameTypeLearn to Play  A tutorial level that teaches the basic game mechanics Easy, Medium and Hard Basic modes that provide the "the classic Fastar experience". The higher difficulties have longer maps with harder enemies Profit Gather as much money as you can Battlemage Players get two spells, but upgrades are priced higher No Excuses A mode in which nothing is random Showdown Literally a showdown against 25 enemies Goliath A gauntlet of giant squares and no healing Sudden Death All enemies deal one hit kills Marathon An incredibly long mode which has an average time of 60 minutes Arena An infinite number of enemies tat progressively get harder Colors 12 different color modes in which all of the enemies take on the color of the mode  Shoppes      Throughout the levels in the game, your character will happen upon villages with shoppes that have upgrades for sale. These upgrades include health restoration (10 cents), attack upgrades (15 cents) and defense upgrades (10 cents). Finding a balance between the upgrades is key to advancing through the higher difficulty levels.  SpellsNameEffect BZAP Stuns the enemy with a bolt of lightning FIAR Sets the enemy ablaze SLEY Destroys the enemy outright BEEFDoubles your defense for a short time  MEER Reflects spells cast on you back to the enemy LIYF Restores your health to maximum SWUP Swaps your power and defense ZOOM Increases running speed for a short time HOAM Returns you to the previous village</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="35325">Half-Minute Hero: Super Mega Neo Climax</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/10/103101/1514466-fastar_logo200.png</image></root>