<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32643</id><name>Dungeon Magic</name><description>OverviewDungeon Magic is a fantasy action game similar to other, more popular, titles like        Dungeons  Dragons: Shadow Over Mystara,        Dungeons and Dragons: Tower of Doom or      The King of Dragons. The plot cosists of a typical and bland story involving an evil wizard who kidnapped a beautiful princess. The game starts in a tavern where each player can choose one of four characters, each belonging to a different class. The characters are controlled with 2 buttons - one responsible for attackinh, the other jumping; pushing both of them at once results in a character-specific special attack (e.g. blade fury or multiple fireballs), which does not use players energy, but is fuelled by special rare orbs. There are also RPG elements present in the game. Characters can be equipped with various weapons (swords, crossbows, staffs etc.) and shields. They also level up and gain experience. The action is presented in an isometric view. Players are also given a certain degree of choice when it comes to moving between location as there often are few ways to exit the map.  Playable characters  Ash. Ash Age: 21 Class: Knight Race: Human      Cisty Age: ? Class: Archer Race: Elf      Gren Age: 29 Class: Fighter Race: Human     Vold Age: 88 Class: Wizard Race: Human Bosses  Giant snake.  King Viper.  Queen Spider.  Lesser Demon.  Venom/Demon.                                                               Dark Knight.                              Ending      The battle has ended. The heroes defeated the Demon (the big guy standing next to Venom in the picture above) and brought light to this world. The people called them Lightbringers.  Apart from the common conclusion of the storyline each character has their own ending.    Vold: I will never use magic again so that there should never be someone like Venom again. Vold stopped teaching magic as one of his disciples sold his soul to the evil. </description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="15143">Knights of the Round</game><game id="22870">Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Tower of Doom</game><game id="22872">Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Shadow Over Mystara</game><game id="3796">The King of Dragons</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/10/106662/1517452-dungeon_magic_title.jpg</image></root>