<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32645</id><name>Felony 11-79</name><description>Overview It always comes down to this.     In the late sixteenth century, archaeologist Thomas Samuel discovered the route to a previously unexplored City of Gold. There he found vast amounts of coveted treasure and caskets buried in the ground, which contained gems, gold bars and the corpses of ancient kings. But there was one casket that could not be opened. Eventually the casket was purchased at an auction by an entrepreneur, Albert Brookmond IV for roughly two million dollars. His late grandfather's writings described a set of keys that would open the casket. There are three keys: the Jade Statue, the Golden Wing, and the Silver Staff. All three must be assembled to open the casket. To find the keys, Mr. Brookmond hired a man feared in the business world for his characteristics of ruthless pursuit and disregard for the law.           Players take the role of a wheelman completing jobs for a shady employer   and outrunning the police. The goal is to retrieve three pieces of a lost artifact; a statue, wings and a scepter, to assemble a "key" that will unlock the tomb holding the untold riches.   The main objective of each mission is to get to the end of each of the three courses within the time limit causing as little or as much damage as possible. Meeting the specific time and/or damage requirements will earn the player access to bigger and better vehicles.   HistoryFelony 11-79 is the first game in a franchise of a different name. It was produced and designed by Kan Naito, one of the founders of Climax Entertainment more notably know for     LandStalker and the    Shining Force franchise. Outside of the United States and European regions the game was released as Runabout. Felony 11-79's soundtrack features The Surf Coasters, a Japanese psychedelic rock group with a cult following. It is unknown why the game's title was changed by ASCII Entertainment during localization. The Japanese release of the game featured a special ranking mode where players with the fastest course times could win a trip to meet the developers.   Missions  Bombs: Some assembly required     The game spans three missions across three courses and each course has multiple routes and shortcuts unlike later games in the Runabout franchise which only featured one larger city. Fuel management is key as better vehicles have varying capacities and consume it at different rates. Each course has places to fuel up so knowing shortcut and gas station locations is important.     The Downtown Course  Mission 1 begins immediately after you have retrieved the first piece of the key, the Jade Statue.  As  you evade the  police you need to collect 5 sticks of dynamite along the narrow Chinatown streets. With that you can now blow open the gate to Michael's Estate and finally make your way through his mansion and the hotel and escape into the suburban streets. Key Locations: Chinatown, Michael's Estate, the hotel, gas station, the tunnel, Broad Street  The Sea Side Course       Mission 2 features a freeway chase where you must obtain the second piece of the key from an evading limo. After assaulting the limo and retrieving the Golden Wing, the tables are turned and once again you must evade the police.Key Locations: Route 39, the beach, the Endless Highway, gas station, Route 24   The Metro City Course       In Mission 3, you make your way through various Paris streets, subways and shopping centers in search for the final piece, the Silver Staff, which remains hidden in a secluded courtyard within an old statue. Smashing a phone booth at the beginning of the mission starts the timer and and begins the chase through the snaking country roads.Key Locations: Montavo Street, the subway, Erasmus Pass, the lake, shopping center, the docks   VehiclesA wheelman is only as good as the vehicle he drives. Felony 11-79 is about choosing the vehicle from your garage to tackle each of the courses and all of the alternate routes. Each vehicle has its own unique characteristics and stats that make certain ones more accustom to a specific courses terrain. Several adjustments can be made to vehicle setups to tweak handling as well. Only 4 vehicles are unlocked at the start of the game but an additional 18 can be unlocked through progressing through the main missions and meeting speed and damage requirements for each courses.  DRMFuel Capacity: 90  HP: 250This 4WD pickup has all around average horsepower. Along with its durability, the DRM is one of the better starting vehicles.Unlocks: When you start the game.318      Fuel Capacity: 70  HP: 150This sports car has lower stats than the RAM making it a much faster choice. However, it is only available with an Automatic Transmission.Unlocks: When you start the game.MIN      Fuel Capacity: 50  HP: 53Similar to the Mini Cooper, this tiny car has all around decent stats and a small frame that makes for high maneuverability. The MIN is only available for road course driving.Unlocks: When you start the game.VES      Fuel Capacity: 5  HP: 12This little scooter barely has any horsepower and can't hold much fuel but it can fit through any alley in the game. The VES along with the RCC are the key to completing the game's $0 damage runs.Unlocks: When you start the game.CIV      Fuel Capacity: 45  HP: 130Another sports car similar to the 320 with lower horsepower and fuel capacity, but weighs less as well. Only available with an Automatic Transmission.Unlocks: After completing Mission 1.NSR      Fuel Capacity: 70  HP: 280Similar to the real world NSX. A very heavy sports car with a high top speed. Available only with a Manual Transmission.Unlocks: After completing Mission 1.GT5      Fuel Capacity: 65  HP: 280The counterpart to the NSR. Has improved acceleration and braking.  Available only with a Manual Transmission.Unlocks: After completing Mission 2.BUS      Fuel Capacity: 120  HP: 235A public transit bus. Has all the benefits of a bus; high durability, lots of horsepower and torque but sacrifices speed and maneuverability. In the Japanese release, the BUS is labeled: SamTrans.Unlocks: After completing Mission 2.DTK      Fuel Capacity: 150  HP: 395A dump truck very similar to the BUS but weighs a bit less. Has better torque and fuel capacity but is even slower than the BUS.Unlocks: After completing Mission 3.LIM      Fuel Capacity: 100  HP: 275A decent, all around vehicle but is very difficult to control and is only available with an Automatic Transmission.Unlocks: After completing Mission 3.VPR      Fuel Capacity: 70  HP: 450Similar to the real world Dodge Viper. Extremely high horsepower and responsive controls but isn't very durable.Unlocks: After completing EASY Mode with a damage total higher than $1,000,000.ELS      Fuel Capacity: 50  HP: 118Another super light sports car with low torque that isn't very durable.Unlocks: After completing MEDIUM Mode with a damage total higher than $2,500,000. 360      Fuel Capacity: 55  HP: 16The counterpart the VES and similar to the real world VW Beetle. Similar to the VES in stats but handles like a car.Unlocks: After completing HARD Mode with a damage total higher than $2,500,000.PCS      Fuel Capacity: 70  HP: 255Similar to the real world Toyota Supra. The FD7's horsepower makes it one of the fastest cars with an Automatic Transmission in the game.Unlocks: After completing EASY Mode within 4 minutes. GT1      Fuel Capacity: 65  HP: 600A rally car made for off-road driving. The GT1 pushes some of the highest horsepower and torque numbers in the game but can't handle the road. Only available with a Manual Transmission.Unlocks: After completing MEDIUM Mode within 4 minutes.DBL      Fuel Capacity: 72  HP: 375Similar to the real world Lamborghini Diablo. A super fast car with low durability and is only available with a Manual Transmission.Unlocks: After completing HARD Mode within 4 minutes.GTK      Fuel Capacity: 90  HP: 230A heavy truck with surprisingly decent acceleration and maneuverability.Unlocks: After doing over 180 km/h on the freeway on the Seaside course. SSP      Fuel Capacity: 100  HP: 200A big street sweeper. This counterpart to the GTK features similar stats but weighs almost three times as much.Unlocks: After doing over 230 km/h on the freeway on the Seaside course.FML      Fuel Capacity: 130  HP: 700A very light Formula racer. Extremely high horsepower and acceleration makes this a very dangerous vehicle.Unlocks: After completing the Downtown course with NO accumulated damagePLC      Fuel Capacity: 60  HP: 820A police cruiser which handles similar to the other sports cars in the game but is much more durable than the rest.Unlocks: After completing the Seaside course with NO accumulated damageTNK      Fuel Capacity: 500  HP: 1500The tank is the most destructive vehicle in the game and can level almost anything its path. It features a cannon with unlimited ammo. Available only with an Automatic Transmission.Unlocks: After completing the Metro course with NO accumulated damageRCC      Fuel Capacity: 1  HP: 1The remote control car features the lowest stats in the game but it can fit anywhere. Available only with an Automatic Transmission.Unlocks: After finding it in the Paris course in the convenient store.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19097">Super Runabout: San Francisco Edition</game><game id="20484">Burnout</game><game id="39116">Runabout 3D: Drive Impossible</game><game id="39126">Runabout 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2303975-box_felony1179.png</image></root>