<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3267</id><name>Commandos 3: Destination Berlin</name><description>OverviewCommandos 3 is actually the fourth game of the  Commandos series developed by  Pyro Studios. It is yet again set during the  second World War and Its structure and gameplay is mostly the same as in previous installments. The games campaign mode is actually separated into three different campaigns all taking place in a different theater of war.  Although the gameplay is very similar to previous games, there are some changes. Such as the introduction of new weapons such as the  assault rifle and changes to the  inventory setup. Also all the commandos can use weapons such as grenades, which were previously only usable by  the Sapper. For commandos such as  the Green Beret, who previously could only use a  pistol, can now use mostly all of the  weapons in the game. A new cover mechanic was also introduced into the game, which gives commandos the ability to cover an area, ready to automatically shoot any enemies that close in on his location. It is useful for covering doors. Area covered is displayed much like that of the  line of sight displayed on guards. This made it much easier for the commandos to defend themselves from a frontal assault and is much more accurate than manual fire.  The number of commandos was reduced from previous games to just 6. These are  the Green Beret,  the Diver , the Sniper,  the Spy,  the Sapper and  the Thief. Commandos such as  the Driver were removed, as their special abilities (in this case driving) can now be carried out by other commandos. Commandos  Diver  Real name: James Blackwood. Birthday: 3 August 1911. Birthplace:  Melbourne,  Australia.Can use his scuba gear to dive underwater and stay there indefinitely. This is useful to disarm underwater objects such as sea mines. He is also the only commando who can pilot boats. Also has a grappling hook and can throw knives at enemies.  Green BeretReal name: Jerry McHale.Birthday: 10 October 1909.Birthplace:  Dublin,  Ireland.The Strongest of the commandos. Green Beret has the ability to carry heavy objects. He can also bury himself in certain areas. His main attribute is his Knife, which he can use to silently take out enemy units without attracting attention.  Army boxing champion from 1934 to 1937.  Sapper  Real name: Thomas Hancock. Birthday: 14 January 1911. Birthplace:  Liverpool, England.He is an expert in heavy weapons and explosives such as C4 and flamethrowers.  SniperReal name: Sir Francis T. Woolridge. Birthday: 21 March 1909. Birthplace: Sheffield,  England.Has the ability to shoot enemies at very long range. To initiate this the player must place the cross hairs over the unit to be shot.  Spy  Real name: Rene Duchamp.  Birthday: 20 November 1911.  Birthplace:  Lyon,  France.Can disguise himself in the clothes of enemies and walk through enemies without attraction attention. While in an enemy uniform the spy can distract guards and, if wearing a high ranking uniform, order low ranking soldiers to face a certain direction.  ThiefReal name: Paul Toledo.  Birthday: March 1, 1916.  Birthplace:  Paris, France.As the smallest and fastest of the Commandos, thief can climb walls as well as jump through windows. He can pick locks on doors and boxes.  System Requirements Minimun: Microsoft Windows 98SE/2000/XP (Admin rights required), Pentium III 700 Mhz (or Athlon(tm) equivalent), 128 MB on Windows 98SE, 256 on Windows 2000/XP, 32 MB DirectX 9 compatible 3D Graphics card (nVidia GeForce or Ati Radeon Chipset), Windows 98SE/2000/XP-compatible sound card (100% DirectX 9-compatible), 2 GB free disk space, 100% Windows 98SE/2000/XP compatible mouse and keyboardRecommended: Pentium® 4 2.0 GHz (or Athlon(tm) XP equivalent), 512 MB, 128 MB GeForce 4ti or ATI Radeon 9xxx equivalentMultiplayer Requirements: Pentium® III 1.0 GHz (or Athlon(tm) equivalent), 256 MB, 64 MB GeForce or ATI Radeon equivalent, LAN, ADSL or Cable Modem </description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6173">Soldiers: Heroes of World War II</game><game id="24466">Jagged Alliance</game><game id="8271">Commandos: Strike Force</game><game id="21175">Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War II</game><game id="25751">Elite Forces: Unit 77</game><game id="10756">Desperados: Wanted Dead or Alive</game><game id="9608">Helldorado</game><game id="11730">Soldiers at War</game><game id="19692">Korea: Forgotten Conflict</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/22/906714-commandos2031.jpg</image></root>