<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32697</id><name>Dark Souls</name><description>OverviewDark Souls is a dark fantasy action-RPG for the PS3, Xbox 360 and PC developed by FromSoftware. It is the spiritual successor to one of the company's previous titles, Demon's Souls. The game's working title was "Project Dark".FromSoftware self-published the game's Playstation 3 version in Japan, where it was released September 22, 2011. The Xbox 360 version will not be released there. Namco Bandai is the publisher for both versions of the game in Western territories. They released the game in North America on October 4, 2011, and in Europe October 7, 2011. The Asian version of the game with English voice-acting and English and traditional Chinese subtitles was released on October 19th, 2011. In April 2012, a German game magazine preview surfaced, revealing a PC version with new Bosses coming in August of the same year. The Prepare to Die Edition was released worldwide for the PC on August 24th, 2012. The additional content, Artorias of the Abyss, came to consoles as downloadable content on October 23rd, 2012 for North America and a day later for other regions.The game (as with its predecessor) is known primarily for its difficulty, including very high combat lethality and scarce information provided to players. Dark Souls director, Hidetaka Miyazaki, has said that the primary "concepts behind Dark Souls are 'sense of achievement' and 'surprise of discovery' with difficulty merely being a means to these ends. Players who excise patience and critical-thinking are rewarded. Dark Souls intentionally does not conform to many established game design conventions, such as maps and designated objectives, contributing to the game's divisive reputation.Story  WorldSeath the Scaleless, traitor of dragons.Long ago the world was a gray, lifeless place covered in fog and dominated by dragons. Then, fire appeared, and creatures emerged from the dark, finding souls of Lords within the flames: Nito, first of the dead; the Witch of Izalith and her daughters of chaos, Gwyn, the Lord of Sunlight, and his knights; and the easily forgotten Furtive Pygmy. They challenged the dragons. With Nito's powers of disease, the witches' firestorms, Gwyn's powerful bolts and the aid of Seath the Scaleless, a dragon who betrayed his own kind, they succeeded, vanquishing the dragons and starting the Age of Fire.Over time, the flames started to fade and darkness began to spread. The world is plagued by hollows, the undead that have gone mad from being resurrected. So the lords have captured the undead and imprisoned them. But you are the chosen undead to leave the Asylum and make your way to Lordran and fulfill the prophecy.DLC AccessIn order to access the new content, one must have (along with purchasing the DLC or owning the PC version):1. Saved Dusk of Oolacile from the golden crystal golem behind the hydra in Darkroot Basin2. Acquired the Lordvessel from GywnevereAfter doing this, you must place down the Lordvessel (whether it be with Kaathe or Frampt) to open up the golden fog gates throughout Lordran.You now must enter The Duke's Archives and take the elevator up. There will be a crystal golem in the right side of the balcony up the stairs. Killing him will reward you with The Broken Pendant.Now backtrack all the way back to Darkroot Basin, to where you originally saved Dusk. There will be a black orb. Touch it to be transported to Oolacile Sanctuary.DLC AdditionsThe addition of the Artorias of the Abyss content includes a whole new area in the Dark Souls universe. Being transported to this area also takes you back in time to when the people of Oolacile still existed (though in a deformed manner). The new content explores the story of Knight Artorias, the legendary Abyss walker. This content includes an area that is visibly recognizable as the darkroot garden in its past form.There are 4 additional bosses from the new content, several new non-playable characters, and new weapons, armor, and spells. The new bosses are intended to challenge even the most experienced Dark Souls players. The conclusion of the new content rewrites the history of Knight Artorias, as the player kills the famous knight after being heavily weakened by the Abyss. The player character takes the place of Knight Artorias as the Abysswalker, defeating Manus, Father of the Abyss. Additionally, the character will take down one of the few remaining Dragon's in Lordran, Kalameet.GameplayDark Souls offers a large, seamless world for players to explore. Compared to Demon's Souls, the game is longer, larger, and features more complex level design, as well as more enemies, spells, and equipment to discover. The various regions of the world are interconnected by many routes, some overt and others hidden, with no fixed hub as The Nexus was in Demon's Souls. Players will often find that they can access multiple areas at once, and will have to rely on their own instincts and experience to decide where to go.SavingA character resting at a bonfire.Dark Souls includes a continuous save system, meaning the game automatically saves itself every few seconds. Players never lose progress due to having to load an earlier saved game, as when the player dies, the game continues on by automatically respawning the player at the last visited bonfire with death penalties (see below). The game only uses one save slot per character, with no option for the player to save to additional slots, which makes every action the player takes carry the weight of permanence (as there is no "earlier save" to reload).DyingDark Souls uses a kind of "two strikes and you're out" system for deaths. When a player dies, the player drops all currently held Humanity and souls, and, if in human form, changes to "hollowed" form (see multiplayer below). On the spot where the player died, a bloodstain will appear, containing all of the player's lost humanity and souls. If the player is able to return to that spot and touch their bloodstain without dying again, the player will reclaim all of their lost humanity and souls. However, if the player dies again before touching the bloodstain of their first death, that bloodstain will vanish forever along with all of the humanity and souls it contained, and a new bloodstain will be created containing only the humanity and souls held by the player at the moment of their second death. In this way, the play can have no more than one bloodstain in existence at any one time.MultiplayerBy default, Dark Souls is played online at all times. While a player is playing alone, they will encounter indirect traces of other players playing in parallel in their own games. These traces come in three forms:Messages can be placed on the ground by players to warn, cajole, or even misdirect other players who happen by and see it. These messages can only be constructed out of a fixed selection of words and phrases, which allows for players worldwide playing in any language to see localized versions of any message. Players can also rate up or down the messages of other players, granting another player humanity in the process.Bloodstains can be seen on the ground that, when interacted with, will produce a ghostly replay of the last 5 seconds of another player's life before they died in that place. By witnessing another player's demise, a player may be able to learn directly from others' mistakes.Apparitions of other players that appear for a few seconds showing a real-time glimpse of what another player is doing at that very moment.Players can also directly impact others' games by summoning other players to engage in cooperative play or by invading another's game to assassinate the host player. All direct multiplayer interaction is subject to the rule that only players who are within 10 levels +10% of the host player's soul level can join the host's game.Cooperative summoning requires both the summoner and the summonee(s) to voluntarily initiate the partnership. Players who wish to be summoned can be in either human or hollowed form and must place their summon sign (a white label with their name) on the ground where they think a potential summoner will see it and then wait. A player who wishes to summon others must first be in human form in order to see the placed summon signs of other players and must be in a level in which the main boss is still alive (since the goal of coop is to kill bosses together) and may then interact with a summon sign of their choice to attempt to summon that player. Up to two players may be summoned at one time (making for a 3-player team).Players who are summoned into a host's game are known as phantoms and special rules apply to them. Phantoms cannot use their Estus Flasks, cannot leave the level that the host is in, and cannot interact with NPCs or objects (like doors, fog walls, or levers). When the host uses an Estus Flask, all phantoms are healed by it as well as the host (making the host responsible for healing his helping phantoms). For every enemy that is killed for any reason, the host gets 100% of the souls and all phantoms also get 50% of the souls. If the host and phantoms manage to kill the level boss, the host gets the standard full rewards, the phantoms get 50% of the soul reward and gain one point of humanity before being returned to their own worlds. If a phantom dies for any reason, he returns to his own world, keeping any new souls they earned and does not suffer any death penalty whatsoever. If the host dies, all phantoms are sent back to their own worlds and the host suffers the full death penalty, dropping all humanity and souls into a new bloodstain and reverting to hollowed form, meaning the host cannot summon new phantoms without first spending humanity to reverse hollowing.Invasions are another form of joining a host's game, but without their permission and for the purpose of PvP. To invade another's game, a player must be in human form and standing in the level they wish to hunt for targets in, then use a red eye orb item. A target is any player in human form who is within the correct soul range of the invader. Soul ranges for red eye orb invasions are different from cooperative summoning in that the player being invaded is limited to 10 levels +10% of the invader's level below, but unlimited above. (For example, an invader of soul level 50 can invade anyone from 35 to 713) If these conditions are met, the invading phantom will appear in the host's game and the host will receive a message warning them of the name of the arriving invader.Kirk - Knight of Thorns. An NPC invader.As an invading phantom, special rules apply, similar to being a summoned phantom: the invading phantom may not use Estus Flasks, leave the level, or interact with NPCs. Because the conditions for a host to get invaded are the same as those for a host to be able to summon cooperative phantoms, the host may summon phantoms to help them to fight back against the invader. If the invading phantom is killed, they return to their own world with no penalties, while the host receives a large number of souls for the victory. If the host dies for any reason while the invading phantom is in their game, the host suffers the standard death penalty and the invader returns to their own world with a bonus of souls and one extra point of humanity.If the invaded player dies and has an item called an Indictment, they can choose to indict the invading player to give them a point of sin, which is recorded in a kind of online leaderboard called The Book of the Guilty. Players recorded in The Book of the Guilty can be targeted for invasions by members of the Blades of the Darkmoon covenant, who use the Blue Eye Orb item for their invasions. These invasions have the opposite level range of the Red Eye Orb invasions, in that any player with sin who is within 10 levels +10% of the invader's level above, and unlimited below, can be targeted.Further into the game, it is possible to acquire an item (Red sign soapstone) in The Painted World which allows players to place down a summon sign on the ground to engage in optional PVP combat. Unlike the white sign soapstone, this summon sign gives off a reddish hue to distinguish itself to other players. Should a player accept the duel, a hostile phantom will enter their world to engage in a battle to the death. A maximum of 3 phantoms may be summoned, all of which can attack one-another, with the victor obtaining an equal amount of humanity to the number of players defeated. They also receive an amount of souls relative to their opponent's soul level. Unlike the white summon soapstone lower levelled players are unable to see the sign, making battles exclusive to higher leveled players.Another form of optional PVP combat is available for players in the Path of the Dragon covenant. Upon joining the covenant, the player receives a Dragon Eye item. When using the item, a summon sign is placed on the ground that will appear in other player's worlds. When another player interacts with this sign, they will show up in the summoning player's world as an invader. The winner of the duel will receive one Dragon Scale and an amount of souls relative to their opponent's soul level. This Dragon Scale is not taken from the losing player's inventory, there is no penalty at all for losing a duel initiated in this manner. Dragon summon signs appear for players within the normal co-op range of 10 +10% of the summoner's soul level.Players in the Gravelord Servant have the ability to initiate invasions in a different form from the other multiplayer options. If they are human and in an area where they have not yet defeated the boss, they are able to use consumable Eye of Death items to "infect" three other player's worlds. Players eligible for this infection are any within a range of 10 +10% of the Gravelord player's level. If the infected player is on their first playthrough of the game this has no effect. If the player is on a New Game+, however, several of the NPC enemies in their game become replaced by more difficult black phantom versions. The Gravelord Servant player's summon sign appears in the infected worlds as well, and in order to remove the black phantom enemies those players must find the sign and interact with it to invade the Gravelord Servant's world. Upon the death of the Gravelord Servant, or the Gravelord Servant leaving the area or quitting the game, the infected player's worlds are returned to normal.Battle of StoicismThe Artorias of the Abyss DLC also added a battle arena to the game for more direct PVP confrontation. There are three modes of play: 1 vs. 1, 2 vs. 2, and 4 player deathmatch.Players will be grouped into 1 of 4 tiers automatically. Soul levels 1-50, 51-100, 101 - 200, and 201+ will all be grouped into matches together. StatsVitalityGoverns the player's maximum health points.Vitality:10203040506070809099Maximum Health:57279211001325150015881675175818371900AttunementGoverns item drop-rates and the number of spell slots.Attunement:10121416192328344150Spell Slots:12345678910EnduranceGoverns stamina, maximum equipment burden and resistance to bleeding.Roll and run speed will vary based on the percentage of maximum burden used by equip weight.Equip weight ≥ 100% of Equip Burden makes rolling and running impossible.Equip weight ≥ 50% of Equip Burden sets movement speed to slow and disabled rolling.Equip weight  50% of Equip Burden sets movement speed to medium and rolling speed to slow.Equip weight  25% of Equip Burden sets movement speed and rolling speed to fast.Endurance:10203040506070809099Stamina:91110133160184211237---Equip Burden:44.054.064.074.084.094.0104.0114.0124.0133.0StrengthGoverns attack power for weapons that scale with strength and decides whether or not the player can properly wield heavier weapons.DexterityGoverns attack power for weapons that scale with Dexterity and increases casting speed for most spells.Casting speed is only effected by Dexterity in the range of 35-45. Anything below 35 and there will be no change in casting speed.ResistanceGoverns physical and flame defense, and resistance to poison.Physical and flame defense are also affected by your total level and the diminishing returns stack, causing resistance's effectiveness at higher levels to become negligible.IntelligenceGoverns the power of sorcery, resistance to curses, attack power with weapons that scale with intelligence and decides whether or not the player can cast more advanced spells.Pyromancy spell power does not scale with intelligence. The Pyromancy Flame (catalyst) can be upgraded to scale with intelligence, however this only affects the Flame's melee attack.FaithGoverns the power of miracles, magical defense, attack power with weapons that scale with faith and decides whether or not the player can cast more advanced miracles.Faith is also a requirement for the Warriors of Sunlight covenant (see below)ClassesThere are ten classes for players to choose from:WarriorWarriors are weapon experts with great strength and dexterity.Starting gear: Longsword, Heater Shield, Standard Helm, Hard Leather Armor, Hard Leather Gauntlets and Hard Leather Boots.Starting stats:Level: 4Vitality: 11Attunement: 8Endurance: 12Strength: 13Dexterity: 13Resistance: 11Intelligence: 9Faith: 9KnightKnights have a high HP stat. They are heavily armoured and hard to knock downStarting gear: Broadsword, Tower Kite Shield, Knight Helm, Knight Armor, Knight Gauntlets and Knight Leggings.Starting stats:Level: 5Vitality: 14Attunement: 10Endurance: 10Strength: 11Dexterity: 11Resistance: 10Intelligence: 9Faith: 11WandererWanderers are dexterous, scimitar-wielding characters.Starting gear: Scimitar, Leather Shield, Wanderer Hood, Wanderer Coat, Wanderer Manchette and Wanderer Boots.Starting stats:Level: 3Vitality: 10Attunement: 11Endurance: 10Strength: 10Dexterity: 14Resistance: 12Intelligence: 11Faith: 8ThiefThieves come equipped with master keys and excel at critical hits.Starting gear: Bandit's Knife, Target Shield, Thief Mask, Black Leather Armor, Black Leather Gloves, Black Leather Boots and Master Key.Starting stats:Level: 5Vitality: 9Attunement: 11Endurance: 9Strength: 9Dexterity: 15Resistance: 10Intelligence: 12Faith: 11BanditBandits are very strong and wield heavy battle axes.Starting gear: Battle Axe, Spider Shield, Brigand Hood, Brigand Armor, Brigand Gauntlets and Brigand Trousers.Starting stats:Level: 4Vitality: 12Attunement: 8Endurance: 14Strength: 14Dexterity: 9Resistance: 11Intelligence: 8Faith: 10HunterHunters are skilled with bows, but weak to magic.Starting gear: Shortsword, Short Bow, 30 Standard Arrows, Large Leather Shield, Leather Armor, Leather Gloves and Leather Boots.Starting stats:Level: 4Vitality: 11Attunement: 9Endurance: 11Strength: 12Dexterity: 14Resistance: 11Intelligence: 9Faith: 9SorcererSorcerers cast a variety of soul spells learned at the Vinheim Dragon School.Starting gear: Dagger, Small Leather Shield, Sorcerer's Catalyst, Sorcerer Hat, Sorcerer Cloak, Sorcerer Gauntlets and Sorcerer Boots.Starting spell: Soul Arrow.Starting stats:Level: 3Vitality: 8Attunement: 15Endurance: 8Strength: 9Dexterity: 11Resistance: 8Intelligence: 15Faith: 8PyromancerPyromancers from the Great Swamp cast fire magic and wield small axes.Starting gear: Hand Axe, Cracked Round Shield, Pyromancy Flame, Tattered Cloth Hood, Tattered Cloth Robe, Tattered Cloth Manchette and Heavy Boots.Starting spell: Fireball.Starting stats:Level: 1Vitality: 10Attunement: 12Endurance: 11Strength: 12Dexterity: 9Resistance: 12Intelligence: 10Faith: 8ClericClerics cast healing miracles and wield maces.Starting gear: Mace, East-West Shield, Canvas Talisman, Holy Robe, Traveling Gloves and Holy Trousers.Starting spell: Heal.Starting stats:Level: 2Vitality: 11Attunement: 11Endurance: 9Strength: 12Dexterity: 8Resistance: 11Intelligence: 8Faith: 14DeprivedThe deprived come equipped with nothing but clubs and old wooden shields. Starts with well-balanced stats.Starting gear: Club and Plank Shield.Starting stats:Level: 6Vitality: 11Attunement: 11Endurance: 11Strength: 11Dexterity: 11Resistance: 11Intelligence: 11Faith: 11GiftsWhen creating a character, the player gets to choose one of the following items as a starting gift:Divine Blessing - A consumable item that restores HP and removes detrimental status effects.Black Firebomb - A type of firebomb that's more powerful than the regular. The player gets ten of these.Binoculars - An item that lets the player get a closer look at distant objects. Can be used as many times as the player wants.Pendant - An item with no known use.Twin Humanities - A consumable item that grants 2 humanity.Master Key - A key that can open simple locks. Can be used as many times as the player wants, but only works on certain locks.Tiny Being's Ring - An equippable item that increases the player's maximum health by 30. (Does not recharge health, as the game initially claims.)Old Witch's Ring - Allows dialog between the player and a witch later in the game.All of these items can be obtained later in the game either by purchasing or finding them scattered around. Some are more easily obtained than others, however.HumanityHumanity:0123456789101112131415Item Discovery:100150158165173180186192198204210210210210210210Curse Resistance:3040506070808896104112120122123125126128Humanity:161718192021222324252627282930 (Max)Item Discovery:210210210210210210210210210210210210210210210Curse Resistance:129131132134135137138140141143144146147149150Humanity is a unique character stat that can change frequently, unlike other stats. It cannot be leveled up like other stats and when a player dies, they drop all of their humanity into their blood stain along with their souls.Obtaining humanity:Humanity can be earned by killing enemies who drop it as an automatically gained item, or as a consumable item. Consumable humanity items are not lost when killed.As of patch 1.05 all bosses award one humanity when killed.Humanity can also be gained by killing a set number of enemies in an area where the boss is still alive. Dying/Resting at a bonfire does not reset the counter.Being summoned into another player's game and helping them kill a major boss will reward the player with one point of humanity.Killing invading phantoms, or invading and killing players rewards one humanity to the victors.Humanity (in consumable item form) can also be bought from Undead Merchant (Female) and Patches the Hyena, although they only have a limited amount.Having a hint sign up rated by another player grants one Humanity.Using humanity:At a bonfire, players can spend one point of humanity to change from hollow form into human form, known as "reverse-hollowing".Humanity can be used to kindle bonfires when the player is human, increasing the maximum number of Estus Flasks that that bonfire can replenish. It costs one point of humanity per kindling.Humanity that is held passively increases item drop rate and resistance to curses. The more humanity held, the greater the increases, as shown in the table above.Chaos-enchanted weapon and chaos spell damage scales with humanity. Maximum damage at 10 humanity.Using a consumable humanity item will restore the player's health completely (in addition to obviously granting one point of humanity).Losing humanity:Although all held humanity is lost upon death, it is stored in a bloodstain along with all of the players souls. If the player can get back to and touch their bloodstain without dying again, the player reclaims all lost humanity and souls.Dying in human form transforms the player back to hollowed form upon respawning at the last visited bonfire. To re-assume human form, the player must spend one point of humanity at a bonfire to "reverse-hollowing".Some credit for this information goes to Darksoulswiki.wikispaces.comBonfiresWhile resting at a bonfire, a player may perform any of the following actions, provided its conditions are met:Rest - Resting at a bonfire refills Estus Flasks (see "Kindle" below) and spells, but respawns all enemies (except bosses and minibosses). Bonfires cannot be accessed while a player's world is invaded or while enemies are in very close proximity.Level up - This is the only way that players can increase their character's soul level. To gain a level, the player must spend souls currently held. Each additional level costs more souls to gain than the last.Reinforce Weapon - After obtaining a Weapon Smithbox, players can spend crafting materials and souls to upgrade their weapons in various ways.Reinforce Armor - An Armor Smithbox is required to upgrade armor similarly to weapons.Repair - With a Repairbox, players can spend souls to repair the durability of their weapons and armor.Attune Magic - Once spells have been learned, players can choose which of their known spells they would like to have equipped for usage.Bottomless Box- After finding it, players can store items in it. There is no limit either to the number of items players can hold in their inventories or the number of items that the Bottomless Box can hold, so using the Box is a strictly organizational choice.Kindle - Kindling bonfires increases the maximum number of Estus Flasks that the bonfire will replenish. Each bonfire must be kindled separately. A bonfire can be kindled only one time when the player begins the game, replenishing 10 Estus Flasks. Bonfires can be kindled up to 3 times once players receive the Rite of Kindling, replenishing a maximum of 20 Estus Flasks. Kindling requires that the player be in human form and expend one point of held humanity per kindling.Reverse Hollowing - Reverts player from hollowed form back to human form at the cost of one point of humanity.Warp - Once the in-game item, the Lordvessel, is acquired, the player can warp from any bonfire to any of several specific bonfires in the world. Each destination bonfire must have already been discovered by the player in order to be able to warp to it.Certain bonfires are tied to Firekeepers who will provide the service of reinforcing Estus Flasks in exchange for a Firekeeper Soul. If a Firekeeper is killed, its corresponding bonfire is extinguished permanently.MagicThere are three types of magic: sorcery, which is powered by the caster's Intelligence stat; miracles, which which are powered by the caster's Faith stat; and pyromancy, which is powered only by the strength of the casting implement. Each class of spells has a corresponding casting implement that is required to cast any of those spells: sorcery spells require an equipped catalyst, miracles require require a talisman, and pyromancy requires a pyromancer's flame. Every spell and miracle has a certain number of uses before it can no longer be used without replenishing it at a bonfire. Each sorcery and miracle also has a minimum stat requirement that must be met in order for a character to learn that spell. Spells can be acquired in the same ways that items can: finding them, being given them, buying them, or starting out with them.CovenantsThere are nine covenants the player can join, each associated with different characters and factions in the game. Honouring the rules of a covenant will lead to the acquisition of various rewards, while breaking its rules will lead to hostility from that covenant's members as well as other penalties.Way of the WhiteOne can enter this covenant by speaking to Petrus of Thorolund, or Reah when she is in the Undead Parish church. Players who choose Way of the White come closer to each other on the network, simultaneously increasing the likelihood of a miracle resonance and decreasing the likelihood of hostile world invasions.Blade of the DarkmoonA pact with Gwyndolin, Gwyn's youngest child. Players who enter this covenant are tasked with hunting down players who have sinned by breaking covenants or invading and killing other players, or those who have attacked Gwynevere. To join this covenant, players must take the central elevator in Anor Londo all the way to the bottom and walk down the central stairs whilst equipping the Darkmoon Seance Ring. Then they are given an opportunity to kneel and join the covenant.Princess' GuardA pact with Gwynevere, daughter of Gwyn, who wishes for players to help thwart her father's plans for the future by destroying him and obtaining his soul. Players who enter this covenant gain the ability to cast sunlight miracles, and become more likely to be matched with members of Princess' Guard, Way of the White and Warrior of Sunlight in online play.Warrior of SunlightA pact with the sun. This covenant originally required 50 faith in order to join, however as of patch 1.04 the requirement has been lowered to 25 to increase accessibility. Assisting other players defeat bosses as a phantom reduces the requirement by 5. Players who enter this covenant appear as gold phantoms in co-op, and become more likely to be matched with members of Princess' Guard, Way of the White and Warrior of Sunlight in online play. When a gold phantom helps someone defeat a boss, everyone in the party gets a Sunlight Medal.Forest HunterA pact with Alvina, a giant cat. Players who enter this covenant are given a white pearl ring. Alvina uses this to send them into the worlds of players entering her forest, who they must then kill. Up to three forest covenant members may invade a player at one time. The champion is awarded souls and a random shard while helpers are awarded a shard. One of the rewards for honouring this pact is a ring that renders the wearer transparent, making him harder to detect. One breaks the pact by killing any creature of the forest. At 5 kills, Alvina will ask the player to kill the Great Grey Wolf Sif.All previously-hostile enemies at the entrance of the Dark Forest become friendly. Shiva of the East opens a store under the waterwheel in Blighttown, providing unique dexterity-heavy weapons.It is recommended to engage in pacifism within the Dark Forest once the player joins this covenant as there is a strong chance of unknowingly breaking the pact. Contrary to popular belief, the player may attack Sif at anytime and not break the covenant.Chaos ServantA pact with one of Quelaag's sisters, who can be found behind an illusory wall near the elevator linking Quelaag's Domain to the Demon Ruins. One honours this covenant by giving the Daughter of Chaos, who has suffered ever since she consumed the great Blight Pus, humanity to ease her pain. The rewards one can gain range from a variety of powerful pyromancy spells to a shortcut bypassing the Lost Izalith. This shortcut is also necessary in order to save the NPC Solaire of Astora and acquire his assistance in the final boss fight.Pact-breakers are punished with a large egg that attaches to their heads, steals a portion of all the souls they get, leaves them very vulnerable to fire and does not allow them to equip armor.Gravelord ServantA pact with Nito, god of the dead, that can only be entered when in an undead state. Grants the Gravelord spell, as well as a variety of poisonous, disease-spreading equipment and magic. Upon using Eyes of Death players can infect other players worlds causing enemies to be harder and half of their souls going to the Gravelord. Find this covenant by going into an empty coffin in the room with the Titanite Demon in the Catacombs.Path of the DragonA pact with The Everlasting Dragon. One honors this pact by collecting dragon scales, which can be acquired either by defeating certain enemies, or by invading the worlds of players with such scales, killing them and taking theirs. Joining the covenant rewards the player with the Dragon Head Stone, giving a the player a dragon's head that breathes fire, as well as an item that will search for players with scales in their inventory to invade. Upon handing in 30 scales, the player can turn their entire body into a dragonoid form.Dark WraithA pact with Darkstalker Kaathe, a Primordial Serpant that wishes to consume the world. Players who enter this covenant are given the Dark Hand, a piece of equipment allowing them to steal other players' humanity. The rewards for honouring this pact include the Red Eye Orb, the Dark Sword and the Dark Armor. To join this covenant, do not talk to Kingseeker Frampt after acquiring the Lordvessel. Instead, go straight to the New Londo Ruins and defeat the Four Kings. This requires the Ring of Artorias, from the Great Greywolf Sif. Upon reloading the area, Kaathe will be waiting there for the player.Kingseeker Frampt Exchange RateKingseeker Frampt appears at the Firelink Shrine after both bells of Awakening have been rung. He is a large serpent like creature that can be fed items and crafting materials in exchange for souls and other items.Exchange Rate for Items1 Large Titanite Shard = 5 Titanite Shards1 Green Titanite Shard = 5 Titanite ShardsShields and Swords = 50 souls a pieceArmor = 100 souls a pieceSnuggly the CrowSnuggly the Crow's nest can be found at the cliffs of Undead Asylum. He asks the player to give him an item (by dropping it into his nest) and when given the right one (he'll tell you if it isn't), he'll exchange it into some other, most of the time more valuable, item. The exchange only happens when quitting out of the game and then loading up your save again. Additionally, you can only trade one item per playthrough. If you drop two of the same item, you will not get two of the item you were trading for.BeforeAfterBlood Red Moss ClumpTwinkling TitaniteBlooming Purple Moss ClumpTwinkling Titanite (2)Cracked Red Eye OrbPurging Stone (2)Dried FingerBlue Titanite ChunkDung PieDemon TitaniteEgg VermifugeDragon ScaleHumanityRing of SacrificePendantSouvenir of ReprisalPrism StoneDemon TitanitePyromancy FlameRed Titanite ChunkPyromancy Flame (+1 or higher)Red Titanite SlabPurple Moss ClumpTwinkling TitaniteRubbishTitanite ChunkRing of the Sun PrincessDivine Blessing (2)SackDemon's Great HammerSkull LanternRing of FogSunlight MaggotOld Witch's RingSunlight MedalWhite Titanite ChunkTwin HumanitiesRare Ring of SacrificeXanthous CrownRing of Favor and ProtectionUpgrading WeaponsCredit for image goes to Otaku_Oyabun  Mud_Chan from gamefaqs.WeaponsBase Damage: Physical / Magic / Flame / Lightning / CriticalParamBonus  ReqParam: Strength / Dexterity / Intelligence / FaithDaggersNameBase DamageParamBonusReqParamDurabilityWeightMiscDagger56/0/0/0/131E/B/-/-5/8/0/02000.5Sold by Undead Burg merchant (300 souls). Starting weapon for Sorcerer class.Parrying Dagger54/0/0/0/131E/B/-/-5/14/0/02000.5Found in Valley of Drakes and New Londo. Strong attack is a parry.Bandit's Knife56/0/0/0/147E/B/-/-6/12/0/02001.0Rare drop from Undead Assassin. Starting weapon for Thief class.Ghost Blade100/0/0/0/127E/E/-/-5/8/0/01000.5Drops from female ghosts in New Londo.Priscilla's Dagger80/0/0/0/100-/A/-/-6/20/0/01001.0Drops from Priscilla's tail in Painted World.Dark Silver Tracer75/0/0/0/160E/S/-/-6/6/0/01200.5DLC only. Trade with Lord's Blade Ciaran, or kill her.Straight SwordsNameBase DamageParamBonusReqParamDurabilityWeightMiscStraight Sword Hilt20/0/0/0/100E/E/-/-6/6/0/02001.0All classes start with this weapon.Broken Straight Sword40/0/0/0/100D/D/-/-8/8/0/02002.0Drops from Zombie/Infested Ghoul with swords.Broadsword82/0/0/0/100C/C/-/-10/10/0/02003.0Sold by Andre of Astora (1000 souls). Starting weapon for Knight class.Shortsword78/0/0/0/100C/C/-/-8/10/0/02002.0Sold by Undead Burg merchant (600 souls). Starting weapon for Hunter class.Longsword80/0/0/0/100C/C/-/-10/10/0/02003.0Sold by Andrei the Blacksmith (1000 souls). Starting weapon for Warrior class.Balder Side Sword80/0/0/0/100E/B/-/-10/14/0/01203.0Drops from Red-Cloaked Knights.Barbed Straight Sword80/0/0/0/100D/D/-/-10/10/0/01603.0Drops from Knight of Thorns and Kirk.Sunlight Straight Sword82/0/0/0/100C/C/-/-12/12/0/02404.0Drops from Solaire of Astoria.Crystal Straight Sword145/0/0/0/100C/C/-/-16/10/0/0606.0Sold by Domhnall of Zena in the Depths. Drops from crystal enemies in Duke's Archives. Can not be repairedAstora's Straight Sword80/80/0/0/100C/C/-/C10/10/0/141403.0Can be found in front of the dragon in Valley of the Drakes.Silver Knight Straight Sword165/0/0/0/100E/C/-/-16/22/0/03006.0Drops from Silver Knight in Anor Londo.Drake Sword200/0/0/0/100-/-/-/-16/10/0/03606.0Drops from Hellkite Dragon's Tail (shoot with arrows).GreatswordsNameBase DamageParamBonusReqParamDurabilityWeightMiscClaymore103/0/0/0/100C/C/-/-16/10/0/02006.0On the bridge in Undeadburg in front of Hellkite DragonMan-serpent Greatsword110/0/0/0/100B/-/-/-24/0/0/030010.0Drops from snakemen in Sen's FortressFlamberge100/0/0/0/100D/C/-/-16/14/0/01606.0Sold by Shiva of the East (1000 souls). Drops from Serpent Mage.Black Knight Sword205/0/0/0/100C/E/-/-20/18/0/03008.0Drops from Black Knights that wield themStone Greatsword148/100/0/0/100C/C/E/-40/10/0/080018.0Two-handed strong attack slows enemies around you but consumes weapon durability(True) Greatsword of Artorias120/85/0/0/100C/C/B/B24/18/20/2040010.0Ascended using Sif's Soul with Broken Straight Sword+10 or Straight Sword Hilt+10(Cursed) Greatsword of Artorias158/0/0/0/100C/C/C/C24/18/18/1840010.0Ascended using Sif's Soul with any greatsword+10Abyss Greatsword160/0/0/0/100C/C/-/-22/18/0/03009.0DLC only. Ascended using Artorias's Souls with any greatsword +10Obsidian Greatsword320/0/0/0/100-/-/-/-20/16/0/03508.0DLC only. Tail cut off KalameetUltra GreatswordsNameBase DamageParamBonusReqParamDurabilityWeightMiscGreatsword130/0/0/0/100C/D/-/-28/10/0/020012.0Sold by Crestfallen merchant (8000 souls). Found in Anor Londo. Drops from Heavy Knight (Mace/Sword).Zweihander130/0/0/0/100C/D/-/-24/10/0/020010.0Found in Graveyard next to Large Skeleton.Black Knight Greatsword205/0/0/0/100B/D/-/-32/18/0/030014.0Drops from Black Knights that wield themDragon Greatsword360/0/0/0/100-/-/-/-50/10/0/040024.0Cut off Ancient Stone Dragon's Tail in Ash Lake (does not cause hostility)Curved SwordsNameBase DamageParamBonusReqParamDurabilityWeightMiscScimitar80/0/0/0/100E/B/-/-7/13/0/01501.5Starting weapon for Wanderer class. Can be bought from the Undead Burg merchant.Falchion82/0/0/0/100E/B/-/-9/13/0/01602.5Found in Blighttown.Shotel82/0/0/0/100E/C/-/-9/14/0/01202.5Can be found in Sen's Fortress or bought from Shiva of the East. Heavy attack bypasses defense.Painting Guardian Sword76/0/0/0/100E/A/-/-7/20/0/01001.5Drops from the painting guardians in Anor Londo.Jagged Ghost Blade140/0/0/0/100E/-/-/-7/0/0/01001.5Drops from ghosts in New Londo.Quelaag's Furysword60/0/180/0/100E/B/-/-11/13/0/06003.5Giant Blacksmith requires a +10 curved sword to forge with Quelaag's Soul. Damage scales with humanity up to 10.Gold Tracer130/0/0/0/100E/A/-/-9/25/0/02402.0DLC only. DLC only. Trade with Lord's Blade Ciaran, or kill her.Curved GreatswordsNameBase DamageParamBonusReqParamDurabilityWeightMIscMurakumo143/0/0/0/100E/B/-/-28/13/0/018012.0Drops from Giant Sword Skeletons, and Shiva of the East.Server107/0/0/0/100E/C/-/-24/13/0/01501.5Found in the Blight Town swamp, guarded by a group of giant leeches. Restores HP when used.Gravelord Sword255/0/0/0/100E/E/-/-24/13/0/060010.0Join Gravelord Servant Covenant. 5 toxin damage per/s over 600 seconds.KatanasNameBase DamageParamBonusReqParamDurabilityWeightMiscUchigatana90/0/0/0/100-/B/-/-14/14/0/0805.0Killing Undead Burg Merchant. Purchase from Shiva of the East (5000 souls). 300 bleeding damage.Iaito88/0/0/0/100-/B/-/-14/20/0/0805.0Found in Blighttown, must jump to reach. 300 bleeding damage.Washing Pole90/0/0/0/100D/D/-/-20/16/0/0608.0Purchase from Shiva of the East (20,000 souls).Chaos Blade133/0/0/0/100-/B/-/-16/14/0/01206.0Upgrade +10 katana with Quelaag's Soul at the Giant Blacksmith. Hurts user when attacking.Thrusting SwordsNameBase DamageParamBonusReqParamDurabilityWeightMiscEstoc75/0/0/0/100D/C/-/-10/12/0/01503.0Found on corpse in lower section of Firelink Shrine along the path to New Londo.Mail Breaker57/0/0/00120D/C/-/-5/12/0/02000.5Rapier73/0/0/0/110D/C/-/-7/12/0/01501.5Drops from undead knights using rapiers.Richard's Rapier70/0/0/0/100E/B/-/-8/20/0/01002.0Drops from Richard in a tower in Sen's Fortress.Velka's Rapier60/97/0/0/100E/C/B/-8/16/16/01302.0Found in the Painted World of Ariamis.AxesNameBase DamageParamBonusReqRaramDurabilityWeightMiscBattle Axe80/0/0/0/100C/D/-/-12/8/0/02504.0Starting weapon for Bandit class.Butcher Knife90/0/0/0/100B/-/-/-24/0/0/025010.0Drops from Black Phantom Maneater Mildred in Blighttown (must be in human form).Crescent Axe115/115/0/0/100D/D/-/B18/12/0/161807.0Sold by and drops from Patches in Firelink Shrine.Gargoyle Tail Axe93/0/0/0/100D/C/-/-14/14/0/01505.0Drops when Gargoyle's tail is cut off (Bell Gargoyle and Anor Londo).Golem Axe155/0/0/0/100C/E/-/-36/8/0/060016.0Ascended from Axe type weapon with Soul of Iron Golem. Provides 100% bonus to Bleed and Poison resist.Hand Axe80/0/0/0/100C/D/-/-8/8/0/02502.0Starting weapon for Pyromancer class. Sold by Undead Burg merchant (450 souls).GreataxesNameBase DamageParamBonusReqBonusDurabilityWeightMiscBlack Knight Greataxe213/0/0/0/100B/E/-/-36/18/0/030016.0Drops from Black Knight (Axe).Demon's Greataxe114/0/0/0/100A/-/-/-46/0/0/060022.0Drops from Taurus Demon.Dragon King Greataxe360/0/0/0/100-/-/-/-50/8/0/040024.0Drops when Gaping Dragon's tail is cut off in The Depths.Greataxe140/0/0/0/100C/E/-/-32/8/0/023014.0Found in The Depths.Stone Greataxe190/0/0/0/100B/E/-/-48/10/0/070024.0DLC only. Dropped from the Stone Guardians in the Royal WoodsHammersNameBase DamageParamBonusReqParamDurabilityWeightMiscBlacksmith Giant Hammer120/0/0/0/100D/-/-/-16/0/0/02506.0Drops from Giant Blacksmith in Anor Londo.Blacksmith Hammer87/0/0/0/100C/-/-/-14/0/0/02505.0Drops from Andre of Astora.Hammer of Vamos105/0/64/0/100C/-/-/-14/0/0/025012.0Drops from Blacksmith Vamos in The Catacombs.Mace91/0/0/0/100B/-/-/-12/0/0/02504.0Starting weapon for Cleric class.Morning Star83/0/0/0/100C/-/-/-11/0/0/01804.0Found in Firelink Shrine, must drop down elevator shaft.Blunt WeaponsNameBase DamageParamBonusReqParamDurabilityWeightMiscClub87/0/0/0/100A/-/-/-10/0/0/02503.0Starting weapon for Deprived class. Sold by Undead Burg merchant (150 souls).Pickaxe89/0/0/0/100B/-/-/-14/0/0/02505.0Drops from Infested Barbarian (Boulder) in Blighttown.Reinforced Club97/0/0/0/100C/-/-/-12/0/0/01004.0Sold by Undead Burg merchant.Skull Lantern30/0/75/0/100E/-/-/-5/0/0/0600.5Found in Tomb of Giants.Warpick91/0/0/0/100C/D/-/-11/10/0/02203.5Sold by Andre of Astora (800 souls).Great HammersNameBase DamageParamBonusReqParamDurabilityWeightMiscDragon Tooth290/0/0/0/100D/-/-/-40/0/0/099918.0Found in Anor Londo behind hidden door in a fireplace.Demon's Great Hammer138/0/0/0/100B/-/-/-46/0/0/060022.0Drops from Asylum Demon (must defeat demon during first encounter). Obtained by trading Sack (helmet) to Snuggly.Grant125/130/0/0/100B/-/-/A50/0/0/060024.0Drops from Paladin Leeroy in Tomb of Giants (must be in human form).Great Club135/0/0/0/100B/-/-/-28/0/0/025012.0Found in Blighttown.Large Club120/0/0/0/100A/-/-/-26/0/0/025011.0Drops from Infested Barbarian (club) in Blighttown.Smough's Hammer275/0/0/0/100D/-/-/-58/0/0/060028.0Ascended from +10 blunt weapon with Soul of Smough.Fist WeaponsNameBase DamageParamBonusReqParamDurabilityWeightMiscCaestus60/0/0/0/100C/C/-/-5/8/0/03000.5Sold by Andre of Astora.Claws65/0/0/0/100E/B/-/-6/14/0/01501.0Sold by Shiva of the East.Dark Hand200/0/0/0/100-/-/-/-?9990.5Given when joining Darkwraith covenant.Dragon Bone Fist90/0/0/0/100A/-/-/-20/0/0/01508.0Ascended from +10 fist weapon with Core of Iron Golem soul.SpearsNameBase DamageParamBonusReqParamDurabilityWeightMiscSpear80/0/0/0D/C/-/-11/10/0/01803.5Sold by merchant at Undead BurgWinged Spear86/0/0/0E/C/-/-13/15/0/01404.5Found at Firelink ShrinePike86/0/0/0D/C/-/-24/10/0/018010.0Sold by Andre of AstoraHas a unique movesetSilver Knight Spear155/0/0/0E/C/-/-16/22/0/03006.0Dropped by Anor Londo Silver KnightsHas a unique movesetDemon's Spear100/0/0/120C/C/-/-12/10/0/04004.0Sold by Shiva of the EastDropped by Anor Londo Bat Wing DemonsHas a unique movesetDeals physical and lightning damageChanneler's Trident70/105/0/0E/C/B/-16/16/24/02406.0Very rare drop from ChannelersDeals physical and magical damageHeavy attack is replaced with a dance that powers up all nearby alliesMoonlight Butterfly Horn0/110/0/0-/-/B/-12/0/14/01604.0Ascended from +10 spear with the Soul of the Moonlight ButterflyOnly deals magical damageDragonslayer Spear90/0/0/60C/B/-/B24/24/0/030010.0Ascended from +10 spear with the Soul of OrnsteinHas a unique movesetCan fire a lightning projectileDeals physical and lightning damageFour-pronged Plow75/0/0/0/100D/C/-/-15/12/0/03005.5DLC only. Dropped by Treant Gardeners in the Royal Wood.Halberds/ScythesNameBase DamageParamBonusReqParamDurabilityWeightMiscHalberd100/0/0/0D/E/-/-16/12/0/02006.0Found in the Undead ParishGargoyle's Halberd115/0/0/0D/D/-/-16/12/0/02006.0Gargoyle dropLucerne110/0/0/0D/D/-/-15/12/0/02005.5Found in the CatacombsDeals blunt damageGiant's Halberd110/0/0/135D/D/-/-36/12/0/030016.0Sold by Anor Londo Giant BlacksmithDropped by Anor Londo GiantsDeals lightning and physical damageBlack Knight Halberd230/0/0/0D/E/-/-32/18/0/030014.0Black Knight dropHas a unique movesetScythe100/0/0/0E/B/-/-14/14/0/01305.0Found in Sen's FortressGreat Scythe100/0/0/0E/B/-/-14/14/0/01305.0Found in the CatacombsHas 300 Bleed buildup per hitTitanite Catchpole120/145/0/0D/D/D/-16/14/0/06006.0Rare drop from Titanite DemonsHas a unique movesetDeals physical and magical damageLifehunt Scythe165/0/0/0E/B/-/-16/14/0/01006.0Ascended from +10 scythe or whip from the Soul of PriscillaHas 500 bleed buildup per hit, but gives a smaller amount of buildup to the playerWhipsNameBase DamageParamBonusReqParamDurabilityWeightMIscWhip80/0/0/0/100-/B/-/-7/14/0/02001.5Found in Blighttown/Quelaag's DomainNotched Whip76/0/0/0/100-/B/-/-8/16/0/02002.0Drop: Xanthous King, JeremiahGuardian Tail84/0/0/0/100-/C/-/-15/10/0/02505.0DLC only. Tail drop from Sanctuary Guardian in Sanctuary GardenBowsNameBase DamageParamBonusReqParamDurabilityWeightMiscShort Bow31/0/0/0D/A/-/-7/12/0/01000.5Can be purchased from the merchant in Undead Burg.Long Bow36/0/0/0D/A/-/-9/14/0/01001.0Found in Darkroot Basin.Composite Bow55/0/0/0C/C/-/-11/12/0/01001.0Found in the New Londo Ruins.Black Bow of Pharis34/0/0/0E/S/-/-9/18/0/01001.0Drop from Pharis in Darkroot Garden. This bow has the longest range.Dragonslayer Greatbow85/0/0/0C/C/-/-20/20/0/010010.0Found in the large room before the boss in Anor Londo. This bow only fires Dragonslayer arrows, which knock over the target upon impact.Darkmoon Bow80/80/0/0E/D/-/D9/18/0/04001.0Ascend any bow with the 'Soul of Gwyndolin'.Gough's Greatbow85/0/0/0B/C/-/-27/20/0/010013.0DLC only. Talk to Gough after defeating Kalameet.CrossbowsNameBase DamageParamBonusReqBonusDurabilityWeightMiscLight Crossbow50/0/0/0-/-/-/-10/8/0/01503Found in Undead Burg, among other places.Heavy Crossbow55/0/0/0-/-/-/-14/8/0/01505.0Found in the Depths.Sniper Crossbow52/0/0/0-/-/-/-20/16/0/01508.0Found in Sen's Fortress. Increases firing range.Avelyn38/0/0/0-/-/-/-16/14/0/01506.0Found in the Duke's Archives, on top of a bookcase. Must jump off of a spinning stairway in order to reach it. This weapon fires 3 bolts at a time.CatalystsNameBase DamageParamBonusReqBonusDurabilityWeightMiscBeatrice's Catalyst40/0/0/0/100E/-/A/-6/0/10/0902.0Found in Valley of the Drakes/New Londo Ruins.Demon's Catalyst100/0/170/0/100D/D/B/-12/10/10/03004.0Drops from Demon Firesage in Demon Ruins.Izalith Catalyst40/0/0/0/100E/-/A/-6/0/14/03002.0Drops from Daughter of Chaos in Lost Izalith.Logan's Catalyst46/0/0/0/100E/-/S/-6/0/24/0902.0Found in The Duke's Archives. Must defeat Seath the Scaleless and buy all of Big Hat Logan's spells. Logan than will leave a chest behind with his armor and catalyst.Oolacile Ivory Catalyst24/0/0/0/100E/-/C-3/0/12/0300.5Sold by Dusk of Oolacile in Darkroot Basin.Pyromancy Flame0/0/40/0/100-/-/D/-4/0/0/0300.0Starting equipment for Pyromancer class. Given by Laurentius in Firelink Shrine after rescuing him in The Depths.Sorcerer's Catalyst40/0/0/0/100E/-/A/-6/0/10/0902.0Starting equipment for Sorcerer class. Sold by Griggs in Firelink Shrine after rescuing him from lower Undead Burg. Sold by Blacksmith Rickert in New Londo ruins.Tin Banishment Catalyst145/0/0/0/100E/D/A/-10/10/12/01603.0Found in Blighttown.Tin Crystallization Catalyst240/0/0/0/100E/-/S/-7/0/32/0902.5Drops from BIg Hat Logan (hollow form).Tin Darkmoon Catalyst44/0/0/0/100E/-/-/A4/0/0/16601.0Ascended with Gwyndolin's Soul.Oolacile Catalyst40/0/0/0/100E/-/C/-6/0/10/0552.0DLC only. Drop from Oolacile SorcerersManus Catalyst190/0/0/0/100B/-/S/-14/0/13/0605.0DLC only. Ascend catalyst using Soul of ManusTalismansNameBase DamageParamBonusReqBonusDurabilityWeightMiscCanvas Talisman14/0/0/0/100-/-/-/A4/0/0/14500.3Starting equipment for Cleric Class. Sold by Patches the Hyena (1000 souls).Darkmoon Talisman14/0/0/0/100-/-/-/A4/0/0/24500.3Darkmoon Covenant.Grandfather's Talisman14/0/0/0/100-/-/-/A4/0/0/14500.3?Ivory Taliman14/0/0/0/100-/-/-/A4/0/0/16500.3Sold by Patches the Hyena (5000 souls). Drops from Rhea of Thorolund.Sunlight Talisman14/0/0/0/100-/-/-/A4/0/0/14500.3Drops from Solaire of Astora.Talisman14/0/0/0/100-/-/-/B4/0/0/10500.3Found in chest near Firelink Shrine.Torolund Talisman14/0/0/0/100-/-/-/D4/0/0/10500.3Sold by Petrus of Thorolund.Velka's Talisman14/0/0/0/100-/-/A/-4/0/16/0500.3Sold by Oswald Of Carim (5000 souls).Collector's EditionAll pre-orders of Dark Souls were automatically upgraded to the Collector's Edition for free. Contents of the Collector's Edition include:Special Designed Metal Tin Case  Protective SleeveDark Souls GameMini-Strategy Guide*Custom Art BookOriginal Game Soundtrack*Behind-The-Scenes Videos**The Mini-Strategy Guide, Original Game Soundtrack  Behind-The-Scenes Videos are provided for digital download via a uniquely redeemable online code printed on a specially marked card inside each Collector Edition box.SoundtrackUS Album Cover ArtThe original soundtrack was composed by Motoi Sakuraba. It was included in the Collector's Edition. Differing from the European and Japanese versions, the US soundtrack version was released as a digital download as well as having a different tracklist order.TrackTitleLength01Prologue3:4402Firelink Shrine2:5503Taurus Demon2:3704Bell Gargoyle3:2405Gaping Dragon2:5606Pinwheel2:1407Chaos Witch Quelaag2:3608Daughters of Chaos2:5309Iron Golem2:4810Crossbreed Priscilla3:0311Great Grey Wolf Sif3:2012The Ancient Dragon3:1613Ceaseless Discharge3:0114Ornstein  Smough2:4815Gwynevere, Princess of Sunlight2:4516Dark Sun Gwyndolin2:5217Four Kings2:4218Centipede Demon2:5819Bed of Chaos3:3820Gravelord Nito3:0721Seath the Scaleless2:5722Gwyn, Lord of Cinder3:3523Nameless Song6:68 PC System RequirementsOS: Windows XP , Windows Vista, Windows 7, or newerProcessor: 2.6 GHz Dual-CoreMemory: 1 GB (XP), 2GB (Vista/7)Hard Disk Space: 4 GBVideo Card: 512 MB RAM, ATI Radeon 4850 or higher, NVIDIA GeForce 8800 GT or higherDirectX®: 9.0cSound: Direct Sound CompatibleAdditional: Multiplayer requires microphone headset support, Online play requires software installation of and log-in to Games For Windows - LIVE</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13214">Monster Hunter</game><game id="24050">Monster Hunter Tri</game><game id="25935">Monster Hunter Freedom Unite</game><game id="20223">Monster Hunter Freedom 2</game><game id="13822">Monster Hunter Freedom</game><game id="23683">Monster Hunter Frontier</game><game id="34776">Dragon's Dogma</game><game id="619">King's Field</game><game id="2620">King's Field</game><game id="28444">King's Field II</game><game id="18509">King's Field: The Ancient City</game><game id="40333">Goblet Grotto</game><game id="35619">ZombiU</game><game id="41344">Dragon's Dogma: Dark Arisen</game><game id="10896">Vagrant Story</game><game id="41696">Deep Down</game><game id="12877">Pitfall II: Lost Caverns</game><game id="24057">Demon's Souls</game><game id="27218">Two Worlds II</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/82063/2555200-dsclean.jpg</image></root>