<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32844</id><name>Antichamber</name><description>OverviewAntichamber is a first-person puzzle game with minor platforming elements made by Alexander Bruce. The game world consists of numerous rooms featuring M.C. Esher-inspired geometry that emphasizes use of perspective and non-linear map design (the game may also be considered to exhibit non-Euclidean geometry) . Rooms in Antichamber are primarily white, but with bold splashes of color to indicate important areas or give clues as to what tool is useful for a given area. There are also a number of cartoon slides on walls that, when interacted with, provide the player with encouragement and hints at how to progress.The game's puzzles make use of hidden passageways/walkways, basic jumping sections, and object manipulation. The bulk of the puzzling is done with small colored cubes and one of four cube "guns" that the player collects during play. Each gun replaces the previous one, and adds to the player's ability to manipulate the small blocks in the environment. The player must also navigate the maze-like map, which includes surprise warp points and space-bending connections between rooms. Development HistoryAntichamber started out life as a mod called "Hazard: The Journey of Life", made with the Unreal Engine by Bruce that debuted at the Tokyo Game Show in 2009. After the release of the Unreal Development Kit, work on a stand-alone version began later that year. As the game moved through development, it was recognized at indie game events such as the Independent Games Festival and IndieCade. It was also chosen as one of the PAX 10 for 2011. In April of 2012, Antichamber became the seventh game to receive financial support from the Indie Fund to help complete development. System RequirementsOS:Windows XP SP2, Vista, or Windows 7Processor:2.0+ GHz or better (dual core recommended)Memory:2 GB RAMGraphics:NVIDIA 8000 series or higher (Shader Model 3 Compatible)DirectX®:9.0cHard Drive:1 GB HD spaceExternal LinksOfficial siteSteam store page</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21170">Portal</game><game id="36268">Q.U.B.E.</game><game id="40886">Perspective</game><game id="30785">The Ball</game><game id="24768">Fez</game><game id="41216">Magrunner: Dark Pulse</game><game id="43514">Dream</game><game id="43344">The Stanley Parable</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2419538-antichamber_final.jpg</image></root>