<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32898</id><name>Shoot Many Robots</name><description>OverviewShoot Many Robots is a 4 player co-op, side scrolling, shoot-em-up game similar to Contra or Metal Slug. The main character, P. Walter Tugnut, is a gun-loving RV-driving redneck that loves to shoot robots. That's virtually it for story in the game; there are a bunch of murderous robots that have taken over the world, and its your job to get rid of them by fighting your way towards the robots factories. Players will traverse levels, collect loot, level up, and shoot a whole bunch of robots.The game is made up of two types of levels:Mission levels - You and your team must get from A to B while shooting any robots that get in your waySurvival levels - You are confined to a small arena and must survive for a set amount of waves.The game doesn't use both analogue sticks to aim, instead you hold down the aim button to put your character in a stance where they can aim around the screen without moving. The slide button allows you to slide under obstacles and you also have a melee ability which can be used to knock back incoming projectiles.CustomizationIn Shoot Many Robots you can customize your character how you see fit. You have a total of five customization slots; primary gun, secondary gun, hat, torso and jeans. Each slot will give your character extra abilities and buffs, such as extra bullet damage, increased critical chance, speed boosts, etc.During the gameplay you will collect "nuts" from destroying robots, and these nuts act as the game's currency. You may also discover hidden crates that once collected will unlock new gear in the shop. After each mission you return to your RV where you can access the shop (via the shower) and use nuts to buy the newly unlocked gear and equip it to your character.Gear is broken down into five categories:Primary weapon- Bottomless clips make these weapons your main defense against murdering device for robots.Secondary Weapon- Limited ammo but increased firepower makes these weapons useful for bigger badder enemies or massive floods of robots.Headpiece- Head gear usually just buffs up your stats, but can occasionally give you access to extra abilities.Backpack- Backpacks, much like Headpieces, give you significant boosts to your stats, but often give you access to the air abilities like Hangtime, as well as the other abilities in the game.Legs- Legs on the other hand tend to give you access to the Slide tackle, as well as the other abilities....and on top of buffing your stats, give you access to some/all abilities such as...Slide- Slide allows you to quickly slide across a small (or large, depending on the level) section of a platform, as well as pop smaller enemies into the air. It is particularly useful for making sure you get loot/nut drops when a very large wave of enemies is preventing you from getting them before they blink out and disappear, or slowing down the fodder to let your coop partner(s) mop em up.Hangtime- Hangtime is the classic platforming hover move, letting you drift down to the ground lazily after jumping or falling. Hangtime is useful for platforming, but is also great for getting some distance from the smaller melee enemies that attack in droves throughout the game, especially in tight spaces when you don't have room to keep back pedaling.Slam- Slam is a ground pound move that allows you to fall with crushing force on robots, doing area of effect damage depending on the level.And much much more! (Well, more anyway)System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Windows XP / Windows Vista / Windows 7Processor: 3.0 GHz Pentium IV or 2.0 GHz AMD Athlon64 X2 3800+Memory: 2GBHard Disk Space: 1GBGraphics: 256 MB DirectX 9.0c-compatible video cardSound: DirectX 9.0-compliant sound cardDirectX®: 9.0cRecommended:OS: Windows XP / Windows Vista / Windows 7Processor: Core2Duo E4400 @ 2.0Ghz or AMD Athlon64 X2 4400+ @ 2.3Ghz or betterMemory: 2GBHard Disk Space: 1GBGraphics: 512 MB GeForce 8800 GTX or ATI Radeon HD 3870 or betterSound: DirectX 9.0-compliant sound cardDirectX®: 9.0c</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="847">Metal Slug</game><game id="19020">Metal Slug Anthology</game><game id="40860">Bleed</game><game id="40920">Bad Bots</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2104767-box_smr.png</image></root>