<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32934</id><name>RailWorks 2: Train Simulator</name><description>Train Simulator. Be the Driver. Meet the Challenge     Railworks 2 is really more simulation than game as it lets you drive an accurately re-created selection of trains though real life scenarios. From the  present day diesel and electric locomotives to the giants of the steam  age, Railworks 2 has tons of engines for players to learn to operate.  All of the locomotives have been carefully researched and modeled to  stunning accuracy. Players can choose between eight different routes, 5 real world, 3 Fictional. Each route contains scenarios ranging from easy, medium, to hard in difficulty. All of the routes have  been carefully recreated with accurate signaling and signage. Railworks  starts players off with a simple control set up and features a new  interface upgrade to help new players learn to drive. Once players master  simple controls they can move on to expert controls.  Once expert  controls are activated players can choose to play the new career mode  with 50 scenarios in which scores are tracked and can be compared  with others across the world. In addition to driving trains players can use the World Editor to create custom routes and scenarios.The Railworks train simulation series should be known to those who  visit the steam store regularly as the game features almost 1,900.00 USD  in DLC at the time of this writing. Although it seems overwhelming, the DLC is really not intended for every player to buy every  piece. Some train enthusiast are steam fans while others are more diesel  or electric fans. The base game contains all kinds of locomotives and  the DLC is there to expand and support those who want a deeper experience with certain kinds of locomotives over others.Included RoutesBath Green Park to Templecombe (real world)  The route is set in 1955 at the peak of the lines activity. A mix of passenger freight stock is provided in authentic colours to represent the truly mixed operations that took place in its day.  Oxford to Paddington (real world)   This inter-city route has been built to represent its modern day form. The route is, as accurately as possible modeled on how the line operates and appears in late 2005. The rolling stock sports the very latest that First Great Western issued after their successful bid ti operate the line foe a further period of 10 years. York to Newcastle (real world)   The route has been constructed around a popular  period set in the mid 1970s. Durings this era, the line reached an all time high for freight traffic volume, maily due to nearby coal reserves and the norths abundance of industrail and manufacturing based commerce. Also fondly remembered from this time is the class 55 Deltic Napier Locomotive, regarded by many as the greatest diesel to grace British Railways. Hagen to Siegen (real world)    Chosen for its mixture of Freight and Passenger operation, this route has been constructed around the period of the late 90s. Barstow to San Bernardino (real world)  This vital artery in the transcontinental movement of freight in America is represented in a modern day setting. The line has been modeled to 2007 reference material and even features the brand new signaling system recently installed throughout- consisting of 3 aspect hooded signal heads. Castle Rock Railroad (Fictional) This fictional railroad is based on an area between Colorado Springs and Denver for the interesting geography and rock formations and is set in the modern era circa 2009. Lakespur houses a preserved F7 engine which is frequently seen in operation down the railroad. Hedborough North (Fictional)   this fictional industrial route has been built to represent post transition period of the railways when British Rail set about modernising its traction and introducing a new fleet wide corporate brand. Seebergbahn (Fictional)  The fictional route is modem day circa 2009, but with the steam heritage centre at Echten and the preserved V 200 at Berndorf Engin Shed the line frequently sees operational rolling stock from the past fifty years for special charters and as a tourist draw.   DLC Content list as of 12/3/2010Doncaster Works Expansion Pack SD70ACe Add-OnClass 170 DMU Add-OnOhio Steel - Dover DivisionFlying Scotsman Add-OnKeeping Up with the Diesels Scenario (Free DLC)RailWorks 2P 4-4-0 Locomotive Add-OnUK Buildings Model Pack (Free DLC)RailWorks Class 56 Add-OnWest Coast Main Line North Add-OnUp the Junction Add-OnPort Road Expansion Pack (Free DLC)Billionaire Benefactor Scenario (Free DLC)Union Pacific Big Boy Add-OnOff the Cotswold Line Career System Scenario Pack (Free DLC)Isle of Wight RailWorks Expansion PackClass 08 Diesel Shunter RailWorks Add-onClass 66 Diesel Locomotive RailWorks Add-onClass 158 Diesel Multiple Unit RailWorks Add-onBNSF Officially Licensed ES44AC  SD40-2 RailWorks Add-onStanier 8F Steam Locomotive RailWorks Add-onRascal  Cottonwood RailWorks Expansion PackColton  Northern RailWorks Expansion PackClass S-2 Berkshire RailWorks Add-onGWR Hall 4-6-0 Locomotive RailWorks Add-onGWR B Set Coach RailWorks Add-onSPS Northerns RailWorks Add-OnBlack Five Scenario Pack 1RailWorks 7F Scenario PackRailWorks Challenger DLCRailWorks HST Buffer VersionClass 37 Diesel Locomotive RailWorks Add-onV2 Steam Locomotive: Green Arrow Edition RailWorks Add-onRailWorks Mk2e Coach DLCA1 Tornado Steam Locomotive Pack RailWorks Add-onClass 390 Electric Multiple Unit RailWorks Add-onClass 20 Diesel Locomotive RailWorks Add-onMk1 Coach Pack RailWorks Add-onTEA Bogie Tank Wagon Pack RailWorks Add-on0-4-0ST Saddle Tank Locomotive Pack RailWorks Add-onSouthern Pacific GS-4 Pack RailWorks Add-onRailWorks Class 380 Electric Multiple Unit DLCNorfolk Southern SD40-2 HighNose RailWorks Add-onCanadian National SD40-2 Wide Nose RailWorks Add-onStanier Jubilee Steam Locomotive RailWorks Add-onClass 45 'Peak' Diesels RailWorks Add-onFort Kent to Eagle Lake RailWorks Add-onRailworks Phorum Peninsula Charity DLCSD40-2 Santa Fe Edition RailWorks Add-onRailWorks DT Wagon Pack 01RailWorks ATSF Warbonnet PackRailWorks MJA Wagon PackRailWorks SD40-2 Burlington Northern Add-onRailWorks Glasgow Airport Rail Link Add-on9F Evening Star RailWorks Add-onRailWorks German Wagon Pack 01RailWorks BNSF Dash 9 PackRailWorks Class 101 DMU PackRailWorks GR Class 143 PackRailWorks Fowler 4F PackRailWorks Class 02 Shunter PackRailWorks Light Pacific Add-OnRailWorks Canadian National Add-onRailWorks Network Southeast Class 47 Add-OnRailWorks BR Standard 4MT Add-onRailWorks Class 57 Add-onRailworks Green and Gold HST Add-OnSystem Requirements OS:  Windows XP / Vista/ 7Processor:  1.7 GHz or fasterMemory:  512 MB RAMGraphics:  64 MB with Pixel Shader 2.0** (AGP PCIe only)DirectX®:  Version 9.0c (Included)Hard Drive:  6 GB of free spaceSound:  Direct X 9.0c compatible</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19087">Microsoft Train Simulator</game><game id="20325">Railroad Tycoon 3</game><game id="18275">Sid Meier's Railroads!</game><game id="3953">Railroad Tycoon II: The Second Century</game><game id="34721">Trainz Simulator 12</game><game id="44011">Train Simulator 2014</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/15/155745/2255893-railworks_2_train_simulator_1.jpg</image></root>