<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>32940</id><name>The Swapper</name><description>OverviewThe Swapper is a 2D puzzle-platformer for PC that explores the concept of identity and the line between mind and body. The player controls an astronaut with a mysterious device called the Swapper which allows them to make clones and swap between them.GameplayThe Swapper relies on two main mechanics, cloning and swapping. The first is the ability to create up to 4 clones of your character at any one time. You create a clone by clicking and holding the left mouse button (which will then drastically slow down time) then moving your cursor to place the outline of the clone where you want it to appear, and releasing the mouse button. You do not have direct control over these clones, as they will only mimic your characters motions.The clones can be used to traverse environments by using the second ability your character possesses which is to swap your character's consciousness (and therefore direct control) with one of your clones. An example would be to place a clone at the top of an inaccessible ledge and then swap to that clone, leaving behind your old body and progressing through the environment. To swap clones you only need to have a clear line-of-sight to your target. Clones will disappear when touched by the one you are in control of, and can also be killed off by being dropped by ledges. Once killed they will be added back to your available clone count. There are also reset points in the environment which will destroy all currently deployed clones.The goal of each puzzle is to navigate your way to obtaining an orb, which you then have to touch with a clone you are currently in direct control of to solve the puzzle. After obtaining a certain number of orbs, you will unlock new areas of the map and while you do not need to solve all puzzles to progress, you will need to eventually solve them all to access the games ending. Later puzzles introduce new mechanics such as colored lights which blocks clone creating or clone swapping in certain areas, pressure plates to remove barriers, and gravity reversing devices.StoryThe story of The Swapper seems simple at first but then reveals surprising depth, laden with heavy and thought-provoking themes. At the beginning of the game the protagonist, a mysterious astronaut whose identity is never revealed, crash lands on some sort of abandoned mining facility in a far flung corner of space. As players explore, they begin to uncover some of the secrets this complex has to offer. Terminals placed throughout the environment will give the player clues as to the recent history of the people that inhabited the facility before it was abandoned. The deeper players get, the more apparent it becomes that things may not be quite as they seem.AestheticThe art style gives the game a very unusual aesthetic. Lighting is used to assign an eerie, sober tone to the setting. While use of images of real world objects integrated into the environment design gives the look of the game a somewhat life-like aspect that is both visually striking, and totally unique to The Swapper.System RequirementsOS: Windows XP SP3Processor: Dual Core CPU (2.2+ GHz Dual Core CPU or better)Memory: 1 GB RAMGraphics: GeForce 8800 or Radeon® HD4800 series, 512 MB of memoryHard Drive: 1 GB HD spaceLinks Official WebsiteSteam Store Page</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21868">The Misadventures of P.B. Winterbottom</game><game id="36243">Closure</game><game id="30380">Limbo</game><game id="20716">Braid</game><game id="21170">Portal</game><game id="33629">Dear Esther</game><game id="44136">Glare</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/13/133506/2502628-the-swapper-cover.png</image></root>