<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33000</id><name>Shin Megami Tensei: Persona 2 - Innocent Sin</name><description>OverviewFans have waited more than a decade to play Persona 2: Innocent Sin. We'll finally see what happened to Yuki after the Ice Queen issue.Persona 2: Innocent Sin is the sequel to Shin Megami Tensei: Persona. It was first released as a Playstation title in Japan on June 24th, 1999. Unlike Persona 1, Persona 2's environments are 3-dimensional maps, with sprite characters rather than a first person corridor sprawl found in other previous Shin Megami Tensei games. Persona 2's main party consists up to five characters. Similar to Persona 1, when the party is in a save point area, shop, or other room without randomly triggered encounters, each party member can be conversed with and will reflect upon the situation at hand. Persona 2 was the first in the series to include the Rumor System; this gameplay mechanic allows the player to collect/exchange rumors throughout the game by interacting with Rumormongers, NPCs that can be found in every district of the city. Once the party hears a rumor, the player has the option to visit the Kuzunoha Detective Agency and speak to Todoroki Daisuke who will in turn spread the rumor, which will result in it becoming real. Rumors typically allow shops to carry secret weapons, armor, and items.Additional Features in the PSP VersionThe first "all out attack" outside of Japan comes to the PSP as Persona 2: Innocent Sin!Featured additions to this remake are similar to additions made for the original Persona game's enhanced remake for the PSP:Improved user interface and combat pacingNew character portraits, models, and aesthetic upgradesThe addition of the Climax TheatreNew challenging difficulty levelA new improved soundtrackA new remix of Satomi Tadashi, the legendary item store music adored by the most obscure and hardcore of Persona fansThe game's director and composer, Shoji Meguro, composed new music for the game. Players have the option to choose between the new, arranged soundtrack or the game's original soundtrack.Climax TheatreThe PSP release of Persona 2: Innocent Sin includes a theater mode called the Climax Theatre.Welcome to the Climax Theatre! Not to be confused with the Golden Theatre from Catherine.The Climax Theater allows the player to take on various optional quests that are separate from the main storyline. These quests offer the player a chance to earn powerful weapons, armor, and items. Also, quests in the Climax Theatre sometimes contain unique demon encounters. Following release, there may be additional quests available for download from the PSN.Players are also able to create their own quests in the Climax Theatre - a sort of "play, create, share" aspect. This includes creating NPCs, battles, events, and even choosing what items can be earned from battles and events.Mini SoundtrackMini SoundtrackThe Persona 2: Innocent Sin Mini Soundtrack, which comes bundled with the initial run of the game, contains 10 songs. It includes music from the original Innocent Sin release as well as remixed tracks and arrangements new to the PSP remake. All of the new music is composed by Shoji Meguro.Tracklist:Unbreakable Tie (Opening theme [short Ver.]) [Remix Side]Hikoujou [Remix Side]Gatten Sushi [Remix Side]CD Shop Giga Macho [Original Side]Ginko no Theme (Kanashii) [Original Side]Velvet Room (#2) [Original Side]Teki no Maketa Toki (unused song) [Another Side]Persona Ondo [Another Side]Battle [Arrange Side]Seisou Kishidan [Arrange Side]</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3966">Pokémon Red/Blue</game><game id="14522">Pokémon FireRed/LeafGreen</game><game id="8210">Pokémon Gold/Silver</game><game id="26372">Pokémon HeartGold/SoulSilver</game><game id="18673">Pokémon Yellow: Special Pikachu Edition</game><game id="15861">Pokémon Crystal</game><game id="11552">Pokémon Emerald</game><game id="10122">Pokémon Ruby/Sapphire</game><game id="12964">Pokémon XD: Gale of Darkness</game><game id="30613">Pokémon Black/White</game><game id="21676">Pokémon Platinum</game><game id="25884">Dino Master</game><game id="23375">Gangway Monsters</game><game id="21933">Digimon World DS</game><game id="15485">DemiKids: Light Version</game><game id="16234">DemiKids: Dark Version</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1885923-box_smtp2is.png</image></root>