<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33118</id><name>GRID 2</name><description>OverviewDeveloped by Codemasters Southam based in the United Kingdom, GRID 2 is the sequel to the "reboot" of the TOCA Race Driver series, GRID. GRID 2 employs the EGO 3.0 engine, the same engine in the previous Codemaster game Dirt 3 and features a new handling system 'TrueFeel', which tries to improve the balance in racing games between accessibility and realism.GRID 2 has races in a variety of locales influenced by the Formula 1 calender such as Abu Dhabi, Chicago, the California Coast and Paris. They also did not include a dashboard view claiming that "only 5% ever use it". The game was released on May 28, 2013 for the Xbox 360, PlayStation 3, and PC. TrueFeelTrueFeel aims to create a balance between the accessibility of arcade racing games with the realism of simulation racing games. Codemaster does this by collecting around 75 sets of technical data per-vehicle. The aim is to create a racing game that's handling can be learned within a few laps but offers depth past those first races after that. MultiplayerGRID 2 has a customization multiplayer progression system powered by RaceNet. By competing with rivals and completing objectives, GRID 2 rewards the player for their progress similar to the progression system found in Call of Duty Modern Warfare. GRID 2 multiplayer also features fully customizable championships and a dynamic ranking system.The CarsGRID 2 features over 70 carsMakeCarsAlfa Romeo4c8cGiulietta Quadrofoglio VerdeArielAtom 3Aston MartinOne-77V12 ZagatoVaguishAudiTT RS RoasterR8 LMS UltraRS5BacMonoBMW1M Coupe320 TCM3 E30 Sport EVOM3 E92BugattiVeyron Super SportCaterhamLola SP300RChevroletCamaro Z28Camaro SSCorvette Z06Cruze Touring CarDodgeChallengerCharger RTCharger SRTDallaraDW12 IndycarFordFocus STMustang Mach 1 TwisterMustang Boss 302GomezCompetition GC10.1HondaNSX-RS2000HyundaiGenesis CoupeIndyCarPace CarJaguarXKR-SKTMX-Bow RKoenigseggAgera RMazdaRX-7McLarenF1 GTMP4-12CMP4-12C GT3Mercedes190 E 2.5-16 Evo IIC63 AMGSL65 AMG Black SeriesSLR McLaren 722SLR McLaren 722 GTMercedes SLS AMG GT3NissanFairlady Z aka 300ZX370Z RoasterSilvia S15Skyline NISMO R34 GT-R Z TuneR35 GT-R Spec VPaganiHuayraSRTViperSubaruBRZVolkswagenGolf RVolvoS60 BTCSZenvoST-1 TracksThese are the tracks that have been covered by Codemasters in various interviews and previews. [Ed. Note: Someone with the game please complete this list.]LocationTypeAutódromo Internacional do AlgarveCircuitBrands HatchCircuitIndianapolis Motor SpeedwayCircuitRed Bull RingCircuitYas MarinaCircuitBarcelonaCity TrackChicagoCity TrackAbu DubaiCity TrackMiamiCity TrackParisCity TrackCalifornia CoastOpen Road/Point to PointCôte d'AzurOpen Road/Point to PointOkutamaOpen Road/Drift System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows Vista, Windows 7, Windows 8Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo @ 2.4Ghz or AMD Athlon X2 5400+Memory: 2GB RAMHard Disk Space: 15 GB HD spaceVideo Card: Intel HD Graphics 3000 / AMD HD2600 / NVIDIA Geforce 8600DirectX®: 11Sound: Direct X compatible soundcardAdditional: Broadband Internet connectionAdditional Supported Graphics Cards: Intel HD Graphics 3000, Intel HD Graphics 4000, Intel Graphics 5200. AMD Radeon HD2600 or higher, HD3650 or higher, HD4550 or higher, HD5000 Series, HD6000 Series, HD7000 Series. NVIDIA GeForce 8600 or higher, 9500 or higher, GTX220 or higher, GTX400 Series, GTX500 Series, GTX600 Series: AMD Fusion A8 or higher.RecommendedOS: Windows Vista 64 Bit, Windows 7 64 Bit, Windows 8 64 bitProcessor: Intel Core i7/AMD BulldozerMemory: 4GB RAMHard Disk Space: 15 GB HD spaceVideo Card: Intel Graphics 5200 / AMD HD6000 Series / Nvidia GTX500 Series minimum 1GB RAMDirectX®: 11Sound: Direct X compatible soundcardAdditional: Broadband Internet connection</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3916">DiRT</game><game id="20729">GRID</game><game id="28194">TrackMania² Canyon</game><game id="40347">TrackMania² Stadium</game><game id="37034">Dirt Showdown</game><game id="40348">TrackMania² Valley</game><game id="44321">WRC 4 FIA World Rally Championship</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2452886-box_grid2.png</image></root>