<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33120</id><name>Melolune</name><description>StoryArchaius is in search of his twin Caleigh, and is caught up in conflicts of the Leebles and others who have been negatively affected by the Ciro Order. CharactersProtagonists  Archaius: A human who was born into a life with inbred professions. Following the catastrophic event which led to his family's demise, Archaius goes in search of his twin Caleigh.   Aero: Aero is a Leeble; the cat-like winged species that have adopted Archaius into their tribe. Aero has become particularly close to Archaius, and follows him on his quest.     Aero  Dominic: Another human who resides within the Leeble's village; a close friend of Archaius.     AntagonistsCiro Order: A faction from the nearby continent of Ciro, who have set up camp near and consequently, threatened the Leeble's village.  MusicAll of the music within Melolune is written and composed by  Laura Shigihara. There will be around 60 tracks total, 40 of which have been completed. The first 20 tracks are available for purchase at her website, and the rest will be added upon completion.   Though it has not been explicitly stated, Track 1 (Silent Melodies) implies that music will play a large role in the abilities of the characters:In my world, there are silent melodies all around us. If you listen carefully, you can catch them, and turn them into a song. Some of us can turn them into more than that. We call these fragments Melolune."  Current Track Listing:  1. Silent Melodies 2. Eclipse and Starlight  3. Melolune (vocal)  4. Leeble Village 5. Tense  6. Sweet Unlucky (Battle Theme)  7. Victory   8. The Calm Before  9. Upperland Forest   10. Ultimate Battle 11. Premonition 12. The Great World 13. Carya de Mio (vocal) 14. The Mines of the Orderian Engineers 15. Taezu Freedom Fighters 16. Traces (vocal) 17.  LIttle Fish 18. Transformation 19. Caleigh 20. Blue Starlight</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9249">Chrono Trigger</game><game id="36242">To the Moon</game><game id="20124">Cave Story</game><game id="42526">Helen - Castle In Wonderland</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/99563/1628592-debonet_rich_quarter.png</image></root>