<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33123</id><name>Warp</name><description>OverviewWarp is a top-down puzzle action stealth game, developed by Trapdoor using the Unreal Engine 3 and is being published by Electronic Arts. In the game you control Zero, a "loveable-yet-lethal" orange alien imprisoned and tortured in a underwater facility by the villainous Commander. You must choose how you want to deal with the guards and scientists as you make your escape from the facility, either killing them violently or by stealthly making your way forward, solving traps and puzzles as you go.GameplayAbilitiesThroughout his journey, Zero can collect grubs which can be used to upgrade his abilities at upgrade stations. His abilities are as follows:MovementBy moving the left analog stick, Zero can move around the facility with style.WarpAs Zero moves, a small orange reticule will appear 4 feet in front of him. By using his warp ability, he will leap through space to that point, ignoring all obstacles in his path. Warp can be upgraded allowing Zero to warp into barrels, turrets, and even humans.FragWiggling the left analog stick while inside an object or person will cause it to explode, destroying the object and creating a small shockwave that will knock down nearby enemies. This can create quite a mess.The player can choose not to frag Zero's foes by instead stunning them; warping in and out of an enemy will stun them for a short while, but warping in, shaking up the person a little bit, and then leaping out will cause a longer lasting stun knockdown.EchoZero can deploy a fantom decoy of himself that can walk through walls. Humans and robots will not be able to tell the difference between an echo and the real thing. This can be used to lure them to other locations or to make them shoot at objects nearby. If Zero is inside an object while creating the echo, it will take on the form of the object. Robots will be tricked into not shooting the shaped echo, but humans will be more discerning of objects that don't act in the way they normally should.SwapBy touching his echo to an object, Zero can swap places with it. If Zero is already in an object before swapping, that object will explode out in a swap frag.LaunchZero can launch objects he is inside of in any direction, stunning enemies and destroying electrical panels.Passive AbilitiesIn addition to the active abilities Zero can also upgrade several passive ones that indirectly benefit the player in traversing the lab.Fast RecoveryHelps Zero recover from getting stunned by water, stun-mines or water-shields faster.Show GrubsDisplays all the grubs as purple icons on your map. Even areas that you have not visited yet will have grubs visible, albeit floating on a black background.Show CanistersSame ability as Show Grubs except that film canisters are highlighted on the map screen.Silent WarpMakes warping inaudible to scientists and guards alike helping you sneak by and surprise enemies easier. If you did not purchase the silent movement upgrade it is possible to silently sneak past guards by just using the right analog to warp through a room without "walking" at all.Fast WarpIncreases the recharge rate of your core warp ability allowing Zero to continously warp at a faster pace when on foot.Silent MovementRunning on foot becomes completely silent to all enemies. Helpful in sneaking up behind guards with only forward facing shields.Fast MovementIncreases core running speed. Especially helpful in latter areas of the game where motion-stun mines are introduced.ChallengesScattered throughout the facility are challenge computers that Zero can warp into, allowing him to escape reality and test his skill in various dangerous mazes. By finishing a challenge with a good time, he can earn bonus grubs. Challenge Leaderboards track finish times and lethality that you can compare against your friends and people on the internet.PC System RequirementsOS: Windows XP SP3, Windows Vista SP2, Windows 7 SP1Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo 2.0GHz or greater;AMD Athlon 64 X2 2.0GHz or greaterMemory: 2048MB or greaterHard Disk Space: 1.9GBVideo Card: ATI Radeon HD 3650 256MB card and the NVIDIA GeForce 8600 GT 256MB or equivalent.Video Card Note: NVIDIA GeForce 8400, 8500, 9400, and 210; ATI Radeon HD3450, HD4350, HD5450 and HD6450; Intel GMA X4500HD and HD Graphics 3000 are all below minimum system requirements.Sound: 100% DirectX9.0c compatible sound card and driversDirectX®: DirectX June 2010</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="33330">Ms. Splosion Man</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2022689-box_warp.png</image></root>