<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33158</id><name>Kaptain Brawe: A Brawe New World</name><description>OverviewKaptain Brawe: A Brawe New World is a point and click adventure game developed by Cateia Games and published by Layernet for the PC, Mac, and iOS platforms.GameplayKaptain Brawe: A Brawe New World is a point and click adventure game that is very similar in style to The Curse of Monkey Island. The characters are moved around by clicking on the spot the player wants the character to be. Various objects and people in the environment can be interacted with by clicking on them. Kaptain Brawe features the option to switch between multiple characters.InventoryThe inventory system in Kaptain Brawe is also much like it is in the Monkey Island series. There is a bag icon in the bottom left corner of the screen that when clicked will bring up the current inventory of items. Items in the inventory can sometimes be combined or used on people or objects in the world.DialogueThe Dialogue system in the game is a fairly simple one. Once a character has been interacted with, if there are any dialogue options they show up at the bottom left of the screen. There are usually multiple options to choose from. A lot of information is obtained by talking with the various characters in the game, and some objectives can only be completed after learning certain information from characters. Kaptain Brawe contains no voice acting, all of the dialogue is told through text.PuzzlesThere are a few environmental puzzles throughout the game. These puzzles are less about combining items and instead about using logic to solve a self contained puzzle. There are not very many of these types of puzzles in the game, and are generally solved using some kind of information previously obtained.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5729">The Curse of Monkey Island</game><game id="5925">Space Quest I: Roger Wilco in the Sarien Encounter</game><game id="10927">Loom</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8960/2346523-kaptainbrawe.jpg</image></root>