<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33171</id><name>Marvel Pinball</name><description>OverviewMarvel Pinball is a collection of original pinball tables (based on the Marvel franchise) developed by Zen Studios for the PlayStation 3 via PlayStation Network on December 14, 2010. The tables themselves were also released on December 8, 2010 for the Xbox 360 (via Xbox Live Arcade) as downloadable content for the free front-end Pinball FX2. The standalone release includes four pinball tables based on major Marvel Comics franchises: Spider-Man, Iron Man, Blade, and Wolverine. Two downloadable tables were released based on the Captain America and Fantastic Four franchises, with more tables on the way.On September 4th 2012, current owners of Marvel Pinball on PlayStation 3 were given a free upgrade to Zen Pinball 2, which allows for more DLC, free trials for each table, and cross platform entitlement for PS Vita.TablesEach of the tables in Marvel Pinball are designed after a superhero in the Marvel universe with their respective villains appearing on the table as 3D models. There are missions involving beating these villains to score bonus points and earn achievements/trophies. Fights between the hero character and the villain can occur when certain conditions are met.Spider-Man tableThe Spider-man table uses mainly red and blue colors, the main colors of Spider-man and features animated characters of the Green Goblin, Doctor Octopus and Mysterio. These are all fightable by performing special actions on the pinball table.The Green Goblin uses bombs (orange colored balls) which must be redirected at him to complete the mission and earn bonus points.Doctor Octopus has the ability to pick up the ball and drop it somewhere else.Mysterio can cause hallucinations, making the pinball table look different (a purple glow and different lights glow up) and reversing the controls of the flippers (Left and Right flipper controls are switched).Iron Man tableMandarin and Whiplash populate the Iron man table, along with Tony Stark who can transform into Iron Man after the necessary actions are performed.The table offers 6 missions for Tony Stark and 6 for Iron Man.Wolverine tableThe Wolverine table is a mainly yellow table and houses characters like Wolverine, Sabretooth, Silver Samurai and Sentinel.Blade tableThe Blade table features a unique Night/Day cycle which changes the available missions and has an Energy meter and Funds meter.At night, the table is dark and the balls are lit, creating a unique pinball experience compared to the other tables.This table includes the characters Blade, Dracula, and Deacon Frost.Vengeance and Virtue DLCFour new tables for Marvel Pinball were released on December 13th 2011 for PSN and December 14th 2011 for Xbox Live, with themes for Ghost Rider, Thor, X-Men and Moon Knight.</description><genres><genre id="30">Pinball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12059">Pinball FX</game><game id="26405">ZEN Pinball</game><game id="28900">South Park</game><game id="36777">The Pinball Arcade</game><game id="12971">Disney/Pixar's Monsters Inc.: Pinball Panic</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/6/63119/1766612-marvelpinball.jpg</image></root>