<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33193</id><name>Yar's Revenge</name><description>OverviewYar's Revenge is a rail shooter named after the classic Atari title Yars' Revenge. The game's existence first came to light publicly through a listing of Atari's 2011 game release schedule published in early November 2010. The game was officially announced on November 16th, 2010 along with the release of a teaser trailer. The spelling of the new game's title, which shifts "Yars'" to "Yar's," is a reflection of the fact that the new game is focused on a single character named Yar, rather than a species known as the Yars.PlotMost elements of the original Atari 2600 title's story have been ignored. The protagonist Yar is a member of a race of humanoid insect creatures facing off against the Qotile. Beyond these simple names, the game focuses on its original characters and universe and isn't concerned with maintaining any continuity with the original title.GraphicsYar's Revenge features an aesthetic strongly influenced by Japanese animation. The developers specifically cite the works of Hayao Miyazaki and the western film Avatar as the primary inspirations behind the game's art design. Where appropriate, the game also features graphic elements that call back to the design of Yars' Revenge, such as how the appearance of Yar's shield is similar to that of the original game's Neutral Zone.GameplayThe game is an on-rails shooter, similar in style to games such as Sin  Punishment or Rez, that pits Yar against hordes of Qotile-controlled enemies. A combo system allows players to accumulate higher scores by chaining kills and keeping the combo meter filled. Yar's Revenge also features a "co-op" mode where two players control the same Yar; one controlling the movement and basic weapons while the other controls the advanced weapons, making it exceedingly difficult to actually do well.DelistedAs of January 19, 2013, Yar's Revenge was removed from Xbox Live Arcade. Though no official reason was given, it was probably because of publisher Atari filing for bankruptcy.It was eventually relisted (this time with a lower price) and is currently available for purchase.PC System RequirementsOS: Windows XP SP2, Vista SP2, 7CPU: Intel Core 2 Duo E4300 or AMD Athlon X2 4400+Memory: 1 GBHD: 1.5 GBVideo: Radeon ATI Radeon HD 2600 or NVIDIA GeForce 8600, DirectX 9</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4489">Panzer Dragoon</game><game id="3984">Star Fox</game><game id="7393">Sin &amp; Punishment</game><game id="32567">Saber Rider and the Star Sheriffs</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1773229-box_yars.png</image></root>