<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33265</id><name>Project Blackout</name><description>Overview Project Blackout is a                     free-to-play FPS from                      SG Interactive that introduces a system of quests within each match for which you will get rewards upon completion, such as XP or emblems. In addition to this, there'll be add-ons for weapons and different armor sets.  Mission Cards  Mission Cards can be purchased at the beginning of each mission, in the  Mission Menu. Any reward (XP and emblems) for missions completed during a  match will only be awarded if the player finishes the match. Whenever  the player completes a set of quests, the rewards get better, and they  will be awarded with new weapons,  master badges and some bonus XP.   A.C.T. System   The  Advance Combat Training System is a way for the player to customize their gameplay, while also increasing their character and/or weapon stats.  This is achieved through means of exchanging emblems (awarded through the completion of missions) by  Titles. There are a total of 8 types of  Titles (better speed, rate of fire accuracy, etc), but only 3 can be equipped at a time.  Game Modes ** as described in the game's official website.Deathmatch                      In Deathmatch, teams are created and the goal is to annihilate                         the opposing team.                                                To win, your team must reach a certain number of kills,                         or have the highest number of kills at the end of the time limit.                            Good map control is crucial to victory in this mode.                         With enemies constantly respawning, you'll need to know where to hole up, and when                         to pin down your enemies.                            Every time you die you will respawn after a short time.                         No rest for the wicked!Demolition This mode gives each team a goal that they need to work                         towards.                                                Corps Operators will be forced to quickly set up their                         C4 charge at the designated bomb site or wipe out the entire Aegis team. Aegis Operators                         will either have to defuse the C4 charge or destroy the Corps team.                            Operators will not respond during the match. Once you're                         dead, you're dead! So move carefully and don't just go running around without your                         team.                            Demolition requires good tactics and great team work! Sabotage Unlike Demolition missions, Sabotage requires Operators                         to attack an objective while defending their own asset.                                                Also unlike Demolition, Operators will respawn throughout                         the match.                            The round will end when an objective is destroyed or                         the time limit runs out. If the time limit runs out, the team that did the most                         damage to the other team's asset wins!                            The decision to split your team up, or have everyone                         rush the objective will be crucial to your victory! Search  Destroy! Search and Destroy requires you to annihilate the opposing                         team to win.                                                The round ends once the entire enemy team is dead.                            The number of rounds one will determine the winner.                            Bonus XP will be awarded for kill strings and other                         impressive feats.                            Search  Destroy can be played on nearly all maps available.AI ChallengeChallenge Mode allows you to test your skills against                         AI opponents on a difficulty scale of 1-10.                                                Up to 4 Operators can join your team and up to 8 AI will                         appear as your enemy.                            AI Challenge will not affect your Kill/Death ratio.                            AI Challenge will test your limits and give you the opportunity                         to use many weapons as you hone your skills.                            The game will end only after the time limit is reached.Ranks and PromotionsEnlistedSymbol Abbreviation Rank Title Required XP Bonus Credits    RCT Recruit N/A N/A    PVT Private 2000 2000    PFC Private First Class 3000 3200    CPL Corporal 4000 4000    SGT Sergeant 5000 6000     NCOSymbol Abbreviation Rank Title Required XP Bonus Credits    SSG-I Staff Sergeant Grade I 7000 8000    SSG-II Staff Sergeant Grade II 8000 9000    SSG-III Staff Sergeant Grade III 11000 8000    SFC-I Sergeant First Class Grade I 13500 10000    SFC-II Sergeant First Class Grade II 16000 10000    SFC-III Sergeant First Class Grade III 18500 10000    SFC-IV Sergeant First Class Grade IV 21000 10000    MSG-I Master Sergeant Grade I 24000 12000    MSG-II Master Sergeant Grade II 27000 12000    MSG-III Master Sergeant Grade III 30000 12000    MSG-IV Master Sergeant Grade IV 33000 12000    MSG-V Master Sergeant Grade V 36000 12000  Company OfficerSymbol Abbreviation Rank Title Required XP Bonus Credits    2LT-I 2nd Lieutenant Grade I 41000 14000    2LT-II 2nd Lieutenant Grade II 46000 14000    2LT-III 2nd Lieutenant Grade III 51000 14000    2LT-IV 2nd Lieutenant Grade IV 56000 14000    1LT-I 1st Lieutenant Grade I 62000 16000    1LT-II 1st Lieutenant Grade II 68000 16000    1LT-III 1st Lieutenant Grade III 74000 16000    1LT-IV 1st Lieutenant Grade IV 80000 16000    1LT-V 1st Lieutenant Grade V 86000 16000    CPT-I Captain Grade I 93000 18000    CPT-II Captain Grade II 100000 18000    CPT-III Captain Grade III 107000 18000    CPT-IV Captain Grade IV 114000 18000    CPT-V Captain Grade V 121000 18000  Field OfficerSymbol Abbreviation Rank Title Required XP Bonus Credits    MAJ-I Major Grade I 151000 20000    MAJ-II Major Grade II 181000 20000    MAJ-III Major Grade III 211000 20000    MAJ-IV Major Grade IV 241000 20000    MAJ-V Major Grade V 271000 20000    LTC-I Lieutenant Colonel Grade I 311000 22000    LTC-II Lieutenant Colonel Grade II 351000 22000    LTC-III Lieutenant Colonel Grade III 391000 22000    LTC-IV Lieutenant Colonel Grade IV 431000 22000    LTC-V Lieutenant Colonel Grade V 471000 22000    COL-I Colonel Grade I 521000 24000    COL-II Colonel Grade II 571000 24000    COL-III Colonel Grade III 621000 24000    COL-IV Colonel Grade IV 671000 24000    COL-V Colonel Grade V 721000 24000  GeneralSymbol Abbreviation Rank Title Required XP Bonus Credits    BG Brigadier General 8255000 28000    MG Major General 9106000 32000    LTG Lieutenant General 10037000 36000    GEN General 11058000 40000    CGEN Command General 12179000 60000Note: promotions to the rank of  Major General and above are based on total XP and are competitive only.System Requirements Minimum Settings  Operating System: Windows NT, 2000, XP SP2 Processor: P4 2.4 GHz or Athlon 2500  or equivalent RAM Memory: 512 MB Video Card: GeForce 2700 / Radeon 9600 or equivalent DirectX: 9.0c Sound Card: DirectX 9.0c compatible Recommended Settings Operating System: Windows NT, 2000, XP SP2 Processor: P4 3.0 GHz / Athlon 3000 or equivalent RAM Memory: 1 GB Video Card: GeForce 6600 / Radeon X600 DirectX: 9.0c Sound Card: DirectX 9.0c compatible Links         Official Website</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="40582">Mission Against Terror</game><game id="21591">Combat Arms</game><game id="36230">Blacklight Retribution</game><game id="7334">Crossfire</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/6/62890/1732620-news_2.jpg</image></root>