<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33329</id><name>Anomaly: Warzone Earth</name><description>StoryAn alien ship has crashed in Baghdad, and turrets have popped up in the streets. You take on the role of a field commander that must guide a convoy of unmanned military vehicles to find their weaknesses and ultimately to destroy the aliens. The missions take place between Baghdad and Tokyo, which was the other city affected by the anomalies caused by the alien machines invasion.Gameplay  Choose your path carefully!      As the field commander, the player's job is to guide a non-stopping convoy through the streets, using those units and certain abilities to defeat the aliens. The game is played from a       top-down perspective and lets the player move the camera around the map in order to plan the best attack. The player can chose the most direct path or take a longer one to avoid any of the tougher enemies throughout the urban battlefield. The player can freely move the Field Commander and use his Combat Suit abilities to support other units.Most enemies are displayed on the tactical map at the start of a mission, but others may spawn from out of nowhere, thus making the player rethink their whole strategy. Money can be found scattered throughout the battlefield and can be used to purchase additional units or to upgrade their existing ones-- it's up to the player to decide the best course of action. No longer required units can be sold for money to buy/upgrade other units. The player is allowed a limited amount of units on the field at a time and must choose their formations correctly in order to have a better chance at defeating the invading aliens.AbilitiesThere are four abilities the player can use in order to aid his units in the field of battle. They are each unlocked at the story goes.AbilityDescription * RepairThe Repair ability, as the name suggests, repairs damaged units. The ability has a limited range and works for a limited time which is why units should be arranged in a way that allows the ability to be utilized to the max. Smoke ScreenThe Smoke Screen reduces damage inflicted by enemies on your units. When attacking units within the circumference of a Smoke Screen, enemies will suffer a loss of accuracy, with some finding their target once every few shots, while others fire blindly. DecoyThe Decoy is a virtual target which attracts enemy fire. All machines within the Decoy's range will immediately begin shooting at it. The Decoy has limited staying power and can be destroyed quickly when attacked by multiple targets. AirstrikeThe Air Strike ability initiates an air raid which bombs a designated area, causing severe damage to enemy units. Be advised: some enemies cannot be destroyed by a single air raid. The Air Strike does not harm friendly units.* as seen in-game.UnitsThere are a total of 6 units available to the player, but with the exception of the first two, the others will only unlock as the story mode progresses. Any unit can be upgraded 3 times, making it more powerful.NameDescription *Fire PowerFire Power upgradeable toStarting ArmorArmor upgradeable toShieldShield upgradeable to Buy / Sell Price The APCThe APC is the mainstay of any army. The unit is inexpensive and well-armored, though its weapons leave a lot to be desired. The APC's mounted automatic rifle has a short range and inflicts only moderate damage. 6096120300------100 The CrawlerThis mobile rocket launcher is useful on every battlefield. Crawlers offer devastating firepower and can attack distant targets. Unfortunately they also have their drawbacks: they're slow to lock onto targets and poorly armored.8528070112------125 The ShieldPower field generators can be utilized during battles against the machines thanks to research conducted by Prof. Veronica Sharp. The Shield is a tactical unit which generates a field that encircles the generator and two adjacent units. The shield can regenerate if a unit protected by is it not under attack.------125---4080 150 The TankRun like the wind if you see a tank: you don't have to tell foot soldiers twice. The unit is heavily armored and well-armed. Tanks don't pack quite the punch of Crawlers, but they lock onto targets more rapidly.75165140308------200 The DragonThis double plasma thrower was developed by Japanese specialists. The Dragon is equipped with two independently operated plasma throwers and can fry enemies to the left and right of it simultaneously... or even set them on fire for a limited time.65123120220------250 The SupplyThis exceptional unit can utilize the energy given off by destroyed enemy machines to generate abilities stocked by the Combat Suit. The ability it generates changes with every upgrade. The unit initially generates the repair ability, followed by the Smoke Screen, the Decoy and then the Airstrike. Varying amounts of energy are required to generate different abilities------120---------175* as seen in-game.Enemies / TowersThere are also a total of 6 different types of enemies, each with their own strenghts and weaknesses.NameDescription * The BlasterThe Blaster is the most prevalent enemy unit. It is equipped with a medium-strength lase, especially effective at damaging weaker units. Warning! Do not underestimate this adversary. It can be very dangerous in larger groups. The ScorcherThe Scorcher is equipped with a thermal weapon which can melt the toughest armor. Thankfully the firing mechanism is so big that the unit is unable to rotate and can only launch frontal assaults. This machine should not be attacked head-on! The BehemothThe Behemoth's main strength lies in its cannon-fired kinetic energy ammo, which unleashes a powerful assault wave on its chosen target. The wave causes severe damage over a large area. The machine is also very well armored. Its only weakness is the extensive time it takes to lock onto targets. An ill-devised attack on the Behemoth can have tragic consequences. The StormrayThis machine concentrates a beam of electric energy on the closest unit. When the beam hits its target it affects other units in the vicinity. The Stormray is exceptionally efficient at destroying defense shields. The machine locks onto and attacks targets at lightning speed. The HackerThe Hacker is one of the enemy's most treacherous weapons. It shoots ammo that forms a hacking field: a deadly trap. If the field encircles the Commander as well as his units, affected units will immediately begin attacking him. I repeat! This is an extremely dangerous adversary! The Commander must not become trapped within its hacking field along with other units! The EnergizerThe Energizer can absorb the energy from nearby, deployed Combat Suit abilities. If the Commander launches an ability within the Energizer's range, the machine will begin sapping its power and charching itself. When it is fully charged it will create a wave that repairs and rebuilds all destroyed enemy units. Abilities must therefore be used with care during the battle: buildings and other obstacles can be used to block the Energizer's energy-draining rays.* as seen in-game.System Requirements           PC Operating System: Windows XP SP2/Microsoft Windows Vista/Microsoft Windows 7            Processor: Intel Pentium 4 2.4GHz or AMD Athlon 64 +2800            RAM Memory: 1 GB Graphics Card: NVIDIA GeForce 7600 / ATI Radeon X1800 or equivalent            DirectX®: 9.0c            Hard Drive Space: 1 GB            Sound Card: DirectX 9.0c compliant soundcard            Mac Operating System: OS X Snow Leopard 10.6.3 or laterProcessor: Intel Pentium 4 2.4GHz or AMD Athlon 64 +2800             RAM Memory: 2 GB              Graphics Card: NVIDIA GeForce 7600 / ATI Radeon X1800 or equivalent             Hard Drive Space: 1 GB             </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="35123">Fortix 2</game><game id="34265">Orcs Must Die!</game><game id="40887">Towers of Oz</game><game id="40909">I Am Weapon</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2132180-box_awe.png</image></root>