<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33371</id><name>Spirits</name><description>OverviewAutumn is coming. Leaves fall, and spirits rise from the fallen leaves to begin their journey home. Guide them by changing how the wind blows or by rebuilding the ground. Each spirit can be sacrificed to perform one of four actions – build a bridge of leaves, create a blowing cloud, dig tunnels, or block wind currents in an area. Use your actions wisely or you will run out of spirits. In each level it's up to you to find your own creative solution on how to get the spirits to the goal.The game contains 46 levels to beat and you can maximize your score by collecting all plants in the level. The game features a worldwide ladder ranking system. The Steam version contains achievements.Spirits has been faithfully ported to PC and Linux by Tim Ambrogi of Final Form Games, developer of top-down shooter Jamestown. The Android version has been developed by Apportable, the team who brought Osmos from iOS to Android.System RequirementsPCMinimumOS: Windows XPProcessor: 2.0GHz Intel Core 2 Duo processor, or similarMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: Graphics card with 128 Mb VRAM and Framebuffer Object support. Integrated graphics cards may not work.DirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 150 MB HD spaceSound: AnyRecommendedOS: Windows XP, Vista or Windows 7Memory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: 256 Mb Video RamDirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 200 MB HD spaceMacMinimumOS: Mac OS X 10.6Processor: 2.0GHz Intel Core 2 Duo processorMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: Graphics card with 128 Mb VRAM and Framebuffer Object support. Integrated graphics cards may not work.Hard Drive: 150 MB HD spaceSound: AnyAdditional: Runs on any Mac built after mid-2007RecommendedOS: Mac OS X 10.7Memory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: 256 Mb Video RamHard Drive: 200 MB HD spaceAdditional: Runs on any Mac built after mid-2007LinuxMinimumOS: Linux Ubuntu 12.04Processor: 2.0GHz Intel Core 2 Duo processor, or similarMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: Graphics card with 128 Mb VRAM and Framebuffer Object support. Integrated graphics cards may not work.Hard Drive: 150 MB HD spaceSound: AnyRecommendedOS: Linux Ubuntu 12.04Memory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: 256 Mb Video RamHard Drive: 200 MB HD space</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1446">Lemmings</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/11/117587/2303249-spirits_character_and_logo.png</image></root>