<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33382</id><name>Ni no Kuni: Wrath of the White Witch</name><description>OverviewOliverNi no Kuni: Wrath of the White Witch (Japanese: Ni no Kuni: Shiroki Seihai no Joō, literally "Second Country: The Queen of White Sacred Ash") is a role-playing game developed and published by Level-5 in collaboration with world-famous animation company Studio Ghibli. The game puts the player in the role of Oliver, a 13 year-old boy who, after his mother's death, is transported to a parallel world, and goes on a quest to bring her back to life.The game is a follow up to Level-5 and Studio Ghibli's first collaboration, Ni no Kuni: Shikoku no Madoshi for the Nintendo DS.GameplayOliver and company preparing for battleNi no Kuni: Wrath of the White Witch is a role-playing game. Players take control of the protagonist, Oliver, to explore the world. Oliver can move around towns and cities, interacting with different characters. Players explore the game's large world on an over-world map, similar to those found in older RPGs.Enemies wander around the world, and battles are initiated when the player comes into contact with them. Combat is played out in real-time, with a meter that must fill for the player to perform an action (similar to the active-time battle system of Final Fantasy). Central to the combat are the creature-like avatars, or "familiars," which the player can summon in combat to assist them.FamiliarsIn combat, the player can opt to do battle with Oliver’s own wizarding skills, or have him summon a familiar to the fore to do battle for him. Familiars share the same health and mana bar as Oliver and as a result cannot be relied on as fodder for strong attacks in place of Oliver himself as should a familiar die, Oliver will die too. Stamina is shown as the yellow circle around each familiar portraitHowever familiars have varied stats and resistances that can make them more useful depending on an enemy’s strengths and weaknesses and knowing which to use when is the key to success in Ni No Kuni’s battle system. A single familiar cannot be used overlong in one fight however because of the game’s stamina system. Once a familiar is summoned, its stamina will drain until it must be switched out to recharge. Familiars have their own abilities known as ‘tricks’ that are unique to them as well as their own equipment and accessories. Close attention must also be paid to the ‘creature cage’ in which familiars can be fed treats to increase desired stats. Once a familiar reaches a certain level, it is also possible to change their form completely via ‘metamorphosis’ which will start them back at level 1, but with increased potential for stat gains and new tricks to learn.AlchemyDuring his adventure Oliver will, with the help of a friend, learn the art of alchemy, allowing him to combine base ingredients with powerful results. Two forms of alchemizing are available. The first can be accomplished by following formulae given to Oliver when talking to various unassuming citizens of towns that can easily be missed. Care should be taken to talk to all citizens once the player has been introduced to alchemy. Second, the player can ‘mix and match’ by picking base ingredients from Oliver’s inventory and either hoping for a result, or knowing an exact recipe beforehand that will always produced a desired item. Such recipes can be found in the wizard’s companion, among other places.Release and Pre-Order InformationNi no Kuni was released in North America on January 22nd, 2013, exclusively for the PlayStation 3. In addition to having a collector's edition known as the “Wizards Edition," two retailers offered pre-order bonuses.Amazon offered the “Griffy” familiar to be used in game.Gamestop gave their customers an alternate metal game case with new art.However, if you were lucky enough to have gotten to pre-order the “Wizards Edition” you will be granted a treasure trove of extras. Level-5 adopted a tiered approach to offering awards in the “Wizards Edition,” where if more people pre-ordered, the more stuff everyone would receive at no additional cost. The “Wizards Edition” is as of now sold out and therefore all of the tiers of extras have been unlocked. Included therein...A Copy of Ni no Kuni: Wrath of the White WitchA 340 Page Hardcover book, which is a replica of the in-game spell-book known as The Wizards Companion, that contains a complete bestiary, description of Items, Spells, and a background of the world's history.An Exclusive CoinTwo audio tracks from the Official Game SoundtrackA plush doll of Oliver's in game companion DrippyTwo Exclusive Familiars: Golden Mite and Golden DrongoSet of 5 Ni no Kuni artwork cardsThe "Wizards Edition" was only offered on the Namco Store online and no more will be manufactured. Namco's "Wizards Edition" was oversold; however, those that reserved a copy and received a cancellation will receive a free copy of the collectors edition strategy guide.The game wasn't the only thing you could gotten extras for, had you pre-ordered. If you had pre-ordered the collector's edition strategy guide, you would have been rewarded the Golden Hurley familiar to be used in-game.SoundtrackCD Cover artworkThe original soundtrack was composed by Joe Hisaishi. A special music selection CD containing two audio tracks was included in the collector's edition of the game, the complete soundtrack is available for purchase at the Wayô Shop websiteDisk 1TrackTitle01Ni no Kuni: Dominion of the Dark Djinn - Main Theme02One Fine Morning03Motorville04The Accident05In Loving Memory of Allie06Drippy07Magic with Oomph08World Map09Ding Dong Dell -The Cat King's Castle-10Al Mamoon -Court of the Cowlipha-11Imperial March12Crisis13Tension14Battle15Shadar, the Dark Djinn16A Battle with Creatures17Labyrinth18The Lead-Up to the Decisive Battle19The Showdown with Shadar20Miracle -Reunion-21Kokoro no KakeraDisk 2TrackTitle01Ni no Kuni: Wrath of the White Witch - Main Theme02The Fairyground03Mummy's Tummy04Battle II05The Horror of Manna06Unrest07Blithe08Sorrow09The Zodiarchs10The Final Battle Against the White Witch11The Wrath of the White Witch12Kokoro no Kakera -Pieces of a Broken Heart- (English Version)DLCDraggle Familiar - On 2/12/2013 NamcoBandai released free DLC that allowed players to get a hold of an in game ticket that upon redemption awarded the player with the previously unobtainable "Draggle" familiar.From the EU PSN store a Gold Hurley familiar can also be downloaded for free which is similar to the regular Hurley familiar with slightly different tricks to learn.DLC and pre-order familiar tickets can be redeemed at the temple of trials once Oliver has participated in said trials.  </description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3579">Dragon Quest VIII: Journey of the Cursed King</game><game id="20836">Tales of Vesperia</game><game id="8825">Final Fantasy IX</game><game id="3966">Pokémon Red/Blue</game><game id="41088">Pokémon X/Y</game><game id="17905">PoPoLoCrois</game><game id="37268">Time and Eternity</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2412937-box_nnk.png</image></root>