<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33400</id><name>Forza Motorsport 4</name><description>OverviewForza Motorsport 4 is the latest installment in Turn 10 Studios' racing franchise, Forza Motorsport, and builds on improvements made in Forza Motorsport 3. The game features over 80 car manufacturers and +500 cars that you'll be able to drive in the game's single player World Tour mode or online during races that can support 16 players (which is twice the amount of the first three games). The game also features Kinect compatibility as well as the Top Gear license and some wacky new events such as car soccer and car bowling.SingleplayerThe new singleplayer mode is called World Tour. World Tour mode takes you to different locations. At each location a choice must be made for which event you want to participate in, much like the Season Play mode in Forza 3. These events will feature different racing modes, car classes and number of cars.When you reach a new level you can now choose from multiple cars instead of only a single car. This brings more variation to the campaign as it depends on your garage to choose your next event just like in the previous game. Turn 10 has further expanded this feature by integrating their DLC to appear as options in the gift menu when you download it.MultiplayerCar ClubsPlayers can create car clubs and let friends join their club. The car club features a shared garage where players can share their cars (including upgrades, paint jobs and tuning setups) with the members of the car club. The most dedicated clubs often use these shared garages to help perfect tuning setups across several drivers, so that they can be used to set times for in-game leaderboards. Some clubs may also choose to share their unicorn cars amongst themselves, for drivers who may not have them.Badges and TitlesMuch like in games such as Call of Duty, Forza lets you customize your online profile with badges and titles (mottos that go with your online profile). There are 400 different kinds of badges and both titles and badges are unlocked through career progression, driver affinity and by performing certain actions. Unlocking these titles can take some time, and some are extremely specific. For example, one of the badges challenges players to drive 1000 miles in a Ford Mustang.Rival ModeRival mode has the player challenge other players in different events to try and beat their times. There are 6 possible events: Community Monthly which groups all 5 other events and imposes special conditions such as no driver assist, Top Gear which are events designed by the Top Gear staff which usually stick with the theme of the show, Spec Hot Laps which is a time trial event where players are assigned one car and a track, Open Time Attack where players can choose their car, tune it and pin it against other player's times, Track Days which requires players to race around a track filled with slow moving cars (the main objective still being to get the best time, not to beat the slower cars), Autocross which requires players to go through gates to complete a lap and Drift where players drift around a track and are rewarded points. Events change every month.Players can pick a rival or from their friends list or from the online leaderboards. By beating their rival, the player is awarded xp and credits. It is possible to unlock everything in the game by just playing rival mode. Players face their rival's ghost and attempt to beat their time. The higher the rival is on the leaderboards, the more credits and xp the player will earn. If the rival is on the player's friends list, the player will be notified if they are beaten.Car AffinityCar Affinity is Forza 4's leveling system. Players do not level cars anymore, instead they level manufacturers. By being loyal to a manufacturer, the player earns xp by driving a manufacturer's car for a certain amount of miles which count towards the player's affinity level. XP leads to store discounts which can lead to certain parts becoming completely free and new titles and badges.  When the game released, the level cap was set at 150 and developers expected that less than 1% of the player base would reach the cap within 24 months of the release.  After hardcore fans were able to reach the cap in 4 months, though, the level cap was raised to 999 in a title update.Car List (534 on-disc + 130 DLC Cars = 664 Cars Total)Abarth1980 131 Rally Abarth Stradale2010 500 esseesseAcura2002 RSX Type-S2010 TSX V62001 Integra Type-R1997 NSX2005 NSX2008 #26 Andretti Green Racing ARX-01b2008 #66 de Ferran Motorsports ARX-01b2008 #15 Lowe's Fernandez Racing ARX-01b2009 #66 de Ferran Motorsports Jim Hall ARX-02a2009 #66 de Ferran Motorsports ARX-02aAlfa Romeo1965 Giulia Sprint GTA Stradale2008 MiTo2009 Brera Italia Independent2007 8C CompetizioneAMC1971 Javelin-AMXAMG Transport Dynamics2554 M12 FAV "Warthog" [Hidden Easter egg / Autovista only]Aston Martin1964 DB5 Vantage1977 V8 Vantage1958 DBR12001 V12 Vanquish2010 Rapide2005 DB9 Coupe2008 DBS2010 V12 Vantage2010 One-772006 #007 Aston Martin Racing DBR92008 #009 Aston Martin Racing DBR92009 #007 Aston Martin Lola2011 #06 Muscle Milk Aston Martin LolaAudi2009 Q7 V12 TDI2000 S42004 TT Coupe 3.2 quattro1995 RS2 Avant2004 S41983 Sport quattro2007 TT Coupe S-Line2003 RS62007 S52010 S42010 TT-RS Coupe2006 RS42009 RS62008 R82010 R8 Coupe 5.2 FSI quattro2009 R8 LMS2004 #8 Audi ABT TT-R2011 #02 Audi A4 Touring Car2011 #03 Audi A4 Touring Car2011 #04 Audi A4 Touring Car2011 #05 Audi A4 Touring Car2011 #06 Audi A4 Touring Car2006 #2 Audi Sport North America R82011 #4 Forza Motorsport R10 TDI2008 #2 Audi Sport North America R10 TDI2009 #2 Audi Sport Team Joest R15 TDIBentley2004 Continental GT2010 Continental Supersports2003 #7 Team Bentley Speed 8Bertone2010 MantideBMW1971 3.0 CSL1973 2002 Turbo1991 M3 E301988 M51986 M635CSi1981 M12009 135i Coupe1997 M32000 Z82002 Z3 M Coupe2005 M32003 M52008 Z4 M Coupe2011 Z4 sDrive35is2010 X6 M2011 X5 M2008 M32010 M6 Coupe2009 M52010 Z4 GT32005 #2 BMW M3 GTR2001 #6 Prototype Technology Group M3 GTR2009 #92 Rahal Letterman Racing M3 GT22010 #79 Jeff Koons BMW M3 GT2 Art Car1999 #15 BMW V12 LMRBugatti1992 EB110 SS2009 Veyron 16.4Buick1987 Regal GNXCadillac2004 CTS-V2009 CTS-V2011 CTS-V Coupe2002 #6 Team Cadillac Northstar LMP-02Chevrolet2011 Spark2011 Volt1979 Camaro Z281960 Corvette1970 El Camino SS 4541969 Camaro Z281970 Chevelle SS-4541964 Impala SS 4091970 Camaro Z281990 Camaro IROC-Z1970 Corvette ZR-11967 Corvette Sting Ray 4272002 Camaro 35th Anniversary SS2010 Cobalt SS Turbocharged1996 Corvette Grand Sport2010 Camaro SS2002 Corvette Z062010 Corvette Grand Sport2006 Corvette Z062009 Corvette ZR12011 #04 Chevrolet Racing Monte Carlo SS Stock Car2004 #3 Corvette Racing C5.R2006 #4 Corvette Racing C6.R2010 #89 Intersport Racing Oreca FLM092010 #55 Level 5 Motorsports Oreca FLM092010 #99 Green Earth Team Gunnar Oreca FLM09Chrysler2004 PT Cruiser GT2006 Crossfire SRT62008 300C SRT-8Citroën2011 C12009 C4 VTS2011 DS3De Tomaso1971 PanteraDeLorean1982 DMC-12Devon2010 GTXDodge1969 Charger R/T1970 Challenger R/T1969 Charger Daytona HEMI2006 Ram SRT102005 SRT4 ACR1996 Stealth R/T Turbo2006 Charger SRT82009 Challenger SRT81999 Viper GTS ACR2003 Viper SRT102008 Viper SRT10 ACR2003 Viper Competition Coupe2008 #2 Mopar Dodge Viper Competition Coupe2008 #11 Primetime Racing Group Viper Competition Coupe2003 #126 Team Zakspeed Viper GTS-R2000 #91 Team Oreca Dodge Viper GTS-REagle1998 Talon TSi TurboFerrari1969 Dino 246 GT1957 250 California1957 250 Testa Rossa1968 365 GTB/41964 250 GTO1991 512 TR1994 F355 Berlinetta2009 California2002 575M Maranello1984 GTO2004 612 Scaglietti1995 F355 Challenge1999 360 Modena1967 330 P42004 F4301987 F401995 F502006 599 GTB Fiorano2011 FF2010 458 Italia2011 599 GTO2002 Enzo Ferrari2006 #62 Risi Competizione F430GT2008 #90 Farnbacher Racing F430GT2010 #89 Hankook Team Farnbacher F430GT2010 #83 Risi Competizione F430GT2010 599XX2005 FXX1989 F40 Competizione1996 F50 GT1998 #12 Risi Competizione F333 SPFIAT2010 Punto Evo SPORTFord2011 Ka1978 Mustang King Cobra2009 Fiesta Zetec S1957 Thunderbird1973 Falcon GT XB2003 SVT Focus1970 Mustang Boss 4291971 Mustang Mach 11993 SVT Mustang Cobra R2006 Focus ST1992 Escort RS Cosworth2010 Fusion Sport2005 Mustang GT1987 Sierra Cosworth RS5002010 Taurus SHO2009 Focus RS2000 Mustang Cobra R2010 Shelby GT5001966 GT40 MkII2005 Ford GT1985 RS200 Evolution2001 #19 Mother Energy Racing Team FG Falcon2011 #5 Ford Performance Racing FG Falcon2011 #9 SP Tools Racing FG Falcon2011 #17 Dick Johnson Racing Team FG Falcon2011 #4 IRWIN Racing FG Falcon2011 #05 Ford Racing Fusion Stock Car2009 #40 Robertson Racing Ford GT Mk7GMC1991 SycloneGumpert2010 Apollo SHolden2009 HSV w4272011 #1 Toll Holden Racing Team Commodore VE2011 #11 Pepsi Max Crew Commodore VE2011 #33 Fujitsu Racing GRM Commodore VE2011 #88 TeamVOdafone Commodore VE2011 #8 Team BOC Commodore VEHonda2009 Fit Sport1994 Civic 1.5 VTi1999 Civic Si Coupe1995 CR-X Del Sol SiR1991 CR-X SiR2000 Prelude SiR2006 Civic Si Coupe2004 Civic Type-R2007 Civic Type-R1997 Civic Type-R2000 Integra Type-R2003 S20002010 Mugen Civic Type-R 3D1992 NSX-R2005 NSX-R2005 #18 TAKATA DOME NSXHummer2006 H1 AlphaHyundai2011 ix202003 Tuscani Elisa2010 Genesis Coupe2010 Rhys Millen Racing Genesis Coupe2010 Forza Motorsport Genesis CoupeInfiniti2003 G352008 G37 Coupe SportJaguar1961 E-type S11956 D-Type2010 XFR2009 XKR-S1993 XJ2202010 #33 RSR XKR GTJeep2009 Grand Cherokee SRT8Joss2010 JT1KIA2011 cee'd2010 Forte Koup SXKoenigsegg2002 CC8S2006 CCX2008 CCGTLamborghini1967 Miura P4001988 Countach LP5000 QV1997 Diablo SV2005 Murciélago2005 Gallardo2008 Reventón2006 Miura Concept1999 Diablo GTR2010 Murciélago LP 670-4 SV2011 Sesto ElementoLancia1974 Stratos HF Stradale1982 037 Stradale1992 Delta Integrale EVOLand Rover2008 Range Rover SuperchargedLexus2011 CT200h2003 IS3002002 SC4302006 IS3502009 IS-F2010 LF-A2008 #6 ENEOS SC4302008 #25 ECLIPSE ADVAN SC4302010 #1 PETRONAS TOM'S SC430Lotus1971 Elan Spirit1980 Espirit Turbo2005 Elise 111S1990 Carlton1999 Elise Sport2009 Evora2006 Exige Cup 2402002 Esprit V82009 2-Eleven2010 Evora Type 124 Endurance Race CarMaserati2006 GranSport2010 GranTurismo S2004 MC122005 #15 JMB Racing MC12Mazda1994 MX-5 Miata2005 Axela Sport 23S2001 Mazdaspeed Familia2007 MX-5 Roadster Coupe2010 MX-5 Superlight2001 Mazdaspeed Roadster1990 Savanna RX072004 RX-8 Mazdaspeed2009 Mazdaspeed 32010 Mazdaspeed 31997 RX-72008 Furai2009 #16 Dyson Racing B09/862010 #16 Dyson Racing B09/86McLaren1993 F12011 MP4-12C1997 F1 GT1997 #43 Team BMW McLaren F1 GTR1998 #41 Gulf Team Davidoff McLaren F1 GTRMercedes-Benz1954 300SL Gullwing Coupe2009 A200 Turbo Coupe1990 190E 2.5-16 Evolution II2004 C32 AMG2009 ML 63 AMG2003 CLK55 AMG Coupe2010 C63 AMG2010 SLK 55 AMG2010 E 63 AMG2010 CL 65 AMG2009 SL 65 AMG Black Series2011 SLS AMG2005 SLR2009 SLR Stirling Moss1998 AMG Mercedes CLK-GTR2008 Mercedes-AMG C-Class Touring CarMercury1970 Cougar EliminatorMINI2003 Cooper S2009 John Cooper WorksMitsubishi2003 Eclipse GTS1988 Starion ESI-R2010 Colt Ralliart1998 FTO GP Version R2006 Eclipse GT1995 Eclipse GSX1997 GTO1999 Lancer Evolution VI GSR2008 Lancer Evolution X GSR2006 Lancer Evolution IX MR2004 Lancer Evolution VIII MRMorgan2010 Aero SuperSportsMosler2010 MT900SNissan1970 Datsun 5102011 Micra2011 Leaf1969 Fairlady Z 4322009 Versa SL1971 Skyline 2000GT-R1994 240SX SE1992 Silvia CLUB K's1994 Silvia K's2007 Sentra SE-R Spec V1994 Fairlady Z Version S Twin Turbo2000 Silvia Spec-R2003 Skyline Coupe 350GT2003 FairLady Z1993 Skyline GT-R V-Spec1997 Skyline GT-R V-Spec2010 370Z2002 Skyline GT-R V-Spec II2010 GT-R SpecV1998 R3902003 #3 HASEMISPORT ENDLESS Z2005 #46 Dream Cube's ADVAN Z2003 #12 CALSONIC SKYLINE2008 #3 YellowHat YMS TOMICA GT-R2008 #24 WOODONE ADVAN Clarion GT-R2008 #23 XANAVI NISMO GT-R2010 #12 CALSONIC IMPUL GT-R1998 #32 NISSAN R390 GT1Oldsmobile1969 Hurst/Olds 442Opel2004 Speedster Turbo2003 #5 OPC TEAM PHOENIX Astra V8Pagani1999 Zonda C122009 Zonda Cinque Roadster2003 #17 Carsport America Zonda GTR2010 Zonda RPanoz2005 Esparante GTLM2005 #51 Panoz Esparante GTLM2003 #11 JML Team Panoz LMP-01Peugeot2011 1072011 308 GTI2007 207 RC2004 206 RC2010 RCZ2007 207 Super 20001993 #3 Peugeto Talbot Sport 905 EVO 1C2009 #9 Peugeot Sport Total 9082011 #10 Matmut-Oreca 908Plymouth1968 Barracuda Formula-S1971 Cuda 426 HemiPontiac1977 Firebird Trans Am1987 Firebird Trans Am GTA1969 Firebird Trans Am1973 Firebird Trans Am SD-4551969 GTO Judge2002 Firebird Trans Am Ram Air2009 Solstice GXP2006 GTO2009 G8 GXPRadical2011 SR8 RXRenault1980 5 Turbo2009 Twingo Renault Sport Cup2007 Clio RS 1972003 Sport Clio V62010 Megane RS 250Rossion2010 Q1RUF2011 Rt 12 SSaab1978 99 Turbo2002 9-3 Aero2008 9-3 Turbo XSaleen2000 S281 Supercab2000 S2812006 S281 E2010 S5S Raptor2004 S72003 #2 Konrad Motorsports S7RSaturn2006 ION Red Line2007 Sky Red LineSSC2010 Ultimate AeroScion2009 xD2005 tCSEAT2009 Ibiza CUPRA2003 Leon Cupra R2007 Leon CUPRA2010 Leon CUPRA R2007 Leon SupercupShelby1968 Mustang GT-500KR1999 Series 11965 Cobra 427 S/C1965 Cobra Daytona CoupeSpada Vetture Sport2010 Codatronca TSSpyker2010 C8 Laviolette LM85Subaru2005 Legacy B4 2.0 GT2010 Legacy B4 2.5GT1998 Impreza 22B STi2008 Impreza WRX STI2004 Impreza WRX STi2005 Impreza WRX STi2003 #77 CUSCO SUBARU ADVAN IMPREZASuzuki2002 Liana GLX2011 SX4 SportbackToyota2011 Aygo1969 2000GT2011 Prius1984 Celica Supra2008 Yaris S1989 MR2 SC1985 Sprinter Trueno GT Apex1992 Supra 2.0 GT Twin Turbo2002 MR-S2004 Altezza RS2002002 Soarer 430SCV2003 Celica SS-I1994 Celica GT-Four ST2051995 MR2 GT1998 Supra RZ2005 #6 EXXON Superflo Supra1999 #3 Toyota Motorsports GT-ONE TS020TVR2001 Tuscan S2005 Sagaris1998 Cerbera Speed 12Vauxhall2011 Agila2009 Corsa VXR2006 Astra VXR2005 Monaro VXR2004 VX220 Turbo2010 Insignia VXRVolkswagen2011 Fox1984 Rabbit GTI1992 Golf GTI 16v Mk22004 Beetle1998 GTI VR6 Mk31995 Corrado VR62003 Bora VR62008 Touareg R502006 Golf GTI2009 Scirocco GT2010 Golf GTI Mk62003 Golf R322010 Golf RVolvo1983 242 Turbo Evolution2009 C30 R-Design2004 S60 R2011 S60 R-DesignWiesmann2010 GT MF5DLC  Bonus Car PacksPorscheFinally coming back to Forza Motorsport, and first time in Forza Motorsport 4, the Porsche car pack features 30 Porsches old and new, new events and more achievements for you to collect. It was released May 22nd 2012.Note: If you're a VIP member (Bought the Limited Collectors Edition or the VIP pass) be sure to purchase it through the in-game marketplace and NOT the Xbox live marketplace since you will get a $5 (400 Microsoft points) discount, from 1600 points (regular member) to 1200 points (VIP member).2010 Porsche 911 Sport Classic2010 Porsche Boxster S1995 Porsche 911 GT22011 Porsche No. 54 Black Swan Racing 911 GT3 Cup1987 Porsche 9592004 Porsche 911 GT3 (996)2012 Porsche Cayenne Turbo2008 Porsche No.2 Gruppe Orange Racing 911 GT3 Cup2005 ALMS GT. Porsche #31 Petersen-White Lightning 911 GT3-RSR (996)1970 Porsche 914/62007 Porsche 911 GT3 RS2011 No.45 Porsche Flying Lizard GT3-RSR1955 Porsche 550 Spyder1987 Porsche #17 AG Racing 962c2007 Porsche No. 80 Flying Lizard 911 GT3-RSR2008 Porsche #16 Dyson Racing RS Spyder Evo2010 Porsche Panamera Turbo2011 Porsche No.17 Team Falken 911 GT3-RSR2012 Porsche Cayman R1989 Porsche 944 Turbo2003 Porsche Carrera GT1982 Porsche 911 Turbo 3.31998 Porsche No. 26 AG 911 GT-1-982007 Porsche 911 GT3 (997)2005 Porsche #66 AXA Racing 911 GT3 Cup (996)2007 Porsche 911 Turbo (997)2011 Porsche No.23 Alex Job Racing 911 GT3 Cup2008 Porsche No.7 Penske Racing RS Spyder Evo1973 Porsche 911 Carrera RS2012 Porsche 911 GT2 RSNovember Speed Car Pack (Included in the first Season Pass)2012 Lamborghini Aventador LP700-42012 Aston Martin Virage2011 #2 Audi Sport Team Joest R15++ TDI2011 Audi RS3 Sportback1957 Chevrolet Bel Air2012 Dodge Charger SRT82011 Ferrari #62 Risi Competizione F458 Italia2013 Ford Focus ST1992 GMC Typhoon2011 Volkswagen Scirocco RDecember IGN Car pack (Included in the first Season Pass)2011 Monster Sport Suzuki SX42011 Mazda RX-8 R32011 Ford F-150 SVT Raptor1967 Chevrolet Chevelle SS-3961977 Ford Escort RS18001981 Volkswagen Scirocco S1986 Alfa Romeo Spider Quadrifoglio Verde1988 Pontiac Fiero GT2010 Maserati GranTurismo MC GT41957 Maserati 300 SJanuary Jalopnik Car Pack (Included in the first Season Pass)2012 Pagani Huayra2012 Honda Civic Si Coupe2011 Lamborghini #08 West Yokohama Gallardo LP560-42011 Honda #33 Level 5 Motorsports Lola2011 Audi RS52000 Fiat Coupe 20V Turbo1996 Chevrolet Impala SS1986 Dodge Shelby Omni GLHS1973 Ford Pinto1970 Alfa Romeo MontrealFebruary ALMS Car pack (Included in the first Season Pass)2011 #2 Audi Sport North America R18 TDI1991 Mazda #55 Team Mazdaspeed 787B2011 Bentley Platinum Motorsports Continental GT2010 Dodge Quinton "Rampage" Jackson Challenger SRT81986 #2 Audi Sport quattro S12011 Panoz #050 Panoz Racing Abruzzi1992 Alfa Romeo 155 Q41995 Ford Mustang Cobra R2011 Holden HSV GTS2011 Volkswagen Polo GTIMarch Pirelli Car Pack (Included in the first Season Pass)2011 Aston Martin V12 Zagato (Villa d’Este)1971 Ferrari #2 Ferrari Automobili 312 P2012 Ultima GTR1969 Chevrolet Nova SS 3962010 Renault Clio RS1966 Ford Country Squire1995 BMW 850CSi1986 Alfa Romeo GTV-62011 Wiesmann GT MF51969 Chevrolet Corvair MonzaApril Alpinestars Car Pack (Included in the first Season Pass)2011 Mercedes-Benz #35 Black Falcon SLS AMG GT32011 Aston Martin #009 Aston Martin Racing AMR One2012 Jaguar XKR-S1995 BMW M52011 Maserati Quattroporte Sport GT S1985 Mazda RX-7 GSL-SE1972 Mercedes-Benz 300 SEL 6.31959 Cadillac Eldorado Biarritz Convertible2012 Scion tC1997 Volvo 850 RMay Top Gear Car Pack2012 Hennessey Venom GT1992 Mitsubishi Galant VR-42011 Ford Transit SuperSportVan2012 Jeep Wrangler Rubicon2012 Chrysler 300 SRT81990 Subaru Legacy RS2012 Smart ForTwo1977 AMC Pacer X1966 Lotus Cortina1965 Austin-Healey 3000 Mk. IIIJune Meguiar’s Car Pack2011 Chevrolet #4 Corvette Racing ZR11959 BMW 5071940 Ford De Luxe Coupe2011 Aston Martin Cygnet1958 MG MGA Twin-Cam1997 Maserati Ghibli Cup2012 Mercedes-Benz C63 AMG Black Series1987 RUF CTR Yellowbird1992 Toyota Celica GT-Four RC ST1851963 Volkswagen BeetleAmerican Muscle Car pack (Comes with the Limited Collectors Edition)1965 Pontiac GTO1968 Pontiac Firebird1970 Buick GSX1970 Dodge Cornet Super Bee1966 Chevrolet Nova SS1969 Shelby GT500 428CJ1971 Plymouth GTX 426 Hemi1967 Dodge Cornet W0231968 Dodge Dart HEMI Super Stock1964 Ford Fairlane ThunderboltVIP Car Pack (Comes with the Limited Collectors Edition)2011 Bugatti Veyron Super Sport2011 Ferrari 458 Challenge2011 Lamborghini Gallardo LP570-4 Superleggera2010 Noble M6002011 RUF Rt 12 RThe limited quantity Launch Bonus car pack available for fans who order Forza 4 early1965 Ford Mustang GT Coupe2011 Koenigsegg Agera1997 Lexus SC3002011 RUF RGT-82011 Tesla Roadster SportThe Limited Edition will also come with the recently unveiled 2012 BMW M5BMW Art Car Pack1981 BMW M1 Design Art Car2008 BMW M3 E92 Design Art Car2012 BMW M5 Design Art Car2010 BMW M6 Coupe Design Art Car2008 BMW Z4 M Coupe Design Art CarRetailer Specific Pre-Order Cars2011 Subaru WRX STi (Amazon.com)2011 BMW 1 Series M Coupe (Best Buy)2011 Alfa Romeo Giulietta Quadrifoglio Verde (GameStop)2011 Honda CR-Z EX (Target, Microsoft Store)2011 MINI John Cooper Works Clubman (Wal-mart)Autovista Warthog ExperienceAt PAX Prime 2011, 343 Industries and Turn 10 announced the addition of the famous vehicle from the Halo series, the Warthog. Just like any other car in Auto Vista, players are able to completely interact with it and view points of interest. However, it is not drivable. In addition to Jeremy Clarkson commenting on the Warthog's fake statistics, Jen Taylor, the voice of Cortana, lends her talents to give an overview of the vehicle to players and talk about it's history. The model for the Warthog was provided to Turn 10 by 343 Industries, and it is the same model that appears in Halo 4.TracksThe first track revealed for the game is known as The Bernese Alps, located in Switzerland. It is a fictional track based on a real location. A backstory has been created for this track in Forza Motorsport 4 to create authenticity for it's existence.Amalfi (Italy)Rally di Positano Full CircuitRally di Positano Full Circuit ReverseAutodromo Internazionale del Mugello (Italy)Full CircuitClub CircuitBenchmark High Speed Ring (USA) [DLC / FREE / Code comes with every new FM4 copy]SpeedwaySpeedway ReverseBernese Alps (Switzerland)Festival CircuitFestival Circuit ReverseStadtplatz CircuitStadtplatz Circuit ReverseClub CircuitClub Circuit ReverseCircuit de Catalunya (Spain)Full CircuitNational CircuitSchool CircuitFujimi Kaido (Japan)Full CircuitFull Circuit ReverseStage AStage A ReverseStage BStage B ReverseStage CStage C ReverseStage DStage D ReverseOld Hill ClimbOld DownhillNew Hill ClimbNew DownhillHockenheimring (Germany)Full CircuitNational CircuitShort CircuitDrag ¼ MileIndianapolis Motor Speedway (USA)SpeedwayRoad CourseInfineon Raceway (USA)Long CourseIndy Racing League CircuitNASCAR CircuitDrag ¼ MileLe Mans Circuit de La Sarthe (France)Full CircuitOld Mulsanne CircuitMaple Valley Raceway (USA)Full CircuitFull Circuit ReverseShort CircuitShort Circuit ReverseMazda Raceway Laguna Seca (USA)Full CircuitMontserrat (Spain)Camino Viejo de Montserrat Full CircuitCamino Viejo de Montserrat Full Circuit ReverseCamino Viejo de Montserrat Short CircuitCamino Viejo de Montserrat Short Circuit ReverseCamino Viejo de Montserrat Mini CircuitCamino Viejo de Montserrat Mini Circuit ReverseCamino Viejo de Montserrat Extreme CircuitIberian International Circuit Full CircuitIberian International Circuit Full Circuit ReverseIberian International Circuit Short CircuitIberian International Circuit Short Circuit ReverseIberian International Circuit Mini CircuitIberian International Circuit Mini Circuit ReverseLadera Test Track Full CircuitLadera Test Track Full Circuit ReverseLadera Test Track Short CircuitLadera Test Track Short Circuit ReverseLadera Test Track Mini CircuitLadera Test Track Mini Circuit ReverseNürburgring (Germany)Full CircuitShort CircuitNordschleifeRoad America (USA)Full CircuitRoad Atlanta (USA)Full CircuitClub CircuitSebring International Raceway (USA)Full CircuitShort CircuitClub CircuitSilverstone Racing Circuit (England)Grand Prix CircuitInternational CircuitNational CircuitSuzuka Circuit (Japan)Full CircuitEast CircuitWest CircuitTopGear Test Track (England)Full CircuitOuter LoopOuter Loop ReverseEast CircuitEast Circuit ReverseWest CircuitWest Circuit ReverseDrag ¼ MileDrag ½ MileDrag MileSoccer Field [DLC / FREE / Code comes with every new FM4 copy]Tsukuba Circuit (Japan)Full CircuitShort CircuitTwin Ring Motegi (Japan)Full CircuitEast CircuitWest CircuitSuper SpeedwayKinectKinect IntegrationThe game uses Kinect for both in game and for menu navigation.Hyperlinks - Forza is known for a rather deep menu structure which is where Kinect hyperlinks come in: the user can, from anywhere in the menu such as quick race, jump to a specific screen by voice commands such as "Xbox, Auction House".Steering - Basically, it's driving with an air wheel. This can be done with two players simultaneously, and is largely intended for a more casual experience. Throttle and brakes are both managed by the game.Head tracking - With head tracking a player can look around in the cockpit mode just by moving his head. This makes it possible to look into a corner or glance into a rear view mirror. The sensitivity of this feature can be adjusted by the player.AutovistaAutovista allows the player to walk around cars and view them in more detail using both the regular Xbox 360 controller and Kinect. The doors and lids of the car can be opened and the player can get into car to take a closer look at the interior or to start the car and listen to the engine. More information about specific features of the car are available in textual and audio format. For example, by selecting a part of the car such as the hood, the hood will open to reveal the engine and facts about it. Not all cars featured in the game are available in this mode.PartnershipsTop GearTop Gear has been seamlessly integrated into Forza 4. Top Gear is in the single player as well as in the multiplayer. The test track from the popular television show is in the game, and there is also an option to use the Top Gear studio as a menu background. Where the Top Gear license really comes to life however is in AutoVista. Here, each car is presented by Top Gear host Jeremy Clarkson. He first says the name of the car before delving into further detail. Clarkson wrote what he wanted to say about each car in the game before recording the dialogue that is completely unedited, leading to things such as Clarkson talking about how McLaren makes weaker cars than Bugatti.American Le MansFor this installment of Forza Motorsport Turn 10 partnered with the American Le Mans series to bring new cars and tracks to the game. The partnership will bring 26 cars and Sebring, Road Atlanta, Road America, Mazda Raceway Laguna Seca as tracks. Players will also be able to participate in community events inspired upon the American Le Mans series and watch the actual race events on ESPN3 on their Xbox.Save Game ImportingForza 4 lets you import your save game from Forza 3, giving you access to tuning setups, paint jobs and some cars you owned in the previous game. Not everything will be imported (not all your cars for example) and based on how you played Forza 3, you will also be gifted several community items. Importing an older save can immediately unlock the Unicorn Hunter achievement, for the Lamborghini Gallardo Superleggera is considered a unicorn in Forza 4, but could be bought normally in Forza 3.Limited EditionA limited edition of Forza Motorsport 4 was released for $79.99 MSRP. The following items are included:Forza Motorsport 4 Limited EditionSteelbook DVD CaseAn additional 25 cars96-page bookVinyl Sticker SetSeason PassSimilar to other popular games, Forza Motorsport 4 offers a season pass for $30. The season pass includes all Forza Motorsport DLC car packs released in the six months following the game's November 2011 release, at a 30% discount compared to buying them all individually.  The larger Porsche expansion pack, as well as the two car packs released after April 2012, are not included in the season pass.DemoA demo was made available on XBox Live Marketplace starting October 3, 2011. The demo is based on the E3 2011 demo and features the new Bernese Alps track. The cars and modes featured in the demo are:Quick Race1970 Mercury Cougar Eliminator2011 Subaru WRX STI2010 Ferrari 458 ItaliaRivals ModeRound the Mountain (2009 Pagani Zonda Cinque Roadster)Blitz Pass (2012 BMW M5)Alpine Rush (2010 Ferrari 458 Italia)Xbox 360 Game InstallationWhen installed on the Xbox 360 Hard Drive, the game takes up 10.3GB of space. The first disc comes in at 7.6GB while the second disc, which contains extra cars, comes in at 2.8GB. There load times are significantly reduced when the game is installed.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21790">Gran Turismo 5</game><game id="32253">SHIFT 2: Unleashed</game><game id="20729">GRID</game><game id="25225">Need for Speed: SHIFT</game><game id="34542">F1 2011</game><game id="25985">F1 2010</game><game id="36993">Project CARS</game><game id="36977">RACE Injection</game><game id="27298">rFactor 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1974939-box_forza4.png</image></root>