<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33408</id><name>Revenge of the Titans</name><description>DevelopmentLast stand against a TitanRevenge of the Titans was developed by indie British studio Puppy games and was released as a playable beta download on May 24, 2010. Players who pre-ordered the game had the chance to play the beta version of the game as updates were constantly being released. During the time of the second Humble Bundle, the game was in its beta stage and later gave purchasers access to the full Steam game. It received notable publicity for its involvement in the Second Humble Bundle, featuring alongside Braid, Machinarium, Osmos, and Cortex Command. The game's visual style is largely rooted in the developer's retro arcade sensibilities, which has become popular among developers of late.GameplayRD ScreenGameplay is centered around constructing and commanding ground forces in increasingly massive battles across the solar system, and is high paced. Players can invest in RD to discover new technologies, such as blaster turrets, rocket launchers, laser cannons, explosives, barricades, shield generators, refineries and reactors. Enemies start off by following a strict path, but later on, will attack from all directions and will take any path needed to get to your base.Mission SelectResources by setting up refineries around crystals. You can also collect various power ups as they pop up on the screen, with various effects such as temporary increase in the turrets fire power, or freezing the Titans for a few seconds.The final stages of the game pivot around invading the Titan alien invaders' own home moon, Titan, and defeating them once and for all.The gameplay depends on your ability to optimize your tower, support tower, upgrade choices.BuildingsRefiningNameDescriptionCostShieldsEffectRefineryGenerates a constant flow of money when placed next to a mineral deposit.2505Extracts $10 every second.ReprocessorIncreases the money output of nearby Refineries.7503Adds 20% money from Refineries.CollectorIncreases the extraction rate of nearby Refineries.5003Adds 1 Refinery extraction rate.TurretsNameDescriptionCostShieldsDamageFire RateAmmoReloadBlasterFires individual blaster shots. Does not pierce armored enemies.2503424-48 per minute1010Heavy BlasterThe middle-tier version of the Blaster. Pierces lightly armored enemies.5003624-48 per minute810Blast CannonThe most powerful version of the Blaster. Pierces heavily armored enemies.7503824-48 per minute610Multi-BlasterA version of the Blaster with a very high rate of fire and a large ammo clip. Does not pierce armored enemies.75034180-540 per minute2020Spreader CannonFire a group of cannon rounds in a fan-like formation to damage and possibly stun multiple enemies. Does not pierce armored enemies.50034x518-30 per minute715Assault CannonA version of the Spreader Cannon with upgraded damage and area of effect. Pierces lightly armored enemies.100038x718-30 per minute620Heavy WeaponsNameDescriptionCostShieldsDamageFire RateAmmoReloadRocketsFires an explosive rocket with a very large area of effect. Can not target enemies at close proximity. Can damage friendly buildings.150032415 per minute530LaserFire a laser beam that can damage multiple enemies with a single straight shot. Can target flying enemies. Available in limited quantities per level.1500320-16012-20 per minute530DisruptorDeals heavy damage to all nearby enemies in one devastating blast.150033212 per minute330ExplosivesAll Explosives can damage friendly buildings and are available in limited quantities per level.NameDescriptionCostDamageBlast RadiusUsesAvailabilityMinesAn explosive device that is triggered by enemy contact.251216120 per levelCluster MinesLess powerful than Mines, but grouped together, four per cluster.7568410 per levelBlast MineA very powerful explosive device. Clicking on Blast Mines begins a 5 second countdown to detonation.100168015 per levelRoboticsNameDescriptionCostShieldsProductionDroid FactoryProduces up to six droids, which attack small enemies.100051 droid every 7 secondsTank FactoryProduces up to six tanks, which attack large enemies.250051 tank every 7 secondsRepair DronesProduces repair drones, which repair damaged buildings.250051 drone every 10 secondsMisc.NameDescriptionCostShieldsEffectCapacitorDamages nearby enemies with the click of the mouse, rather than firing automatically. Can target invisible enemies.7503DecoyAttracts nearby enemies. Useful for keeping Titans away from the HQ. Available in limited quantities per level.15003TanglewebEnemy movement is hampered through Tanglewebs. Available in limited quantities per level.503Availability - 20 per level.Shield GeneratorImproves the shields of nearby buildings.25003Adds 1 to Shields.ScarecrowUsed to keep enemies away from an area.2503Cloaking DeviceRenders nearby buildings invisible to enemies.7503Add-OnsNameDescriptionCostShieldsEffectScannerIncreases the range of nearby turrets.5003Adds 1 turret range.Cooling TowerIncreases the Fire Rate of nearby turrets.2503Adds 1 Fire Rate.ReactorIncreases the Damage of nearby turrets. Can enhance nearby Robotics factories.2503Adds 1 Damage.BatteryIncreases the Ammo capacity of nearby turrets.2503Adds 1 Ammo.ReloaderDecreases the Reload time of nearby turrets.2503Adds 1 Reload.BarricadesAll Barricades are available in limited quantities per level.NameDescriptionCostStrengthAvailabilityConcrete BarricadeImpedes the advancement of Titans.101240 per levelSteel Barricade50% stronger than Concrete Barricades.201830 per levelTitanium Barricade33% stronger than Steel Barricades.302420 per levelNanomesh BarricadeAt 25% stronger than Titanium Barricades, Nanomesh is the toughest Barricade material.403010 per levelSystem RequirementsMinimumRecommendedOperating System: Windows XP or laterProcessor: 1.8GHz single coreMemory: 512MB RAMHard Disk Space: 120MBVideo Card: OpenGL 1.3+, 128MB video memorySound Card: StereoOperating System: Windows XP or laterProcessor: 2GHz Dual-CoreMemory: 750MB RAMHard Disk Space: 120MBVideo Card: OpenGL 1.3+, 256MB video memorySound Card: Stereo</description><genres><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25709">Plants vs. Zombies</game><game id="9376">Darwinia</game><game id="23102">South Park Let's Go Tower Defense Play!</game><game id="35676">Two Worlds II Castle Defense</game><game id="22139">Desktop Tower Defense</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/15/155745/2168070-box.png</image></root>