<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33431</id><name>Modern Combat: Domination</name><description>OverviewModern Combat: Domination is a team-based first person shooter from developer Gameloft. The game pits Special Forces against Mercenaries and is primarily a 16-player online shooter, although it can be played offline with AI bots.The game rewards the player's actions with money, which is earned by getting kills, completing objectives, and finishing matches. Each time a player enters a game, they have to buy their equipment for the round using the money they've earned, choosing a primary weapon, grenades, and armor. There is no health regeneration, and no health packs.Game ModesModern Combat: Domination has six different game modes:DeathmatchTeam DeathmatchDomination - (a Conquest game mode)Boom  Bust - (an Assault game mode)Escort - (one player is randomly assigned as the "escort," and all his teammates must help him escape the level. If the escort dies, the round is over.)Extraction - (a briefcase is spawned in the level, and one team must retrieve it and bring it back to their spawn point.)Note: Boom  Bust, Escort, and Extraction modes feature No Respawns.MapsThere are five maps in Modern Combat: Domination. Deathmatch, Team Deathmatch, and Domination can be played in all the maps, while Boom  Bust, Escort, and Extraction are map-specific.MapDeathmatchTeam DeathmatchDominationBoom  BustEscortExtractionSandstormXXXXThe HideoutsXXXXSouksXXXXHeadquartersXXXXFactoryXXXX</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="30185">Blacklight: Tango Down</game><game id="11339">Counter-Strike: Source</game><game id="30478">Breach</game><game id="30196">SOCOM 4: U.S. Navy SEALs</game><game id="21116">MAG</game><game id="35307">Gotham City Impostors</game><game id="8266">Tactical Ops: Assault on Terror</game><game id="11663">Half-Life: Counter-Strike</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/6/63119/1659197-moderncombatdomination.jpg</image></root>