<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33588</id><name>Embric of Wulfhammer's Castle</name><description>SummaryAfter a bit of backstory, the player assumes the role of the Duchess of Elstwhere as she is en route to the Castle Wulfhammer to be married.  Once there, the game allows the player to roam around and meet the Awesome Fellowship, save for the one she is engaged to, Embric, who is out adventuring.   As she waits for Embric to return, the Duchess will get to know the people who inhabit the castle and the surrounding area.  CharactersAs much of the game is centered around character development, these descriptions contain minimal spoilers. The Duchess of ElstwhereAt the start of the game, little is known about the player character, except that her uncle was a greedy and unpopular king, until he was overthrown. She is to be married as a means of bringing Embric into the royal family.   EmbricOften viewed as the leader of the Awesome Fellowship, Lord Embric is a typical hero, using lots and lots of swords to win the day.  He is not in his castle when the Duchess arrives.  Louni QuickfingersAs the name suggests, Lady Louni is a quick and stealthy rogue, allegedly capable of looting a corpse before it even hits the ground.  She is not fond of anyone snooping around in her room or touching her possessions.   Falwithwier WindgraceLady Falwithwier is an elf, and a powerful user of magic.  She is also quick to anger, so the Duchess must tread lightly to stay on her good side.  The Good DwarfNot much is known about the Good Dwarf, as his thick accent makes it hard for the others to understand him.  He spends time in the basement, smelting metal and brewing alcohol simultaneously.  AliceShe is assigned to be the Duchess's personal maid upon arrival at Castle Wulfhammer.  She has a reputation for breaking things due to her rare (for a maid) strength, but is always there to help the Duchess out.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="27673">Eternal Filena</game><game id="294">Summon Night: Swordcraft Story</game><game id="14817">Summon Night: Swordcraft Story 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/80354/1666441-carmina1.jpg</image></root>