<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33797</id><name>Gemini Rue</name><description>OverviewDelta-Six.Set in two different locations, the story unfolds around two protagonists, Azriel Odin and Delta-Six. Azriel, an ex-assassin turned cop, finds himself under the perpetual rains of the planet Barracus, in the Gemini system. He is looking for his long lost brother in a city ruled by an evil crime syndicate called the Boryokudan.Delta-Six is trapped in a stellar prison, where people erase minds and shape inmates into renewed citizens. He struggles to regain his memory and must figure a way out. As the two stories proceed, both will unlock mysteries to discover a bigger picture.Gemini Rue is mostly played as a point and click adventure. The two main protagonists can talk to people, investigate or interact with objects and people, and combine them with the items they have handy. The game also offers shoot-out sections that require timed shots in order to kill assailants. Here, there is also an option to take a deep breath to focus an attack and land a headshot. Usually an action sequence will be preceded by an autosave, just in case the player dies.On April 11th, 2013, the game will be released on iOS devices for $4.99, though it will initially be priced at $3.99 as a special promotion.FeaturesOver 60 hand-drawn backgrounds.A film noir atmosphere.A gripping sci-fi mystery.DVD-style commentary track for added replay value, further enhancing the cinematic feel of the game. This also explains a lot of transitions and features blooper reels.PC System RequirementsOperating System: Windows XP / Vista / 7Processor: Pentium 4 1.6 GHzRAM Memory: 1 GBGraphics Card: 128 MB (GeForce 5900 or better)Other InfoAvailable for purchase from the developer's official website at http://www.wadjeteyegames.com/gemini-rue.html or on Steam. There is also a free demo available.TriviaThe labels on the contraband boxes inside the burned orphanage are actually references to classic adventure games, as is also indicated by the contents of the boxes and Sayuri's dialogue when each box is activated:PQ1 = Police Quest 1 ("It's full of police badges, equipment, and evidence.")SQ2 = Space Quest 2 ("It's full of some kind of space gear, helmets, and rays.")LSL5 = Leisure Suit Larry 5 ("It's full of... I'd rather not say.")MI2 = Monkey Island 2 (It's full of pegs, hooks, and dolls.")</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10915">Beneath a Steel Sky</game><game id="13950">DreamWeb</game><game id="2800">The Shivah</game><game id="1066">Flashback: The Quest for Identity</game><game id="8175">Blackwell Unbound</game><game id="24709">Goin' Downtown</game><game id="2564">Overclocked</game><game id="36748">Blackwell Deception</game><game id="19852">The Blackwell Legacy</game><game id="37891">Da New Guys: Day of the Jackass</game><game id="37223">Resonance</game><game id="39355">Primordia</game><game id="6355">Neuromancer</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3699/1780392-gemini_rue.png</image></root>