<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33862</id><name>War of the Dead</name><description>OverviewShiryou Sensen: War of the Dead, a 1987 title developed by Fun Factory and published by Victor Music Industries for the MSX2, PC-88 and PC Engine platforms, is considered the first true survival horror game. Designed by Katsuya Iwamoto, the game is a horror action RPG revolving around a female SWAT member Lila rescuing survivors in an isolated monster-infested town and bringing them to safety in a church. The plot later involves a portal to another world and the family that has secretly protected it for generations.GameplayIt has open environments like Dragon Quest and real-time side-view battles like Zelda II, though War of the Dead departs from other RPGs with its dark and creepy atmosphere expressed through the storytelling, graphics, and music, while the gameplay lacks a leveling system and features side-scrolling shooter based combat with limited ammunition for each firearm, forcing the player to search for ammo and often run away from monsters in order to conserve ammo, though the player could punch or use a knife if out of ammo. The game also features a limited item inventory and crates to store items, and introduces a day-night cycle, where it becomes dark at night, the player can sleep to recover health, and a record is kept of how many days the player has survived.In 1988, War of the Dead Part 2 for the MSX2 and PC-88 abandoned the RPG elements of its predecessor, such as random encounters, and instead adopted action-adventure elements from Metal Gear while retaining the horror atmosphere of its predecessor.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16241">Zelda II: The Adventure of Link</game><game id="15120">Sweet Home</game><game id="16305">Dragon Warrior</game><game id="10041">Laplace no Ma</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/97089/1684417-wardeadcover.png</image></root>