<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>33886</id><name>Muchi Muchi Pork! &amp; Pink Sweets</name><description>A region-free compilation featuring ports of 2006's Pink Sweets ~Ibara Sore Kara~ and 2007's Muchi Muchi Pork!  The compilation includes in addition to the original versions of the games Ver 1.01 modes tweaked to be easier and special arrange modes. The first print also includes a DLC card allowing players to download Muchi Muchi Pork! Matsuri Version, a special crossover version of Muchi Muchi Pork! with the bosses from Pink Sweets. The limited edition includes a 2 disc soundtrack for both games in the compilation.  Modes Muchi Muchi Pork! ArcadeThe original Muchi Muchi Pork!.Muchi Muchi Pork! Arcade Ver 1.01 A slightly tweaked version of Muchi Muchi Pork!. Changes: The lard shot drains the lard gauge at a slower pace.The lard gauge fills faster.To reach the second loop, the player only needs to 1CC the the first loop instead of clearing it on one life.In the second loop, extends are given the same way as in the first loop. Muchi Muchi Pork! Arrange A heavily altered version of Muchi Muchi Pork!. Changes:The hitbox is visible.The lard shot doesn't require lard meter, and slows down enemy bullets it touches.Bombs turn bullets into gold medals instead of pigs.There's a counter that fills as gold medals and pigs are collected. When the counter hits 10,000, the player enters fever standby mode. In this mode, the lard shot causes bullets it touches to split into multiple smaller bullets. The counter stays at 10,000 until the player is hit by a bullet or presses the bomb button. When one of these two things happens, fever mode is activated, causing all on-screen bullets to turn into gold medals, and the counter to start dropping. When it reaches 0, fever mode is deactivated. Getting hit before the counter has reached 0 makes it instantly jump to 0. Muchi Muchi Pork! Matsuri VersionA version of Muchi Muchi Pork! in which every regular boss fight  is followed by a fight against a boss from Pink Sweets. Pink Sweets ~Ibara Sore Kara~ ArcadeThe original Pink Sweets.  Pink Sweets ~Ibara Sore Kara~ Arcade Ver 1.01A slightly tweaked version of Pink Sweets. Changes:It is possible to activate a Rose Cracker before it's fully charged, but doing so will cause it to last shorter.It is possible to have up to three Rose Hips instead of two.  Respawning is quicker.Enemy health is reduced.The rank increases at a slower pace. Pink Sweets ~Ibara Sore Kara~ Arrange A heavily altered version of Pink Sweets. Changes:The hitbox is visible.Respawning is quicker.The rose cracker turns enemy lasers and bullets it touches into medals.Holding the rose cracker button releases a surge gun. This costs one rose hip.Aside from rose medals, there are no items.Killing enemies with a rose cracker or a surge gun increases a score multiplier, which maxes out at 64.Extends are given based on score.</description><genres><genre id="15">Compilation</genre><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="32547">Battle Bakraid</game><game id="22919">Battle Garegga</game><game id="31088">Armed Police Batrider</game><game id="22956">Ibara</game><game id="34124">Ibara Kuro: Black Label</game><game id="34268">Mushihime-sama Futari Black Label</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2291763-box_mmpps.png</image></root>