<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34035</id><name>Angry Birds Rio</name><description>OverviewThe latest of the long running series Angry Birds makes it's way to the continent of South America. Featuring familiar characters from the animated film Rio; the game takes place in the tropical hotspot Rio de Janeiro. Angry Birds Rio currently features six chapters that each contain 30 levels. In Rio, the objectives slightly differ from defeating the menacing green piggies of prior Angry Birds titles. In contrast, the first chapter tasks the player with freeing various native exotic birds, while the second has you attacking evil marmosets in a jungle environment. Another major difference from past titles is that Rio features a unique and challenging boss fight. Developer Rovio Mobile has promised additional content in the upcoming months leading to the films worldwide release.In October 2011, the Mighty Eagle add-on was made available for in-app purchase on iOS versions of the game. This adds an additional challenge to each level where the player attempts to achieve complete destruction. It also allows the player to skip a level every hour.ReceptionAngry Birds has been met with critical acclaim, which is especially surprising as it is a licensed title. Touch Arcade noted that, "Angry Birds Rio is anything but a quick cash in". While Slide to Play remarked, "It is a textbook example of how to seamlessly blend a game with a movie, and with additional levels on the way, it's a must play for longtime fans as well as newcomers". Angry Birds Rio currently averages 5 stars on the Itunes App Store and an 89% on Metacritic.ChaptersSmugglers' DenJungle EscapeBeach VolleyCarnival UpheavalAirfield ChaseSmugglers' PlaneAchievements1. Breakout!All warehouse levels cleared2. Jungle FeverAll jungle levels cleared3. Warehousing SkillsEarn 3 stars in all the warehouse levels4. Master of the JungleEarn 3 stars in all of the jungle levels5. StellarvoreEarn 3 stars on all levels6. Marmoset TerminatorHit 2,800 marmosets7. Flower Power100 flowers destroyed8. A Star is Born40 stars earned in total9. Rising Star100 stars earned in total10. Scrambled EggsWhite bird unlocked11. Birds of a FeatherBlue and Jewel unlocked12. Pineapple PuristCollect all pineapples13. Banana FanaticCollect all bananas14. Dedicated PlayerPlay for 2 hours15. Credit Where Credit is DueCredits viewed from beginning to end16. Friendly FireHit a bird with another bird17. SniperDirect hit on a marmoset18. Lateral Thinker3 birds launched backwards19. Sharp ShooterLevel completed with a single bird20. Block Obliterator10,000 blocks destroyed in total</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="33909">Trucks and Skulls</game><game id="37033">Amazing Breaker</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1950/1694194-164561_10150092292454928_314467614927_5972828_1061263_n.jpg</image></root>