<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34088</id><name>State of Decay</name><description>OverviewState of Decay is developer  Undead Labs' ambitious  zombie-survival open world game, currently under development and to be released on  Xbox LIVE Arcade and  PC. According to the developers website, State of Decay is the embodiment of the “What if?” zombie apocalypse scenario.GameplayState of Decay will feature an open world game world.Both melee and gun combatStrong emphasis on survival game play, "doing what you must do to stay alive"Vehicle transportation and  combatEvolving world that changes depending on the actions you takeDestructible Environments James Phinney, Lead Designer of State of Decay, stated that the game will focus on player actions and the consequences of those actions on the world,Where will you sleep? How will you feed yourself? Will you go it alone or will you team up with others? These are real decisions you get to make and of course they all have consequences for you. But that’s not all. These decisions have consequences for the world.DevelopmentState of Decay was codenamed "Class3" and was announced February 2011.On August 18th, 2012 Undead Labs announced that State of Decay would use the  CryEngine 3.Class3 was officially name-changed to State of Decay on August 21st, 2012 and a first trailer was released on the YouTube channel of  Undead Labs.Undead Labs plans to develop a MMO style property based around State of Decay in the future.On the 17th June, 2013 Undead Labs announced that the sales of State of Decay had crossed over 500,000 copies making it one of the fastest selling new IP's on XBLA and that due to this feat they would be developing a new Sandbox mode for the game which would remove all story elements and turn the game into a full and pure survival experience. No date for the Sandbox mode was given though. Undead Labs also announced that State of Decay will be coming to PC via Steam although announced the date as TBD.PC System RequirementsMinimumRecommendedOS: XP SP3OS: Windows 7 Processor: Cor 2 Duo 2.4GHz (E6600) / Athlon X64 3400Processor: Intel Core i5 or equivalentMemory: 2 GB RAMMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: Radeon HD 2600 XT / GeForce 9600 GSO / Intel HD 3000Graphics: Radeon HD 4750 / GeForce GT 240 / Intel HD 4000DirectX: Version 9.0cDirectX: Version 9.0cHard Drive: 3 GB available spaceHard Drive: 3 GB available space</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="34902">Project Zomboid</game><game id="34507">Red Dead Redemption: Undead Nightmare</game><game id="20253">Survival Crisis Z</game><game id="39256">DayZ</game><game id="39063">Infestation: Survivor Stories</game><game id="35619">ZombiU</game><game id="43405">How to Survive</game><game id="43931">Nether</game><game id="44027">The Stomping Land</game><game id="44401">Frozen State</game><game id="42902">Dead Rising 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2303996-box_sod.png</image></root>