<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3410</id><name>Mario Party 5</name><description>OverviewMario Party 5Mario Party 5 is the fifth game in the  Mario Party franchise and the second to be released for the Gamecube. Mario Party 5 was released on November 10, 2003 in North America, on November 28, 2003 in Japan, and on December 5, 2003 in PAL regions. The game was developed by  Hudson Soft and published by  Nintendo for the Nintendo GameCube. Mario Party 5 was generally well-received by critics. Reviewers found that the new minigames were fun and interesting, but due to the few original aspects of the game, it was criticized. However, Mario Party 5 still became a Player's Choice title in 2004. Mario Party 5 has an average rating of 71% on Game Rankings and of 69% on Metacritic.StoryMario Party 5 is set in the world of Dream Depot, a world that contains seven different game boards. The single-player story modes involves the player in a variety of games against the  Koopa Kids, who have been dispatched as part of  Bowser's plot to take over Dream Depot.GameplayA four player minigame.Mario Party 5 retains the traditional Mario Party gameplay. Each "level" is a game board, with the objective to gain the most stars by the end of the game. Stars are usually available for purchase for 20 coins (if the player doesn't have enough coins, they just pass by and must wait until the next time they pass the designated space). Coins are earned by landing on certain squares or winning minigames.Minigames all have varying goals, with several different types of minigames. There are four player minigames, that have all of the players playing against each other. One versus three minigames have one player (usually with a large advantage) against three others. Two versus two has two teams of two against each other. Battle minigames having varying goals. A  Donkey Kong minigame has goals relating to collecting coins. A duel minigame is a minigame between two randomly selected players.  Bowser minigames are minigames that Bowser presents near the end of the single-player game. In all there are 75 in the game (a 50% increase from Mario Party 4's minigame count, which was 50).Mario Party 5's multiplayer mode is called Party Mode. Up to four players can compete on any of the game boards. Before playing a game, the players can select difficulty of computer controlled opponents, as well as the amount of turns in the game, ranging from 10-50. There are ten playable characters in the game ( Mario,  Luigi,  Peach,  Yoshi,  Wario,  Daisy,  Waluigi,  Toad,  Boo, and Koopa Kid). Donkey Kong is no longer a playable character, but instead is in a DK Space, which initiates a DK minigame. As always, you start the game by hitting Dice Blocks to decide the match's turn order, then players will get ten coins for free. Next, he'll show you where the DK Space is and place six capsule events. Then, he'll show you where the first Star of the match is located and... let's party!The Wiggler Capsule Mario Party 5's biggest difference from previous Mario Party games is the capsule system. Previous games had shops where players could purchase items. In Mario Party 5, capsules can be gathered by passing a Capsule Machine. Capsules contain certain items, from injuring opponents in one's path, to extending the number of spaces moved in one turn. You can use it on yourself for coins, or throw your capsule up to 10 spaces away from you.Mario Party 5 also introduced a "Super-Duel Mode," which has players in a vehicle, combating in a variety of events. Vehicles can be custom fitted with parts that can be purchased. Once a vehicle is constructed, players can take it in matches against either computer controlled or human opponents.  Gameboards  Bowser Nightmare Bowser NightmareFuture DreamUndersea DreamPirate DreamToy DreamRainbow DreamSweet DreamMinigamesFour player minigamesChimp ChaseChomp RompConey Island Coin Cache Coney IslandDinger DerbyDodge BombFish SticksFish Upon A Star Flower ShowerFrozen FrenzyFlower Shower Ground Pound DownHotel GoombaHydrostarsLeaf LeapLater SkaterMazed  ConfusedNight Light FrightPop-star PiranhasPushy PenguinsRumble FumbleTriple JumpVicious VendingWill Flower One versus three minigamesBeam TeamBig Top DropCurvy Curbs Fight CardsFight CardsFlatiatorHeat StrokeMario MechsMathletesQuilt for SpeedRevolving FireSquared AwayTube It or Lose It Two versus two minigamesBanking CoinsBerry BasketBus BufferClock StoppersDefuse or LoseHandy HoppersID UFO Manic Mallets Manic MalletsMario Can-CanPanic PinballRumble ReadySubmarathon Battle minigames Astro-Logical Bill Blasters Lucky Lineup Random Ride Random Ride Tug-o-Dorrie Twist 'n' Out Duel minigamesBlown AwayBound of MusicButton Mashers Countdown Pound Countdown PoundGet a RopeHead WaiterMerry PoppingsPiece OutPound PerilPump 'n' JumpShock Absorbers Shy Guy Showdown Shy Guy ShowdownSky SurvivorWhomp MazeWind Wavers Other minigamesFrightmare Card Party!Ice HockeyBeach Volleyball DK Minigames Banana PunchBanana Punch Da Vine ClimbMass A-PeelBowser Minigames  Cage-in Cookin'Rain of FireScaldin' Cauldron </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="14">Trivia/Board Game</genre><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21617">Rayman: Raving Rabbids</game><game id="8753">Bomberman Land Touch!</game><game id="21186">Mario Party DS</game><game id="6424">Mario Party</game><game id="8362">Mario Party 8</game><game id="5995">Mario Party Advance</game><game id="7508">Mario Party 7</game><game id="8380">Mario Party 6</game><game id="13685">WarioWare: Smooth Moves</game><game id="20568">Rayman Raving Rabbids 2</game><game id="15952">Crash Bash</game><game id="2819">Sonic Shuffle</game><game id="23732">Bomberman Land Touch! 2</game><game id="16650">Fuzion Frenzy</game><game id="404">Disney's Party</game><game id="7669">Cartoon Network Block Party</game><game id="17156">My Street</game><game id="31210">Wii Party</game><game id="33914">Doraemon Wii: Himitsu Douguou Ketteisen!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2129489-box_mparty5.png</image></root>