<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34104</id><name>Atom Zombie Smasher</name><description>OverviewThe zombie apocalypse is upon mankind and it's up to the player to evacuate any survivors before they fall to the undead army by organizing rescue operations with the tactical help of snipers, artillery crews, orbital bombardments, etc. The game includes local co-op, but no network functionality.GameplayThe game is played from a birds-eye (top-down) view of a section of city. The player positions his mercenaries before the start of the level. The goal each level is to evacuate as many survivors as possible by means of helicopter transport, while protecting them from the Zed (zombies). Alternately, a map can be won by killing all of the Zed before nightfall. The Zed spawn from marked spots on the edges of the map, and the amount of spawns depends on the threat level of the mission, which can range from 1 to 4.The campaign is played from a larger map of a fictional place called Nuevos Aires. Each month, the player is allowed one deployment to try to fend off the Zed invasion. After the player completes the deployment for the month, additional areas of the map become infested. If the goal number of survivors is evacuated, the area will become neutral, and the Zed will be unable to invade it again. After all invasions and deployments are completed for the month, victory points are awarded, both to the player, and to the Zed horde. Any areas where the player was able to completely eliminate the Zed threat before nightfall will give bonus victory points. The player and the Zed horde race to fill their victory point bar first.MercenariesThere are several types of mercenaries available to the player. Once a player has more than the maximum deployment limit, their squad will be randomly chosen from their stables of mercenaries.The types are as follows:NameDescriptionHelicopterThe basic mercenary, available in every deployment. Used to evacuate survivors. Capable of relocating at any time during the mission.SnipersSnipers are deployed to a selected rooftop, and fire at Zed in a cone-shaped area. Cannot move, but can reposition their cone.ArtilleryArtillery is deployed to a rooftop, and it capable of firing shells anywhere on the map.InfantryInfantry are deployed to the street. They kill Zed visible to them on the street, and are capable of relocating during the mission.BarricadesBarricades are used to block off streets. They cannot be placed anywhere that would prevent the Zed from entering the map, and cannot be moved once the map starts.DynamiteDynamite are a single-use explosive that are deployed on the street. They are triggered by the player.LandminesLandmines are single-use explosives that are deployed on the street and are only triggered by Zed walking over them.Zed BaitZed bait is a lure that causes all Zed in the radius to move toward the bait. It can be deployed multiple times during the mission, and lasts a short duration.PC System RequirementsOperating System: Windows XP/Vista/7Processor: 1GHzRAM Memory: 512MBHard Disk Space: 60MBVideo Card: 60MBMac System RequirementsOperating System: OSX 10.6 or laterProcessor: 1GHzRAM Memory: 512MBHard Disk Space: 60MBVideo Card: 60MB</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="29932">Flotilla</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/97089/2428199-z.png</image></root>