<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34218</id><name>Chaos Code</name><description>OverviewChaos Code is a 2D fighting game developed by FK Digital, a Taiwanese game development company. The game was released in Japanese arcades in 2011. Arc System Works published Chaos Code on the PlayStation Network for North America on September 3, 2013. The PSN version currently does not have online mode, but FK Digital stated on an interview in Siliconera that they are working on online mode in-studio.Game ModesStory ModePlay through the story of all Chao Code characters.Versus ModeOne-on-one battle against another human player or against the game's computer.Survival ModeThe player battles through a number of computer opponents until their fighter runs out of stamina.Practice ModeThis mode allows the player to practice their fighter against a dummy. The player can adjust the dummy's settings, such as guard, recovery, stance, etc., to their preference.GameplayMovementChaos Code utilizes an eight-way directional movement to move the fighter back and forth, block, dash, jump, and execute special and super moves.Normal AttacksChaos Code uses four buttons to execute normal attacks.A - Weak PunchB - Weak KickC - Strong PunchD - Strong KickNormal CommandsThe fighter performs a particular action when the following buttons are pressed together.Forward RollCommand: A + BThe fighter will perform a ground forward roll.RecoveryCommand: A + B upon knock back or before hitting the groundThe fighter will quickly recover to a fighting position.ThrowCommand: A +CThe fighter will grab and throw their opponent to the ground. Pressing back with A + C will make the fighter perform a backward throw.Chaos Gauge CommandsThe following commands require an amount of chaos meter available for the fighter to perform the following actions.Guard Break AttackCommand: Forward + C + D; Consumes 1 Chaos MeterThe fighter will perform an unblockable attack to the opponent, causes the opponent to be frozen in place if they are hit.Tactical GuardCommand: C + D; Consumes 1/2 Chaos MeterThe fighter will counter an opponent's attack if the command is timed properly.EX Special MoveConsumes 1/2 Chaos MeterThe fighter will perform an EX version of their special move.Ultimate ChaosConsumes 1 Chaos MeterThe fighter's super move. Each fighter has two super moves.Destruction ChaosConsumes 3 Chaos MetersThe fighter's ultimate super move.Chaos ShiftCommand: A+C during Ultimate Chaos; Consumes 1 Chaos MeterThis command will cancel the fighter's ultimate chaos attack and return them back to a neutral state.Chaos CancelConsumes 2 Chaos MetersThe command allows the fighter to cancel a special move action into an ultimate chaos.Exceed ChaosCommand: B + C; Consumes 3 Chaos MetersThe fighter will enter in exceed chaos state, where their chaos gauge changes into a time gauge.The fighter in the exceed chaos state are given four special properties.Their stun gauge is reset back to zero.All chaos consuming moves can be used at all times.Stamina regenerates.All normal attacks are cancel-able.Once the time gauge for exceed chaos runs out, the fighter's chaos gauge enter into overheat mode where no accumulation of chaos meter can be gain, nor the use of any chaos commands can be used untilSkill Selects, Run / BounceChaos Code allows the player to choose the following options after the character is chosen.Skill SelectsThe player can choose two out of the four additional skills for their character. The top two skills are additional special moves while the bottom two are additional super moves. The two chosen additional skills will have their commands displayed under the chaos gauge during battle.Run / BounceThe player can choose the forward dash preference for the character. The run option will have the fighter run along the ground, while the bounce option will make the fighter hop forward.CharactersHikaruMG HikaruKagariCereberusKudlak-SinCeliaCelia IIVeinHermesCatherineCthyllaBravoCait  SithRuiLinksJapanese Portal SiteEnglish Site</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="28321">BlazBlue: Continuum Shift</game><game id="21768">BlazBlue: Calamity Trigger</game><game id="29779">BlazBlue Calamity Trigger Portable</game><game id="32481">Blazblue: Continuum Shift II</game><game id="22574">Melty Blood</game><game id="21863">Melty Blood: Act Cadenza</game><game id="27450">Melty Blood: Actress Again</game><game id="20477">Arcana Heart</game><game id="22818">Arcana Heart 2</game><game id="29341">Arcana Heart 3</game><game id="11813">Guilty Gear</game><game id="19278">Guilty Gear XX #Reload</game><game id="3978">Guilty Gear X</game><game id="800">Guilty Gear XX Λ Core</game><game id="8534">Guilty Gear X2</game><game id="21802">Guilty Gear Judgment</game><game id="25188">Guilty Gear XX Λ Core Plus</game><game id="34011">Super Cosplay Wars Ultra</game><game id="35513">Phantom Breaker</game><game id="37140">Melty Blood: Actress Again: Current Code</game><game id="34082">Skullgirls</game><game id="44008">Dengeki Bunko: Fighting Climax</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/12/122378/1712307-chaos_code_poster.jpg</image></root>