<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34222</id><name>Instant Brain</name><description>StoryZenya Barataki, a legendary paparazzi, is commissioned to investigate dark rumours surrounding a top idol, a job that gets him involved in a huge show business conspiracy that is somehow connected to his memory loss.CharactersCharacter design is credited to Irumakamiri (いるまかみり).Zenya BaratakiZenyaThe game's protagonist, and a paparazzi legendary for his ability to take photographs nobody else can. He lives in a multi-tenant building in the lower parts of Tokyo. Six years prior to the game's beginning, he awoke without any memories, holding an supernatural instant camera called Exposure. Exposure has the power to capture the memories of any person or object photographed with it -- an ability Zenya has used to get many a scoop.Android CAndroid CKnown simply as C, she is the latest maid-model android. Her official name is Model H4667C. Maid-model androids are rare, and cost about as much as a large luxury apartment in Tokyo.Voiced by: Mamiko Noto (能登 麻美子)Kirin YatsuhishaKirinA high-school student and self-proclaimed genius hacker who runs an intelligence business. To mask her business, she takes care of an antique shop managed by her grandfather.Voiced by: Rie Kugimiya (釘宮理恵)Kuroe JakouKuroeThe producer of the largest domestic commercial television station, "Channel ∞", which her grandfather is the chairman of. She is the youngest producer in the industry, and though many see her career as the result of nepotism, she actually rose in the company purely due to her own competence. She has gained the nickname "Ratings Woman" because of the lengths to which she is prepared to go to for the sake of ratings.Voiced by: Miyuki Sawashiro (沢城みゆき)Mikuri KinshokuMikuriA novice detective working in the first investigation division of the imperial capital's police force.She is very serious and honest, and consequently neither flexible nor accomodating. She is a good friend of Fuuka's.Voiced by: Marina Inoue (井上麻里奈)Fuuka OujouFuukaA forensics expert working at the scientific crime-detection group at the imperial capital's police force. She is actually a male idol-otaku, and a good friend of Mikuri's.Voiced by: Chiaki Takahashi (たかはし智秋)Additional charactersThe minor characters.According to the game's official site, three major characters have not yet been revealed. All that is currently known are the names of their voice actors: Kana Hanazawa (花澤香菜), Kenyuu Horiuchi (堀内賢雄) and Akio Ootsuka (大塚明夫). The official site also shows portraits of 22 minor characters.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="34221">Nin² -Jump</game><game id="21705">DoDonPachi</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/86881/2076370-622617_199906_front.jpg</image></root>