<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34233</id><name>SingStar Danske Hits</name><description>Overview SingStar Danske Hits (SingStar Danish Hits in English) is the first installment in the long running series that only features songs from Danish artists. That does not mean that all of them sings in Danish (like Alphabeat or Aqua), but more than half of them do. The tracklist features both new and old songs, and a couple of them can also be found in the SingStore. None of the songs feature guitar support as of yet but "Back to the 80's" has dance support.  TracklistAlphabeat - The SpellAqua - Back to the 80'sAtaf - SommerfuglBryan Rice - No PromisesCarpark North - Just HumanCelina Ree - Når du rør ved migCut 'N' Move - Give It UpDúné - Dry LipsHej Matematik - CenterpubbenHej Matematik - WalkmandJakob Sveistrup - Tænder På DigJoey Moe - Yo-YoJooks - Hun vil ha' en rapperJunior Senior - Move Your FeetLaban - Hvor skal vi sove i natLizzie - Ramt i nattenMagtens Korridorer - Picnic på KastelletMedina - EnsomMedina - Kun for migNabiha - Deep SleepNik  Jay - En dag tilbagePoul Krebs - Sådan nogen som osPrivate - My Secret LoverRasmus Seebach - EngelRasmus Seebach - Glad igenShu-Bi-Dua - SexchikaneSukkerchok - Hvor som helst, når som helstTina Dickow - Give InVolbeat - The Garden's Tale</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20787">Karaoke Revolution Presents American Idol Encore</game><game id="5769">High School Musical: Sing It!</game><game id="28936">Disney Sing It: Pop Hits</game><game id="32221">Disney Sing It: Family Hits</game><game id="33148">Disney Sing It: Party Hits</game><game id="24413">Karaoke Revolution Presents American Idol Encore 2</game><game id="27944">Karaoke Revolution</game><game id="31978">Karaoke Revolution: Glee</game><game id="12946">Karaoke Revolution Presents American Idol</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/329/1715410-singstar_danske_hits_cover.jpg</image></root>