<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34294</id><name>Sins of a Solar Empire: Rebellion</name><description>OverviewRebellion introduces Titan-class warships, which dwarf every other unitAnnounced at GDC 2011, Rebellion is the third expansion to Sins of a Solar Empire franchise following Entrenchment and Diplomacy. It is the series' first stand-alone expansion, meaning it does not require the base game to function.Rebellion adds new "loyalist" and "rebel" sub-factions to the game. These sub-factions gain exclusive access to new technologies and ship variants. Additions also include new victory conditions, capital ships for each faction, maneuverable corvette-class ships, and titan-class ships which can single-handedly wipe out entire armies. On a more technical level, the expansion improves lighting and particle effects, artificial intelligence, CPU usage, modding support and adds Impulse::Reactor support for improved connectivity with Stardock's Impulse platform.DLCForbidden WorldsThe Forbidden Worlds DLC pack introduced four new planet types to colonize, a new planet specialization system, 15 new research subjects and 40 new planet bonuses.System RequirementsMinimumRecommendedOS: Windows 7 / Vista SP2 / XP SP3OS: Windows 7Processor: Intel Pentium 4 3GHz Processor or EquivalentProcessor: Intel Core i5 or Equivalent ProcessorMemory: 2 GB RAMMemory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: 256 MB DirectX 9.0c Compatible Video Card w/Pixel Shader 3.0 SupportGraphics: 1 GB DirectX 9.0c Compatible Video Card w/Pixel Shader 3.0 SupportDirectX: 9.0cDirectX: 9.0cHard Drive: 5 GB HD spaceHard Drive: 5 GB HD spaceSound: DirectX 9.0c Compatible Sound CardSound: DirectX 9.0c Compatible Sound Card </description><genres><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5861">Galactic Civilizations II</game><game id="9398">Galactic Civilizations</game><game id="24445">Supreme Commander 2</game><game id="1901">Supreme Commander</game><game id="9473">Homeworld 2</game><game id="11590">Homeworld</game><game id="5921">M.A.X.: Mechanized Assault and Exploration</game><game id="18545">Pax Imperia: Eminent Domain</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/13/136036/2492737-81rztwbwwcl._sl1500_.jpg</image></root>