<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34337</id><name>Wrecked: Revenge Revisited</name><description>OverviewMuch like the MASHED games that Supersonic developed during the PlayStation 2/Xbox era, WRECKED brings arcade style, track-based vehicular combat to Xbox Live Arcade and PlayStation Network. Played from an overhead, third-person view the rounds are fast and frantic including familiar and new weaponry as well as vehicle customizations. Defeated players are now given one of five airstrikes to perform a single revenge attack and customizations allow players to create unique vehicles that are both easily recognizable to online players and have buffed up stats and abilities.ModesBattle Mode - The classic "Mashed" game mode where the main objective is to knock your opponents off the track, or out-drive, to score points. Online, local or co-op play for 1-4 players.Single Player Championship Mode - A new game mode which is more of a single player challenge mode. By completing 24 challenges you can unlock livery, parts for your car and more. These 24 challenges are split into 4 sections - Speed/Skills/Weapons and Elite SeriesWeapons"14 Kick-Ass Weapons" have been confirmed. So far the weapons present in footage are:Machine GunSmart MortarMineGuided MissileDrum BombFlashPlasma CannonFlamethrowerShockerShotgunRailgunSonic BoomBall and ChainDroneAir Strike: (These are used when you have been knocked out of the round)Homing MissileCannonSky BeamSwapperSteer HunterVoicesOne of the quirky aspects of MASHED was its peculiar non-native sounding character taunts. At the press of a button each player could whip out -- in an unending stream -- a myriad of awkwardly acted one-liners. Supersonic has revealed that they'll return in WRECKED but with an option to disable them and has asked visitors to their blog to comment with their favorite lines they'd like to see included in the final game.In the games latest trailer, plenty of taunts can be heard such as:"Hail to the King baby."This is what it's about.""This is war!"Come on! Bring It!""Take that sucker.""Revenge is sweet.""In the zone.""Get back to kindergarten junior.""Just a walk in the park.""Want me to tell you what it takes to be a winner?""Now, i'm gonna get me some retribution.""Come on man. At least try."VehiclesYou can customise your cars, however this feature appears to be purely an aesthetic one, such as changing the colour and design of your car.SecatorThe first vehicle to be announced by 505 games via their Facebook page.ThracianThe second vehicle to be announced.RetiarriThe third vehicle to be announced. Follows the trend of the previous models, perhaps in a sports car category.MirmillionThe fourth vehicle to be announced.CoursesSix tracks in three different locations:An abandoned iron ore mine in the desert of the Australian outback.A track formed from ice and snow in a remote part of Scandinavia.A jungle highway taken over by vines and foliage.The only confirmed race course at the moment is the ever so popular Polar Wharf from MASHED, as voted for by the community.</description><genres><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14204">Mashed: Drive to Survive</game><game id="14413">Mashed: Fully Loaded</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1821536-box_wrr.png</image></root>