<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34336</id><name>Hot Springs Story</name><description>OverviewHot Springs Story, released for North American cell phones on February 28, 2011, is a follow-up to Kairosoft's Game Dev Story. Unlike the company's previous title, which charges players with the task of running a game development studio, Hot Springs Story revolves around the management of a Japanese hot springs resort.Targets ListHot Springs Story revolves around the people visiting the player's hot spring. The list below includes all Targets identified so far as well as their bonuses.TargetBenefitTea ExpertFacilitiesTV HostAdvertisingNovelistVotesFishermanItemsCartoonistMoneyJournalistAdvertisingProgrammerStayersAnnouncerStayersStudentAdvertisingBiz-womanStayersResearcherFacilitiesPainterFacilitiesM. ArtistStayersComedianAdvertisingHousewifeVotesG. ManagerAdvertisingPastry ChefItemsOld CoupleItemsIllustratorFacilitiesModelAdvertisingFortunetellerItemsBiz-manItemsManagerMoneyYoung CoupleStayersHikerMoneyBooth BabeVotesLandlordStayersYoung FamilyVotesAntique DirectorVotesFacilitiesHot Spring Story includes a variety of facilities you can use to expand your hot spring. Below is a list of each facility and it's cost.Facility NamePrice to BuildTatami Room$150Western Room (Requires Store Purchase)$150Vending Machine$100Massage Chair (Requires Story Purchase)$250Bath (Male)$360Bath (Female)$360Reception$500StoresHot Spring Story also uses a variety of stores to enhance the player's hot spring, and to ensure the hot spring's maximum amount of luxury. Below is a list of all the stores and their prices.Store NamePrice to BuildRestaurant$300Souvenir Stand$350Arcade (Requires Investment)$320Reading Room (Requires Investment)$340Pachinko Machine$220Salon (Requires Investment)$420Cafe (Requires Investment)$480Fortuneteller (Requires Investment)$0Ping Pong Table (Requires Investment($500CompatibilitySome rooms are more compatible with other rooms stationed near them. Below is a list of rooms that are enhance other rooms.Facility/Store 1Facility/Store 2End ResultTatami Room or Western RoomPachinko MachineBenefits all guestsTatami Room or Western RoomMassage ChairBenefits Adults and SeniorsTatami Room or Western RoomCafeBenefits MenTatami Room or Western RoomFortunetellerBenefits WomenTatami Room or Western RoomVending MachineBenefits all guestsTatami RoomTatami RoomBenefits all guestsWestern RoomWestern RoomBenefits all guestsWestern RoomRestaurantBenefits all guestsSouvenir StandWestern RoomBenefits Youth, Hurts everyone elseSouvenir StandVending MachineBenefits Youths, Adults and GroupsPachinko MachineArcadeBenefits MenPachinko MachinePachinko MachineBenefits Adult MenMassage ChairSalonBenefits WomenCafeReading RoomBenefits Adult and Senior MenCafeArcadeHurts both Adult Men and Senior MenSalonFortunetellerBenefits WomenSalonPachinko MachineBenefits WomenVending MachinePing Pong TableBenefits AllVending MachineArcadeBenefits YouthReading RoomPachinko MachineHurts AllPing Pong TableArcadeBenefits GroupsGuidesEach year the player's hot spring is put against other springs in Japan in magazine guide competitions. Below is a list of each guide, and info about it.Guide NameCopies DistributedNumber of Inns CompetingSpecial FocusLocal Springs (Easy)460k23NonePrefectural Springs (Moderate)9100k142NoneTouring Japan (Tough)18,400k230NoneLe Nichelin Guide (Hard)32,700k76NoneGlamour Springs (Moderate)7,400k84Focuses on WomenTop 100 Springs (Tough)11,600k100Focuses on Bath'sGourmet Springs (Moderate)13,200k88Focuses on EateriesRelaxing Springs (Tough)14,100k78Focuses on SceneryStore ItemsThe Store lets the player buy items that can be used on rooms in the hot spring. Each item's cost is raised with each purchase. Below is a list of each item, and it's recommended use.ItemBest used onGreen TeaRestaurants, Vending MachinesHoneyRestaurantsIced TeaVending MachineMilkRestaurants, Vending MachinesComic BooksReading Rooms, StoresPopularity SeedAll RoomsPrice SeedAll RoomsSpecial SeedsThere are also several special seeds that are only available from winning first place in specific guides.Seed NameSeed EffectHow to WinGlamour SeedBoost popularity with Women1st Place in Glamour Springs GuideGourmet SeedBoost popularity and price in all restaurants1st Place in Gourmet Springs Guide</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="33312">Game Dev Story 2</game><game id="35624">Grand Prix Story</game><game id="35767">Pocket Academy</game><game id="35945">Soccer Club Story</game><game id="36075">Mega Mall Story</game><game id="36369">Pocket League Story</game><game id="36888">Oh! Edo Towns</game><game id="36915">World Cruise Story</game><game id="37639">Dungeon Village</game><game id="37007">Venture Towns</game><game id="37901">Cafeteria Nipponica</game><game id="37077">Epic Astro Story</game><game id="42759">The Sushi Spinnery</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/37185/1724257-mzl.ypuifpsc.320x480_75.jpg</image></root>