<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34383</id><name>Tiny Wings</name><description>OverviewReady for takeoff!Tiny Wings is an iOS game developed by German game creator Andreas Illiger and was released onto the iTunes App store on February 18, 2011. Andreas developed the project solely over the course of seven months. The game revolves around the player controlling a tiny bird whose wings are too small to fly. The user can tap the screen in order for the small bird to nosedive and gain momentum off rolling hills. The objective is to fly across as many islands as possible before nightfall arrives. The game features special challenges that the user can complete in order to permanently increase their score multiplier. In addition, a fundamental feature of the game is that the island's aesthetics are procedurally generated daily; presenting the player a vastly different look for each day.Updates1.10 - Game Center Support, New Objectives, Statistics Page1.11 - Minor Bug Fixes.ReceptionTiny Wings has been very highly regarded by critics alike. Touch Arcade gave the title a 5/5 score and remarked that, "The simple gameplay in Tiny Wings is sublime, but there is an intangible aspect that makes it a total joy to play". Likewise, GamePro lauded the game with praise, "This impressive one button App Store entry is simple by design, but deep and engaging enough to make it more than worth the ninety nine cent price point". Tiny Wings currently averages 5 stars on the App Store and an 86% on Metacritic.AchievementsScores Multipliers1. Pocket Money - Collect 100 coins2. Island Hopper - Reach the 4th island3. Tiny Slides - Do 7 great slides in one game4. Touch The Clouds - Do 1 cloud touch5. Early Points - Gain 5000 points on the 1th island6. Tiny Fever - Be 5s in fever mode7. Odd Number Slide - Do 5 great slides on the 3rd island8. Tiny Flow - Do 1 great slide directly after an island jump9. Tiny Pirate - Collect 200 coins10. Nervous Fever - Be 5x in fever mode in one game11. Big Points - Gain 60000 points12. Too Fast For Me - Reach the 5th island withoud speed coins.13. Island Jump Fever - Reach the 4th island being in fever mode14. Giant Slides - Do 32 great slides in one game15. Stairway To Heaven - Do 2 cloud touches on the 5th island16. Feverish Dream - Do 5 cloudtouches in fever mode17. One Cloud Touch Per Finger - Do 10 cloud touches in one game18. Great Motoring - Do 10 great slides on the 1st island19. Healthy Fly - Reach the 5th island without fever mode20. Heavy Fever - Be 17s in fever mode21. Upside Down - Turn your device upside down and reach the 5th island22. Mega Fever - Be 34 seconds in fever mode23. The Holy Island - Reach the 7th island24. Ground Slider - Reach the 4th island without doing any great slide25. Byte Island - Reach the 8th island26. Heavy Points - Gain 175000 points27. Perfect Flow - Do one great slide directly an island jump28. Far Away From Home - Reach the 9th island29. Fever King - Fly through the 4th island in fever mode30. No Fever No Fun - Do 20 cloudtouches not being in fever mode</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="34470">Snuggle Truck</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/32107/1727232-tiny_wings.png</image></root>