<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34396</id><name>Aquapazza: Aquaplus Dream Match</name><description>OverviewAquapazza: Aquaplus Dream Match is a 2D fighting game developed for arcades by EXAMU Inc and published by Aquaplus. The game will make use of Taito's NESiCAxLive digital distribuation system and promises a diverse cast consisting of characters from various other franchises owned by Aquaplus.Atlus USA announced on August 21, 2013 that this game will be released in North America on Holiday 2013 for the Playstation 3. The game will feature a full localization from Atlus USA, but retain the Japanese voices.GameplayGameplay ScreenshotThe game features an Active Emotion System, which awards a character extra damage when they are "feeling confident" and penalizes them with a decreased defence when they are "feeling down". A character's mood is reflected in their facial expressions on screen. Lifting a character's mood seems to involve continuously landing successful hits on the opponent.Another feature is Partner Assistance. During the match, the player can signal their partner, who is selected before the match begins, to perform one of their own unique abilities.Health and DamageAll characters have two bars of health with 10,000 points each. The game features an Active Emotion System which features three emotions.High: Emotion marked by a red portrait. High emotion can be caused by playing aggressively or utilizing the Impact Guard. Being in an emotion high increases attack damage by 10% or 15% if the health is below 10,000.Normal: The normal emotional state that you start in.Low: You will enter a low if you are too defensive. Being in a low causes guard break to occur more frequently and lower defense by 30%.Game MechanicsSplash Arts: A super that costs 3 Power Gauge. It can only be used at 1/2 health and when the portrait begins flashing.Partners: In Aquapazza, an assist character is selected after choosing your character. Each one has their own abilities and fall into three different categories.You can activate an assist with back, forward or neutral D button. Assist will cost 1 Power Gauge if you cancel into it or cancel your guard into it.Standby: These are the partners that will not move and stay in place until you give them a command. Standby Partners include Mizuki, Ulthury, Camyu, and Yuma.Follow: These partners lock and follow your character around as much as possible.Generally faster than most of the other partners. Follow Partners include Satsuki, Rathty, Octavia, and Ma-ryan.Special: They don't appear on screen until their assist activates, They can't be hit or punished. Special partners are Yuki and Rina.Heavy Smashes are heavy blows that will wall bounce on hit and can be combo'd off of. It is performed B+CThrows are unblockable moves that require close range. It is performed by holding back or forward with the C button.Impact Guard: Performed by blocking right before an attack connects. This game's instant blocking. It increases sensitivity and prevents chip damage and guard crush.Resist Smash: Allows your block to cancel into a heavy smash at the cost of 1 Power Gauge. Used by blocking and the pressing forward B+C.Fast Standing: Allows you to get up immediately after being knocked down. Used by holding up while being knocked down.CharactersThe game features two separate character rosters: one for main characters, which are characters the player controls directly, and a second for partners.Player CharactersHakuowloOrigin: Utawareru MonoVoice: Rikiya KoyamaKarulauOrigin: Utawareru MonoVoice: Atsuko TanakaToukaOrigin: Utawareru MonoVoice: Kaya MiyakeArawnOrigin: Tears to TiaraVoice: Tooru OokawaMorganOrigin: Tears to TiaraVoice: Mai NakaharaRiannonOrigin: Tears to TiaraVoice: Yuuko GotouTamaki KousakaOrigin: To Heart 2Voice: Shizuka ItouKonomi YuzuharaOrigin: To Heart 2Voice: Yurina HaseManaka KomakiOrigin: To Heart 2Voice: Noriko RikimaruMultiOrigin: To HeartVoice: Yui HorieSasara KusugawaOrigin: To Heart 2 Dungeon TravelersVoice: Ryouko OnoOboroOrigin: Utawareru MonoVoice: Daisuke KiriiChizuru KashiwagiOrigin: KizuatoVoice: Ryouka YuzukiPartnersSatsuki YuasaOrigin: RoutesVoice: Rie KugimiyaMizuki TakaseOrigin: Comic PartyVoice: Riko SayamaRathtyOrigin: Tears to TiaraVoice: Kana UedaOctaviaOrigin: Tears to TiaraVoice: Rie TanakaUlthuryOrigin: Utawareru MonoVoice: Sayaka OoharaCamyuOrigin: Utawareru MonoVoice: Rie KugimiyaYuma TonamiOrigin: To Heart 2Voice: Hitomi NabatameYuki MorikawaOrigin: White AlbumVoice: Aya HiranoRina OgataOrigin: White AlbumVoice: Nana MizukiMa-ryanOrigin: To Heart 2Voice: Ema KogureYuu InagawaOrigin: Comic PartyVoice: Kaoru MorotaLlyrOrigin: Tears to TiaraVoice: Kaori NazukaSerika KurusugawaOrigin: To HeartVoice: Junko Iwao</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23670">Utawarerumono</game><game id="13207">To Heart</game><game id="25033">Tears to Tiara</game><game id="23687">Comic Party</game><game id="35513">Phantom Breaker</game><game id="36274">Persona 4 Arena</game><game id="37140">Melty Blood: Actress Again: Current Code</game><game id="25355">Fate/Unlimited Codes</game><game id="36051">Ougon Musou Kyoku</game><game id="34082">Skullgirls</game><game id="44008">Dengeki Bunko: Fighting Climax</game><game id="44068">Twinkle Queen</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/16/164924/2552996-waterpizza.jpg</image></root>