<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34411</id><name>Magic: The Gathering - Duels of the Planeswalkers 2012</name><description>OverviewSimilar to Duels of the Planeswalkers, this is a downloadable version of the Magic: the Gathering trading card game. The game is available for download via Xbox Live, Playstation Network, and Steam. The game contains cards from the 2012 core set and previous sets. The first piece of DLC added cards from the Innistrad set which was had yet to be released. The game's modes follow the Vintage constructed format.Parts of a TurnBeginning PhaseUntap StepUpkeep StepDraw StepPrecombat Main PhaseCombat PhaseBeginning of Combat StepDeclare Attackers StepDeclare Blockers StepCombat Damage StepEnd of Combat StepPostcombat Main PhaseEnd PhaseEnd of Turn StepCleanup StepNew Mode: ArchenemyIn the new Archenemy mode, three players team up to take down an Archenemy boss. These bosses have double your starting life and powerful scheme cards. In turn, the Archenemy must defeat all three players to win, so even if 1 or 2 allies are defeated you can still win. The mode is playable online with the ability to add bots if there are not enough players. The mode originally limited players to the role of the allies. In the expansion, players were allowed to play the role of the Archenemy online and offline.The game plays similarly to the traditional one-on-one format except the three allies all take their turns at the same time, sharing their upkeep, main, and battle phases. In addition, the Archenemy has a scheme deck which is a secondary 20-card deck containing cards of considerable power in respect to normal card effects. At the beginning of the Archenemy's main phase, they turn over the top card of the scheme deck and activate its effect. Once its effect resolves, the scheme is put on the bottom of the scheme deck.Deck listsMagic: The Gathering 2012 offers 10 new decks. Two decks are available from the start, while the other 8 have to be unlocked through the campaign. The first expansion added three more decks and four more unlockable cards for each deck, the 3 subsequent deck packs added 2 decks each.Core Game Decks:Kiora Atua's "Ancient Depths" - Blue  GreenFull Deck ListThis deck is all about Lands, every other card in its deck allows for extra Land cards to be played in a turn so in a relatively small amount of time this deck will vastly outmatch its opponent, which is great as most of its main monster cards are very expensive.Chandra Nalaar's "Unquenchable Fire" - Mono RedFull Deck ListThis Mono Red deck is characterised by its very high count of direct damage cards and abilities, this is balanced out by its relatively low creature count, of which few are particularly troublesome.Sorin Markov's "Blood Hunger" - Mono BlackFull Deck ListThe Blood Hunger deck is also the "Vampire" deck, with its high vampire count and cards with the Bloodthirst and Lifelink abilities, the deck likes to buff its creatures in response to its opponents misfortune.Jace Beleren's "Realm of Illusion" - Mono BlueFull Deck ListThe Mono Blue deck is built around its Illusion cards, with creatures being buffed by Illusions, and cards buffing said Illusions, this deck also favours effects that send cards back to their owners hands and drawing extra cards. Similar to the Black / Green deck with its Elf buffing.Gideon Jura's "Wielding Steel" - Mono WhiteFull Deck ListThe Wielding steel white deck is centered on cheap, aggressive creatures boosted by a good number of equipment cards. This deck closely resembles the Mono White deck from the first Duels of the Planeswalkers - third expansion. Soldiers make up the most of this deck's creatures, with a few angels thrown in.Garruk Wildspeaker's "Apex Predators" - Mono GreenFull Deck ListGarruk is back this game with another mono green deck. This deck plays more or less the same as the starter deck from Duels of the Planeswalkers. There are plenty of land boosting cards with several dangerous and powerful monsters thrown in.Tezzeret's "Machinations" - Blue  Black  WhiteFull Deck ListA different spin on an artifact deck, this deck is a more powerful version of the one in the previous game. The deck is still based on cheap artifacts which boost other artifacts and several highly dangerous creatures as well.Sarkan Vol's "Dragon's Roar" - Red  BlackFull Deck ListThe efficient dragon deck from the previous game returns. This time, the deck is even more efficient and powerful. The usual assortment of dragons, dragon boosters, and land creatures make up this deck.Nissa Revane's "Guardians of the Wood" - Green  BlackFull Deck ListThe elf deck returns as well. Like the green and dragon decks, the elf deck has been boosted as well to remain competitive in this new game.Koth's "Strength of Stone" - Mono RedFull Deck ListA creature-based red deck. The unquenchable fire deck concentrates on spells and direct damage, whereas this deck focuses on creatures both big and small.Expansion Pack 1 Decks:Liliana Vess' "Grave Whispers" - Mono BlackFull Deck ListLiliana's deck has many effects dealing with the cards in each player's hands, with effects that force opponents to discard, buffing based on the number of cards in a hand or dealing damage based on the size of a hand.Ajani Goldmane's "Auramancer" - Green  WhiteFull Deck ListThis deck pretty much consists of just low powered / low cost creatures with a ton of Enchantments used to buff them, it's very similar to the Mono White deck.Ral Zarek's "Cloudburst" - Red  BlueFull Deck ListA deck with some low cost but relatively very powerful creatures, many with negative effects such as sacrificing it at the end of the turn or dealing damage to the player that controls it in exchange for using it's ability for example.Deck Pack 1 Decks:"March to War" - Red  WhiteFull Deck ListThis deck contains plenty low cost cards with abilities meant to give you a very quick advantage, whether by quickly amassing a large number of creatures, lands, cards in your hand or life. The complete lack of very high powered creatures present in other decks means players will have to end the game as quickly as possible, and the quick nature of this deck allows that."Ghoulkeeper" - Mono BlackFull Deck ListThis is the Zombie deck, most creatures are Zombie or Undead and the deck deals with the reanimation of corpses and the general raising of the dead, a deck that seems to get more powerful the more creatures present in the graveyard as there are many effects that deal with the player's graveyard.Deck Pack 2 Decks:"Forest's Fury" - Mono GreenFull Deck ListTrees, lots and lots of trees, and the interaction between the Treefolk Creatures and Forest Lands, similar to the elf deck, the Treefolk will buff one another or otherwise help other Treefolk."Dark Heavens" - White  BlackFull Deck ListThis deck heavily features a Light / Dark, Angels / Demons theme. The White cards buff, resurrect "spirits" and give life, the Black cards debuff, destroy and raise "corpses"Deck Pack 3 Decks:"Beknighted" - Mono WhiteFull Deck ListA typical Mono White deck full of cheap cards, what sets this apart is that every card in this deck has a secondary (or even tertiary) effect."Trinity of Elements" - Green  Red  BlueFull Deck ListVERY cheap cards, this is due to the multiple colours and that the deck is full with single colour cards, it doesn't give much room for high power creatures, oh they do exist, but designed more for hit-and-run tactics.System RequirementsOS: Windows XP with Service Pack 3Processor: 2GHz CPU (Pentium 4 or equivalent)Memory: 1GB RAM (2GB for Vista)DirectX®: DirectX 9.0c or laterHard Drive: 700MBSound: DirectX 9.0c compatible sound cardVideo: 256MB VRAM GPU capable of Pixel Shader 3 or better</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="13">Card Game</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10489">Pokémon Trading Card Game</game><game id="19085">Dragon Ball Z: Collectible Card Game</game><game id="2789">Duel Masters: Limited Edition</game><game id="23867">Fullmetal Alchemist Trading Card Game</game><game id="13159">Duel Masters Kaijudo Showdown</game><game id="9324">Duel Masters Sempai Legends</game><game id="3210">Marvel Trading Card Game</game><game id="11558">Shin Megami Tensei Trading Card: Card Summoner</game><game id="30800">Yu-Gi-Oh! 5D’s Decade Duels</game><game id="23618">Star Wars Galaxies Trading Card Games : Champions of the Force</game><game id="25488">Spectromancer</game><game id="34301">Scrolls</game><game id="9459">Culdcept</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1817070-box_mtgdotp2012.png</image></root>