<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34464</id><name>Rocksmith</name><description>OverviewRocksmith is Ubisoft's attempt at entering the stagnating music genre. Although many other games like this are on the market, Ubisoft is hoping to differentiate Rocksmith from the competition by adding compatibility with real electric guitars, adding a more educational bent to the game. By using a real guitar, the game purports to teach chords and notes to novices, while an adaptive difficulty level will ramp up the challenge for guitar vets. The technology behind the game is undeniably impressive, as it is the first video game to allow for a true plug-and-play experience with a real electric guitar, no matter the manufacturer or model of instrument. Once you learn how to play the song using the in-game prompts, you can plug the guitar into an amp and play the song through the amp, with no game necessary.GameplayRocksmith is played on any real guitar that is equipped with a 1/4-inch jack socket. The game is bundled with a special 1/4-inch audio jack-to-USB cable that allows the player's guitar to be plugged into the gaming system. A regular controller is required for general menu navigation, but the majority of the gameplay is performed on the instrument itself.InterfaceWhen playing a song, the player is presented with a cross section of the guitar neck oriented horizontally at the bottom of the screen. Each string on the guitar is labeled with a different color. Notes in the song are indicated by streaming colored rectangles placed within vertical segments that line up with the guitar's frets. As in other guitar-based music games, a note is played when it crosses the displayed portion of the neck at the bottom of the screen. The color of individual notes that stream down correspond with the string they should be played on, while their horizontal position indicates each note's fret on the guitar's neck.In addition to the basic note indicators, the game also presents interface elements to specify certain guitar techniques. Open notes, meaning notes played on un-fretted strings, are indicated by horizontal lines of the appropriate color. Other techniques, such as palm mutes, bends, slides, and harmonics are also indicated with distinctive symbols over their respective notes.Song LevelingEvery song is broken up into individual phrases, which can comprise a section or riff within the song. Each song starts out at a basic level that includes only a few notes that comprise the entire phrase. As the player consistently completes a phrase, more notes are added until the player maxes out the phrase and is playing all of the notes/chords that comprise it. If the game detects many missed notes within a phrase, it levels down to allow the player to regain a grasp on the phrase. Any phrase can be practiced individually in the games Riff Repeater and leveled up separately from the song itself.ProgressionPlaying songs or completing gigs earns the player RSP, which increases the player's level within the game. As the player's level increases, new game elements are unlocked including new gig locations and guitars.Bass SupportOn June 5, 2012, Ubisoft announced the addition of bass guitar support to the core game via download content. This update will let players plug in a bass guitar and allow them to play the bass portions of songs available in the game. A standard 6-string guitar can also be used to emulate a 4-string bass if that's the only option the player has. The bass update will be released on September 4, 2012, and will be available for $29.99. Additionally, on October 16, there will also be a new retail edition of the game, available for $79.99, that will have the bass support included on the disc.The bass update will also include new bass specific technique challenges, mini-games, and video tutorials to practice bass playing concepts like 2-finger plucking, slapping, and popping.Game ModesJourneyThe main form of progression in Rocksmith is structured around the format of a guitar player's rise to stardom, which is referred to as the "Journey". Every step in the journey is based upon practicing and performing a setlist at several gig locations. Individual setlists are comprised of groups of songs that generally increase in difficulty and required technical skill as the game progresses. Players can choose to rehearse these predetermined songs, or choose individual songs to comprise a new setlist. During a rehearsal, the player attempts to meet or exceed a required point threshold that indicates that the song has been sufficiently rehearsed.After all songs have been rehearsed, the player has the option to perform all of the songs at once in the gig's venue, akin to a live performance. Scoring highly on the songs in the gig can trigger an Encore of another song that the player may or may not have played yet, with the potential of triggering an additional Double Encore if the player continues to play well."Guitarcade"The Guitarcade is a series of mini-games tailored towards exercising individual concepts for guitar playing. These mini-games include:Ducks - The player shoots ducks by playing their relevant fret on a single string. This is meant to teach fret placement and transitioning.Super Ducks - Like Ducks, but employs all six strings.Scale Runner - The player runs through a series of notes within a scale, with points allotted for speed and accuracy. The player may choose their scale and key prior to playing.Quick Pick Dash - The player runs along a course by rapidly picking individual strings. The player avoids obstacles by following on-screen prompts to change between strings.Big Swing Baseball - The player is given a note to find and play within a short period of time. They then round bases on a baseball field based on the accuracy and timing of hitting the note.Super Slider - The player positions falling blocks by performing slides. Gameplay is similar to Dr. Mario or Lumines in that the player wishes to connect regions of similarly colored blocks to score points.Dawn of the Chordead - The player is presented with a chord name and form, then required to find and play it within a certain time frame. Success is indicated by shooting a screen full of zombies that appear when the chord is announced.Harmonically Challenged - The player must play a series of pick harmonics in a Simon-like fashion in an attempt to defuse a bomb.Amp ModeAmp Mode allows players to freely play their guitar while using the game as an amplifier. A player's tone can be modified by including effects pedals and different amplifiers in an effect chain, each effect being similar to its real-life counterpart. Over 70 pedals and amplifiers can be unlocked through gameplay. In addition, scoring 70,000 points or more on a song will unlock the tone used in that song, which can then be used in Amp Mode.LessonsIndividual lessons for general guitar techniques are provided to teach the player through song challenges. After walking the player through a technique (such as bends, slides, or barre chords), the game presents a unique song that heavily employs the technique. The player's performance in this song is scored and a rank is assigned between bronze, silver and gold.In addition to technique lessons, many lessons about guitar management and treatment are available. This includes videos on how to tune the guitar, how to replace strings, and more.SoundtrackSongArtistHouse of the Rising SunThe AnimalsWhen I'm With YouBest CoastI Got MineThe Black KeysNext GirlThe Black KeysSong 2BlurStep Out of the CarBoxer RebellionSunshine of Your LoveCreamWe Share the Same SkiesThe CribsBoys Don't CryThe CureI Want Some MoreDan AuerbachRebel RebelDavid BowieI Can't Hear YouThe Dead WeatherRun Back to Your SideEric ClaptonTake Me OutFranz FerdinandDo You RememberThe HorrorsI Miss YouIncubusSlow HandsInterpolAngelJarvis CockerWell OK HoneyJenny OUse SomebodyKings of LeonAre You Gonna Go My WayLenny KravitzSurf HellLittle BarrieFree Bird (pre-order DLC)Lynyrd SkynyrdSweet Home AlabamaLynyrd SkynyrdPlug In BabyMuseUnnatural SelectionMuseBreedNirvanaIn BloomNirvanaWhere is My Mind?The PixiesGo With the FlowQueens of the Stone AgeBodysnatchers (pre-order DLC)RadioheadHigh and DryRadioheadCalifornia BrainRapscallionsNumber ThirteenRed FangHigher GroundRed Hot Chili Peppers(I Can't Get No) SatisfactionThe Rolling StonesPlay With FireThe Rolling StonesThe Spider and the FlyThe Rolling StonesGobbledigookSigur RosPanic SwitchSilversun PickupsOutshinedSoundgardenMe and the BeanSpoonBetween the LinesStone Temple PilotsVasolineStone Temple PilotsUnder Cover of DarknessThe StrokesMean BitchTaddy PorterA More Perfect UnionTitus AndronicusGood EnoughTom Petty and the HeartbreakersSlitherVelvet RevolverBurnishedWhite DenimIcky ThumpThe White StripesIslandsThe xxChimneyYellow Moon BandDownloadable SongsRocksmith has had a steady roll out of DLC since its launch, releasing new 3-packs of songs every few weeks. All songs are available individually for $2.99 on PSN and 240 Microsoft Points on Xbox Live Marketplace, or as a three song bundle for $7.99 on PSN and 640 Microsoft Points on Xbox Live Marketplace.SongArtistSong PackFree BirdLynyrd SkynyrdRock Hits 1BodysnatchersRadioheadRock Hits 1Tighten UpThe Black KeysRock Hits 1Smoke on the WaterDeep PurpleRock Hits 70sMore than a FeelingBostonRock Hits 70sJessicaThe Allman Brothers BandRock Hits 70sCousinsVampire WeekendRock Hits 220th Century BoyT. RexRock Hits 2I Hate Everything About YouThree Days GraceRock Hits 2Symphony of DestructionMegadethMegadeth Song PackHangar 18MegadethMegadeth Song PackPublic Enemy No. 1MegadethMegadeth Song PackCarol of the BellsSeth ChaplaHoliday Song Pack (free)God Rest Ye Merry, GentlemenBrian Adam McCuneHoliday Song Pack (free)We Three KingsVersus ThemHoliday Song Pack (free)Just Got To BeThe Black KeysThe Black Keys Song PackMind EraserThe Black KeysThe Black Keys Song PackGold on the CeilingThe Black KeysThe Black Keys Song Pack(Don't Fear) The ReaperBlue Oyster CultRock Hits 60s-70sSpace OddityDavid BowieRock Hits 60s-70sBarracudaHeartRock Hits 60s-70sJeremyPearl JamPearl Jam Song PackBlackPearl JamPearl Jam Song PackDammitBlink-182Blink-182 Song PackAll the Small ThingsBlink-182Blink-182 Song PackWhat's My Age Again?Blink-182Blink-182 Song PackKryptonite3 Doors Down3 Doors Down Song PackLoser3 Doors Down3 Doors Down Song PackWhen I'm Gone3 Doors Down3 Doors Down Song PackThe Thrill is GoneB. B. KingBlues HitsBorn Under a Bad SignAlbert King w/ Stevie Ray VaughnBlues HitsSoul ManThe Blues BrothersBlues HitsBring Me to LifeEvanescenceRock Hits 3Pumped Up KicksFoster the PeopleRock Hits 3This LoveMaroon 5Rock Hits 3Breaking the LawJudas PriestJudas Priest Song PackLiving After MidnightJudas PriestJudas Priest Song PackPainkillerJudas PriestJudas Priest Song PackRoxanneThe PoliceThe Police Song PackMessage in a BottleThe PoliceThe Police Song PackSynchronicity IIThe PoliceThe Police Song PackGone AwayThe OffspringThe Offspring Song PackCome Out and Play (Keep 'Em Separated)The OffspringThe Offspring Song PackSelf EsteemThe OffspringThe Offspring Song PackPlanetary (GO!)My Chemical RomanceMy Chemical Romance Song PackWelcome to the Black ParadeMy Chemical RomanceMy Chemical Romance Song PackNa Na Na (Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na)My Chemical RomanceMy Chemical Romance Song PackTom SawyerRushRush Song PackLimelightRushRush Song PackRed BarchettaRushRush Song PackSubdivisionsRushRush Song PackYYZRushRush Song PackHeadlong FlightRushN/ASuper FreakRick JamesN/AGive Up The Funk (Tear the Roof off Sucker)ParliamentN/AGood TimesChicN/ACowboys From HellPanteraPantera Song PackDominationPanteraPantera Song PackWalkPanteraPantera Song PackBottoms UpNickelbackNickelback Song PackHow You Remind MeNickelbackNickelback Song PackRockstarNickelbackNickelback Song PackWheelsFoo FightersFoo Fighters Song PackWalkFoo FightersFoo Fighters Song PackTimes Like TheseFoo FightersFoo Fighters Song PackBest of YouFoo FightersFoo Fighters Song PackMy HeroFoo FightersFoo Fighters Song PackSmoothSantana Feat Rob ThomasSantana Song PackBlack Magic WomanSantanaSantana Song PackOye Como VaSantanaSantana Song PackNo RainBlind MelonN/ACliffs of DoverEric JohnsonN/AAlivePearl JamN/ALast NiteThe StrokesThe Strokes Song PackReptiliaThe StrokesThe Strokes Song PackJuiceboxThe StrokesThe Strokes Song PackBorn To Be WildSteppenwolfN/AAmerican WomanThe Guess WhoN/ASurrenderCheap TrickN/ADance, DanceFall Out BoyFall Out Boy Song PackSugar, We're Going DownFall Out BoyFall Out Boy Song PackI Don't CareFall Out BoyFall Out Boy Song PackAmerica's SuiteheartsFall Out BoyFall Out Boy Song PackThnks Fr Th MmrsFall Out BoyFall Out Boy Song PackShould I Stay or Should I GoThe ClashThe Clash Song PackLondon CallingThe ClashThe Clash Song PackGuns of BrixtonThe ClashThe Clash Song PackCarry On Wayward SonKansasN/AYou've Got Another Thing Comin'Judas PriestN/ABlack BettyRam JamN/AAnna MollyIncubusIncubus Song PackLove HurtsIncubusIncubus Song PackWish You Were HereIncubusIncubus Song Pack Burnin' For YouBlue Oyster CultRock Hits 80s 2 + Blue Oyster Cult PackBlister in the SunViolent FemmesRock Hits 80s 2Cult of PersonalityLiving ColourRock Hits 80s 2Love SongThe CureThe Cure Song PackJust Like HeavenThe CureThe Cure Song PackThe End of the WorldThe CureThe Cure Song PackOther Downloadable ContentNameTypePackPriceRelease DateTone Designer Time SaverAll standard pedalsTone Designer Time Saver Pack400 ms points/$5 on PSN and SteamOctober 18th, 2011SicSicSicSDistortion pedalHeavy Metal - Gear Pack400 ms points/$5 on PSN and Steam (as part of Heavy Metal - Gear Pack)February 28th, 2012CaverbDelay pedalHeavy Metal - Gear Pack400 ms points/$5 on PSN and Steam (as part of Heavy Metal - Gear PackFebruary 28th, 2012ScoopedFilter pedalHeavy Metal - Gear Pack400 ms points/$5 on PSN and Steam (as part of Heavy Metal - Gear PackFebruary 28th, 2012RSMP-12High-Gain AmpHeavy Metal - Gear Pack400 ms points/$5 on PSN and Steam (as part of Heavy Metal - Gear packFebruary 28th, 2012RSMP-12 4x12Cabinet ampHeavy Metal - Gear Pack400 ms points/$5 on PSN and Steam (as part of Heavy Metal - Gear pack)February 28th, 2012  ReceptionAlthough Rocksmith's technology is impressive and unique, the actual content of the game was panned by some critics. According to some critics, Rocksmith's educational aspects are downplayed due to the adaptive difficulty level, which they felt posed a constant uphill challenge. Additionally, Rocksmith was criticized for relying on the game's electronic tuning system, instead of teaching players how to tune by ear or other methods. Finally, some critics disliked the bland presentation of the game, which never shows any of the player's fictional band, instead lingering on the audience.Other critics, however, were impressed by the accuracy of the game, and found that by ignoring the lack of any real tuning advice, Rocksmith could still be used as an effective learning tool. The game is good at teaching songs slowly, while the competition splits songs up by difficulty.Despite positive user reviews averaging 9.1 on a 10 point scale, Rocksmith currently sits at a 78 average on Metacritic. (360 version)PC System RequirementsMinimum:OS:Windows Vista, Windows 7Processor:2.0 GHz Intel® Core™2 Duo E4400 or 2.0 GHz AMD Athlon™ 64 X2 3800+Memory:2 GB RAMGraphics:256 MB DirectX 9 / NVIDIA® GeForce® 8600 GT or ATI Radeon™ HD 2600 XTDirectX®:9.0Hard Drive:12 GB HD spaceSound:DirectX 9.0c-compliant</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23219">Guitar Rising</game><game id="27919">Rock Band 3</game><game id="14271">The Miracle Piano Teaching System</game><game id="37590">BandFuse: Rock Legends</game><game id="42913">Rocksmith 2014</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2331142-box_rsmith.png</image></root>