<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34619</id><name>Renegade Ops</name><description>OverviewRenegade Ops is a top down dual-joystick shooter developed by a 15 man team at Avalanche Studios. The game has you driving vehicles and helicopters as you shoot bad guys. The game was part of the PSN Play program.StoryRenegade Ops has a simple story, similar to those found in 80s movies and video games. It's told through vignettes at the beginning of each mission. The evil Inferno is hell-bent on ruling the world and terrorizes Europe by blowing up Catalonia City. International governments are too afraid to unite against Inferno so General Bryant decides to take matters into his own hands by searching the globe for elite soldiers who would be able to foil Inferno's plans. He finds Armand, Roxy, Diz and Gunnar, and in the Steam version, Doctor Gordon Freeman joins the team as well, somehow.GameplayBlowing stuff up in the helicopter.You can play the game as either Armand, Roxy, Diz or Gunnar. Each character has a different vehicle and different abilities, but controls the same. The left stick is used to move while the right stick is used to shoot. 3 face buttons are used: one for each character's special ability, the other to speed up the vehicle that you're driving and the third and final button is used to fire missiles. Controls are about the same when piloting a helicopter except that you must dodge obstacles and you can do flips.Levels have both primary and secondary objectives. These objectives range from rescuing hostages to blowing up tanks and ammo depots. Each mission is timed and you are awarded points for killing enemies, completing objectives and doing flips in the helicopter. During missions, you can pick up items that can give you temporary damage boosts, increase your life or increase your weapon range.The game features online co-op for up to 4 people and split screen co-op for up to 2 people. The 2-player co-op features a dynamic split screen which only splits the screen if the two players drive far enough away from each other. The split is not limited to left/right or up/down and is based on which directions the two players are moving. There are also three difficulties, Casual, Normal and Hardcore. Casual gives players unlimited lives, but eliminates the leveling and upgrades of the two higher difficulties.Character AbilitiesCharacter NameSpecial AbilityArmandHold LT or L1 to make your car invulnerable, but unable to fire any weapons.DizPress LT or L1 to use an electromagnetic pulse that disables enemy weapons.RoxyPress LT or L1 to unleash an airstrike barrage.GunnarHold LT or L1 to use a powerful heavy machine gun that renders your car stationary for the duration of use.Items and Pick-upsDuring combat numerous items and pick-ups are dropped by enemy vehicles and defenses.Item NameItem TypeDescriptionRail GunWeaponThe rail gun fires a charged shot. Hold the right trigger to charge the weapon before firing. Uses a laser beam to target. Very accurate and very powerful at full charge.Flame ThrowerWeaponThe flamer discharges a depletion bar as it is used. It is powerful against many easy enemies.RocketsWeaponThe rocket launcher shots one unguided rocket at the enemy. The aiming is not as precise as the rail gun and it takes more time to reach the target. Very powerful against the exposed rear panel of tanks.Small HealthConsumableIncreases the player's health by a small amount.Full HealthConsumableFully heals the player.AmmunitionConsumable (1x ammo)Adds one round of ammunition to the player's weapon stores or restores half of the player's flame thrower reserve.Machine Gun BonusUpgradeUpgrades the player's standard machine to a more powerful gun. Both the spread and the damage are increased. There are three levels of machine gun upgrade: 1) Default 2) Two shot spread 3) Three shot spread.Key CardQuestUsed in various levels to unlock gates.Side Mission ObjectQuestConsists of prisoners, documents, relics, and other items. These must be collected to complete the side missions.PC System RequirementsMinimumRecommendedOS: Microsoft Windows Vista (Windows XP not supported)Processor: Intel CoreR 2 Duo 2.6 GHz or AMD Phenom X3 2.4GHz or similarRAM Memory: 2GB System memoryGraphics: DX10 compatible graphics card with 256 MB memory (Nvidia GeForce 8800 series/ ATI Radeon HD 2600 Pro)DirectX®: Microsoft DirectX 10Hard Drive: 10GB available spaceSound: 100% DirectX 10 compatible sound cardOS: Windows 7Processor: Intel CoreR i5 M540 or similarRAM Memory: 3GB system memoryGraphics: DX10 compatible graphics card with 512 MB memory (Nvidia GeForce GTS 250 series/ ATI Radeon HD 5750 series)DirectX®: Microsoft DirectX 10.1Hard Drive: 10GB available spaceSound: 100% DirectX 10 compatible Dolby Digital 5.1 sound card</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="31">Dual-Joystick Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9183">Jackal</game><game id="7758">Cannon Fodder</game><game id="1">Desert Strike: Return to the Gulf</game><game id="12724">Return Fire</game><game id="10593">Grand Theft Auto 2</game><game id="2180">Jungle Strike</game><game id="5222">Assault Heroes</game><game id="20657">Assault Heroes 2</game><game id="28127">Scrap Metal</game><game id="29265">Zombie Driver</game><game id="35928">Voltron: Defender of the Universe</game><game id="42275">Pressure</game><game id="39683">Thunder Wolves</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2291772-box_rops.png</image></root>