<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34715</id><name>Sniper Elite V2</name><description>OverviewSniper Elite V2 is a sniper action game set in World War II that follows Karl Fairburne, an allied Sniper that is behind the enemy lines during the Battle of Berlin. The story is centered around the scientists that surrounded the V-2 rocket program. The game is a reboot of 2005's Sniper Elite. It was released for the PlayStation 3, Xbox 360 with publishing duties handled by 505 Games while Rebellion self-published the game on PC. An enhanced version of the game, ported by Rebellion themselves, is coming to Wii U in May 2013.Gameplay  FeaturesGameplay will revolve around stealth, with great emphasis on being silent and remaining undetected. Karl will carry a silenced pistol for covert kills and will be able to perform neck-breaks. Players will also be able to use the environment to their advantage, such as using loud noises in the area to mask the sound of the sniper rifle.Physics will be a big part of the game. Examples include taking into consideration all three coordinates, and bullet drop caused by gravity, crosswinds, as well as muzzle velocity. One will have to aim accordingly to compensate for these factors.Firing at explosive components (such as grenades hanging on someone's belt) to take out a group of enemies.An improved real-time, dynamic "Killcam" that explicitly portrays the bullet penetrating organs/skeleton.Improved ballistics.Players will be able to drag bodies and use them as bait to attract nearby enemies.Heart rate will be one of the factors to watch out for when aiming.Difficulty LevelsCadet - There are no bullet ballistics enabled.Marksman - There are simplified bullet ballistics.Sniper Elite - There are realistic bullet ballistics.Custom DifficultyA feature of Sniper Elite V2 is the ability to set very defined, custom difficulty settings altering the physics and assists rendered in the game.The custom difficult options are:Enemy SkillRookie - Enemies will offer limited resistance.Veteran - The enemies in the game will challenge you.Elite - Enemies will work together in teams and try to hunt you down.Ballistic RealismSimple - The player will always have steady aim and bullets will fly in straight lines unaffected by wind nor gravity.Limited - Gravity will affect bullets and the players scope will be slightly less steady.Realistic - Both gravity and wind will affect player bullets and you will need to monitor your heart rate closely while taking shots.Tactical AssistanceNone - All artificial assistance is disabled in the game, provides the most realistic sniping simulation.Moderate - The threat indicator, ghost image, enemy tagging and aim assistance are all enabled.Full - All artificial assistance is enabled in the game and the aim assist reticule when aiming down the scope appears quicker than usual.Multiplayer ModesSniper Elite V2 features several multiplayers modes both competetive and cooperative alike although the Team Deathmatch mode is unique to the PC version of the game. The remaining online modes are available on all platforms (XBOX 360, Playstation 3, PC) All online modes are restricted to online only and so far there is no support for split screen gameplay.CampaignThe entire campaign story-mode of Sniper Elite V2 can be played with a friend cooperatively.Team Deathmatch (PC Only)Supports up to 12 players in a single match - two teams of snipers face off against one another.DeathmatchFree for all mode where you face off against other snipers in a closed off 'arena.'Kill TallyA take on horde mode gameplay. Can also be played alone as well as with a friend cooperatively - players face off against waves of enemies in a closed off 'arena' and must survive as long as possible.Bombing RunA race against the clock mode - players must try to escape a scheduled bombing run by finding repair parts as well as fuel for their broken down vehicle.OverwatchA unique cooperative mode where one player take on the role of the sniper in a remote location while the other takes on the role of the spotter/soldier. While the soldier players goes about fullfilling various objectives the sniper must ensure his safety from above and provide sniper cover.Weapons and EquipmentThe game features prominent sniper rifles as well as other miscellaneous weapons from the latter part of the World War II time period from all major factions depicted in the game (American, German and Russian). Additionaly the developer advertised realistic uniforms for the Allied and Axis forces appropriate for those times.Sniper RiflesSpringfield M1903Kar98kSVT-40Mosin NagantGewehr 43PistolsWelrod PistolColt PistolLuger PistolSubmachine GunsThompson M1MP40PPSh-41EquipmentBinocularsRocksTrip MineLand MineF1 GrenadeStielhandgranateDynamitePanzerfaust LauncherSystem requirements for Sniper Elite V2Minimum system requirementsOS: Microsoft® Windows® Vista (Service Pack 2) or Windows® 7 (Windows® XP is NOT supported)Processor: Dual-core CPU with SSE3 (Intel® Pentium® D 3GHz / AMD Athlon™ 64 X2 4200) or betterMemory: 2GB system memoryHard Drive: 10GB of free drive spaceGraphics: Microsoft® DirectX® 10.0 compatible graphics card with 256 MB of memory (NVIDIA® GeForce® 8800 series / ATI Radeon™ HD 3870) or betterSound: Microsoft® DirectX® 10.0 compatible sound card or betterDirectX®: Microsoft® DirectX® 11.0Internet: Free STEAM® account and internet connection required for activation. Broadband connection and service required for multiplayer connectivity.Recommended system requirementsOS: Microsoft® Windows® Vista (Service Pack 2) or Windows® 7 (Windows® XP is NOT supported)Processor: Quad-Core CPUMemory: 4 GBHard Drive: 10 GB of free drive spaceGraphics Card: DirectX 11 compatible with 1024 MB RAM (NVIDIA GEFORCE GTX 560 or ATI RADEON 6950) Sound Card: DirectX compatibleDirectX®: Microsoft® DirectX® 11.0Internet: Free STEAM® account and internet connection required for activation. Broadband connection and service required for multiplayer connectivity.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17853">Sniper Elite</game><game id="33002">Sniper: Ghost Warrior 2</game><game id="37516">Snipers</game><game id="41928">Sniper Elite 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2139808-box_sev2.png</image></root>