<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34774</id><name>Rugby World Cup 2011</name><description>Rugby World Cup 2011 is a rugby union simulation game developed by HB Studios. It was published by 505 Games, which is the first rugby union games they have publish. Rugby World Cup 2011 is the official game of the IRFU Rugby World Cup 2011 in New Zealand. There will be twenty different international sides to choose from and the game was launched in Europe on August 26th, 2011. It was released in North American release on September 6th, 2011.Game ModesRugby World Cup 2011The main game mode found in the game. Players can choose from any of the twenty teams competing in the 2011 World Cup. Starting off at the pool stage, you can guide your team from there to the quarter finals, semi finals or final to try lift the William Webb Ellis Cup. The real-world fixtures and pools from the 2011 World Cup are available to play or can decide to make a random set of pools and fixtures.The official jerseys of the licensed teams in the game can only be used in this mode (the jerseys are unlocked using the game's Online Pass). Most of the game's offical stadia are only playable here too. From the main screen you can alter your team's squad and set your tactics and formations as well as look at your upcoming matches and your pool or tournament bracket.Warm-Up ToursPicking from one of the twenty teams, you can go on a "warm-up" tour and play a few friendly matches against teams from around the world. This mode is split in two parts: Northern Hemisphere and Southern Hemisphere. In the Northern Hemisphere tour you can play as a team from the south and take on northern team. The opposite applies to the Southern Hemisphere tour. The tougher tours (Six Nations and Tri Nations) are not unlocked until the other two tours are beaten. Here are the six available tours:Northern HemisphereNorth American (USA Eagles and Canada)Eastern Tour (Romania, Russia, Georgia and Japan)Six Nations (England, Ireland, France, Scotland, Wales and Italy)Southern HemispherePacific Islands (Tonga, Samoa and Fiji)South Atlantic (Argentina and Namibia)Tri Nations (South Africa, Australia and New Zealand)Online MultiplayerOnline Multiplayer is available for players over Xbox Live and PlayStation Network, which involve single 80-minute test matches. There are three modes of online play available; player match, ranked match and custom match. There are no tournament modes or leaderboards. In order to play online, the player must enter an Online Pass which is available on the Rugby World Cup game's official websiteInternational Test  Penalty Kick ShootoutInternational test is the game's exhibition mode. You can choose any of the available teams and play them in an 80-minute friendly match-up. Extra time and penalty kicks come into play if a draw is held at the end of a match. The Penality Kick mode allows the player to contest a penalty kicks shootout between two teams of their choosing.DemoA demo version of Rugby World Cup 2011 is was released on both the Playstation Network and Xbox Live Marketplace on August 2nd. The demo features two teams, England and South Africa, and and can be played in at the Eden Park ground in Auckland.TeamsThe game features all twenty national teams of the 2011 Rugby World Cup. Not all of the teams are fully licensed featured are fully licensed. Names of players from countries like Australia and New Zealand are not real and have been altered due to the lack of a official license.ArgentinaAustrailaCanada*England*FijiFrance*GeorgiaIreland*Italy*JapanNamibiaNew ZealandRomaniaRussiaSamoaScotland*South Africa*TongaUSA Eagles*Wales*(*) - Licensed with player names, kits etc.StadiumsThere are thirteen stadia to choose from in the game, of which three are licensed.Official StadiumsMillenium StadiumMurraryfieldTwickenhamUnlicensed StadiumsAuckland (Eden Park)Buenos Aires (Estadio José Amalfitani)Christchurch (Lancaster Park)Dublin (Aviva Stadium)Johannesburg (Ellis Park)Napier (McLean Park)Paris (Stade de France)Rugby ParkSouth PacificSydney (Stadium Australia)Wellington (Westpac Stadium)</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="596">Rugby</game><game id="20074">Rugby 2005</game><game id="21725">Rugby 06</game><game id="25537">Rugby 08</game><game id="4264">Jonah Lomu Rugby</game><game id="33167">Rugby Challenge</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/6/65194/1818635-51p3ptxhfrl._sl500_.jpg</image></root>