<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34784</id><name>DanceDanceRevolution</name><description>OverviewDanceDanceRevolution is a music-rhythm game and is part of the long running Dance Dance Revolution franchise. The Xbox 360 and PS3 versions feature a new visual style whereas the Wii version sticks to the more arcade style the series is famous for.GameplayThe core gameplay is the same as previous DDR games with the exception of motion control being added for the Wii and PS3 versions. The Xbox 360 version does not have Kinect Support However.As with previous DDR's the game is played using a dance mat peripheral featuring 8 arrows pointing in different directions that you step on in time with the arrows scrolling on the screen.You can also now record your performance using the PlayStation EYE! or Xbox Live Vision camera and upload it directly to YouTube.In the new Battle Mode, players can compete in a Dance Off! Players take turns to dance as they compete over the ownership of arrows.Song ListLicensed Tracks:ArtistSong TitleOrianthiAccording to YouKe$haAnimalLady GagaBad RomanceJordin SparksBattlefieldKool and the GangCelebrationParamorecrushcrushcrushMartha and the VandellasDancing in the StreetTrainHey, Soul SisterLeona LewisI Got YouJason MrazI'm YoursNatasha BedingfieldLove Like ThisThe B-52'sLove ShackEverything But The GirlMissingKelly ClarksonMy Life Would Suck Without YouLady AntebellumNeed You NowGorillaz (feat. Mick Jones  Paul SimononPlastic BeachDuran DuranRioSean PaulSo FineBananaramaVenusSister SledgeWe Are FamilyOriginal Songs by Konami Japan:ArtistSong TitleNaoki feat. FracusRescue Mejun  NRG Factory feat. Anna KAelinDreaming Can Make A Wish Come TrueAtomsoak feat. CerolPrivate EyeU1 (NPD3 Style)  KIDD KAZMEOIN THE ZONEJ-Mi  Midi-D feat. Hanna StockzellTop The ChartsNaoki Feat. Brenda BurchLet's Get Away</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre><genre id="44">Fitness</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="35532">Dance Central 2</game><game id="31705">Dance Central</game><game id="27859">Just Dance</game><game id="35553">Just Dance 3</game><game id="31347">Just Dance 2</game><game id="31978">Karaoke Revolution: Glee</game><game id="31724">Michael Jackson: The Experience</game><game id="36861">Nickelodeon Dance</game><game id="40961">Pump It Up!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2280557-box_ddr_2.png</image></root>