<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34811</id><name>Sanctum</name><description>OverviewSanctum is a tower defense game played from the first-person perspective developed by Coffee Stain Studios, built on Unreal Engine 3. You play as Skye, an elite soldier protecting her home town of Elysion One from a devastating alien horde.GameplayThe game is split between a building phase and an extermination phase.Building PhasePlayers build and upgrade eight different towers, as well as having the ability to upgrade Skye's three weapons.UpgradingDuring the building phase, players have to option to upgrade their towers and their weapons. Both towers and weapons have five levels of upgrades, each costing more than the last.Extermination PhaseWaves of varying creatures will then attempt to reach the core in the extermination phase, and the player's mission is to prevent them from doing so. The player controls Skye to provide support to the towers built during the building phase. Waves are formed of either a single enemy type or a combination of two.DLCSanctum's debut DLC was released on 26th September, 2011. Content included two new maps and three extra towers. In addition to the DLC, a free update entitled Elysion One Overrun! brings two more towers, a new map, and an extra weapon for Skye. A Second DLC Map pack was released on October 12, 2012.TowersAnti-AirAnti-Air launches missiles at the enemy and causes blast damage to any target within the area.Level UpgradeDamage per HitDamage per SecondShots per SecondRangeArea of EffectUpgrade CostSell Price190450.510.42.0---1922001000.511.02.3505734002000.511.72.610013247903950.512.32.6200282515807900.513.02.64005826320016000.513.62.68001182GatlingMakes up for its poor accuracy with a high rate of fire. Gatling is ideal at short distances.Level UpgradeDamage per HitDamage per SecondShots per SecondRangeSpreadUpgrade CostSell Price14369.03.99.1---8288911.14.09.1202331316312.54.19.1405342129814.24.29.18011353964716.64.39.1160233680132816.64.49.1320473LightningLightning discharges powerful bolts of electrical energy. At level 3 and level 5, Lightning will also produce a respective second and third damaging bolt that spreads out to other enemies.Level UpgradeDamage per HitDamage per SecondShots per SecondRangeBolt Damage*Upgrade CostSell Price1155470.32.4155---1523601080.32.5360404537202160.32.6480, 24080105414404320.32.7960, 480160225529758930.32.81700, 850, 4253204656612518380.32.93500, 1750, 875640945MortarThis powerful tower fires explosive rounds over large distances, but is rendered useless if the enemy draws near.Level UpgradeDamage per HitDamage per SecondShots per SecondRangeArea of EffectUpgrade CostSelling Price130150.57.91.1---15290450.58.01.140453180900.58.21.28010543601800.58.31.216022557203600.58.41.2320465614407200.58.61.3640945Scatter LaserScatter Laser randomly targets any enemy within its vicinity, unleashing high-powered beams with a very high rate of fire.Level UpgradeDamage per HitDamage per SecondShots per SecondRangeSpreadUpgrade CostSell Price163054.29.1---152157554.39.1404533015054.49.18010546030054.59.1160225512060054.69.13204656240120054.79.1640945Slow FieldSlow Field reduces the running speed of all creatures that enter its area of effect. Slowing effect stacks with Skye's freezing weapon.Level UpgradeSlow RateUpgrade CostSell Price120%---15230%4045340%80105450%160225560%320465670%640945TelevatorA teleporter and elevator hybrid, Televator can elevate the player to a higher altitude, and can also teleport the player to its position from any point in the map.Level UpgradePurchase CostSell Price---43BlockThe most important part of any defence, Block is used to divert enemy forces and provides the foundation for all offensive towers.Level UpgradePurchase CostSell Price---22Killing floorLevelDamage Per ShotShots Per SecondDamage Per SecondBuy/Upgrade PriceTotal CostSelling Price11530.34620201524590.313840604539190.327680140105418350.3551160300225536700.31101320620465673550.322076401260945Increases damage dealt to enemies on block.Amp FieldLevelDamage AmpAmp% Per Resource SpentBuy/Upgrade PriceTotal CostSelling Price125%1.25202015250%0.83406045375%0.54801401054100%0.331603002255150%0.243206204656233%0.186401260945Increased damage of shots that pass through it.HoloLevelDamage IncreaseBuy/Upgrade CostTotal CostSelling Price128%10108256%203023384%4070534112%801501135140%1603102336168%320630473ViolatorLevelDamage Per ShotShots Per SecondDamage Per SecondRangeBuy/Upgrade PriceTotal CostSelling Price1920.19171125251922650.195011.550755735110.201021210017513249700.2120412.5200375282518600.2240913400775582635500.238171380015751182Fires beams that pierce enemies.PenetratorLevelDamage Per ShotShots Per SecondDamage Per SecondRangeBuy/Upgrade PriceTotal CostSelling Price1450.2951010821350.2275.320302332700.2545.540705345400.21085.880150113510800.22166160310233621600.24326320630473Slows flying enemies.KairosLevelArea of EffectBuy/Upgrade PriceTotal CostSelling Price1125251921.350755731.610017513241.920037528252.340077558262.680015751182Releases a swarm of drones that attack one enemy at a time.DroneLevelDamage Per ShotShots Per SecondDamage Per SecondRangeBuy/Upgrade PriceTotal CostSelling Price164243.42020152154603.440604533041203.48014010546042403.4160300225512044803.4320620465624049603.46401260945Fire rate increased the longer its locked onto a target.AcceleratorLevelDamage Per ShotShots Per SecondDamage Per SecondRangeBuy/Upgrade PriceTotal CostSelling Price1800.5403.420201522400.51203.440604534800.52403.48014010549600.54803.4160300225519200.59603.4320620465638400.519203.46401260945WeaponsAssault GunSimilar to the Gatling tower, Skye's Assault Gun has a very high rate of fire, but will overheat with prolonged use. Launches grenades with its alternate firing mode, damaging any enemy within its blast radius.Level UpgradeDamage per HitDamage per SecondShots per SecondGrenade DamageGrenade Hit AreaUpgrade Cost19819401.1---21515010701.150327307.5111401.1100454599.4112801.1200580100012.55601.14006170212512.511201.1800Freeze GunFreeze Gun deploys a small orb, slowing the movement speed of any enemy it attaches itself to. Additionally, can completely freeze a small number of enemies in place for a small period of time with its alternate firing mode.Level UpgradeSlow PercentageSlow AreaFreeze TimeUpgrade Cost1250.52---2290.52.9503330.53.81004370.64.72005510.65.64006550.66.5800SniperPerfect for attacking weak spots for massive damage, Sniper is a high-powered rifle suited for taking down large foes over great distances.Level UpgradeDamage per HitClip SizeDamage per SecondUpgrade Cost184133.6---21142695031633132.210042644257.5200549244804006105141025.5800Rexmissile launcherLevelDamageUpgrade CostRounds Per MagSecondary damage1204---186220450286328710031214446200418657424005312612868006542ShotgunLevelDamage Per ShellDamage Per PelletDamage Per SecondDamage Per MagAmmo1136171505444224030264120053416524582496647609583653207513601701496108808629123643202232968TeslaLevelDamagePrimary AOEShots Per SecondSecondary DamageUpgrade CostDamage Per Second150.331056x3---502100.3310112x3501503190.3310216x31001904380.3310432x32003805640.3310691x340064061360.33101365x38001360EnemiesLand EnemiesNameStrengthsWeaknessesBlockerTemporary invulnerabilityLow HPSmall numbersBobble HeadImmune to body damageAlmost immune to turret damageWavering movement makes it difficult to hitLow HPSmall numbersChargerVery fast on straight pathsVery slow went confronted with cornersHovererImmune to frontal damageSlowEasy to land critical hits from the backRunnerFastAttack in large numbersLow HPSoakerVery high HPRepeated damageSmall numbersTankHigh HPReduced damage takenHeadshotsWalkerLarge numbers---Big WalkerHigh HPEasy to land critical hitsHeadshotsSmall numbersAir EnemiesNameStrengthsWeaknessesDodgerIntermittent movementLow HPGliderFast movingLow HPSpore PodLarge numbersSlowEasy to land critical hitsSoundtrackSoundtrackSanctum FPS-TD: OST, composed by Gustaf Tivander, was released on 17th August, 2011.Skye's Theme (5:17)Below (3:15)The Wanderers (5:02)Loek 3 (5:16)Cloud Control (3:01)Glider Hunt (4:37)Spore Gas Serenade (3:41)Explorer (3:35)Elysion One (05:10)Meat Grinder (05:17)Core Guardians (03:24)System RequirementsPCOperating System: Windows XP SP2, Windows Vista or Windows 7Processor: 2.0+ GHz Core 2 DuoRAM Memory: 2 GBHard Disk Space: 2 GB free hard drive spaceVideo Card: Shader Model 3, compatible video cardDirectX®: 9.0c or higherSound Card: DirectX 9.0c compatible, 16-bitMACOperating Systen: OS X version 10.6.3 or laterProcessor: 1.6 GHz (Dual Core) Intel CPURAM Memory: 2GBHard Disk Space: 2 GBVideo Card: Open GL 3.3 / Shader Model 3 capable graphics card with 256 MB video RAM</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="29806">Monday Night Combat</game><game id="34304">Iron Brigade</game><game id="32474">Dungeon Defenders</game><game id="34265">Orcs Must Die!</game><game id="33593">Dungeon Defenders: First Wave</game><game id="37860">Orcs Must Die! 2</game><game id="37420">Sanctum 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4344/1760553-sanctum_logo__2_.jpg</image></root>