<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34833</id><name>Sonic Generations</name><description>OverviewWelcome back to Green Hill Zone!Sonic Generations is a hybrid 2.5D/3D platformer developed by Sonic Team and published by Sega for the Xbox 360 (on November 1, 2011), PlayStation 3 (also on November 1, 2011), PC (via Steam, on November 3, 2011, ported by Devil's Details), and Nintendo 3DS (on November 22, 2011, developed by Dimps). Created to celebrate the 20th anniversary of the Sonic the Hedgehog franchise, the game remasters a level from certain mainline Sonic games (Sonic the Hedgehog, Sonic the Hedgehog 2, and Sonic  Knuckles for the "Classic" era; Sonic Adventure, Sonic Adventure 2, and Sonic Heroes for the "Adventure" era; and Sonic the Hedgehog (2006), Sonic Unleashed, and Sonic Colors for the "Modern" era), in which players run through each stage in two ways: in classic 2D perspective as Classic Sonic, and in modern 3D perspective as Modern Sonic.The story, set sometime after the events of Sonic Colors, has Sonic and his friends being sucked into various "time holes" by a mysterious new being, scattering them into different places in history. As Sonic is thrown back to his early days in Green Hill Zone, he encounters a younger, less talkative self (known in the game as Classic Sonic). Together, they must rescue their friends (including a younger Classic Tails) and find out the true mastermind behind the mysterious Time Eater.The game features unlockables (such as concept artwork) and references to the 90s era of Sega games. A playable version of the original Sonic the Hedgehog is also unlockable for the Xbox 360 and PlayStation 3 versions of the game.GameplayGameplay is broken up between two versions of Sonic. The 1990's-era-based "Classic Sonic" sees levels from a strictly side-scrolling perspective, with many of the game mechanics being pulled directly from the series' 16-bit heritage. "Modern Sonic" on the other hand borrows more heavily from games like the Sonic Unleashed titles and Sonic Colors Wii, with boost-focused gameplay punctuated by perspective shifts between side-scrolling and behind-the-back 3D. A 2D hub world exists between stages, allowing players to pick between levels by walking up to that stage in the environment and cycling through a menu of available "Acts".Though "Classic Sonic" and "Modern Sonic" are the only playable characters, after completing the main two acts of a stage, you rescue one of Sonic's many friends, who hang around in the hub world and challenge you to complete optional side missions. Each act has 10 challenges attached to it (5 as "Classic Sonic", 5 as "Modern Sonic"). Beating these will unlock additional music and artwork, as well as restore that particular hub area back to normal by returning color to it.Xbox 360/Playstation 3/PC ZonesEach zone includes a main act for both Classic Sonic and Modern Sonic. Essentially, Sonic Generations features 9 Classic Sonic stages and 9 Modern Sonic stages, not counting side acts and boss encounters.Each zone and boss is based on a level or boss from a previous Sonic title. As coinciding with the anniversary theme of Sonic Generations, you are essentially taken on a tour through 20 years of Sonic's history."Classic Era" StagesSonic the Hedgehog (1991): Green Hill ZoneSonic the Hedgehog 2: Chemical Plant ZoneSonic and Knuckles: Sky Sanctuary ZoneBoss: Death Egg Robot / Death Egg Zone (Sonic The Hedgehog 2)Rival: Metal Sonic / Stardust Speedway Bad Future ( Sonic CD)"Adventure Era" StagesSonic Adventure: Speed HighwaySonic Adventure 2: City EscapeSonic Heroes: Seaside HillBoss: Perfect Chaos / Station Square ( Sonic Adventure)Rival: Shadow the Hedgehog / Space Colony ARK ( Sonic Adventure 2)"Modern Era" StagesSonic the Hedgehog (2006): Crisis CitySonic Unleashed: Rooftop RunSonic Colors: Planet WispBoss: Egg Dragoon / Eggmanland (Sonic Unleashed)Rival: Silver the Hedgehog / Crisis City (Sonic The Hedgehog (2006))Bonus ContentCasino Night Zone Pinball Table (Pre-Order DLC)Sonic the Hedgehog(Full 1991 Game) Sonic Generations 3DSFACT: Orcas hate hedgehogsThe Nintendo 3DS version of Sonic Generations has, for the most part, separate levels from the PS3/360/PC editions. Though the game's producer Takashi Iizuka originally mentioned the 3DS version would pull from Sonic's Gameboy Advance and Nintendo DS entries, the vast majority of the levels are still largely from Sonic's console outings, save for a single level from Sonic Rush.Each zone includes a main act for both Classic Sonic and Modern Sonic. Essentially, the 3DS Sonic Generations features 7 Classic Sonic stages and 7 Modern Sonic stages, not counting side acts and boss encounters."Classic Era" StagesSonic The Hedgehog (1991): Green Hill ZoneSonic The Hedgehog 2: Casino Night ZoneSonic  Knuckles: Mushroom Hill ZoneBoss: Big Arms / Launch Base Zone (Sonic 3)Rival: Metal Sonic / Casino Night (Sonic 2)"Adventure Era" StagesSonic Adventure: Emerald CoastSonic Adventure 2: Radical HighwayBoss: Biolizard / Cannon's Core (Sonic Adventure 2)Rival: Shadow the Hedgehog / Radical Highway (Sonic Adventure 2)"Modern Era" StagesSonic Rush: Water PalaceSonic Colors: Tropical ResortBoss: Egg Emperor / Final Fortress (Sonic Heroes)Rival: Silver the Hedgehog / Tropical Resort (Sonic Colors) Collector's EditionTo celebrate the 20 years of the hedgehog, Sega released a limited collector's edition. These were released in European regions for the Xbox 360 and Playstation 3 and included:We really hope you like HedgehogsLenticular Sleeve with standard gameA "collectable" figurine which features the current generation ''Modern Sonic'' and the ''Classic Sonic''.A commemorative numbered golden ring''20 Years of Sonic'' art book20th Anniversary Soundtrack (Songs picked from Sonic Team)"History of Sonic: Birth of an Icon" DVD DocumentaryCasino Night Mini-Game DLC VoucherA massive collector's edition box with both hedgehogs featured.TriviaThis is one of the few console Sonic games to feature new versions of music originally composed by Dreams Come True bassist Masato Nakamura. It has been a long-standing rumor that Nakamura asks high licensing fees regarding the music he wrote for Sonic the Hedgehog and Sonic the Hedgehog 2. The only other post-Genesis Sonic console games to feature new recordings of Nakamura's work are Sonic Adventure 2 and Sonic the Hedgehog (2006).Scattered around the "City Escape" stage are billboards and posters referencing a number of easter eggs, including: Wanted posters for Fang the Sniper, Bark the Polar Bear, and Bean the Dynamite (See: Sonic Triple Trouble, Sonic the Fighters). Missing Persons posters for Mighty the Armadillo and Ray the Flying Squirrel (See: SegaSonic the Hedgehog, Knuckles Chaotix). Billboards for Charmy Bee Honey, Chao in Space 2, chili-dog restaurants, and more.Voice samples from the Sega Saturn "It's Out There" promotional video were used by Cash Cash for their Sonic R "Super Sonic Racing" remix. These voice clips were removed for the OST release of this song and only exist as part of the in-game music.Sonic Generations has been in development since Sonic Unleashed was finished in 2008.Issue #230 of the Archie Sonic the Hedgehog comic series has a tie in to Sonic Generations.The Chaos Emerald given to you by Shadow the Hedgehog for defeating him in a rival battle is the 4th Chaos Emerald in the game, a (most likely unintentional) reference to a line in 2005's Shadow the Hedgehog that has since achieved ironic cult status among fans, where Shadow suddenly shouts "Where's that damn fourth Chaos Emerald?!" during a cutscene. It is also the yellow chaos emerald, the same color as the fake emerald Sonic used to execute Shadow's "Chaos Control" ability in Sonic Adventure 2.Sonic 1 Concept Art In a mission where ''Modern Sonic'' must compete against Vector the Crocodile in a rhythm competition, Vector stands on a concert stage with keyboards behind him. Vector was originally slated to be a character in the original 1991 Sonic the Hedgehog game, when the original plot involved Sonic as the lead singer of a rock and roll band. In this now lost concept, Vector played keyboard. This is also referenced in Sonic Heroes, where the team blast attack of Vector, Espio, and Charmy involve them performing as a band, and Vector screaming in a microphone, destroying all enemies nearby.Even though this game revisits "Crisis City" from Sonic The Hedgehog (2006), that entire timeline was completely erased from continuity by the ending to the very game it originated from, technically making its existence impossible.PC System RequirementsMinimum System Requirements:OS: Windows XP, Vista or Windows 7CPU: Intel Pentium Dual-Core T4200 2 GHz or AMD equivalentRAM: 2GB in XP/7, 3GB in VistaHDD: 11 GB free disk spaceGraphics: 512 MB Graphics MemorySound Card: DirectX 9 CompatibleDirectX: Version 9Recommended System Requirements:OS: Windows XP, Vista or Windows 7CPU: Intel Core i5 2.66 GHz or AMD Phenom II X4 3.0 GHzRAM: 3 GBHDD: 11 GB free disk spaceGraphics: 1 GB Graphics MemorySound Card: DirectX 9 CompatibleDirectX: Version 9</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7670">Crash of the Titans</game><game id="25673">Ratchet &amp; Clank Future: A Crack in Time</game><game id="15212">Ratchet &amp; Clank Future: Tools of Destruction</game><game id="16094">Super Mario Galaxy</game><game id="26839">Super Mario Galaxy 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2211868-box_sonicgen.png</image></root>