<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34891</id><name>Dawn of War II: Retribution – The Last Standalone</name><description>This standalone release includes only one of the multiplayer modes in the Dawn of War II expansion Retribution, with the option to unlock the full expansion at an additional cost.The Last Stand mode is a three player cooperative survival mode that pits heroes from each faction against waves of enemies. There are currently two maps for to hold out on and both contain 20 waves of progressively harder enemies. Each wave grants more experience to the player, that is used to unlock more gear for the hero being played. While there are only currently 6 heroes to choose from each one is continually being updated with different gear for different roles. As you customize your hero to fit your team of three, you are scored in every round of last stand on how well your team preforms and ranked on a global ladder.Basic RulesScoring: The number of points your team racks up is determined by the number of kills accumulated. Each kill has a preset value which is dependent upon its unit type, the stronger the unit more it is worth. Granted your team's performance is tracked by three factors that contribute to a overall multiplier for each kill.Time: Each wave has a preset time to be finished in. If you fail to kill all the enemies in the time provided, you will no longer gain any more points. On the flip side of this, the faster enemies fall, the more they are worth. The timer provides at the most 5x multiplier.Control Points: Every map contains 2 control points and each control point is worth 3x multiplier. The challenge is in holding these nodes as squads of enemies try to take them back while simultaneously trying to kill you.Survival: Every wave some doesn't die you will gain one more multiplier. You can at the most only have 20x multiplier and if any point in the round someone is to die, it will reset back to one.Combat: The style of the fighting is derived from the PvP portion of Retribution but without all the balancing. You are given all the overpowered tools to crush your enemies but have a limited inventory. As each hero can only hold one weapon (one 2-hander or duel wield), one armor set, three accessory items and one commander item. You must design your hero, while keeping in mind the balance you must make with your team in order to complete the map with the best possible score.MapsThe Bloodied ColosseumThis the launch map for last stand and is the easier of the two. It is easier due to not only its weaker waves but its size as well. Bloodied Colosseum is very large and escaping enemies is easy when you can leave their firing range. This map is most useful for lower-level heroes and players new to the game.The layout of the map is done in a symmetric fashion. With the four entry points of the enemies lied out in a cross and all objects of strategic value set between them.Wave 1: 100 experience4x Shoota Boyz squadsWave 2: 100 experience4x Hormagaunt squads2x Termagant squadsWave 3: 100 experience6x Guardian squadsWave 4: 200 experience6x Imperial Guardsmen Squads1x Force Commander2x ApothecariesWave 5: 150 experience2x Warrior Broods4x Termagant squadsWave 6: 150 experience2x pairs of Ork Nobz6x Shoota Boyz squads3x Stikkbombaz squadsWave 7: 150 experience2x Shuriken cannon teams4x Banshee squads2x warp spider squadsWave 8: 300 experience3x Zoanthropes2x Warrior Broods4x Termagant squads4x Hormagaunt squadsWave 9: 200 experience9x Banshee squads6x Shuriken cannon teams2x warp spider squadsWave 10: 200 experience10x Tactical Marine squads6x Scout squadsWave 11: 200 experience6x 'Uge Hammer Nobz8x Stronga Shoota Boyz squads6x Storm Boyz squads2x 'Uge Choppa BoyzWave 12: 400 experience6x Guardian squads5x Warp Spider squads2x Banshee squads4x Wraithlords2x Shuriken Cannon teamsWave 13: 250 experience9x Stronga Shoota Boyz4x "Uge Choppa Nobs4x Rokkit Launchaz1x Ork NobzWave 14: 250 experience7x Termagant squads2x Warrior brood4x Raveners4x HormagauntWave 15: 250 experience8x Stikkbombaz6x Rokkit Luachaz5x Stronga Shoota Boyz8x 'Uge Choppa NobWave 16: 600 experience3x Clones of player's teamWave 17: 300 experience8x Hormagaunts5x Termagants2x Warrior Broods4x Raveners3x Carnifexs1x Lictor AlphaWave 18: 300 experience11x Stronga Shoota Boyz4x "Uge Choppa Nobz3x Rokkit Launchaz4x 'Uge Hamma Nobz6x Deff Dreads1x WarbossWave 19: 300 experience11x Scout squads6x Tactical Marine squads4x Dreadnoughts3x Dreadnought with assualt cannons1x Terminator MarineWave 20: 600 experience1x Clone team12x Bloodletter pairs1x Licter Alpha1x Warboss1x Terminator Marine1x Chaos LordCompletion of a round on this map grants a total of 5,100 experience.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="38224">Company of Heroes 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/13692/1766428-header_292x136.jpg</image></root>