<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>34975</id><name>Assassin's Creed: Revelations</name><description>DevelopmentAssassin's Creed: Revelations was developed simultaneously at six different  Ubisoft studios, indicating the scope of this sequel in comparison to previous instalments. Ubisoft used a new type of facial technology entitled 'Mocam' that Game Informer describes as:"an intriguing amalgamation of traditional animation, performance capture and the fascinating new style of performance on display in games like  L.A. Noire."An unfortunate side-effect of this new face technology is that returning characters, such as  Ezio Auditore,  Altair Ibn la-Ahad, and most especially  Desmond Miles, bear little-to-no resemblance to themselves from previous games.StoryEzioAfter being forced to murder his friend  Lucy, Desmond falls into a coma and is put into the  Animus's "black room" in an attempt to stave off brain death, rendering him a vegetable. Unbeknownst to the other Assassins, his consciousness is confronted with a challenge by the Animus and the "digital ghost" of  Subject 16; Desmond must relive one last experience from the life of his ancestor, Ezio Auditore da Firenze, in order to reconstruct his fractured mind and awaken from his coma. It is revealed that the primary problem is that Desmond was already on the brink of going insane because of the crossover in his mind between his own memories and those of Ezio and their mutual ancestor Altair Ibn la-Ahad. In order to seperate their memories from his own and save himself, Desmond must synchronize his mind with a "key memory" that actually connects himself, Altair and Ezio together. Desmond begins reliving Ezio's later life in which he questions his life as an Assassin and how his life would've been had he made different decisions.Ezio embarks on a spiritual journey to  Masyaf in a journey of self-discovery. Upon arrival, he discovers that Masyaf has been conquered by  Templars. Upon infiltration of Masyaf, Ezio finds an ancient library chamber which can only be opened by five seals hidden in the ancient Ottoman city of  Constantinople. Within Constantinople, he finds a Templar threat forming in the region, threatening to destabilize it, and must defeat it as he defeated the Borgia in the past in order to both recover the seals and bring peace to Turkey. At the same time, the seals themselves are made of ancient technology like the Pieces of Eden; using them allows Ezio to relive the memories of Altair in much the same way that the Animus allows Desmond to relive the memories of Ezio.In the end, Ezio unlocks the library room with the seals, and discovers that in truth, it is not a library, but a tomb; the final resting place of Altair, who sealed himself in with a Piece of Eden and a sixth seal showing his final moments. At this moment, the key memory takes place; standing in front of the body of Altair, Ezio turns and addresses Desmond, whom he somehow senses is watching him from centuries in the future, expressing his hope that Desmond will be able to find the answers to the questions that eluded Ezio during his lifetime. With his mind repaired, Desmond is contacted by Jupiter, one of The Ones Who Came Before, who gives him a grim vision of the end of the previous Human civilization, a doomsday which is rapidly approaching again, before giving Desmond another vision, of the location of a secret cache of technology, failed attempts to prevent the end of days, which the Assassins can hopefully use to save mankind. At this, Desmond awakens, and tells his friends he knows what he needs to do, only for them to reveal that they also somehow knew about it, and have taken him to the location while he was unconscious.GameplayAssassin's Creed: Revelations plays similarly to its predecessors, evolving the current formula, as well as presenting new gameplay additions. New features include:Ezio is now in possession of a Hookblade. This hookblade is not only usable in close combat to pull enemies in but also allows him to use various zipwires scattered throughout the city and make corner chase breaker movements.A new crafting system has been implemented into the game which will allow players to craft over three hundred types of bombs from 3 categories: lethal, tactical and diversion. Ezio can carry up to 15 bombs. Eagle Vision is now 'Eagle Sense.' It will allow you to focus on a particular character and is described as: "You'll get an approximation of where he will go. If you're able to detect the path a guard will take, you can run ahead, set a bomb, and create a trap or an ambush."Assassins' Dens will act as the new 'Borgia Towers.' These dens are placed throughout the city and the player will need to complete set tasks in order to overthrow the Templar influence before they can use the den. Ubisoft have said that there will be a larger variety of methods/tasks that will allow the player to take these dens. Once a player is in control of a den they will be able to refurbish buildings in the region as well as set the behaviour of guards. In addition to this, players will be able to set a 'Master Assassin' to control the den so that they absolutely cannot be taken by the Templar. If you are unable to make it to a den that is currently under attack, you will be able to send your assassin recruits to defend it.MultiplayerSimilar to  Assassin's Creed: Brotherhood, this game features a multiplayer component. Ubisoft placed a bigger focus and structured narrative in the multiplayer of Revelations then the previous multiplayer incarnation.Various Templars in Assassin's Creed: RevelationsThe multiplayer of Revelations features new customization options, both aesthetic and weapons, as well as the ability to create 'guilds', an specialised term for 'Clans'.A "beta" for Assassin's Creed: Revelations was released on Playstation 3, early for PlayStation+ members. The early access for AC: Revelations Multiplayer came out on September 1, 2011 and the beta ended on September 10, 2011. As this was barely two months before the game released, this is not really a beta so much as a multiplayer-only demo.Downloadable ContentUpon the games launch, Ubisoft stated that it was working on various types on DLC for the game. The first one titled "Ancestors Character Pack" was released in December 2011, the four playable characters include Privateer, Corsair, Brigand and Gladiator.Meet the new guysThe second stayed within the multiplayer aspect of the game and was titled the "Mediterranean Traveler Map Pack" and included 3 brand new maps and 3 from the previous game and was released late January 2012.The first single player story driven DLC was released late February 2012 titled "The Lost Archive". It includes an insight into Subject 16's capture and the past of Lucy Stillman.EditionsSignature Edition (Pre-order Bonus)Signature Edition DetailsAnnounced at the end of the debut trailer, Assassin's Creed: Revelations is also available in a special 'Signature Edition' when pre-ordered from select retailers. The Signature Edition seems to have standard edition packaging but also contains the following:An Exclusive Single Player MissionWeapon Capacity UpgradesAn Exclusive Multi-player Character'Embers' Animated Short Film"Best of AC Soundtracks" CDSpecial EditionSpecial Edition DetailsRetailer exclusive Special Edition.Special Edition Packaging"Best of AC Soundtracks" CDSingle Player Armor: Turkish Assassin ArmorMultiplayer Character: The CrusaderMultiplayer Character: Ottoman DoctorCollector EditionCollector Edition DetailsThe Collector Edition is a retailer exclusive special edition SKU with unique packaging and items.Collector Box Packaging50 Page Artbook'Embers' Animated Short Film DVD"Best of AC Soundtracks" CDSingle Player Mission: Vlad the Impaler PrisonMultiplayer Character: The CrusaderMultiplayer Character: Ottoman JesterAnimus EditionAnimus Edition DetailsThe Animus Edition is a retailer exclusive special edition SKU which features unique packaging as well as exclusive items and DLC. The Animus Edition features:Animus Box PackagingAssassin's Creed Encyclopaedia'Embers' Animated Short Film DVD"Best of AC Soundtracks" CDSingle Player Mission: Vlad the Impaler PrisonSingle Player Armor: Armor of BrutusSingle Player: Weapon Capacity UpgradesMultiplayer Character: The CrusaderMultiplayer Character: Ottoman JesterPS3 EditionAll PS3 versions of AC: Revelations come with a bonus copy of the original  Assassin's Creed.PC System RequirementsMinimumRecommendedOS: Windows® XP SP3 / Windows Vista® SP2 /Windows 7® SP1Processor: Intel Core®2 Duo E4300 @ 1.8 Ghz or AMD Athlon64 X2 4600+ @ 2.4GHZMemory: 1.5 GB Windows® XP / 2 GB Windows Vista® - Windows 7®Graphics: 256 MB DirectX® 9.0–compliant card with Shader Model 3.0 or higher (see supported list)DirectX®: DirectX® June2010 or newerHard Drive: 12 GBSound: DirectX 9.0 – compliant sound cardDRM: U-Play DRM requires one time activation online or an always online internet connectionOS: Windows® XP SP3 / Windows Vista® SP2 /Windows 7®Processor: Intel Core®2 Duo E6700 @ 2.6 GHz or AMD Athlon64 X2 6000+ @ 3.0Ghz or betterMemory: 1.5 GB Windows® XP / 2 GB Windows Vista® - Windows 7®Graphics: 512 MB DirectX® 9.0 – compliant card with Shader Model 5.0 or higherDirectX®: DirectX® June2010 or newerHard Drive: 12 GBSound: Surround Sound 5.1 capable sound cardSoundtrackThe soundtrack was composed by Lorne Balfe and Jesper Kyd. It was released digitally by Ubisoft Music on three volumes on November 15, 2011.  Assassin's Creed: Revelations - Original Game Soundtrack - The Complete Recordings, Vol. 1No.Track TitleLength (72:08)1.Assassin's Creed Theme4:442.Animus Island2:523.The Road to Masysaf2:554.The Wounded Eagle2:025.The Noose Tightens1:266.Sailing to Constantinople1:357.Master and Mentor1:458.Welcome to Konstantiniyye3:329.The Crossroads of the World3:3210.Sofia Sartor0:4311.Son of Umar1:2412.No Mistakes2:4813.The Traitor3:3914.A Heated Discussion1:5015.Ambush3:0916.A Familiar Face1:2217.Byzantium3:2318.Nova Roma4:0219.Templar Occupation3:3620.Arrocco2:3121.On the Attack4:2822.Last of the Palaiologi0:5723.Yerebatan Cistern1:5424.Fight or Flight2:4725.Galata Tower2:0526.Die by the Blade3:0627.Forum of Ox1:5728.Suleiman's Grief2:04  Assassin's Creed: Revelations - Original Game Soundtrack - The Complete Recordings, Vol. 2No.Track TitleLength (55:33)1.Istanbul3:012.We Talk Together1:153.Altair Escapes1:384.Betrayal1:135.The Mentors Return1:566.Rebuilding the Brotherhood2:017.Of Life and Death1:278.Greek Fire2:079.An Unsubtle Approach0:5010.The Hidden City0:3311.Infiltration2:0912.Cappadocia3:5213.Street Fight2:2314.Mastermind1:3215.Notorious3:1016.Constantinopolis3:3617.Investigation2:1118.Everything Changes3:0319.You Have Earned Your Rest1:0920.Passing the Torch0:5221.Crossed Swords2:0222.Scheduled for Deletion1:0123.Altair and Darim1:1524.The Library2:5725.The Revelation2:2626.Labored and Lost2:5427.Reunion0:5728.Enough for One Life2:03 Assassin's Creed: Revelations - Original Game Soundtrack - The Complete Recordings, Vol. 3No.Track TitleLength (33:45)1.Abstergo Industries2:042.Rhodes0:423.The Hunted2:104.Antioch0:355.The Hunter1:556.Kill Streak0:387.On the Run1:578.Constantinople0:439.In the Simulation2:1010.Find the Target2:0511.Firenze0:4112.Welcome to the Fold1:4313.Souk0:3514.Chase the Target2:0315.The Lobby1:5616.Venezia0:4617.Let the Chase Begin2:0418.Sienna0:3719.Tracking Templar2:1320.Castel Gandolfo0:4221.On a Kill Streak0:4622.The Pursuit2:0023.Assassinate the Target1:5524.San Donato0:45</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20464">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Conviction</game><game id="21213">Mirror's Edge</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2074739-box_acr.png</image></root>