<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35168</id><name>Monster Bash</name><description>OverviewMonster Bash is a pinball machine that features the Universal Monsters. Monster Bash was re-created digitally as part of the Table Pack #3 DLC for The Pinball Arcade.Game ModesThe main goal in Monster Bash is to collect the musical instrument of all six monsters. To collect an instrument the player must complete one of the six modes.Creature FeatureThe goal of Creature Feature is to hit all of the main shots and shoot all the ramps and loops before the time runs out. The player has twenty seconds to complete each shot. Each shot that is made will reset the timer to twenty seconds again. If the player completes this mode, Creature From the Black Lagoon's saxophone will be awarded.Full Moon FeverIn Full Moon Fever the goal is to shoot the ball through the two ramps four times each. If Full Moon Fever is completed, The Wolfman's drums will be awarded.Ball  ChainTo start Ball  Chain the player must shoot each of the ramps three times. Once Ball  Chain is started the goal is to then shoot each of the ramps three times each again. If Ball  Chain is completed, The Bride of Frankenstein's microphone will be awarded.Frankenstein MultiballIn Frankenstein Multiball the player must assemble Frankenstein. To assemble him the player must hit him a total of seven times. Once Frankenstein has been hit seven times he will rise up. Once he has risen the goal is to then hit him six more times. If Frankenstein Multiball is completed, Frankenstein's keyboard will be awarded.Mummy MayhemOnce started, the goal of Mummy Mayhem is to collect 7.5 million points in forty-five seconds. If the 7.5 million points have been collected, The Mummy's bass will be awarded.Drac AttackThe goal of Drac Attack is to earn the letters to spell Dracula. The letters can be collected by hitting the Drac and Attack buttons. These Drac and Attack buttons must be hit a total of seven times (collectively). Once Dracula has been spelled out Dracula will emerge from his coffin. Once Dracula is out of the coffin the player must hit him five times. If Drac Attack has been completed, Dracula's guitar will be awarded.</description><genres><genre id="30">Pinball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14374">Monster Bash</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/10/103881/1780690-mb.jpg</image></root>