<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35163</id><name>Dragon Ball Z: Ultimate Tenkaichi</name><description>OverviewDragon Ball Z: Ultimate Tenkaichi is a game in the long running Dragon Ball Z franchise. As it's name suggests this game is developed by Spike and follows in the footsteps of their long running Tenkaichi and Raging Blast seres of over-the-shoulder, open arena, full movement fighting games.Announced by the long running Japanese manga magazine Weekly Shōnen Jump as "Dragon Ball: Game Project AGE 2011", developer Spike stated that they are attempting to create a new landmark in the Dragon Ball video game franchise. This game is also being stylized more like the Dragon Ball manga than the anime, with characters and landscapes modeled to fit that aesthetic appropriately.With Japan Expo 2011 came a final name and release date. The official name was "chosen" through fan survey submissions with the possible choices being (and all starting with "Dragon Ball Z"): Tenkaichi Z, Saiyan Rising, Awakening Saiyans, Ultimate Tenkaichi, and Saiyan Warriors. The game was released on October 25, 2011 in the US, October 28, 2011 in Europe, and on December 8, 2011 in Japan.GameplaySpike is creating somewhat the same style of fighting games they're known for. The matches are one vs one and use a selection of characters from the Dragon Ball Z franchise we all know well. The fights take place in large destructible environments that are recognizable from the fiction. The environments themselves are very open due to the game's 3D fighting style that strays from mainstream fighters. As such fighters can be knocked around and attacks can be dodged in more grandiose fashions.The set-up to a fight.In this new iteration, the over-the-shoulder camera thats been the norm for Spike's DBZ franchises has been improved to be more dynamic. If melee combos are being dealt, the camera gets up close to the action. The camera also can briefly set into a more classic 2D style.Also added are different types of classing moves. Fast pace teleporting clashes and up close punch smashes are styled like rock-paper-scissor quick time event guessing games similar to previous DBZ fighting franchise Budokai.Improved environment damageAnother improvement is the arena destruction. With previous games, a beam attack like the popular Kamehameha could be fired onto an enemy with so much as a few rocks flying up from the ground. Now attacks like this have more of an impact with blasts being shown launching off the planet, and large craters being left in their wake.Story ModeOne of the newly remastered cutscenes used in Ultimate TenkaichiThe story mode in Dragon Ball Z: Ultimate Tenkaichi is similar to other Dragon Ball Z games, in that it closely follows the story of the anime. Players will go through the different the different sagas of the Dragon Ball Z world, going through the "Saiyan Saga," "Namek Saga," "Frieza Saga," "Android Saga," "Cell Saga," and "Buu Saga," as well as various Dragon Ball Z movies. The equivalent to one episode of Dragon Ball GT is also included. Digitally-remastered clips from the anime are used as the game's cutscenes, usually played after a major boss fight, or important plot point.In story mode, players will fly around an open-world environment, much like in Dragon Ball Z: Budokai 3 and Dragon Ball Z: Budokai Tenkaichi 2. Players will be going through the world looking for the legendary Dragon Balls and opponents to fight. Every time all seven Dragon Balls are collected, the player gains the ability to wish for (unlock) a new costume or stage.Goku fighting Great Ape Vegeta, one of the various boss fights.The story mode also has special boss battles, fights with enemies that are much larger and more difficult than regular opponents. In these fights, players will attack the boss's limbs while avoiding there attacks. After enough damage is done, a quick time event is engaged which--if performed successfully--will end the fight.Hero ModeOne example of a "Custom Character."Dragon Ball Z: Ultimate Tenkaichi has a new "Hero Mode," which allows players to experience an alternate story in the Dragon Ball Z universe. Players can create their own custom character, customizing their appearance and attributes like the model body, face, hair, attire, type of voice your character will have, as well as their fighting style and special moves.The "Hero Mode" will have players using this character, going through an alternate Dragon Ball Z world, finding a bunch of familiar characters like Captain Ginyu, Piccolo, and Androids 17  18. Crafting a wholly unique story separate from the shows cannon.Battle ModeStandard fighting game mode. Able to create one-on-one battles or team battles for either 1P vs. CPU or 1P vs. 2P. In this mode players can select the fighters they want, the special move loadouts, costumes, stages, and battle music. As well as change the time limit and opponent difficulty.World Tournament ModeLike other Dragon Ball games, Ultimate Tenkaichi has a "World Tournament" mode. Serving as a ladder fight, there can be up to 16 participants in the tournament, and you are able to use your custom fighter from "Hero Mode" to play.CustomizeThe customize mode allows players to customize certain aspects of the game. From this menu, players can create custom "Skill Sets" using techniques and moves they unlock playing "Hero Mode." These skill sets can then be used with the created character or with regular fighters in the "Battle Mode."Players can also use this menu to create custom playlists of the games background music.Online BattleThe online mode in Dragon Ball Z: Ultimate Tenkaichi is similar to the games offline "Battle" mode, the only difference being you cannot play with teams, strictly one-on-one battles. As is standard in multiplayer fighting games there are ranked and player matches, as well an online edition of the games "World Tournament" mode. You can also check your ranking as well as customize your online profile.Capsule HouseThe "Capsule House" serves as Dragon Ball Z: Ultimate Tenkaichi's trophy room. Here players can listen to the games soundtrack, watch the remastered clips from the show, watch replays that they've saved from their battles, get bio info on all of the characters, and summon the Dragon once they find all seven Dragon Balls.Training ModeDragon Ball Z: Ultimate Tenkaichi's "Training" mode offers a tutorial which teaches players the basics of the game, as well as some more advanced moves. It also has a regular training mode where players can practice pulling off characters different moves and techniques.Character RosterDragon Ball Z: Ultimate Tenkaichi features 42 playable characters (including a custom created character you get from the games "Hero Mode"). Characters from Dragon Ball Z as well as Dragon Ball GT are featured.Android 16Android 17Android 18Android 19BardockBrolyBurterCaptain GinyuCell (Imperfect Form, Semi-Perfect Form, Perfect Form, Super Perfect Form)Cell Jr.CuiCustom Character [Light, Standard, Heavy] (Base, Super Saiyan)DodoriaDr. GeroFrieza (1st Form, 2nd Form, 3rd Form, Final Form, 100% Power)Future Trunks (Base, Super Saiyan)Gogeta (Super Saiyan 4)Goku (Base, Super Saiyan, Super Saiyan 2, Super Saiyan 3)Gotenks (Super Saiyan, Super Saiyan 3)JeiceKid BuuKid GohanKrillinMajin BuuMajin VegetaNappaOmega ShenronPiccoloRaditzRecoomeSaibamenSuper Buu (Base, Gohan Absorbed)Super GogetaSuper JanembaSuper VegitoTeen Gohan (Super Saiyan, Super Saiyan 2)Tien ShinhanUltimate GohanVegeta (Scouter)Vegeta (Base, Super Saiyan, Ascended Super Saiyan)YamchaZarbonBossesThere are two separate sets of bosses depending on if you're playing the games story mode or the hero mode.Story ModeGreat Ape VegetaMetal Cooler (Nucleus)JanembaHirudegarnHero ModeGreat ApeGolden Great Ape Baby VegetaUltimate ShenronStagesBig Gete Star (Story Mode Only)CaveCell Games ArenaGlacierHighlandsIslandPlanetPlanet NamekRocky LandRuined CityRuined Planet NamekWastelandWorld Martial Arts Tournament Arena</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="35816">Naruto Shippuden: Ultimate Ninja Storm Generations</game><game id="42977">Dragon Ball Z: Battle of Z</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2352260-box_dbzut.png</image></root>