<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35242</id><name>Starhawk</name><description>OverviewStarhawk is a PS3 exclusive developed by Lightbox Interactive and published by Sony. It has been described as having the, "same essence as Warhawk, but [Starhawk] is also bigger and better." The game is being focused around a single player story-driven campaign in addition to a reworked multi-player as seen in Warhawk. Both modes will feature a "build and battle" RTS feature which allows players to drop, fight with and upgrade offensive and defensive structures.GameplayThe gameplay's 3rd person camera angle is no longer like Warhawk as the camera is off-centered, and also features the ability to zoom in for a closer over-the-shoulder view for more accurate shooting as seen in Gears of War and Metal Gear Solid 4: Guns of the Patriots. Another addition is the sprint feature.Build and BattleFeaturing in both the single-player campaign and multi-player modes, the build and battle system is an answer to the time consuming management based RTS features that normally hamper action games. You must accumulate Rift Energy to build each unit of structure, this rift energy is collected upon kills of opponents. The structures can be accessed by a radial menu UI which allows the player to build fast, not distracting from the fight. Structures will destroy enemy mechs if they are built on top of them as the foundations are launched down from the sky. It should also be noted that building structures is possible in mid-air when flying a Hawk.StructuresStructureUpgradeAdditional NotesWallGateWalls and Gates will join together if built side by sideAnti-air Laser TurretHawk StationNo Hawk Station, no Hawks/mechsGarageNo Garage, no JeepsBeaconAllows team-mates to spawn in the area using shuttles/podsBubble Shield GeneratorCall down the bubble instead of using it as an ability of Warhawk's APCMulti-playerLike Warhawk, Starhawk's maximum is 32 players. The multi-player has been described as dependent on the play-style of each individual. Both offensive and defensive play is possible. You will play as the Rift Miners-aka Rifters-or the Outcasts. Factions will play identically to each other as they did in Warhawk. Features that have also been announced are game invites, voice chat, a party system and a calender (details of which haven't yet been stated)Another interesting change in the multiplayer is the spawn method, no longer will spawn camping be a major nuisance as Stawhawk has adopted the drop pod spawn method which are also found in the Section 8 games. This also gives players a low degree of control when falling, which is sometimes crucial for dropping behind or in the front line.ModesCapture the FlagTeam DeathmatchDeathmatchZonesVehiclesVehicleOn-board WeaponsAbilitiesAdditional NotesJeepMachine Gun turret on the back-Can carry three players at onceHawkMachine Gun and missilesCan transform into a mech for ground combatCan use all pick-ups found in the airJet Bike--Fast response vehicle, carries only oneMapsAcid Sea - An area in one of many moons surrounding the planet in which the single-player campaign takes place. As the name implies, running in the acid is not a viable option.Space Station - A map which has the outcast vs. the riftters fighting on two different sides in space. This map will be good for using the jetpacks and gaining an advantage on the enemy.WeaponsMachine GunRocket Launcher (lock-on)Assault RiflePistol (Magnum)StoryIn Starhawk you play as Emmet Graves in an area of space known as The Fringe. Emmet is one of two brothers who are miners, exposed to the highly hazardous but invaluable "blue gold" rift energy resource that is being fought over by the two factions at war. These are the Rift Miners and the Outcasts, replacing the Eucadians and Chernovans from Warhawk.Emmet and his brother are former Rift Miners, they were infected after an assault by the Outcasts. Sydney Cutter provides radio tech-support and unlocks more powerful structures. Alternately you can find schematics on the ground.LocationsThe RiftA lawless assembly of planets where Rifters have rushed to find their fortune or end. Here pockets of Rift energy exist hidden inside scattered moons and planets ready to be discovered. After generations of Rift mining, the Frontier has become a violent battle ground where Rifters and Outcast struggle for control over this rare and mysterious resource.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1168">Battalion Wars 2</game><game id="20700">Brütal Legend</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2171296-box_starhawk.png</image></root>