<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35377</id><name>Awesomenauts</name><description>OverviewAwesomenauts is a 2D multiplayer platformer developed by Ronimo and published by dtp on May 1, 2012 for the Xbox 360 (via Xbox Live Arcade for 800 msp) and the PlayStation 3 (via PlayStation Network for $9.99, free for PlayStation Plus members). Influenced by the MOBA (Multiplayer Battle Online Arena) sub-genre, the game is set in the far future, where two factions (red and blue) send out mercenaries (the Awesomenauts) to battle each other in 3-on-3 scenarios. The game is noted for a strong late-80s, early-90s cartoon vibe, including wacky characters (including a futuristic cowboy and a hip-hop inspired frog humanoid) and cartoonish presentation.It was later published by Ronimo for the PC (either directly from their website or from Steam) on August 1, 2012, where it received numerous patches (including new playable characters). Players who purchased the Steam version before September 5th, 2012 also received cross-promotional cosmetic items for Team Fortress 2, including a badge with the Awesomenauts logo, a jetpack (for the Pyro) resembling Yuri's jetpack, and a combination of Lonestar's facial hair and hat (for the Sniper). It was also released for Mac on December 6, 2012, making it cross-play compatible between PC and Mac.GameplayAwesomenauts has the standard starting elements that most MOBAs have. The game field is set with two bases at opposite ends of the map in this case the far left and far right. Extending outward from each of the bases are the lanes. In these lanes there are bushes to hide in to do stealth attacks platforms and moving platforms as well as areas for creeps. At predetermined areas sit turrets that each team works to destroy thru out the course of each game.Your profile gains levels as you play the game earning new item options, areas to play in and new characters to play as. There are currently 3 stages in total.Ribbit IV - This is the stage that is unlocked initially. It consists of 2 main paths with 2 turrets on each path per team. There is a jungle area that spawns up to 4 standard critters and 2 of the giant solarboss. The solarboss, unlike the standard critters, will attack players. There are several areas to hide in near the center of the map. There is also a jump pad at the bottom center of the map.Sorona - This stage is unlocked at level 12. This stage consists of 2 main pahs with 1 turret on each path per team, this funnels into a single final turret. The top area for each team holds the critter area. Only 2 critters spawn on each teams side. The spawn is initially protected by a team specific force field. However, once the final turret is destroyed, this force field disappears and enemies may use the upper path to gain entry to the oppositions drill. This stage also has an environmental hazard in the form of a giant worm. At the very bottom center of the stage there is a platform with a button. Standing on this button unleashes the worm to feast on any player or creep in the immediate area. Be careful as you can destroy your own team's creep or players with this.AI Station 404 - This stage is unlocked at level 22. This stage consists of a single path that diverges and then re-converges. The middle of the map features a low gravity area above the turrets, and a critter area above that. The upper access to the critter area is protected by a force field that is also disabled when the first turret is destroyed. This stage is the only stage that contains special creep that can be released at the players discretion. These creep fly and use a ranged attack to fight against enemy turrets, creeps, and players. While they are more powerful than the standard creep, they do not receive the benefit of shields when approaching a turret.Some of the key differences that set Awesomenauts apart from most other MOBAs is at the start of the match you choose which upgrades you want to purchase in the store. You are given 6 options that unlock over time to upgrade various parts of your character from movement speed to attack damage. Some of these can even add extra effects to your character allowing you to do more damage to your enemy or cripple them depending on the upgrade. To purchase these items you must gather solar which can be found scattered throughout every level as pick up items, and gained from killing enemies, creeps or turrets. When you spawn in the match either from the start of the game or after you die you are dropped from a space ship to the planet you are fighting on, when you are dropped you can move your dropship around to pick up solar.Solar gained from killing an enemy is shared by the entire team. The player the scores the kill earns 50 solar, while the other members of the team earn 25. The game only keeps track of kills and deaths with assists not reflected in the games stats.Some levels have special triggers such as a button that allows a giant worm to come out of the ground and attack anyone standing above it killing them instantly be them friend or foe.If you get killed by a creep the game will state that you have been humiliated.If you kill 3 people with out dying it will say that you are dominating.Each of the characters in the game are controlled with the left joystick and the bottom button of the controller is used as the jump button similar to most side scrolling platforming games. The remaining 3 face buttons are the attack and special move actions. The special move actions must be unlocked from the store before you will be able to use them at any time. The dpad can trigger taunts or requests for assistance from your teammates.CharactersBasic Unlocks:Power Pills (3 ranks) - Increases the player's maximum health by 30. Costs 135 solar per rank.Med-i'-can (2 ranks) - Grants the player automatic health regeneration (2 health per second). Costs 180 solar per rank.Space Air Max - Adds 1.2 to the player's movement speed. Replaced by the Rocket Boots upgrade for Sheriff Lonestar, which grants him the ability to perform another jump while in mid-air. Costs 135 solar.Solar Tree - Grants the player additional solar over time. This ability doubles the rate that solar is gained from 30 solar per minute to 60 solar per minute. Costs 125 solar.Piggy Bank - Unlocked at level 4. Gives the player 125 Solar. Costs 0 solar.Power Pills Turbo - Unlocked at level 35. Increases the player's maximum health by 90. Costs 270 solar.These abilities are shared among all characters.Sheriff LonestarSheriff Lonestar is a genetically re-engineered human cowboy (with a thick cowboy accent) created by a semi-intelligent cow race (the Bovinians) to be caged in a zoo for the Bovinians to gander. However, he escapes and ends up wrangling the entire Bovinian civilization before becoming a mercenary (spending solar on whiskey and cigars).He is unlocked at the start of the game and is used in the tutorial mission.Jumping Mechanic: Rocket Boots - Lonestar can propel himself up with his rocket boots, and can perform another jump in midair. The Rocket Boots upgrade can let him perform yet another jump in midair.Primary Attack: Blaster Shot - Lonestar shoots a medium-ranged bullet from his blaster.Eagle Bullets (2 ranks) - Increases the damage of each bullet. Costs 200 solar per rank.Cheetah Bullets (2 ranks) - Increases the attack speed of each bullet. Costs 185 solar per rank.Missile - Adds a slow-loading homing missile to the bullet string (similar to Clunk's primary attack). Costs 220 solar.Crystal Eagle Bullets - Further increases the damage of each bullet. Costs 320 solar.Booming Bullets - Unlocked at level 5. Adds an area of effect explosion to each bullet. Costs 250 solar.Another Missile - Unlocked at level 22. Adds another slow-loading homing missile to the bullet string. Costs 220 solar.Ability: Dynamite - Lonestar chucks a stick of dynamite in front of him, which explodes after a second (dealing damage to nearby enemies).An Extra Stick! (2 ranks) - Adds an extra stick of dynamite to Lonestar's dynamite chuck. Costs 220 solar per rank.Mister TNT (2 ranks) - Increases the range of the dynamite explosion. Costs 140 solar per rank.Dark Matter Flashbang (3 ranks) - Adds the ability for the dynamite explosion to temporarily blind affected targets. Costs 145 solar per rank.Rubber Sleeve - Makes the dynamite bounce on surfaces and explode on contact with an enemy. Costs 135 solar.Transfusion Grenades - Unlocked at level 17. Adds the ability for the dynamite explosion to heal Lonestar based on damage given. Costs 220 solar.Contact Detonator - Unlocked at level 40. Increases the amount of time before the dynamite explodes to 20 seconds, while making it explode on contact with an enemy. Costs 180 solar.Ability: Hyper Bull - Lonestar summons a holographic bull that charges forward, knocking away enemies in its path. While the bull is destroyed after a short amount of time, it can also be destroyed prematurely by enemy attack.Super Breed 2.0 - Increases the knockback effect and health of hyper bull. Costs 135 solar.Cattle Rebooter - Reduces the cooldown of the Hyper Bull ability. Costs 185 solar.Ribbit Snail Slime (3 ranks) - Adds the ability for the hyper bull to temporarily slow down affected enemies. Costs 120 solar per rank.Bull Charger - Increases the hyper bull's movement speed. Costs 90 solar per rank.Techno Viking Helmet (2 ranks) - Unlocked at level 10. Adds the ability for the hyper bull to deal damage during knockback and for it to explode when destroyed, dealing damage to nearby enemies. Costs 190 solar per rank.Mature Ribbit Snail Slime - Unlocked at level 32. Further increases the slow down effect of Ribbit Snail Slime. Costs 250 solar.Froggy GNate Frogg, known better as Froggy G, is a humanoid toad (with a gangsta flair) who was raised in the ghettos of Ribbit IV. After ending up in jail from a bloody gang-war with neighboring toads, he became an unsuccessful rapper and later a hired gun.He is unlocked at the start of the game.Jumping Mechanic: Waterpack - Froggy G can charge his waterpack (by holding down the jump button) to perform higher jumps.Primary Attack: Fishgun Shot - Froggy G shoots lethal short-ranged jets of water from his fishgun.Swirling Octopus Cartridges (2 ranks) - Increases the range of each shot. Costs 145 solar per rank.Piranha Cartridges (2 ranks) - Increases the damage of each shot. Costs 200 solar per rank.Mutant Worms (3 ranks) - Increases the attack speed of each shot. Costs 145 solar per rank.Viridian Eel Cartridges - Adds the ability for shots to pierce through enemies, affecting multiple targets. Costs 225 solar.Mutant Worms: Limited Ninja Edition - Unlocked at level 18. Further increases the attack speed of each shot. Costs 270 solar.Thorn Fish - Unlocked at level 41. Splits the number of water blasts in each shot to two slightly-weaker blasts. Costs 280 solar.Ability: Splash Dash - Froggy G dashes through enemies, both damaging and stunning affected targets.Hydro Splash (3 ranks) - Increases the damage of each splash dash. Costs 140 solar per rank.Ice Cubes (2 ranks) - Increases the stun duration of affected targets. Costs 150 solar per rank.Golden Watch (2 ranks) - Increases the cooldown speed of the Splash Dash ability. Costs 110 solar per rank.Hammer Pants - Adds a ground pound ability to splash dash (while aiming at the ground), which doubles the damage against nearby enemies. Costs 220 solar.Clock Necklace - Unlocked at level 7. Further increases the cooldown speed of the Splash Dash ability. Costs 180 solar.Hydro Smash - Unlocked at level 26. Further increases the damage of each splash dash. Costs 315 solar.Ability: Tornado - Froggy G spins himself into a slightly-slower whirlwind waterspout of pain, damaging enemies for a short amount of time.Beat Box (2 ranks) - Increases the attack speed of the tornado. Costs 220 solar per rank.Turbo Tape (2 ranks) - Increases Froggy G's movement speed during Tornado. Costs 140 solar per rank.Can't Touch This - Adds damage protection to Froggy G during Tornado. Costs 220 solar.Bio Fuel Cells (2 ranks) - Increases the duration of the tornado. Costs 150 solar per rank.Twister Tweesters (2 ranks) - Unlocked at level 14. Adds the ability for the tornado to explode after wearing off, dealing damage to nearby enemies. Costs 150 solar per rank.Right Back At Ya! - Unlocked at level 34. Adds the ability for the tornado to reflect enemy projectiles. Costs 260 solar.Leon ChameleonLeon Chameleon is a humanoid chameleon (with a thick French accent) that lives on a life of crime and women. After losing an arm in a jeu de boules incident and becoming the most wanted criminal on his planet (for accidentally breaking into the bedroom of the prime minister's wife while looking for the wine cellar), he becomes a mercenary (spending solar on women and exquisite meals).He is unlocked at the start of the game.Jumping Mechanic: Reptilian Jump - Leon can leap high into the air.Primary Attack: Slash - A powerful short-ranged melee attack.Chainsaw Addon (3 ranks) - Increases the damage of each slash. Costs 225 solar per rank.Enhanced Muscle Fibers (2 ranks) - Increases the attack speed of each slash. Costs 195 solar per rank.Clover of Honour (2 ranks) - Adds a 20% chance for the slash to perform a critical hit (dealing 18 more damage). Costs 180 solar.Backstab Blade - Increases the damage of each slash against the backside of enemies. Costs 275 solar.Hungry Sword - Unlocked at level 13. Adds a life steal that heals 25% of his attack. Costs 200 solar.Electrifier - Unlocked at level 36. Adds the ability for slash attacks to slow down affected enemies. Costs 235 solar.Ability: Tongue Snatch - Leon throws out his long tongue in front of him, snatching enemies and pulling them back to you (while damaging hem).Spiked Tongue Piercing (3 ranks) - Increases the damage of the tongue snatch. Costs 200 solar per rank.Tongue Stretcher (2 ranks) - Increases the range of the tongue snatch. Costs 130 solar per rank.Cheese  Garlic Mints (2 ranks) - Adds the ability for the tongue snatch to silence enemies affected by it. Costs 205 solar per rank.Steel False Teeth (2 ranks) - Adds the ability for the tongue snatch to heal Leon based on damage given. Costs 190 solar per rank.Morning Star Piercing - Unlocked at level 19. Further increases the damage of the tongue snatch. Costs 340 solar.Magnet Piercing - Unlocked at level 42. Adds the ability for the tongue snatch to grab Solar pickups (while also converting damage given into Solar). Costs 180 solar.Ability: Stealth - Leon makes himself invisible from enemies while deploying a weaker robotic stationary dummy of himself.Surprise Party Mask (2 ranks) - Increases the damage of the first Slash while being decloaked. Costs 140 solar per rank.Pinot Noir - Adds the ability to regenerate health while cloaked. Costs 190 solar.Basic AI Chip - Forces the robotic dummy to move forwards. Costs 205 solar.Aggressive AI Chip - Forces the robotic dummy to slash if there are any enemies, creeps, turrets, or drills in range. Costs 225 solar.Extra Battery Pack - Unlocked at level 8. Increases the health of the robotic dummy. Costs 205 solar.Blow Up Doll (2 ranks) - Unlocked at level 29. Forces the robotic dummy to explode on death, dealing damage to nearby enemies. Costs 220 solar per rank.ClunkClunk is a large robot that suffers from anger management issues. Originally created as part of a robot army built to battle a powerful super-villian (who died from a bacterial infection before the army was completed), Clunk became a hired gun to do what he's best at: wrecking things.He is unlocked after reaching level 3.Jumping Mechanic: Jet Boost - Clunk uses jet boosters to ascend him.Primary Attack: Missile - A long-ranged missile that's slow to reload but immensely powerful (and has a minor homing effect).Fragmenting Shells - Adds an area of effect to the missile explosion while increasing the explosion damage. Costs 280 solar.Free Flight Fins (2 ranks) - Increases the missile projectile speed while reducing the attack's cooldown. Costs 130 solar per rank.Missile Barrage (2 ranks) - Adds large missiles (fired one to two at a time) to the launch string. Costs 160 solar per rank.The Juggernaut "Fat Pete" - Adds a very large, very powerful missile to the launch string. Costs 160 solar.Improve Homing Sensor - Unlocked at level 21. Increases the homing effect of missiles. Costs 140 solar.Salvo Value Pack - Unlocked at level 38. Adds the missiles used in Missile Barrage and The Juggernaut "Fat Pete" to the launch string. Costs 400 solar.Ability: Vacuum Bite - Clunk bites down on nearby enemies, replenishing part of his own health.Quick'n Cleaner (2 ranks) - Increases the Vacuum Bite's damage and life steal by 6 per rank. Costs 155 solar per rank.Medical Pump (2 ranks) - Temporarily adds maximum health to Clunk for each successful bite. This health boost is removed when he dies. Costs 210 solar per rank.Multi Hose (2 ranks) - Adds the ability for the Vacuum Bite to affect more than one nearby enemy at a time. Costs 230 solar per rank.Screamer Engine (2 ranks) - Adds the ability for the Vacuum Bite to ensnare enemies affected by it. Costs 190 solar per rank.The Suckanator Power 9000 Cleaner - Unlocked at level 25. Further increases the Vacuum Bite's damage and life steal. Costs 250 solar.Cash Container (2 ranks) - Unlocked at level 45. Adds the ability for the Vacuum Bite to give Solar to Clunk for each successful bite. Costs 140 solar per rank.Ability: Self Destruct - Clunk charges up and then explodes with a wide area of effect, causing damage to both him and enemies around him.Thermonuclear Cleaner (2 ranks) - Increases the Self Destruct's explosion damage. Costs 215 solar.Titanium Hard Hat (2 ranks) - Reduces the self-inflicted damage from the Self Destruct explosion. Costs 145 solar per rank.Grease Lightning Snail (2 ranks) - Adds the ability for the charging up duration of the Self Destruct ability to slow down nearby enemies. Costs 180 solar per rank.Blueprints Container (2 ranks) - Temporarily reduces the respawn time for the player after dying from self-inflicted damage from the Self Destruct explosion. Costs 150 solar per rank.Reactor Cooler - Unlocked at level 15. Reduces the cooldown of the Self Destruct ability. Costs 200 solar.Universal Charger - Unlocked at level 30. Reduces the charging up duration of the Self Destruct ability. Costs 200 solar.Voltar the OmniscientVoltar the Omniscient is a brain (carefully kept inside a braintank) whose past is shrouded in mystery. Believed to be part of a researcher in a power station that exploded around 500 years prior to the events of this war, he made some modifications to his braintank (with the help of his loyal robot drones) and later participated in the war as a mercenary.He is unlocked after reaching level 6.Jumping Mechanic: Hover - Voltar is always hovering above ground, thanks to thrusters attached to his braintank. By holding down the jump button while in mid-air, he can stop all vertical momentum and fall at a much slower pace.Primary Attack: Healing Wave - A short-ranged blast that heals all friendly drones and players that come into contact with it.Happy Thoughts (3 ranks) - Increases the Healing Wave's healing power. Costs 200 solar per rank.Psychokinetic Repulsion - Adds a mild knockback effect to each Healing Wave shot. Costs 135 solar.Psychothrust (2 ranks) - Increases the Healing Wave's range. Costs 180 solar per rank.Dreams of Greed - Increases the amount of Solar gained from the Healing Wave. Costs 205 solar.Twisted Nightmares - Unlocked at level 23. Sacrifice's the Healing Wave's Solar gain for the ability for it to damage enemies. Costs 270 solar.Euphoric Thoughts - Unlocked at level 33. Further increases the Healing Wave's healing power. Costs 380 solar.Ability: Combat Drone - Voltar summons two robotic drones from his braintank to fly around him, shooting nearby enemies. While the drones have no time limit, they can be destroyed by enemy fire.Drone Army (2 ranks) - Increases the amount of drones Voltar can summon. Costs 175 solar per rank.Force Fields - Adds a shield to the drones while increasing their maximum health. Costs 160 solar.Weapon Clip-On (3 ranks) - Increases the damage of the drones' shots. Costs 190 solar per rank.Hyper Drive (2 ranks) - Increases both the movement speed and attack speed of the drones. Costs 210 solar per rank.Weaponised Hull - Unlocked at level 9. Further increases the damage of the drones' shots. Costs 315 solar.Warpgate Overdrive - Unlocked at level 39. Reduces the cooldown of the Summoner Drone ability from 16 seconds to 6 seconds. Costs 110 solar.Ability: Healbot - Voltar summons a robotic stationary turret that heals all nearby friendly drones and players. The Healbot can be destroyed by either enemy fire or automatically after a certain amount of time.Cortex Tank (2 ranks) - Increases the health and longevity of the Healbot. Costs 170 solar per rank.Energy Drink (3 ranks) - Increases the healing power of the Healbot. Costs 210 solar per rank.Turret Add-On (2 ranks) - Adds a gun to the Healbot, enabling it to shoot at nearby enemies. Costs 190 solar per rank.Hydraulic Sugar Dispenser (2 ranks) - Reduces the cooldown of the Summon Healbot ability. Costs 140 solar per rank.Overheal Potion - Unlocked at level 28. Further increases the healing power of the Healbot. Costs 360 solar.Healthpack Surprise - Unlocked at level 43. Adds the ability for the Healbot to spawn a health pack after it times out. Costs 140 solar.YuriYuri is a monkey who was launched into space by Soviet Russia during the Cold War space race of the 1960s. After his spacecraft mysteriously entered a warfield anomaly, transporting him thousands of years into the future and greatly boosting his intelligence, he repairs his broken rocket into a time-warping supercomputer jetpack (which can also translate everything he says with a thick Russian accent). Now he becomes a hired gun (for unknown reasons).He is unlocked after reaching level 11.Jumping Mechanic: Jetpack - Pressing the jump button midair toggles his use of his jetpack, in which he can move around, indefinitely, in the air.Primary Attack: Laser - A long-ranged continuous laser beam attached to the jetpack that is able to fire in any direction, slicing through enemies while bouncing off surfaces.Giant Monocle - Increases the Laser's beam length. Costs 280 solar.Instant Charge Battery (2 ranks) - Increases the Laser's hit speed. Costs 210 solar per rank.Resonance Amplifier (2 ranks) - Increases the maximum damage of the Laser's beam. Costs 155 solar per rank.Tractor Beam Amplifier - Adds the ability for the Laser to physically attract hit enemies. Costs 270 solar.Hubble's Lens - Unlocked at level 20. Further increases the maximum damage of the Laser's beam. Costs 205 solar.Baby Yeti - Unlocked at level 31. Adds the ability for the Laser to slow down hit enemies. Costs 225 solar.Ability: Mine - Yuri deploys a timed mine under him, which falls to the ground and explodes after a certain time.Titanium Spikes (3 ranks) - Increases the explosion damage of mines. Costs 180 solar per rank.Aerial Spring - Adds the ability for the mines to bounce on surfaces. Costs 140 solar.Toaster Timer - Increases the timer before mines expire from 12 seconds to 20. Costs 130 solar.Mine Constructor (3 ranks) - Reduces the cooldown of the Mine ability. Costs 150 solar per rank.Carpet Bombs - Unlocked at level 27. Adds two mines to each deployment while cutting the damage out of each of them by 1/3. Costs 205 solar.Uranium Spikes - Unlocked at level 44. Further increases the explosion damage of mines. Costs 325 solar.Ability: Time Warp - Yuri creates an area of effect around himself to alter the flow of time, slowing down enemies and their projectiles.Chrono Rift - Increases the Time Warp's slowdown effect. Costs 250 solar.Regeneration Pod (3 ranks) - Adds the ability for the Time Warp's area of effect to heal friendly drones and players over time. Costs 150 solar per rank.Spacetime Continuity Device (2 ranks) - Increases the Time Warp's duration while reducing the ability's cooldown. Costs 155 solar per rank.Flash Forward - Adds the ability for the Time Warp's area of effect to temporarily increase the movement speed and attack speed of friendly drones and players. Costs 180 solar.Pod Pack Deluxe - Unlocked at level 16. Adds the ability for the Time Warp's area of effect to heal friendly drones and players over time. Costs 270 solar.Time Primer - Unlocked at level 37. Increases the Time Warp's area of effect. Costs 180 solar.Derpl ZorkDerpl Zork is an alien with incredibly low intelligence. He is the heir apparant to a galaxy-spanning business empire currently run by his uncle, Blabl Zork. Fearing that Derpl would inherit the company with his low IQ, Blabl put Derpl in charge of field-testing a "secretary interface" for the corporation's combat walkers, in hopes that he suffers a fatal blow.He was made playable in the July 23, 2012 patch, and is unlocked after reaching level 18.Jumping Mechanic: Booster Rocket - Derpl uses jet boosters similar to Clunk's.Primary Attack: Cat Launcher - Derpl is armed with a gun which fires explosive holocats at his enemies.Longcat (2 ranks) - Increases the range of cat shot. Costs 190 solar per rank.Kitty Catsuit (3 ranks) - Increases the damage of cat shot. Costs 160 solar per rank.Cat Package (3 ranks) - Increases the rate of fire of cat shot. Costs 150 solar per rank.Cat Cat - Adds a second, backwards cat shot. Costs 200 solar.Hover Cat - Makes the normally arched cat shots fly straight. Costs 135 solar.Bat Catsuit - Greatly increases the damage of cat shot. Costs 380 solar.Ability: Siege Mode - Derpl Zork is able to transform his combat walker into an immobile turret armed with a machine gun instead of the cat shot.Sniper Bullets - Increases the range of machine gun. Costs 165 solar.Force Field (3 ranks) - Adds a damage absorbing force field to Siege Mode. Costs 130 solar per rank.Iron Fist Bullets - Adds a stun chance to the machine gun. Costs 225 solar.Hollow Point Bullets - Increases the damage of the machine gun. Costs 230 solar.Deployment Pads - Reduces the cooldown of Siege Mode. Costs 200 solar.Brim Force Field - Adds a strong damage absorbing force field. Costs 320 solar.Ability: Grid Trap / Nuke - Derpl's second ability changes its functionality depending on whether or not he is in Siege Mode. Outside of Siege Mode this ability lays down a trap that will ensnare enemies if they walk past it. While in Siege Mode, Derpl gains the ability to launch a highly damaging nuke.Empowered Grid (2 ranks) - Increases the snare duration of Grid Trap. Costs 145 solar per rank.Strengthened Trap - Increases the persistence of deployed Grid Traps. Costs 135 solar.Hydrocollision Lava Lamp (3 ranks) - Increases the damage of Nuke. Costs 225 solar per rank.Combustion Lava Lamp - Increases the explosion size of Nuke. Costs 200 solar.Lead Casing - Adds a silencing effect to Grid Trap. Costs 225 solar.Super Powered Grid - Greatly increases the snare duration of Grid Trap. Costs 260 solar.Coco NebulonCoco Nebulon is a psyonic alien (with a thick surfer accent) who uses a cosmic waveboard and psyonic powers in battle.She was made playable in the July 23, 2012 patch, and is unlocked after reaching level 10.GnawGnaw is a Skroggle (an omnivorous and toxic alien specie that can vomit plant-like creatures). After rampaging through a science facility when captured by Kremzonian scientists, he was then raised by Amphibian cosmic bikerpirates (who sell his "services" as a mercenary).He was made playable, for the PC version only, in the August 22, 2012 patch, and is unlocked after reaching level 16.SkølldirSkølldir is a fat space viking. 'Nuff said.He was made playable, for the PC version only, in the October 4, 2012 patch, and is unlocked after reaching level 12.RaelynnRaelynn is a mercenary who loves big guns (more specifically, her pulserifle "Cuddles"). Originally put into an elite squad doing covert operations against the first robot invasion she was put in cryostatis, only to be found 578 years later.She was made playable, for the PC version only, in the November 1, 2012 patch.SoundtrackThe soundtrack for Awesomenauts was created by SonicPicnic. A giveaway version of the vinyl edition of the soundtrack was awarded as a prize for several contests and ended on May 18th 2012. SonicPicnic plans on releasing the full soundtrack on June 1st 2012.Track #TitleDuration1.Awesomenauts Theme03:412.Juno's Travels to Planet DX702:523.Clunk's Machinery04:194.Wormhole Surfing03:415.Bagpipin' Blastfest04:246.Interstella Gangsta03:187.Party at the End of the Universe04:368.Space, Full Colour04:259.Gitarren sind AbFab!04:2610.We Will Take You There, Mr. Monkey04:0611.No Blue Elephants, Please01:0512.The Awesomenaut Tunes03:4913.Awesomenauts Theme (Remix by Totally Tuur)04:1314.Awesomenauts Mega Mini Master Mix10:5015.My Only Awesomenaut01:32PC System RequirementsMinimum:OS:Windows XP, Vista, Windows 7 or Windows 8Processor:Any processor with 2 CoresMemory:2 GB RAMGraphics:ATI or Nvidia Videocard with at least 256MB, or Intel GMA 950 or newerHard Drive:600 MB HD spaceRecommended:OS:Windows XP, Vista, Windows 7 or Windows 8Processor:Any processor with 2 CoresMemory:2 GB RAMGraphics:ATI or Nvidia Videocard with at least 512MBHard Drive:600 MB HD spaceOther Requirements:Broadband Internet connection</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="24024">League of Legends</game><game id="43181">Solstice Arena</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2188497-box_anauts.png</image></root>