<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35398</id><name>Dragon Age: Inquisition</name><description>OverviewDragon Age: Inquisition is the upcoming third primary entry in BioWare's Dragon Age franchise. The game is scheduled for release in the fall of 2014. In addition to the PC, PS3, and Xbox 360, versions are also being developed for the PlayStation 4 and Xbox One. It is the first game in the franchise to be developed on DICE's Frostbite 3 engine.Dragon Age KeepDue to the new console generation (PlayStation 4 and Xbox One) and Dragon Age: Inquisition's transfer over to the Frostbite 3 engine, BioWare have developed an alternative to transferring the varying Dragon Age worlds created by players from their playthroughs in previous games, over to DAI. Dragon Age Keep is a web app that will launch prior to DAI in 2014 and allow players to mold worlds as they see fit, defining their Wardens, Hawkes, companions and choices made in important moments in the Dragon Age world.CharactersThe Protagonist: The InquisitorPlayers will play as a new protagonist with customizable race, class, gender, and appearance. This protagonist, the Inquisitor, must save Thedas from itself by assuming control and building up an organization known as the Inquisition. The Inquisitor's quest will stretch across Thedas and into nations such as Ferelden and Orlais.Unlike Dragon Age II, in which the player was restricted to playing as a human character named Hawke, Dragon Age: Inquisition brings back many of the customization options from the original game. The player may choose to play as a human, elf, dwarf, or a Qunari--which is a first for the series--with the player's chosen race bearing some level of impact on the game's story and interactions with specific characters and groups. As in previous games, the player can also choose whether to play as a male or female, and as a warrior, mage, or rogue.Confirmed Returning CharactersMorrigan Confirmed as a non-player character, Morrigan has been heavily involved in events of the Dragon Age world behind the scenes since her departure at the end of Dragon Age: Origins - Witch Hunt DLC.Varric Tethras - The first former companion (as seen in Dragon Age II) confirmed to return as a companion in DAICassandra Pentaghast - An NPC from Dragon Age II, Cassandra is a sword and shield warrior loyal to the Chantry and will make her playable debut as a companion in DAINew CharactersVivienne - A new playable companion who is a former Circle-mage from Orlais, she fights to help her fellow mages.Development Dragon Age: Inquisition was confirmed to be in development following a post from executive producer Mark Darrah on September 17th, 2012, and has been in development since 2010.Like its predecessors, Dragon Age: Inquisition will be set in Thedas and will feature a new protagonist. Whereas Dragon Age: Origins took place in Ferelden and Dragon Age II in Kirkwall (and the Free Marches), this time the adventure will span across all of Thedas. The game will be set after Dragon Age II and the novel Dragon Age: Asunder, in which both the magi of Thedas and the Seekers of Truth, leading the Templar Order, have broken off from the Chantry and prepare to go to war with each other.On the BioWare panel at Edmonton Comic  Entertainment Expo 2012, creative director Mike Laidlaw stated that "customization is going to be bigger than Dragon Age: Origins", and also include "follower customization". On the same panel, lead writer David Gaider mentioned that "You will be human", and that "backgrounds will be in Dragon Age 3 even though you will be human, it's not playable but it does significant impact on the story". (Gaider's words were later contradicted when Bioware revealed in August of 2013 that the player will, in fact, be able to play as an elf or dwarf.) Cinematic designer John Perry also stated that "he's had a longer pre-production on DA3 than any other BioWare project he's worked on". Perry also mentioned that "just one level in DA3 is as big as all of DA2's levels combined".At E3 2013, the first Dragon Age: Inquisition trailer was released with Dragon Age: Origins character Morrigan (voiced again by Claudia Black) narrating over war-zones featuring unspoken appearances by Dragon Age II characters Varric Tethras and Cassandra Pentaghast. Having foreseen (along with her mother, Flemeth) the chaos that the Dragon Age universe would descend into, Morrigan asks the new protagonist if he/she will save Thedas or lead it to its destruction.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="27218">Two Worlds II</game><game id="41696">Deep Down</game><game id="41484">The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt</game><game id="38206">The Elder Scrolls Online</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/99864/2526593-8681662127-Drago.png</image></root>