<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35407</id><name>Deadstorm Pirates</name><description>OverviewDeadstorm pirates is a first person light-gun arcade shooting game released by Namco in 2010. It was later packaged with Time Crisis: Razing Storm and released October 19,2010. It was again later released separately over the Playstation Network. The arcade game uses the guncon3 light-gun while the PS3 version uses the Playstation Move controller. Up to two players can go into the machine and take the helm of a pirate ship. The player has to not only shoot every danger they come across, but they also have to steer the ship using a wheel whenever the ship is in danger of crashing.The PS3 version comes with its own ranking mode as well as the normal arcade mode.GameplayPlayers must complete 3 stages before the fourth and final stage is unlocked. The stages can be completed in any order with their difficulty scaling as the game progresses. The boss of each stage must be defeated by aiming and breaking their weak points shown on the screen. If two players aim at the same spot on the screen, then the attack becomes concentrated and attack is extra powerful.The game is an on rails shooter but the key to the arcade version is the fact that the player is seated inside the machine. The players cannon shakes as they fire as well as the players seat moving and shaking with the ocean and explosions. The players can not reduce their hp to 0 and receive a game over from crashing the ship too much. Instead, the players hp would be reduced to 1 for immediate death from the next hit. All shooting is paused for when the player has to turn the wheel as fast as they can. During each event, the time is recorded to give the player a good, bad, miss, perfect rating. If the player does exceptionally well, they may receive a special Yo-ho-ho rating after the stage during the score screen.The score screen ranks how many kills the player accumulated for that particular stage along with how many points they earned. In the PS3 ranking mode, the player can attempt to get a S rank in each stage. After each stage, the players may receive health bonuses and recovery depending on how well they performed. Any extra health a player receives may be transferred to the other player so the health is not wasted.Game AreasThe player is a pirate in search of Poseidon's treasure. The adventure takes place through:The stormy sea: Full of undead pirate skeletons, shield skeletons, flying wraiths, scarabs and enemy pirate ships which the player must destroy with their own ships cannons. The player must steer to turn the ship towards other enemy pirate ships.Mountain valley: Home to large schools of piranha, scarabs, crabs, massive amounts of bats and a gigantic king crab. The player must steer to avoid crashing into rocks while traveling downstream.Cave: The cave has magic swords, tight corners, enemies firing cannons at you, undead pirate skeletons, bats and a giant snake. The player must steer to avoid crashing in a mine cart.Great whirlpool: Most of the time spent is avoiding a giant kraken trying to destroy your ship as well as steering to avoid crashing. Some wraiths and undead skeleton pirates are common. The player must steer to avoid the center of the whirlpool as well as all the debris and other ships caught.Treasure: The undead pirate king as well as constant portals opening which contain undead pirate skeletons and wraiths. The player must steer to aim a giant crossbow.</description><genres><genre id="35">Light-Gun Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21468">Time Crisis 4</game><game id="9898">Time Crisis 3</game><game id="15867">Time Crisis</game><game id="15365">Time Crisis 2</game><game id="422">The House of the Dead 2</game><game id="7703">The House of the Dead III</game><game id="508">The House of the Dead</game><game id="25358">Dead Space Extraction</game><game id="11454">Resident Evil: The Umbrella Chronicles</game><game id="25558">Resident Evil: The Darkside Chronicles</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/5/57764/1789058-dpiratesnews1.jpg</image></root>