<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35449</id><name>The Baconing</name><description>OverviewThe Baconing is the third entry in the DeathSpank series following the original game and DeathSpank: Thongs of Virtue. The game features new levels, new enemies, and two new characters: Bob from Marketing and Tankko.The two new characters are only used by the second player in co-op. Bob from Marketing is a hammerhead shark in a business suit that shoots laser-beams from his eyes. Tankko is a spider-human hybrid that can encase enemies in webs. Two player asymmetrical co-op can only be played locally.While the combat remains almost entirely unchanged from the previous titles, this entry adds a new block mechanic that, when timed correctly, causes attacks to be reflected back at enemies for damage.The Baconing is available for download on the Playstation Network, Xbox Live Arcade, Steam, and the Mac Appstore.On October 11, 2011, DLC was added in the form of an extra co-op character named Roesha. She is a 1970s-inspired police woman whose primary weapon is an over-sized pistol. She can summon a disco ball onto a large group of enemies, which makes them dance before striking them with lightning. She can also heal DeathSpank by firing first aid shells, and her taunt is reflective of the Charlie's Angels pose.PlotHaving recovered all of the Thongs of Virtue in his prior adventure, DeathSpank decides to try on all six of the Thongs at once with disastrous results. An evil version of himself, the Anti-Spank, is created. DeathSpank must travel to the Fires of Bacon in order to destroy five of the six Thongs of Virtue, kill the Anti-Spank, and bring peace to SpankTopia.PC System RequirementsMinimumRecommendedOS: Windows XP SP3Processor: Intel Pentium 4 or AMD Athlon 64 (or equivalent) running at 1.7 GHz or greaterMemory: 1 GB or greaterGraphics: ATI Radeon X1900 GT 256MB and the Nvidia GeForce 6800 Ultra 256MB PCI-E cards (Shader Model 2.0 and 24bit depth buffer support required)DirectX®: DirectX June 2010Hard Drive: 1.5 GB of free spaceSound: 100% DirectX compatible sound card and driversOS: Windows 7 or Windows Vista SP2Processor: Intel Pentium 4 or AMD Athlon 64 (or equivalent) running at 1.7 GHz or greaterMemory: 1.5 GB or greaterGraphics: ATI Radeon X1900 GT 256MB and the Nvidia GeForce 6800 Ultra 256MB PCI-E cards (Shader Model 2.0 and 24bit depth buffer support required)DirectX®: DirectX June 2010Hard Drive: 1.5 GB of free spaceSound: 100% DirectX compatible sound card and driversMac System RequirementsOS: OS X version Leopard 10.5.8, Snow Leopard 10.6.3, or later.Processor: Intel 1.8 GHz or higherMemory: 1.5 GB RAMGraphics: ATI Radeon x1900 or better / NVIDIA 8600M or better with 128 MB or higher Video Memory (VRAM)Hard Drive: 2 GB free disk space</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13091">Baldur's Gate: Dark Alliance</game><game id="12107">Baldur's Gate: Dark Alliance II</game><game id="5985">Diablo</game><game id="1119">Diablo II</game><game id="20803">Diablo III</game><game id="25983">Torchlight</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15693/1828696-baconingcover.jpg</image></root>