<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35451</id><name>Yu-Gi-Oh! 5D's World Championship 2011: Over the Nexus</name><description>OverviewYu-Gi-Oh! 5D's World Championship 2011: Over the Nexus is a card battling game developed and published by Konami Corporation for the Nintendo DS platform.PlotStarting OutThe protagonist of the game (the player) has a dream of becoming the greatest duelist in the world. The protagonist starts out being told that becoming the best will never happen, however Toru reveals that he has been working on a Duel Runner and the protagonist should participate in a local rental deck tournament.Rental Deck TournamentThe Rental Deck Tournament is a tournament in which all participating players must use a pre-made deck instead of a customized one. The Rental Deck Tournament was originally full, however one of the participants could not make it, opening a slot of the protagonist to then join.There are three matches that the protagonist must win in order to become the champion of the tournament. The first participant the protagonist must duel is West, followed by Nico, and then finally the girl that works at the card shop.Duel with BronsonAfter the protagonist wins the Rental Deck Tournament, Bronson is encountered. Bronson asks the protagonist where the location of the card shop is, also revealing that he was the player that didn't make it to the torunament. Once the protagonist reveals that the tournament is over, Bronson gets angry and challenged the protagonist to a duel. Once the player wins the duel it is revealed that they won the tournament. After winning the duel against Bronson the protagonist returns home who finds Klaus that says they need to do some shopping in Satellite.SatelliteWhile in Satellite the protagonist runs into a girl who proceeds to ask if some help can be given to find Crow Hogan. The protagonist finds Crow, who mistakenly thinks the player is trying to kidnap the girl. Crow then duels the protagonist, after which the girl tell Crow the truth and Crow apologizes to the protagonist.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="13">Card Game</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3210">Marvel Trading Card Game</game><game id="23867">Fullmetal Alchemist Trading Card Game</game><game id="10489">Pokémon Trading Card Game</game><game id="37907">Magic: The Gathering - Duels of the Planeswalkers 2013</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2210224-box_ygo5dswc2k11.png</image></root>