<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35485</id><name>Metro: Last Light</name><description>OverviewMetro: Last Light is the sequel to Metro 2033, developed by 4A Games. The game takes place in a post-apocalyptic Moscow and follows the adventures of Artyom as he fights to get a hold of a doomsday device. Unlike its predecessor, the game diverges from Dmitri Gloukhovski's books, meaning that this is not an adaptation of Metro 2034.Last Light's events take place after the ending of Metro 2033 in which Artyom launches a barrage of warheads to finish off The Dark Ones, which makes this the canonical ending to Metro 2033. Things have evolved since the first game. The nuclear winter is passing, the sun has re-appeared and the ice has melted. However, the environment has remained hostile as the outside air is unbreathable and Moscow is populated by mutants.The developers have promised better A.I., more stealth, more options to deal with situations, improved economy elements and multiplayer.Although the project was put on hiatus by THQ, which subsequently went under, the game will be published by KOCH Media under its Deep Silver brand. A Wii U version was at one point announced by THQ and in development but was put on indefinite hold due to a lack of resources. The game was released on May 14, 2013.System RequirementsPCMinimumWindows: XP (32-Bit), Vista, 7 or 8CPU: 2.2 GHz Dual Core e.g. Intel Core 2 DuoRAM: 2GBDirect X: 9.0cGraphics Card: DirectX 9, Shader Model 3 compliant e.g. NVIDIA GTS 250 (or AMD equivalent e.g. HD Radeon 4000 series) or higherFor 3D Vision SupportNVIDIA GTX 275 or higher120Hz MonitorNVIDIA 3D Vision kit for Windows Vista, 7 or 8RecommendedWindows: Vista, 7 or 8CPU: 2.6 GHz Quad Core e.g. Intel Core i5RAM: 4GBDirect X: 11Graphics Card: NVIDIA GTX 580/660 Ti (or AMD equivalent e.g. 7870) or higherFor 3D Vision SupportNVIDIA GTX 580/660Ti or higher120Hz MonitorNVIDIA 3D Vision kit for Windows Vista, 7 or 8OptimumWindows: Vista, 7 or 8CPU: 3.4 GHz Multi-Core e.g. Intel Core i7RAM: 8GBDirect X: 11Graphics Card: NVIDIA GTX 690 / NVIDIA TitanFor 3D Vision SupportNVIDIA GTX 690120Hz MonitorNVIDIA 3D Vision kit for Windows Vista, 7 or 8MACMinimumOS: 10.8.4 (Mountain Lion)Processor: 2.7 Ghz Intel Core i5 Memory: 8 GB RAM Graphics: NVIDIA GeForce GT 640M 512 MB Hard Drive: 10 GB available spaceRecommendedOS: 10.8.4 (Mountain Lion)Processor: 3.2 GHz quad core Intel Core i5 Memory: 16 GB RAM Graphics: NVidia Geforce GTX 680MX with 1GB Hard Drive: 10 GB available space</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21478">Cryostasis</game><game id="4800">F.E.A.R.: First Encounter Assault Recon</game><game id="11725">S.T.A.L.K.E.R.: Shadow of Chernobyl</game><game id="42744">Stalker 1: Path of Fire</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/82063/2213657-metroart.jpg</image></root>