<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35534</id><name>Halo: Combat Evolved Anniversary</name><description>OverviewHalo, now remastered in HDHalo: Combat Evolved Anniversary is a sci-fi first-person shooter developed by 343 Industries (in collaboration with Saber for the campaign and Certain Affinity for the multiplayer) and published by Microsoft for the Xbox 360 on November 15, 2011. Released on the tenth anniversary of the Halo franchise, the game is a fully-remastered version of Bungie's original Halo: Combat Evolved.While the original gameplay, physics, and controls remain intact, the campaign includes remastered sounds and an updated high-definition graphics engine that can be toggled on-the-fly (using both a dedicated button and Kinect voice recognition). Kinect voice recognition can also be used to give in-combat directives and scan the environment for a unique Halo encyclopedia. The game also includes new extras, such as achievements, Xbox Live co-operative multiplayer, collectible "skulls" (which modify gameplay when activated), and hidden terminals that provide plot information for Halo 4.The game also includes a restricted version of the multiplayer portion of Bungie's Halo: Reach, featuring six remakes of classic Halo maps (Beaver Creek, Damnation, Hang 'Em High, Prisoner, and Timberland from Halo: Combat Evolved, and Headlong from Halo 2) and one unique Firefight map (with architecture resembling the levels of Halo: Combat Evolved). New copies of the game also included a redeemable marketplace code so that players of Halo: Reach could download the maps for free (where other players must purchase the Anniversary Map Pack for 1200 msp, or $15).Players who pre-ordered the game received two bonuses: a Dress-Up item for their avatar that resembles Master Chief, and a special game-modifying Skull (titled the Grunt Funeral Skull) that causes killed Grunts to violently explode with the force of a Plasma Grenade).</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22034">Rez HD</game><game id="35508">Metal Gear Solid HD Collection</game><game id="28001">God of War Collection</game><game id="32696">The Ico &amp; Shadow of the Colossus Collection</game><game id="31788">The Sly Collection</game><game id="29021">Resistance 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2011577-box_halocea.png</image></root>