<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35545</id><name>Fuse</name><description>OverviewThe original OverStrike, in CG form...Fuse (formerly known as OverStrike) is a third person shooter developed by Insomniac Games and published by EA under EA partners. This is Insomniac's first multiplatform game, releasing on Xbox 360 and PS3 in May 2013. This will also mark their first wholly intellectual property.The game was originally revealed as Overstrike during the EA's E3 2011 press conference. The game then disappeared until September 2012, when it resurfaced as Fuse, sporting a less cartoonish art style.PlotThe game takes place in the near-future and tells the story of OverStrike 9, a rag-tag group of special agents who are infamous for breaking protocol. They are tasked with thwarting a terrorist plot. An evil terrorist organization plans to break into a top-secret US facility containing alien weaponry recovered during the 1940s. Overstrike recovers some of said weaponry and go on a killing spree to defeat the terrorists.OverStrike 9OverStrike 9 consists of four members, of whom players will take control in the game:Dalton Brooks (Bravo-Six-Tango), an ex-mercenaryJacob Kimble (Whiskey-Six-Victor), a detectiveIsabelle "Izzy" Sinclair (November-Three-Alpha), a scientistNaya Deveraux (Delta-One-Foxtrot), a thiefGameplayFuse is a third person-shooter with an emphasis on cooperative gameplay. Players can choose to play as either one of the Overstrike 9 operatives and switch between them at will while playing alone (if playing in coop, the player's allies will take control of the operatives). By killing opponents in fast, stylish ways, players get Fuse points which can then be used in the Fuse store....and the redesigned Fuse, in-engine.The Fuse store is where players can unlock new abilities and weapons for their characters. For example, the thief of the group can unlock an ability to become invisible. The game also has a variety of special weapons that only certain members of the group can unlock and use. The heavy of the group can use the MagShield, a weapon that creates a large force field that protects teammates while allowing them to shoot through at enemies. The medic of the group can use the Shattergun, which freezes enemies in place.DevelopmentOverstrike was first revealed at E3 2011, as a new EA Partners publishing arrangement. The animated trailer by Blur Studios, showed a stylistically caricatured art style with vibrant colors, that combined humor and action. Though visually and stylistically the project was still going through revisions process. The main reasons for Insomniac’s partnership with EA, was the fact that they had been a single platform developer for Sony, since the company’s inception, which impeded both sales and exposure to a different audience. Prior to this point, Insomniac also did not owned any of their intellectual properties, due to its exclusivity development with Sony, marking their first wholly owned title."Not all images represenative of actual gameplay" On August 31st, 2012, Insomniac revealed that they had retooled Overstrike and rebranded it to; Fuse - though still keeping the core gameplay relatively the same; a class based, four player co-operative shooter, most of revisions were aimed towards the atheistic look and the writing of the narrative. As a result of the revisions, the comic art direction, caricature model designs and narrative tone, changed dramatically from what was originally shown to the public in 2011. Fuse was a darker, grounded narrative and a more serious game. According to game designer Brian Allgeier, the drastic changes in tone and art direction came after focus testing with a certain demographic of gamers." Maybe it was going to appeal to gamers who, we thought at the time, might be in their late teens. The industry’s changed quite a bit…We started to discover that everyone thought this was a game for their younger brother. We would hear this from 12-year-olds. So we decided that we needed to make a game that had an older appeal." - Brian AllgeierAllgeier had also stated that due to the serious tonal shift in the game’s narrative, the campy cartoony aesthetics would not suit the “action orientated”direction the game was heading in or the intended target audience they're after. Insomniac’s staff writer T.J. Fixman has said much of the game’s humor was toned down to a “more sophisticated, dry wit”.With the changes included a more graphic and mature take on violence and gore, Insomniac founder, Ted Price, considers this as the best way to exemplify the weapons and not have its affects restricted to a T-rating.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21109">Resistance: Retribution</game><game id="20699">Resistance 2</game><game id="34018">Resistance: Burning Skies</game><game id="21000">Secret Agent Clank</game><game id="18745">Ratchet: Deadlocked</game><game id="4618">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Going Commando</game><game id="18309">Ratchet &amp; Clank</game><game id="21115">Ratchet &amp; Clank Future: Quest for Booty</game><game id="8837">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Size Matters</game><game id="38458">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Full Frontal Assault</game><game id="32361">Ratchet &amp; Clank: All 4 One</game><game id="25673">Ratchet &amp; Clank Future: A Crack in Time</game><game id="37715">Ratchet &amp; Clank Collection</game><game id="1563">Spyro 2: Ripto's Rage</game><game id="15249">Spyro Orange: The Cortex Conspiracy</game><game id="20908">The Legend of Spyro: Dawn of the Dragon</game><game id="7836">Spyro the Dragon</game><game id="3883">The Legend of Spyro: A New Beginning</game><game id="8420">Spyro: Enter the Dragonfly</game><game id="10579">Spyro: Season of Ice</game><game id="19433">Spyro: Attack of the Rhynocs</game><game id="34129">Skylanders: Spyro's Adventure</game><game id="13512">Spyro: Shadow Legacy</game><game id="13370">Spyro 2: Season of Flame</game><game id="12209">Spyro: A Hero's Tail</game><game id="35406">Crash &amp; Spyro Superpack</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2390572-fuse_cover.jpg</image></root>