<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35553</id><name>Just Dance 3</name><description>OverviewJust Dance 3 is a dance game by Ubisoft. In it, up to four players mirror the motions of a silhouetted FMV character in the center of the screen, with stickfigure prompts in the bottom-right corner. This is accomplished with the aid of one Wii Remote or Playstation Move controller in each player's right hand on non-Kinect platforms.Counter to previous installments (which were only available on the Nintendo Wii), Just Dance 3 is the first game in the Just Dance franchise to also release on Playstation 3 and Xbox 360 (due to Move and Kinect support, respectively).FeaturesFully animated stage-specific backgrounds. The dancer on Black Eyed Peas - "Pump It" causes crystals to shoot up out of the ground in time with the music, which shatter and fall to the floor.Specific songs have 4-part choreographies. "I Was Made For Lovin' You" has each player miming out a part in a four-person band.Dance Mashup mode, which combines moves and routines from several songs into one, providing a unique experience every time.An enhanced Just Sweat mode, featuring more workout plans.Returning modes include Classic Mode, Duet Mode, Medley, and Simon Says.Just Create mode, in which players on the Xbox 360 can film their own routines with the Kinect camera and upload them via a user-generated content interface, allowing friends to dance along and try to match the routine.The Kinect version is the first Kinect dance game to support 4 players dancing at once.Song LIstOver 45 songs are confirmed for release on-disc, spanning new genres for the Just Dance series (including Bollywood and Reggaeton). Additionally, Ubisoft plans to support Just Dance 3 with downloadable content on all three platforms.2 Unlimited – "No Limit"A-ha - "Take On Me"Anja - "Dance All Nite"Bananarama - "Venus"Black Eyed Peas – "Pump It"Bollywood Rainbow - "Kurio ko uddah le jana"Cee Lo Green - "Forget You"Countdown Mix Masters - "Beautiful Liar"Daft Punk - "Da Funk"Danny Elfman - "This is Halloween"Donna Summer - "I Feel Love"Dr. Creole - "Baby Zouk"Duck Sauce - "Barbara Streisand"Girls Aloud - "Jump (For My Love)"Groove Century - "Boogie Wonderland"Gwen Stefani - "What You Waiting For"Inspector Marceau - "The Master Blaster"Janelle Monae - "Tightrope (Solo Version)"Jessie J featuring B.o.B - "Price Tag"Brahms by Just Dance Classical Orchestra - "Hungarian Dance No. 5"Katy Perry featuring Snoop Dogg - "California Gurls"KISS - "I Was Made For Lovin' You"Konshens - "Jamaican Dance"African Ladies - "Pata Pata"Latino Sunset - "mamasita"Laura Bell Bundy - "Giddy On Up (Giddy On Out)"Lena Meyer-Landrut - "Satellite"LMFAO featuring Lauren Bennett and GoonRock - "Party Rock Anthem"Madness - "Night Boat to Cairo"MIKA - "Lollipop"Nelly Furtado featuring Timbaland - "Promiscuous"Pointer Sisters - "I'm So Excited"Queen - "Crazy Little Thing Called Love"Reggaeton Explosion - "Boom"Rita Mitsouko - "Marcia Baila"Robbie Williams and Nicole Kidman - "Somethin' Stupid"Robin Sparkles - "Let's Go To The Mall"Scissor Sisters - "I Don't Feel Like Dancin'"Sweat Invaders - "Gonna Make You Sweat (Everybody Dance Now)"Taio Cruz - "Dynamite"The Buggles - "Video Killed The Radio Star"The Chemical Brothers - "Hey Boy Hey Girl"The Girly Team - "Baby One More Time"The London Theatre Orchestra  Cast - "Think"The Sugarhill Gang - "Apache (Jump On It)"Tommy Sparks - "She's Got Me Dancing"Wilson Pickett - "Land of 1000 Dances"Exclusive EditionsBest Buy sells a retailer-exclusive edition of Just Dance 3 for all three systems, containing two additional Katy Perry singles: "E.T." and "Teenage Dream".Target also sells their own addition of Just Dance 3, featuring two songs different from the Best Buy edition: Rihanna - "Only Girl In The World" and B.o.B. feat. Hayley Williams - "Airplanes".</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="35532">Dance Central 2</game><game id="35638">Everybody Dance</game><game id="34784">DanceDanceRevolution</game><game id="31705">Dance Central</game><game id="36861">Nickelodeon Dance</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1988275-box_jd3.png</image></root>