<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35610</id><name>Fortune Street</name><description>OverviewOne of the Boards in the game.Fortune Street is the ninth entry in Square Enix's long-running Itadaki Street series of video board games and the first to see official release in North America. This particular entry features characters from the Dragon Quest and Mario franchises, as well as Miis, in addition to boards themed after each. The game was published by Nintendo in North America and launched on December 5, 2011. This game supports online multiplayer with the Nintendo Wi-Fi Connection.GameplayDescribed as Monopoly with a stock market, Fortune Street lets up to four players go around one of fifteen boards to collect four symbols, buying properties along the way. Once the heart, diamond, spade, and club symbols are collected, a player can go to the bank to get a promotion (level up). The objective of the game is to acquire a certain amount of money and return to the bank before the other players or to hold the lead when a minimum number of players go bankrupt.At the bank they can buy stocks on groups of properties referred to as districts, inflating the value of the individual properties. Players can also add to the value of their properties by leveling up, buying all the properties of the same group or investing directly on one of them. Landing on a rival's property forces a player to pay a fee, determined by its value, to the owner and all shareholders of the group's property. Selling ten or more stocks in a single turn will lower the value of the district. The stock market mechanic is eliminated if the player chooses to play under the "Easy Rules" rule set.Some spaces on the boards trigger mini games, one of which involves betting on slime races.Some boards have a Wild card space known as a vacant plot. any player landing on it, can build a space as a ploy to basically collect more money. </description><genres><genre id="14">Trivia/Board Game</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12812">Star Wars: Monopoly</game><game id="21714">Monopoly: Here &amp; Now Worldwide Edition</game><game id="20786">Culdcept Saga</game><game id="9459">Culdcept</game><game id="36400">Culdcept II</game><game id="24844">Every Party</game><game id="39909">Matsumoto Tooru no Kabushiki Hisshou Gaku</game><game id="40216">Super Momotarou Dentetsu II</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2079823-box_fstreet.png</image></root>