<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35638</id><name>Everybody Dance</name><description>OverviewEverybody Dance is a dancing game that utilizes both the Playstation Move wand and the Playstation Eye. The game tasks you with doing a variety of dance moves while jamming out to popular songs. A friend can sing along as you dance with a Singstar mic and you can upload a video of you dancing to the game's website.GameplayDancin'You play the game with one Playstation Move wand in your hand (it doesn't matter if it's left or right). The song starts (some songs play with the music video) and the game will begin giving you dance moves to perform, telling you where to place your hands and feet. If you are singing while performing the song, the lyrics to the song will appear at the bottom right side of the screen.Everybody Dance comes with a variety of game modes. Dance Class is a tutorial that teaches you different dance moves. Dance Battle is a versus mode where each player tries to score the most points while the Co-Operative Routine mode lets you dance in tandem with a partner. Finally Dance Party lets you and 19 other people dance together. It's unclear how this mode will work. Dance Workout is a mode where you can dance to songs and the game estimates how many calories you have burn dancing to each song. Also during the Dance workout mode it will show your progress in calories burned with a chart that shows the last 30 days. The actual calories burned is more accurate than Just Dance 3 similar mode in that at least asks and takes your weight into account when doing the calculations.TracklistThe game features forty tracks that can be played on three different difficulty levels. Additional tracks will be available at launch as DLC.TracksAmerie - 1 ThingBarry White - You’re The First, The Last, My EverythingBasement Jaxx - Where’s Your Head AtBilly Idol - Dancing with MyselfBodyrockers - I Like The WayCarl Douglas - Kung Fu FightingCeCe Peniston - FinallyChromeo - Night By NightDam-Funk - Hood Pass IntactDeadmau5 - Ghosts ‘N’ Stuff (feat. Rob Swire)Diana Ross - Upside DownDuck Sauce - Barbra StreisandEllie Goulding - Starry EyedElton John - I’m Still StandingFatboy Slim - Praise YouGroove Armada - Superstylin’Ida Corr Vs Fedde Le Grand - Let Me Think About ItJay Sean featuring Lil Wayne - DownKool And The Gang - Get Down On ItLady Gaga - Born This WayLMFAO - Party Rock AnthemM/A/R/R/S - Pump Up The VolumeMiami Sound Machine - Dr BeatNew Kids On The Block - You Got It (The Right Stuff)Nicole Scherzinger - Don’t Hold Your BreathOk Go - Here It Goes AgainOutkast - The Way You MovePuretone - Addicted To BassR. Kelly - Step In The Name of LoveRaphael Saadiq - RadioRepublica - Ready To GoRihanna - Rude BoySNAP! - The PowerSublime - SanteriaThe Chemical Brothers - Hey Boy Hey GirlTiesto v Diplo feat Busta Rhymes - C`Mon (Catch `Em By Surprise)Tinie Tempah - Pass OutUsher featuring Pitbull - DJ Got Us Fallin’ In LoveUsher featuring will.i.am - OMGWillow - Whip My Hair</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20462">SingStar</game><game id="31705">Dance Central</game><game id="35532">Dance Central 2</game><game id="27859">Just Dance</game><game id="31347">Just Dance 2</game><game id="35553">Just Dance 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2452880-box_ed.png</image></root>