<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35668</id><name>Of Orcs and Men</name><description>OverviewIn Of Orcs and Men the player is placed in the role of an elite Orc soldier that belongs to the Bloodjaws legion, a legendary league of warriors heavily involved in the war between the Orcs and Goblins against Humankind. As a seasoned warrior who has experienced brutal battles and bloodshed, the Orc is appointed a mission by the Orc commander. The Orc is to slay the Emperor whom is responsible for all the devastation and loathing against the green-skinned people and ultimately change the course of the war.Aiding the Orc on this mission is a Goblin with distinct character skills which the player must use to their advantage on and off the battlefield. Both the Orc and the Goblin have unique skill trees that will need to be developed throughout the course of the game. The Orc's skill tree is based specifically on power while the Goblin uses dark arts and stealth abilities.As the world continues to spiral down into chaos, the two heroes will encounter a cruel and merciless human existence bent on persecution of the Orcs and Goblins with one final chance to change the course of history and bring peace to the lands.PC System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows XP, Vista, 7, 8Processor:Dual Core 2 GHZMemory:2048 MB RAMGraphics: 512 MB 100% DirectX 9 and shaders 4.0 compatibleDirectX®:9.0cHard Drive:6 GB HD spaceLinksOfficial Website</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="36886">Game of Thrones</game><game id="30718">Confrontation</game><game id="40731">Dark Shadows - Army of Evil</game><game id="10473">The Witcher</game><game id="30330">Kingdoms of Amalur: Reckoning</game><game id="33394">The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim</game><game id="33494">Dungeons &amp; Dragons Daggerdale</game><game id="34384">Orc Attack</game><game id="40725">Dungeon Gate</game><game id="36056">Dungeons: The Dark Lord</game><game id="27878">Fable III</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2392941-of_orcs_and_men_01_artwork.jpg</image></root>