<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>357</id><name>Burnout 3: Takedown</name><description>OverviewReleased on September 7, 2004, Burnout 3: Takedown is the first Burnout title to be published under the EA banner and the first to receive a T rating from the ESRB. Previous entries were published by Acclaim. Initially available for the PlayStation 2 and Xbox, the game was also released in downloadable form as an Xbox Original on the Xbox 360 in early 2008.Takedown is similar in structure to its predecessor, Burnout 2: Point of Impact. But the game does have several new features that make it more than the "racing game plus big crashes" formula used in the past. New features include Impact Time, which allows players to slow time after a crash in order to direct their mangled frame of a car around the road and, ideally, hit other cars for an Aftertouch Takedown. This adds a new layer to the game, slowing down the normally intensely high-speed feel in order to get some post-crash satisfaction.Players take on multiple event types over the course of the game, including Race, Road Rage, and Crash Mode. Race is fairly straightforward--first one to the finish line wins. Road Rage sets a target number of "takedowns" for the player to reach. Crash mode pins drivers not against other cars, but rather, against set patterns of parked cars and traffic, making it feel almost like a high-speed puzzle that's solved when you find the precise spot to cause the biggest crash.Burnout 3: Takedown featured online support, allowing up to six players to compete in race events and up to eight in a Crash event. As part of Microsoft's shutdown of Xbox Live for original Xbox games, on April 15th 2010 EA turned off the servers for Xbox and PS2. VehiclesCompact SeriesCompact Type 1Compact Type 2Compact Type 3Tuned CompactModified CompactCustom CompactAssassin CompactCompact PrototypeCompact DXDominator CompactMuscle SeriesMuscle Type 1Muscle Type 2Muscle Type 3Tuned MuscleModified MuscleCustom MuscleAssassin MuscleMuscle PrototypeMuscle DXDominator MuscleCoupe SeriesCoupe Type 1Coupe Type 2Coupe Type 3Tuned CoupeModified CoupeCustom CoupeAssassin CoupeCoupe PrototypeCoupe DXDominator CoupeSports SeriesSports Type 1Sports Type 2Sports Type 3Tuned SportsModified SportsCustom SportsAssassin SportsSports PrototypeSports DXDominator SportsSuper SeriesSuper Type 1Super Type 2Super Type 3Tuned SuperModified SuperCustom SuperAssassin SuperSuper PrototypeSuper DXDominator SuperSpecial SeriesOval Racer SpecialCustom Coupe UltimateEuro Circuit RacerClassic HotrodUS Circuit RacerWorld Circuit RacerHeavyweightsHeavy Pick Up4WD RacerSUV Deluxe4WD Heavy DutyB Team VanDelivery TruckTractor CabLongnose CabCity BusTrash TruckFire TruckLocationsBurnout 3: Takedown features 18 tracks on three continents; USA, Europe and Far East ( Asia). It's also possible to play each track in the opposite direction, doubling the number of tracks to 36.USASilver LakeTraffic: 3/10Corner amount: LowLocation: USAWaterfrontTraffic: 4/10Corner amount: MediumLocation: USADowntownTraffic: 9/10Corner amount: LowLocation: USAKings of the RoadTraffic: 6/10Corner amount: MediumLocation: USAMountain ParkwayTraffic: 5/10Corner amount: Low/MediumLocation: USALakeside GetawayTraffic: 5/10Corner amount: HighLocation: USAEuropeVineyardTraffic: 6/10Corner amount: MediumLocation: EuropeRivieraTraffic: 4/10Corner amount: Low/MediumLocation: EuropeAlpineTraffic: 3/10Corner amount: LowLocation: EuropeWinter CityTraffic: 4/10Corner amount: LowLocation: EuropeAlpine ExpresswayTraffic: 6/10Corner amount: HighLocation: EuropeFrozen PeakTraffic: 7/10Corner amount: Medium/HighLocation: EuropeCoastal DreamTraffic: 9/10Corner amount: HighLocation: EuropeContinental RunTraffic: 8/10Corner amount: MediumLocation: EuropeAsiaDocksideTraffic: 6/10Corner amount: Low/MediumLocation: AsiaGolden CityTraffic: 10/10Corner amount: MediumLocation: AsiaIsland ParadiseTraffic: 2/10Corner amount: LowLocation: AsiaTropical DriveTraffic: 10/10Corner amount: HighLocation: Asia100%All Burnout games have provided some sort of status page as to how much of the game has been completed. This includes a percentage of the over all game you have done. To get 100% the player must get all 173 gold medals in World tour (races and crash junctions), all signature takedowns, all crash headlines, and all four Burnout trophies.Signature TakedownsTo unlock the Oval Racer Special under the Special car class, the player must get all 20 signature takedowns. Signature Takedowns are takedowns done at certain points on tracks and the player receives a [stock] photo.Gone Fishin' - Takedown over the trailer park (Silverlake)Pillar Driller - Takedown into a Pillar (Downtown)Tram Ram - Takedown into a Waterfront Tram (Waterfront)Euro Tram Ram - Takedown into a Winter City Tram (Winter City)Rumble in the Jungle - Takedown on the Island Paradise Offroad Route (Island Paradise)Snowed Under - Takedown into a Snow Plough (Winter City)Paid the Price - Takedown into Alpine Tollbooths (Alpine)Berth Trauma - Takedown into Riviera Marina (Riviera)Grapes of Wrath - Takedown into a Wine Truck (Vineyard)Tuk-Down - Takedown into a Tuk-Tuk (Golden City)Home Wrecker - Takedown into a Motor Home (Silverlake)Hit the Split - Takedown into Wall at tunnel entrance in Downtown (Downtown)Truck Torpedo - Takedown into a Big Rig hauling Speedboats (Silverlake)Catch the Tour Bus - Takedown into the Parked Tour Busses in Island Paradise (Island Paradise)Ship Wreck - Takedown into the Dockside Tanker Port (Dockside)Avalanche! - Takedown over the edge of Alpine Bridges (Alpine)Riviera Roustabout - Takedown into Riviera's Roundabout Monument (Riviera)Gate Crasher - Takedown into the town gate (Vineyard)Market Stalled - Takedown into Golden City Market (Golden City)Tunnel of Shove - Takedown into a Tunnel Support in Dockside (Dockside)Crash HeadlinesTo get the best crash vehicle in the game - The Firetruck - players must get all 10 Crash Headlines. These are newspaper headlines received from getting so much money on the following crash junctions.Bayside Blitz! - $900,000 Crash Damage on a Waterfront JunctionDowntown Demolition - $650,000 Crash Damage on a Downtown JunctionSilver Lake Lunacy! - $600,000 Crash Damage on a Silver Lake JunctionWinter City Frozen - $800,000 Crash Damage on a Winter City JunctionAlpine Smash! - $900,000 Crash Damage on a Alpine JunctionRiviera Wreck! - $750,000 Crash Damage on a Riviera JunctionGrape Harvest Crushed! - $850,000 Crash Damage on a Vineyard JunctionGolden City Madness! - $750,000 Crash Damage on a Golden City JunctionDockside Ridge Ruin! - $1,000,000 Crash Damage on a Dockside JunctionTrouble in Paradise! - $750,000 Crash Damage on a Island Paradise Junction4 Burnout TrophiesBy acquiring all Burnout trophies players will receive the fastest car in the game, the Euro Racer.Easy Takedowns2 Wall Takedowns in a race1st Car Takedown1st Aftertouch Takedown5 Takedowns in a race1st Takedown RampageAdvance Takedowns1st Revenge Takedown1st Psyche out Takedown1st Big Rig Takedown2 Bus Takedowns in a race10 Takedowns in a raceExpert Takedowns1st Double Takedown2 Tram Takedowns in a race2 Trailer Takedowns in a race3 Aftertouch Takedowns in a race20 Takedowns in a road rage eventChampion Takedowns1st Triple Takedown1500 Total Takedowns15 Takedowns in a race40 Takedowns in a road rage event2000 Total TakedownsSoundtrack1208 - "Fall Apart"Amber Pacific - "Always You"Ash - "Orpheus"Atretyu - "Right Side of the Bed"Autopilot Off - "Make a Sound"Bouncing Souls - "Sing Along Forever"Burning Brides - "Heart Full of Black"Chronic Future - "Time and Time Again"Donots - "Saccharine Smile"Eighteen Visions - "I Let Go"Fall Out Boy - "Reinventing the Wheel to Run Myself Over"Finger Eleven - "Stay in Shadow"Franz Ferdinand - "This Fire"From First to Last - "Populace in Two"Funeral for a Friend - "Rookie of the Year"Futureheads - "Decent Days and Nights"Go Betty Go - "C’mon"Jimmy Eat World - "Just Tonight"Letter Kills - "Radio Up"Local H - "Everyone Alive"Maxeen - "Please"Midtown - "Give It Up"Moments in Grace - "Broken Promises"Motion City Soundtrack - "My Favorite"Mudmen - "Animal"My Chemical Romance - "I’m Not Okay"New Found Glory - "At Least I’m Known"No Motiv - "Independence Day"Silent Drive - "4-16"Sugarcult - "Memory"The D4 - "Come On!"The Explosion - "Here I Am"The F-Ups - "Lazy Generation"The Lot Six - "Autobrats"The Matches - "Audio Blood"The Mooney Suzuki - "Shake That Bush"The Ordinary Boys - "Over the Counter"The Von Bondies - "C’Mon C’Mon"Yellowcard - "Breathing"Xbox OriginalsOn January 14, 2008, Burnout 3: Takedown became available on the Xbox 360's Xbox Originals download service for 1200 Microsoft Points.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6836">FlatOut: Ultimate Carnage</game><game id="859">FlatOut 2</game><game id="12976">Need for Speed: Most Wanted</game><game id="11473">Full Auto</game><game id="21606">Crash Time: Autobahn Pursuit</game><game id="13776">Destruction Derby 2</game><game id="786">Destruction Derby</game><game id="13177">FlatOut</game><game id="7777">Juiced</game><game id="14204">Mashed: Drive to Survive</game><game id="9813">Crashday</game><game id="22207">Karnaaj Rally</game><game id="16728">Powerslide</game><game id="689">Jak X: Combat Racing</game><game id="20998">FlatOut: Head On</game><game id="25627">Smash Cars</game><game id="20451">MotorStorm: Pacific Rift</game><game id="8458">San Francisco Rush: Extreme Racing</game><game id="20698">Wheelman</game><game id="27802">Sideswiped</game><game id="31698">Need for Speed: Hot Pursuit</game><game id="34943">Need for Speed: The Run</game><game id="1321">L. A. Rush</game><game id="44094">X-Treme Express: World Grand Prix</game><game id="44015">Gas Guzzlers Extreme</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1793279-box_bout3t.png</image></root>