<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35773</id><name>Tiny Tower</name><description>OverviewThe goal of this management game is to build as high a tower as possible. The player is given only a lobby and just enough gold coins to build his first floor. That enables him to start the economy and make more money to build more floors. There are two main types of floors: residential and money producing. Residential can accommodate up to 5 Bitizens (inhabitants of the Tiny Tower), who pay rent and also serve as employees in the money producing floors.There are 5 types of product selling floors:Building new floors is the main goal.FoodServiceRecreationRetailCreativityEach of these types has its own demand, which is calculated from the current number of each type built. This leads player to have roughly equal amount of each type, for the best results.Every floor is built using earned gold coins, the price of every new one is higher than the last one. When a non-residential floor is built, it must be filled with up to three Bitizens (workers), each enables one of the three specific product to be stocked and sold (for example having three Bitizens employed at Mexican Food enables player to sell Chips  Salsa, Tacos and finally Shrimp Platter). Each Bitizen also has a rating for every category, ranging from zero to nine for each, making them more effective in certain types of sales - the higher the number, the cheaper it is to restock given product. In addition to these ratings each Bitizen has a set Dream Job - if he or she is assigned to work in their desired place, the restocked amount of the product is doubled.In addition to the main currency (mentioned gold coins) there are also "Bux" available in Tiny Tower. These can be used to speed up all time consuming processes, like construction of a new floor, restocking a product or even enabling to quick-sell all remaining supplies. These Bux are obtained in various ways: player can randomly get one for fully restocking a floor (which normally gives a gold cash bonus), as a reward for finding a certain Bitizen when asked for by the game and more. Also, there is also an ingame store, where it is possible to buy Bux for real money.GameplayPlayer's main role in Tiny Tower is to oversee the development of the new floors, managing restocking of the floors and lastly there is an option to operate an elevator, taking random Bitizens to their desired floors for gold coins reward (and random Bux drops). Time passes even when the application is not running, so the player can set tasks like building or restocking of a product and shut the game down. When he returns, passed time is subtracted from each timer and money for sales in this time is added to player's account. The game also supports push messages, alerting player when his attention is needed.Every floor and Bitizen can also be customized - floors can change colors and Bitizens can be outfitted in different clothes, their facial hair and some accessories can also be randomized.Bitizens stat screenThere are also various menu screens available, where player can browse all of his Bitizens (their mood depends on the actual job), buy faster elevator, exchange Bux for Gold coins, browse stats or read "Bitbook" - local version of Facebook, where Bitizens leave their messages as time passes. It is also possible to visit a friend's Tiny Tower (these friends must be connected via Game Center).Organization / ManagementThere are several organizational strategies that you can utilized to make your experience more pleasant. When your floors start to really add up it becomes very difficult to find a specific bitizen for their delivery quests. A great organization technique for floors is to keep all types together. For instance, keep all apartment floors together on the bottom, all the green floors together next, and so on. When you build a new floor you do are given 1 bux which can be used for moving the floor to your desired location.Next, color code your bitizens to match the color of the floor that they currently reside on. If they work on a blue floor give them a blue outfit. This saves a great deal of time because instead of looking through all the floors you can just search through a specific section and/or apartment levels.Types of BusinessesFoodBusiness NameLow Tier ItemMid Tier ItemHigh Tier ItemBakerySugar CookiesWalnut MuffinsBread LoafBBQ PlaceOnion RingsBBQ SandwichBeef RibsFancy CuisineSparkling JuiceCaviarRoast DuckPubBar NutsRoot BeerHot WingsSushi BarCalifornia RollTuna SushiSea UrchinMexican FoodChips  SalsaTacosShrimp PlatterAsian CuisineSpring RollsNoodle BowlOrange TofuScoopsIce Cream BarTriple ScoopIce Cream CakePizza PlacePizza SlicePersonal PanGiant PizzaSub Shop6 Inch Sub9 Inch Sub12 Inch SubSky BurgerFriesNuggetsBig BurgerVegan FoodBeet SaladRoasted PotatoesSoy BurgerDinerCup of JoeBacon  EggsSoup  SandwichTea HouseGreen TeaDumplingsPork KatsuCoffee HouseEspressoTall LatteFrappeSmoothie ShopWheatgrassSmall SmoothieJumbo JuiceFrozen YogurtMini ChocolateMedium VanillaJumbo SwirlPancake HousePancakesBerry PancakesBig StackDonut ShopDonut HolesGlazed DonutsBearclawsServicesBusiness NameLow Tier ItemMid Tier ItemHigh Tier ItemFortune TellerPalm ReadingTarot ReadingSeanceWedding ChapelQuick HitchFull CeremonyThemed CeremonyTravel AgencyCar ReservationFlight BookingCruise BookingLaundromatSock FluffDelicate CycleDenim DryRecyclingNewspaperCansGlassShip  PrintPhotocopiesShipmentSales ReportBarber ShopShaveHaircutPermMartial ArtsWhite BeltRed BeltBlack BeltDay SpaPedicureFacialStone MassageHealth ClubWeight WorkoutBall WorkoutCardio WorkoutDentists OfficeCleaningTeeth WhiteningGold CrownOptometristEye GlassesContact LensesLaser TreatmentDoctors OfficeCheck UpPrescriptionLab TestPharmacyCold MedicineFlu ShotRX RefillBankCheck DepositNew AccountLoan ApplicationTutoring CenterAddition HelpGrammar HelpTrig HelpPrivate EyeBackground CheckSurveillanceMurder MysteryCourthouseSmall ClaimsFamily CourtGrand JurySecurity OfficeID BadgesRadiosTasersRecreationBusiness NameLow Tier ItemMid Tier ItemHigh Tier ItemPlanetariumPlanet TourSolar TourLaser ShowAquariumAdmissionFish ToyAnnual PassMuseumAdmissionAudio TourCharity EventMini Golf1 Player Round2 Player Round3 Player RoundPaintball Arena100 Paintballs500 Paintballs1000 PaintballsRock Climbing1 Climb2 Climbs3 ClimbsVolleyball ClubPracticeFriendly GameTournamentRacquetballPracticeFriendly GameTournamentBowlingShoe RentalSingle GameTournamentCineplexPopcornMatinee3D MovieTheaterInterpretive DanceComedyTragedyComedy ClubLOL'sLMAO'sROFL'sNight ClubCover ChargeCocktailVIP TicketKaraoke ClubSolo SongDuet SongClub RentalCasinoNickel SlotsDollar SlotsPoker GameHaunted HouseChillsCreepsScreamsArcade1 PlayExtra LifeHigh ScoreCyber CafeWeb BrowsingComputer GamesGame TourneyVideo RentalMovie RentalNew ReleaseConsole RentalRetailBusiness NameLow Tier ItemMid Tier ItemHigh Tier ItemGame StoreUsed GameControllerGame SystemComic StoreMage CardsBattleclub FigureAtom Man No 1Book StorePaperbackHardbackBoxed SetRecord ShopSingleAlbumDiscographyMusic StoreSheet MusicTrumpetElectric GuitarCandle ShopVanilla CandlePine CandlePumpkin CandleFabric ShopThread SpoolQuilt SquareBolts of FabricMens FashionTieDress Belt3 Piece SuitWomens FashionCute HatPurseNice OutfitShoe StoreSandalsSneakersDress ShoesHat ShopTrucker HatCowboy HatTop HatPlant NurserySmall CactusHanging PlantFertilizerFurniture StoreFake PlantEnd TableModern ChairAuto DealerUsed VanHatchbackConvertibleBike ShopBike ShirtBike WheelMountain BikeTech StoreCameraLaptopFlat Screen TVMapple StoreMyPodMyPhoneMyBookToy StoreToy BlocksRocket ShipToy SoldiersGrocery StoreCerealTabloidProduceCreativeBusiness NameLow Tier ItemMid Tier ItemHigh Tier ItemCake StudioSingle LayerDouble LayerTriple LayerSoda BreweryCherry SodaCola 6 PackSoda KegTattoo ParlorButterflyDemon SkullFancy ParrotPhoto StudioPet PortraitSingle PortraitFamily PortraitFilm StudioFood CommercialTV EpisodeMovie ShootArt StudioSmall PortraitStill LifeLandscapeAnimation StudioAnimated ShortDVD ReleaseCinema ClassicAd AgencyPrint AdBillboard AdTV AdGraphic DesignAlbum CoverBand PosterWeb SiteGame StudioMatch 3 GameCity SimMMORPGSoftware StudioCalendar AppAnti-virus AppBank SoftwareRecording StudioJingle RecordingSingle RecordingAlbum RecordingFloral StudioCorsageBouquetArrangementArchitect OfficeRoom AdditionHouse DesignTower DesignWood ShopChairRocking HorseBookcasePottery StudioSimple BowlPretty PlateDetailed VaseGlass StudioGreen TumblerOrange VaseAqua BottleFashion StudioWrap DesignBlouse DesignOutfit DesignLaboratoryLove PotionMystery GooMonsterApartmentsStorage ApartmentsLoft ApartmentsMismatch AptsSweetside AptsPlainlake AptsClub AptsBeach AptsTiki AptsSafari AptsPinehurst AptsBaycrest Apts50's Apts70's AptsStonecrest AptsHifi AptsGlendale AptsSanta Fe AptsMesa AptsIvymoss AptsTuscana AptsGarden AptsLotus AptsGreenwood AptsRustic AptsBridgeview AptsCottage AptsEclectic AptsGoldcreek AptsHacienda AptsSubmarine AptsNerd Cave AptsAquatic AptsBroadleaf AptsRidgemill AptsBrightpoint AptsDevonshire AptsAnti Grav AptsSilverwell AptsPlumbrook AptsMapleton AptsFawlty AptsBirchside AptsArt Deco AptsModerna AptsHigh Tech AptsMistmont AptsMillspring AptsMagic AptsGothic AptsZen AptsEstate AptsWestgrove AptsChateau AptsGreek AptsRoman AptsEgyptian Apts</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4881">Yoot Tower</game><game id="2447">SimTower: The Vertical Empire</game><game id="38495">Lil' Kingdom</game><game id="38711">Pocket Planes</game><game id="40278">My Little Pony: Friendship is Magic</game><game id="44139">Star Wars: Tiny Death Star</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/12/129913/1840534-photo_11_07_15_9_02_43_am.png</image></root>