<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35793</id><name>Marksman: Long Range</name><description>An Xbox indie game that focuses on realistic target rifle shooting. It was Developed by Andy Campbell over the course of roughly 250 hours. Campbell developed the game as a way to introduce players to a realistic system of rifle shooting.  Campbell has said on his personal blog that he hopes this game introduces more people to real life sport target shooting. Gameplay        The game has a simple menu interface that allows you to select a gun type, a play mode and a difficulty setting along with a simple leader board of your best scores.   The control scheme is meant to be a realistic representation of shooting a rifle over long distances. Because of this elements such as elevation, distance, bullet drop and windage all effect your shot.  To facilitate an easier shot, the game automatically creates a "drop table" that gives the player different scope settings for different distances and winds. All a player needs to do is figure out the range and plug the numbers from the "drop table" into their scope.   The player must also keep a slow steady pull on the controller trigger, or the shot will pull to the left or right wildly. At higher difficulties the player must also contend with "grip steadiness" which is controlled by keeping the right thumb stick in a particular position throughout the shot. Modes  There are four modes in Marksman: Long Range.        Rifle Golf: The player must hit the 10 ring of 5 different targets of varying distances. Distances of the targets are not marked, so the player must figure that out for themselves. There is no time limit in this mode.  Zombie Horde: Paper cutout targets of zombies slowly cross a green field as you try to eliminate them with head shots. The targets move from side to side, making a head shot difficult. The game ends when either the targets are all eliminated or a zombie reaches the player.  Time Attack: Exactly how it sounds. Players must shoot 10 rounds in 60 seconds to achieve the highest possible score in the shortest amount of time. The target distances are marked, so the focus is on how smoothly and quickly the player can aim and fire.  Free Shoot: Exactly how it sounds. Players select a distance and load out and shoot at a target without any game structure.  Graphics      The game has a sparse graphical style familiar to most Xbox Indie games. It has a simple open field and a standard scoring target set at various distances. There are moments when the camera will follow your bullet and rotate around it as it enters the target. This shows a self shadowing reflective bullet  spinning into the target.      Trivia  Conceptualized, developed and programmed by one man. 33000+ downloads in the first week 6000 sales in the first week The altitude setting, AI AWSM rifle and 2500m distance were added to replicate the recent world record sniper shot. The ACOG scope for the M16 is the only non cross-hair scope reticle in the game.  The ACOG is calibrated for the M193 catridge, although the real ones are typically calibrated for the M855. The cross hatches for 400m and beyond are matched to the width of a man's shoulders at the corresponding distance  Further reading Here is a blog by Andy Campbell outlining his experience making and submitting the game:  http://blog.andyc.org/2011/03/18/post-mortem-for-marksman-long-range/</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/30849/1826602-marksmanlongrange.jpg</image></root>