<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35816</id><name>Naruto Shippuden: Ultimate Ninja Storm Generations</name><description>OverviewNaruto: Ultimate Ninja Storm for the Playstation and Xbox 360 is CyberConnect2's latest instalment in its Ultimate Ninja series, based on the highly acclaimed manga and anime series Naruto. It will feature the most characters in any fighting game and the first Storm game to feature fan favourites Zabuza and Haku.The story mode covers both Part I and Part II from the series featuring both the older and younger versions, mainly focusing on Naruto's adventure based on the series but will also feature new sidestories lead by other characters including Sasuke  Itachi Uchiha and Minato Namikaze.DevelopmentNaruto Shippūden: Ultimate Ninja Storm Generations was first announced by Namco Bandai Games in late June from 2011 in the manga magazine Weekly Shōnen Jump. In addition to tweaks and battle mechanics it will have characters from Part I, with the addition of these characters, the staff comments the game will have a wider variety of battles than the previous game, Producer Yusuke Sasaki stated the staff wanted to give combat a greater focus than its prequels. The term "Generations" stands for "the ultimate ninja battle that crosses generations". The game is meant to satisfy the gamers' wishes and interests regarding the series according to Hiroshi Matsuyama, the president of CyberConnect2.Matsuyama commented the story mode is different from Naruto Shippūden: Ultimate Ninja Storm 2, with Part II meant to have a different impact in the gamers. 60 minutes of original animation has been created by Studio Pierrot, making exclusive storylines just for the game. The demo was officially released January 24, 2012 on the Japanese PlayStation Store. It contains 3 battles which include Sasuke, Masked Madara and Pain.In November 2011, Namco Bandai announced the game would be released in Japan on February 23, 2012, America March 13, 2012 and Europe in March 30, 2012.RosterAnko MitarashiAsuma SarutobiChiyoChiyo with PuppetsChoji AkimichiDeidaraDaruiDanzo ShimuraFirst HokageGaaraHakuHidanHidan (Jashin Ritual Form)Hinata HyugaByakugan HinataIno YamanakaItachi UchihaJiraiyaJiraiya (Sage Mode)JiroboJugoKabuto YakushiKakashi HatakeYoung KakashiKakuzuKakuzu (Four Hearts)KarinKankuroKiba InuzukaKidomaruKiller BeeEight-Tailed Killer BeeKimimaroKimimaro (Second State Curse Mode)Kisame HoshigakiKonohamaruKurenai YuhiMei TerumiMight GuyMinato Namikaze (The Fourth Hokage)Neji HyugaNaruto UzumakiNaruto Uzumaki (Nine-Tails Cloak)Four-Tailed Naruto UzumakiSix-Tailed Naruto UzumakiNine-Tails Chakra Mode Naruto UzumakiSage Mode NarutoObito UchihaOnokiOrochimaruPainRock LeeSaiSakonSakura HarunoSasori (w/Third Kazekage)Self-puppet SasoriSasuke UchihaSasuke Uchiha (Second State Curse Mode)Sasuke (Taka)Second HokageShino AburameShizuneShikamaru NaraSuigetsu HozukiTayuyaThird HokageTemariTentenTobiTsunadeYamatoZabuza MomochiPlayable StagesKonohagakure (Normal, Destroyed, Ruined, Part 1)Training Field (Day, Night)Grassy Waves PrairieForest of DeathForest of Quiet Movement (Day, Evening, Night)Konohagakure Forest (Day, Evening)Kage Summit HallGreat Naruto BridgeOrochimaru's Hideout (Normal, Destroyed)Akatsuki HideoutThe Uchiha Hideout (Normal, Destroyed)Forest of Dead TreesAmegakure (Upper, Lower)Chūnin Exams StadiumChūnin Exams Preliminary ArenaTop of the Lookout TowerValley of the End (Sunny, Rainy)Samurai Bridge (Upper, River)Land of IronValley of Clouds and LightningMountains' GraveyardSite of Planetary DevastationFive-Seal Barrier CliffSunagakure GateSunagakureTanzaku TownMount MyōbokuSpecial EditionsThe Original European Card EditionIn Japan, pre-ordering the game would get them a CD soundtrack with tracks from Ultimate Ninja Storm and Ultimate Ninja Storm 2 called "Ultimate Ninja Storm Best Sound" composed by Chikayo Fukuda.In Europe, Namco Bandai were going to release a "Card Edition" of the game. That would include a starter pack of 51 trading cards, a booster pack of 8 trading cards, a folded box and a giant poster signed by Matsuyama. Instead they released a version which featured more cards and a different box.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="35163">Dragon Ball Z: Ultimate Tenkaichi</game><game id="34360">Bleach Soul Resurrección</game><game id="38786">Naruto Shippuden: Ultimate Ninja Storm 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2215082-box_narutounsg.png</image></root>