<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35891</id><name>Fortune Summoners: Secret of the Elemental Stone</name><description>OverviewArche Plumfield just moved into town with her parents after years of being away. Her parents open an item shop and Arche has her first day of school, where she learns she needs an elemental stone to participate in magic class.GameplayMovementGetting around the world is done simply enough, you can run from left to right. You can jump over obstacles and push boxes by running into them. There is a button for switching characters if you have someone other then Arche in your party, and their abilities and style of movement will differ somewhat from Arche.Other options, whether your party members should stay, follow you, camera controls, and various tweaks such as that are done threw the F-Keys or can be mapped to buttons on your controller.CombatCombat is done in real-time in an action oriented fashion. As Arche (a melee character) you can swing your sword and use it to block, and most of her special attacks are done using a combo system.If you switch to a magic using character, the button normally used to draw Arche's sword is instead used to switch between spells. Small level spells can sometimes be done using a combo such as "down+attack" or for larger, selectable spells, you hold down the attack button, wait for it to charge, and it let it go when it's ready.PC System RequirementsMinimum:OS:Windows XP/Vista/7Processor:Pentium III 1.0GHzMemory:384 MB RAMGraphics:DirectX 8 or higher compatible video cardDirectX®:dx80Hard Drive:250 MB HD spaceSound:DirectX 8-compatible sound deviceRecommended:OS:Windows 7Processor:Pentium IV 2.4GHzMemory:512 MB RAMGraphics:DirectX 8 or higher compatible video cardDirectX®:dx90Hard Drive:250 MB HD spaceSound:DirectX 8-compatible sound device</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16241">Zelda II: The Adventure of Link</game><game id="4208">Ys III: Wanderers from Ys</game><game id="14787">Popful Mail</game><game id="3003">Monster World IV</game><game id="28142">Chantelise</game><game id="20627">Castlevania: Order of Ecclesia</game><game id="11602">Valkyrie Profile</game><game id="32155">Recettear: An Item Shop's Tale</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/429/2078518-fs_deluxe_box.jpg</image></root>