<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35892</id><name>RailWorks 3: Train Simulator 2012</name><description>HistoryThe history of the RailWorks series and technology can be traced back to 2001 when Kuju developed Microsoft Train Simulator, an ambitious but profoundly boring train simulation game with an active modding community to this day. Eventually, they developed the successor called Rail Simulator. The graphics were not a vast improvement over MSTS, but the physics improvements were a major focus. By utilizing the PhysX middleware, Rail Simulator offered much more advanced physics simulations such as individual wheels slipping on the rails. The game came with a world editor to build your own routes.RailWorksAfter some corporate shuffling and an uncertain future, a subsidiary of Kuju was created and named RailSimulator.com. Due to the difficulty in offering a consistent and updated experience across players with retail games, as well as acquiring the maximum amount of money by charging for said updates, it was decided that Rail Simulator would turn into a Steam exclusive title and thus RailWorks was born. The Steam platform allowed the developers to issue timely updates to every player and to utilize the DLC system to nickel-and-dime their users for additional content such as routes, locomotives, and scenery assets. This system also allowed third party expansion makers to develop and release DLCs to a single centralized store and for users to know that the content is officially supported by RailSimulator.com.In 2010, a significant free update to RailWorks was released and the name of the game was curiously changed to RailWorks 2. It contained a new driving interface that was easier to use, Steam Achievements, and a "Career System" that is basically leaderboards of the game.Similar to RailWorks 2, Railworks 3: Train Simulator 2012 (originally renamed just Train Simulator 2012) is a free update for all existing RailWorks owners. New purchasers currently get upgraded to the "Deluxe Edition" that contains the Horseshoe Curve Expansion, which is designed as a showcase of the enhancements made to the RailWorks engine.FeaturesVarious real-life and fictional routes in Europe and North AmericaOver 70 scenarios, which contain specific goals based on a schedule similar to real world situationsSteam, diesel, and electric locomotivesOther train cars such as passenger cabs or shipping carsWorld Editor to create or modify routes and scenariosLots of paid and free additional contentSteam achievements and leaderboardsNew Features In Train Simulator 2012Visual StyleNew, clean user interfaceNew action-oriented loading screensRealistic presentation of driving environmentsExtended Terrain Draw DistanceNew terrain shadowingParticle effects on train windowsWorking wipersImproved clouds  skyGraphical ImprovementsMultiple Source Dynamic LightingDepth of fieldSoft shadowsWeather effects on windowsGameplay and RealismMultiple headed consists to allow consists to be powered by different types of tractionSuperelevation to allow accurate simulation of curved tracksImproved track unevenness and cab camera movementSmoothing of vertical curves on tracks.ToolsImproved browser list and functionalityNew stopping point feature to simplify scenario creationNew way of simplifying display of editor featuresNew way of authoring Marshalling of AI trains – particularly useful in yardsContentNew route – Horseshoe Curve* (included with new buyers of the Steam version)New concept train (IEP)New Warbonnet F7 locomotiveImproved sounds for North American contentRefreshed Class 166Refreshed Class SD40Hundreds of dollars of DLC available for purchase in the Steam store, including the popular Halloween themed "Trains vs. Zombies" level packThe new graphics engine can be toggled on or off in order to provide compatibility for existing content or users with older hardware.The developer is working on adding online multiplayer support in the future.System RequirementsOS: Windows XP / Vista/ Windows 7Processor: 2.8 GHz or faster* (relative to Pentium 4, modern CPUs are faster than this at less GHz)Memory: 2.0 GB RAMGraphics: Video 256 MB with Pixel Shader 3.0* (with the new graphics engine disabled, Shader 2.0 cards are capable of running the game)Hard Drive: At least 6 GB of free space + more for DLCsSound: Direct X 9.0c compatible</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="34721">Trainz Simulator 12</game><game id="32000">BVE</game><game id="10399">Boso View Express</game><game id="34348">Train Simulator Real: The Yamanote Line</game><game id="34371">Train Simulator: JR East Yamanote Line</game><game id="27981">Forklift Truck Simulator 2009</game><game id="37986">European Bus Simulator</game><game id="23560">Railfan</game><game id="27397">Railfan: Taiwan High Speed Rail</game><game id="44011">Train Simulator 2014</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4344/1908760-train_sim_2012_railworks3.jpg</image></root>