<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35901</id><name>Aliens: Infestation</name><description>OverviewThis game was revealed as Aliens: Colonial Marines DS when a video was released on YouTube which was taken down again after a short period of time. It depicted a side scrolling shooter in the vein of Alien 3 on the Sega Genesis. The game was believed to be canceled or caught in development hell since SEGA canceled Obsidian Entertainment's Aliens RPG and there were also no news on the Gearbox developed console version of Aliens: Colonial Marines.On July 20th, 2011, SEGA announced the game would finally be released under the name Aliens: Infestation. Development on the game had actually been completed for a long time before the announcement.GameplayIn this Metroidvania-style game, players have the ability to recruit and play as 19 unique Marines, each of whom can die permanently, resulting in a game over if all of them happen to die. The game also features upgrade systems and collectibles. Aliens: Infestation features character designs by comic artist Chris Bachalo.StoryThe plot of Aliens: Infestation takes place six weeks after the events of the movie Aliens 3 begins when the Marines stumble upon the remains of the USS Sulaco. Seemingly abandoned, the ship has been torn up in some kind of apparent attack. As the Marines delve deeper into the ship, they uncover the vicious Xenomorphs that have taken roost inside. Now, it's a desperate battle for them, not just to make it out alive, but to uncover what really happened on the Sulaco. A horde of Xenomorphs and armies of hostile soldiers, combat robots, and mercenaries stand between the Marines and the truth. In this sequel to the film Aliens, players must fight through the Sulaco, planet LV-426, and other infamous worlds to uncover the truth of what happened to the Sulaco, and why it might be in some people's best interest to ensure that information never sees the light of day.</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8292">Super Metroid</game><game id="10323">Metroid Fusion</game><game id="5708">Metroid II: Return of Samus</game><game id="17356">Metroid: Zero Mission</game><game id="26706">Shadow Complex</game><game id="14356">Alien³</game><game id="4350">Contra</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/82063/2549365-aliensinfestationclean.jpg</image></root>