<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35926</id><name>Project Dream</name><description>StoryThere are very few screenshots of the game online, making details very scarce. The game was centered around a young boy named Edison, who used a big wooden sword. Edison had long-standing trouble with pirates, led by Captain Blackeye, who are the main antagonists in the game. The pirates wanted to capture Edison, though their motives are unknown. It is assumed that the story follows Edison as he deals with the pirates.CharactersThere were quite a few main characters in Project Dream who eventually made it to the Nintendo 64 game Banjo-Kazooie, excluding Edison. Banjo was originally intended to be an ally to Edison in Project Dream, but was later given the role of main character once Rare found Edison to be too generic. Captain Blackeye was another character who did not make the transition into Banjo-Kazooie, but later made a cameo appearance in Banjo-Tooie.Gruntilda was also supposed to be in Project Dream, though not until development was moved to the Nintendo 64. In that version of the game, she was intended to be a giant, though it isn't known if she was an antagonist or protagonist. Though, once Rare canceled Project Dream and started on Banjo-Kazooie, she was made a witch and the game's main antagonist. Tooty was also a character in the game, though in Project Dream she was cast as Banjo's girlfriend, not sister as she is in Banjo-Kazooie. Tiptup was also set to appear in Project Dream, and also appeared in Banjo-Kazooie. Making the biggest leap between games was Kazooie. In Project Dream, she was only supposed to make a brief appearance after Edison's sister finds Kazooie's egg and watches her hatch. But after the project was canceled, she was made a main character in Banjo-Kazooie.Other characters in the game but did not make it into Banjo-Kazooie include Edison's girlfriend, Bully, Big Belly, Cockeye, an unnamed rabbit and an unspecified dog character.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/12/128387/1842106-project_dream.png</image></root>