<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>35938</id><name>Ultimate Marvel vs. Capcom 3</name><description>OverviewNew challengers Strider and Ghost Rider do battle in the updated Bonne WonderlandUltimate Marvel vs. Capcom 3, the standalone update to Marvel vs. Capcom 3: Fate of Two Worlds was first revealed on July 20, 2011 and features:12 brand new fighters bringing the total roster up to 508 brand new stages from the Marvel and Capcom UniversesBrand new modes and a more comprehensive online experience including a Spectator ModeRebalanced gameplayA cosmetic redesign including a brand new HUDNew CharactersCapcomFirebrandFirebrandBackground - A some times enemy of Arthur, Firebrand is a fire-breathing demon/gargoyle on a quest to defend the village he calls home.Fighting Style - His ability to cancel in and out of flight almost at will allows Firebrand to dominate the air, approaching his enemies with attacks from odd angles that are very difficult to defend against.First Appearance: Ghosts n' GoblinsAttire Description: RevampedNormal Moves: Devil's ClawSpecial Moves: Bon Voyage, Demon Missile*, Hell Dive, Hell Spitfire*, Hell's Elevator, HoverHyper Combos: Chaos Tide**, Dark Fire*, Luminous BodyAssists: α - Hell Spitfire; β - Demon Missile; γ - Demon MissileAlternate ColorsColor #2: Blue  yellow (Capcom logo)Color #3: Yellow  silver (primary colors)Color #4: DemonicColor #5: Stone statueColor #6: Green GoblinFrank WestFrank WestBackground - Always willing to go the extra mile for a story, Frank "I've covered wars" West is a freelance photographer who became an unlikely hero after investigating a zombie outbreak in Willamette, Colorado.Fighting Style - Bringing the flavor of Dead Rising and Dead Rising 2 into the world of Marvel vs. Capcom, Frank West wields a variety of mundane and combo weapons as he levels himself up through a unique photography mechanic. While his zombie summoning abilities grant him some flexibility at longer ranges, his main goal should be to reach level 4 in order to unlock the dominating paddle saw.First Appearance: Dead RisingAttire Description: Dead RisingNormal Moves: Knee Drop, Object ThrowSpecial Moves: Barrel Roll, Bottoms Up, Giant Swing, Hammer Throw, Object Throw, Roundhouse Kick, Snapshot, Tools of SurvivalHyper Combos: Blue Light Special, Funny Face Crusher, Survival TechniquesAssists: α - Shopping Cart; β - Tools of Survival; γ - Pick Me UpAlternate ColorsColor #2: Red WineColor #3: Cuban gangster inspiredColor #4: Mobster inspiredColor #5: Chuck Greene (Dead Rising 2)Color #6: Spotted coatNemesis T-TypeNemesisBackground - Nemesis is a bio-weapon developed by the Umbrella Corporation with keen intellect and massive strength. Nigh indestructible, It is unrelenting in its mission to terminate the surviving members of S.T.A.R.S. including Chris Redfield and Jill Valentine.Fighting Style - Nemesis is a lumbering fighter with slow, deliberate movements. While it prefers to fight at close range, it's variety of tentacle attacks and trusty bazooka give it the flexibility to fight at mid and full-screen.First Appearance: Resident Evil 3: NemesisAttire Description: Resident Evil 3: NemesisNormal Moves: Deadly ReachSpecial Moves: Clothesline Rocket, Launcher Slam, Rocket Launcher, Tentacle SlamHyper Combos: Biohazard Rush, Bioweapon Assault, Fatal Mutation**Assists: α - Clothesline Rocket; β - Launcher Slam; γ - Rocket LauncherAlternate ColorsColor #2: Dried blood redColor #3: Zombie greenColor #4: Corpse blueColor #5: Dainty pinkColor #6: "Nurse Nemesis"Phoenix WrightPhoenix WrightBackground - With the help of his assistant Maya Fey and her mystical Magatama, Phoenix Wright has defended the innocent time and time again in the court of law. He is always ready to point his finger and shout "Objection!" when presented with anything but the truth.Fighting Style - Although he's not much of a fighter, Phoenix Wright can manage to do a decent amount of accidental damage as he files paperwork and searches for clues, relying on allies like Maya Fey and Missile to help buy time distracting the enemy. As a unique three-stance character, his goal is to gather enough evidence while in Investigation Mode to strike the enemy with an Objection! while in Courtroom Mode in order to enter his powered-up Turnabout Mode.First Appearance: Phoenix Wright: Ace AttorneyAttire Description: Ace AttorneyNormal Moves: Bridge to the Turnabout, Cross-Examination, Illuminating Point, "Just a Little More...!", Note Scribbling, Pursuit, Slip-up, QuestioningSpecial Moves: Break the Witness, Discard, Investigate, "M-Maya!?", Mode Change, Paperwork, Paperwork Storm, Present Evidence, Press the WitnessHyper Combos: Ace Attorney**, "Order in the Court!", Steel Samurai Maya Smelting!Assists: α - Paperwork (High); β - Press the Witness; γ - "Get 'em, Missile!"Alternate ColorsColor #2: Miles Edgeworth (Ace Attorney); Mia Fey (Phoenix Wright: Ace Attorney); Canine Warrior Take (Okami)Color #3: Dick Gumshoe (Ace Attorney); Franziska Von Karma (Phoenix Wright Ace Attorney - Justice For All); Canine Warrior Hayabusa (Okami)Color #4: Larry Butz (Phoenix Wright: Ace Attorney); Maggey Byrde (Phoenix Wright Ace Attorney - Trials and Tribulations); Canine Warrior Ume (Okami)Color #5: Godot (Phoenix Wright Ace Attorney - Trials and Tribulations); Kay Faraday (Ace Attorney Investigations: Miles Edgeworth); Karmic Transformation 8 (Okami)Color #6: Sissel (Ghost Trick: Phantom Detective); Lynne (Ghost Trick: Phantom Detective); Amaterasu (Okami)Strider HiryuStriderBackground - A top-ranking member of the secret Striders organization, Strider expertly wields his plasma-generating blade Cypher as he does his duties as a spy and assassin.Fighting Style - A character with many options, Strider's effective keepaway tactics using his wide variety of robotic projectiles are only outshone by his amazing melee pressure skills, getting in close with a variety of teleports and keeping the opponent on guard with his Ouruboros Hyper Combo.First Appearance: StriderAttire Description: Marvel vs. Capcom 2: New Age of HeroesNormal Moves: Arch Cut, SlideSpecial Moves: Ame-No-Murakumo*, Climb, Cypher Attack, Descend, Dismount, Excalibur*, Formation A1, Formation A2, Formation B, Formation C, Gram, Jump Kick, Ladder Kick, Vajira*, Wall Cling, Wall ExchangeHyper Combos: Legion*, Ouruboros**, Ragnarok**Assists: α - Ame-No-Murakumo; β - Gram; γ - VajiraAlternate ColorsColor #2: Ninja blackColor #3: Kenji (Red Earth)Color #4: Strider Hien (Strider 2)Color #5: Ibuki (Street Fighter III: New Generation)Color #6: Guy (Final Fight)VergilVergilBackground - Dante's more mature twin brother, Vergil's quest for power led to him being enslaved by the demon Mundus. Transformed into the armored warrior Nelo Angelo, he was ultimately defeated by his brother. His current whereabouts are unknown.Fighting Style - Combined with a sword that reaches halfway across the screen, Vergil has an arsenal of tools to deal with almost any situation. He's at his most dangerous when he combines his summoned swords with various teleports to open his opponent up for a lengthy combo.First Appearance: Devil May CryAttire Description: Devil May Cry 3: Dante's AwakeningNormal Moves: Helmet Breaker, High Time, Stinger, Upper SlashSpecial Moves: Judgement Cut, Lunar Phase, Rapid Slash, Rising Sun, Round-Trip, Trick, Trick Down, Trick UpHyper Combos: Blistering Swords, Dark Angel**, Devil Trigger, Dimension Slash, Spiral Swords, Summoned Swords, Sword StormAssists: α - Judgement Cut; β - Rising Sun; γ - Rapid SlashAlternate ColorsColor #2: Villainous blackColor #3: Nero (Devil May Cry 4)Color #4: Vergil vs. Vergil (Devil May Cry 3: Special Edition)Color #5: Blood stained white coatColor #6: Demitri Maximoff (Darkstalkers)MarvelDoctor StrangeDoctor StrangeBackground - Doctor Strange was a successful doctor before nerve damage forced him to quit his practice in search for a mystical cure. He served as Earth's Sorcerer Supreme for many years, but recently lost the title and is currently lending his unique abilities to the New Avengers.Fighting Style - Preferring to face his foes from afar, Doctor Strange's strength lies in his ability to fill the screen with a wide variety of projectiles. While he lacks the mobility of an air-dash, his ability to instantly teleport can help him navigate the playing field in a pinch.First Appearance: Strange Tales #110Attire Description: Classic blue  redNormal Moves: Illusion, Impact PalmSpecial Moves: Bolts of Balthakk, Daggers of Denak, Eye of Agamotto, Flames of the Faltine, Flight, Grace of Hoggoth, Mystic Sword, TeleportHyper Combos: Astral Magic**, Seven Rings of Raggador, Spell of VishantiAssists: α - Daggers of Denak; β - Eye of Agamotto; γ - Bolts of BalthakkAlternate ColorsColor #2: Classic blueColor #3: Marvel Super Heroes: War of the GemsColor #4: The Official Handbook of the Marvel UniverseColor #5: Doctor Strange: The Sorcerer SupremeColor #6: Marvel 1602 (2004)Ghost RiderGhost RiderBackground - To save the life of a loved one, Johnny Blaze sold his soul to Mephisto. Now he is bound to the demon Zarithos, forced to take on the persona of the Ghost Rider whenever in the presence of evil.Fighting Style - Ghost Rider utilizes an interesting combination of long-range chain whip attacks in conjunction with grapple abilities, making him a dangerous threat whether at mid-screen or point blank.First Appearance: Marvel Spotlight #5Attire Description: Classic black leather  chainsNormal Moves: Heartless Spire, Rage WhipSpecial Moves: Chain of Punishment, Chain of Rebuttal*, Chaos Bringer, Conviction Slam, Hell's Embrace, Hellfire*, Judgement StrikeHyper Combos: Hellfire Maelstrom, Penance Stare**, Spirit of Vengeance*Assists: α - Chain of Rebuttal; β - Heartless Spire; γ - HellfireAlternate ColorsColor #2: Dan KetchColor #3: New Fantastic Four (Mini Marvels)Color #4: Robert Blackthorne (Ultimate universe)Color #5: Noble KaleColor #6: Phantom RiderHawkeyeHawkeyeBackground - The orphan Clint Barton spent his youth in the circus where he learned to become a master archer. Despite starting his costumed career as a reluctant villain, Hawkeye has since become a member of the Avengers and one of Earth's most reliable heroes.Fighting Style - While his agility makes him no slouch up close, Hawkeye excels at controlling the screen and opponent at long-range with his myriad arrow attacks. Not content with just doing damage, he is able to inflict a wide variety of status ailments on his foes using a plethora of tools including a gradually draining poison arrow and a weighted arrow that removes opponent's ability to super-jump.First Appearance: Tales of Suspense #57Attire Description: Classic blue  purpleNormal Moves: Double Roundhouse, Shock Value, SlideSpecial Moves: Quick Shot*, Ragtime Shot*, Trick ShotHyper Combos: Gimlet*, Kiss of Fire, Tag Team Special**Assists: α - Quick Shot (Greyhound); β - Trick Shot (Violet Fizz); γ - Ragtime Shot (Kamikaze)Alternate ColorsColor #2: Original blue, purple  yellowColor #3: Heroes RebornColor #4: Ultimate universeColor #5: The Avengers: Earth's Mightiest HeroesColor #6: Evil Hawkeye (Marvel Super Heroes in War of the Gems)Iron FistIron FistBackground - Daniel Rand is a formidable martial artist and the 66th person granted the mystical powers of the Iron Fist. Previously heroes for hire, Daniel and his friend Luke Cage have recently become members of the New Avengers after purchasing the Avengers Mansion from Tony Stark.Fighting Style - Iron Fist's offense revolves primarily around his various power-ups and chain specials. With low, overhead, OTG, crumple, pop-up, and wallbounce attacks that all cancel into one another, his ability to mix-up his opponents at melee range is unparalleled.First Appearance: Marvel Premiere #15Attire Description: Classic gold  greenNormal Moves: Dual Palm, Quick KickSpecial Moves: Chi, Crescent Heel, Dragon Tail, Dragon's Touch, Lotus Whip, Rising Fang, Surging Fist, Twin Snakes, Wall of K'un-LunHyper Combos: Dragon's Prey**, Iron Rage, Volcanic RoarAssists: α - Dragon's Touch; β - Crescent Heel; γ - Rising FangAlternate ColorsColor #2: Modern gold  whiteColor #3: Evil Iron Fist (Power Man and Iron Fist #119)Color #4: Classic Steel SerpentColor #5: 90's Steel Serpent (Iron Fist #2)Color #6: Power Fist (Exiles #21)NovaNovaBackground - Nova is the sole surviving member of the Nova Corps and wields the full power of the Nova Force. He now shoulders the burden of policing the entire universe in the absence of his comrades.Fighting Style - Not be the subtlest of characters, Nova has numerous attacks that launch him across the screen at his opponent and with his various OTG, ground-bounce and wall-bounce specials, he can convert to a full combo in almost any situation.First Appearance: The Man Called Nova #1Attire Description: Modern black  goldNormal Moves: Nova SlamSpecial Moves: Centurion Rush, Energy Javelin, Flight, Gravimetric Pulse, Nova StrikeHyper Combos: Gravimetric Blaster, Human Rocket, Super NovaAssists: α - Gravimetric Pulse; β - Centurion Rush; γ - Nova StrikeAlternate ColorsColor #2: The New Warriors #2Color #3: New Warriors uniformColor #4: Marvel Knights: 2001 Millennial VisionsColor #5: Quasar (War of Kings)Color #6: Nova 0:0Rocket RaccoonRocket RaccoonBackground - Accomplished star fighter pilot and master tactician, Rocket Raccoon is the standby leader for the Guardians of the Galaxy and has a special affinity for heavy weapons.Fighting Style - Whether he's keeping the opponent at bay with a variety of traps and guns, or he's running circles around his opponent with his rocket skates, Rocket Raccoon is a fighter that is completely capable at any range.First Appearance: The Incredible Hulk #271Attire Description: Modern blue  redNormal Moves: Wild RipperSpecial Moves: Angel Gift, Claymore, Grab Bag, Mr. Flapper, Oil Bomb, Pendulum, Rocket Skates, Spitfire, Tunnel RatHyper Combos: Mad Hopper, Rock 'n' Roll, Rocky Raccoon**Assists: α - Spitfire Twice; β - Claymore; γ - PendulumAlternate ColorsColor #2: Annihilation: Conquest - Starlord #2Color #3: AnnihilatorsColor #4: Annihilators #1Color #5: Original blue  red (The Incredible Hulk #271)Color #6: Annihilators: Earthfall #3* available in Simple Mode** Level 3 Hyper ComboReturning Capcom CharactersAkumaAkumaBackground - A practitioner of the assassination art Ansatsuken and master of the murderous energies of the Satsui no Hadou, Akuma is on a constant quest to find warriors worthy of killing and, eventually, one he hopes will be strong enough to take his life.Balance Changes:Health decreased to 750,000Hyakki Shuu can be performed in the airTatsumaki Senpukyaku hit-box size reducedTatsumaki Senpukyaku knock-back increasedMessatsu-Gohado can be mashed for additional damageTenma Gozanku can be mashed for additional damageRaging Demon can be mashed for additional damageTatsumaki Senpukyaku assist soft knockdown attribute removed*Alternate ColorsColor #1: Super Street Fighter II TurboColor #2: UnhealthyColor #3: Oni AkumaColor #4: BlondeColor #5: Flipped color scheme***Color #6: Street Fighter III: 3rd Strike***AmaterasuAmaterasuBackground - After losing her physical form in order to seal the monstrous Orochi, the Goddess of the Sun Amaterasu was reborn as a white wolf. With the aid of her celestial brush and three divine instruments, she continues on her eternal quest to vanquish evil.Balance Changes:Normal attack hit-stun decreasedCrouching M hit-box decreasedCrouching M active frames increasedGlaive Chop hard knockdown attribute addedThunder Edge active frames increasedCold Star assist hit-stun decreasedWeapon Change can be performed in the airDivine Instruments can be mashed for additional damageAlternate ColorsColor #1: OkamiColor #2: Canine Warrior Take (Okami)Color #3: Canine Warrior Hayabusa (Okami)Color #4: Canine Warrior Ume (Okami)Color #5: Karmic Transformation 8 (Okami)***Color #6: Shiba inu***ArthurArthurBackground - A noble knight and expert wielder of many weapons, Sir Arthur has vanquished every ghoul, ghost, and goblin that has stood between him and his beloved Princess Prin Prin.Balance Changes:Health increased to 850,000Jumping S downward momentum increasedJumping S hits OTGHeavenly Slash invincibility frames addedHellbound Slash first hit hit-stun increasedGoddess' Bracelet can be mashed for additional damageAlternate ColorsColor #1: RevampedColor #2: Ultimate Ghosts N' GoblinsColor #3: Golden Armor (Super Ghouls N' Ghosts)Color #4: Bronze Armor (Super Ghouls N' Ghosts)Color #5: Old Arthur***Color #6: Lover Arthur***Chris RedfieldChris RedfieldBackground - Originally a member of the S.T.A.R.S. Alpha team, Chris has since gone on to found the B.S.A.A. and is constantly going toe-to-toe with the Umbrella Corporation and their biological experiments.Balance Changes:Dash can be canceled immediatelyCrouching H float increasedJumping S start-up frames reduced and active frames increasedCommand-normal gun attacks can be special-canceledSpecial attacks minimum damage scaling increasedCombination Punch H first hit hit-stun decreasedProne Position can be canceled into Prone Shot earlierShot Gun active frames increasedShot Gun damage decreasedSweep Combo Machinegun hits OTGAlternate ColorsColor #1: Resident Evil 5Color #2: Blue (Jill Valentine  Leon S. Kennedy)Color #3: Cody Travers (Final Fight)Color #4: Safari (Resident Evil 5 alternate)Color #5: Dark***Color #6: Chuck Greene (Dead Rising 2)***Chun-LiChun-LiBackground - While she has pitted her kung-fu mastery against a large variety of criminal organizations as a member of interpol, Chun-Li's true goal is to investigate her father's death at the hands of the mysterious Shadaloo syndicate.Balance Changes:New EX Spinning Bird Kick specialStanding M and crouching M can be jump-canceledYosokyaku hits OTGHyakuretsukyaku hit-box increasedKikoanken input window increasedTenshokyaku L arc decreasedTenshokyaku start-up reducedTenshokyaku last hit hit-stun increasedTenshokyaku recovers immediately when performed in the airKikosho can be mashed for additional damageAlternate ColorsColor #1: Street Fighter II: The World WarriorColor #2: Street Fighter II: The World Warrior alternateColor #3: Street Fighter IV alternateColor #4: Street Fighter III alternateColor #5: Super Puzzle Fighter II Turbo alternate***Color #6: Shadow Lady (Marvel vs. Capcom: Clash of Super Heroes)***C.ViperC.ViperBackground - Although she is an agent of the CIA, the advanced battle suit Crimson Viper (AKA Maya) wears was acquired during her time working as a double agent, infiltrating the S.I.N. Corporation.Balance Changes:New Optic Laser specialThunder Knuckle L and M feint timing window increasedThunder Knuckle M forward momentum decreasedThunder Knuckle H is now subject to hit-stun scalingAlternate ColorsColor #1: Street Fighter IVColor #2: Mismatched pants and jacketColor #3: Loud yellow suitColor #4: Pop-starColor #5: Villainous purple***Color #6: Claire Redfield (Resident Evil 2)***DanteDanteBackground - A hybrid child born from the demon knight Sparda and a human woman named Eva, Dante was inspired to become a devil hunter in order to seek retribution for his mother's murder.Balance Changes:Knock-back of all attacks increasedHit-stun and float of all attacks adjustedNormal and special attack minimum damage scaling decreasedStanding L and standing M hit-box decreasedClay Pigeon float decreasedBold Move cancel window decreasedSpecial moves that were executed by performing the same command twice can now be done with one directional input followed by 2 repeated button inputs (e.g. Grapple previously QCF+H, QCF+H is now performed QCF+H,H)The Hammer start-up invincibility frames increased and overall invincibility frames reducedVolcano - Beehive damage decreasedBeehive knock-back increasedAbility to triple-jump or air-dash twice during Devil Trigger addedMillion Dollars can be mashed for additional damageAlternate ColorsColor #1: Devil May Cry 3: Dante's AwakeningColor #2: BlackColor #3: WhiteColor #4: CamouflageColor #5: Orange***Color #6: Vergil (Devil May Cry 3: Dante's Awakening)***FeliciaFeliciaBackground - A cat-woman raised by nuns, Felicia currently works in an orphanage where she dreams of becoming a music star.Balance Changes:Toy Touch is now subject to hit-stun scalingDelta Kick can be performed in the airDelta Kick final hit ground-bounce attribute added when performed air-to-air in a comboRolling Buckler no longer tracks opponentSand Splash total frames decreasedSand Splash hits OTGKitty Helper total frames decreasedDancing Flash can be mashed for additional damagePlease Help Me can be mashed for additional damageAlternate ColorsColor #1: Darkstalkers: The Night WarriorsColor #2: Super Puzzle Fighter II Turbo alternateColor #3: Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors alternateColor #4: Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors modified alternateColor #5: Ode to Marvel redheads***Color #6: Darkstalkers 3 alternate***HaggarHaggarBackground - As a former wrestler, Mike "The Fighting Mayor" Haggar has no problems taking the law into his own hands when protecting Metro City from the Mad Gear gang, especially when his daughter Jessica is one of the people in peril.Balance Changes:Crouching H soft knockdown attribute replaced by hard knockdown attributeCrouching H hits OTGCrouching H can not be canceledAir-throw downward momentum increasedLariat assist start-up invincibility frames decreasedLariat assist hard knockdown attribute replaced by soft knockdown attributeRapid Fire Fist start-up invincibility frames addedRapid Fire Fist can be mashed for additional damageFinal Haggar Buster can have the joystick spun for additional damageAlternate ColorsColor #1: Final FightColor #2: Camoflaged fatiguesColor #3: Formal wearColor #4: Stately retired generalColor #5: Rejuvenated and youthful***Color #6: Kraven the Hunter***Hsien-KoHsien-KoBackground - Using forbidden magic, twin sisters transformed themselves into Jiang-Shi in order to obtain the power necessary to save their mother's soul. Mei-Ling now resides as a charm on Hsien-Ko's forehead, helping her sister maintain control of her powers.Balance Changes:Crouching M start-up and active frames decreasedJump attacks float decreasedCommand-normals can be jump-canceledEdoga hit-stun increasedRantetsu can be canceled into EdogaAnki-Hou special has more varieties of projectiles (including oil drum, hunk of meat, felyne doll, Chris Redfield's stun rod, snowman)Tenrai Ha can be mashed for additional damageAlternate ColorsColor #1: Night Warriors: Darkstalkers' RevengeColor #2: Darkstalkers 3 alternateColor #3: Night Warriors: Darkstalkers' Revenge alternateColor #4: Mr. Vampire color schemeColor #5: Darkstalkers 3 alternate***Color #6: Red jewel tone***Jill ValentineJill ValentineBackground - After her apparent death at the hands of Albert Wesker, Jill later resurfaced as one of Wesker's puppet soldiers in Africa. Her old partner Chris managed to free her from the control device embedded in her chest, and she has resumed her duties as a member of the B.S.A.A.Balance Changes:All attacks float increasedCrouching M forward momentum decreasedJumping attacks hit-box decreasedAlternate ColorsColor #1: Resident Evil 5Color #2: Saki Kanebou (Quiz Nanairo Dreams)Color #3: Intera Fusion suit (P.N.03)Color #4: Military freenColor #5: Pink***Color #6: Vanessa Z. Schneider (P.N.03)***MorriganMorriganBackground - Although she is head of the Aensland house in the demon world, the succubus Morrigan's action-seeking tendencies cause her to ignore her duties more often than not. Rather than prey on men and absorb their sexual energy, she is able to sustain herself through the thrill of combat.Balance Changes:New Soul Drain specialThrow hit-stun increasedFlight total frames decreasedSoul Fist damage increasedSoul Fist hit-stun increased but now is subject to hit-stun scalingFinishing Shower can be mashed for additional damageFinishing Shower missiles trajectory can be altered to a greater degree*Alternate ColorsColor #1: Darkstalkers: The Night WarriorsColor #2: Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors alternateColor #3: RoseColor #4: PinkColor #5: Lilith (Darkstalkers 3)***Color #6: Darkstalkers 3 alternate***RyuRyuBackground - A warrior in the truest sense, Ryu's entire existence is devoted to testing his mettle against the strongest fighters in the world. Though he once was at a risk of being consumed by a murderous intent, Ryu has since mastered his inner demons.Balance Changes:Dash can be canceled immediatelyNormal attack minimum damage scaling increasedCollarbone Breaker can be special canceledNew Baku Hadoken specialNew Hado Shoryuken specialNew Ren Hadoken specialNew Hado Kakusei hyper comboNew Shin HadokenNew Shin Tatsumaki SenpukyakuShinku and Shin Hadoken can be mashed for additional damageShinku and Shin Tatsumaki Senpukyaku can be mashed for additional damageAlternate ColorsColor #1: Street Fighter II: The World WarriorColor #2: Street Fighter IV alternateColor #3: X-Men vs. Street Fighter alternateColor #4: Street Fighter IV alternateColor #5: Ken Masters (Street Fighter II: The World Warrior)***Color #6: Evil Ryu (Super Street Fighter IV: Arcade Edition)***SpencerSpencerBackground - Despite his heroic efforts defending his country from the Empire, Nathan "Rad" Spencer's bionic arm caused him to be branded as a traitor and imprisoned following the Bionic Purge. Now that the United States are under attack once again, the Bionic Commando has been released to do his patriotic duty.Balance Changes:New Bionic Bomber specialArmor Piercer start-up frames decreasedZip Kick float height increasedZip Line speed increasedAlternate ColorsColor #1: Bionic Commando (2009)Color #2: Contrasting redColor #3: Flipped colorsColor #4: BioReign terrorists (Bionic Commando)Color #5: Blinged out***Color #6: P.N.03 ***TrishTrishBackground - The demon Mundus created Trish in the image of Dante's mother in order to trap the devil hunter. What he did not anticipate was how their shared humanity would lead to his eventual betrayal. Now Trish and Dante work together out of their demon hunting storefront, Devil May Cry.Balance Changes:Standing M can be canceled into crouching MAir Raid total frames decreasedTrip "Hopscotch," Trick "Peekaboo," or Round Harvest can only be performed one in a jumpMaximum Voltage hits OTG when performed in the airMaximum Voltage can be mashed for additional damageAlternate ColorsColor #1: Devil May CryColor #2: Dante (Devil May Cry)Color #3: Rainbow Mika (Street Fighter Alpha 3)Color #4: Vergil (Devil May Cry 3: Dante's Awakening)***Color #5: Orange***Color #6: Pink***Tron BonneTron BonneBackground - A prideful air-pirate with a secret crush on Mega Man, Tron Bonne's thirst for booty often leads her on misadventures that leave her poorer than when she started.Balance Changes:Jumping H knock-back increasedThrow hit-stun increasedCommand-normals can be special-canceledBandit Boulder first two hits are now subject to hit-stun scalingGustaff Fire assist invincibility removedSpecial attacks minimum damage scaling increasedBonne Strike float decreased when performed on the groundBonne Strike now subject to hit-stun scaling when performed in the airServbot Launcher special can fire three Servbots in a rowAttacks can be canceled into Bonne Mixer and Shakedown Mixer when whiffedServbot Surprise can be mashed for additional damageShakedown Mixer can have the joystick rotated for additional damageAlternate ColorsColor #1: Mega Man LegendsColor #2: Roll Caskett (Mega Man Legends)Color #3: Marvel vs. Capcom 2: New Age of Heroes alternateColor #4: Teisel Bonne (Mega Man Legends)***Color #5: Bon Bonne (Mega Man Legends)***Color #6: Marvel vs. Capcom 2: New Age of Heroes alternate***Viewtiful JoeViewtiful JoeBackground - After being sucked into Movieland when his girlfriend Silvia was kidnapped, Joe was transformed into a superhero and has since been tasked with defending the world beyond the silver screen from all manner of threats.Balance Changes:New V-Dodge specialJumping S hurt-box decreasedGround throws range increasedShocking Pink total frames decreasedShocking Pink will not explode when sliding in between buttons and cannot be juggledDesperado hits OTG when performed in the airMach Speed can be mashed for additional damageAlternate ColorsColor #1: Viewtiful JoeColor #2: Captain Blue (Viewtiful Joe)Color #3: Jet Black Final Form (Viewtiful Joe 2)Color #4: Black Emperor (Viewtiful Joe 2)Color #5: Blade Master Alastor (Viewtiful Joe)***Color #6: Sexy Silvia (Viewtiful Joe)***WeskerWeskerBackground - An Umbrella bioterrorist whose abilities were greatly enhanced by an unknown virus, Albert Wesker's most recent plan involved an attempt to infect the world with his newly developed Uroboros virus. While he was apparently killed by Chris Redfield and Sheva Alomar, he may yet return in order to achieve complete global saturation.Balance Changes:Health decreased to 1,000,000New sunglasses mechanic (As Wesker takes damage his sunglasses become cracked, granting him 110% damage and 105% speed, and eventually broken, granting him 115% damage and 110% speed. Tagging, Taunting, and performing Hyper Combos resets this effect)Jumping M start-up increasedSamurai Edge (Horizontal) float decreasedSamurai Edge hit-stun decreasedCobra Strike can be canceled into Phantom MoveJaguar Dash start-up reduced and active frames increasedJaguar Kick damage increasedTiger Uppercut L and M hit-box increasedTiger Uppercut M and H hard-knockdown attribute addedRhino Charge start-up invincibility frames increasedRhino Charge damage-scaling increasedLost in Nightmares can be mashed for additional damageAlternate ColorsColor #1: Resident Evil 5Color #2: Lab coat whiteColor #3: 70s brown leatherColor #4: Military green***Color #5: Villainous purple***Color #6: M. Bison (Street Fighter II)***ZeroZeroBackground - Despite being the last creation of the maniacal Dr. Wily, Zero's intense hatred of evil has led to him becoming one of the most fearsome hunters of Mavericks, robots who have become a threat to humanity.Balance Changes:Health increased to 830,000Normal attacks hit-stun decreasedShippuuga knock-back increased against airborne opponentsHyper Zero Blaster can be charged before the round beginsHyper Zero Blaster can only be performed a limited number of times in the airSpecial moves can now be canceled into Max Hyper Zero BlasterMax Hyper Zero Blaster hard knockdown attribute replaced by soft knockdown attributeSentsuizan recovery frames increasedSentsuizan H trajectory adjustedRaikousen will travel behind the opponent in the cornerAlternate ColorsColor #1: Mega Man XColor #2: Bass (Mega Man 7)Color #3: Axl (Mega Man X7)Color #4: Mega Man Zero***Color #5: Vile (Mega Man X)***Color #6: Mega Man X (Mega Man X)***Returning Marvel CharactersCaptain AmericaCaptain AmericaBackground - Born with a frail frame but the heart of a lion, Steve Rogers was granted peak physical perfection by the experimental Super Soldier Serum at the onset of World War 2. Now thrust into the modern age, Cap has risen to the head of S.H.I.E.L.D. as Top Cop and is acting leader of both the Avengers and Secret Avengers.Balance Changes:Double-jump ability addedInvincibility frames added to CartwheelCharging Star hard knock-down attribute addedCharging Star M and H damage reducedCharging Star knock-back increasedCharging Star and Stars  Stripes assist damage increasedShield Slash L hits OTGShield Slash hit-stun decreasedHyper Charging Star knockdown duration decreasedHyper Charging Star can be mashed for additional damageAlternate Colors:Color #1: Classic Red, White  BlueColor #2: Captain America Comics #1***Color #3: Age of X***Color #4: The Avengers: Earth's Mightiest Heroes***Color #5: Bucky Barnes***Color #6: Punisher (Punisher War Journal #7)**DeadpoolDeadpoolBackground - A mercenary with extensive military training, the Weapon-X program imbued Wade Wilson with a healing factor similar to Wolverine's, fracturing his mind in the process. He is currently employed by Archangel on the covert mutant team X-Force.Balance Changes:Normals can be canceled into TauntMad Wheel can no longer be canceledThrow knockdown duration increasedSpecials can be canceled into TELEPORT!Quick Work can be canceled into Chimichangas!!Ninja Gift H float height decreasedNinja Gift H incapacitation duration increasedNinja Gift H incapacitation duration is now subject to hit-stun scalingHappy-Happy Trigger can be mashed for additional damageAlternate Colors:Color #1: Classic black  redColor #2: X-Men uniform***Color #3: Deathwish (Deadpool Annual)***Color #4: Weapon X: Days of Future NowColor #5: Weapon X uniformColor #6: X-Force uniform**Doctor DoomDoctor DoomBackground - A powerful sorcerer and genius scientist, the dictator of Latveria has proven to be more than a match for his foes the Fantastic Four on more than one occasion. In order to have his recent brain damage cured, he has agreed to work alongside his nemesis Reed Richards as a member of the newly formed Future Foundation.Balance Changes:Jumping H start-up frames reduced and hit-box size increasedJumping S hard knockdown attribute addedJumping S downward momentum increasedPhoton Shot animation frames reduced when performed in the airPhoton Array and Doom Time can be mashed for additional damageForward throw and forward air-throw soft knockdown attribute replaced by hard knockdown*Hidden Missiles stacking glitch removed*Alternate Colors:Color #1: Classic gray  greenColor #2: Future Foundation uniform***Color #3: Dark Reign: The Cabal***Color #4: Wolverine: Old Man LoganColor #5: Doom 2099Color #6: Death Mask (Deadpool Annual)***DormammuDormammuBackground - Once a human sorcerer, Dormammu is now the lord of the Dark Dimension and has gained immortality by trading his physical body for one made of mystic energy. His constant attempts to achieve domination of Earth have been thwarted time and again by Dr. Strange.Balance Changes:Ground normal chain maximum increased to 3L normals knock-back increasedFlame Carpet disappears if Dormammu is hitThrow soft knockdown attribute replaced by hard knockdownDark Matter can be special canceledDark Spell: Creation and Dark Spell: Destruction can be performed in the airLiberation can be performed in the air and teleports Dormammu to the groundLiberation (2 Destruction, 1 Creation) is active from 1st frame and causes hard knockdownLiberation (2 Destruction, 1 Creation) projectiles are delayed and cause increased damageLiberation (2 Creation, 1 Destruction) is active from 1st frameChaotic Flame can be mashed for additional damageDark Dimension OTG no longer whiffs on bouncing opponents*Alternate Colors:Color #1: Defenders (2005)Color #2: Original blue  greenColor #3: Classic green  orange***Color #4: Red uniform (unknown origin)Color #5: New Exiles Annual***Color #6: Rorkannu***HulkHulkBackground - Once a mild-mannered scientist, an accidental exposure to gamma radiation transformed Bruce Banner into the rampaging giant known as the Hulk. The return of his inner monster, thanks to the influence of the Serpent's divine hammer, has battered his psyche and left him unsure of his future as a hero.Balance Changes:New Incredible Punch command-normalL and M normals can be canceled into Incredible PunchGamma Charge hurt-box decreasedGamma Charge now has super armorGamma Charge Second pop-up increasedGamma Charge Second M (Anti-Air) wall-bounce attribute addedGamma Tornado damage increasedGamma Wave charge time decreasedAlternate Colors:Color #1: Classic green  purpleColor #2: Original green  purple***Color #3: Gray Hulk (The Incredible Hulk #324)Color #4: Red HulkColor #5: Age of X***Color #6: Captain Universe***Iron ManIron ManBackground - When an errant piece of shrapnel became lodged in his chest, Tony Stark was forced to create a suit of magnetic iron armor in order to save his life. Despite the collapse of Stark Industries, he is determined to rebuild and has founded new company, Stark Resilient.Balance Changes:Double-jump ability removedJumping normals can now be air-dash canceledNormal attacks minimum damage scaling decreasedCrouching H can be special canceledCrouching H hit-stun increasedJumping H and S hit-boxes increasedInitial air-dash speed decreasedSpecial attacks minimum damage scaling increasedFlight start-up frames decreasedDuring Repulsor Blast, further inputs are based on Iron Man's original facingRepulsor Spread can now be performed by pressing HRepulsor Spread hard knockdown attribute addedSmart Bomb damage increasedSmart Bomb hit-stun decreasedSmart Bomb animation frames reducedIron Avenger and Proton Cannon can be mashed for additional damageAlternate Colors:Color #1: Extremis (The Invincible Iron Man #1)Color #2: Original iron suitColor #3: Silver Centurion (Armor Wars)Color #4: Stealth Suit (The Invincible Iron Man #152)Color #5: Golden Avenger (Tales of Suspense #40)***Color #6: Evil Iron Man (Marvel Super Heroes in War of the Gems)***MagnetoMagnetoBackground - Born Max Eisenhardt, a lifetime of tragedy and betrayal twisted the master of magnetism into one of Earth's most reviled mutant villains, Magneto. Experiencing a recent change of heart, he is working to atone for his past sins by serving as a member of Cyclops's council on Utopia Island.Balance Changes:New Fatal Attraction specialNew Repulsion specialNew Reverse Polarity specialStanding H hard knockdown attribute removedDiagonal air-dash speed reducedElectromagnetic Disruptor L and M animation frames increasedElectromagnetic Disruptor block-stun decreasedMagnetic Tempest invincibility frames removedGravity Squeeze and Magnetic Tempest can be mashed for additional damageJumping H knock-back increased*Alternate Colors:Color #1: Classic purple  redColor #2: Eve of Destruction***Color #3: Age of X***Color #4: Ultimate universeColor #5: Mutant X universe**Color #6: Marvel vs. Capcom 2: New Age of Heroes alternate (MAG-F#$%IN'-NETO)M.O.D.O.K.M.O.D.O.K.Background - Whether he volunteered or was forced, the experiments performed on George Tarleton to unlock his mental potential transformed him into M.O.D.O.C. (Mental Organism Designed Only for Computing). With his new found abilities he quickly took control of A.I.M., the organization responsible for his change, and placed himself in command, renaming himself M.O.D.O.K. (Mental Organism Designed Only for Killing) in the process.Balance Changes:Jumping normals can now be air-dash canceledKiller Illumination can be mashed for additional damageAlternate Colors:Color #1: Classic purple  yellowColor #2: Tales of Suspense #93Color #3: M.O.D.O.K.'s 11Color #4: What If? #37***Color #5: M.O.D.A.M.Color #6: M.O.D.O.T. (Howard the Duck 2007)***PhoenixPhoenixBackground - The weakest of the original five X-Men, Jean Grey was granted immeasurable reality-altering power when she agreed to become host to the Phoenix Force in order to survive a lethal dose of radiation poisoning. Recently sacrificing herself to protect the universe from the potential return of the destructive Dark Phoenix persona, it is likely only a matter of time before she rises from the ashes once more.Balance Changes:Health reduced to 375,000Crouching M distance reducedFlight cancels after teleporting to the groundUnable to act after TK Shot when performed in the airTK Shot projectiles disappear if Phoenix is hitTK Traps disappear if Phoenix is hitAlternate Colors:Color #1: Classic gold  greenColor #2: Phoenix: EndsongColor #3: New X-Men**Color #4: X-Men Forever**Color #5: X-Factor uniform***Color #6: Age of Apocalypse***SentinelSentinelBackground - Created by Bolivar Trask, the Sentinels were giant humanoid robots armed with the latest in weaponry and detention technology. Although they have gone through many iterations their mission has always remained the same, total eradication of the mutant race.Balance Changes:Health reduced to 900,000Standing S Hyper Armor attribute replaced with 1-hit Super ArmorRocket Punch hit-stun decreasedSentinel Force assist now pushes the opponent away from the projectiles when hitting from behindPlasma Storm can be mashed for additional damageRocket Punch assist soft knockdown attribute removed*Alternate Colors:Color #1: COTA-94 (X-Men: Children of the Atom)Color #2: X-Men: Mutant ApocalypseColor #3: Nimrod***Color #4: Second ComingColor #5: Turquoise***Color #6: Marvel vs. Capcom 2: New Age of Heroes alternate (Da Mango Sentinel)She-HulkShe-HulkBackground - After receiving a life-saving blood transfusion from her cousin Bruce Banner, AKA the Hulk, Jennifer Walters found herself transformed into the savage She-Hulk. Having gained full control over her powers, she now spends more of her time green than lean, galavanting about with numerous heroes and super-teams.Balance Changes:New Savage Swing command-normalWeight classification increasedCrouching L chain cancel attribute removedCrouching H distance reducedChariot gains Super Armor when its activation is delayed after Runner's StartClothesline wall-bounce attribute added against airborne opponentsRunner's Start can be canceled into Clothesline and Torpedo earlierEmerald Canon horizontal range increasedTaking out the Trash can have the joystick spun for additional damageAlternate Colors:Color #1: Modern purple  whiteColor #2: Fantastic Four uniform***Color #3: Gray She-Hulk (The Sensational She-Hulk #15)***Color #4: Betty Ross (Ultimate universe)Color #5: Red She-Hulk**Color #6: Lyra**Shuma-GorathShuma-GorathBackground - A Chthonic elder god as old as the universe itself, Shuma-Gorath ruled over Earth during its primordial days before entering a self-imposed hibernation. Since his recent awakening his numerous attempts to reconquer the Earth have failed, thanks in large part to the efforts of Dr. Strange.Balance Changes:Jumping S OTG attribute removed and hard knockdown attribute addedThrows can now absorb a portion of the opponent's Health Meter and Hyper Combo GaugeDevitalization start-up frames reducedChaos Dimension and Hyper Mystic Smash can be mashed for additional damageAlternate Colors:Color #1: Classic greenColor #2: Original purpleColor #3: Marvel vs. Capcom 2: New Age of Heroes alternateColor #4: WhiteColor #5: Red***Color #6: Black***Spider-ManSpider-ManBackground - A fateful bite from a radioactive spider during a science exhibition transformed puny Peter Parker into the amazing Spider-Man. One of Earth's busiest heroes, he currently is an active member of the Future Foundation and multiple Avengers teams and is working to guide the next generation of heroes by lending a hand at the Avengers Academy.Balance Changes:Web Glide now travels fasterWeb Glide hits OTG when performed in the airSpider Sting, Web Ball and Web Swing specials can be canceled into Web GlideWeb Swing can be performed in the air after a Web Swing on the groundWeb Throw is now subject to hit-stun deteriorationCrawler Assault animation frames reducedCrawler Assault hard knockdown attribute addedUltimate Web Throw vertical hit-box reduced and horizontal hit-box increasedMaximum Spider can be mashed for additional damageUltimate Web Throw can have the joystick spun for additional damageAlternate Colors:Color #1: Classic blue  redColor #2: Black symbioteColor #3: Iron Spider suitColor #4: New Spider Armor (Amazing Spider-Man #656)***Color #5: Stealth Suit (Big Time)**Color #6: Future Foundation uniform***StormStormBackground - Before she became an X-Man, Ororo Iqadi T'Challa led a wildly varied youth, beginning as an orphan pickpocket in Egypt and ending as a revered goddess in Kenya. Although she spends a majority of her time with her husband, the Black Panther, ruling their kingdom of Wakanda, she is always ready to return to action when her friends are in danger.Balance Changes:New Fair Wind specialNew Foul Wind specialElemental Rage, Hail Storm, and Lightning Storm can be mashed for additional damageHail Storm area of effect increased*Alternate Colors:Color #1: Modern black  yellowColor #2: 90's UniformColor #3: Revolution***Color #4: The New Fantastic Four***Color #5: Early 90's uniform***Color #6: X-Men: To Serve and Protect***Super-SkrullSuper SkrullBackground - The Skrull empire granted Kl'rt augmented versions of the powers of the Fantastic Four so that he could serve as the vanguard for their invasion of Earth. Dismissed by his people as an obsolete relic decades later, he found himself in the unlikely role of hero when he destroyed a ship full of Skrulls in order to protect his one-time ally Nova from assassination.Balance Changes:Stone Smite hit-box enlargedMeteor Smash can now be performed in the airOrbital Grudge super armor activates earlierOrbital Grudge pop-up increasedOrbital Grudge soft knockdown attribute removedDeath Penalty tracks opponentInferno can be mashed for additional damageAlternate Colors:Color #1: Classic black  purpleColor #2: Skrulls (Fantastic Four #2)***Color #3: Classic blue  white***Color #4: Ultimate universe**Color #5: Rl'nndColor #6: Avengers: The Initiative #14TaskmasterTaskmasterBackground - When a young Anthony Masters discovered that he had photographic reflexes he quickly focused his new-found talents on financial gain, training henchmen for his numerous super-villain clients. Since he ended his long teaching carreer, he has found himself the target of assassination by a far-reaching criminal agency known as "The Org."Balance Changes:New Sting Master specialNormal attack minimum damage-scaling decreasedJumping H pop-up increasedCharging Star knock-back increased against airborne opponentsCharging Star pop-up increasedWeb Master can be special canceledAim Master damage decreasedAim Master H pop-up decreasedHyper Combo minimum damage-scaling decreasedLegion Arrow can be mashed for additional damageAlternate Colors:Color #1: Modern blue  whiteColor #2: Original blue, orange  whiteColor #3: Frightful Four uniformColor #4: Deadpool #9***Color #5: Black Knight***Color #6: Mr. Fear***ThorThorBackground - Banished to Earth in order to learn humility, the thunder god has become one of humanity's most stalwart allies. Now that Galactus has come to consume the Worldseed from the fallen Yggdrasil, Thor has engaged the Silver Surfer in combat allowing the gods of Asgard to focus their assault on the world eater.Balance Changes:Normal and special attack minimum damage-scaling increasedStanding M knock-back reducedStanding and jumping L hit-boxes increasedMighty Hurricane active frames increasedMighty Hurricane range increasedMighty Smash H requires fewer frames to reach maximum chargeMighty Spark initial hit-box increasedMighty Spark hit-stun increasedMighty Strike requires fewer frames to reach maximum chargeMighty Strike animation frames reducedMighty Punish start-up invincibility frames added and active frames increasedMighty Punish knockdown duration increasedMighty Tornado can be mashed for additional damageAlternate Colors:Color #1: Modern gray  redColor #2: Thor #378***Color #3: Heroes Reborn***Color #4: Ultimate universe***Color #5: The Avengers: Earth's Mightiest Heroes***Color #6: Beta Ray BillWolverineWolverineBackground - Alive for more than 100 years thanks to his powerful healing-factor, James "Logan" Howlett has one of the bloodiest histories of any of Earth's heroes. He is currently working under the command of Cyclops as a member of the newly reformed X-Force.Balance Changes:New Berserker Rage specialJumping L and Dive Kick hit-boxes decreasedBerserker Slash invincibility frames removedBerserker Charge input priority is now lowest among Hyper CombosBerserker Barrage X, Fatal Claw, and Weapon X can be mashed for additional damageAlternate ColorsColor #1: Astonishing X-Men #1Color #2: Classic brown  yellowColor #3: X-Force uniformColor #4: Wolverine: Enemy of the State***Color #5: Age of ApocalypseColor #6: Evil Wolverine (Marvel Super Heroes in War of the Gems)***X-23X-23Background - Laura Kinney was the 23rd and only successful attempt to create a female clone of Wolverine, raised under torturous conditions to become a living weapon for assassination. She is currently traveling the world alongside Gambit seeking the answers to questions about her past, all the while dealing with her guilt over the past atrocities she has committed.Balance Changes:Specials can be canceled into Talon AttackCrescent Scythe pop-up increasedCrescent Scythe hit stun decreasedRage Trigger knock-back increasedRage Trigger can be mashed for additional damageAlternate Colors:Color #1: Classic blackColor #2: Messiah CompleXColor #3: X-23 #1Color #4: Captain UniverseColor #5: Modern blue  white***Color #6: Kirika**** unannounced changes based on player observation** updated alternate color from Marvel vs. Capcom 3: Fate of Two Worlds*** new alternate colorSystem ChangesAir-DashThe ability to block while air-dashing has been removed across the castThe speed of air-dashing down-back has been decreased for characters with an 8-way air-dashAssistsHitting an assist with a snap-back will cause both assist characters to be unavailable for an extended durationAssists are now subject to hit-stun scalingAlternate ColorsEach character will be receiving two additional colors, bringing the grand total to sixNew colors for Marvel characters draw their inspiration from the Marvel universeSome old alternate Marvel colors have been updated to hew closer to their original inspirationCombo SystemNew toggled option to automatically super-jump by holding the Special button when launching the opponentHyper CombosHyper Combo Gauge generation rate decreased by 10%Certain Hyper Combos can be mashed for additional hits and damageMagic PixelCharacters will no longer continue to take damage beyond the end of their visible life barNew StagesAsgard: Sea of Space*Bonne Wonderland*Chaos at Tricell*City that Never Sleeps*Danger RoomDays of Future Past*Demon Village Redux*S.H.I.E.L.D. Air Show*ShadowlandTeam Aerial Exchange (TAC)Side TAC now removes one Hyper Combo Gauge from the opponentTAC Whiff glitch has been removedTeam Hyper Combo (THC)THC Damage/Hitstun Scaling glitch has been removedX-FactorX-Factor can now be activated in the airSpeed and damage bonuses have been normalized across the castThe damage bonus has been reduced overallThe minimum damage after scaling has been reduced from 50% to 35%Hyper Combos are now subject to damage scaling* modified Marvel vs. Capcom 3: Fate of Two Worlds stageGameplay ModesPlayer and Ranked MatchesCapcom has added a number of upgrades to Ranked and Player matching in order to provide an online experience more robust than what was offered in Marvel vs. Capcom 3: Fate of Two Worlds. New features include the following:Spectator ModeThe ability to view an opponent's stats before accepting a matchNew Gold, Silver, and Skull icons assigned based on network mannersEasier matchmaking with a faster retry functionNetwork failure while matching no longer boots players to the main menuMore efficient leader-board viewing toolsGalactus ModeDuring the 2011 New York Comic-Con, Galactus was announced as a playable character in his own mode.Heroes and HeraldsReleased on December 19, 2011, Heroes and Heralds mode was originally announced during the 2011 New York Comic-Con as free, post-release DLC. This new mode, available both offline and online, allows players to collect over one-hundred cards representing various characters from the Marvel and Capcom universes such as Howard the Duck and equip them in sets of three for various power-ups.Offline CampaignAfter choosing their faction for the campaign mode, players fight against increasingly difficult AI opponents as they attempt to take over territories represented by a hexagonal grid. Defeating specific opponents according to an in-game hit-list unlocks special area battles that give players one chance to win a rare card. Not only does this mode allow players to build up their collection for online play, it also serves as an area for experimentation by allowing players to freely change cards between matches.Online PlayAt the beginning of every week, solitary players and clans can choose to ally themselves with either the Heroes or the Heralds. Victories will earn points for players that contribute to an overall faction ranking. At the end of the week, the winning faction will have an increased chance to unlock rare cards in addition to a Heralds alternate color for use in the regular game.Deck BuilderAs they play through the offline and online Heroes  Heralds modes, players will earn cards of varying rarity. Classified as either C, B, A, or the rarest and most powerful S rank, cards will be used to create three-card decks in the deck builder mode. Each deck consists of one primary slot and two secondary slots. Depending on their assigned position, each card will offer a variety of different power-ups in battle.Capcom CardsAkiraAnakarisAstarothBatsu IchimonjiBishamonBlodiaCaptain BlueCaptain CommandoChuck GreeneClaire RedfieldCyber BlueDevilotDemitri MaximoffDr. WilyFalconFelynesFou-LuFranziska Von KarmaGeneGodotGrandmasterHayatoHideo ShimazuH.U.N.K.Jin SaotomeJuneKaijin No SokiKenjiKyosukeLadyLeon S. KennedyLickerLilithLinLord RaptorMega ManMiles EdgeworthMissileMyriaNinaPrincess Prin PrinRathalosRathianRollRyuSakuyaSasquatchServbotSisselSteven ChapmanVileXMarvel CardsAbominationAnti-VenomBeastBlack PantherBlack WidowBladeBullseyeCleaColossusCyclopsDakenDaredevilDazzlerDestroyerDoctor OctopusElektraEnchantressFantastic FourFing Fang FoomGreen GoblinHoward the DuckHulkbuster ArmorIcemanJuggernautKingpinLokiLuke CageMaestroMandarinMephistoMs. MarvelMultiple ManMystiqueNick FuryNightcrawlerProfessor XPunisherRed HulkRed SkullRogueSabretoothScarlet WitchThe SerpentSilver SamuraiSilver SurferSpider-HamThanosUlikUltronWaspWatcherWinter SoldierDownloadable ContentDuring the 2011 San Diego Comic-Con it was revealed that while the previous Marvel vs. Capcom 3: Fate of Two Worlds costume and character DLC would carry over to UMvC3, Shadow Mode and all previous Shadow Mode DLC would not be making a return. Additionally, new costume packs were announced for the remaining cast, with three initially made available as pre-order bonuses through major retailers.Pre-Order Costume PacksGame Stop - Femme Fatale PackAmazon - New Age of Heroes PackBest Buy - Villains PackMarvel vs Capcom 3 Alternate Costume Pack (March 1, 2011; PSN - $4.99 / XBL - 400 Microsoft Points)Captain America - Top Cop (Steve Rogers: Super Soldier)Chris Redfield - S.T.A.R.S. (Resident Evil)Dante - SpardaIron Man - Iron PatriotRyu - Street FighterThor - Classic black, blue  orangeJill Valentine (March 15, 2011; PSN - $4.99 / XBL - 400 Microsoft Points)Jill Valentine - Resident Evil 3: NemesisShuma Gorath (March 15, 2011; PSN - $4.99 / XBL - 400 Microsoft Points)Shuma Gorath - Quoggoth (Wolverine: First Class #12)Evil Twin Costume Pack (November 22, 2011; PSN - $3.99 / XBL - 320 Microsoft Points)Deadpool - Cable-Pool (Deadpool  Cable #26)Hsien-Ko - Mei-LingSpider-Man - Scarlet SpiderVergil - Corrupt Vergil (Devil May Cry 3: Dante's Awakening)Rising Dead Costume Pack (November 22, 2011; PSN - $3.99 / XBL - 320 Microsoft Points)Frank West - Real Mega Buster (Dead Rising)Ghost Rider - Ghost Rider 2099Nemesis T-Type - Battle damagePhoenix - X-Men (1991)Ancient Warrior Costume Pack (December 20, 2011; PSN - $3.99 / XBL - 320 Microsoft Points)Arthur - Boxers/SkeletonFirebrand - Red Arremer King (Ghouls n' Ghosts)Hulk - World War HulkMagneto - House of MBrawler Costume Pack (January 10, 2012; PSN - $3.99 / XBL - 320 Microsoft Points)Haggar - Final Fight 3Iron Fist - Ultimate universeShe-Hulk - She-Hulk #7Spencer - Bionic Commando: RearmedFemme Fatale Costume Pack (January 17, 2012; PSN - $3.99 / XBL - 320 Microsoft Points)Chun-Li - Street Fighter AlphaMorrigan - Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors victory poseStorm - Uncanny X-Men (1983)X-23 - X-Men EvolutionNew Age of Heroes Costume Pack (January 17, 2012; PSN - $3.99 / XBL - 320 Microsoft Points)Akuma - Cyber Akuma (Marvel Super Heroes vs. Street Fighter)Doctor Doom - DoomwarSentinel - Classic X-MenStrider Hiryu - Strider (1989)Villains Costume Pack (January 17, 2012; PSN - $3.99 / XBL - 320 Microsoft Points)C.Viper - Battle ArmorM.O.D.O.K. - "Graceland" M.O.D.O.K.Super-Skrull - AnnihilationWesker - S.T.A.R.S. (Resident Evil)Animal Costume Pack (January 24, 2012; PSN - $3.99 / XBL - 320 Microsoft Points)Amaterasu - Jon Talbain (Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors)Felicia - Yellow Iris (Battle Circuit)Rocket Raccoon - Original costumeWolverine - Weapon X (Marvel Comics Presents #72)Weapon Expert Costume Pack (February 7, 2012; PSN - $3.99 / XBL - 320 Microsoft Points)Hawkeye - Ronin (New Avengers #26)Taskmaster - Taskmaster (2002)Trish - Gloria (Devil May Cry 4)Zero - Mega Man XViewtiful Strange Costume Pack(February 21, 2012; PSN - $3.99 / XBL - 320 Microsoft Points)Doctor Strange - Doctor Strange #177Dormammu - Original costumeNova - Ultimate Spider-ManPhoenix Wright - "Feenie" (Phoenix Wright: Trials and Tribulations)Tron Bonne - Servbot suitViewtiful Joe - Regular JoeValue Costume Pack (March 6, 2012; PSN - $19.99 / XBL - 1600 Microsoft Points)All 48 costumes</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="28437">Super Street Fighter IV</game><game id="28321">BlazBlue: Continuum Shift</game><game id="32161">Street Fighter X Tekken</game><game id="36274">Persona 4 Arena</game><game id="30142">The King of Fighters XIII</game><game id="38480">Injustice: Gods Among Us</game><game id="30558">Sunday vs. Magazine: Shuuketsu! Choujou Daikessen</game><game id="34475">Hajime no Ippo: The Fighting!</game><game id="38394">Divekick</game><game id="42599">Dead or Alive 5 Ultimate</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1982790-box_umvc3.png</image></root>