<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36051</id><name>Ougon Musou Kyoku</name><description>Ougon Musou Kyoku (黄金夢想曲) is a spin-off on the popular Japanese visual novel Umineko no Naku Koro ni that pits the characters of that series against each other in a 2D fighting game where each match has two pairs of fighters engage in a tag-team battle. While it's based on the characters and events of the visual novels, it's considered to be an alternative continuity from the rest of the series and has no bearing on the actual canon of the series. Instead, the characters have their own unique stories and endings in the game's single player arcade mode depending on the pairings, with the story told between matches told in a visual novel-like style similar to the story modes in the BlazBlue series.GameplayOugon Musou Kyoku has several mechanics that distinguishes it from other fighting games.SPThis represents your character's magical power and is used to perform your character's most powerful special moves and to activate the Metaworld. Your character's SP gauge won't increase from fighting but instead gradually charges for the character that's tagged out, forcing the player to use the tagging system strategically. Up to five units of SP can be stored for each character with most advanced moves requiring one to two units of SP.AbilitiesEvery character has a passive ability that is activated either when the Metaworld is active or when a character is tagged out normally. This grants a brief bonus such as increasing the damage from counters or improving the chances to stun an opponent.TouchThe Touch command is the cornerstone of the game's tagging system. When the Touch gauge at the bottom corner of the screen is full it can be used to switch out a character. It can also be used to make your partner perform various assist moves when they're tagged in that consume one to two bars of their stored SP. After using Touch, the Touch gauge will need to be recharged before it can be used again.MetaworldActivating Metaworld transforms the stage.Using the Metaworld command costs one point of SP. When triggered, the background is drastically changed the character that activated it gains access to both their and their partner's passive ability for the duration of the event. The character that declared Metaworld also gains access to their most powerful attack, the Meta Super, and can use regular SP Supers without expending SP while the Metaworld is active.When one player tries to activate the Metaworld the other player can use their SP to try and prevent them from doing so by using the Metaworld command at the same time as their opponent. This forces the opposing player to use more SP to try and force a Metaworld declaration, or wait before they can try to activate it again.Playable charactersNameAbilityDescriptionAnge UshiromiyaStun BoostIncreased chance of stunning the opponent.Battler UshiromiyaResurrectionGradual health regeneration.BeatriceInfinity SPPlayer can perform SP Supers without using SP.Eva-BeatriceBerserkGreatly increases the player's attack strength.Jessica UshiromiyaShave BoostAttacks cause damage to blocking opponents.KanonSilent AttackReduced SP recovery rate for the opponent.LuciferAttack TouchThe player can perform one Attack Touch without a full Touch gauge.RonoveCounter BoostIncreases the damage dealt by the player's counter attacks.ShannonAuto-GuardAutomatic blocking.Siesta 410Break BoostIncreases the rate that the opponent's Break Limit gauge will fill.VirgiliaBrimfulGradually restores the player's SP gauge.Non-playable characters and cameosApart from the roster of selectable characters, several other characters from the Umineko no Naku Koro ni visual novels also appear in the game. Some, like Siesta 00, Siesta 45, Mammon, Satan, Belphegor, Leviathan and Sakutaro can be called upon by certain characters to perform special moves or assist the character with their SP attacks. Others, like Gaap, Rudolf Ushiromiya and Maria Ushiromiya, only appeared in certain stage backgrounds, while Featherinne Augustus Aurora, Furfur and Zepar appear on certain menu screens. Bernkastel, Lambdadelta, Erika Furudo, Dlanor A. Knox (along with her subordinates Gertrude and Cornelia) and Rosa Ushiromiya only appeared as background characters in the original Ougon Musou Kyoku, but would later become fully playable characters in future installments of the series.Release historyThe game was originally released on the 31st of December, 2010, at Comiket 79. A patch for the game was later released on the 8th of July, 2011, and added Jessica Ushiromiya as a playable character. It also introduced character-specific health, a CG gallery, replay functionality and improved netplay. A XBox 360 port (Ougon Musou Kyoku X) developed and published by Alchemist was released in Japan on he 6th of October, 2011, and George to the game's roster of fighters. An append disc for the original PC title, Ougon Musou Kyoku Cross, was released on the 31st of December, 2011, at Comiket 81, and would add Erika Furudo, Dlanor A. Knox, and an alternate version of Battler Ushiromiya (B.Battler) to the game's roster of selectable fighters along with the characters previously only featured in the XBox 360 version of the game. Willard H. Wright was patched into the game's roster on the 24th of February, 2012, with Lambdadelta and Bernkastel are expected to be patched into the game in the near future.PC System requirementsMinimumRecommendedOS: Windows XP (32-Bit)CPU: Dual-Core CPUMemory: 1 GB (Windows XP), 2 GB (Windows 7)HDD: 2GBGraphics card: Any one applicable to DirectX9.0, VRAM 256MB and upSound card: Any one applicable to DirectX9.0Input device: Gamepad with 6+ buttons, keyboardOS: Windows 7 (64-bit)CPU: Quad-Core CPUMemory: 2 GB (Windows XP), 3 GB (Windows 7)HDD: 2GBGraphics Card: Nvidia Geforce 8500GT and up, ATI Radeon HD 4650 and upExternal linksOfficial website at 07th ExpansionOfficial website of OMK Cross at 07th ExpansionOugon Musou Kyoku X official website at AlchemistOMK Wiki for translation help, strategies and links to patches.</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21768">BlazBlue: Calamity Trigger</game><game id="29779">BlazBlue Calamity Trigger Portable</game><game id="28321">BlazBlue: Continuum Shift</game><game id="32481">Blazblue: Continuum Shift II</game><game id="11813">Guilty Gear</game><game id="3978">Guilty Gear X</game><game id="8534">Guilty Gear X2</game><game id="15074">Guilty Gear Isuka</game><game id="8605">Marvel vs. Capcom: Clash of Super Heroes</game><game id="36253">BlazBlue Continuum Shift Extend</game><game id="36274">Persona 4 Arena</game><game id="34082">Skullgirls</game><game id="21367">Sengoku Basara X</game><game id="34396">Aquapazza: Aquaplus Dream Match</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/12/127673/1852214-ougon_musoukyoku_cover.jpg</image></root>