<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36093</id><name>Legends of Yore</name><description>OverviewLegends of Yore is a roguelike game for the PC and mobile systems. It was developed by Kevin Glass, featuring music by Arthur Lang and graphics by Oryx (TIGSource Assemblee), and some additional art by Dave Fillion and Kevin Glass himself. The game is free-to-play up until level 20, at which point it becomes pay-to-play. You can also play it in java equipped browsers via the official website.GameplayThe gameplay is very casual and simplistic, with almost every aspect of the game able to be controlled with the mouse or tapping on mobile devices. After choosing one of three classes (Warrior, Archer, Wizard) players are free to explore towns and dungeons as you come across them. Of course, being a roguelike, the bulk of the game features randomly generated dungeons, monsters, and loot. Quests are obtained by talking to various people in the towns. One interesting feature of the game is that after each floor of a dungeon, the game will save, allowing players to quickly complete a floor or two and come back later and continue where they left off. Upon death, players will resume from the last save, unless the game is being played with perma-death on. Unlike modern games baring the "roguelike" descriptor however, the combat and navigation is still turn-based in design like the original game from which the nomenclature is derived. Players still click on monsters to attack them, but they will not attack back until the player performs another action. Clicking on the ground will still move the character, but it also allows enemies to move as well. Nothing happens in real time.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22309">Rogue</game><game id="29823">Grim Dawn</game><game id="32085">Bastion</game><game id="19703">Darkstone</game><game id="32130">Darkspore</game><game id="35468">Crimson Alliance</game><game id="20803">Diablo III</game><game id="25290">Fate:  Undiscovered Realms</game><game id="21229">Mythos</game><game id="30628">Pocket Legends</game><game id="11521">Record of Lodoss War</game><game id="21633">Soma Bringer</game><game id="13762">Titan Quest: Immortal Throne</game><game id="32255">Torchlight II</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/913/1858646-loy.png</image></root>