<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36106</id><name>Grand Slam Tennis 2</name><description>OverviewEA Sports plants both feet firmly on the court, trying to establish Grand Slam Tennis as their next big sports franchise. They've made the jump to the PS3 and Xbox 360 have left the Wii behind in the process. They've also moved away from the cartoon-ish art style that was used in the previous Wii version, and have adopted a more realistic look for the sequel, in line with other EA Sports franchises such as FIFA and NHL.Along with this visual upgrade comes a new feature: the "Total Racquet Control" system, which allows you to perform all of your swings with the right analog stick. The game also boasts a 20+ roster size which will include past legends such as John McEnroe, Pat Cash and Björn Borg and current players like Rafael Nadal, Roger Federer and the Williams sisters. A new feature called "P.R.O. AI" will capture the authentic play styles and behaviors of each member of the roster, including their signature swings. "ESPN Grand Slam Classics" is a mode that will allow you to replay 25 of tennis' most historic moments, as some of the sport's most memorable players.Other new features include a 10-year career mode, online versus play, and the return of the four major tennis tournaments, the Grand Slams: the Australian Open, U.S. Open, French Open, and Wimbledon. The Playstation 3 version of Grand Slam Tennis 2 also features Playstation Move support.RosterGrand Slam Tennis 2 features more than 20 players, past and present, for you to play with.ATP MenRoger FedererRafael NadalNovak DjokovicAndy MurrayLleyton HewittJo-Wilfried TsongaKei NishikoriWTA WomenVenus WilliamsSerena WilliamsMaria SharapovaAna IvanovicATP LegendsBoris BeckerBjorn BorgStefan EdbergPat CashJohn McEnroePete SamprasMichael StichWTA LegendsLindsay DavenportChris EvertJustine HeninMartina Navratilova</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="25">Tennis</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21822">Smash Court Tennis: Pro Tournament 2</game><game id="32594">Top Spin 4</game><game id="32369">Virtua Tennis 4</game><game id="14977">Tennis 2K2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2136547-box_gst2.png</image></root>