<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36116</id><name>Quadradius</name><description>The idea for Quadradius originally came from Jimmi Heiserman's 1995 High School project which was called "Squares". Finally deciding to update the game, Jimmi created a new version in Flash, with Brad Kayal providing the graphics. Quadradius is free to play, but there is an optional payed membership that provides access to more power ups, member ranks, and etc. The game can be found at http://www.quadradius.com.GameplayThe Quadradius board is set up much like a checkers board, with each player starting with the same amount of pieces. On a player's turn, they are allowed to move a piece one square. To win, a player must simply destroy every enemy piece. The easiest way to destroy pieces is to move a piece on top of an enemy's piece.Quadradius' most interesting feature is the power ups. As a game goes on, orbs will occasionally spawn on top of random free spaces on the board. Landing on an orb will cause that specific piece to acquire a power up. A player can use any amount of power ups on their turn, as long as they only move once. Each piece has its own inventory of the power ups it has collected. Power ups come in a variety of forms, including bombs that destroy random spaces on the map, armor that makes pieces unable to be destroyed through others landing on them, teleportation spots, and etc. Some power ups can even move the terrain to create high and low ground. Usually, by the time the game is nearing its end, the the board will be incredibly chaotic, hence the reason the players like to call it "checkers on steroids".Power UpsBelow is a comprehensive list of every power up in the game, with their effects, and whether or not they are members only.NameEffectMembers Only?MultiplyCreates a new piece. Can be placed anywhere adjacent to the piece that used the ability.NoOrbic RehashRemoves all current Power Orbs and randomly places new ones onto the board.NoGrow QuadradiusExtends the range for any move the piece uses that effects either a row, column, or radial. Row and column power ups will now affect all three rows or columns around the piece, and radial power ups will affect any space that is at most 2 spaces away. The range can be extended further with another Grow Quadradius power up.NoBombsRandomly blows up squares on the board. Kills any piece that is hit, and pushes the square downwards.NoSmart BombsSame effect as the Bombs, but tends to hit the enemy's pieces more often than your own.NoSnake TunnelingEnergy tunnels under the board, randomly seeking out opponents. This raises tiles and destroys any enemies that might be hit. Snake Tunneling moves randomly, and can backtrack its path.NoRaise TileRaises the tile that the piece using the ability is currently on.NoLower TileLowers the tile that the piece using the ability is currently on.NoClimb TileThe piece is able to move up any tile no matter how high it is.NoPlateauRaises every tile within a radial of your piece.NoMoatLowers every tile next to your piece.NoTrench RowLowers every tile in the same row as your piece.NoTrench ColumnLowers every tile in the same column as your piece.NoWall RowRaises every tile in the same row as your piece.NoWall ColumnRaises every tile in the same column as your piece.NoInvert RadialAll surrounding tiles have their elevations inverted.NoInvert RowAll tiles in the same row as your piece have their elevations inverted.NoInvert ColumnAll tiles in the same column as your piece have their elevations inverted.NoDredge RadialAll of your surrounding pieces are raised to their max height while your opponent's are lowered to their deepest.YesDredge RowAll enemy pieces in the same row as your piece are taken to the lowest height, while your pieces are taken to the highest height.YesDredge ColumnAll enemy pieces in the same column as your piece are taken to the lowest height, while your pieces are taken to the highest height.YesTeach RadialAll allied pieces in the same radial as your piece will learn all of the abilities your piece currently has.NoTeach RowAll allied pieces in the same row as your piece will learn all of the abilities your piece currently has.NoTeach ColumnAll allied pieces in the same column as your piece will learn all of the abilities your piece currently has.NoLearn RadialYour piece learns all abilities your surrounding pieces have.NoLearn RowYour piece will learn all abilities the allied pieces in the same row as yours know.NoLearn ColumnYour piece will learn all abilities the allied pieces in the same column as yours know.NoPilfer RadialSteal all powers from the opponents surrounding you.NoPilfer RowSteal all powers from the opponents in your row.NoPilfer ColumnSteal all powers from the opponents in your column.NoParasite RadialLeeches onto any surrounding enemy pieces. Any new powers they acquire your piece will also acquire.NoParasite RowLeeches onto any enemy pieces in the same row. Any new powers they acquire your piece will also acquire.NoParasite ColumnLeeches onto any enemy pieces in the same column. Any new powers they acquire your piece will also acquire.No2xDoubles the amount of powers your piece currently possesses.NoBeneficiaryAll of your pieces give away their powers and put them onto this one piece.NoScavengerIf a scavenger piece jumps on an enemy piece, all of your scavenger pieces will receive that enemy piece's abilities.YesPower PlantSteals any orbs that spawn on the tile, and shares them with any piece on your aligned power plant grid.YesNetwork BridgeThis piece will tap into all the networked powers activated by others in your squadron. Any power that is normally absorbed through the squadron-wide network, is now absorbed by this piece also.YesMove AgainThis piece can move twice in this one turn.NoMove DiagonalThis piece can permanently move diagonally.NoFlat to SphereThis piece can now move off the map, and will appear on the opposite side.NoRelocateTeleports this piece to a random unoccupied location on the board.NoHotspotAny of your pieces can now permanently move to this tile, no matter where they are, as long as one of your pieces isn't already on the tile.NoSwitcherooYou can switch this piece with any other allied piece.YesCenterpultYour piece can catapult itself into the vacant center of any four, symmetric pieces, as long as occupying the empty, center tile will complete either a plus sign or an 'x' shaped pattern.YesInvisibleYour opponent can no longer see your piece. It can still be destroyed, however.YesJump ProofThis piece can no longer be defeated by being jump on by an enemy piece.NoScramble RadialRandomly moves around every piece in the same radial as yours.NoScramble RowRandomly moves around every piece in the same row as yours.NoScramble ColumnRandomly moves around every piece in the same column as yours.NoSwap RadialYour piece and all surrounding pieces swap ownership with your opponent.NoSwap RowYour piece and all pieces in its row swap ownership with your opponent.NoSwap ColumnYour piece and all pieces in its column swap ownership with your opponent.NoSpyware RadialYou can see any powers that the opponent's surrounding pieces have. This stays permanently on the pieces, letting you see new powers they acquire as well.NoSpyware RowYou can see any powers that the opponent's pieces in the same row have. This stays permanently on the pieces, letting you see new powers they acquire as well.NoSpyware ColumnYou can see any powers that the opponent's pieces in the same column have. This stays permanently on the pieces, letting you see new powers they acquire as well.NoOrb Spy RadialBugs every tile surrounding your piece. You can view the power of any orb that spawns on these tiles.YesOrb Spy RowBugs every tile in the row. You can view the power of any orb that spawns on these tiles.YesOrb Spy ColumnBugs every tile in the column. You can view the power of any orb that spawns on these tiles.YesRefurb RadialResets every tile surrounding your piece.YesRefurb RowResets every tile in the same row as your piece.YesRefurb ColumnResets every tile in the same column as your piece.YesBankrupt RadialResets every enemy piece that comes into contact with a tile in this radial.YesBankrupt RowResets every enemy piece that comes into contact with a tile in this row.YesBankrupt ColumnResets every piece that comes into contact with a tile in this column.YesPurify RadialRemoves any disabilities on your pieces in the same radial as your piece, and removes any benefits your opponent's pieces have as well.NoPurify RowRemoves any disabilities on your pieces in the same row as your piece, and removes any benefits your opponent's pieces have as well.NoPurify ColumnRemoves any disabilities on your pieces in the same column as your piece, and removes any benefits your opponent's pieces have as well.NoTripwire RadialIf any enemy piece within the same radial as your piece moves off of its tile, it will be destroyed.NoTripwire RowIf any enemy piece within the same row as your piece moves off of its tile, it will be destroyed.NoTripwire ColumnIf any enemy piece within the same column as your piece moves off of its tile, it will be destroyed.NoInhibit RadialYour opponent's pieces in the same radial as your piece can no longer acquire power ups from Power Orbs.NoInhibit RowYour opponent's pieces in the same row as your piece can no longer acquire power ups from Power Orbs.NoInhibit ColumnYour opponent's pieces in the same column as your piece can no longer acquire power ups from Power Orbs.NoKamikaze RadialDestroys all pieces in the same radial as your piece, including the piece activating the ability, and any of your pieces within range.NoKamikaze RowDestroys all pieces in the same row as your piece, including the piece activating the ability, and any of your pieces within range.NoKamikaze ColumnDestroys all pieces in the same column as your piece, including the piece activating the ability, and any of your pieces within range.NoDestroy RadialDestroys any surrounding enemy pieces.NoDestroy RowDestroys any enemy pieces in the same row as your piece.NoDestroy ColumnDestroys any enemy pieces in the same column as your piece.NoAcidic RadialDestroys any surrounding enemy pieces. Their tiles become completely uninhabitable.NoAcidic RowDestroys any enemy pieces in the same row as your piece. Their tiles become completely uninhabitable.NoAcidic ColumnDestroys any enemy pieces in the same column as your piece. Their tiles become completely uninhabitable.NoRecruit RadialSteal any enemy pieces surrounding your piece.NoRecruit RowSteal any enemy pieces in the same row as your piece.NoRecruit ColumnSteal any enemy pieces in the same column as your piece.No</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8256">Squares</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/13/130411/1860450-quadradius_t_shirt_design.png</image></root>