<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36170</id><name>War of the Roses</name><description>SettingWar of the Roses takes place in 15th century England, during the titular period of civil war. The conflict is between the royal houses Lancaster (the red roses) and York (the white roses). This period also saw some of the earliest use of gunpowder in Western conflicts.GameplayPlayer engaged in mounted combat.The game features a variety of period-appropriate weapons, with a focus on melee (e.g. broad swords and battle axes), however, longbowmen and crossbowmen are also playable classes. Mounted combat is also possibleSingle-PlayerThe game's only single-player component is a brief tutorial that introduces mechanics found in multiplayer. Developer Fatshark originally planned to include a full single-player campaign, but the feature was dropped in development.MultiplayerIn multiplayer, each player selects a class with the ability to use certain kinds of equipment. Persistent upgrades are available for each class, including different weapons and armor.Character ClassesWar of the Roses includes four predefined profiles, each with their own unique weapons, armor and perks. Players can also unlock 4 custom profiles, which can be outfitted with any combination of weapons, armor and perks.LongbowmanEquipped with a  Longbow and an Archer's Hanger  SwordFootmanEquipped with a Castillion Sword and  shield.CrossbowmanEquipped with an Archer's Hanger sword, half shield and Steel Spanned  CrossbowFootknightEquipped with a Pollaxe and Longsword.Primary WeaponsTwo Handed Axes  ClubsTwo Handed Axes  Clubs contain a variety of powerful brute force hacking and bashing weapons as well as Billie.Hammers  Axes excel at stunning  destroying shields and plate armor alike, whereas Billie are longer reach multi-purpose tactical weapons.Attacking with the head of the weapon is a must in order to do any damage.WeaponCostDescriptionWarhammerlvl unlock 46Warhammers are fast versatile bludgeoning  piercing close range weapons.Executioner's Axelvl unlock 36The Executioner's Axe is a blazing fast high damage close range weapon. Although hard to use initially, this kind of axe is devastating once mastered.Simple Billlvl unlockSimple Bills are great long reach weapons that provide decent speed and striking power. Be sure to strike with the head of the Bill to do any damage.Pronged Billlvl unlock 4Prolonged Bills are great long reach weapons that provide decent speed, striking power and multiple damage types. Be sure to strike with the head of the Bill to do any damage.Galloglaigh Axelvl unlockGalloglaigh axes are perfect weapons for doing massive damage at a distance, but don't fare well at close ranges. Be sure to strike with the head of the axe to do any damage.Spiked Billlvl unlockSpiked Bills are great long reach weapons that provide decent speed, striking power and multiple damage types. Be sure to strike with the head of the Bill to do any damage.Pole-armsPole-arms excel at penetrating armor and striking from a distance.The longer range makes them slower  more difficult to use, but are deadly tactical weapons that deal death with multiple damage types.WeaponCostDescriptionProlonged Bill Halberdlvl unlockProlonged Bill Halberds are great extended reach weapons that provide good striking power and multiple damage types. Be sure to strike with the head of the Bill to do any damage.Peasant Pole-armlvl unlockNever underestimate an ill treated peasant. You need not sword nor axe to break the upper class. Take up you trusty rake  wield it with anger.Pollaxelvl unlockPollaxes are the most complete  technical weapons available to any warrior. Fortunately Pollaxes come with a slew of benefits like multiple damage types, the ability to stun, and high damage output. Be sure to strike with the head of the Pollaxe to do any damage.Spiked Bill Hallberdlvl unlockSpiked Bill Halberds are great extended reach weapons that provide good striking power and multiple damage types. Be sure to strike with the head of the Bill to do any damage.SpearsSpears excel in penetrating armor and striking from a distance.Their longer range makes them slower and more difficult to use, but are deadly tactical weapons once mastered.WeaponCostDescriptionBoar Spearlvl unlockBoar Spears are great long reach weapons. A fully charged thrusting attack will pierce through anything.Chiavarinalvl unlockChiavarinas are quick short spears that don't become obsolete at close melee rangesLancesUsable only on horseback, lances can easily kill with one thundering blow while traveling at full speed.Broken lances will return to your inventory over time.Two Handed SwordsTwo Handed Swords are reliable weapons of destruction capable of great slashing and piercing damage.Be mindful of trying to attack an opponent in very close proximity; these weapons perform best at medium to long distances.WeaponCostDescriptionScottish Swordlvl unlockScottish Swords are very reliable, high power weapons great for medium or long range melee.CrossbowsThe Crossbow's damage  piercing effects are more powerful than any bow's fully charged shot. Additionally, shots do not require charging. However it has very long reload times  shots need to be steadied to be accurate.Engaging with the active reload system can speed up reloading.Quarrels drop over time, be mindful of angle and distance. The angle at which a shot hits its target will affect its chance to pierce armor.BowsBows come in a variety of types from fast and less damaging "Hunting Bows" to slower and more powerful "Warbows."Arrows drop as they travel, so players must be mindful of angle and distance. The angle at which a shot hits its target will affect its chance to pierce armor.Charged shots do more damage and have better chance to pierce armor.DaggersDaggers are trusty, lightning-quick, armor-piercing tools of precision killing.Daggers are great as unbreakable last resort weapons, tactically advantageous in tight spaces, and good for harassing opponents.WeaponCostDescriptionPointy Sticklvl unlockMake the lord of the land understand your "point"!Ballock Daggerlvl unlockDaggers are great to fight with in small locations. They are great for harassing knights with their armor-piercing properties, fast strikes and ability to complete swings at very close range.PerksOffensive PerksArcherAllows your character to spawn with ranged weapons.Gives access to specialized ranged weapon perk.PerkCostDescriptionIconLongbowman2000 goldAllows your character to draw his bow faster. Nimble Minded2000 goldCrossbow active reload difficulty decreased. Increases the size of the bottom notched strip in crossbow active reload game, making it easier to actively reload. Forest Warden2000 goldReduces the penalty to movement speed while aiming with ranged weapons Sleight of Hand2000 goldFaster passive reload on all ranged weapons. Marksman Training2000 goldReduces projectile drop for bows  crossbows. Steady Aim2000 goldExtends the time your character can keep a bow drawn. Eagle Eyed2000 goldGrants 2x and 4x zoom modes to ranged weapons. Strong of Arm2000 goldFully charged shots will stay at full power for a short period of time before the charge dissipates.Man-at-armsProvides passive movement speed bonus, provides special tackle abilities and reduces melee weapon penalties.Reduces weapon penalties allows for quicker readying of swings  attack charge up times.Gives access to specialized melee related perks.PerkCostDescriptionIconHighwayman2000 goldDecreases the time it takes to switch weapons. Shield Breaker2000 goldAllows your character to deal more damage to shields. Riposte2000 goldEnables follow up attack after parry.Upon successfully parrying an opponents attack, your character's next attack will ready up  charge up considerably quicker allowing your character to make a quick counter attack.This can only be performed every 20 seconds. Break Block2000 goldAny of your fully charged attacks will force your opponent to ready another parry instead of being able to keep up their previous parry. Hamstring2000 goldAll fully charged attacks that strike the back of an enemy's legs will knock them down. Push2000 goldGrants your character the ability to push away foes. This special ability also damages and stuns your opponents. Defensive PerksArmor TrainingReduces armor encumbrance.Reduced encumbrance results in faster movement  acceleration as well as quicker readying of swings  attack charge up times.Gives access to specialized armor perks.PerkCostDescriptionIconHardened2000 goldDecreases the amount of time it takes other to revive your character. Thick Skinned2000 goldIncreases your armor's "absorption" stat. Increased damage absorption results in taking less damage from attacks that penetrate your character's armor. Regenerative2000 goldAllows you to bandage yourself more quickly than normal. Oblivious2000 goldYour character feels no pain and is immune to bleeding and other damage over time effects, but cannot use bandages on self or be bandaged.Shield BearerAllows your character to spawn with a shield.Gives access to specialized shield perks.PerkCostDescriptionIconShield Wall2000 goldMove faster while blocking. Shield Expert2000 goldSignificantly reduces the encumbrance of shields. Reduced encumbrance allows for faster movement  acceleration as well as quicker readying of swings  attack charge up time. Shield Bash2000 goldGrants your character the ability to make a shield bash. This special attack also damages and stuns your opponent.Support PerksWatchmanLowers the time it takes to capture control pointsGives access to specialized tactical support perkPerkCostDescriptionIconKeen Eyes2000 goldReveals enemy names faster. Spotter2000 goldYou are rewarded more XP than normal when teammates kill targets you've tagged. SurgeonDecreases the time it takes to bandage yourself and allies.Gives access to specialized medical support perks.PerkCostDescriptionIconSterilized Bandages2000 goldRevives  bandages give full health. Second Opinion2000 goldAllows you to see special health status icons on enemies. Barber Surgeon2000 goldYour character can revive others faster than normal. Movement PerksInfantryReduced weapon encumbrance.Reduced encumbrance of weapons results in faster movement  acceleration as well as quicker readying of swings  attack charge up times.Gives access to specialized infantry movement perks.PerkCostDescriptionIconRunner2000 goldIncreases your character's maximum "double time" speed. Field Warden2000 goldIncreases you character's jump height. City Watch2000 goldYour character can climb ladders faster than normal. Cat Burglar2000 goldAllows your character to survive falling from greater heights. Fleet Footed2000 goldIncreases movement acceleration and allows your character to reach maximum speed more quickly while changing strafe directions. CavalryEnables spawning with a horse  the horse calling ability.Gives access to specialized horse movement perks.PerkCostDescriptionIconHeavy Cavalry2000 goldAllows access to armored horses. Horse Racer2000 goldIncreases your mount's maximum speed. Horse Master2000 goldImproved acceleration  turn radius with mounts. Officer PerksOfficer TrainingAllows you character to tag objectives in addition to enemies.Selecting this perk gives access to specialized squad buffing perks.Officer training perks are only usable when your character is squad leader.PerkCostDescriptionIconReinforce Banner Bonus2000 goldDamage buff bonus for squads. Replenish Banner Bonus2000 goldAmmo regeneration buff bonus for squads. Regen Delay Banner Bonus2000 goldBandage on self speed increase for squads. Courage Banner Bonus2000 goldSmall "heal over time" effect for squads. Armor Banner Bonus2000 goldArmor buff bonus for squads. March Speed Banner Bonus2000 goldSpeed buff bonus for squads. Mounted Speed Banner Bonus2000 goldMounted movement speed buff bonus for squads. Berserker Banner Bonus2000 goldIncreases maximum health for squads at the expense of not being revivable. ArmorHeavy ArmorHeavy armor provides solid plate mail protection that completely covers your character from head to toeHeavy armor slows down your character's movement acceleration and increases penalties when changing movement directions.Heavy armor also increases the time it takes to ready up attacks, charge up attacks, and recover after missing or having your attacks blocked/parried.Suit of PlateCostDescriptionStandard0 goldStandard steel plate armor.Red Knight of Fortitude12,000 goldRed dyed steel plate armor.Green Knight of Vitality12,000 goldGreen dyed steel plate armor.Brown Knight of Experience12,000 goldBrown dyed steel plate armor.Medium ArmorMedium armor provides a thick plate mail chest guard, with mail covering the back.Cloth and leather cover your legs, arms, feet and hands respectively.Medium armor doesn't offer any distinct penalties or bonuses to movement acceleration, movement direction changing, readying up attacks, charging up attacks, missing attacks, or having your attacks blocked/ parried.Plate CuirassCostDescriptionStandard0 goldStandard plate cuirass armor.Battle Worn Rusted Brown12,000 goldBattle hardened brown dyed plate cuirass armor.Brown Warrior of Experience12,000 goldBrown dyed plate cuirass armor.Green Warrior of Vitality12,000 goldGreen dyed plate cuirass armor.Red Warrior of Fortitude12,000 goldRed dyed plate cuirass armor.Light ArmorLight armor provides a thick cloth gambeson and mail protection in the upper body. Legs and arms are merely covered by fitted cloth. Hands and feet are protected with leather.Light armor enables the fastest movement acceleration and lessens penalties when changing movement directions.Light armor also allows you to be quicker in combat by decreasing attack ready up times, charge up times, and piss penalties.Light ArmorsCostDescriptionMail Gambeson12,000 goldA mail skirt underneath a linen gambeson stuffed with flax or insulated with layers of fabric, was a standard of equipment laid down on law by the muster rolls of the 15th Century as the equipment that every man whose increase reached a set level would be expected to don. The combination of padding and mail protected the body against slashing cuts and blunt attacks alike, and gave adequate protection from missiles or thrusting attacks, for little cost.Peasant Ragslvl 30 unlockPeasant rags are made of a mish mash of wool scraps gathered from shrubs and a cheap itchy peasant invented material called linsey-woolsey. These rags were almost never laundered, but the heavy smell of wood smoke that permeated the fabric acted as deodorant, providing a unique class-defining odor.HelmetsHeavy HelmetsHelmets made of plate steel offer maximum protection, but encumber your character. Some helmets will impair your vision but do so while protecting your face from fatally wounding blows.Heavy HelmetCostDescriptionArmet0 goldThis type of Close Helm - so called for its close-fitting form, shows the distinctive workmanship of Iralian or Flemish armorers, both greatly prized in England. Sometime mounted with a wrapper, a secondary plate that gives even more protection to the face and throat, at the price of a little mobility. Such helms are mound the most effective protection available in England during the wars.Frogmouth4000 gold Medium HelmetsHelmets made of mail or plate steel offer great protection while encumbering your character a moderate amount. Some helmets will impair your vision when using a visor. Visors will protect your face from fatally wounding blows.Medium HelmetsCostDescriptionBascinet4000 gold Barbute4000 goldMade in Venerian Breseia and the Adriatic, these helmets were particularly popular throughout the Mediterranean region, where their shape was closely associated with the helms of classical Greek warriors. Small numbers were exported north as well, into Burgundy, France, and England. This helm offers an excellent compromise between the need for protection and the need for clear vision on foot.Kettlehelm Round4000 goldVarying in design back over centuries, these easily-made, segmented helmets were commonly worn by both English and French foot-soldiers of the Hundred Years War. Improvements in the armorers craft have made such kettle hats obsolete, but many still survived in armories and houses throughout England, and sill offer good protection from missiles at range. The Iralian example is particularly old-fashioned.Maille Coif4000 gold Sallet4000 gold Kettlehat4000 goldTracing its design back over centuries, this broad-brimmed helmet was commonly worn by both English and French foot-soldiers of the Hundred Years War. Improvements in the armors craft have made such kettle hats obsolete, but many remain in armories and housed throughout England, and still offered good protection from missile-fire at range. This example from the German states is quite modern, perhaps only 20 or 30 years old.Light HelmetsHelmets made of cloth  leather offer minimal protection in accordance with their materials. However, they do not weigh down you character as steel helms would.EngineWar of the Roses uses the  Bitsquid Tech engine.Deluxe EditionsThere are two deluxe editions of War of the Roses.War of the Roses: House of York Deluxe EditionHouse of York Deluxe Armor.Plate Cuirass: Warrior of York Plate CuirassRoyal Helm: Royal Helm of YorkCharge: House of York White Boar ChargeSword: Black Iron Oxide Castillion SwordCrest: Royal Honey Badger Helmet CrestOfficial soundtrack.War of the Roses: House of Lancaster Deluxe EditionPlate Cuirass: Warrior of Lancaster Plate CuirassRoyal Helm: Royal Helm of LancasterCharge: House of Lancaster Golden Lion ChargeSword: Black Iron Oxide Castillion SwordCrest: Royal Honey Badger Helmet CrestOfficial soundtrack.PC System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows Vista / Windows 7Processor: Dual Core 2.4GHz processorMemory: 4GBHard Drive: 5GBVideo Card: Shader 4.0 compatible card (minimum: Nvidia GeForce 9800,AMD Radeon 4830)Graphics Memory: 512MBDirectX: Direct3D 11 compatible cardOnboard Integrated Video Card not supportedMinimumOS: Windows Vista / Windows 7Processor: Quad Core Intel or AMD processorMemory: 4GBHard Drive: 5GBGraphics Card: Shader 4.0 compatible card (recommended: Nvidia GeForce 460, AMD Radeon 5870Graphics Card Memory: 1GBDirectX: Direct3D 11 compatible cardOnboard Integrated Video Card Not Supported</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21192">Mount &amp; Blade</game><game id="25622">Mount &amp; Blade: Warband</game><game id="34889">Mount and Blade: With Fire &amp; Sword</game><game id="27769">Lead and Gold: Gangs of the Wild West</game><game id="38006">Chivalry: Medieval Warfare</game><game id="1567">Die by the Sword</game><game id="14344">Dark Messiah of Might and Magic: Elements</game><game id="24003">Age of Chivalry</game><game id="22142">Darkfall</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2323889-box_wotr.png</image></root>