<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36242</id><name>To the Moon</name><description>OverviewTo the Moon is a visual novel / adventure game released on November 1st, 2011 as a digital release on the website of Freebird Games. On the website you can also find the trial version in which you can play one hour of the game for free. The game was created using RPG Maker VX.StoryThe story is the main focus of the game and features a very emotional and layered narrative which is unraveled while playing through the game. The theme of the game bears similarities to the movie "Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind": traveling through someone's memories and their relationship with a loved one. The seriousness of the overall plot is often alternated with light-hearted comments from the two protagonists. It took the creator of To The Moon, Kan R. Gao, five years to complete To The Moon.Description Of The GameDr. Eva Rosalene and Dr. Neil Watts have rather peculiar jobs: They give people another chance to live, all in their head. But due to the severity of the operation, the new life becomes the last thing the patients remember before drawing their last breath.This story follows their attempt to fulfill the dream of an elderly man, Johnny. With each step back in time, a new fragment of Johnny's past is revealed. As the two doctors piece together the puzzled events that spanned a life time, they seek to find out just why the frail old man chose his dying wish to be what it is.And Johnny's last wish is, of course... to go to the moon.GameplayWhile the game is described as an Adventure\RPG, the RPG part only applies to the art direction which is very reminiscent of the 16-bit RPGs such as Chrono Trigger. The gameplay itself mostly consists of acquiring the mementos necessary to travel to the next memory, driving the story along. There's no action in the game as it's mostly known for it's emotional storytelling. As homage to its JRPG-esque art design, one scene in the beginning allows you the option to enter into battle with a squirrel.Aside from acquiring mementos through pixel-hunting, there are a number of origami puzzles requiring you to turn each square of a grid the same way in order to complete a picture. Each puzzle describes an "ideal" number of moves through which to complete the puzzle, however there is no penalty for going over.In total the game offers about 5 hours of gameplay.SoundtrackThe game features an original sound track by Kan R. Gao (featuring Laura Shigihara) consisting of 31 tracks, most of which are piano pieces. The soundtrack can be listened to and purchased via Freebird's website.Track ListingTo The Moon's soundtrack cover.To the Moon - Main Theme 04:56Between a Squirrel and a Tree 01:18Spiral of Secrets 01:06For River - Piano (Sarah  Tommy's Version) 02:58Bestest Detectives in the World 01:15Too Bad So Sad 00:08Teddy 00:42Uncharted Realms 01:08Having Lived 01:21Moonwisher 02:10Born a Stranger 01:41For River - Piano (Johnny's Version) 01:39Lament of a Stranger 01:05Everything's Alright (Music Box) 00:40Moongazer 02:15Anya by the Stars 02:15Take Me Anywhere 00:59Warning (AKA best track ever) 00:09Beta-B 01:06World's Smallest Ferris Wheel 00:35Once Upon a Memory 02:25Once Upon a Memory (Piano) 01:35Laura Shigihara - Everything's Alright 03:25Everything's Alright (Reprise) 00:58Tomorrow 02:10Launch 01:57To the Moon - Piano (Ending Version) 05:15Eva's Ringtone 00:04Trailer Theme - Part 1 01:43Trailer Theme - Part 2 (feat. Laura Shigihara) 01:49Trailer Theme - Part 2 (Instrumental) 02:00ReceptionAt the time of writing, the reception of the game has been largely positive. Gamespot declared To The Moon to be one of 2011's best 25 PC Games.PC System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows XPProcessor: Intel Pentium 4 @ 1.5 GHz / AMD Athlon XP 1500+Memory: 64 MbHard Drive: 100 Mb freeVideo Memory: 64 MbVideo Card: DirectX CompatibleSound Card: DirectX CompatibleDirectX: 9.0cKeyboardMouseRecommendedOS: Windows XP/Vista/7Processor: Intel Pentium 4 @ 2.0 GHz / AMD Athlon XP 2200+Memory: 1 GbHard Drive: 100 Mb freeVideo Memory: 128 MbVideo Card: nVidia GeForce FX 5500 / ATI Radeon 9500Sound Card: DirectX CompatibleDirectX: 9.0cKeyboardMouse</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21752">RPG Maker VX</game><game id="33120">Melolune</game><game id="42526">Helen - Castle In Wonderland</game><game id="43488">Postmortem</game><game id="39854">Brothers: A Tale of Two Sons</game><game id="21406">Fragile Dreams:  Farewell Ruins of the Moon</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/15/155745/2550621-8260917012-jaque.jpg</image></root>