<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3626</id><name>The Last Express</name><description>OverviewThe Last Express is a       point-and-click adventure game that takes place on a European train traveling through Europe shortly before the outbreak of      World War I. The Last Express was created by        Jordan Mechner and        Smoking Car Productions and it was released in 1997. The entire game takes place on the Orient Express in what appears to be real time, with each important choice resulting in one of many endings, most of which resulting in the main character dying or being arrested by the police. At the time, the game was the most expensive game ever produced. Unfortunately, it was a commercial disappointment, despite many positive reviews and an impressive pre-release response. StoryThe Last Express features a large cast of characters      In the game you take control of        Robert Cath, an American doctor on the train's final journey from    Paris to Constantinople (know today as     Istanbul) before   World War I. Cath, already wanted by the French Police as a suspect of the  murder of an Irish police officer, is contacted by an old friend        Tyler Whitney through an urgent message in a letter to join him on the Orient Express. The said letter states that there is a possible exit from all of his troubles. Cath boards the train via a motorcycle while it was traveling from one station to another. As soon as Cath boars the luxurious train, he finds Whitney dead, killed by someone else on board the train. To blend in, he disposes of Whitney's body and takes his place, becoming involved in a web of treachery, lies, political conspiracies, personal interests, romance and murder.Soundtrack         The soundtrack, composed by Elia Cmiral, was published by Intrada Records on June 6, 2000.The Last Express - Original Game Soundtrack (Elia Cmiral)No.Track TitleLength (38:42)1."Departure"2:502."The Golden Egg"1:313."A Woman Traveling Alone"1:184."Anna and Cath"0:555."Retribution in Vienna"1:016."Duel Atop the Train"1:547."Nightmare"1:318."Pursuit"2:039."Tatiana"0:5510."Kronos' Sanctum"2:1511."Death of Alexei"2:4712."Goodbye, August"1:0713."Joyride"1:1114."A Loyal Friend"1:1215."Death of Milos"0:4116."Stop the Train"0:5017."The Dream Shattered"0:4718."Defying Kronos"1:0619."Anna"1:0620."A Narrow Escape"1:3221."Runaway Train"1:5322."Battle with Salko"1:2223."Tsardas / The Firebird"1:1124."War"2:5725."End Titles"2:46</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3181">Burn: Cycle</game><game id="16298">The 7th Guest</game><game id="24845">A Vampyre Story 2: A Bat's Tale</game><game id="43488">Postmortem</game><game id="42346">The Raven</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3817/391090-964826116_00.jpg</image></root>