<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36283</id><name>Go! Go! Nippon! ~My First Trip to Japan~</name><description>OverviewGo! Go! Nippon! was developed by Overdrive and released by MangaGamer on September 30th, 2011 as an Original English Language Visual Novel (OELVN) that caters to players outside of Japan.PlotOur protagonist is a fan of Japanese anime and games. He makes friends with some Japanese people on the internet, and decides to stay with them for a week.Thrilled by the prospect of a week's sightseeing in Japan, he touches down in the airport, only to discover that his new friends -- "Makoto" and "Akira" -- are actually a pair of attractive young sisters!After their introductions, the protagonist arrives at their house to learn that no one else is there."Um... where are your parents?""Our parents were called out of town for two weeks on urgent business."(In other words, the only ones in the house will be Makoto, Akira, and I?)(How is that going to work!?)The local culture has some surprises in store on your first night there, but you'll soon head out on the town! Enjoy the date-like atmosphere as Makoto and Akira take you on a tour of famous sites. You'll marvel at the beauty and history of Japanese culture, fill up on local delicacies, and even share some thrilling moments with the girls!The week you spend in Japan will certainly be memorable!GameplayGo! Go! Nippon! is designed as a guide to Japan told in a visual novel form with a touch of romance. It takes place over the course of a week. The player can choose the destination for the first 3 days. The 4th and 5th days are spent at Kyoto and the 6th day is determined by the girl who the player is closer to.FeaturesThe dialogue is displayed in both English and Japanese languages.System RequirementsRequired CPU:Pentium 4 1.4GHzRecommended CPU:Pentium 4 2GHzRequired Memory:256MBRecommended Memory:384MBRequired Resolution:800x600Required Colors:16bit colorsRecommended Colors:24bit colorsRequired Graphics:64MB VRAMRecommended Graphics:128MB VRAMRequired HDD Free Space:400MBDirectX:DirectX 9.0c</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="8">Educational</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/24960/2115682-f19b7ff9_56ae_40e6_a390_abd49d7f126c.png</image></root>