<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36297</id><name>All Zombies Must Die!</name><description>OverviewAll Zombies Must Die! is an action game developed by doublesix and published by Square Enix for the PC, Xbox Live Arcade, and PS3 Network platforms.Four players (a gamer, a girl, an alien, and a mad scientist) are all that stands between billions of zombies and a near-endless supply of delicious brains. The game drops the players into the town of Deadhill, USA where they must use a variety of weaponry to fight off hungry zombies. Players also complete quests that correspond to the game's fantastical plot. This game includes elements of action, role playing, character levelling, crafting weapons, and challenging quests. Bright, comic-style graphics complement the zany characters and insane theme.StoryThe story begins with the town being overrun with zombies and Jack, the Gamer, being hassled by his ex-girlfriend. He even suspects he's in a videogame, and he might not even be the protagonist. Jack has to get through the day and escape the town, but he can't do it by himself. He has to join forces with his ex-girlfriend and anyone else that will help him to survive!CharactersJack, The GamerDefault prefered weapon: ShotgunUtility element: FireRachel, The GirlDefault prefered weapon: UziUtility element: SonicBrian, The GeekDefault prefered weapon: RevolverUtility element: RadiationLuxo, The AlienDefault prefered weapon: Ray GunUtility element: ShockCraftingThe game features a robust crafting system that allows the various weapons to be imbued with four different environmental modifiers, such as fire or radioactivity. Each modifier then has a different effect on a zombie, as listed below. Each modifier also has a more potent variation, unlocked later in the game, that has a stronger effect.Fire: Chance on weapon to burn a zombie, dealing extra damage for a few secondsSonic: Zombies will stand still as they're paralyzed with sound for a moment. Causes a slight increase in size.Radiation: Occasionally transforms a Zombie into a Mutant.Shock: Zombies are momentarily stunned.Health: Steals health from the zombies.The game also features a number of weapons that can be unlocked throughout the game's progression, with every weapon being able to be imbued with a modifier.ChainsawCricket BatShotgunAssault RifleUziRevolverRay GunSwordThe utility item that each character always has can also be upgraded once to a more effective version of itself. This is done in much the same manner as creating the tool the first time, with the only difference being that you use the more powerful item in the combination.SkillsEach character has four skills that can be upgraded as the player levels up. Skills require that a certain number of points be attributed to them before leveling up. Each character needs a different number of points for each skill, depending on their strengths and weaknesses. Skills may need as low as three points or as many as six to be upgraded. Five points are given upon each level earned. Characters are upgraded separately, but do not need to be leveled up individually.AttackDefenseHealthSpeedPC System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Windows XP SP3 (32 bit only)Processor: 2.0 GHzMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: Shader Model 3.0DirectX®: 9Hard Drive: 256 MB HD spaceRecommended:OS:Windows 7Processor: 2.0 GHzMemory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: Shader Model 3.0DirectX®: 9Hard Drive: 1 GB HD space</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="31">Dual-Joystick Shooter</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="24253">Burn Zombie Burn!</game><game id="16116">Zombies Ate My Neighbors</game><game id="16760">Ghoul Patrol</game><game id="37228">Dead Meets Lead</game><game id="38058">All Zombies Must Die!: Scorepocalypse</game><game id="38099">Tiny Troopers</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2092585-box_azmd.png</image></root>