<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36334</id><name>Deponia</name><description>OverviewDeponia is a PC and Mac point and click adventure game developed by Daedalic Entertainment. The German version of the game was released on January 27, 2012; in English speaking regions, the game was released on August 7, 2012.StoryRufus - the game's protagonist.The first of a planned trilogy, Deponia is a point-and-click adventure game that follows Rufus, an egotistical outcast whose dream of leaving the trash planet of Deponia and reaching the shining world above of Elysium has made him the outcast and resident jerk of his hometown; however, when his latest attempt results in an enigmatic yet beautiful Elysian girl called Goal falling down in Deponia, Rufus sees his chance to make his dream come true, unaware that he's about to dive into an adventure that might not only determine the fate of a world and tie him and Goal's destinies together, but end up changing himself forever.GameplayThe inventory screen.Deponia follows the classic point-and-click adventure game interface, but with a simpler implementation; an inventory screen allows access to items at all times, and is used to combine items together. Most items can be interacted upon with a single left mouse click, while alternative actions (subject to the item or character currently being selected by the cursor) can be triggered with a right mouse click. Most puzzles are based on combining items together or using them with other interactive markers in each location. Interactive points on-screen, be they items, characters or objects can be highlighted with a single press of the space bar.Deponia also includes several puzzles based on patterns and combination, but these can be optionally skipped if the player chooses to do so.PC System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows XPProcessor: 2.5 GHz (Single Core) or 2 GHz (Dual Core)Memory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: OpenGL 2.0 compatible with 512 MB RAMDirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 5 GB HD spaceSound: DirectX compatibleRecommendedOS: Windows Vista/7Processor: 2.5 GHz (Single Core) or 2 GHz (Dual Core)Memory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: OpenGL 2.0 compatible with 512 MB RAMDirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 5 GB HD spaceSound: DirectX compatible</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="31979">Edna &amp; Harvey: The Breakout</game><game id="32796">Tales of Monkey Island</game><game id="22111">The Whispered World</game><game id="37503">The Dark Eye: Chains of Satinav</game><game id="3460">Discworld</game><game id="40113">Edna &amp; Harvey: Harvey's New Eyes</game><game id="41730">The Night of the Rabbit</game><game id="43556">Memoria</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/97089/2102771-box.jpg</image></root>