<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36373</id><name>Pokémon Trading Card Game Online</name><description>OverviewPokémon Trading Card Game Online is a collectible card game developed by Nintendo and published by The Pokémon Company. Pokémon Trading Card Game Online was a browser based online collectible card game that eventually changed into being a downloadable client. Playing the Pokémon Trading Card Game Online requires a free registration. Pokémon Trading Card Game Online can be downloaded at the following website: http://www.pokemontcg.com/GameplayPokémon Trading Card Game Online plays exactly like the real world counter-part. Players use a deck of cards and battle their opponents, which can be a computer controlled opponent or another human.Avatar CreationThe appearance editorWhen first playing Pokémon Trading Card Game Online an online avatar can be created. The first to be created is the avatars appearance. There are eight different editable appearance categories with multiple options contained in each. The eight different appearance categories are:Face ShapeSkin ColorEyesHairNoseMouthEyebrowsFacial HairHat SelectionAfter the appearance has been set there is another layer to the avatar creation. The next step in creating an avatar is to select the various clothing and accessory options. There are five different categories of clothing options. The five categories of clothing are:TopsBottomsShoesHatsAccessoriesOnce both of these main parts of avatar creation are done the avatar creating process is complete. Other clothing and accessories can be unlocked either through the in-game purchasing or through unlock codes found in packs of the real world cards and sets.TutorialsThe Tutorials TeacherThere are several tutorials available to help a new player learn how to play the game. The twelve tutorials are broken down into three different categories: Basic Skills, Intermediate Skills, and Advanced Skills. The tutorials are all voice acted with a teacher character explaining the various concepts. The skills in each category are:Basic SkillsIntermediate SkillsAdvanced SkillsEnergyPokemon EvolutionsTrainer Cards Save the DayBattle!Weakness  ResistanceRetreating Your PokemonPrize Cards  Winning the GameYou're in the Hot SeatPoke Powers  Poke BodiesIntro to Special ConditionsSpecial Conditions in ActionSetup  First TurnTrainer ChallengeThe League Challenge Screen in the no longer existing browser version of Pokemon TCGOTrainer Challenge is the single player component to Pokemon Trading Card Game Online. Once the Trainer Challenge tab has been clicked on the player will be taken to the league games screen.In this mode there are three different basic decks that can be used: Basic Blue, Basic Red, and Basic Green. You could also use physical theme decks you've purchased in real life by inputting the code inside the box. (However, older theme decks do not come with codes.)Play Online!Clicking on Play Online! will go to the main hub for playing Pokémon Trading Card Game Online. On the main Play Online! screen there is an option to chat with other online players.Play Online! SectionImage of sectionChat[Unavailable in current version of Pokemon Trading Card Game Online.]On the main page of the Play Online! section there is a chat box. In the chat box players from all around the world can chat in various rooms.The Chat WindowAnnouncementsThe Announcements box is where various announcements about the game from the development team are displayed.The Announcement Box (empty)Collection[Unavailable in current version of Pokemon Trading Card Game Online.]The Collection icon takes the player to their entire collection of cards. The types of cards displayed can be narrowed down. There are different categories of cards which can be displayed or sorted, these categories include:Pokemon - Any of the element types, Stage 1, Stage 2, or LEGEND can be selected in the sub-menu.Trainers - Item, Supporter, and Stadium can be selected from the sub-menu.Energy - Basic and Special can be selected from the sub-menu.Attack Cost - Any of the energy card types can be chosen as can the numbers of 1 through 5 can be chosen in the sub-menu.Retreat Cost - Any of the numbers of 1 through 5 can be chosen in the sub-menu.Collector - Common, Uncommon, Rare, Holo-Rare, and Foils can be chosen from the sub-menu.Set - Any of the various card sets can be chosen in the sub-menu.Trading - My for Trade, My Wanted, and Their Wanted can be selected from the sub-menu.If you have redeemed a booster pack or deck or other product, the collection is where you must go to open them, as well as view acquired items such as play coins.The Collection ButtonDeck Builder[Unavailable in current version of Pokemon Trading Card Game Online.]The Deck Builder icon takes the player to the Deck Builder section. The main deck builder screen is split into two windows, one for the currently opened, the other for the player's collection. Cards can be simply dragged between the collection window into the deck window to add it to the current deck.The deck window will display the number of cards total in the deck, how many of them are Pokemon, Trainers, and Energies. In the deck screen there are also options to start a new deck, open an existing deck, save the current deck, and display a printable version of the deck.The Deck Builder ButtonTrading[Unavailable in current version of Pokemon Trading Card Game Online.]The Trading icon takes the player to the trading section. The trading section looks much like the deck building section. The difference between this section and the deck building section is that the bottom screen is for cards to trade.The first step is to choose a partner from a drop down list of players currently online. After selecting a trade partner the cards for trading are drug down from the top screen to the bottom screen.The Trading ButtonMultiplayer[Unavailable in current version of Pokemon Trading Card Game Online.]The multiplayer games are actually broken up into two different buttons. The first button, multiplayer expert game will take the player to an expert game lobby. In the lobby the currently used deck can be chosen, the chat window can be used, and a list of previously played games by people online are displayed. Once the find game button is clicked the matchmaking will kick in and find another expert opponent.The set up in the multiplayer novice game are the same, except the player will be connected with another player who is matchmaking in the novice category.The Multiplayer ButtonsSingle PlayerJust like the multiplayer section, the single player section is actually broken up into two buttons. The first single player button takes the player to the Trainer Challenge screen.The second single player button takes the player to a game that works in a similar way to a multi player match, except the player it finds in matchmaking is an A.I. player.The Single Player ButtonsUnavailable FeaturesAs of January 16th, 2012 the game is still in an open beta. Since the game is in open beta it is currently missing some features. The currently missing features are:Tournament ModeFriends ListTrade With FriendsMultiplayer Match With FriendsBecause the game has been reverted to a downloadable client instead of a browser game, some core features are currently inaccessible and are to be re-added at a later time:MultiplayerCollectionDeck BuilderChat</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="13">Card Game</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="23550">Yu-Gi-Oh! Online</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/10/103881/2106392-tcgologo.png</image></root>