<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3641</id><name>007: From Russia with Love</name><description>OverviewWelcome back to the 1960's, Mr. Bond.007: From Russia With Love is a third-person shooter developed by EA Redwood Shores and published by Electronic Arts for the Xbox and PlayStation 2 on November 1, 2005 (and later for the GameCube on November 15, 2005). It was later ported to the PSP on April 3, 2006 by Rebellion. Part of the James Bond franchise of video games, players reprise the role of 1960's suave secret agent James Bond (featuring the likeness and voice acting of Sean Connery) as they play through a re-imagining of the 1963 film From Russia With Love (which was based on the 1957 novel From Russia, With Love).The main plot of the game involves James Bond undergoing an elaborate theft of a Soviet encoding machine (known as the Lektor) in Turkey with the help of a defecting Soviet agent, Tatiana Romanova. However, they are unaware that they are being manipulated by the global terrorist organization OCTOPUS (named SPECTRE in the movie and novel), mainly from ex-KGB agent Rosa Klebb and her trained assassin, Donald "Red" Grant.GameplayBond using his jetpack007: From Russia with Love is in a minority among modern James Bond games, being as it is a third-person shooter. The game features an auto-aim for easier targeting, and several missions are heavily focussed around the use of machine-gun equipped jetpacks. In addition the game includes a handful of vehicular combat missions in Bond's icon Aston Martin DB5, (a car that didn't actually debut until the 1964 film Goldfinger), and a couple of on-rail shooting segments in which James takes control of a gun turret mounted on the back of a boat.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13700">24: The Game</game><game id="6530">007: Everything or Nothing</game><game id="2242">The Punisher</game><game id="10853">Freedom Fighters</game><game id="8201">Lara Croft Tomb Raider: Anniversary</game><game id="16559">007: Agent Under Fire</game><game id="20614">Star Wars Battlefront: Renegade Squadron</game><game id="10543">Virtua Cop</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1841793-box_frwl.png</image></root>