<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36612</id><name>Cardinal Quest</name><description>OverviewCardinal Quest is a roguelike game developed and published by TameTick for the PC, Mac, iPhone, iPad, and Android platforms. There are three playable classes to choose from. StoryThe dread minotaur Asterion fell upon the peaceful town of Hallemot late one balmy night. The few townfolk he did not kill, he made his slaves. Their misery is his delight.Years have passed. Deep in his underground den, he and his minions exult in the spoils of their wicked deeds. They revel in human suffering.You fled when you were young. You grew strong. The time has come to rid the land of his dominion. ClassesFighterA mighty warrior of unparalleled strength and vigor, honorable in battle, high master of hack-n-slash melee.The best choice for new players.ThiefA cunning and agile rouge whose one moral credo is this: Always get out alive.The most challenging character - use his speed and skills to avoid taking damage.WizardA wise safe, knower of secrets, worker of miracles, master of the arcane arts, fantastic barista.Can cast spells rapidly - use his mystic powers as often as possible. InventoryThe mechanics of the game differ from games like Dungeons of Dredmore and Hack, slash and loot as the player almost doesn't have to worry about managing his inventory and spells. The game decides on itself if equipment is better than currently equipped. If better, it equips it automatically and sells the old stuff. If it is about the same, it puts it in your little inventory where you can sell it yourself. SpellsEach class starts with 1 spell but can find more within the dungeon, 5 spells can be equipped at a time, although more spells can be placed into the inventory.Column HeadColumn HeadFireball*Hurls a ball of fire that explodes on impact.Berserk**Induces a berserked rage that greatly increases your strength and speed.Recharged by your Attack stat.Shadow Walk***Renders you invisible for a few seconds.Recharged by your Speed stat.Reveal MapReveals the layout of the current floor.Enfeeble MonsterWeakens monsters and renders them less dangerous.FreezeSlows a monster down for a short duration.Magic ArmorEngulfs you in a magical protective aura.HealRestores health and vigor.Recharged by gaining XP.HasteMakes you faster and more nimble.BlinkTransport you to a random location.PolymorphTransform a create into another form.Stone SkinHardens your skin, rendering you tough but slow.FearMakes a monster flee in horror.Magic MirrorCreates a duplicate of yourself to draw enemies away.* Wizard starting spell.** Fighter starting spell.*** Thief starting spell. StatsThe following stats will automatically be improved every time the player levels up by acquiring enough experience points. The players health will also refill after a level-up.HealthHow many hit points your character has.AttackHow much damage your character does.DefenseReduces damage your character takes.SpeedIncreases your chances of dodging attack.SpiritHow quickly spells rechargeVitalityReduces chance of being affected by poison MapThe player always starts the game with a map of each level of the dungeon. The map shows all the rooms, doors, treasure chest locations and the stairs to the next floor.The Reveal Map spell will show everything on the map for you without having to explore the map yourself. FloorsThe objective of each floor is to locate the stairs which lead down to the next floor. There are 8 floors in total, each one harder than the last. The final floor has a boss fight with the evil minotaur Asterion. PotionsHealing PotionA small vial containing a fragrant, red salve. It restores life when applied.Full heal.Mana PotionA refreshing draught which charges spells and sets nerves tingling.full chargeElixir of Elephant HideThis elixir temporarily protects the drinker's body with a thick hide.+6 defense.Elixir of Tiger StrikeThis elixir temporarily grants ultra-human strength and reflexes.2 damage multiplier+3 attackEspresso ElixirThis mysterious beverage grants great speed when quaffed.+6 speed. EquipmentThere are 6 slots to equip items on your character, torso, helmet, boots, weapon, ring and gloves.Torso Leather ArmorThis armor us made of leather that was boiled in wax for extra toughness.+1 defense.BreastplateThis iron breastplate offers excellent protection to vital organs without limiting mobility.+2 defense. Helmet Cap of EnduranceThis steel skullcap protects the head without restricting the wearer's ability to wear fashionable hats.+1 life.Superb Cap of EnduranceThis steel skullcap protects the head without restricting the wearer's ability to wear fashionable hats.+2 life.Boots Boots of EscapeThese finely crafted leather boots allow the wearer to run with great speed.+1 speed.Hermes' SandalsThese winged sandals are made of imperishable gold and allow the wearer to move as swiftly as any bird.+2 speed.Weapon DaggerA double-edged blade used for stabbing or thrusting.1-2 damage.Short SwordA one handed hilt attached to a thrusting blade approximately 60cm in length.1 - 3 damage.StaffA sturdy shaft of hardwood with metal tips.1 - 3 damage.+1 spirit.Magical Staff A sturdy shaft of hardwood with metal tips.1 - 3 damage.+1 attack.+1 spirit.Long SwordLong swords have long cruciform hilts with grips and double-edged blades over one meter long.2 - 4 damage.Accessories Ring of WisdomThis small, silver ring imbues its wearer with uncanny wisdom.+1 spirit.Amulet of EnlightenmentEnlightenment permeates this simple looking amulet, granting its wearer the spirit of the gods.+2 spirit.Gloves Gloves of DexterityThe swiftness of these hand gloves allows their wearer to perform faster in battle.+1 attack.Achilles' BracerThis magical bronze bracer contains within it the great warrior's spirit.+2 attack. SoundtrackThe game has an original soundtrack created by Whitaker Trebella, and can be purchased from the Cardinal Quest: Original Soundtrack band camp page. Track listingTrack NameTrack TimeHallemot Suffers02:15Hero's Defeat00:09The Quest Begins03:16Woods02:09Forbade03:38An Arduous Undertaking02:43Cave03:08What is this Place?02:14Kill the Minotaur01:34The End of Asterion00:13Satsuma Audio - A Basstastic Undertaking03:28Disasterpiece - The Cardinal03:38Joe Cavers - A Break in the Journey03:16Charlie McCarron - Ghosts of Hallemot02:06Cain German - A Hard Trip03:47some1namedjeff - The World After Asterion05:49  </description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22309">Rogue</game><game id="35423">Dungeons of Dredmor</game><game id="39560">MiniFlake</game><game id="41686">Cardinal Quest II</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/10/103881/2257755-cardinalquest.1.jpg</image></root>