<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36661</id><name>Tiger Woods PGA Tour 13</name><description>OverviewKinect FeaturesTiger Woods PGA Tour 13 continues to focus on The Masters tournament after the previous installment introduced Augusta National Golf Club to the franchise. This year's title features fourteen other championship courses including The Old Course at St. Andrews, Pebble Beach Golf Links, and TPC Sawgrass. The collector's edition features an additional set of courses bringing the total to twenty-one.After a couple years of PlayStation 3 players being able to play the game with PlayStation Move, Xbox 360 players now have the ability to play using motion and voice controls via Kinect.The Masters Collector's EditionTitled as "EA Sports Masters Collector's Edition," this special version of Tiger Woods PGA Tour 13 features several exclusive bonuses.Six additional championship courses.Green Jacket ceremony.Ability to walk the grounds of Augusta National Golf Club.Exclusive pro shop equipment.Pre-Order BonusesAmazon - Sports Celebrity Golfer PackMarshall Faulk (NFL Hall of Fame Running Back)Dwight Howard (NBA Center for the Orlando Magic)Sugar Ray Leonard (Boxing Legend)Jeremy Roenick (NHL Legend)Best Buy - Emerald Dragon Golf CourseOrder from Best Buy and receive this fantasy course located by Japan's Mt. Fuji.GameStop - Wolf Creek Country ClubOrder from GameStop or EB Games and receive this extra course located in Mesquite, Nevada.Courses#CourseIncludedNewLocation1Atlanta Athletic ClubDLCNoJohns Creek, Georgia2Augusta National Golf ClubOn-DiscNoAugusta, Georgia3Augusta National Golf Club - Par 3 CourseCE / DLCNoAugusta, Georgia4Banff Springs Golf CourseDLCNoAlberta, Canada5Bethpage State Park - Black CourseOn DiscNoBethpage, Long Island, New York6Celtic Manor Resort - Twenty Ten CourseOn-DiscNoNewport, South Wales7Costa Navarino - The Dunes CourseDLCNoCosta Navarino, Greece8Crooked Stick Golf ClubOn-DiscYesCarmel, Indiana9East Lake Golf ClubOn-DiscNoAtlanta, Georgia10The Els ClubOn-DiscNoDubai, United Arab Emirates11Emerald Dragon (Fantasy)Pre-Order / DLCNoMt. Fuji, Japan12The Greek Isles (Fantasy)DLCNoGreece13The Highlands (Fantasy)DLCNoScotland14Liberty National Golf ClubDLCNoJersey City, New Jersey15Oakmont Country ClubCE / DLCNoPittsburgh, Pennsylvania16The Ocean Course at Kiawah IslandOn-DiscYesKiawah Island, South Carolina17The Old Course at St. AndrewsOn-DiscNoSaint Andrews, Scotland18The Old White TPCCE / DLCNoSulphur Springs, West Virginia19Pebble Beach Golf LinksOn-DiscNoPebble Beach, California20PGA National Resort  Spa - The Champion CourseCE / DLCYesPalm Beach Gardens, Florida21Pinehurst No. 2CE / DLCNoPinehurst, North Carolina22The Predator (Fantasy)DLCNoBelize23River Course at Blackwolf RunDLCNoKohler, Wisconsin24Royal Birkdale Golf CourseOn-DiscYesSouthport, England25Royal County Down Golf CourseOn-DiscYesNewcastle, County Down, Northern Ireland26Royal Melbourne Golf ClubOn-DiscNoMelbourne, Australia27Spyglass Hill Golf CourseDLCNoPebble Beach, California28TPC San Antonio - ATT Oaks CourseDLCNoCibolo Canyon, Texas29TPC SawgrassOn-DiscNoPonte Verda Beach, Florida30TPC Scottsdale - Stadium CourseOn-DiscNoScottsdale, Arizona31Torrey Pines Golf CourseOn-DiscNoSan Diego, California32Valhalla Golf ClubOn-DiscYesLouisville, Kentucky33Waialae Country ClubDLCNoHonolulu, Hawai'i34Whistling StraitsCE / DLCNoSheboygan, Wisconsin35Wolf Creek Country ClubPre-Order / DLCNoMesquite, NevadaGolfers#NameNewAgeFrom1Paul CaseyNo34Cheltenham, Gloucestershire, England2Ben CraneYes35Portland, Oregon3Paula CreamerNo25Windermere, Florida4Rhys DaviesNo26Edinburgh, Scotland5Luke DonaldNo34Hemel Hempstead, Hertfordshire, England6Ross FisherYes31Ascot, Berskhire, England7Jim FurykNo41West Chester, Pennsylvania8Natalie GulbisNo29Sacramento, California9Dustin JohnsonYes27Columbia, South Carolina10Zach JohnsonNo36Iowa City, Iowa11Rickie FowlerNo23Anaheim, California12Hunter MahanYes29Orange, California13Graeme McDowellYes32Portrush, Northern Ireland14Rory McIlroyNo22Holywood, County Down, Northern Ireland15Rocco MediateNo49Greensburg, Pennsylvania16Edoardo MolinariNo31Turin, Italy17Ian PoulterNo36Hitchin, Hertfordshire18Justin RoseNo31Johannesburg, South Africa19Adam ScottNo31Adelaide, Australia20Bubba WatsonNo33Bagdad, Florida21Boo WeekleyNo38Milton, Florida22Tiger WoodsNo36Cypress, CaliforniaCover AthletesIn October 2011, EA Sports launched a three week, 16-player tournament on Facebook where fans could vote on which golfer would appear alongside Tiger Woods on the cover of the game in their respective region.Week 1Week 2Week 3NA WinnerEU WinnerWeek 3Week 2Week 1Dustin JohnsonLuke DonaldD. JohnsonL. DonaldRocco MediateRoss FisherR. FowlerL. DonaldJim FurykIan PoulterR. FowlerI. PoulterRickie FowlerPaul CaseyR. FowlerR. McIlroyBubba WatsonGraeme McDowellB. WatsonG. McDowellZach JohnsonJustin RoseB. WatsonR. McIlroyHunter MahanRory McIlroyH. MahanR. McIlroyBen CraneEdoardo Molinari</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="28">Golf</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2146388-box_twpgat13.png</image></root>