<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3667</id><name>WWF Wrestlemania 2000</name><description>GameplayWWF Wrestlemania 2000 used the AKI engine, previously seen in the studios prior wrestling games under the WCW brand ( WCW/nWo: World Tour and WCW/nWo Revenge) and as a result used many of the same buttons to perform the same moves. The D-pad is used to move, the control stick taunts, and the c-buttons can run and change targets. L dodges and R blocks. Pressing these at the last possible moment before being attacked initiates a counter move. A and B can grapple and strike respectively. Holding the buttons down perform stronger versions. After grappling, the player can use A or B and the d-pad to attempt different moves. These can be reversed with the R button.In the match itself, there is no health bar, but the wrestlers will begin to slouch, limp or hold a damaged limb. There is a momentum meter, however, which pulses more brightly and harder as moves and taunts are performed and gets slower and duller as damage is inflicted. Once the meter is maximized, a taunt will bring the wrestler into a sort of "rage" mode in which they can't be pinned or made to submit, their moves do significantly more damage and they can perform their devastating finisher.ModesThe game featured a prominent story mode which had no branching storyline, but accurately recorded wins and losses rather than having the match won or lost based on the plot. The story generally followed the major story lines of WWF television leading up to the previous WrestleMania.There is also an Exhibition Mode, in which any match may be set up with any wrestlers. The matches include standard wrestling fare, though it was notable at the time for including a Cage Match and a First Blood, as neither of the WCW games had either.It is the also first western THQ wrestling game to feature a create-a-wrestler mode rather than a simple costume change. The mode is extensive, allowing customization of appearance, taunts, entrances and a move-set. Once a wrestler is created, the player can enter them in the Story Mode. The create-a-wrestler mode also allows the default wrestlers' costumes to be edited with four different templates for alternate costumes (or in the case of Mankind, alternate wrestlers) with the same moves. The default wrestlers' moves couldn't be changed.There is even a create-a-belt feature in which you design the look of a belt and put them up for grabs in Exhibition matches. Up to ten belts can be created and customized.Playable RosterAl SnowBig Boss ManThe Big ShowThe Blue MeanieBradshawBrian ChristopherChazChris JerichoChristianChynaDebraD'Lo BrownDrozEdgeFaarooqGangrelGerald BriscoThe GodfatherHardcore HollyIvoryJacquelineJeff HardyJeff JarrettJerry "The King" LawlerJim RossKaneKen ShamrockMankind / Cactus Jack / Dude LoveMark HenryMatt HardyMeatMichael HayesMideonMr. AssPat PattersonPaul BearerPrince AlbertRoad DoggThe RockScott TaylorShane McMahonShawn MichaelsStephanie McMahonSteve BlackmanStone Cold Steve AustinTerri RunnelsTestThrasherToriTriple HThe UndertakerVal VenisVince McMahonVisceraX-Pac</description><genres><genre id="10">Wrestling</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14786">WCW vs. nWo: World Tour</game><game id="2410">Def Jam: Vendetta</game><game id="20680">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2009</game><game id="4315">WWE Crush Hour</game><game id="15815">WWE SmackDown! Here Comes the Pain</game><game id="4155">WWF Raw</game><game id="11394">WWF No Mercy</game><game id="7485">WWF In Your House</game><game id="10177">WWF King of the Ring</game><game id="20282">WWF Wrestlemania Challenge</game><game id="7951">Legends of Wrestling II</game><game id="18333">Backyard Wrestling 2: There Goes the Neighborhood</game><game id="18320">WCW/nWo Revenge</game><game id="9216">Power Move Pro Wrestling</game><game id="30637">Lucha Libre AAA Heroes del Ring</game><game id="13440">Backyard Wrestling: Don't Try This at Home</game><game id="28430">WWF Royal Rumble</game><game id="557">WCW vs. the World</game><game id="23213">Virtual Pro Wrestling 2: Ōdō Keishō</game><game id="23212">Virtual Pro Wrestling 64</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2139914-box_wwfwm2k.png</image></root>