<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36687</id><name>The Amazing Spider-Man</name><description>OverviewAlistair Smythe, the main villain of the game.The Amazing Spider-Man takes place after the events of the 2012 Sony movie reboot of the franchise, and features a return to the open world elements of the past Spider-Man movie games. After Peter Parker becomes Spider-Man and defeats The Lizard, Oscorp, under the leadership of a new CEO named Alistair Smythe, begin to clear up the Cross-Species experiments Curt Connors left behind during his time there. However one night, as Gwen Stacy gives Peter a tour around the facility, the Cross-Species experiments break out, infecting Gwen and a number of Oscorp scientists with a deadly plague that begins to spread about New York City. Spider-Man breaks the now cured Curt Connors out of the mental institute he resides in, being branded a criminal in the process, in order to create a cure to save the city. Smythe begins to send out armies Drones designed to hunt down the escaped Cross-Species monsters (including versions of Spider-Man villains such Rhino, The Scorpion and Iguana), including Spider-Man himself, whose hybrid DNA also makes him a target.GameplayWeb Rush Mode, when activated.For the first time since Spider-Man: Web of Shadows, The Amazing Spider-Man returns to featuring Manhattan as an open world sandbox for Spider-Man to swing around in, stopping random crimes, collecting comic book pages - which, once a certain amount are collected, unlock digital copies of famous issues of Spider-Man comics throughout history, including Amazing Fantasy #15, Spider-Man's first appearance - and taking photos to unlock bonus costumes. Apart from web-swinging, the open world also utilizes a new Traversal mechanic called Web Rush, which slows down time and pulls the camera into a first person perspective, highlighting different areas Spider-Man can zip-line to. Web Rush can also be used in combat to highlight enemies Spider-Man can zip to, or objects he can interact with to take out multiple targets at once.Combat itself is akin to the systems found in the Rocksteady Batman games, with spider-man chaining combos and dodges using his spider-senses in order to be able to pull off powerful and acrobatic finishing moves. Through these combat encounters Spider-Man gains experience which can be used to level up, unlocking extra skills or modifying the strength of his current ones.Voice ActingUnlike past Spider-Man movie titles, The Amazing Spider-Man does not use the cast from the movie to voice its characters. Sam Riegel plays the part of Spider-Man, with Kari Wahlgren playing Gwen Stacy and Steven Blum as Doctor Connors. Ali Hillis makes an appearance as the Black Cat, and Nolan North voices main villain Alistair Smythe. The game also features voicework from Bruce Campbell in a cameo role as an extreme sports reporter, in the vein of his previous cameos in Spider-Man games, as well as voicework from Stan Lee in a pre-order bonus mission pack.Collectable Comic BooksThe game also features 500 comic book pages to collect, which in total unlock 10 digital comics to read:5 Pages Collected - Amazing Fantasy #15 (First Appearance of Spider-Man)15 Pages Collected - Amazing Spider-Man #6 (First Appearance of The Lizard)30 Pages Collected - Amazing Spider-Man #630 (First comic in The Lizard 'Shed' storyline)50 Pages Collected - Amazing Spider-Man #41 (First Appearance of Rhino)80 Pages Collected - Amazing Spider-Man #19 (First Appearance of Scorpion)125 Pages Collected - Amazing Spider-Man #194 (First Appearance of Black Cat)175 Pages Collected - Amazing Spider-Man Volume 1 #294 (Part of the 'Kraven's Last Hunt' event, featuring Vermin)250 Pages Collected - Spectacular Spider-Man #32 (First Appearance of Iguana)350 Pages Collected - Amazing Spider-Man #31 (First Appearance of Gwen Stacy)500 Pages Collected - Amazing Spider-Man Annual Volume 1, #19 (First Appearance of Alistair Smythe)Players who got the Stan Lee Adventure Pack also receive a bonus issue for completing the DLC, appropriately titled 'Excelsior!'.Pre-Order BonusesStan Lee starring as himself in the Stan Lee Adventure Pack.Players who pre-order the title from Amazon for the Xbox 360 or PlayStation 3 will receive the Stan Lee Adventure Pack. Voiced by himself, Stan Lee is the playable character, swinging through New York City with Spider-Man's powers, looking for pages of his latest script.Also available was a pre-order bonus was a challenge pack allowing players to play as Rhino rampaging throughout the streets of Manhattan.Wii U VersionA Wii U version of The Amazing Spider-Man has been announced for release in Spring 2013. This version will include all previously released DLC packs and feature optional motion and touch controls, such as charting a path through the city via GPS.PC System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Windows® 7/XP (SP 3)/Vista (SP 2)Processor: Intel Core® 2 Duo 2.6 GHz or AMD Athlon 64 X2 6000+Memory: 3 GB RAMGraphics: NVidia Geforce 7600GT / AMD ATI Radeon X1800 GTODirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 7500 MB HD spaceSound: Any DirectX 9.0 compliant Sound CardAdditional: Internet connection required for installation and authentification.Recommended:OS: Windows® 7/XP (SP 3)/Vista (SP 2)Processor: Intel Core® 2 Quad 2.4 Ghz or AMD Athlon II X4 2.6 GhzMemory: 3 GB RAMGraphics: NVidia 8800GT / AMD ATI Radeon HD4830DirectX®: 10Hard Drive: 8000 MB HD spaceSound: Any DirectX 9.0 compliant Sound CardOther Requirements: Broadband Internet connectionAdditional: Internet connection required for installation and authentification.</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2171297-box_tasm.png</image></root>