<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36681</id><name>Fusion: Genesis</name><description>PlotHumanity has taken its place among the stars . . . only to find itself scorned by the alien races and fighting over a startling discovery that threatens the balance of interstellar power forever. Embark on a dangerous journey through a galaxy on the brink of war, and pursue long-forgotten secrets under the shadow of an invasion from beyond known space.Features6 storylines to play as a free trader, a lawless mercenary, a galatic peacekeeper, a military loyalist, or a devout seekerAn "always connected" environment where friends and enemies populate the world dynamicallyHundreds of solo and co-op quests23 levels to exploreMore than 100 ships, from agile scout fighters to huge cruisers1,000 different ship upgradesOver 200 weapons for shipsMore than 40 unique combat skillsCooperative (1-4 players) and PvP (1-8 players)Connects with Fusion: Sentient, a Windows Phone 7 game where players can level up and trade AI units that will help them in Fusion: GenesisSoundtrackFusion: Genesis' soundtrack was composed by ex-Rare employee  Steve Burke, most well-known for the critically praised  Kameo: Elements of Power original soundtrack. Burke said he was attracted to Fusion: Genesis because of the amount of music he could compose. It consists of 39 tracks, lasting 1 hour 22 minutes.You can  read the full interview with Steve about the soundtrack on ScoreNotes. You can also listen to the full soundtrack and download it via the links below, courtesy of Steve Burke and Starfire Studios. Listen to the full soundtrack on YouTube Download the full soundtrack on SoundCloudNo.TitleLength1Graveyard2:082Proelium Primus1:283Solaria2:424Periculum Primus1:105Ether Perpetua1:246Meteor Storm2:247Tartarus4:088Station0:569Asteroid Belt3:0510Proelium Secundus1:3911Crucible3:0212Caelum3:0113Proelium Tertius1:1414Vires2:0515Dominion1:1116Confrontation1:5717Cavus1:4418Wonder2:5119To The Stars1:5220Sentient2:5621Periculum Secundus1:4222Order2:0023Shadowrift2:3224Folly1:5625Syndicate1:0026Proelium Quartus1:0327Tutorial4:1128Erebus3:4329Leviathan2:0130Ominon1:2431Proelium Quintus1:3732Choralsa2:0033Ventus Primus2:2834Ventus Secundus1:1435Sonus2:1536Ventus Tertius2:4637Tempum2:3838Angelica Solaria2:0439Praetorian1:52Fusion: Sentient IntegrationFusion: Sentient on WP7Fusion: Sentient is a  Windows Phone 7 action/strategy game developed by  Wahoo Studios, better known under their independent label,  Ninjabee. Players command squads of robots, known as Sentients that can be upgraded and used in Fusion: Genesis.</description><genres><genre id="31">Dual-Joystick Shooter</genre><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19771">Darkstar One</game><game id="31010">DarkStar One: Broken Alliance</game><game id="7164">Armada</game><game id="7306">Starscape</game><game id="29777">Abaddon</game><game id="12406">Operation: Inner Space</game><game id="35942">Space Pirates and Zombies</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2022683-box_fuziong.png</image></root>