<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>367</id><name>Need for Speed II</name><description>Overview    Need for Speed II is the sequel to     The Need for Speed and part of     The Need for Speed franchise.  In Need for Speed II you race with exotic cars on different tracks all around the world.  The game also features a split-screen mode to play with friends.  The game does not include police pursuits like in the original The Need for Speed.Cars    The cars in Need for Speed II are divided into A, B, and C classes based on their performance.  Most cars you drive are exotic cars with the exception of a few concept cars and the ability to drive slower traffic cars via cheat codes.  List of player drivable cars:Ferrari F50Lotus GT1Jaguar XJ220Ford GT90Lotus Esprit V8McLaren F1Isdera CommandatoreItaldesign CalaFord Indigo Concept Car  (Bonus) Tracks     All tracks are circuit tracks.  There is an ability to toggle tracks to be played forwards/backwards and regular/mirrored.  Giving a total of four different tracks per track.  You can also toggle traffic.  The tracks take place all around the world.  Some of the places include: USA, Canada, Australia, Mexico, Greece, Nepal, and Germany.List of tracks:OutbackLast ResortPacific SpiritMediterraneoNorth CountryProving GroundsMystic PeaksMonolithic Studios (Bonus) Special Edition Need For Speed II Special Edition (SE)  was a version of Need For Speed II that featured not only the original  game but also some extra tracks and cars.  Cars  Extra Cars for Special Edition:  Ford Mustang Mach III Ferrari F355 F1  Berlinetta BMW Italdesign Nazca C2Ford Indigo Bonus Cars for Special Edition (unlocked via cheat codes): Bomber BFSTombstone Daytona RacecarFZR2000  (fictional car) Tracks    NEW to Special Edition: Last  Resort</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9651">Need for Speed Underground 2</game><game id="11055">NASCAR 08</game><game id="13713">Screamer</game><game id="20038">NASCAR: Dirt to Daytona</game><game id="4246">Daytona USA: Championship Circuit Edition</game><game id="941">Project Gotham Racing</game><game id="2279">Project Gotham Racing 2</game><game id="19809">Project Gotham Racing 3</game><game id="8437">TOCA 2: Touring Car Challenge</game><game id="20729">GRID</game><game id="7019">Ridge Racer V</game><game id="16276">Ford Bold Moves Street Racing</game><game id="20919">Ford Racing: Off Road</game><game id="7431">Ford Racing</game><game id="12950">Gran Turismo 3 A-Spec</game><game id="22853">Peak Performance</game><game id="7777">Juiced</game><game id="11625">Ridge Racer DS</game><game id="10124">Midnight Club: Street Racing</game><game id="284">NASCAR 2005: Chase for the Cup</game><game id="17872">TOCA Race Driver 3 Challenge</game><game id="8438">NASCAR 06: Total Team Control</game><game id="20418">Midnight Club II</game><game id="5875">Midnight Club 3: DUB Edition</game><game id="20927">Midnight Club: Los Angeles</game><game id="21114">Midnight Club: Los Angeles Remix</game><game id="5909">Viper Racing</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1793298-box_nfs2.png</image></root>