<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36777</id><name>The Pinball Arcade</name><description>OverviewThe Pinball Arcade is a pinball game developed and published by FarSight Studios for multiple platforms.GameplayThe Pinball Arcade is a virtual collection of real world pinball machines. The tables in The Pinball Arcade were created by four of the largest pinball machine makers in history; Williams, Gottlieb, Bally, and Stern. The base game comes with four popular pinball tables with additional pinball tables available as Downloadable Content. Farsight intends for the title to become somewhat of a playable mueuem, containing the world's best pin tables.Two downloadable tables, Twilight Zone and Star Trek: The Next Generation, were funded through the help of Kickstarter. Farsight took their case to Kickstarter after realizing that licensing fees were way more than the project could afford. Both Kickstarter projects were successful, and the tables have since been released. Since then, a future Kickstarter to fund the Terminator 2: Judgement Day table has been announced by Farsight. Included TablesThe base game comes with four tables:Tales of the Arabian Nights (Williams)Ripley's Believe It or Not! (Stern)Black Hole (Gottlieb)Theatre of Magic (Bally)Tables available now as downloadable content:*Pack 1:Medieval Madness (Williams)The Machine: Bride of Pin·bot (Williams)Pack 2:Funhouse (Williams)Cirqus Voltaire (Bally)Pack 3:Gorgar (Williams)Monster Bash (Williams)(Tables below this point are not yet available on XBLA)Pack 4:Black Knight (Williams)Creature from the Black Lagoon (Bally)Pack 5:Taxi (Williams)Harley-Davidson (Stern)Pack 6:No Good Gofers (Williams)Elvira and the Party Monsters (Bally)Pack 7:Big Shot (Gottlieb)Scared Stiff (Bally)Pack 8 (Premium Table Add-On 1):Twilight Zone (Bally)Pack 9 (Premium Table Add-On 2):Star Trek: The Next Generation (Williams)Pack 10:Genie (Gottlieb)Attack from Mars (Bally)Pack 11:Dr. Dude (Bally)Firepower (Williams)Pack 12:Cactus Canyon (Bally)Central Park (Gottlieb)Pack 13:White Water (Williams)Space Shuttle (Williams)Pack 14:Pin•Bot (Williams)Centaur (Bally)Pack 15:The Champion Pub (Bally)Whirlwind (Williams)Pack 16:Flight 2000 (Stern)Goin' Nuts (Gottlieb)Pack 17 (Premium Table Add-On 3):Terminator 2: Judgement Day (Williams)Pack 18:Tee'd Off (Gottlieb)Haunted House (Gottlieb)Pack 19:Victory (Gottlieb)Class of 1812 (Gottlieb)Pack 20:El'Dorado: City of Gold (Gottlieb)JunkYard (Williams)Tables confirmed by Farsight Studios as future downloadable content:The Addams Family (Williams)Future Kickstarter tables:Eight Ball Deluxe (Bally)Ace High (Gottlieb)Sorcerer (William)*DLC availability varies between platforms - as a general rule, new content comes to Android, iOS, Mac, and PC devices before it arrives on home consoles, and the PS3 has usually released tables before the Xbox 360. Cross Platform DLCAccording to the official The Pinball Arcade Facebook page, any DLC tables purchased for the PS3 version of the game will also allow you to access them on the Vita (and vice-versa). The developer has also promised the addition of "many many more tables coming as DLC for years to come." XBox 360 DLC issuesAfter Table Pack 3 was released for the XBox 360 during the late Summer of 2012, the remainder of the year saw no further table releases. This was eventually revealed to be due to issues regarding the publisher of The Pinball Arcade content on the 360 (Crave Entertainment) going into bankruptcy. In December of 2012, Farsight announced via their Pinball Arcade newsletter that they were in the final stages of securing a new publisher and would be making further announcements when they knew when new tables would be arriving for the 360.</description><genres><genre id="30">Pinball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12059">Pinball FX</game><game id="32513">Pinball FX2</game><game id="33171">Marvel Pinball</game><game id="20994">Pinball Hall of Fame: The Williams Collection</game><game id="27346">Theatre of Magic</game><game id="35197">Tales of the Arabian Nights</game><game id="35205">Ripley's Believe It or Not!</game><game id="37977">Black Hole</game><game id="33821">The Machine: Bride of Pin*Bot</game><game id="24687">Medieval Madness</game><game id="39784">Pinball FX3</game><game id="40892">Capcom Arcade Cabinet</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2126448-box_parcade.png</image></root>