<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36898</id><name>LEGO Batman 2: DC Super Heroes</name><description>OverviewA direct sequel to the original Lego Batman game, Lego Batman 2 has expanded its horizons from the Batman heroes and villains, and now encompasses many more DC properties. A first for the series, Lego Batman 2 introduces voiced dialogue--featuring an all-star voice cast--for the Lego characters over the mumbling and grumbling from past Traveller's Tales' Lego games.The game also has more of an open world style as opposed to the previous Lego games' more level-oriented style. The game leaves the player free to explore Gotham City in between missions, with challenges to complete, secrets to find, and gold bricks to collect. This is the series' first foray into an open world gameplay style, one that will be continued in Lego City Undercover.GameplayLego Batman 2: DC Super Heroes is fairly similar to previous Lego games, with a few new added elements. The meat of the game is still the story mode where up to two players, go through an original story set in the Batman Universe. Players will go level to level, beat up bad guys, do some platforming, and smash up the environment to find collectables and thousands upon thousands of studs, which act as the games currency.What's new in Lego Batman 2 is an open world to run around and explore. In between missions players are free to roam around a Legoized version of Gotham City. Players can go about Gotham as any character they want (once completing the story mode), and collect different red and gold bricks, fight bosses, unlock characters and vehicles, and just explore the world.CharactersLego Batman 2 features 64 playable characters, three being exclusively available on the handheld versions, and ten of them being pre-order bonuses. Lego Batman 2 also features a fully voiced cast, with Tara Strong, Nolan North, Troy Baker, and more lending their voices to the game.Alfred (Voiced by Steve Blum)AquamanAzrael (Handheld Exclusive)Bane (Voiced by Steve Blum)BatgirlBatman (Power Suit, Sensor Suit, Electricity Suit, Bat Suit, voiced by Troy Baker)Bizarro (Pre-Order)Black Adam (Pre-Order)Black CanaryBlack Manta (Pre-Order)BrainiacBruce WayneCaptain BoomerangCaptain Cold (Pre-Order)CatwomanCheetah (Voiced by Claudia Black)Clark KentClayfaceCommissioner GordenCyborgDamian Wayne (Pre-Order)Dethstroke (Handheld Exclusive)FlashGeneral ZodGorilla Grodd (Pre-Order)Green LanternHarley Quinn (Voiced by Tara Strong)HawkgirlHawkmanHuntress (Voiced by Tara Strong)HushJoker Henchman (No Hat, Mime)Katana (Pre-Order)Killer Croc (Voiced by Steve Blum)Killer Moth (Voiced by Steve Blum)LexBotLex Luthor (Voiced by Clancy Brown)Lois LaneMad HatterMan-BatMartian Manhunter (Voiced by Cam Clarke)Mr. FreezeMr. Freeze HenchmanNightwing (Pre-Order/Handheld)Police OfficerPoison Ivy (Voiced by Laura Bailey)Ra's Al GhulRiddler HenchmenRobin (Acrobat Suit, Hazard Suit, Ice Suit, Magnet Suit)ScarecrowShazam (Pre-Order)SinestroSuperboy (Handheld)SupergirlSupermanTim DrakeThe Joker (Voiced by Steve Blum)The Penguin (Voiced by Nolan North)The Riddler (Voiced by Rob Paulsen)Two-Face (Voiced by Troy Baker)Two-Face HenchmanVicki ValeWonder Woman (Voiced by Laura Bailey)Zatanna (Pre-Order)PlotLex Luthor, after losing to Bruce Wayne for the Man of The Year award, decides to join forces with The Joker so as he can help become the next US President. After breaking Joker out of Arkham Asylum, along with many other notorious villains, Batman and Robin are called in. After cornering the dastardly duo within Lex's heavily armored truck, they find out that he's making kryptonite and take it back to the Bat Cave for research. It soon turns out that the kryptonite is fake and is actually a tracking device that Joker and Luther used to locate the Bat cave. Overpowering the dynamic duo thanks to Luthor's latest weapon, The Deconstructor--which breaks down any black objects--they are able to steal the real stash of kryptonite Batman keeps in his safe.Luthor and The Joker use the kryptonite to power a new highly powerful mech, built to feature the likeness of The Joker. After Batman's Batmobile was destroyed by Luthor, Robin sets to repair it while Superman also arrives to give Batman a hand in stopping The Joker and Luthor. Using The Joker's laughing gas from their newly built robot, Luthor attempts to influence the public into voting for him as President. Batman and Superman are always there to arrive to thwart their plans and inflict an increasing amount of damage to the robot. Eventually Luthor utilises the robot's kryptonite core to severely weaken Superman, hindering his ability fly. Still sticking by Batman, the two continue to do battle against the robot across the city.After Superman dives right through the core, dealing critical damage to the mech but also weakening himself considerably, Robin manages to return just in time with Batman's newly rebuilt Batmobile - complete with a much brighter color scheme. Leading the mech around the city as it drips krytonite, the duo are able to cause the mech to inadvertently signal members of the Justice League to come to their aid. The combined power of Batman and Robin, along with Cyborg, The Flash, Green Lantern and Wonder Woman, are then able to soundly thrash the mech and take both The Joker and Lex Luthor down. But only as Brainiac watches from afar within his spaceship once again plotting to destroy Superman.System RequirementsMinimumRecommendedCPUIntel Core 2 Duo 2 GHz orAMD Athlon 64 X2 3800+Quad Core CPU 2.7 GHzRAM1 GB2 GBOSWindows XP, Vista or 7Windows XP, Vista or 7Video CardNVIDIA 7600, 7800, 8xxx or betterATI 1950 or betterNVIDIA GeForce 8800 or betterATI HD3870 or betterFree Disk Space10 GB10 GB</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="251">LEGO Star Wars: The Video Game</game><game id="9631">LEGO Star Wars II: The Original Trilogy</game><game id="29992">LEGO Star Wars III: The Clone Wars</game><game id="11120">LEGO Star Wars: The Complete Saga</game><game id="26699">LEGO Indiana Jones 2: The Adventure Continues</game><game id="33207">LEGO Pirates of the Caribbean: The Video Game</game><game id="26753">LEGO Harry Potter: Years 1-4</game><game id="35388">LEGO Harry Potter: Years 5-7</game><game id="32196">Marvel Super Hero Squad: The Infinity Gauntlet</game><game id="41090">LEGO Marvel Super Heroes</game><game id="20822">LEGO Batman: The Videogame</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2199357-box_lbm2.png</image></root>