<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36947</id><name>Ougon Musou Kyoku Cross</name><description>OverviewOugon Musou Kyoku Cross (黄金夢想曲†Cross) is an append disc for the 2D versus fighting game Ougon Musou Kyoku, a spin-off to the Umineko no Naku Koro ni visual novel series by 07th Expansion. In addition to featuring all the characters from the original title and the Xbox 360 port (Ougon Musou Kyoku X), the characters Dlanor A. Knox, Erika Furudo and an alternative version of Battler Ushiromiya have been added to the game's roster of selectable fighters, with Willard Wright, Lambdadelta and Bernkastel expected to be added at a later date. It was released at Comiket 81 on December 31st, 2011.Playable charactersPlayable charactersNameAbilityDescriptionAnge UshiromiyaStun BoostIncreased chance of stunning the opponent.B. BattlerMassacreGain health upon dealing damage.Battler UshiromiyaResurrectionGradual health regeneration.BeatriceInfinity SPPlayer can perform SP Supers without using SP.BernkastelDlanor A. KnoxArmor BoostTemporarily increase player's defense.Erika FurudoForce CounterAutomatically counter-attack after being hit.Eva-BeatriceBerserkGreatly increases the player's attack strength.George UshiromiyaJessica UshiromiyaShave BoostAttacks cause damage to blocking opponents.KanonSilent AttackReduced SP recovery rate for the opponent.LambdadeltaLuciferAttack TouchThe player can perform one Attack Touch without a full Touch gauge.RonoveCounter BoostIncreases the damage dealt by the player's counter attacks.Rosa UshiromiyaDetachmentOpponents hit during the effect of the ability will be stunned for a short period of time.ShannonAuto-GuardAutomatic blocking.Siesta 410Break BoostIncreases the rate that the opponent's Break Limit gauge will fill.VirgiliaBrimfulGradually restores the player's SP gauge.Willard H. WrightSP CancelAllows him to cancel special moves, EX moves and SP2s into any super move of higher priority.Release HistoryShortly after the game's release a V2.01 patch was release that added Black Battler for network play and made several balance tweaks and bug fixes. On the 24th of February 2012 V2.10 was released that added Willard Wright as a playable character and made even more balance tweaks and bug fixes.External linksOfficial website at 07th ExpansionOfficial website for the original game at 07th ExpansionOMK Wiki for translation help, strategies and links to patches.</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21768">BlazBlue: Calamity Trigger</game><game id="29779">BlazBlue Calamity Trigger Portable</game><game id="28321">BlazBlue: Continuum Shift</game><game id="32481">Blazblue: Continuum Shift II</game><game id="36253">BlazBlue Continuum Shift Extend</game><game id="29341">Arcana Heart 3</game><game id="25188">Guilty Gear XX Λ Core Plus</game><game id="20456">Street Fighter IV</game><game id="2612">Marvel vs. Capcom 2: New Age of Heroes</game><game id="36274">Persona 4 Arena</game><game id="34082">Skullgirls</game><game id="21367">Sengoku Basara X</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/12/127673/2068678-omkc.jpg</image></root>