<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36967</id><name>Really Big Sky</name><description>OverviewReally Big Sky is the semi-sequel of the PC game Big Sky, released in early 2011. This time different game modes, co-op play, bigger explosions and many other features have been included. The game, just like it's predecessor, is procedurally generated, so there's no pattern memorization and every run is it's own.GameplayReally Big Sky is a fast paced dual-joystick shooter in which players must shoot enemies while dodging bullets. A drilling mechanic is also implemented, so the player can cross asteroids that would otherwise crush the ship, although bullets cannot be fired while drilling. Enemies appear randomly, and so do boss encounters. After a boss is killed, shields are reestablished and dead co-op players respawn.At the first play the ship has weak bullets, slow movement and dies at a single enemy touch, so it's likely to run for less than a minute. No health bar, no lives. This, besides confusing the player, leads to an upgrading screen, where the money collected during the last run can be spent on shields, better and broader lasers, faster movement, claymore bombs and other upgrades. This changes are permanent on further runs, allowing them to be longer, which will lead to more money and an even better spaceship.All of this is complemented with the voice of an English narrator (voiced by Mr. Pineapple), which will make witty remarks on how is the player doing and what enemies are appearing.As different milestones are reached, other game modes are unlocked.PC System RequirementsOS:Windows XPProcessor:2ghz Core 2 DuoMemory:512 MB RAMGraphics:DirectX 9.0c or aboveDirectX®:9.0cHard Drive:200 MB HD spaceSound:DirectSound-compatible Sound CardAdditional:Controller support extends to official Xbox 360 controllers only.</description><genres><genre id="31">Dual-Joystick Shooter</genre><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11099">Geometry Wars: Retro Evolved</game><game id="35732">Galaga Legions DX</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3699/2071282-really_big_sky.jpg</image></root>