<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>36971</id><name>World Gone Sour</name><description>OverviewWorld Gone Sour is a 2D platformer developed by both Beefy Media and Playbrains and published by Capcom for the PC, Xbox 360 (via Xbox Live Arcade), and PlayStation 3 (via PlayStation Network) on April 11, 2012. An advergame based on the sour sugar coated candy Sour Patch Kids, players control a green (or blue, for player two) Sour Patch Kid who must make it through different levels such as a movie theatre concession stand to take his rightful place inside a human stomach.The game features the song "World Gone Sour (The Lost Kids)" by Method Man as well as voice work by Creed Bratton.GameplayWorld Gone Sour is a side-scrolling platformer. Similar to Pikmin, the game has you flinging your little sour friends into objects or combining with them in order to advance.Sour SacrificesIn each level, there are many ways to kill and be killed by harmful dangers in the levels. Many times, right above dangers are points and, in order to get them, other Sour patch kids must be flung into them as a sacrifice. But don't worry, they come back.There are Eight different kinds of SacrificesSlicedDrownedExplodedBurntFlungMeltedSkeweredSquashedThe Lost CandiesThe "Lost" are the candy that gets lost between couch cushions, , the floor, etc. When they don't get eaten, they go insane. There are four lost candies and they are bosses in this game. Each boss has their own level.Semi-SquishedSemi-Squished is a combination of a Blue Sour Patch, a shoe, and a wad of gum.Dolly-DollDolly is a little girl's doll with its mind taken over by a Yellow Sour Patch.Pump-KindPump-Kind is a rotten pumpkin inhabited by a Purple Sour Patch that befriended some fireflies.Red FriendRed is your friend that got left at the factory. You encounter him multiple times over the course of the game, and he is also the final boss.</description><genres><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7301">Toy Story 2: Buzz Lightyear to the Rescue!</game><game id="20221">Yo! Noid</game><game id="11746">Cool Spot</game><game id="10584">Spot Goes to Hollywood</game><game id="14701">Chase the Chuck Wagon</game><game id="24729">M&amp;M's Blast!</game><game id="3421">Global Gladiators</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5150/2072384-c4777e899e59f9bb1a1f884ee6b1c060.png</image></root>