<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37043</id><name>X3: Albion Prelude</name><description>OverviewX3: Albion Prelude marks the last game to use the engine that's been iterated upon for nearly all of the X franchise's games. It also bridges the story events from X3: Terran Conflict to X: Rebirth focusing on the war between Earth and the rest of the X Universe.Although a separate game, X3: Albion Prelude uses most of the assets contained in X3: Terran Conflict and as such requires purchase of that game to play for the PC. The Mac version is standalone and does not require X3: Terran Conflict to be purchased. Most, if not all, of the in-game features from X3: Terran Conflict carry over into this game.Key New FeaturesA new plot that engages the player in a power struggle between corporations at a time of war. Including large scale battles that the player can participate in.More than 30 new ship designs and stationsA Stock Exchange has been added allowing players to not only buy and sell stocks/commodities, but also influence prices through their actions in game.The game uses the same basic engine as X3: Terran Conflict, however it can now take advantage of hardware improvements made in the past few years. Yielding improved graphical quality.Improved UI including charts to visualize economical developments. Interactive spreadsheets.Support for head tracking hardware.X3: Albion Prelude is available for PC on Steam and for Mac on the app store and Deliver2Mac. This game has been automatically added to some Steam collections, such as the X: Superbox, and does not require additional purchase for owners of those collections.Ship ClassesCombatM1: CarriersCarriers are capital ships that are able to have smaller classed ships (M3's to M5's) dock in them. This allows easy transportation of a large fleets of fighters to the battlefield.M2: DestroyersDestroyers are capital ships focused on combat. These ships use turrets (which are usually located on all sides of the ship) to defend itself and attack enemies.M3: FightersFighters are the slowest of the small class combat ships (M3, M4, M5) but also the most powerful.M4: InterceptorsInterceptors are the middle of the road small class combat ships. They are faster than M3's but less powerful.M5: ScoutsScouts are the fastest of the small class combat ships but this also makes them the least powerful.M6: CorvettesCorvettes are heavily armored and well armed combat ships that are usually found as escorts for patrols or capital ships.M7: FrigatesFrigates are larger and more powerful than the M6 but much slower. They have a docking bay for several smaller ships that can be used as defense against fighter attacks since they can have trouble with them due to slow maneuverability.M8: BombersBombers use long range missiles to support fleets attacking capital ships or stations.TransportTL: Large TransportsLarge Transports are the only transports capably of carrying the parts needed for building stations. This makes them essential late game for setting up a network of factories and trading posts.TM: Military TransportsMilitary Transports are tasked with transporting small groups of fighters either to the battlefield or to different sectors for storage.TP: Personnel TransportsPersonnel Transports are tasked with the transport of living beings.TS: Basic TransportsBasic Transports are usually used as traders or to supplement factories with resources that are needed to keep it running.You can see a ship's class when you target them. Every ship has a name as well as a call-sign of sorts which is a mixture of letters and numbers. In the center of this call-sign is the ships designation (ex. M5) which allows you to quickly tell what kind of fight you are getting into.System RequirementsWindowsOperating System: Windows XP (Service Pack 2) or higherProcessor: 2.0 GHz, Pentium 4 or AMD equivalentRAM: 1 GBVideo Card: 256MBDirectX: DirectX 9 compatible with Pixel Shader 1.1 supportHDD Space: 10GB free spaceMac OS XOperating System: 10.6.8 or higherProcesser: Intel CPU, 2.16 GHz or fasterRAM: 1 GBVideo Card: GeForce 8600, Radeon X 1600, 256MBHDD Space: 7G free spacePatchesVersion 2.0This patch was released 2/25/2012 and contained minor bug fixes and improvements as well new mini-plots for the Player HQ and The Hub. These mini-plots are based off of the original plots in X3: Terran Conflict and allow X3: Albion Prelude players to get the main rewards that were given at the end of the X3: Terran Conflict plots.The new features and fixes are listed by Egosoft's CBJ in this forum postNew Features and Improvements:- New mini-plot: The HUB- New mini-plot: Player HQ and UFJD- New ships- New graphs- Added option to disable war reports- Megalodon and Xenon I rebalanced and adjusted- Introduced setup time for new lasertowers- Made USC Baldric Miner available for purchase- New sector music tracks in certain sectors- Prevent purging all marines, so theres always some available- Improved UI handling of typing repeated letters in text fields- Improved graph axis display to use round numbers where possible- Added minimum notoriety requirement for buying Lasertowers.- Added achievements for new mini-plots- Added war missions to stats export- Added new script commands to support new graphs- Added script command to get complex hangar of factory- Added missing beacon, drone and mine classes to script editor class list- Added set_notoriety action to Mission Director for setting notoriety between non-player races- Added {object.realigntime@hub} variable for Mission Director for next available HUB gate realignment- Added hue/saturation global parameters for "spare" races for use by moddersFixes:- Fixed more cases of stuck comms windows- Fixed formatting of numbers in certain cases- Fixed issues with missing voice when loading saved game in a different language- Fixed attacked signal for Sector/Universe Trader- Fixed weapon switching when going out of sector- Fixed menu display for Defend Sector command- Fixed RRF stopping ship commands when it shouldn't- Fixed emergency jump and 100% shield recharge for RRF ships.- Fixed duplicate actions when using Force option in Mission Director debug window- Fixed duplicate events in Mission Director when a variable refers to the player ship- Fixed changing of current sector background using alter_sector in Mission Director</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19771">Darkstar One</game><game id="31010">DarkStar One: Broken Alliance</game><game id="19727">Star Wars: TIE Fighter</game><game id="20121">Star Trek: Klingon Academy</game><game id="34871">X Rebirth</game><game id="22157">Space Rangers 2: Reboot</game><game id="18775">Space Rangers</game><game id="16484">Space Rangers 2: Rise of the Dominators</game><game id="25963">Age of Pirates 2: City of Abandoned Ships</game><game id="16330">Frontier: Elite II</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/15/155745/2168573-i1k0w_dcmagnets.ru_x3_albion_prelude_2011.jpg</image></root>