<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37054</id><name>Pokémon Conquest</name><description>OverviewPokémon Conquest, known as Pokémon + Nobunaga no Yabou in Japan (translated as Pokémon + Nobunaga's Ambition in English), is a turn based tactical RPG for the Nintendo DS that also serves as a crossover between Nintendo's Pokémon franchise and Koei's Nobunaga's Ambition series. It is set in a fictionalized incarnation of Warring States era Japan known as Ransei in which Pokémon also exist and fight alongside the warriors of the age. The game was released in North America on June 18, 2012.Though the game is a crossover with the Nobunaga's Ambition series, a number of the characters based on historical figures take their appearances and personalities from the Samurai Warriors series. In particular, their physical appearances are most reminiscent of Samurai Warriors 3.StoryNobunaga's sister Oichi with her Jigglypuff.In the Ransei region, the setting of Pokémon Conquest, there are seventeen kingdoms. The protagonist, whose name and gender are determined by the player, starts the game as the warlord of the Aurora. The player fights the forces of the other kingdoms for control of Ransei. There is a legend that if all seventeen kingdoms are united under one banner, a legendary Pokémon will appear, influenced by the personality of the unifying warlord. The ultimate goal is to gain control of Ransei before rival warlord Nobunaga Oda, whose unification of Ransei would surely summon forth a legendary Pokémon that would lay waste to the entire region.The game's premise takes influence from the history of Japan's Warring States era. During this point in history, Japan was in a constant state of war between rival warlords that sought to unify the nation under their control. Nobunaga Oda, one of the most powerful and influential warlords of the era, came closer than anyone before him in his attempt to unify Japan, but his success was cut short when one of his officers, Mitsuhide Akechi, staged a coup and forced him to commit suicide. This same period of history serves as the setting of the Nobunaga's Ambition series of strategy games, which commonly feature scenarios based around major events in Nobunaga's military career.GameplayBattles are fought between teams of up to six Pokemon per side.Pokémon Conquest is a turn-based strategy RPG in which the player must win a series of battles in order to progress the story. Players are a warlord in control of an army, extending their reach across the different nations that comprise Ransei. Each nation is controlled by a rival warlord, while each territory is home to a certain type of Pokémon, such as fighting or water. In all, there are seventeen nations, one each for the seventeen types of Pokémon. In addition to battling against rival warlords, players can also explore each nation under their control in order to recruit new team members and fight wild Pokémon; the Pokémon found within each nation correspond to the nation's Pokémon affinity, as do the recruitable warriors that players can battle. For example, the region of Ignis contains fire themed battlefields and it is where the player can recruit the warlord Takatora, who has an affinity for flying and fire-type Pokémon, and is paired with Charmander, a fire type Pokémon. In order to recruit a warrior, the player must either defeat them within four turns, defeat them using a 'Super Effective' move, or occasionally fulfill specific requirements.As the player's territory expands, warriors can be stationed at the various nations under the player's control up to a maximum of six per nation. The player may then optionally choose to delegate governance of that nation to one of the stationed officers present. When the option to delegate is selected, the officer in charge can be assigned to focus on a specific task such as training, recruiting, or mining for gold.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="24220">Fire Emblem: Shadow Dragon</game><game id="24472">Shin Megami Tensei: Devil Survivor</game><game id="34522">Shin Megami Tensei: Devil Survivor 2</game><game id="21286">Final Fantasy Tactics A2: Grimoire of the Rift</game><game id="41346">Shin Megami Tensei X Fire Emblem</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2171279-box_pkmncon.png</image></root>