<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3705</id><name>Dragon Valor</name><description>Dragon Valor is the third and final game in the Dragon Buster series of action role-playing games. The first chapter of the game is essentially a remake of Namco's 1984 arcade classic Dragon Buster. The player originally controls Dragon Buster's protagonist Clovis (though he looks markedly different) and fights across several maps in a scrolling brawler-type hack  slash format, along with platformer elements. There are additional RPG elements that allow the player to power-up their character and unleash magical spells, the latter in a similar manner to Golden Axe's screen-clearing special abilities.In Clovis' chapter, the player can decide the girl he ends up marrying out of the two he meets while adventuring, depending on the moral decision of whether he rescue Princess Celia (the princess in the original Dragon Buster). This choice decides who the next protagonist will be, as each new main character is invariably the child of the previous protagonist and their betrothed. The rest of the game branches out in a similar manner, with many various main characters to unlock. Although each character more or less fights similarly in melee, they have different spells with varying effects.The different possible genealogies were intended to increase the replay value, as a single run through the game tends to be rather on the short side.Several characters from Dragon Valor appear in Namco Super Wars for the Wonderswan, a cameo-filled "Namco mythos" game that's a precursor to Namco X Capcom.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14351">Golden Axe</game><game id="12337">Dragon Buster</game><game id="5572">Dragon Buster II: Yami no Fuuin</game><game id="22872">Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Shadow Over Mystara</game><game id="22870">Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Tower of Doom</game><game id="6608">River City Ransom</game><game id="20733">Castle Crashers</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2133348-box_dvalor.png</image></root>