<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37077</id><name>Epic Astro Story</name><description>GameplayEpic Astro Story revolves around the exploration of planets, production of materials, and improving the appeal of your planet for tourists. The game is controlled via a handful of menu systems giving the user an indirect control over their city and it's citizens. Options include improving your residents, adding appeal to your overall tourism, exploring dangerous and unknown territories and planets, as well as controlling the economy through means of material production and consumption.BuildingsEpic Astro Story consists of 3 different "types" of structures. These include "Environment," "Work," and "Tourism." Each collection of buildings focus on a specific part of the overall economy of the players planet. The tourism category houses special bonus buildings that are found through exploration of the map that benefit both the appeal and research production of your tourists.EnvironmentStructureExplanationHouseYour general purpose building for your inhabitants. These buildings "improve" with the increase in your citizen's level.DestroyDestroy structures and (unlocked) environment.RoadYour general system connection tile. Roads are needed for your citizens to travel to the various buildings in your city.ExporterBuilt next to "fields," exporters sell the harvested field immediately instead of allowing for transport to a factory, or processor.--WorkStructureExplanationFieldYour general-purpose material producer. It is required to create foods at the Factory and processor.FactoryGenerates specialty foods and items from gathered materials at the Field and Mine.MineLike the field, but generates materials like Rock, Iron, and Rare metals.ProcessorUses materials created at the field and mine to create higher tiered materials.--TourismStructureExplanationSpace-portYour city's mode of entry for interplanetary visitation.HotelHousing for your tourists. Improves your relations with discovered civilizations with increased appeal.Flower-bedWhen built next to a Hotel, the flower-bed adds +2 appeal to the Hotel's overall appeal.Tourism bonus buildings.These buildings are found through exploration of caves and unknown territories on your planet. They add bonus research and cash when visited.StructureIvory StatueFood CartMuseumParkGymFast-food RestaurantToy StoreWeapons and Armor and AbilitiesYou can equip your citizens with weapons, armor, and abilities to aid them in their exploration of the unknown universe. They are discovered my "researching" the specific field which can be found throughout your exploration of the planet.WeaponsMeleeConditionClubWeapon Tech 01KnifeWeapon Tech 02Short-swordWeapon Tech 03Long-swordWeapon Tech 04Battle-axeWeapon Tech 05SwordWeapon Tech 06HammerWeapon Tech 07Heat AxePlanet Level 06 RewardBeam SabreWeapon Tech 07 + Electronics Tech 04DrillWeapon Tech 07 + Mining Tech 03Golden AxeBottomless Chasm Challenge Dungeon L13 RewardForce SwordBottomless Chasm Challenge Dungeon L4 Battle RewardRangedConditionRockN/ABoomerangWeapon Tech 02Throwing KnifeWeapon Tech 03Shock BladeLevel 02 Planet RewardThrowing StarWeapon Tech 04Iron BoomerangWeapon Tech 05PistolWeapon Tech 06BazookaWeapon Tech 07Beam RifleWeapon Tech 07+ Electronics Tech 04Wind BladeLevel 09 Planet RewardMultiple-launch BazookaBottomless Chasm Challenge Dungeon L4 RewardPlasma RifleBottomless Chasm Challenge Dungeon L10 RewardArmorArmorConditionBattle GearArmor Tech 01Space-SuitArmor Tech 02Power Suit 01Armor Tech 03Power Suit 02Armor Tech 04Power Suit 03Armor Tech 05Chimpan Z Suit100% Exploration of home planet.Kairo SuitBottomless Chasm Challenge Dungeon L16 RewardAbilities/SkillsSkillExplanationRageAttack increased  50% health.RecoverySmall heal when health  50%.Heal allyHeal's an ally when health  50%.Battle-cryIncreases allies attack when  50% HP.Sharpshooter+1 range to citizen weapon.Power-strikeMelee attack increased periodically.Power-shotRanged attack increased periodically.GuardGuards against enemy attacks when health is  50%.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="37639">Dungeon Village</game><game id="37901">Cafeteria Nipponica</game><game id="34336">Hot Springs Story</game><game id="36075">Mega Mall Story</game><game id="36369">Pocket League Story</game><game id="35624">Grand Prix Story</game><game id="36915">World Cruise Story</game><game id="36888">Oh! Edo Towns</game><game id="35767">Pocket Academy</game><game id="42759">The Sushi Spinnery</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/36102/2089269-mr5xs9o6rxxnj2uz1ipiaipog7dyfygjxkhnomncz47br0jd7dyvngyllsk_bvjy7uy1_.jpg</image></root>