<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37140</id><name>Melty Blood: Actress Again: Current Code</name><description>OverviewCharacter Select ScreenMelty Blood: Acress Again: Current Code is the fourth installment in the Melty Blood series, a spin off to Tsukihime, and is available on Windows PCs. It contains many unique features, such as the different fighting styles called Moons. These styles determine a character's play style and movelist. Characters can build meter in order to activate Heat or perform EX moves. Heat allows characters to recover some health over time, this only applies to red health since damage dealt can be either permanent or recoverable. Once the circuit meter reaches 300%, Crescent and Full Moon characters enter Max mode which allows them to perform Arc Drive moves. By pressing A+B+C during Max mode, characters can enter Blood Heat which allows them to perform Last Arc moves, these are very powerful moves and are triggered by shielding against an attack. There are 36 different skins for each characterMoonsCrescent Moon StyleSimilar gameplay to and shares the same movelist with Melty Blood: Act Cadenza. Characters can reverse beat and dodge attacks while in the air or on the ground. When getting hit, characters can circuit spark while in max meter mode. You can activate Heat after the circuit meter fills past 100% and can enter Blood Heat mode if the circuit meter fills to 300%. While in Heat, characters receive a 1.07 damage modifier and a 0.9 defense modifier while in Blood Heat characters receive a 1.13 damage modifier and a 0.85 defense modifier. Characters have EX shield and normal shield. This style has the most control over meter.Half Moon StyleLike Crescent Moon Style, characters can reverse beat and dodge attacks while in the air or on the ground. They can only use EX shield. The circuit meter goes up to 200% but there's no way to activate Heat manually, once the circuit meter reaches 200%, heat will trigger automatically. During Heat, life slowly regenerates and circuit spark triggers automatically if hit.Full Moon StyleUnlike the other two styles, characters cannot reverse beat. Like Crescent Moon Style, the circuit meter goes up to 300% but instead of being able to use Heat, you can charge the circuit meter manually by holding down A+B+C. Once the meter reaches 300%, you character can enter Blood Heat. Characters can circuit spark on the ground or in the air but cannot dodge. Characters cannot Ex shield, they can only normal shield and EX guard.CharactersAkiha TohnoAkiha is the younger sister of Shiki Tohno, she is one of the five heroines of Tsukihime.Crescent Moon Style Special MovesShooting Down the Bird 「鳥を落とす」- 236ABC (Can also be performed in air)Piercing the Moon 「月を穿つ」- 214ABCScorching the Beast 「獣を焦がす」- 22ABCBrilliant Crimson Submerge 「赫訳・沈紅」- 63214ABCBrilliant Autumn Leaves 「赫訳・紅葉」 - 623ABCArc DrivesCrimson Lord Origami　「赤主・檻髪」- 41236CAkiha VermillionAkiha Tohno, overcome by the Inversion Impulse caused by her demonic heritage.Crescent Moon Style Special MovesFlame Tongue - 236ABC (Also in midair)- 623ABCFlame Pillar - 214ABCFlame Pit - 22ABC (Also in midair)Ignite Flame Pit - 22ABC (Also in midair)Arc Drives- 41236C- 41236C (While in Blood Heat)Aoko AozakiAoko is one of only five remaining sorceresses in the world. Also known as "Miss Blue" she is capable of controlling Blue Magic. She gave a pair of glasses to Shiki Tohno to prevent him from seeing the lines of death.Crescent Moon Style Special MovesBlowing Starmine - 236ABC (Can also be performed in air)Blazing Starmine - 22ABCFloating Starmine - 214ABCExploding Starmine - 421ABCBlowing Starbow - 63214ABCKeri Tobasu Wa Yo - 623ABCArc DrivesSevere Break - 41236CSevere Break Slider - 41236C (While in Blood Heat)Arcueid BrunestudArcueid is the White Princess of Shinso and one of the five heroines of Tsukihime, she is considered the main heroine.Crescent Moon Style Special MovesRekka Series - 236ABCElbow Series - 214ABCClaw Series - 623ABCForce Ring Series - 63214ABCCielCiel is one of the five heroines of Tsukihime. She is a skilled assassin and member of a secret organisation in the Catholic Church called the Burial Agency.Crescent Moon Style Special MovesBlack Keys - 214ABC (Can also be performed in air)Halo - 236ABC (Can also be performed in air)Ciel Somer - 22ABC (Can also be performed in air)Hidden Black Keys - 63214ABCArc DrivesThe Seventh Scripture - 41236CThe Seventh Scripture: Forgiving the Original Sin - 41236C (During Blood Heat)Last ArcCremation Ritual - EX Shield an attack while in the air during Blood HeatHisuiHisui is one of the five heroines of Tsukihime. She is the twin sister of Kohaku, and a maid in the Tohno Mansion. She is a terrible cook, but is very good at cleaning. She and Kohaku are the opposites of each other. Hisui's storyline takes place after the events of the main storyline.Crescent Moon Style Special MovesYayaya - 236ABCDust - 623ABCRandom projectile throw - 214ABCExplosive Bento - 22ABCArc DriveSaturday Night Fever - 41236CDark Hisui Punch - 41236C (During Blood Heat)Last ArcBrainwasher Detective HisuiKohakuKohaku is one of the five heroines of Tsukihime. She is the twin sister of Hisui and a maid in the Tono Mansion. She always has a cheerful disposition and is very gifted with medicine. She was the target of the Tatari curse and gained vast scientific knowledge resulting in her creation of Mech Hisui.Crescent Moon Style Special MovesDraw Out Hidden Sword 「抜刀・秘密の業物」- 236ABCMagical Amber Missile 「マジカルアンバーミサイル」- 214ABCI Tried My Best To Raise This 「こんなん育ててみました♪」 - 22ABCJohnny 「ジョニー」- 2222CThis is a Victim of Modern Medicine 「現代医学の犠牲者です」- 22222CMagical Attack 「マジカルアタック・コハポンX」- 1632143CAmber Colosseum Upper 「アンバーコロシアム・アッパー」- 63214CArc DrivesUnsealed Amber Kick 「開打靠靭琥珀脚」- 41236CFlying Unsealed Amber Kick 「開打散靭琥珀失脚」- 31236C (During Blood Heat)Last ArcSecret Draw out　・ New Year Comet 「抜刀奥義・賀正箒星」Kouma KishimaUnder the orders of Tohno Makihisa, Kouma eliminated the Nanaya clan. Demon blood runs strongly through his clan.Crescent Moon Style Special MovesCommand Grab - 214ABCRising Flame Kick - 623ABCFlaming Rekka - 236ABCArc DriveCommand Grab - 41236CLenLen entered a contract with Shiki Tohno in order to become his familiar. She is a Succubus Demon with the ability to manipulate dreams. She is capable of transforming into a cat. She rarely speaks, she thoroughly enjoys cakes and hates taking baths. After her Magus' death, Arcueid took care of Len. Since then she is only awakened at the same time Arcueid hunts vampires.Miyako ArimaArima is a cousin of Shiki and Akiha Tohno. She has the ability to gain amazing strength due to the effects of the Night of Wallachia and uses a form of Chinese Kenpo. She is very shy, especially around her cousin Shiki. Miyako's storyline takes place after the events of the main storyline.Crescent Moon Style Special MovesDashing Elbow - 236ABCCrescent Kick - 623ABCLunging Punch - 214ABCJumping Elbow - 421ABCStomp - 22ABCNeco-ArcNeco-Arc is a feline version of Arcueid Brunestud, she is the mascot of Type-Moon and a joke character in Melty-Blood, similarly to Dan Hibiki in the Street Fighter franchise. She is the shortest character in the game, almost half the size of any other character. She can summon Kinoko Nasu to a fight as her Last Arc. Neco-Arc's storyline takes place after the events of the main storyline.Crescent Moon Style Special MovesLaser Eyes - 236ABCMuda Muda Muda - 623ABCNeco Arc Throw / Neco Arc Rocket - 22BCTeleport - 214ABCCall in more Neco Arcs to wreak some havoc - 421ABNrvnqsr ChaosNrvnqsr (pronounced Nero) Chaos is one of the Twenty Seven Dead Apostle Ancestors. His body is comprised of the lives of 666 creatures which he can summon to help him during battle.Crescent Moon Style Special SummonsCrows - 236ABC / 623ABCSnakes - 214ABCDeer - 421ABCPhantom Hand - 63214CTeleport - 66 / 44Arc DriveUltimate Transformation - 41236CLast ArcDark LaserRiesbyfe StridbergRiesbyfe is the leader of the Kinght's Heresy Persecution Group and a vampire hunter. She uses a Conceptual Weapon which imitates the appearance of a stringed instrument.Crescent Moon Style Special MovesWrist Pizzicato 「リスト・ピッツィカート」- 236ABCBreath Cantino 「ブレス・カンティーノ」- 623ABCWrist Staccato 「リスト・スタッカート」- 214ABCWrist Portato 「リスト・ポルタート」- 63214ABCArc DriveOfficial Apocrypha 「正式外典」- 41236CLast ArcOfficial Apocrypha: Embrace the Original Sin 「正式外典・原罪抱擁」Michael Roa ValdamjongRoa is the main antagonist of Tsukihime. He is a member of the Twenty Seven Dead Apostle Ancestors and is a vampire. He is able to reincarnate himself after his currently form is destroyed, allowing him to live forever.Crescent Moon Style Special MovesLightning Bolt - 236ABCAir Counter - 623ABCLightning Orb - 214ABCArc DriveLightning Strike - 41236CSatsuki YumizukaSatsuki was turned into a Dead Apostle and killed by Shiki Tohno. She was later resurrected by the Night of Wallachia.Crescent Moon Style Special MovesGrasping the Endless Dream - 236ABCChasing the Unreachable Dream - 623ABCLet's Go! - 214ABCDon't Interrupt Me - 22ABCSorry But Just One bite! - 63214CArc DriveI'm angry! - 41236CLast ArcReality Marble - Depletion GardenShiki TohnoShiki is Akiha's older brother and the main protagonist of Tsukihime. Being a demon hunter, he developed the Mystic Eyes of Death Perception. His glasses, given to him by Aoko, block out the lines of death.Crescent Moon Style Special MovesDash Slash - 236ABCCrescent Kick - 623ABCSliding Kick - 214ABCSion Eltnam AtlasiaSion is the main female Protagonist of Melty Blood. She is an alchemist and was turned into a vampire by the Night of Wallachia.Crescent Moon Style Special MovesWarning Shot 「威嚇射撃」- 236ABCEtherlite Ground 「エーテライト・グランド」- 214ABCSlide Air 「スライド・エア」- 214ABC (Air only)Etherlite Air 「エーテライト・エア」- 623ABC (Air only)Cutting Sync 「カッティング・シンク」- 421ABCReload 「リロード」- 22DArc DriveBarrel Replica 「バレルレプリカ」- 41236CLast ArcBarrel Replica・Obelisk 「バレルレプリカ・オベリスク」WarakiaWarakia, also known as the Night of Wallachia, is one of the Twenty Seven Dead Apostle Ancestors. He is a disembodied Tatari and can transform himself into the fears of a community. He was originally an alchemist from Atlas.Crescent Moon Style Special MovesKatto - 236ABC (Can also be performed in the air)Summon - 214ABCTeleport - 421ABCTornado - 22ABCAirdash - 22ABC (In air only)Red Arcuied Summon - 63214C (Can also be performed in air)Arc DriveMassive Tornado - 41236CDemo  Official ReleaseAfter several delays due to netcode issues, the demo for the PC version of Melty Blood: Actress Again: Current Code was released by Soft Circle French-Bread on December 12th, 2011. The demo included 4 playable characters, Sion, V. Sion, Arcueid Brunestud and Red Arcueid. The full version of the game was released on December 31st, 2011 and was bundled with a Blu-Ray edition of Carnival Phantasm, a collection of parodies and stories which are loosely based on Melty Blood and Tsukihime.SoundtrackTrack 1Elegant Summer2:41Track 2Beat from Melty Blood3:03Track 3Mech Hisui Theme1:30Track 4Wonderful Boy3:44Track 5Blood Heat2:12Track 6End of a Thousand Years4:45Track 7Help Me!1:39Track 8Truth from Melty Blood3:02Track 9Blood Drain3:00Track 10Troublesome Visitor3:30Track 11Basilica2:07PC System RequirementsOS: Windows Japanese (R) Sp3/Vista/7 XPCPU: Intel (R) Celeron (R) 440 2.0GHz or higherMemory: 1.5GB or moreHDD: 2.1 GB or more free spaceVideo Card: DirectX (R) 9.0c or higher, Direct 3D w/ Shader 3.0, NVIDIA (R) GeForce (R) 7900 or AMD Radeon (TM) X1600 reccomendedVideo Memory: 256MB or moreSound: Direct Sound (R)Numpad NotationNumpad numbers represent the in game directions. ABC represent low, medium and heavy attack.</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre><genre id="36">Text Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11813">Guilty Gear</game><game id="21768">BlazBlue: Calamity Trigger</game><game id="22812">Battle Fantasia</game><game id="34218">Chaos Code</game><game id="800">Guilty Gear XX Λ Core</game><game id="26032">Million KNights Vermilion</game><game id="22362">Street Fighter II': Hyper Fighting</game><game id="27723">Vanguard Princess</game><game id="35030">Akatsuki Blitzkampf</game><game id="1615">Street Fighter III: 3rd Strike</game><game id="29184">Jackie Chan in Fists of Fire</game><game id="34396">Aquapazza: Aquaplus Dream Match</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/10/103881/2096182-cover.jpg</image></root>