<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37186</id><name>Marvel: Avengers Alliance</name><description>Main Details Marvel: Avengers Alliance is a 2012 Facebook game for the PC platform. It features Heroes and unlockable costumes from the Joss Whedon film The Avengers as well as heroes from other franchises such as The Fantastic Four, Spiderman, and the X-men.The game takes place during story lines that are interconnected with the Marvel comics, featuring such powerhouse villians like Loki, Magneto and Doctor Doom. Players take on the role of an customizable S.H.I.E.L.D. agent leading a team of super powered heroes. The combat is composed turn based RPG style action similar to franchises like Final Fantasy. Players unlock and train other heroes through currency called command points and S.H.I.E.L.D. points, as well as pick up supplies from earned in game silver to research and level p abilities as well as purchase new weapons.The initial team that is unlocked for no charge is Iron Man, The Black Widow, and Hawkeye.Much akin to the style of Facebook games is the concept of a "freemium" game which is free to play, but allows for micro transactions to purchase in game gold or silver, which can be applies to services throughout the game.The price set is currently designed to give you lower level heroes quickly to build a roster, with such heroes as Iron Fist and She Hulk being the cheapest, and Main title heroes such as Captain America and the Hulk being the most expensive.While there is no co-op mode, players can give resources to Facebook friends by simply playing the game, which allows players once daily access to their friends for supplies.A PVP (Player vs. Player) mode lets you take your chosen squad of three into battle against other players for leaderboard ranking.This summer, Marvel: AA introduced Specs Ops mode, which features side stories accessible for a limited time which unlock weapons, supplies and special characters. The following Spec Ops chapters have been released.Don't Say A Word... (May 15, 2012 - June 20, 2012)Long Live the Queen (July 25, 2012 - August 27, 2012)Avengers Vs X-men (September 21, 2012 - October 23, 2012)All Hallows (October 26, 2012 - November 27, 2012)The Wild Hunt (November 30, 2012 - January 07, 2013)Cry Havok (January 29, 2013 - February 25, 2013)Ghost in the Machine!Vision of The FutureExtremisAnd So Shall Ye ReapSins of the FatherGameplay BasicsThe game was formatted into a role-playing online game. In order to start a battle with a threat, a mini boss, a final boss or an epic boss, the player must first click any symbol on a map Once clicked, click fight or show help if ever the case the player needs a guide.During a fight, the player must click on any of the icons below. In order to attack or use any gear, click on the first four icons. If a player must access the neceessary resources, simply click the inventory button (the black box icon). If ever the case the selected character has run out of stamina, click the recharge button (the blue arrow icon). Need more fire power? No problem, simply click the store icon. Note that you need gold to purchase a weapon or any item. Need a little help? Not to worry, click the distress call to get help from friends. Remember that you must invite friends to join your side to get distress calls. Once the player has selected an action, if the action is an attack move, click on any enemy and if the action is for healing, click on an ally. Also note that throughout the fight, the selected character runs out of stamina once performing an action (excluding the use of distress calls, weapons or anything that heals), as previously stated, the player must click the recharge button to, well you know, recharge. After a battle with final or epic bosses, a player instantly gets a reward by using the reward spin that automatically appears after a fight. Once the final boss is defeated and all deploys are completed, an icon that has "Exit Map" in it will appear. Click on it to finish the level and earn your reward. Recruitment and Command PointsAs the player progresses throughout the game, he or she will always need more teammates. In order to recruit more heroes, the player must always have enough points to get the heroes into your side, and those points are called Command Points (blue coins with the Avengers symbol). To know where all heroes are, click the Team icon. Here you'll be able to see and purchase all available heroes and costumes. However, not all heroes can be recruited upon the use of command points and some are only available for only a limited time. Once a hero is recruited, the hero or heroine can now be trained or used in deploys or fights in the game. Command Points can be earned in boss rewards, if exchanged for gold or giving critical hits to epic bosses. Training, Research, Store and SHIELD PointsEvery once in a while, the hero needs some time to power up. The answer to that is Training. Once a hero or heroine was able to reach the maximum of his or her experience bar, the words "Training Available" can be seen after a battle. Note that only heroes only have this and the agent automatically levels his or herself up. To train a character, click Team and select a hero that has "Train" in their picture. Think Training is free? Wrong. You need Command Points (purple coins with the SHIELD symbol) to train them. Once the player has enough SHIELD points, he or she must click train to start training. The time allotment of the training depends on what his or her next level will be. You will also see the time of training in the icon. Training takes too long? Simply click speed up use gold to complete or boost the training a little. When it's done, click Team and the hero's leveled up. You will notice the word "Done" in the icon when finished. Research is really important when it comes to winning. In order to research new items, click "Research" and simply select any item you want researched. Like training you need SHIELD Points to research. Not all items are re searchable, StorylineThroughout the game, a new story is seen every season. So you better keep your eyes peeled for anything new! Season 1The player takes the role of a newly recruited SHIELD Agent. After receiving training, assisting Black Widow, Iron Man and Hawkeye, an unknown pulse of energy has been felt all over the world. It's up to you now to investigate the threat, before it goes horribly wrong. While SHIELD (including you) trying to maintain the peace as every goes on a riot, many forces of villainy are causing chaos and mayhem. In the game, you'll be fighting villains and teams from the comic books. Afterwards, evidences say that Doctor Doom is the possible mastermind of everything evil.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="38104">Young Justice Shadow Mission</game><game id="33081">Dragon Age Legends</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/13/135472/2099074-maamarvel_avengers_alliance_l.jpg</image></root>