<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3724</id><name>Grand Theft Auto III</name><description>A New LookGrand Theft Auto III is the follow up to the previous top down iterations in the series. Featuring similar themes to its predecessors, Grand Theft Auto III diverges to become one of the greatest games on the PlayStation 2, and establishes a basis for one of the best selling game franchises in history.Grand Theft Auto III went leaps and bounds beyond the previous games, leaving the top down view to become an expansive open world third person shooter, establishing new precedents for graphics in games. GTA III popularized the then-mostly-unknown concept of "sandbox" gameplay, where a player can go anywhere in the game, and is not required to follow a linear path. Also new to GTA III was an auto target system, allowing the players to overcome difficulties with aiming on the PS2. The PC version of the game, which could take advantage of a mouse, dropped the lock-on system in favour of a superior free-aiming system, allowing them to easily shoot targets in game. The final defining implementation was the radio, something to be included in every other game in the franchise except Grand Theft Auto Advance. The soundtrack was expansive, and players could listen to any of the stations, and the various humor included on each one.Though Grand Theft Auto III was one of the games that made the PlayStation 2 a must-own system, the game was originally optioned to Microsoft as an exclusive launch game for the Xbox. However, Microsoft turned Rockstar's offer down, objecting to the content of the game and how the company and their new system would be perceived because of it, which led to the game launching exclusively on PS2. Eventually, GTA III would come out on the Xbox in the form of the Grand Theft Auto Trilogy pack, bundled with sequels Grand Theft Auto: Vice City and Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas.In October 2011, Rockstar announced that Grand Theft Auto III would be released on select mobile and tablet devices in celebration of the games 10th anniversary. The game is coming to A5 enabled iOS devices and select Android phones and tablets.PlotIn the beginning, the main character (who was later given the name "Claude" in GTA: San Andreas) is escaping from a freshly-robbed bank with his girlfriend Catalina and another partner after robbing it. Just when they are about to get away, Catalina murders their partner and shoots the protagonist, and leaves with the cash.Later, the player, who survived the gunshot, is being transported in the back of a police truck to a prison. Suddenly, the doors fling open and the player, along with a man known as 8-Ball, are set free. Apparently, the Columbian Cartel needed a prisoner free and it just so happens that he was in the same convoy as the player and 8-Ball. 8-Ball knows a place where they can lay low, so the two drive over to the safehouse.The protagonist puts on some new clothes so the police don't recognize him: the trademark black jacket with green pants. He then heads over to Sex Club Seven and meets Luigi Goterelli, a man connected to the Mafia who has work available. He has the player pick up a girl named Misty from the hospital, and when he returns the player is informed about a dealer giving out drugs to Luigi's girls. Luigi, naturally, is rather upset by this and instructs the player to kill the dealer and return his car to them. Luigi, pleased that the protagonist is doing such a fine job, provides a few more jobs and has the player meet Joey Leone, who gives him more dirty work. For a while the player comes into contact with many people and does many, many jobs for them. Eventually, he meets a woman named Maria and it is implied that she has romantic feelings for him, though it is unclear whether the silent protagonist feels anything in return. One thing leads to another and Maria ends up being kidnapped by Catalina. At the end of the game, a dramatic battle ensues and Claude appears to exact his revenge by murdering Catalina.The main character in GTA III is nameless within the context of the game itself. However, many speculated that the character was named Claude Speed, who is the protagonist of the previous GTA game. Game files on the GTA III disc reportedly list "Claude" as a text string. Rockstar went on to place the GTA III protagonist into Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas, where his silence becomes something of a gag. A lone phone call in GTA:SA identifies the protagonist as Claude, but this still isn't concrete proof that the man is, indeed, Claude Speed.Side MissionsAside from the core narrative component, there are a number of side missions that can be completed. Taking part in illegal street racing and delivering stolen cars to order are just two of the available activities you can take part in outside of the main storyline.Vehicle MissionsIn Grand Theft Auto III, you can steal various service vehicles, and perform missions associated with them, these vehicles include; police cars, fire trucks, ambulances, and taxis. Completing a certain level on these vehicles has various benefits for the player.WeaponsFistBaseball BatPistolUziShotgunAK-47M16Sniper RifleRocket LauncherFlamethrowerMolotov CocktailGrenadeDetonatorControversyGrand Theft Auto III was enormously controversial, not least because of its violent and destructive nature. The game has been used as a scapegoat by a number of politicians; who aimed to ban the game entirely, or at least put restrictions on its sale. Violent videogames such as this formed an easy target for society's problems, and the high prevalence of underage players only exacerbated this notion. This game also sparked the publicized relationship between the Grand Theft Auto franchise and Jack Thompson, whom repeatedly tried to have the game banned, and frequently represented people who were filing charges against the game.In an interview with gaming author Harold Goldberg, Sam Houser relates several changes made to the game in sensitivity to the September 11th terrorist attacks on New York City. Specifically, a character using terrorist plots to bring down the Liberty City economy was completely removed, as were the Liberty City versions of the "Twin Towers." Also, the police cars were changed from blue to black.SoundtrackDouble Clef FMDouble Clef FM - Where the songs have wordsDJ: Morgan MerryweatherGenre: Classical, OperaTracklist:Le Nozze di Figaro - "Non piu andrai farfallone amoroso"Lucia di Lammermoor - "Chi mi frena in tal momento"La traviata - "Libiamo ne' lieti calici"Don Giovanni - "Finch'han del vino"Gianni Schicchi - "O mio babbino caro"Rigoletto - "La donna è mobile"Flashback 95.6Flashback 95.6DJ: ToniGenre: 1980's Pop musicTracklist:Debbie Harry - "Rush Rush"Elizabeth Daily - "Shake It Up"Paul Engemann - "Push It to the Limit"Amy Holland - "She's On Fire"Elizabeth Daily - "I'm Hot Tonight"Game Radio FMGame Radio FMDJ: Stretch Armstrong, Lord SearGenre: Underground hip hop, Midwest hip hop, East Coast hip hopTracklist:Reef - "Scary Movies (Instrumental)"Royce Da 5'9" - "We're Live (Danger)"Nature - "Nature Freestyle"JoJo Pellegrino - "JoJo Pellegrino Freestyle"Royce Da 5'9" feat. Pretty Ugly - "Spit Game"Royce Da 5'9" - "I'm the King"Rush - "Instrumental Bed 1"Black Rob - "By a Stranger"Sean Price feat. Agallah - "Rising to the Top"Rush - "Instrumental Bed 2"Head RadioHead RadioDJ: Michael HuntGenre: Soft Rock, Adult ContemporaryTracklist:Dil-Don't - "Stripe Summer"Whatever - "Good Thing"Craig Gray - "Fade Away"Conor  Jay - "Change"Frankie Fame - "See Through You"Scatwerk - "Electronic Go Go"Dezma - "Life Is But A Mere Supply"K-JahK-Jah RadioDJ: Horace "The Pacifist" WalshGenre: DubTracklist:Scientist - "Dance of the Vampires"Scientist - "Your Teeth in My Neck"Scientist - "The Corpse Rises"Scientist - "The Mummy's Shroud"Scientist - "Plague of Zombies"Lips 106Lips 106DJ: AndeeGenre: Pop musicTracklist:Fatamarse - "Bump To The Music"Marydancin - "Wash Him Off" [25]April's in Paris - "Feels Like I Just Can't Take No More"Lucy - "Forever"Boyz 2 Girls - "Pray It Goes Ok?"Da Shootaz - "Grand Theft Auto"Funky BJs - "Rubber Tip"MSX FMMSX FMDJ: MC Codebreaker, TimecodeGenre: Drum and BassTracklist:Calyx - "Quagmire"Rascal and Klone - "Get Wild"Ryme Tyme - "Judgement Day"Omni Trio - "First Contact"Aquasky - "Spectre"Rascal and Klone - "Winner Takes All"Ryme Tyme - "T Minus"Cause 4 Concern - "Spasm"D Kay - "Monolith"TJ Rizing - "Agent 007"Rise FMRise FMDJ: Andre "The Accelerator"Genre: Anthem Trance aka Uplifting TranceTracklist:Slyder - "Neo (The One)"Slyder - "Score (Original Mix)"Chris Walsh  Dave Beran - "Shake (Revolt Clogrock Remix)"Shiver - "Deep Time"R.R.D.S. - "Innerbattle"Chatterbox FMChatterbox FMDJ: Lazlow JonesGenre: Talk radioUnlike the other stations, Chatterbox does not play music. Instead, Lazlow takes calls from listeners who voice their opinions on various matters. The show also features two interviews with guests.10 Year AnniversaryIn October 2011, Rockstar announced for celebration of the first 10 years since release, that they would be releasing a 10th Anniversary edition of the game for compatible iOS and Android devices. As well as Claude action figure, complete with changeable clothing.Grand Theft Auto III: 10 Year Anniversary Edition:The 10th anniversary edition is the original release of GTA III onto compatible Apple iOS and Android devices. It will be released on December 15, 2011 on both devices.Compatible devices include:iOS:iPadiPad 2iPhone 4iPhone 4SiPod Touch fourth generationAndroid phones:HTC RezoundLG Optimus 2xMotorola Atrix 4GMotorola Droid X2Motorola Photon 4GSamsung Galaxy RT-Mobile G2xAndroid tablets:Acer IconiaAsus Eee Pad TransformerDell Streak 7, LG Optimus PadMotorola XoomSamsung Galaxy Tab 8.9 and 10.1Sony Tablet SToshiba ThriveLimited Edition Claude Action FigureThe limited edition Claude action figure was released in November 2011 and only 1,500 were made. The figure includes two outfits and several weapons.PC System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Microsoft® Windows® 2000/XPProcessor: Pentium III® 450 MHz CPUMemory: 96 MB RAMGraphics: 16 MB Direct 3D Video CardDirectX Version: Microsoft DirectX® 8.1Hard Drive: 500 MB uncompressed free hard disk spaceSound Card:Fully DirectX compatible Sound CardRecommended:Processor: 700 MHz CPUMemory: 128 MB RAMGraphics: 32 MB Direct3D Video Card</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2103135-box_gta3.png</image></root>