<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37256</id><name>Temple Run</name><description>OverviewIn Temple Run, the player controls controls a tomb raider fleeing from beasts whilst jumping and sliding to avoid obstacles such as logs, gaps, fire barriers and more.Coins can be collected in game or purchased in-app and then can be used to buy power-up upgrades, single use utilities, new characters and wallpapers from the store.Power-upsAll but one of the power-ups can be collected during the game. They can all be unlocked and then upgraded in the store. Unlocking each costs 500 coins, then the cost of upgrading increases from 1000, 2500, 5000 to 7500 coins. Once a power-up has been fully upgraded you can spend 25000 coins to access the ability to turn it off completely. This has the net affect of making the remaining power-ups appear more often.Mega CoinWorth 50, 75, 100, 125 or 150 coins depending on the upgrade level.Coin MagnetAttracts coins towards you, removing the need to pass though to collect them. Upgrades increase the length of the power-up and will double or triple the value of coins collected.InvisibilityAllows you to run through and over obstacles. Upgrades increase the length of the power-up.BoostBoosts the player up to 675m through the level depending on the upgrade level.Coin ValuesIncreases the value of coins once the player reaches a certain distance. Upgrading reduces the distance and increases the coin values. Is not a pick-up like the other power-ups.GlitchThere is a known glitch where swiping twice in quick succession to turn the first corner in the tutorial results in the tomb raider performing a 180 degree turn. The game generates an infinite straight path until the player touches the screen once more.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13795">Pepsiman</game><game id="28976">Canabalt</game><game id="31983">Robot Unicorn Attack</game><game id="36260">Jetpack Joyride</game><game id="39290">Pitfall!</game><game id="39533">Harold</game><game id="39653">Ninja Hunting</game><game id="39689">Rayman: Jungle Run</game><game id="39897">Zaxxon Escape</game><game id="39958">Bust-N-Rush</game><game id="40902">Rockman ×over</game><game id="40986">Ninja Feet of Fury</game><game id="41368">Gunstringer: Dead Man Running</game><game id="42263">Subway Surfers</game><game id="43462">Despicable Me: Minion Rush</game><game id="43862">Catcha Catcha Aliens!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/88377/2106518-1033_1_temple_run.jpg</image></root>