<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37377</id><name>Analogue: A Hate Story</name><description>OverviewAnalogue: A Hate Story is an adventure game written by Christine Love and drawn by Katawa Shoujo artist Raide that takes place in the far future. Originally tasked with merely salvaging the remnants of a long-dormant Korean space ship sent to colonize the stars in the 25th century known as the "Mugunghwa," the player quickly finds himself involved in reliving a much larger story that played out on the ship and ultimately led to its demise. Guided by the ship's pair of on-board AIs, *Hyun-ae and *Mute, details of the story slowly unfold in a non-linear fashion as the player goes through various data logs maintained by the ship's inhabitants as each AI provides its own take on the events that happened. Similarly to one of Love's previous game, Digital: A Love Story, interacting with the ship's internal systems and computers via manual keyboard commands is also necessary at times to progress.GameplayWhile the story of the Mugunghwa is told in a non-linear fashion, the game and its surrounding plot unfold in a predominantly linear matter. As the player reads various logs that detail the lives and politics of the ship's former inhabits, players can also request additional input and elucidation on the logs from each of the AIs, which often produce different reactions to the same log. Periodic conversations not directly related to the player's scavenging also occur with the AIs, enabling one's relationship with the two characters to progress as they deem fit. The end results of these choices, as well as decisions made during Analogue's climactic moments, can therefore bring about one of five different endings.In addition to the log reading, the player can also interact with the Mugunghwa's onboard computer through inputting text commands. Among other things, the player can choose which AI to talk to, decrypt blocks of data, and, in the case of *Hyun-ae, change its outward appearance. It's necessary to undertake all these actions at various points in the plot, especially with regard to AI swaps, as one often holds the key to gaining more information on the other.DLCThe DLC, Hate Plus, takes place after the ending of the game. It will answer the question about what happened to the Ship; specifically, how society broke down from the modern, equal society to the regressive, misogynistic society it turned into. It is vaguely scheduled for release in "summer" of 2013.PC System RequirementsOS: Windows XPProcessor: 1.66 GHzMemory: 1 GBHard Disk Space: 80 MBVideo Card: DirectX compatible cardDirectX®: 9.0cMac System RequirementsOS: OS X version Leopard 10.5.8 or laterProcessor: 1.66 GHzMemory: 1 GBHard Disk Space: 80 MB</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="33066">Digital: A Love Story</game><game id="34713">Don't Take It Personally, Babe, It Just Ain't Your Story</game><game id="38651">Magical Diary</game><game id="41592">Sweet Fuse: At Your Side</game><game id="42478">Hate Plus: ~Mute’s Golden Days~</game><game id="42605">Dysfunctional Systems</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/97089/2230125-726963808_1.jpg</image></root>