<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37389</id><name>Pineapple Smash Crew</name><description>OverviewIn Pineapple Smash Crew, the player controls four marines through randomly generated missions with various objectives to complete.Grenade MechanicGrenades can be picked up by killing enemies, or found in destructible crates throughout the level. Furthermore, these collected grenades can be used in combination to create deadly traps for enemies. The player has access to a handful of grenade types at the beginning of the game, and can unlock up to thirteen different types by gaining experience and leveling up. The player also has the ability to shoot in any direction, a la dual stick shooter; each of the characters shoots to create a small cloud of bullets. However, the guns do not have an infinite fire; after continuous fire they must be recharged before shooting again.Marine MechanicEvery marine in the squad also gains experience on missions, becoming tougher and changing appearance with each level gained. If a marine dies while on a mission his death is permanent, and a new level one marine is added to the squad.Grenade TypesStandard Grenade: After tossing this, the player detonates it for a small explosion, travels like a normal grenade.Laser Grenade: After tossing this, the player chooses the direction of the laser, the laser can shoot through walls.Missile: After tossing this, player chooses direction and the missile launches. The player can choose when to detonate the missile, causing a large explosion.Vortex Grenade: Upon detonation, the grenade creates a vortex sucking enemies, bullets, and other grenades into it.Shield Grenade: A grenade that creates a shield protecting players from damage.Health Grenade: when deployed it heals all characters inside the white sphere it produces.PC System RequirementsMinimum:OS:Windows® XP SP3Processor:Intel® Pentium® 4 (2Ghz) or AMD® Athlon 64 (1.6GHz) processor or betterMemory:1GB RAMGraphics:NVIDIA 6600 or ATI X700, 256MB GPU memory or betterDirectX®:DirectX® 9 or laterHard Drive:50 MB HD spaceSound:DirectX compatible sound cardRecommended:OS:Windows® Vista / Windows® 7Processor:Intel® Pentium® 4 (2Ghz) or AMD® Athlon 64 (1.6GHz) processor or betterMemory:1GB RAMGraphics:NVIDIA 6600 or ATI X700, 256MB GPU memory or betterDirectX®:DirectX® 9 or laterHard Drive:50 MB HD spaceSound:DirectX compatible sound card</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="31">Dual-Joystick Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7758">Cannon Fodder</game><game id="10865">Syndicate</game><game id="4719">Alien Breed</game><game id="16384">Cannon Fodder 2</game><game id="20715">Rocket Riot</game><game id="16194">Smash TV</game><game id="37446">Cannon Fodder 3</game><game id="26940">Larva Mortus</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/81005/2120914-8445127_orig.png</image></root>