<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37416</id><name>Yesterday</name><description>PlotIn Yesterday the game shifts perspective amongst three separate characters, the first being the enigmatic John Yesterday, a man with a case of amnesia regarding his past as an investigator. He is hired by wealthy socialite Henry White, the second character, to investigate the serial killings of vagrants in New York City. The third character is Samuel Cooper, a close friend of Henry White. Cooper grew up amidst violence, until he was saved by Henry, who took him under his wing. The game has been cited to have four different endings depending on your play style throughout the story. GameplayYesterday makes some modern advances in Adventure game mechanics. Instead of having to walk all the way to pick up or interact with an object, the character will teleport to where it is, saving the trouble of having to wait for the same walking animation and over again.PC System RequirementsMinimum:OS: WINDOWS XP SP2/VISTA SP1/WINDOWS 7Processor: INTEL/AMD 2.0GHZMemory: 1024 MB (XP)/2048 MB (VISTA/7)Graphics: 256 MB 100% DIRECTX 9 COMPATIBLE. ATI RADEON X800/INTEL GMA 3000/NVIDIA GEFORCE 6800 OR HIGHER*DirectX®: 9Hard Drive: 8 GBSound: DIRECTX 9 COMPATIBLEOther: INTERNET CONNECTION REQUIRED FOR GAME ACTIVATION *SIS AND VIA/S3G GRAPHICS CONTROLLERS NON SUPPORTED</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="37503">The Dark Eye: Chains of Satinav</game><game id="1014">Runaway: A Road Adventure</game><game id="14075">Gabriel Knight: Sins of the Fathers</game><game id="1353">The Beast Within: A Gabriel Knight Mystery</game><game id="17544">Broken Sword: The Shadow of the Templars</game><game id="4084">Broken Sword II: The Smoking Mirror</game><game id="5804">Broken Sword: The Sleeping Dragon</game><game id="34205">The Walking Dead</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1306/2148857-yesterday_pack2d_int.jpg</image></root>