<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37420</id><name>Sanctum 2</name><description>OverviewSanctum 2 provides a mix of intense action and strategic gameplay that combines thrilling multiplayer and stunning graphics, raising the bar for indie games. Melding the best elements of the tower defense and first-person shooter genres, players are challenged to protect oxygen-producing Cores from hordes of deadly aliens who are threatened by their existence.Outfit your character exactly the way you want through the new and extensive customization system. Choose your own loadout of towers, weapons and perks, but choose wisely because you are humanity’s last defense against the unrelenting hordes set out to destroy it. In Sanctum 2, you will utilize elements from multiple gameplay genres to succeed. Construct towers and walls during the building phase before the enemies attack, then jump into the fray and blast everything to pieces in FPS mode. You can progress through the single-player campaign yourself, or play with up to four friends in co-op to discover the secrets of the planet LOEK III and learn the backstory on why the aliens are so intent on destroying the Cores you are sworn to protect.CharactersSkye AutumnSkye AutumnAge: 29Rank: CG-01Height: 179 cmWeight: 61 kgBlood Type: B+Duty: Squad LeaderWeapon: Assualt Rifle.Abilities:Deals more damage for each hit on the enemy/can double jump.Sweet AutumnSweet AutumnAge: 19Height: 168 cmWeight: 64 kgBlood Type: AB+Duty: Demolitions ExpertWeapon: RexAbilities: Shots set target on fire/great air control. SiMoSiMoAge: 8Height: 220 cmWeight: 150 kgBlood Type: Synthetic B3-PlasmaDuty: Designated MarksmanWeapon: Sniper RifleAbilities: Deals more weakspot damage for each weakspot hit depending on damage done/Has high accuracyHaigen HawkinsHaigen HawkinsAge: 26Height: 185 cmWeight: 70 kgBlood Type: O+Duty: EngineerWeapon: ShotgunAbilities: Deals high damage when close to enemies/has a large amount of health. EnemiesStandard EnemiesWalker Pup - Smaller version of the Walker with less health but slightly faster movement.Walker - Standard enemy, average movement speed and health, its weak-spot is its 'face'.Walker Warrior - Larger version of the Walker, has more health and will leap at players in an attempt to attack them.Runner - Small, quick enemies which constantly juke and dodge, its weak-spot is its head.Brood Mother - Larger version of the Screamer, has significantly more health and does more damage.Screamer - ranged enemy which attacks players by spitting globs of acid, its weak-spot is the orange mass on its back.Soaker - Four-legged monster who's entire 'body' is it's weak-spot, it takes increased damage for each bullet that hits its weak-spot, meaning rapid fire weapons are extremely effective.Spitfly - Flying enemy which spits acid at players, can fly over walls and towers, the weak-spot is its face.Rhino - Armored enemy which moves much faster in a straight line, weak-spot is its head.Armored Heavy - Armored enemy which is immune to most non-explosive weapons, except for the weak-point on its rear.Hoverer - flying enemy which is completely immune to damage from the front, and can only be shot in the back. It will turn to face players who get to close and knock them away.BossesSuper HeavyWalker PatriarchWeaponsAssault RifleREXSniper RifleShotgunVoltaic Hand CannonBattle RifleETK-Tesla PrototypeTowersCannonLevelDamage Per ShotShots Per SecondDamage per secondRangeBuy/Upgrade PriceTotal CostSelling Price1215002.50140140702685003.2717031015531625004.10190500500GattlingLevelDamage Per ShotShots Per SecondDamage per secondRangeBuy/Upgrade PriceTotal CostSelling Price137001.750050259002.170010530000000LightningLevelDamage Per ShotShots Per SecondDamage per secondRangeBuy/Upgrade PriceTotal CostSelling Price12750001.751501507523650001.9122537537534550002.08225600600AR-Mine DispenserLevelDamage Per ShotShots Per SecondDamage per secondRangeBuy/Upgrade PriceTotal CostSelling Price175000-1.33100100100295000-1.66150250250300-0000ACPLevelDamage Per ShotShots Per SecondDamage per secondRangeBuy/Upgrade PriceTotal CostSelling Price1690002.00001802000000030000000KairosLevelDamage Per ShotShots Per SecondDamage per secondRangeBuy/Upgrade PriceTotal CostSelling Price100000002000000030000000DroneLevelDamage Per ShotShots Per SecondDamage per secondRangeBuy/Upgrade PriceTotal CostSelling Price130001.7500140276001.7521003503122001.752100560ViolatorLevelDamage Per ShotShots Per SecondDamage per secondRangeBuy/Upgrade PriceTotal CostSelling Price11925008.00200200200235250010.330050050030000000 Multiplayer OptionsSanctum 2 offers online cooperative play for up to four players.Steam AchievementsAchievementDescriptionHumble BeginningsComplete your first map.The Bas(e)icsBuild 20 tower bases.The Best Defense is OffenseUpgrade a tower to the max.Growing StrongerComplete a map with a Feat of Strength enabled.Halfway AwesomeReach rank 10.HerculesComplete a map with 5 Feats of Strength enabled.Game in a GameComplete a game in a game.Hope Rides AloneComplete Facility, Rocky Fields, Giant Trees, and Swamp.Team PlayerComplete one level with 5 Feats of Strength enabled in Co-op.Full-time Ass-kickerReach rank 20.Total BadassComplete Facility, Rocky Fields, Giant Trees, and Swamp with 5 Feats of Strength enabled.Final DestinationComplete The End in a party of four.PC System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows XP (SP3), Windows Vista (SP2), Windows 7, Windows 8Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo, AMD Athlon X2, or equal at 1.6GHz or betterMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: DirectX 9.0c-compatible, SM 3.0-compatibleDirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 2 GB HD spaceSound: DirectX 9.0c-compatible, 16-bitOther Requirements: Broadband Internet connectionRecommendedOS: Windows 7 or 8Processor: Quad Core 2.0 GHz +Memory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: DirectX 9.0c-compatible, SM 3.0-compatible, 512MB VRAM+; NVIDIA GeForce 8800 GTS or betterDirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 4 GB HD spaceSound: DirectX 9.0c-compatible, 16-bitOther Requirements: Broadband Internet connection</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="34304">Iron Brigade</game><game id="34811">Sanctum</game><game id="32474">Dungeon Defenders</game><game id="37860">Orcs Must Die! 2</game><game id="34265">Orcs Must Die!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2472249-box_sanctum2.png</image></root>