<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37440</id><name>Battleship</name><description>OverviewBattleship is a modern military first-person shooter developed by Double Helix (for the Xbox 360 and PlayStation 3) and Magic Pockets (for the Nintendo 3DS, Nintendo DS, and Wii) and published by Activision on May 15, 2012. This game is a tie-in to the movie of the same name, which in turn is loosely based on the classic Hasbro board game of the same name.GameplayWhile the majority of the game goes through standard first-person shooter gameplay, during the story the player is given indirect control of titular battleships via a strategic, gridded overhead view reminiscent of the board game. The action takes place around various Hawaiian islands, with the player engaging in ground-based combat on the island while the ships are controlled around it. The player has to juggle between first person combat and the concurrent sea battle, maneuvering ships to combat the enemy. In the standard first-person mode, the player utilises both modern military weapons and alien technology to battle the invading aliens on the island.What sets Battleship apart from other generic first-person-shooters is the use of the ships and their effect on the missions. Stationing ships close to player positions will enable the player to call in fire support from the ships to help defeat the aliens. Simultaneously, players have to manage the ships as they are under attack by alien ships. Each ship the player controls has statistics that represent the ship's armor and weapon power, and ships will sink when their armor is fully depleted after sustaining sufficient damage from attacks from the alien ships. The player can tactically move the ships to defeat the enemy ships strategically, or the player can gain an upper-hand by picking up randomly dropped "Cards" dropped by aliens on the island after they are killed. These "Cards" can be activated and equipped to ships to grant passive bonuses such as increased firepower, or active bonuses such as repairs and temporary buffs. Failure to complete mission objectives on the island or failure to keep the naval fleet alive will result in a game over.PlotBattleship follows elite explosives specialist Cole Marthis as he battles against a water-based alien in and around the Hawaiian archipelago, and it is up to you and your squadron to eliminate the attacking alien. The Nintendo version follows Capt. Danny Hunter and Lt. Roads and is a turn-based strategy (TBS) instead of a first-person shooter (FPS).</description><genres><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2160103-box_bship.png</image></root>