<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37503</id><name>The Dark Eye: Chains of Satinav</name><description>StoryThirteen years ago a prophet, called "The Seer" by the townsfolk, was executed in Andergast. The real reasons for the execution remain unclear, according to rumors he was executed because he cursed the kingdom of Andergast.One of the witnesses of the execution was a young boy called Geron, with his dying breath the prophet predicted a dark future for Geron. From this moment on Geron was considered a bringer of bad luck and a witches brat in Andergast and besides his efforts most of the townsfolk avoids him and makes him responsible for everything bad happening.Now thirteen years later, when a flow of aggressive crows appears and people which were in involved in the execution of the prophet start to die, Geron has finally a chance to clear his name once and for all when the king give him the task to end the scourge of crows.GameplayThe game is a classic point-and- click adventure with a few modern comfort functions. With the right mouse button the player can examine objects in their surroundings. The left mouse button is for all interactions in the game world and is context sensitive. With the mouse wheel the player can scroll through their inventory.Some of the comfort functions are the highlighting of hotspots by pressing the space bar, directly leaving areas by double clicking the left mouse button and some more help functions. All these comfort functions are optional and can be turned on/off in the game's menu.FranchiseThe Dark Eye (German: Das Schwarze Auge) is a 20 year old Fantasy German table top RPG system and universe. Other games within this series include the Realms of Arkania RPG series as well as the Drakensang RPG series, available on GOG and Steam respectively.System RequirementsWindows XP/Vista/72,5 Ghz Single Core or 2 Ghz Dual Core2 GB RAM (2,5 GB for Windows Vista/7)OpenGL2.0-compatible graphic card with 512 MB RAM (shared memory is not recommended)DirectX9.0c-compatible sound card5 GB free disk spaceDVD driveMouse (third mouse button and wheel recommended)</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="37416">Yesterday</game><game id="36334">Deponia</game><game id="22111">The Whispered World</game><game id="31979">Edna &amp; Harvey: The Breakout</game><game id="31451">The Book of Unwritten Tales</game><game id="43556">Memoria</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/97089/2161879-dark.png</image></root>