<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37510</id><name>pop'n music FANTASIA</name><description>Gameplay ChangesVery few sizable changes have been made to the formula in FANTASIA; it's still very much the same. CHALLENGE and SUPER CHALLENGE modes are now combined in NORMAL mode, ENJOY mode has been renamed to EASY mode (more accurate to what that mode entails), ojamas are the last thing you set before the song starts, and NORMAL mode now has COOLS on (unlike EASY mode.)The only real new feature (outside of the songs and whatnot) in pop'n music FANTASIA is the highlight pop-kuns. After hitting them, the player earns a bonus for getting no misses. They don't provide any drastic change to the gameplay, but they add another means of racking up points.MusicNewThis list only contains music added to pop'n music FANTASIA that hasn't appeared in previous entries in the main pop'n music franchise or other Bemani franchises. Songs that are not listed here or in the Removed section carry over from pop'n music TUNE STREET.Take note that the online features of pop'n music FANTASIA allow for the addition of new songs, so this list may not always be complete.English and romanized names are used whenever possible.TV, Anime, and Other Licensed MusicGenres for licensed songs in pop'n music FANTASIA are the same as the song titles. All licensed music added to pop'n music FANTASIA (with the exception of "MEMESHIKUTE") is covered for the game. Since the people who do the covers go unnamed, the artist listed below is the original artist.Song TitleArtistCharacterDifficulty LevelsOriginal TV/Anime ApperanceCONNECTClariSNyami14 / 23 / 31Mahou Shoujo Madoka MagicaGod only knows DAISANMAKUOratorio The World God Only KnowsA.Michel15 / 26 / 34The World God Only KnowsMEMESHIKUTEGolden Bomberロミ夫16 / 26 / 33MEMESHIKUTE is a single by the artist previously mentioned.Everyday, KATYUSHAAKB48RIE-chan17 / 24 / 29MoshidoraCORE PRIDEUVERworldMZD20 / 26 / 34Ao No ExorcistOriginal MusicAll songs listed below are new, original songs created for pop'n music FANTASIA. Hidden songs are marked with an asterisk (*).GenreSong TitleArtistCharacterDifficulty LevelsPROGESSIVE REELTradriaYasunori MitsudaArk14 / 25 / 32BLACK FUSIONJiGSaW!Soyo OkaEdward15 / 28 / 34MUNE KYUN MARBLEBukiyou no KoishiteruHiroaki Sano feat. Megumi TatsumiLICA15 / 25 / 32EPIC TRANCEEPICSota FujimoriC-noid16 / 31 / 36ROUND POPZero GravityROUND TABLE  acane_madderReo★kun16 / 27 / 32URBAN ROCKlife goes onYotsuya TakahiroMr.KK17 / 25 / 29ULTRA 90'sNo! No! WayApachEBOUNTY17 / 29 / 37crimms TALESIkimono ShikkakuAsaki  crimmにんじん17 / 30 / 36AFRO PERCUSSION PARTYEarth BeatCAPACITY GATENYANGA18 / 34 / 40MAGICAL HEROINELove Getter ~Purecle Lip~sei☆shin feat.MAIピュアクル♡リップ18 / 27 / 36FANTASYTECFutago no Ferret742DiNO19 / 33 / 38A.I. DARKNESSDOES NOT COMPUTEフレディ波多江とエレハモニカ feat. ALTAlt2.020 / 33 / 41FASCINATIONOboroHHH x MM x STmoimoi21 / 34 / 39FALSIONTHE FIRST SPACE FIGHT from FALSIONKonami Kukeiha Club Remix KOHTASHOLLKEE21 / 30 / 39ELECTRO SWINGBroadway DivaROMANTIC PRODUCTION feat. akinoSherry22 / 33 / 39SCIENCE POPKoi wa dou? Moro Hadou OK Houteishiki!!あべにゅうぷろじぇくと feat. 佐倉沙織 produced by ave;newルート@超ドー研22 / 30 / 40BUBBLY DISCO*Bubbly TimeFantastic Bubbly9LEON17 / 27 / 35SENTIMENTAL*MintyManami FujinoPoet17 / 27 / 33PLATINUM FANTASIA*MarchenTËЯRAROSEMARY19 / 34 / 39UPPER POP*How LowMAKINOmiho19 / 31 / 36CHURISU EURO*Majiyaba Saikyo DensetsuDJ Command feat. KouheiCHARA-O18 / 31 / 37POPPING WONDER*Fushigi HikouSATOE vs. Keiichi Uenopuririn17 / 28 / 34CHINA PROGRESSIVE*Hengen Jizaim@sumiSAN20 / 30 / 37NEVER ENDING PUNK*Seishun no TobiraTAKA  Hideo SuwaFRESHMAN22 / 36 / 41Internet UnlocksThe online features of pop'n music FANTASIA allow for songs to be added. So far, they've all been part of online ranking competitions organized by Konami held every two weeks, starting with the first week after FANTASIA's release.GenreSong TitleArtistCharacterDifficulty LevelsSTRIFEHayatePower of Nature雷蔵, Raizou19 / 34 / 40TRADITIONAL ROOTSKoujou MelancholyTomoaki Hirono feat. Mille FaceCastle18 / 30 / 37NORO-EMO?Misako no Nikki (michadame!)Des-Row + ミサコちゃんミサコ”ちゃん, Misako-chan21 / 35 / 41CrossoversAlong with new songs and those carried over from TUNE STREET, FANTASIA features a few songs from other Bemani games and console versions of previous pop'n music games.As with the list of original songs, asterisks (*) mark ones that are hidden.GenreSong TitleArtistCharacterDifficulty LevelsOriginal AppearanceLOUD BEACHNAMINORI_www.Des-ROW with BMHushMAN17 / 33 / 38pop'n music portable 2KAGRUNGEIkitekoso ~ Tokubetsuban ~Asakiぐわんぜさま19 / 36 / 41pop'n music portable 2SPACE POPμ9PAXAPARABO23 / 33 / 41pop'n music portable 2BEAT ROCK*LAZY GIRLYuichi TsuchiyaHugh16 / 29 / 36pop'n music 9 (Console)DIVA METAL*Gensou HanaKanako HoshinoLENA20 / 29 / 36GuitarFreaks XG  DrumMania XGRemoved SongsGenerally due to licensing issues, some songs from previous pop'n music games are removed for the next arcade release, while the rest carry over. That's the case with FANTASIA; all of the songs that have been removed are from pop'n music TUNE STREET's line-up of licensed music. For more specific information on the songs themselves, see the listings from TUNE STREET.Song TitleOriginal AppearanceTV Eiga 'Yoshimune Hyoubanki Abarenbo Shogun' BGMAbarenbo ShogunBara wa utsukushiku chiruThe Rose of VersaillesMoonlight DensetsuPretty Soldier Sailor MoonTank!Cowboy BebopOdoru PompokolinChibi Maruko-chanWe are!One PieceClimax Jump pop'n formKamen Rider Den-OKero! to MarchSgt. FrogSobakasuRurouni Kenshin / Samurai XTsuki no WaltzMinna no Uta (Tsuki no Warutsu)Lovin' LifeOriginally by Funky Monkey Babys.ShuuchishinTentai Senshi Sun RedButterflyUsed in commercials for Zexy, a Japanese magazine.Itoshisato Setsunasato Kokoro TsuyosatoStreet Fighter II (anime film)JAPSengoku BasaraLover SoulOtomenSamurai Sentai ShinkengerSamurai Sentai ShinkengerHamanasu no HanaUsed in commercials for LISMO, a Japanese music service.</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/14/147621/2130160-pop_20.jpg</image></root>