<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37545</id><name>Famicom Mukashi Banashi: Yuyuki</name><description>OverviewFamicom Mukashi Banashi: Yuuyuuki ("Famicom Fairy Tales: Yuuyuuki") is the second of two text adventure games in the Famicom Mukashi Banashi series developed by Pax Softnica and Nintendo themselves for the Famicom Disk System peripheral. It shares many similarities with its predecessor Shin Onigashima: Both games required two disks that were released separately, both feature an innovative "main character switch" feature that allows the player to switch from two playable characters and both are based on ancient far Eastern literature. In Yuuyuuki's case the literature in question is the ancient Chinese novel Journey to the West.The player controls Goku (Sun Wukong) and Chao (an original character) who are travelling separate journeys to meet up with each other. True to the novel, Goku is also accompanying the monk Sanzo and his other followers Hakkai and Gojo, though these three characters have been comedically reimagined as lazy and greedy.Yuuyuuki would be the penultimate game developed by Nintendo for the Famicom Disk System. It was also the last game for the peripheral to receive any sort of TV advertising. While Shin Onigashima has been rereleased on more recent Nintendo platforms, such as the Game Boy Advance, Yuuyuuki remains exclusive to the Famicom Disk System.GameplayAs with Shin Onigashima and many adventure games for the system the player directs the player character via a menu of commands. They can talk, examine, pick up and otherwise interact with all sorts of people and items in the surroundings. An ability to switch between Goku and Chao is frequently available as well. </description><genres><genre id="36">Text Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="34684">Famicom Mukashi Banashi: Shin Onigashima</game><game id="14657">Heisei Shin Onigashima: Zenpen</game><game id="8715">Heisei Shin Onigashima: Kouhen</game><game id="5758">Famicom Tantei Club Part II: Ushiro ni Tatsu Shoujo</game><game id="26613">Famicom Tantei Club: Kieta Koukeisha</game><game id="37810">Nakayama Miho no Tokimeki High School</game><game id="37842">Time Twist: Rekishi no Katasumi de...</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/15/151939/2133456-yuyuki_boxarts.png</image></root>