<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37702</id><name>Thirty Flights of Loving</name><description>GameplayThirty Flights of Loving is a First Person Perspective game with a decently interactive environment. The standard controls of PC games apply, WASD Movement and mouse look with the E for interactions with the aforementioned environment. There are items that can be picked up, such as bottles of whiskey, a Skorpion vz 61, and ammunition, but there is no apparent reason to do so. The game lets the player interact and infer rather than setting them up with lengthy tutorials.PlotThirty Flights of Loving, a sequel to the previous Blendo Games joint, Gravity Bone, is a first person short story action game that was created in the Quake II engine. The story beats occur quickly and vaguely. The player takes control of a silent protagonist and quickly finds out through in-game interactions that the character is part of criminal team of three that operates out of a German bar that is smuggling various alcoholic beverages during a prohibition. The criminal team of Thirty Flights of Loving plans and executes a grand heist. Things don't go the way they were intended.Joining the player's silent protagonist, who goes unnamed through the entirety of the game, are two partners.Anita, the efficient and technically adept weapons expert and love interest to the player character. It is unlikely that the player character and Anita took interest in each other for long term reasons. Anita also really likes oranges and doesn't care where the peelings of said fruit fall.Borges, the getaway driver and operations specialist for the team. Possibly the leader of the operation and a good friend of the player character. The player's silent protagonist may be more emotionally and professionally invested in Borges than Anita. In terms of interaction with the player, there is little to none with Borges other than in the actual mission element. Borges may also be responsible for the involvement of the player character and Anita.Behind the ScenesThe Assassin from Gravity BoneGoing in depth with the game's developer commentary reveals that Brendon Chung, the Creative Director behind the game, took many lessons of direction with lighting, in-game signage, and interactivity in a First Person setting to heart when creating this game.Thirty Flights of Loving was released as a backer reward as part of the Idle Thumbs Video Game Podcast Kickstarter. Backers received access to the game via Steam code about a month before its official release.The game's music is composed by Idle Thumbs co-host Chris Remo.The Female Assassin from Gravity Bone, a previous Blendo Game, makes a cameo appearance.PC System RequirementsOS: Windows XP/Vista/7/Mac OS XProcessor: 1GHzMemory: 512 MB RAMGraphics: 60 MB OpenGL-compatibleHard Drive: 90 MB HD space</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="32874">Dinner Date</game><game id="9468">The Graveyard</game><game id="33629">Dear Esther</game><game id="29278">Gravity Bone</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/97089/2428197-30.png</image></root>