<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37715</id><name>Ratchet &amp; Clank Collection</name><description>OverviewCelebrating Ratchet  Clank's first release on the PlayStation 2, Idol Minds, with Insomniac Games, remastered the first three games to release on the PlayStation 3. The games feature 1080p visuals, 720p stereoscopic 3D, and a platinum trophy for each title.The TrilogyRatchet  ClankOriginally released in 2002, the original game received generally favourable reviews.This game shows Ratchet meeting the robot Clank for the first time. Clank discovers someone from the Blarg race called Chairman Drek plans to create a new planet for his own species, which also involves destroying the rest of the universe. Clank and Ratchet go on a journey to find the world famous Captain Qwark to help them, but find out they will go it alone.Ratchet  Clank: Going CommandoThe second game was released in 2003 and received significantly better reviews than the first game.Since the end of the first game Ratchet has a job at the company "Megacorp". His job there is to find a creature that was stolen from their laboratory called the "Protopet". After both Ratchet  Clank track down the thief and return the creature they realise that "Megacorp" are actually the people up to no good and it is up to them to stop them.Ratchet  Clank: Up Your ArsenalThe third game in the Playstation 2 trilogy was released in 2004 to good reviews and praise for the online gameplay.This games sees Ratchet  Clank take on the evil robotic villain Dr. Nefarious whose plan is to rid the universe of all organic lifeforms. The online modes include Deathmatch, Capture The Flag, and Siege modes. This online mode was retained for the Trilogy version.ReleaseThe game released on May 16, 2012 in Europe and August 28, 2012 in North America. As compensation for the delay North American copies of the Trilogy come with a voucher for early access to the Sly Cooper: Thieves in Time demo.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="36890">Jak &amp; Daxter Collection</game><game id="31788">The Sly Collection</game><game id="32696">The Ico &amp; Shadow of the Colossus Collection</game><game id="28001">God of War Collection</game><game id="33396">Splinter Cell Trilogy</game><game id="33731">The Tomb Raider Trilogy</game><game id="39248">God of War Saga</game><game id="35545">Fuse</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2303987-box_racc.png</image></root>