<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37719</id><name>The Showdown Effect</name><description>OverviewThe Showdown Effect is a 2.5D side-scrolling, multiplayer, skill based action brawler from Arrowhead Game Studios, the makers of Magicka. The gameplay draws influences from Soldat, Worms, Hunter Hunted and Super Smash Bros. just to name a few. Stylistically, conceptually and thematically, the game draws influences from action movie genre of the 80s and 90s, as well others.The game features eight playable characters, all stereotypical clichés of the archetypal action hero, each with his/her own unique abilities.The game also has an integrated feature to live stream matches to a Twitch.TV channel.CharactersAll character chosen in the game operate the same in their basic abilities such as a jump, a roll, a sprint and other basic abilities. Where the characters diverge is in their special abilities.NameSpecial AbitiesCostDutch McClonePersonal Shield: Dutch becomes nearly invulnerable for two and half seconds.FreeHailey SkyeRocket Boost: Hailey launches herself vertically into the air or when accompanied with a roll at a 45 degree angle.FreeHank StreamFrag Grenades: Hank chucks a grenade that deals serious damage.FreeMizu IchibanBlood Bath: Mizu enables a lifesteal that's cool down is reduced with every successful hit while active.Preorder BonusLord Edmund GauntletPoison Flask: Edmund throws a flask onto the ground that creates a mist of deadly poison.1,500 ACLeona WolfThe Hunt: Leona's speed slightly increases and she can now see enemies through walls as smoky clouds.1,500 ACSgt. Lance KoboldskiDoughnuts: Lance consumes doughnuts recovering a quarter of his health instantly and a quarter of his health over time.1,500 ACMr. Shur FooFury Kick: Mr. Shur Foo performs a flying kick dealing moderate damage and stun to his enemy.1,500 AC Game ModesFeatures four different free for all and team based game modes, as well as customizable rule sets and game modes.NameDescriptionShowdownFree-for-all where the last player alive. Near the end of the match a timer is started and a sudden death is initiated.Team EliminationEach death of a teammate in team elimination turns the respawn clock back 5 seconds. When the entire opposing team is dead at the same time the round is won.The ExpendablesThe Expendables is a mode that pits the Showdown cast against a group of Henchmen. The players on the 'Expendables' side have a respawn timer while the Henchmen do not. The round ends when all expendables are eliminated.One Man ArmyOne Man Army pits a one man army against a large group of Henchmen. The henchmen that kill the One Man Army becomes the replacement as a result. Just like in The Expendables, in One Man Army henchmen respawn in perpetuity.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26706">Shadow Complex</game><game id="25637">Shank</game><game id="36561">Shank 2</game><game id="13773">Soldat</game><game id="3546">Hunter Hunted</game><game id="37628">Loadout</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2331148-box_tsde.png</image></root>