<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37839</id><name>Starbound</name><description>StoryDetails have not been released about Starbound's story, however every race starts the game crashed on a unexplored planet (reasons differ per race).An early ship orbiting a planet GameplayStarbound is a two dimensional platformer with an emphasis on exploration, mining, crafting, and fighting. Players will travel from planet to planet, and have the option of following the main story quest or striking out on their own. There are many combat possibilities, with weapons ranging from small knives to rocket launchers. Besides the craftable weapons, there is also the random weapon creation system, whereby found weapons will have randomized stats (such as projectile type) and abilities similar to Borderlands. There is also a pokemon style pets system, where players can capture pets they have weakened and train them to use different abilities. These pets can then be called on to fight for the player.An early game house and farm ExplorationThe player's expandable and customizable ship serves both as home base and transport between the stars and planets of Starbound. Planets are procedurally generated, with a many different types of biomes and sub-biomes. For example a planet can be a frozen arctic biome or a heavily wooded forest biome. A given biome will vary in how it can look. A forest biome can just be a run-of-the-mill forest or it could be a forest where the trees are made of metal. See this video for an example of the diversity possible in the game. Within the overarching biomes can exist "mini biomes" such as meadows, lakes, etc.Exploring procedurally generated caves </description><genres><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre><genre id="45">Block-Breaking</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="34940">Terraria</game><game id="24741">Scribblenauts</game><game id="30475">Minecraft</game><game id="38759">Edge of Space</game><game id="23230">Cortex Command</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14230/2165185-starbound.jpg</image></root>