<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37851</id><name>Takedown: Red Sabre</name><description>OverviewThere used to be a wide range of different games to choose between within the shooter genre, from run-and-gun action titles to slow-paced tactical shooters focusing on strategy and tactics, but now most shooters follow the same model of big set pieces, regenerating health, linear levels, and “cinematic experiences”. The realistic tactical shooters with in-depth planning have almost entirely disappeared.TAKEDOWN: Red Sabre is developed by the Serellan studio based in Seattle, Washington spear-headed by acclaimed games designer Christian Allen. The game is a result of a successful Kickstarter project, where the goal was to reach enough interest to raise a minimum of $200.000 in donations. In the wake of the Kickstarter project completion, VC investors (Venture Capital) have been lined up to fuel the game with the rest of the funds needed to make this title AAA.On February 15 2013, it was announced that 505 Games had picked up the publishing for the game.This game is a spiritual successor to games like the original Rainbow Six and SWAT series realized through Unreal Engine 3.With Takedown, Serellan aims to extract what made those games great into something new and improved. It will focus on squad based play in a close-quarters battle setting. This game is described as thinking-person’s shooter. The type of player that takes things slow, aims carefully, and plans their moves right will overcome the player who runs in with guns blazing. More often than not this game will bring the fight indoors, as you would see SWAT teams or SOF units taking down small numbers of dangerous, unpredictable adversaries as opposed to the endless waves of generic enemies the shooters of today tend to throw your way. Non-linear environments allow for multiple routes and tactics and adds to the replayability.The XBLA version of the game was originally set to launch alongside the Steam version on September 20, 2013, but it was delayed after failing certification two days prior.MultiplayerBoth co-op and adversarial multiplayer has been confirmed. MLG is working with Serellan in order to ensure that gamers have all the features and support required for fun and competitive online play.PC System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows XP SP3 (32-bit only)Processor: 2GHz or better CPUMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: A graphics card with Shader Model 3.0 supportDirectX: Version 9.0Network: Broadband Internet connectionHard Drive: 3 GB available spaceRecommendedOS: Windows 7 64-bitProcessor: Intel Core2Extreme Quad Core Processor - Q6800 - 2.93 GHzMemory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: nVidia GeForce 8800 (768 MB GDDR3)DirectX: Version 9.0Network: Broadband Internet connectionHard Drive: 3 GB available space</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7887">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six</game><game id="12727">SWAT 3: Close Quarters Battle</game><game id="7288">SWAT 4</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2543320-box_tdrs.png</image></root>