<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3785</id><name>Putt-Putt Saves the Zoo</name><description>Putt-Putt Saves the Zoo is the third title in Humongous Entertainment's series of point-and-click adventures starring the anthropomorphic car Putt-Putt. The game, aimed at children aged 3 through 8, takes place in Putt-Putt's home city of Cartown, where the local zoo is preparing for its grand opening. Putt-Putt and his dog Pep are asked to deliver Zoo Chow to the Cartown Zoo by the local grocer, but when they arrive at the zoo it is revealed that the baby animals have gone missing, and it is up to the player to find them. While looking for the baby animals players get to explore a colorful, highly interactive environment filled with mini-games and NPCs.The game, like other early entries in the series, is powered by LucasArts' SCUMM engine; Ron Gilbert, creator of The Secret of Monkey Island and other point-and-click adventures from the company's early years, was one of the original founders of Humongous Entertainment.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="8">Educational</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14824">Spy Fox in "Dry Cereal"</game><game id="14441">Pajama Sam 2: Thunder and Lightning Aren't so Frightening</game><game id="3090">Fatty Bear's Birthday Surprise</game><game id="14961">Pajama Sam: Life is Rough When You Lose Your Stuff</game><game id="2373">Freddi Fish and the Case of the Missing Kelp Seeds</game><game id="15666">Freddi Fish 2: The Case of the Haunted School House</game><game id="10911">Freddi Fish 4: The Case of the Hogfish Rustlers of Briny Gulch</game><game id="18903">Pajama Sam: Games to Play on Any Day</game><game id="8430">Pajama Sam: No Need to Hide When It’s Dark Outside</game><game id="19472">Fatty Bear's FunPack</game><game id="22727">Spy Fox in: Hold the Mustard</game><game id="17987">Pajama Sam: Lost and Found</game><game id="11852">Sam &amp; Max Hit the Road</game><game id="5449">Freddi Fish and Luther's Water Worries</game><game id="13067">Freddi Fish &amp; Luther's Maze Madness</game><game id="9805">Freddi Fish's One-Stop Fun Shop</game><game id="5729">The Curse of Monkey Island</game><game id="4372">Maniac Mansion: Day of the Tentacle</game><game id="14743">Blue's 123 Time Activities</game><game id="14412">Blue's Reading Time Activities</game><game id="17810">Blue's Clues: Blue's Art Time Activities</game><game id="11848">Blue's ABC Time Activities</game><game id="5784">Blue's Treasure Hunt</game><game id="16775">Blue's Clues: Blue's Birthday Adventure</game><game id="13230">Grim Fandango</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8884/411253-puttputtzoo.jpg</image></root>