<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37894</id><name>Shadowrun Returns</name><description>OverviewShadowrun Returns is a 2.5D isometric, turn-based tactical RPG from Harebrained Schemes; a studio staffed by Shadowrun franchise veterans, as well as being led by Jordan Weisman, one of the original designers behind the Shadowrun fiction. The game will continue the hybrid theme of cyberpunk and elements of high fantasy role playing that has become synonymous with the Shadowrun name. The storyline also fits within the existing Shadowrun timeline and both the previous SNES and Genesis games.The game was funded through Kickstarter donations. These Kickstarter donations exceeded the originally asked for amount of $400,000 with an end result of $1,895,772 donated by 36,276 backers.The developers wanted the gameplay to combine the strategic turn based combat from the original X-COM and the 2012 re-imagining, with the depth of RPG customization and film noir style detective work.PC and MAC version will also be shipped with the same level editor used by the developers to create the game, allowing users to construct their own environments and original scenarios. User created content can also be uploaded and shared with the wider community.PlotIn an alternative future of 2054, set across two cities; Seattle, Washington and Berlin, Germany, the protagonist's old friend Sam - has been murdered. Sam’s sister, Jessica Watts requires help to find out what happened. The player must then go to Seattle, Washington. While at the morgue the player is met by the antagonistically hardboiled Detective Mitch Macklusky. He tells the player that Sam was another victim of an organ stealing serial killer; or killers. From there, the player will unravel more mysterious organizations and societies.MusicThe composer for the SNES version of Shadowrun, Marshall Parker, and the composer for the Genesis version of Shadowrun, Sam Powell, will collaborate on the music for Shadowrun Returns.External LinksWebsiteKickstarter PageFacebook Page PC System SettingsOS:Windows XP SP3/Vista/Windows 7Processor: x86-compatible 1.4GHz or faster processorMemory:2 GB RAMGraphics:DirectX compatible 3D graphics card with at least 256MB of addressable memoryDirectX®:9.0Hard Drive:2 GB HD spaceMAC System SettingsOS: OSX 10.5+Processor: Intel-based Macs only (x86-compatible, 1.4GHz or better)Memory: 2 GB RAMHard disk space: 2 GB HD space</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="38456">Cyberpunk 2077</game><game id="37721">Wasteland 2</game><game id="884">Jagged Alliance 2</game><game id="37152">XCOM: Enemy Unknown</game><game id="6346">Fallout Tactics: Brotherhood of Steel</game><game id="5559">Fallout 2</game><game id="11704">Fallout</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/99864/2518007-9798814274-Shado.jpg</image></root>