<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37912</id><name>1 vs. 100</name><description>Overview1 Vs. 100 is a game show/trivia game developed by EC Interactive and published by DSI Games for the Nintendo DS platform.Gameplay1 Vs. 100 is a trivia game based on the TV game show of the same name. The game contains the main game mode which is like the TV show as well as two mini games. The main game mode and both of the mini games can be played single player or with a friend. The game shows host, Bob Saget does his own voice for the game.1 Vs. 100 Mode1 Vs. 100 mode is the main mode of the game. The goal in 1 vs. 100 is to try and walk away with the most amount of money possible. Players answer a trivia question after a crowd of 100 people all secretly choose an answer. The amount of money the player can walk away with in between questions will go up with every 10 members of the mob that get the question wrong. HelpsIn the main 1 Vs. 100 mode the player has 3 different "helps" that can be used on any of the questions.Trust the Mob - Trust the Mob will lock in the players answer to that of the answer chosen by the biggest percentage of mob members.Ask the Mob - When the Ask a Mob help is used, 2 random members of the mob will be chosen, one with the correct answer and one with a wrong answer. Those two mob members answers will still be able to be chosen while the third wrong answer will be darkened out. Poll the Mob - With Poll the Mob the player can choose any one of the possible answers and then see how many members of the mob chose it.Mini Game ModesThere are two playable mini games in 1 Vs. 100. 1 Vs. 100 PokerIn 1 Vs. 100 Poker two players start with a pot of $25,000. The players receive a question and then can bet either $1,000, $2,000, or $5,000 that the question will be answered correctly. After the results are shown if the correct answer was chosen the player wins the money, if incorrect the money will be lost.TemptationIn Temptation two players are shown a category. Both players then have 5 seconds to either bet an amount of money that the answer can be achieved, or can choose to skip it. Whichever player bets first will have the first shot at answering the question. If that player chooses correctly then they will win the money, if not then it is passed to the next player.</description><genres><genre id="14">Trivia/Board Game</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="34728">Who Wants To Be A Millionaire?</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/10/103881/2171067-cover.jpg</image></root>