<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37942</id><name>Zen Pinball 2</name><description>OverviewThe new table selection dashboardMuch like Pinball FX2 did on the Xbox 360, Zen Pinball 2 is a free download on PlayStation 3  WiiU, and a free upgrade for existing owners of Zen Pinball and Marvel Pinball. While those older games are still available on PSN, this download consolidates them into one game that houses all the tables from both. It also takes advantage of Cross Buy for Vita owners, allowing any content purchased to be available on either system.Additional features:Local split-screen  hotseat multiplayer, online modes, and worldwide tournaments.Trial versions of all tables not owned, allowing players to try before they buy.Graphics  physics upgrades.New social system integrations, with friend challenges, Facebook integration, ProScore (personal performance across all tables) and TeamScore (a combined score ranking you and your friends).New rule sheets to help players better understand the mechanics of the tables.New trophies for all tables.TablesExclusive to Zen Pinball 2 (i.e. not available on Pinball FX2)Ninja Gaiden Sigma 2All other tables are available in Pinball FX2:V12El DoradoTeslaShamanStreet Fighter IIEarth DefenseExcaliburMarsParanormalSorcerer's LairEpic QuestPlants vs ZombiesMarvel PinballWolverineIron ManSpider-ManBladeStandalone Marvel Pinball tablesCaptain AmericaFantastic FourCivil WarMarvel Pinball: Vengeance and VirtueGhost RiderMoon KnightThorX-MenMarvel Pinball: Avengers ChroniclesMarvel's The Avengers MovieWorld War HulkFear ItselfThe Infinity GauntletUpcoming TablesDoctor Strange - Based on Marvel comics. To be released in 2013.Outside of Marvel tables, there are also two upcoming "major deals ... based on huge entertainment franchises". These amount to "roughly a dozen tables in the works," according a May 2012 post by the Zen Studios community manager.</description><genres><genre id="30">Pinball</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="32513">Pinball FX2</game><game id="39784">Pinball FX3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/6/63119/2256104-zen_pinball_2_vita.jpg</image></root>