<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37963</id><name>Republique</name><description>OverviewIn Republique, the player does not directly control an on-screen character Hope. Instead, they communicate with an off screen character through her contraband phone while using their device (iPhone, iPad, PC, or Mac) to manipulate security cameras, hack computers, and open and close doors to facilitate her escape from the shadowy Overseer. Not many details are released currently at this time, although it has been revealed that David Hayter will be voicing an unknown character who has left memoirs for Hope to follow and discover the truth of her current dystopia. Jenifer Hale has also been confirmed as a member of the force controlled by the Overseer.StoryRepublique's story, which is inspired by George Orwell's 1984, focuses on a captive named Hope who is attempting to escape her mysterious oppressors. By accessing an off screen character, controlled by the player, Hope will evade her captors through scenarios that the player can alter to make it possible for her to escape.GameplayThe player navigates Hope through obstacles and enemies by setting off various elements using the environment. They can expand a field of view using a widen gesture using two fingers or narrow using a pinch on the touch screen. Although not a direct set of rules have been revealed, it does appear to give the player the ability to command hope down a certain path while combating enemies using a stun gun. The concept does strike a resemblance to Ghost Trick: Phantom Detective although adding a Survival Horror real time atmosphere.CharactersHopeVery little is known about Hope's origin but so far it appears that she is captive in an environment by a group of soldiers and a faceless enemy named "The Overseer".</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19969">Lifeline</game><game id="12735">The Experiment</game><game id="28028">Ghost Trick: Phantom Detective</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1817/2175355-republique.jpg</image></root>