<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37972</id><name>Hyperdimension Neptunia Victory</name><description>OverviewHyperdimension Neptunia Victory (神次元ゲイムネプテューヌV or Kami Jigen Game Neptune V in Japan) is the third installment in the Hyperdimension Neptunia series, mainly set in an alternative continuity from its predecessors.StoryThe game takes place in 1989 after Neptune is thrown into a past version of Gamindustri. In this continuity, Planeptune is a small protected by a new CPU named Iris heart. Lastation is an area connected to Planeptune, Lowee is a traditionalist Japanese-style nation and Leanbox is a military state invading from abroad. As Neptune embarks on her adventure to return to her original timeline, she'll come across a new group of villains, both old and new to the series, known as the Seven Sages that act as the main antagonists throughout the game.CharactersMuch of the old cast in the series returns. Apart from Neptune, the Goddesses Blanc, Vert and Noire come back with new attires to fit with the time travel motif of the game with their Hard Drive Divinity forms respectively being inspired by the Famicom, the original XBox and the PS1. IF, Compa, and the CPU candidates from Hyperdimension Neptunia Mk.2 return as well. A few villains from the past series such as Pirachu and Arfoire, will return as members of the Seven Sages.GameplayThe gameplay stays close to the formula of Hyperdimension Neptunia Mk.2 with some added features, extra polish, and several less accepted changes Mk.2 made reverting to how things were handled in the original Neptunia.  The world map is now split between nations, and the player must traverse a dungeon in order to move between them.  Character portraits during evens are once again two-dimensional but with light animation.  Load times are significantly reduced, edges are smoother, and the framerate is more stable.  The battle system has received a tune-up with some simplification (particularly around HDD usage) and some added features like the new EXE attacks.  A new Challenges system keeps track of several statistics like distance run per character, damage dealt/received per character, etc., and rewards the player with permanent stat increases when certain benchmarks are achieved.  Overall story progression is handled almost identically to Mk.2, but with new types of events mixed throughout.External linksNeptunia V official website</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26556">Trinity Universe</game><game id="37766">Mugen Souls</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2452887-box_hdnv.png</image></root>