<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>37997</id><name>Mount &amp; Blade Warband: Napoleonic Wars</name><description>OverviewMount and Blade: Napoleonic Wars is an expansion for Mount and Blade: Warband that features only multiplayer. Set in early 19th century Europe during the Napoleonic wars, this expansion features five playable nations: Prussia, Austria, Russia, France, and United Kingdom.Also, it is important to note that this is not a standalone expansion and requires Mount  Blade: Warband, unlike previous expansions from the series.Gameplay and mutliplayer are similar to native Mount  Blade: Warband multiplayer, except for a restrictive class system and some additions and changes to the combat mechanics.Features5 playable nations: Prussia, Austria, Russia, France, and United KingdomHistorically accurate firearms, artillery and uniforms from the early 19th centuryNew commander mode; akin to the mode introduced from MountBlade: Fire and SwordPlayable musicians with historically accurate soundsDestructible buildingsFeatures over 40 classical music tracksSupports 200+ player matches8 game modesWeaponsHistorically accurate firearms and artillery . All classes ranging from line infantry to cannoneers can use all firearms, but only cannoneers can use artillery. All firearms, with the exception of pistols require the player to be stationary to reload.MusketsMuskets: The most common weapon on the battlefield; it has average accuracy and reloading time ,deadly damage through melee and long range(bayonet). Shots are relatively straight in 50 yards of in-game and goes into random directions after. Also, in melee mode (key-bind to X) and crouch(key-bind to Z) the player will be in a brace-mode that would kill either the horses or the rider of incoming cavalry.PistolsPistols: Quickest reloading time, worst accuracy and average damage. Usually used by the officer rank of classes.RiflesRifles: Longest reloading time, best accuracy and deadly damage. Usually used by skirmisher units such as light infantry, riflemen and the like. The melee mode of this weapon is half as deadly as the musket and shorter melee range. Carbines and cavalry musketsCarbines and cavalry muskets: Both feature above average reloading times, below average accuracy. The melee mode of the carbine is quick and low-ranged. Whereas, the melee mode of the cavalry musket lacks a bayonet and functions similar to the rifle, but slower. Swords, sabres and butter knivesSwords and sabres: Both have variants in sizes, the shorter ones usually go to the infantry-men and the rest go towards the Officers and cavalry. The damage and range is average or above average, depending on the type of sword or sabre used. Lances in yo faceLances: Mainly used by cavalry or Russian partisans, long ranged and average damage, but can be deadly if used by cavalry charges. Couch-lancing on horse can be activated via pressing X on the gallop. Women fight with swords, men fight with cannon!Cannons: Deadly damage, long ranged, slow reloading times. Can level some environments and are vary from 6-pdr to 12-pdr ranges.   Assortment of other weapons: The Russian partisans used a variety of random weapons ranging from farming equipment to a wood log.ClassesMost classes includes the following ranks: Ranker, Sergeant, Captain, Drummer, Fifer, Bugler, Piper. Armaments may differ by faction and class. Also to note that Officers and musicians give specific singular buffs for melee, accuracy or speed of reload time.Infantry classes:Have the highest stats of strength and agility. Usually highly skilled with polearms(bayonet) and firearms.Prussian infantry, foot-guards and skirmishersMilitia: Low melee and accuracyLine infantry/Line Militia: Average melee stats, average accuracy.Light Infantry: Low melee stats, better accuracy.Skirmisher: Low melee stats, great accuracy.Foot Guard / Grenadiers: Better melee stats, same accuracy as line infantry.Specialized classes:Usually have specialized roles in the battlefield.Specialized classes: British Cannoneers, Rocketeers and General *note: these are outdated modelsLower stats in terms of strength and agility and not specifically skilled in any weapons under the rank of ranker.Sappers/Engineers: Able to construct various forms of cover for infantry and cannons, as well as TNT packs to breach buildings, destroy bridges, etc.Cannoneers: Able to use artillery tools, such as the ramrod, and able to ride some horses for limbering.Ship Crew/Marines: Includes the Sailor class who, similar to the Partizani, is spawned with random weapons each time. Marines include an infantry class wielding an infantry musket. Also includes an Officer rank.Generals: Higher base defense and skilled in one-handed melee. Gives a buff that is the combination of the all the buffs given from Officers and musicians.Cavalry classes:French CavalryAll are able to ride horses, but have low stats in strength and agility compared to infantry.Dragoons: Skilled in firearms and one-handed melee.Hussars : Highly skilled with one-handed melee.Lancers: Highly skilled with polearms.Cuirassiers/Carabineer/Heavy Cavalry : Very high base defense and skilled with one-handed meleeGame ModesConquestCapturing and holding as many flags as possible. Respawn is available corresponding to the number of tickets available to each faction. If your enemies’ ticket reaches zero or capture all the flags you won the battle.Commander BattleTake control of bots into line-battles with or against other players.BattleTwo factions set against each other with no respawns.SiegeWhere you try to capture or defend the fort via holding the flag in the middle of the fort. Usually the attackers have unlimited respawns, whereas the defenders are limited.Capture the FlagTry to capture the other team's flag.Team DeathmatchTwo factions against each other with unlimited respawns.DeathmatchA free for all with respawn available.DuelChallenge another player to a 1 versus 1 match for a contest of skill and honour.FactionsMount  Blade: Napoleonic Wars will have five historically accurate factions upon release: Kingdom of Prussia, Austrian Empire, Russian Empire, French Empire, and United Kingdom.French EmpireFranceLed by Napoleon Bonaparte, the French Empire in 1812 was the most powerful continental European state. Although, the disastrous Russian invasion of late 1812 led to her downfall in 1814 as the coalition of opposing European powers marched into the heart of France. The exiled emperor returns in 1815, ready to fight against all of Europe once again to regain his and France's former glory.United KingdomUnited KingdomThe British Empire is steadfast in the expansion of her holdings and influence in the world, but there is growing problem back in the continental side; the French Empire. Now, with the return of Napoleon in the reins of France. Britain once again pressures other European powers to form another coalition against France.Kingdom of PrussiaPrussiaPrussia's humiliation and subjugation from France in 1806 was a hard lesson to Kingdom of Prussia, but it was a well learned lesson. The Fatherland's army has been reformed to early 19th century standards from a inept relic of the "Seven Years' War" ready to fight for their homes and family against the French Empire.AustriaAustrian EmpireThe early periods of the Napoleonic Wars has left the Holy Roman Empire into shambles with numerous lands lost to France. Now, the newly named empire under the name of the Austrian Empire is ready to strike back at France for the honour lost.Russian EmpireRussiaThroughout most of the Napoleonic Wars Russia has always been patient and slow to move, albeit humbled by the French Empire on occasion. Nevertheless, her soldiers are brave and obedient, patriotic fueled defiance towards French influence at the ready. The ambitious Czar of the Russian Empire now seeks out not lands, but to defeat Napoleon to "save Europe" from French dominance.ModsThe Union Army units as of version 0.3North  South: First Manassas :A ongoing American Civil War mod for Napoleonic Wars; currently a complete re-texture of the game with some slight tweaks in game-play, i.e. firearm accuracy.Spanish line infantrySpanish Faction:A retexture of either the British or Austrian factions for Spanish units. Currently it is incomplete, backing up folders such as resources,textures and the like is highly advised.Some Italian and French unitsKingdom of Italy Faction:A re-texture of the French faction for Italian units. Currently it is incomplete, backing up folders such as resources,textures and the like is highly advised.Development HistoryThis expansion is a spiritual successor to a highly active multiplayer mod called MountMusket. The mod developers of the MountMusket, now under the company name of Flying Squirrels Entertainment obtained the license to use the Warband engine and with the aid from Taleworlds were able to optimized and improve the engine. A Quote from Vincenzo on the announcement of the upcoming expansion, a developer from Flying Squirrels Entertainment :" It has finally come to the point where we can show you what we have been working on the past year. Some of you may already have seen it, but for those who haven’t, please take somemoments to read the announcement here:http://www.paradoxplaza.com/press/2012/3/mount-blade-warband-napoleonic-wars-multiplayer-dlc-announcedWatch the announcement trailer here:http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XPv56deYrsQSo what does this mean? Well, first of all - MountMusket: Battalion doesn’t exist anymore. It is now MountBlade Warband: Napoleonic Wars - a multiplayer-only DLC that you can buy for Mount  Blade: Warband. We hope you will find it even more enjoyable than the mod ever was.The base is still there - the idea of large multiplayer battles, trying to realistically show the Napoleonic Wars while still maintaining enjoyable and rewarding gameplay. But it is now wrapped in a new shiny and professional package. We re-made it completely from scratch: bigger, better and more. Graphics have been vastly improved with new beautiful units and environments - while focusing on performance means it will run just as good as, and hopefully even better than, before." (From thehttp://forums.taleworlds.com/index.php/topic,222384.0.html)System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Windows® XP, Vista, Windows 7Processor: Intel Pentium 4 2.0 GHz or AMD 2.5 GHzMemory: 1GB RAMHard Disk Space: 1.2 GB available spaceVideo Card: Graphics card (128 MB+) (does not support integrated graphics card)DirectX®: Directx 9.0cSound: Direct X-compatible sound cardRecommended:OS: Windows® XP, Vista, Windows 7Processor: Intel Core Duo 2.0 GHz or AMD Athlon 64 X2 3600+Memory: 2GB RAMHard Disk Space: 1.2 GB available spaceVideo Card: NVIDIA GeForce 8600, ATI Radeon HD 2600, or better (does not support integrated graphics card)DirectX®: Directx 9.0cSound: Direct X-compatible sound card</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="27879">Napoleon: Total War</game><game id="20509">Empire: Total War</game><game id="41179">Caribbean!</game><game id="39594">March of the Eagles</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2188511-box_mabwnw.png</image></root>