<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38028</id><name>Sir, You Are Being Hunted</name><description>OverviewSir, You Are Being Hunted provides a unique twist on survival gameplay by thrusting the player into a strange world featuring hostile humanoid robots. Players are tasked with surviving the continuous threat of the hunting robots while foraging for supplies to ensure survival. Finding mythical runes spread out across the vast island that hold the key to escaping, and eventually escaping from the island and your robotic adversaries. It is expected to launch for Mac, PC, and Linux in August 2013.KickstarterTowards the end of 2012, the game was put up on Kickstarter in order for developer Big Robot to secure more funding via "crowd funding" with the hopes of getting the game funded. By the end of 2012 when the Kickstarter funding window had closed, the game had secured roughly £92,551 ($141,223 US Dollars), far more than the original £40,000 ($61,036 US Dollars) goal that was set for Sir, You Are Being Hunted. Several stretch goals were also exceeded, adding new elements to the game like new enemies (Hot Air Spotter Patrols, The Riders, The Landowner), new in-game biomes (Castle Biome), the ability to hunt various wildlife in order to harvest food, and even a 4-player multiplayer mode.AlphaSir, You Are Being Hunted is currently in a closed alpha version only accessible to those who met a certain donation goal on the game's Kickstarter page. At this time, roughly 900 players who contributed to the game have early access to Sir, You Are Being Hunted.BetaAccess to a public beta version of Sir, You Are Being Hunted for those who have pre-ordered the game will be released on August 19th, 2013.EnemiesThere are several types of dangerous enemies in Sir, You Are Being Hunted. From gun-toting robots who scour the landscape in their attempts to find you along with their loyal robot canine companions to more fearsome, dangerous foes, it won't be easy keeping out of their clutches for long. Enemies listed below:Robots: Gun-toting robots who scour the island endlessly searching for your current whereabouts in the quest to kill you. Each robot carries a rifle and are quite eager to pump you full of lead. Dangerous in groups!Robot Dogs: Loyal robotic canine companions to the robots that wander the island, they will attack and give chase if you fall into their clutches.Hot Air Spotter Patrols: Sentry balloons that silently hover in the air scanning the environment for your whereabouts. If it's sweeping sensors pick you up, prepare to run for your life as it not only summons robots to your location, but it shoots you as well!The Riders: Think of the legendary red-coated riders who perform the fox hunts in England with a pack of hounds, only this time they are robotic in nature and are hunting you! These adversaries give chase, so be prepared to run for the hills!The Landowner: An elite version of the standard-issue robots that relentlessly hunts you with his superior tracking skills and his deadly aim. A true force to be reckoned with and someone you should fear if you are unfortunate enough to cross paths with his red-eyed gaze.The Squire: A specialized robot that wanders around rural areas near the various houses that can be found on certain islands, the Squire will go after those who dare enter their patrol area to loot the in-game houses.The Scarecrow: A scarecrow that stalks the player in the corn fields, acting as a siren which attracts other near by enemies to your location. It's behavior resembles that of Slenderman.System RequirementsPCMinimumOS: Windows 7, Windows 8Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo, AMD Athlon X2, or equal at 1.6GHz or betterMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: DirectX 9.0c-compatible, SM 3.0-compatibleDirectX: Version 9.0cHard Drive: 500 MB available spaceSound Card: DirectX 9.0c-compatible, 16-bitRecommendedOS: Windows 7, Windows 8Processor: QuadCore 2.0 GHz +Memory: 8 GB RAMGraphics: NVIDIA GeForce 8800 GTS or better, 512MB+ VRAMDirectX: Version 9.0cHard Drive: 500 MB available spaceSound Card: DirectX 9.0c-compatible, 16-bitMacMinimumOS: 10.7.5 (Lion)Processor: 2.2 GHz Intel Core 2 DuoMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: IntegratedHard Drive: 500 MB available spaceRecommendedOS: 10.8.2 (Mountain Lion)Processor: 2.4 GHz Intel Quad CoreMemory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: Nvidia Geforce GT 120 / ATI Radeon HDHard Drive: 500 MB available spaceLinuxMinimumOS: Ubuntu 12.04Processor: 2.2 GHz Intel Core 2 DuoMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: DirectX 9.0c-compatible, SM 3.0-compatibleHard Drive: 500 MB available spaceRecommendedOS: Ubuntu 12.04Processor: QuadCore 2.0 GHz +Memory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: Nvidia Geforce GT 120 / ATI Radeon HDHard Drive: 500 MB available space</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/97089/2495490-1.png</image></root>