<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38040</id><name>007 Legends</name><description>Overview007: Legends is a first-person shooter developed by Eurocom and published by Activision for the Xbox 360 and PlayStation 3 on October 16, 2012 and the PC on November 1, 2012. Players reprise the role of secret agent James Bond (with the likeness of Daniel Craig) as he relives missions based on five classic James Bond movies: Goldfinger, On Her Majesty's Secret Service, Licence to Kill, Die Another Day, and Moonraker. The game is a spiritual sequel to Goldeneye 007: Reloaded (using the same game engine and sharing the same game modes) and was made to commemorate the 50th anniversary (as of October 5th, 2012) of James Bond on film. The game is also a video game tie-in to the 2012 film Skyfall (released a month after this game).Legends also includes an experience point system. Players can earn XP for reaching certain in-game milestones, e.g. killing a certain number of villains with a named gun, hacking a certain number of terminals, completing objectives, etc. These points can then be spent on upgrading weapons, gadgets or Bond's physical abilities.StoryIn similar vein to Hitman: Contracts, the overall narrative of the game ties everything together as a near-death experience, with Bond's mind being drawn to past events after being grievously wounded on his most recent mission in Istanbul (during the events of the movie Skyfall). He begins to remember five of his previous assignments (in which players reenact as Bond):Investigating the gold-smuggling operations of wealthy gold dealer Auric Goldfinger in Goldfinger's plant of operations in Switzerland. Along the way, he encounters Goldfinger's personal pilot (Pussy Galore) and bodyguard (the mysterious Oddjob). He is also assisted by friend and CIA agent Felix Leiter. Based on the film Goldfinger.Assaulting the lair of terrorist organization leader Ernst Blofeld on the peak of the Swiss Alps (while rescuing his fiancée, Tracy di Vicenzo). Based on the film On Her Majesty's Secret Service.Infiltrating the base of Mexican drug lord Franz Sanchez (with the intent for revenge after the attack on his friend and then-DEA agent Felix Leiter and the murder of Felix's wife) in the fictional Republic of Isthmus. He is assisted by Pam Bouvier, an undercover CIA informant. Based on the film Licence to Kill.Investigating a scientific demonstration of the "Icarus" project by British entrepreneur Gustav Graves in Iceland. He is assisted by NSA agent Giacinta 'Jinx' Johnson. Along the way, he encounters the mysterious North Korean terrorist Zao. Based on the film Die Another Day.Infiltrating the spaceport facility of billionaire industrialist Hugo Drax in Brazil. Along the way, he is assisted by CIA agent Holly Goodhead. He also encounters Drax's bodyguard, the giant steel-toothed Jaws. Based on the film Moonraker.After completing these assignments, players re-enact the chase sequence leading to the prologue cutscene (where we learn that Bond, along with MI6 field agent Eve, must chase down a mercenary named Patrice, who murdered another MI6 agent and stole personal details of undercover NATO agents).After the chase sequence, where we learn that Bond survives the near-death experience, Bond tracks the mercenary to Shanghai, where he must stop him from assassinating a target.Because the game was released prior to the 2012 Skyfall movie, the final missions in the game (both the Istanbul chase and the Shanghai encounter, both based on the film) were deliberately left out as free downloadable content. It was released on November 10, 2012 for the PlayStation 3 and on November 20, 2012 for the Xbox 360 and PC.LevelsMission 01. GoldfingerAuric EnterprisesFort KnoxMission 02. On Her Majesty's Secret ServiceAlpine ValleyBlofeld's LairMission 03. License to KillRefineryMountain RoadsMission 04. Die Another DayIce HotelIce LakeGraves' Cargo PlaneMission 05. MoonrakerSpace PortSpace StationChallenge ModeSimilar to Spec Ops Mode from recent Call of Duty games, there are ten additional challenges - special missions which take place in the same environments as the regular missions. Missions are split into four categories; assault, elimination, stealth and defense, and some allow you to play as characters other than James Bond, such as Oddjob.This mode encourages players to compete for high scores via online leaderboards. Each challenge gives the player the option of adjusting around ten variables which effect the difficult of the mission, e.g. number of enemies, health regeneration speed, enemy aggression, ammo scarcity, etc. Adjusting these variables has the additional effect of changing your score multiplier, which is applied to your base score at the end of each mission. The leaderboards also give you the option of automatically setting your difficult settings to that of any player who has already posted a score.MultiplayerThe game includes a few staple first person shooter modes and provides 4 player split screen local play as well as online support.PC System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows® XP/ Windows® Vista / Windows® 7Processor: Intel® Core™ 2 Duo E6600 or AMD Phenom™ X3 8750 processor or betterMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: Shader 3.0 or better NVIDIA® GeForce™ 9600GT 512MB / ATI® Radeon™ HD 3870 512MB or betterDirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 10 GB HD spaceSound: DirectX® 9.0c compatibleRecommendedOS: Windows XP, Vista or Windows 7CPU: Any Quad core processorRAM: 4 GBHDD: 10 GB free disk spaceGraphics: 1 GB Graphics MemorySound Card: DirectX 9 CompatibleDirectX: Version 9Supported Video CardMinimum – NVIDIA GeForce 9600 GT / ATI Radeon HD 3870 or betterRecommended – NVIDIA GeForce GTS 450 or AMD Radeon HD 6750 (suggested)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26423">Call of Duty: Black Ops</game><game id="38039">Call of Duty: Black Ops II</game><game id="14782">Far Cry</game><game id="20665">Far Cry 2</game><game id="29336">Medal of Honor</game><game id="37580">Medal of Honor: Warfighter</game><game id="35850">Dishonored</game><game id="36178">Outdoors Unlimited</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2331078-box_007l.png</image></root>