<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38047</id><name>Soul Sacrifice</name><description>OverviewSoul Sacrifice is an action role-playing game with a multiplayer focus. The "Sacrifice" part of the title depicts how magic will be used in the game: in order to cast various kinds of magic, players will need to "make payment" through sacrificing certain objects. Elements such as stones and trees can be used for weaker kinds of magic, however for stronger spells players will need higher sacrifices such as body parts to summon creatures. The more a player uses magic, the more they lose their humanity; coming to resemble more and more as the beasts they slay who also lost their humanity by abusing magic.GameplayThe playable character will be able to be chosen from multiple types and customizable to a player's preferences, based on the basic template of sorcerer.MP is not the resource used to utilize magic as is typical for the RPG genre, however players must make sacrifices such as losing blood to attack the enemy or sacrificing their life to obtain Excalibur.When players defeat an enemy, they can choose to either sacrifice it or to revive/help it. Players will receive different things depending on what they choose to do.Four players can play Soul Sacrifice together simultaneously. When going against boss creatures, all of the players must decide to either sacrifice or save the creature. They don't need to agree, however what occurs when players don't agree is unknown at this point.DevelopmentThe game's origin came from when Keiji Inafune left Capcom and thought about a number of ideas for potential projects. He ended up coming with an idea that seemed to befit the Vita, so he presented it to Sony. The multiplayer of the game is a core aspect of it, so the Vita was a platform of choice.According to the game's director, Keiji Inafune, the principal concept of the game is named "True Fantasy". The "true" part comes from the fact that, in life, to obtain something good, sacrifices must be made. This is what the development seeks to demonstrate with their take on fantasy.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="27204">Gods Eater Burst</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2478700-box_ss.png</image></root>