<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38064</id><name>New Super Mario Bros. 2</name><description>OverviewThe game was formally announced during Nintendo's Direct video presentation on April 21, 2012. A number of screenshots were shown, featuring Mario in a Raccoon Suit (including P-Wing meter!) along with a Golden Mario and golden enemies. The game will be released worldwide in both physical retail form and as a digital download via the eShop, making it the first Nintendo-published game to be released in such a manner.GameplayNew Super Mario Bros. 2, like previous entries in the New Super Mario Bros. series, is a side-scrolling platformer built in the vein of the earlier Super Mario Bros. titles on the NES. This entry, however, puts a greater emphasis on coin collection. A new fire flower-like power-up grants Mario the power to turn enemies and blocks that are in his path into coins.MultiplayerDuring its 3DS showcase at E3 2012, Nintendo revealed that New Super Mario Bros. 2 would feature local 2-Player co-op with Mario and Luigi throughout the full game, as opposed to the original New Super Mario Bros. that had a dedicated Battle Mode for multiplayer. Both players have to stay on the screen at all times. If one of them fails to do so, they fly behind the other player in a bubble as if they had died and the other has to pop them out of it. The camera orientation in the cooperative mode begins centered on the player who is hosting the session, however each player can then fight for control of the orientation by ground-pounding the other.StreetPass FunctionalityThe game's use of StreetPass encompasses a competitive mode reminiscent of EA's autolog/battlelog. Since this game is all about gold coins, there are special challenges that make players run through three levels in a row with only one life with the goal to collect the most gold coins possible. This data then gets shared via StreetPass and other players can then challenge the high scores achieved by the original player.DLCDuring their post-E3 Nintendo Direct presentation, the company announced that the game would also support downloadable content in the form of new Coin Rush stages. Unlike past Nintendo DLC, this would be offered for a price.ReceptionNew Super Mario Bros. 2 became the fourth 3DS game in the United States to surpass 1 million units sold, with a total of more than 1.45 million as of January, 2013.Compatible 3DS FeaturesNintendo NetworkMii SupportLocal Play (2 Player Co-op)StreetPassSpotPasseShop VersionSize: 2950 blocks (369 MB)</description><genres><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="39484">Giana Sisters: Twisted Dreams</game><game id="44033">Giana Sisters: Twisted Dreams - Rise of the Owlverlord</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2266525-box_nsmb2.png</image></root>