<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38081</id><name>Legends of Eisenwald</name><description>OverviewLegends of Eisenwald is independent developer Aterdux Entertainment's second game. It's a mix of RPG and strategy that uses turn based combat on an economic scale. A heavy emphasis will be on story, and tailoring that story to the players class. The developers describe it as a 'Knight-Errant simulator', with a variety of units, skill trees, spells, and a world full of Castles to conquer.SettingThe setting is more medieval than fantasy, the developers using the term 'medieval mysticism' to describe the world. While magic exists, there are no elementals to be summoned, or fireballs to be thrown. Instead the game takes a more realistic edge with a focus on alchemy and the devine.The world itself is dangerous place, where 'Heroes' forge lives seeking after their own selfish motives, as opposed to saving the world or fighting for the honour of the gods. Instead they fight for love, revenge and power.LocalisationAnnounced so far:EnglishRussianSystem RequirementsMinimumOS: XP, Vista, 7Processor: 2 GHz dual-core CPUMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: 512 MB graphics memory, shader model 3 (Radeon HD 4600, GeForce 8600)DirectX: Version 9.0cHard Drive: 2 GB available spaceAdditional Notes: Screen resolution 1280x1024; Dedicated video card requiredRecommendedOS: XP, Vista, 7Processor: 3 GHz quad-core CPUMemory: 4 MB RAMGraphics: 1024 MB graphics memory, shader model 3 (GeForce GTX 260, Radeon HD 5770 or better)DirectX: Version 9.0cHard Drive: 2 GB available spaceAdditional Notes: Screen resolution 1680x1050 or higher; Dedicated video card requiredExternal LinksKickstarter PageSteam Early AccessDeveloper's Website</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10935">Darklands</game><game id="19690">King's Bounty</game><game id="1915">Heroes of Might and Magic V</game><game id="19052">Disciples II: Rise of the Elves</game><game id="15406">Disciples II: Dark Prophecy</game><game id="16006">Disciples II: Guardians of the Light</game><game id="18102">Disciples II: Servants of the Dark</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9407/2185634-eisenwald.jpg</image></root>