<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38144</id><name>Leisure Suit Larry in the Land of Lounge Lizards RELOADED</name><description>OverviewLeisure Suit Larry Reloaded is an updated point-and-click version of the original. Along with updating the visuals and the sound, Replay Games has eliminated the penalty for death (when you die, you start at a safe point before the cause of death) and for losing all your money. The controls are similar to those found in Leisure Suit Larry VI - by right clicking, you switch through options like Look, Use, Unzip, Smell/Taste, or whatever inventory item you currently are holding.The series' raunchy humor has also been updated for 2013, and while the set-up for the gags is still essentially the same, specific lines have been altered to reflect the passage of time since the original game's release. The game follows the misadventures of Larry Laffer, a "loveable loser" as the series is fond of calling him. Larry arrives in the city of Lost Wages looking to lose his virginity and possibly find love.The game was the result of a successful Kickstarter campaign.System RequirementsPCOS: Win 7, Vista and XPProcessor: 1.8 or 2.5 GhzMemory: 2 GB RAM (4 GB RAM)Graphics: Direct X 9.0c or Direct X 9.0c compatible video card with 256 MB RAMDirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 4 GB HD spaceMacOS: Mac OS X or BetterProcessor: Intel 1.8Ghz or higherMemory: 4 GB RAMHard Drive: 4 GB HD space</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9038">Softporn Adventure</game><game id="9648">King's Quest</game><game id="2634">Space Quest 6: Roger Wilco in the Spinal Frontier</game><game id="9815">Space Quest II: Chapter II - Vohaul's Revenge</game><game id="152">Police Quest 3: The Kindred</game><game id="2912">Police Quest 2: The Vengeance</game><game id="147">Police Quest: In Pursuit of the Death Angel</game><game id="12901">Daryl F. Gates' Police Quest: Open Season</game><game id="3019">The Secret of Monkey Island</game><game id="5729">The Curse of Monkey Island</game><game id="9058">Escape from Monkey Island</game><game id="32796">Tales of Monkey Island</game><game id="1256">King's Quest III: To Heir is Human</game><game id="2240">King's Quest VI: Heir Today, Gone Tomorrow</game><game id="14195">King's Quest II: Romancing the Throne</game><game id="16771">King's Quest V: Absence Makes the Heart Go Yonder</game><game id="409">King's Quest IV: The Perils of Rosella</game><game id="10656">Roberta Williams' King's Quest VII: The Princeless Bride</game><game id="9949">King's Quest: Mask of Eternity</game><game id="13230">Grim Fandango</game><game id="4372">Maniac Mansion: Day of the Tentacle</game><game id="2037">Maniac Mansion</game><game id="14075">Gabriel Knight: Sins of the Fathers</game><game id="1353">The Beast Within: A Gabriel Knight Mystery</game><game id="2845">Gabriel Knight 3: Blood of the Sacred, Blood of the Damned</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2520105-desura_960x1320.jpg</image></root>