<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38240</id><name>Family Guy: Back to the Multiverse</name><description>FAMILY GUY: Back To The Multiverse is a third person, action-adventure game, based on the popular T.V. series. Like the Stewie chapter of the previous console title, the game's villain will be Bertram, Stewie's just as sinister half-brother. The plot is a continuation of the episode 'The Big Bang Theory' and sees Stewie and Brian pursue Bertram through various universes, featuring some from the episode 'Road to the Multiverse', and Bertram sending henchman to kill Stewie (after discovering that Stewie is going to kill him).The story mode will feature co-operative multiplayer with players taking control of either Stewie or Brian along with some competitive multiplayer modes and challenge modes. It will feature characters familiar to fans of the franchise including more playable characters which will be unlocked as the player progresses through the game, along with additional costumes and multiplayer maps. Each character is said to have individual skills which will also separate it from it's last console-based title. The game has a similar graphical style to it's predecessor (resembling the TV series). This outing however has a bit more sharpness and higher overall graphical fidelity to reflect the franchise coming to the 'new' console generation. The game itself will also feature additional content and concepts from more of the long running show's previous episodes.PC System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Windows® XP/ Windows® Vista / Windows® 7Processor: Intel® Core™ 2 Duo E2180 @ 2.00 GHz or AMD Athlon 64 X2 4000+ processor or betterMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: NVIDIA® GeForce™ 8800GT 256MB/ ATI® Radeon™ HD 3450 256MB or betterDirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 6 GB HD spaceSound: DirectX® 9.0c compatibleOther Requirements: Broadband Internet connectionOther Requirements: Broadband Internet connection Additional: Internet connection is for Steam only. No online MP.</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5899">Futurama</game><game id="8845">South Park</game><game id="36978">South Park: The Stick of Truth</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2341980-box_fguybotm.png</image></root>