<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38446</id><name>Divinity: Original Sin</name><description>OverviewDivinity: Original Sin allows you to control a party, which consists of two characters in the beginning:A woman who has recently been resurrectedA condemned warrior who has suffered years of agony and tortureDuring the course of the game, you will either control both characters independently in the single player mode or have separate players controlling separate characters in multiplayer co-op. Along with multiplayer co-op control, a co-op dialogue decision system (much like that found in Star Wars: The Old Republic) will allow both players the ability to make decisions within the game's world.The world itself will be far more interactive than any previous iteration of the games. Almost everything can be directly interacted with, while some objects can offer bonuses. One example is that a mushroom on the ground can be picked up and applied to your weapon in order to give it a few stacks of a poison damage buff.The game will also feature a deep magic system that allows you to take advantage of reactive spells. As an example, if you cast an ice spell and it freezes something, you can then cast fire and it will cause the ice to melt. After that, you could cast a lightning spell and it will electrocute the enemy in the melted ice water.Divinity: Original Sin will ship with a full level editor using many of the same tools that Larian has used to make the Divinity games in recent years, and any adventures/areas/etc will be made available through direct interface built into the game for players to download and use.Unlike previous Divinity games, Larian Studios is self publishing the game and started a Kickstarter campaign.  Unlike other crowd funded games, Divinity: Original Sin is close to being finished and the Kickstarter funds will be used to increase the size of the development team and greatly expand the scope of the game.  Links Official Website </description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9789">Beyond Divinity</game><game id="5985">Diablo</game><game id="52">Baldur's Gate</game><game id="5242">Icewind Dale</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/19306/2219819-divinityosboxart.jpg</image></root>