<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38461</id><name>Tiny and Big: Grandpa's Leftovers</name><description>OverviewTiny and Big: Grandpa's Leftovers is a physics based, action-adventure, platforming, sandbox game, developed and published by Black Pants Game Studios released for PC, Linux and Mac, on June 19 2012. The game is a sandbox in which you need to solve puzzles presented to you using various tools including a ray cutter, a grappling-device, and rockets.The player controls Tiny, an inventor with a penchant for destruction. After Tiny's nemesis Big steals Tiny's late Grandfather's pants - the only thing left to Tiny by his Grandfather - Tiny must traverse "the Forsaken Desert" to reclaim these stolen pants. His only ally is "the Radio", though it is not made clear whether his benefactor is someone using the radio to speak to Tiny, or if the device he is carrying has some sort of artificial intelligence within it.SoundtrackThe game has a 15+ song soundtrack composed entirely by indie bands; throughout the game, players collect songs from the soundtrack, in the form of cassette tapes.3typen - Pretty Little Thing - produced by 3typenSeven That Spells - Black Om Rising - written by Niko PotocnjakOnda Bidon - Me Abborezzco Cada Vez Que Llego Tarde - written by Luis ManitaMr Noone - Retro Blues - written by Christian NiemandThe Voodoo Trombone Quartet - Cold Reader - written by Paul Thorpe3 Body Problem - Thoroughbred - written by Jonas GigerThe Cromagnon Band - Lusitania - written by Tom WattWilliam Honda - The Dirt - written by Ingo WillamCosmic Analog Ensemble - Cordes Discordes - written by Charif Megarbane3 Body Problem- The Wudu - written by Jonas GigerMan And Birdmen  Giallos Flame - Day of the Revenge - written by Sevi Landolt, Giallos FlameMan And Birdmen  Giallos Flame - Sport Acapulco - written by Sevi LandoltDJ Phoney - The Rise  Fall - written by Dirk BorrmannWilliam Honda - STAMPEDE - written by Ingo Willam3 Body Problem - SATURN ONE - written by Jonas GigerAntares - Padanum - written by Peter SchmidSeven That Spells - Daktari - written by Niko PotocnjakSystem RequirementsPCMinimumRecommendedOS: Windows XPProcessor: Core 2 Duo / Athlon X2, at least 2 GHzMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: ATI Radeon 2400 or better / NVIDIA GeForce 8600 or betterHard Drive: 1500 MB HD spaceSound: OpenAL compatibleAdditional Notes: 3 button mouse or Xbox 360 controller recommended. Requires Open GL drivers.OS: Windows 7Graphics: ATI Radeon 2900 or better / NVIDIA GeForce 8800 or betterDirectX®: dx9Additional Notes: 3 button mouse or Xbox 360 controller recommended. Requires Open GL drivers.MacMinimumRecommendedOS: 10.5Processor: Intel Core DuoMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: ATI Radeon 2400 or better / NVIDIA 8600M or betterHard Drive: 1500 MB HD spaceAdditional Notes: 3 button mouse or Xbox 360 controller recommended.Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo / Core i5Memory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: ATI Radeon 2800 XT or better / NVIDIA GeForce 9600 or betterAdditional Notes: 3 button mouse or Xbox 360 controller recommended.</description><genres><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2906">Psychonauts</game><game id="40874">Oozi Earth Adventure</game><game id="38186">Gunman Clive</game><game id="42389">A Hat in Time</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/81005/2240680-box_tnb.jpg</image></root>