<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38488</id><name>Rift: Storm Legion</name><description>OverviewRIFT: Storm Legion is being developed by Trion Worlds. The game is set to release on the 13th of November 2012.StoryAfter the long war between the Guardians and Defiants, they have now placed their differences beside them, and banded together against a much greater foe, Crucia. The ascended now delve into the time-lost lands of Bravane and Dusken, to face the might of Crucia's colossi, enourmous beasts and mechanical wonders. Within these lands the ascended shall discover the Infinity Gate, which is a port and tool for Crucia, to invade the beautiful land, Telera.Crucia, her dragon form and the Infinity Gate.In the picture to the left, Crucia herself is pictured in the foreground, with her army beneath her, and then her dragon form roaring across the battlefield. In the far background, you can see the Infinity Gate, which she uses to transport her hordes of monsters, beasts and mechanical colossi.The gate will make Crucia able to transport her mechanical wonders through to Telara, to overtake it once and for all.New key featuresTwo huge new continents, tripling the size of the already existing world.A new stronghold for both the Guardians and Defiant.Increased level cap by 10 levels, increasing the cap to 60.4 complete new souls, 1 for each class.7 new dungeons.3 new raids (two 20-man, one 10-man).An all new chronicle.Housing! Players will now be able to customize their very own sliver, for housing and guild halls as well.Cape system, for showing off which guild you represent or a design of your own.New puzzles, artifacts and collectibles, achievements, mounts, pets, titles, and much more.Release infoRIFT: Storm Legion will be released on the 13th of November, 2012 in various formats. The Digital Standard Edition will only include the base game for 24,99 €, but new players are able to buy a combo pack with both RIFT and RIFT: Storm Legion + 30 days of game time, for 34,99 €.Purchase options.If you pre-order any edition of RIFT: Storm Legion, you will receive a Storm Warden's Cape + early access for one of the seven new dungeons, a few weeks before the launch of RIFT: Storm Legion.The Digital Collector's Edition (Infinity Edition) will only include the base game, as well a Brevanic Portal Generator (a portable porticulum), a Cyclone mount and a Mini Regulos companion pet, for a price of 34,99 €. New players are able to make the same deal as the standard edition, where they get the base game of RIFT + RIFT: Storm Legion Infinity Edition + 30 days of game time, for 44,99 €.Players are also able to make the deal of getting RIFT: Storm Legion essentially for free, when they buy a 12-month subscription for RIFT for 107,88 €. By doing so, they will also receive a special "Landslide" mount, as well as the title, "Stormbringer".Official websitehttp://stormlegion.riftgame.com/PC system requirementsMinimumOS: Windows XP, Vista or 7Processor: Dual Core 2.0 GHz or betterMemory: 2 GBGraphics: Nvidia GeForce FX 5900, ATI/AMD Radeon X300, Intel GMA X4500 or better.DirectX®: 9.0c, June 2010 updateHard Drive: 8.0 GB availableSound: DirectX 8.1 compliant cardOther: Broadband internet connection (DSL, cable modem or other high speed connection)RecommendedOS: Windows XP, Vista or 7Processor: Core 2 Duo 2.2 GHz or betterMemory: 4 GBDesktop Graphics: Nvidia GTS 250 or betterNotebook Graphics: Nvidia GTX 200M series or betterDirectX®: 9.0c, June 2010 updateHard Drive: 8.0 GB availableSound: DirectX 8.1 compliant cardOther: Broadband internet connection (DSL, cable modem or other high speed connection)</description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10796">EverQuest</game><game id="18547">EverQuest II</game><game id="36734">World of Warcraft: Mists of Pandaria</game><game id="27896">World of Warcraft: Cataclysm</game><game id="20701">World of Warcraft: Wrath of the Lich King</game><game id="18603">World of Warcraft: The Burning Crusade</game><game id="17494">Guild Wars</game><game id="20666">Warhammer Online: Age of Reckoning</game><game id="9641">Age of Conan: Hyborian Adventures</game><game id="27876">Age of Conan: Rise of the Godslayer</game><game id="21223">Guild Wars 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3361/2336021-storm_legion.jpeg</image></root>