<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38507</id><name>Assassin's Creed III: Liberation</name><description>OverviewAssassin's Creed III: Liberation stars a female assassin by the name of Aveline de Grandpré who is of French  African heritage. The story takes place during 1765 and 1780 in the period between the end of the French and Indian war up to the middle of the American Revolution. The game will feature multiplayer "tailored specifically to the Vita experience."The game can be linked with the PS3 version of Assassin's Creed III to unlock new and exclusive content. Exclusive content will include Connor's (Assassin's Creed III's protagonist) tomahawk, a character skin, a multiplayer character and all ammunition pouches being upgraded.Unlike previous games in the series, the player will not be exploring the ancestral memories of Desmond Miles. Instead the game will feature a historical simulation that has been altered by the Templars to make themselves look like the good guys. By identifying and assassinating people who have been added by the Templars, the player can then disrupt the simulation and uncover the true course of events.PlotAveline, the main character of Liberation.Aveline de Grandpré is a byproduct of a wealthy French father and a free African slave during the 18th century in New Orleans. At an early age, Aveline was separated from her mother while chasing a chicken and never saw her again, while narrowly escaping a slave auction from which she was rescued by her mentor, escaped slave Agaté. Years later, she is found to be defending herself from a group of guards and returns to her father's Bruce Wayne-esque manor secretly through the second floor to change into more appropriate garb.Her family is partially responsible for naval trading in the Caribbean and the east coast of America during Revolutionary times between 1765 and 1780, but usually leaves the business in the hands of her friend and ally Gerald Blanc.Throughout the game, Aveline traverses through the port town of New Orleans, its swampy, alligator-filled Bayou, and the ruins of Chichen Itza to protect the Prophecy Disk and find the identity of "The Company Man" and stop him once and for all.GameplayLiberation's gameplay is very similar to that of the other games in the franchise, placing a light emphasis on stealth and moving through the city unnoticed and accomplishing your task as quickly, and quietly should the player choose to be, as possible. A new addition to the franchise is the use of personas to accomplish certain tasks through charm, brute force, or under the guise of low social standing, among other things.PersonasLadyRestricted movement (no freerunning or sprinting)Limited use of offensive weaponry (primarily restricted to the Assassin hidden blades)Exclusive use of a special parasol dart gunAbility to charm others so they can follow and protect Aveline when the need arisesAssassinIncreased health poolFull range of offensive weaponry, similar to that of a fully upgraded Ezio or ConnorAlways on guard alert 'Notoriety 1' meaning guards will always detect Aveline and investigate when in an area for too longSlaveNotoriety increases faster than other personasSlightly limited range of offensive weaponryHealth pool similar to that of the Lady personaAbility to incite riots to provide a distractionMinigamesNot unlike other big franchise games coming to the PlayStation Vita, Assassin's Creed III: Liberation uses the handheld's numerous touchscreens and its gyroscope to their full advantage by the inclusion of creative minigames for activities such as:Tearing open a letterHolding up a piece of paper to a bright light to locate treasureTilting a maze puzzle similar to those in LabyrinthPS Vita BundleAssassin's Creed III: Liberation will be bundled with a PS Vita game system at launch for a limited time. The bundle retails for $249.99 (US) and includes:An exclusive white-colored PlayStation VitaA copy of Assassin's Creed III: Liberation4 GB memory cardSoundtrackThe soundtrack was composed by Winifred Phillips, and released in October 2012 by Ubiosoft Music.Assassin's Creed III: Liberation - Original Game Soundtrack (Winifred Phillips)No.Track TitleLength (68:28)1."Liberation" (main theme)2:022."Stealth"2:113."Virtual Pursuit"2:134."The Docks"2:035."Abstergo Ops"3:446."Secrets of the Bayou"2:037."Poverty"2:118."Aveline's Escape"3:379."Society Suite in 4 Movements"7:1610."Ride to Oblivion"2:1311."Mayan Labyrinth"2:0512."Chasing Freedom"2:2013."The Hunt"2:1314."Bayou Fortress"2:0015."Safe Harbor"2:0716."Shanty Town"2:0117."Deliverance"2:2718."Winter in the North"2:0419."The Cathedral Grounds"2:0620."Animus"2:2721."In the Bayou"2:2422."Mayan Ruins"2:0323."River of the Mayans"2:3524."Agate's Power"3:2625."In the Service of Humanity"3:1126."Virtual Reality Room"3:26</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21213">Mirror's Edge</game><game id="20961">Prince of Persia</game><game id="24617">Tenchu: Shadow Assassins</game><game id="4523">Thief: The Dark Project</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2323851-box_ac3l.png</image></root>