<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38545</id><name>Scribblenauts Unlimited</name><description>OverviewScribblenauts Unlimited is a new game for the Wii U, Nintendo 3DS and PC developed by 5th Cell. Players can create any object they want and share them via the Miiverse on the Wii U or Steam Workshop with their friends. It also features cooperative multiplayer. The game was released for the Wii U and 3DS on November 13, 2012. The PC version was released on November 20, 2012 in North America, however the international release was delayed for unspecified reasons until 2013. The game's 3DS and Wii U versions are being published in Europe by Nintendo with on February 8, 2013.StoryMaxwell and his sister Lily, two of fourty-two children, are sent out into the world by their explorer parents. Along the road, they come across an old man who is begging for food. The siblings play a prank on the old man by creating a rotten apple, and giving it to him to eat, which enrages the old man, who puts curses on both of them, and turns Lily partially to stone. Maxwell now must gather starites to help his sister return to normal.GameplaySimilarly to previous Scribblenauts games, much of the gameplay involves the player creating objects by entering words into Maxwell's notebook. Unlike previous games, which feature a linear progression through levels, in Scribblenauts: Unlimited, Maxwell is placed into an open world where he must interact with NPCs in order to fragments and starites which in turn open up new areas. Maxwell has a new ability, called star vision, which allows him to see which NPCs offer starites.PC Version DifferencesThe PC version has no multiplayer, but has a higher resolution, comes with Steam Workshop support, allowing for sharing of created characters and objects. 25 Steam achievements are also included.  PC System RequirementsOS: Windows XP or higherProcessor: AMD Atholon 64 X2 Dual-Core 4000+ or better / Intel Core 2 Duo Processor 2.0GHz or betterMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: ATI X1800 or better / nVidia 7800 or better / Intel 4100 or better. 256MB Video RAM. Shader 3.0 or betterDirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 2 GB HD space</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/82063/2328134-scribunl.jpg</image></root>