<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38557</id><name>Game &amp; Wario</name><description>OverviewOff-screen photo from E3 2012Game  Wario is a WarioWare successor for Wii U announced at E3 2012. Rather than the hundreds of microgames of previous installments, Game  Wario features more focused, traditional minigames. It uses only the Wii U GamePad and features both single-player games and pass-the-GamePad multiplayer for up to 5 players.Some of the games included, such as Pirate, were originally featured as tech demos for the Wii U at E3 2012.MinigamesThere are 16 minigames, each with a simple, Game  Watch-style name and is represented by a WarioWare character:Wario: ArrowPlayers: 1The GamePad is used as a bow to attack enemies approaching on the TV screen; the gyroscope is used to aim and the touchscreen is used to draw the string back and fire. The GamePad can also be raised to block incoming cannonballs. Enemies include toy Warios and a massive Wario tank.Orbulon: SketchPlayers: 2-5A Pictionary-style sketch game in which players draw using the GamePad.Mona: ShutterPlayers: 1The GamePad is used like a  camera to take photos of criminals hidden in a town displayed on the TV. Players have to find specific people on the screen and then take clear photos of them with increased rewards for better pictures.Mike: DiscoPlayers: 2Players place the GamePad vertically between themselves and each take one half of the screen.Wario: PiratePlayers: 1A rhythm game in which the player must follow audio cues to block incoming arrow five from multiple directions. Once complete, the player must then emulate Wario's dance moves, similar to the rhythm portions of the earlier WarioWare titles.9-Volt: GamerPlayers: 1Gameplay takes the form of a regular WarioWare game on the Gamepad, featuring 22 randomized, rapid-fire microgames. A twist is added in the form of 9-Volt's mother, who is prowling to ensure he isn't staying up late playing games.Young Cricket: Kung-FuPlayers: 1The player must jump across an obstacle course while collecting meat buns to maintain Young Cricket's energy. The map is viewed from an overhead perspective on the GamePad, which must be tilted to direct Young Cricket's direction of movement as he jumps.Kat  Ana: PatchworkPlayers: 1A puzzle game in which the player must place patchwork pieces into the proper spaces on a grid in order to form pictures. It is played by dragging pieces into place on the GamePad screen.Jimmy T.: SkiPlayers: 1Players must tilt a vertically-oriented GamePad to maneuver a Jimmy T. down a snow slope. A map is displayed on the touch screen, and the skier is shown on the TV to entertain onlookers.Dribble  Spitz: TaxiPlayers: 1A driving/action game shown from the first person on the GamePad with an overhead map of the region displayed on the TV. The player must drive a taxi around, and then use the gyroscope in the GamePad to aim and shoot down enemy targets so that passengers can be rescued and delivered safely for a fare.Dr Crygor: DesignPlayers: 1A minigame based on drawing lines of specific lengths and shapes on the GamePad. The more accurately the player follows Dr. Crygor's directions, the better the score.Ashley: AshleyPlayers: 1A side-scrolling action game in which the primary action is displayed on the TV. The player must guide Ashley through each course by tilting the GamePad to the left and right to change the angle of her path and collect magical energy orbs. The player loses if Ashley runs out of energy, which is lost when she is hit by enemies or runs into obstacles. If the player is particularly careless, Ashley will become frustrated, and the action will pause momentarily so the player can calm on her the GamePad screen to prevent energy loss.Fronk: IslandPlayers: 2-5Penny: FruitPlayers: 2-5A town full of people is displayed on the screen, and players take turns to anonymously control a character in the scene to steal fruit. The other players must then use the GamePad to uncover the suspect amongst the crowd.BonusesCluck-A-PopThe Cluck-A-Pop is where the player can exchange tokens earned by playing the minigames for prizes delivered in the form of capsule toys. These features include microgames, character profiles, and assorted oddities that are more digital toy than game.Miiverse SketchA single-player version of the Sketch game in which drawing prompts are submitted to and taken from Miiverse. Drawings made are also shared to Miiverse.</description><genres><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="38549">Nintendo Land</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/82063/2474463-gnwcroppedclean.jpg</image></root>