<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38596</id><name>Payday 2</name><description>OverviewPayday 2 (also known as PAYDAY 2) is a co-operative crime-themed first-person shooter developed by Overkill and released by 505 for the Xbox 360, PlayStation 3, and PC (via Steam) on August 13, 2013.The sequel to Payday: The Heist, players team up as one of four masked criminals ( Dallas, Hoxton, Wolf, and Chains) as they descend on Washington, D.C. for an epic crime spree. The crew now takes advantage of CRIMENET, an underground network where they deal with local criminal contacts (such as Vlad the Ukrainian, shady politician "The Elephant", and drug trafficker Hector). Using the CRIMENET interface, players can progress through various sizes of heists (from small-time convenience stores to major bank vaults), upgrade their criminal's special skills (through four special Skill Trees), purchase various weapons, items, and weapon modifications, and customize their mask. Along with an expanded metagame, the game now takes advantage of heists that are dynamic (with random geometry and events), multi-part (splitting the heist into separate levels), and open-ended (including branching paths that lead to completely different levels).The console versions of the game were originally planned to be digital downloads (similar to the PC version and the PS3 version of the original Payday), but were changed to full retail releases. A beta for the PC version was given out in late July 2013 for Steam users who either pre-purchased the special "Career Criminal Edition" of the game or previously purchased the Steam version of Payday: The Heist.Key featuresCRIMENETThe dynamic contract database lets gamers pick and choose from available jobs by connecting with local contacts such as Vlad the Ukrainian, shady politician “The Elephant” and Mexican drug trafficker Hector, all with their own agenda and best interests in mind. CRIMENET features dozens of varied, exciting jobs and as the player progresses, new contacts with new jobs become available. Choose Your ProfessionAs players progress they can invest in any of four special professions: the Mastermind, the Enforcer, the Ghost and the Technician.Each features a customization tree of 3 vertical lines of skills, which are purchased with skill points and spending money; each skill having two tiers, and unlocking all skills per horizontal giving another bonus.The Mastermind is partly the medic of the group, as well as being able to help with the Heist in various ways, such as increasing the experience gained, and making various actions, such as reviving or taking hostages perform quicker and with better effect.The Enforcer is the guy with a big gun of the team, carrying ammo, and increasing the ability to do damage and take it, it also unlocks the ability to use the OVE9000 Saw, which is a special tool that can be used to speed a Heist up.The Ghost is the stealthy pick of the professions, being able to jam electronics, move faster, and get more money for pickups and the PaydayThe final profession is the Technician, which makes working with the tools more effective, unlocks explosives and unlocks the Sentry Gun to be used for covering fire. PAYDAY LootAfter finishing a set of days and finishing the Payday, each player can pick from 3 cards, those being either a gun part, colour, material, mask type, or extra spending money.Colours, materials and mask types are used for crafting a new mask to wear, the look of it depending on the ingredients.Gun parts unlock purchasable upgrades for weapons (which also change the look of the gun), such as extra ammo in the form of different magazines, different handles and slides, these however depend on the gun, each one having it's own set of upgrades and parts available. Mission AssetsEvery job has a set of purchasable assets that can alter and enhance the heist such as a faster escape car, blueprints or inside help, in the form of a dead drop of ammunition or health packs. Multistage JobsContracts are now made up of days, with each one being a level (Easier Heists are 1 day only), Eg: Day 1 is getting the goods, Day 2 is transporting them, and Day 3 is passing them on for the cash, with Day 3 being the Payday and end to the Heist.In total Heists can be up to 7 days long.Continuing with the random elements throughout the game, depending on how the players act and perform in earlier days, it will cause options later on, such as being able to get information without a firefight, to not be present. Another example is if the team kills too many cops or civilians, during the transport day the getaway van is tailgated and destroyed, causing you to have to do a HEAT-style run away to another getaway vehicle. System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows XP SP3Processor: 2 GHz Intel Dual Core ProcessorMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: NVIDIA GeForce 8800/ATI Radeon HD 2600 (256MB minimum)DirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 10 GB HD spaceSound: DirectX 9.0c compatibleRecommendedOS: Windows XP SP3/Vista/Windows 7Processor: 2.3 GHz Intel Quad Core ProcessorMemory: 3 GB RAMGraphics: NVIDIA GeForce GTX460/ATI Radeon HD 5850 (512MB minimum)DirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 10 GB HD spaceSound: DirectX 9.0c compatible</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2489461-box_payday2.png</image></root>