<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38681</id><name>Worms Revolution</name><description>OverviewIntended as a major return and modernization of the series roots, Worms Revolution is a 2.5D turn-based tactics game with a new 3D engine and the classic 2D gameplay of the series. The game marks Andy Davidson's return to the Worms franchise. The focus once again is on worm-on-worm combat, with up to 4 teams of 4 worms each facing off on a variety of islands, caverns, and fort based environments.The main additions Worms Revolution makes to the 2D setup are the introduction of a class system and a physics engine for both physical objects and water.The ClassesSoldier: The soldier is the most basic of the four classes in the game. It is Revolution's equivalent of the basic worms used in every previous entry in the series. As such, the soldier has a basic balance of mobility and power, and no real special abilities to speak of. Compared to the rest of the classes, he has the second highest damage output in the game; second only to the tank.Scientist: The scientist is the most support and defense oriented of the classes. Not only does he place the strongest sentry guns in the game, but he also regenerates his entire team for 5 hit points every time his turn comes around- allowing him to help counteract water and poison damage if your enemy is relying on them. His damage output is higher than the scout, but lower than the soldier. His mobility is also slightly lower than the soldier's. The scientist is notably well-suited to darksiding due to how well his abilities fit with a defensive playstyle.Tank: The largest, slowest, and strongest of the classes. On his own, the Tank is by far the slowest class in the game, though a few of the game's transportation options- especially ninja ropes- can at least partially counteract this weakness while they last. The Tank has the highest damage output in the game, as his weapons cause more direct damage and can have slightly larger explosions. Overall, the tank is notably well suited to fort matches - but can struggle in more open levels where his limited mobility can easily restrict him to one area.Scout: The smallest and fastest of the classes. The Scout has the best jumps and fastest walk speed of all the classes. He also has superior interaction with many of the game's transportation options- especially jetpacks. This mobility comes at a cost though: the scout has the lowest damage output in the game. As such, the scout is best used in large open levels. This is especially true for shopper matches where his mobility makes it easier to reach crates faster.PC System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows XPProcessor: Dual Core CPUMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: NVIDIA GeForce 8600 GT (256 MB) or Radeon HD 3650 (512 MB)Other Requirements: Broadband Internet connection</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="35283">Wild Ones</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2304000-box_wormsrev.png</image></root>