<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38788</id><name>Warframe</name><description>OverviewDeveloped by Digital Extremes--the team known for developing Dark Sector and more recently working on the multiplayer component of Bioshock 2 and developing The Darkness 2--Warframe is a free-to-play title that will be set in the future. The enslaved race of Tenno is facing extinction by the hands of the Grineer when at the cusp of the conflict they discover an ancient alien technology of the Warframes - advanced exoskeleton suits created by an long forgotten civilization. The player enters the conflict at this delicate time and participates in procedurally-generated missions of PVE combat in squads of up to four players.Of interest is the fact that, long ago when Digital Extremes was showing first teaser videos of their upcoming title Dark Sector, the rendered cinematics showcased a figure wearing a suit that looked almost exactly like the Warframe exoskeleton. Down to the bone-white color, moving about a spaceship or some form of installation, and taking out alien foes. In the end, Dark Sector was grounded more in reality and the sci-fi aspect was ditched for a biological approach to the suit and weapon of the main protagonist.The first gameplay trailer features numerous Warframes, all fighting the Grineer enemy.Along with their own games, the developer also cited the influence of online multiplayer games such as Phantasy Star Online and Left 4 Dead.StoryTenno, warriors of blades, guns and masters of the Warframe armor were left drifting in the ruins of an old war are now needed again to stop the vast armies of the Grineer from taking over the entire solar system. You were rescued from your cryostasis chamber by Lotus. Lotus will guide you and teach you the ways of the warframe and their secret powers.TennoThe descendants of an ancient mystical civilization from the Orokin era on Earth. Stored in their cyropods for centuries after an old war are awakened into a new war were they must fight and resist the Grineer Empire's attempt to conquer the Solar System. Their memories have faded but their ability to use a gun, sword and exo-armor have not. The historic values of the Tenno are chivalry and discipline but they may not all be so in this new war as they emerge into this unfamiliar world. They stand united against a common foe, and loyal to only each other.GrineerVast in numbers from cloning technology the Grineer seek to expand their vile empire from Earth outward and control the whole solar system. They took over Earth by their numbers alone. While high in power the Grineer army is decaying. The constant cloning is increasingly making them more primitive. The Grineer's ideology of enormous hate and discrimination towards the Tenno drives them to the face of inevitable dissolution.CorpusThe Corpus are a dominating proto-corporation of humans that maintain and operate the trade routes of the Solar Rails. They control the entire supply chain of goods in the Solar System and see Orokin artifacts as profit and will exploit it at any cost. The Corpus are rarely seen by others and are better known for their robot proxies that serve them. The Corpus have taken the social structure from ancient mercantile guilds from the old Earth. They blend technology and ritual in their production methods.InfestedAlthough not explicitly stated, the Infested are what is appeared to be Technocyte plague stricken Corpus Crewmen and Grineer Lancers. It is rumored that J3-Golem, a boss of the Infected, was created alongside the plague by the Orokin themselves as a super weapon against "the Sentients". This boss also hints to the player during battle that it may be Tenno itself which conflicts with "the Lotus" statement that "no Tenno have fallen to the plague". It is unknown whether J3-Golem was at one point a Tenno or "the Lotus" is an unreliable narrator.LotusThe Lotus is an organization of mysterious origins who has close links to the Tenno and their technology. Sometimes referred to in the singular as "The Lotus" in reference to a female the player hears throughout the game. The has great knowledge of the Warframes, their unique powers and a great understanding of Orokin relics. After deactivating the cryostasis on the Tenno she uses this knowledge to manipulate the Tenno warriors to fight for their cause.WarframesA Warframe is an exo-armor that uses unique combative technology to create the ultimate weaponry. Each Warframe holds many mysterious powers and mastering one requires dedicated use.VOLTVolt can create and harness electrical elements. This is a high-damage Warframe perfect for players who want a potent alternative to gun-play.Shock: Launches a shocking projectile. It stuns and deals high damage to a single target and stuns enemies nearbySpeed: Significantly increases the player’s movement speed and dexterity for a limited timeElectric Shield: Deploys a temporary shield, providing cover for the playerOverload: Emits an energy field from within the player, destroying electronics and damaging enemiesEXCALIBUR/EXCALIBUR PRIMEThe perfect training Warframe: the Excalibur suit allows players to explore the power of Warframes with a balanced set of capabilities. Founders who purchased the Hunter Founder Pack or greater get access to the Excalibur Prime which is identical to the standard Excalibur but with an extra "V" polarity slot and some cosmetic tweaks.Slash Dash: Forces the user forward and violently damages any enemies in its pathRadial Blind: Radial Blind emits a bright flash of light that temporarily blinds its victims, leaving them open for attackSuper Jump: Propels the user into the air three times higher then your normal jumpRadial Javelin: Ejects spears towards enemies with enough force to impale them to wallsEMBEREmber is a nightmare for light-armored targets, best suited for crowd control.Fireball: Projectile, deals high fire damage on contact and moderate damage in residual flamesOverheat: Envelopes the player in an aura of fire damage for a limited timeFireblast: After slamming close by enemies to the ground, Fire Blast creates a lingering ring of fire, gradually causing high damage with enemy exposureWorld on Fire:Creates an aura of fire to the issuer's surroundings and causes a high degrees of damage to enemies in the area.ASHThis Warframe relies on a more stealthy approach to combat and is complemented with abilities to distract the enemy.Shuriken: Launches a blade that deals high damage and impales enemies to wallsSmoke Screen: Drops a smoke bomb that stuns enemies and obscures their vision, rendering the player invisible for a short timeTeleport: Teleports the player towards the target, bringing them into melee rangeBlade Storm: Sends the player into a rampage, teleporting to and destroying all enemies within rangeMAGThis Warframe commands its surrounding magnetic energy and is an expert of enemy manipulation. Perfect for dealing heavy damage in unique ways.Pull: Pulls the enemy towards you, stunning them and bringing them into melee rangeShield Polarize: Will restore an ally's shield or damage an enemy shieldBullet Attractor: Strongly magnetizes a target enemy, causing bullets that pass nearby to redirect and strike the enemyCrush: Magnetizes the bones of nearby enemies, causing them to collapse and explodeRHINOThe heaviest of all the Warframes. His strength enables him to combine a mix of devastating offensive attacks with formidable defensive powers.Rhino Charge: Charges towards a target clobbering any in his path, and goring his victimIron Skin: Hardens his skin, greatly reducing damage taken for a short timeRadial Blast: Punches the ground, dealing high damage to enemies in a small radiusRhino Stomp: Rhino stomps with enough force to disrupt time, tumbling enemies around him in stasisLOKILoki offers a variety of reconfiguring abilities. The abnormality of Loki's powers allows players to manipulate the battlefield.Decoy: Loki creates a holographic copy of himself, drawing enemy fireInvisibility: Loki camouflages himself, becoming invisible to enemiesSwitch Teleport: Instantaneously swaps positions with a targetRadial Disarm: Use a wave of energy to disarm and disrupt enemy weapons, forcing them to revert to melee combatTRINITYTrinity is great for players who prefer a supportive role. Warframes with healing technologies are rare making Trinity a great equalizer when the odds are stacked against the Tenno.Well of Life: Creates a well of life on an enemy, allowing players to gain health from damaging the targetEnergy Vampire: Allies gain energy when damaging a target marked with this abilityLink: Any damage taken when Link is activated will be channeled to a nearby EnemyBlessing: Fully heal and regenerate the energy of all allies. Your team also gains temporary invulnerabilityNYXMind control and psychic attacks make Nyx a very dangerous foe. Her ability to reach into enemy consciousness and manipulate their behavior can turn the tide of any battle.Mind Control: Confuses target, causing them to fight on the player’s side for a brief periodPsychic Bolts: Launches a cluster of telekinetic bolts that homes in on targetsChaos: With a powerful psychic blast, Nyx causes mass hysteria on the battlefield by confusing all enemies to attack at randomAbsorb: Nyx absorbs all incoming damage and channels that energy into an explosive radial blastFROSTBy channeling moisture and vapor in the surrounding environment, Frost creates formidable defenses and lethal attacks from sub zero conditions.Freeze: A frigid energy blast that freezes targets in their tracksIce Wave: Creates a wave of ice towards an enemy, dealing heavy damageSnow Globe: Frost deep freezes any vapor and moisture in the surrounding area to create an impenetrable sphere of protectionAvalanche: Summons a landslide of ice that freezes and shatters enemies within its radius.  SARYNThe beautiful and mysterious SARYN is one of the most feared Warframes in the solar system. Her venomous attacks are horrifyingly effective against organic and synthetic enemies, and her ability to "shed" her skin makes her very elusive.Venom: Highly toxic spores are released, which inflict poison damage over time. Destruction of the spore causes viral infection to enemies within range.Moult: A decoy is left behind by shedding skin, similar to a snake, to draw enemy fire.Contagion: A toxic substance is secreted onto melee weapons, dealing poison damage to all enemies who come in contact with the weapon.Miasma: The atmosphere is filled with a highly toxic corrosive mist, lethal to all enemies, organic or synthetic within range.BANSHEEUsing a combination of sonic attack and acoustic target detection, BANSHEE is well suited for stealth gameplay and is capable of filling both attack and support roles.Sonic Boom: A damaging cone of sonic energy is sent forth, which can push back or kill enemies.Sonar: Using acoustic location, BANSHEE's SONAR power finds and tracks enemies, and exposes critical weak spots to everyone in your squad.Silence: Ideal for stealth and intrusion situations, using SILENCE on unaware enemies will limit their perceptions and tactical response.Sound Quake: Sonic energy is channeled into the ground, causing reverberations, which violently shake the environment, lethally affecting all enemies in range.SentinelsA new addition to the game as of update 7, sentinels are robotic companions which accompany you into missions and provide combat bonuses and additional firepower. Players can choose between Wyrm, a more offensive oriented sentinel or Shade, a stealth oriented sentinel.  WeaponsWarframes carry three weapons with them into missions. These consist of a Long Gun (such as a rifle, shotgun, or sniper rifle), a sidearm that can be used single-handed or dual-wielded, and a melee weapon.Weapons level up by using them in combat and by picking up white Affinity orbs. By leveling up, weapons gain new ranks that offer the ability to equip more mods. Each weapon can be ranked to level 30 but this can go up to a total of 60 once the weapon has been supercharged. To improve a weapon further, mods can be used and placed within the eight mod slots available for every weapon. Mods are randomly dropped from enemies and bosses and can significantly boost base weapon attributes or add unique effects to the weapon.New players start with the MK1-Braton automatic rifle, Lato pistol, and Skana sword as their default loadout. Additional weapons can be acquired either from crafting them from blueprints in the Forge or by purchasing them directly from the Marketplace.Mastery RankMastery is an in-game method of measuring a players cumulative skill by how many weapons they have increased in rank. Protected by anti-exploitative measures, this system has on some weapons a minimum level before mastery experience is given. Mastery Rank s unlocking weapons that are capped by level and can be viewed by clicking on the profile menu.Sentinels earn 100 mastery points per level while upgrading your Warframe will garner you 200 mastery points per level. Certain weapons such as the Lato and Mk-1 Braton are weapons which currently have a threshold that must be hit in rank before they start giving Mastery Points.Tenno ArmamentsLong gunsNameTypeBase DamageBase Fire RateAccuracyBase Clip SizeCost (Credits)Cost (Platinum)MK1 - BratonStarting - automatic rifle13.08.325.048.08,00050Braton VandalOpen beta weekend limited edition Braton20.012.525.0481N/ABoarAutomatic shotgun60.05.010.010.050,000225BoltorAutomatic rifle18.011.750.048.015,000*150BratonAutomatic rifle16.015.025.048.010,00075BurstonBurst-fire rifle20.025.0100.048.012,000125GorgonHeavy automatic machinegun24.012.55.49050,000225HekShotgun140.02.29.1425,000*225LatronSemi-automatic rifle30.04.2100.015.050,000225SnipetronSemi-automatic sniper rifle100.01.7100.04.050,000225StrunStandard shotgun120.01.720.06.017,500175ParisCompound Hunting Bow45.01.016.7120,000*225GrakataAutomatic Rifle9.020.028.66015,000*125        Side ArmsNameTypeBase DamageBase Fire RateAccuracyBase Clip SizeCost (Credits)Cost (Platinum)LatoStarter Semi-Automatic Pistol24.06.718.2154,00050Lato PrimeGrand Master Founder's Package Exclusive Lato27.06.718.215N/AN/ALato VandalClosed Beta Tester Exclusive Lato30.05.023.015N/AN/ASicarus3-round Burst Fire Pistol26.03.520.01512,000120LexHeavy Pistol70.01.116.0635,000190BroncoSmall Scale Shotgun105.05.03.7235,000190BoltoSemi-Automatic Pistol25.06.826.71515,000*175AkboltoAkimbo Boltos25.010.026.73015,000*225AklatoAkimbo Latos24.08.311.13012,00075FurisAutomatic Pistol14.010.015.43515,000120AfurisAkimbo Furis14.020.08.77015,000*225Kraken2-round Burst Fire Heavy Pistol45.02.816.01420,000*120ViperAutomatic Pistol16.014.415.41420,000*75Twin VipersAkimbo Vipers16.025.08.72815,000*225Melee WeaponsNameTypeBase DamageBase Fire RateAccuracyBase Charge-DamageBase Charge-SpeedCost (Credits)Cost (Platinum)SkanaStarting-Sword25.01.010075.01.015,000150Dark DaggerShort Dagger20.01.510075.01.0N/AN/ADual ZorenShort axes15.02.010050.02.015,000*175FuraxGauntlets25.01.0100150.01.030,000125Heat DaggerShort dagger20.01.510075.01.0N/A75Ceramic DaggerShort dagger20.01.510075.01.0N/AN/ACronusSword35.01.310075.01.0N/AN/ADark SwordSword25.01.0100125.01.0N/AN/ABoStaff25.01.010075.01.015,000*65Heat SwordSword 35.01.510075.01.0N/AN/AJaw SwordSword35.01.010075.01.0N/AN/APangolin SwordSword30.01.310075.01.0N/AN/APlasma SwordSword25.01.0100125.01.0N/AN/ADual SkanaDual Skana25.01.0100100.01.045,000175Dual Heat SwordHeat Sword in one hand, Heat dagger in the other30.01.0100150.01.015,000175FragorHeavy Hammer50.01.0100200.01.015,000*150GramHeavy Sword40.01.3100200.01.015,000*150ScindoHeavy Axe50.01.0100200.01.015,000*150Skana PrimeMaster and Grand Master Founder's Exclusive Skana35.01.010085.01.0N/AN/AGlaiveThrowing Disk25.01.2100.0150.01.5N/A150MireLongsword35.01.3100.075.01.015,000*150Dual EtherDual Short Blades30.01.3100.0100.01.320,000*175FangDual Daggers15.01.5100.065x21.020,000*135Ether DaggersDual Daggers30.00.8100.065x2N/A20,000*175AmphisStaff30.01.3100.0100.01.715,000*150AnkyrosGauntlets22.01.5100.0100.01.015,000*125* = Blueprint onlyStats and costs are subject to changeThe Warframe Founders ProgramWarframe Founders ProgramAs of December 12, 2012 Digital Extremes introduced the Warframe Founders Program. For a limited time you can help the future of the game and get exclusive in-game items and privileges. All members get instant access to the beta and depending on your founder status the more rewards you get. You can upgrade your status anytime for just the difference in price between tiers.1. Disciple: The minimum of $19.99 USD.A unique Disciple badge for their sites forum370 platinum, in game currency (a $20 value)Instant beta access2. Hunter: The second tier will cost you $49.99 USD.A unique Hunter badge for their sites forum1220 platinum (a $60 value)Instant beta access3 guest beta keysExcalibur Prime Warframe3. Master: For $99.99 USD will get you the third tier.3210 Platinum (a $150 value)A unique Master founders badge for their forums.Instant beta access7 guest beta keys.Excalibur Prime WarframeSkana Prime SwordGain exclusive access to the Design Council and vote on upcoming game features.4. Grand Master: The top tier of the Warframe Founders Program. $249.99 USD.8875 Platinum (a $400 value)An exclusive Grand Master Forum Founders BadgeInstant beta access15 guest beta keysExcalibur Prime SwordSkana Prime SwordLato Prime PistolExclusive access to the Design Council.Have a solar landmark and have a in game location named after you.These exclusive items will not be available ever again once the Founder Program ends.PlatinumThere are numerous items in Warframe, that can augment your Frame to its fullest possibilities. Most of these items can be crafted by using blueprints in the foundry, or by purchasing them from the in-game Marketplace using one of two currencies. F2P Credits are earned by completing missions, killing enemy units, or as random drops from breakables during each mission. Platinum on the other hand, can only be acquired using real money (US Dollars or other currency). The Marketplace has items that can be purchased with either Credits or Platinum. Certain items, mostly cosmetic, can only be purchased with PlatinumPlatinum can currently be purchased in a variety of tiers:Platinum PointsUSD2100 Pt (1500 + 600 Bonus Pt)$99.991000 Pt (750 + 250 Bonus Pt)$49.99570 Pt (450 + 120 Bonus Pt)$29.99170 Pt (150 + 20 Bonus Pt)$9.9975 Pt$4.99These prices are subject to change before the time of launch. All digital purchases are made through UltePay.System RequirementsOS: Windows XP SP 3 or higher Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo e6400 or AMD Athlon x64 4000+ Memory: 2 GB RAM Graphics: Nvidia GeForce 8600 GT or ATI Radeon HD 3600 DirectX®: 9.0c Hard Drive: 2 GB HD space Other Requirements: Broadband Internet connection</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="31169">Darkness Within 2: The Dark Lineage</game><game id="20827">BioShock 2</game><game id="20690">Left 4 Dead</game><game id="20252">Phantasy Star Online</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/12/123968/2415111-tennofactionthreeroenc.jpg</image></root>