<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3880</id><name>Monty Python's The Meaning of Life</name><description>Overview  Monty Python's The Meaning of Life was a game released by 7th Level in September 1997. It was the third (and final) in their series, following A Complete Waste Of Time and The Holy Grail. Critical feedback for the game was mildly positive, however the entire game was tainted by a fatal bug that meant that the title, in its released state, could not be completed.  The game offered the player the chance of discovering the Meaning of Life, and like The Holy Grail and A Complete Waste of Time, followed the point and click format of previous Python titles. The game also included 'new' content, mostly contributed by Eric Idle, that added nonsensical narration to the events onscreen.   Once again, the game combined various screen 'clickables' with mini games and clips from the film of the same name. The game involved the travel from location to location in order to follow various linked 'stories' of characters. The player was expected to follow these threads in order to understand the various outcomes for characters, and, of course, ultimately the Meaning of Life.  Gameplay  The game was notable from the previous Python titles in that there was more to 'do' in the in-game options. There were interactive options, such as a ringing phone in 'The Living Room' and TV options.    The game was split across several screens and stories.  These game locations were split between the Study and The Living Room. The Study was a 360 degree viewing environment that the player could interact with, while the Living Room was made up of -  The Organ Area The TV area and The Computer Area  Each of these were separate 'clicky' areas that the player could interact with.  These stories were -   Broadnose's Quandry The Chronicle of Thog The yarn of Mary Catherine The Story of Henri The Redemption of Preacher Bob and The Reasonably Heroic Intention of Fraidicus  Once again, the game progressed through the player clicking parts onscreen, with many of the options changing upon multiple clicks.   The game also offered a further Python in-service, by inviting players with the opportunity to find a character named 'Dennis Moore' (the Python equivalent to Dick Turpin) in various locations throughout the game. </description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3970">Myst</game><game id="10927">Loom</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/18329/625447-meaning_of_life_box.jpg</image></root>