<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38824</id><name>McPixel</name><description>OverviewMcPixel is a game heavily influenced by the Saturday Night Live sketch "MacGruber", which in turn was inspired by MacGyver. It was initially created in 48 hours for the Ludum Dare 21 competition, which took place on August 19, 2011.The game launched for PC, Mac, and Linux on June 25, 2012. It is also available on iOS and Google Play, and will be made available for the Commodore 64. Current and future DLC is free for those that purchase the game; the game also features a level creator.GameplayA typical puzzle found in McPixel.The game is a mix of adventure game mechanics with the urgency of a WarioWare-style game.The player has up to 20 seconds to complete each level. A level is completed when the bomb present is diffused, which is accomplished by clicking on various objects in each level. The game is divided into chapters, rounds, and levels. There are four chapters, each of which is divided into three rounds. Each round has the player cycling through six levels. If a level is failed, the bomb explodes, and the player then advances to the next level. Failed levels can be attempted again when they come back through the cycle. The round is complete when the player has saved the day in all six levels. Each chapter also has a fourth round which is only unlocked after finding all the gags in the chapter.In addition, successfully completing three levels in a row allows the player to attempt a bonus level.DistributionArs Technica reported that on September 7th of 2012, Sos Sosowski, the creator of McPixel, made available and promoted a torrent of his game to the downloading public for the weekend, in fact directing fans to start using the torrent on The Pirate Bay. (You can find the story here.) He told downloaders that, "not everyone can afford entertainment. But everyone needs it," and that he is "most happy just to see people enjoy [his games]." Sos encouraged people to download his game and donate whatever money they wish in his direction.On September 11, 2012, it was announced that McPixel will be one of the first 10 games to advance on Steam's Greenlight program. On September 25, 2012 the game was published on Steam and McPixel became the first Greenlight game to have reached the store.The game is also available on Desura.</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14405">WarioWare, Inc.: Mega Microgame$!</game><game id="10093">WarioWare: Touched!</game><game id="23985">WarioWare D.I.Y.</game><game id="24313">WarioWare: Snapped!</game><game id="13685">WarioWare: Smooth Moves</game><game id="12208">WarioWare Twisted!</game><game id="38589">Frobisher Says!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2306947-movieposter.png</image></root>