<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38828</id><name>Little Inferno</name><description>OverviewLittle Inferno is the first game by Tomorrow Corporation, and has been released for Wii U, Mac, Linux, Windows, and iOS. The game's first teaser was shown on July 11th, 2012. The trailer showed a kid-friendly advertisement for a fireplace, and positioned it as the only way to survive a new Ice Age. The game is situated "almost entirely" around this fireplace and involves burning "flaming logs, screaming robots, credit cards, batteries, exploding fish, unstable nuclear devices, and tiny galaxies". The game has an art style that is reminiscent of World of Goo. The Wii U version was released on November 18th, 2012, while the Windows, Mac, and Linux versions were available a day later. An iOS version was released on January 31st, 2013.GameplayLittle Inferno revolves around its realistic fire propagation in the controlled environment of your new "Little Inferno" toy, a product of Tomorrow Corporation (a fictional corporation within the game, but also the name of the developer of the game).The items are of varying materials, size, and scale, and are purchased from catalogs within the game. Burning items produces coins which are used to purchase more items, as well as stamps which are used to increase the speed of delivery on your orders. The game also includes a combo system wherein combining certain items in the fireplace causes unique reactions and also rewards the player with bonus coins and stamps. The story progresses and additional themed catalogs become available for purchase, allowing for more complex combos. Item catalogs include such categories as: plushy toys, edibles, a machismo-centric male catalog, video games, and more conceptual pieces such as "email" and "Internet cloud." The game also includes some light adventure game elements with dialogue trees.CharactersMiss NancyThe owner of the Tomorrow Corporation, the maker of the Little Inferno fireplace.Sugar PlumpsThe player character's next door neighbor. She also has a Little Inferno fireplace. As the game progresses, she will send the player character letters and occasionally request items from the player.The Weather ManHe gives out the weather report in a weather balloon.List of CatalogsChimney StufferCost of Catalog: FreeTotally Recalled ToysCost: 75Snooty FoodieCost: 1001st Person ShopperCost: 150Guide to Stylish LivingCost: 225Shop  AweCost: 340Existence, NowCost: 525Mailbox UpgradesItems can be bought from the catalogs and stored in the Mailbox (located at the bottom of the screen). Initially, the maximum number of items that can be hold is 4, but it can also be upgraded for a fee.5 Items - 306 Items - 1007 Items - 450SoundtrackA soundtrack has also been released for the game which can be bought here.System RequirementsPCOS: Win 7, Vista and XPProcessor: 1.5 GhzRAM: 1GBHard Drive: 200 MBVideo Card: You will need a graphics card that supports Shader Model 2.0 or greater and DirectX 9.0c.MacOS: OSX 10.6 or laterProcessor: 1.5 GhzRAM: 1GBHard Drive: 200 MBVideo Card: You will need a graphics card that supports OpenGL 2.1 or greater.LinuxProcessor: 1.5Ghz CPUMemory: 1 GB RAMHard Disk Space: 200 MBVideo Card: graphics card that supports OpenGL 2.1 </description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="24052">Trash Panic</game><game id="32626">Doodle God</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2426093-mzl.rdbxymyd.png</image></root>