<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38839</id><name>Cloudberry Kingdom</name><description>OverviewA glimpse into madness.Clouberry Kingdom's signature feature is an A.I. director that randomly generates levels. Thus, the game will technically have infinite levels that the AI knows to create according to certain algorithms. Additional features include a level editor, leaderboards, character customization, hats, Super Meat Boy-like combined-death-replays, custom campaigns, sharing levels online and other stuff. The game will offer the following difficulty settings: Easy, Unpleasant, Abusive, Hardcore Masochistic.Cloudberry Kingdom was released in Late July 2013 on PC (steam), Wii U, Xbox Live Arcade, and PlayStation Network (PS3). Vita, Mac, and Linux versions are currently set to be released in Fall 2013. (Ubisoft is acting as publisher for the XBLA release.)The game was Kickstarter-funded on May 28, 2012.Game ModesCloudberry Kingdom has a variety of different game modes for players to choose from, all making use of the procedural generation the game advertises as a core feature.The ArcadeThe Arcade is where the player will find the most primitive implementation of the game's core concept. This comes in the form of Escalation. Escalation allows the player to pick a pre-set character, and then use that character to play through an infinite number of levels which are generated on-the-fly. They will be different every time the player loads this mode up. The mode is called "Escalation" because the levels are arranged in order of ascending difficulty, as the A.I. director is able to make distinctions about how hard a jump is to make, how many obstacles the player must navigate, and so on. Additionally, the player cannot access any other parts of Arcade Mode without first unlocking them through Escalation.Story ModeStory mode is a partially-authored game mode. Similar to games like Daggerfall, the procedural levels were "baked" before release, and then manually placed. So while the levels are still randomly generated in Story Mode, they will be the same each time the player plays the game.Free PlayIn Free Play, the player is able to use a custom hero with adjustable physics properties(as well as abilities such as double jump) in a level to which they set the parameters. The length, difficulty, location(an aesthetic option), number of checkpoints, and so on are all adjustable by the player.System RequirementsOS: Windows® XP (SP3) / Windows Vista® (SP2) / Windows® 7 (SP1) / Windows® 8Processor: 2.0 GHz Intel® Core™2 Duo E4400 or 2.0 GHz AMD Athlon™ 64 X2 3800+ or betterMemory: 1 GB RAM (2 GB or greater recommended)Graphics: 256 MB DirectX® 9.0c–compliant with Shader Model 4.0 or higher (see supported list)*DirectX®: 9.0Hard Drive: 750 MB HD space (2 GB recommended)Sound: DirectX Compatible Sound Card with latest drivers</description><genres><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="24999">Spelunky</game><game id="41639">Super House of Dead Ninjas</game><game id="42029">Another Castle</game><game id="25114">Super Meat Boy</game><game id="15544">Super Mario Bros.</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2525159-box_cbk.png</image></root>