<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38861</id><name>Gnomoria</name><description>OverviewGnomoria have several aspects of strategy. For example, you need to feed your gnomes by utilizing agriculture, give them drinks through a well or a brewery, fend off creatures and build a prosperous kingdom for them! There's also crafting, trap-making, mining for precious ores underground among other things.The gnomes have different professions, depending on what you need them to do. This can be changed at any time during the game, but when you do the gnomes take a quick nap and cancels their current task. By building bedrooms for them, the need for naps is reduced and work becomes more efficient.List of job skillsMinerMasonStonecarverWoodcutterCarpenterWoodcarverSmelterBlacksmithMetalworkerWeaponsmithArmorerGemcutterJewelerWeaverTailorPotterLeatherworkerTinkererMachinistEngineerMechanicRancherButcheryGardenerFarmerChefMedicCaretakerBrewerBuilderHaulerThe player may also may also make custom "professions" by making a list one or many of the above skills and assigning a priority to them. This custom profession may then be assigned to a gnome on the fly to influence what tasks they undertake and when.The game is currently in alpha stage, but is available for a reduced price on the Gnomoria homepage as well as through Steam's early access program. You can also download a demo which lasts for 6 in-game days. After that you can purchase the game and keep your world.Credits(Quoted from the homepage of Gnomoria)Programming and Design: Robert West (RoboB0b)Art: RhopunzelAudio: James PrimateSystem RequirementsOS: Windows Xp, Vista, Win 7Processor: 2.0 GhzMemory: 1GBHard Disk Space: 50MBVideo Card: 128mb Video MemoryDirectX®: 9.0c or Greater</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21594">Slaves to Armok II: Dwarf Fortress</game><game id="17620">Dungeon Keeper</game><game id="35075">Dwarfs!?</game><game id="37295">A Game of Dwarves</game><game id="37574">Towns</game><game id="44272">RimWorld</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/15/155745/2328514-box_art.png</image></root>