<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38900</id><name>The Walking Dead: Survival Instinct</name><description>OverviewExploring zombie-infested towns is encouraged in the game.The Walking Dead: Survival Instinct is a first-person survival horror / action-adventure game developed by Terminal Reality and published by Activision for the Xbox 360, PlayStation 3, PC, and Wii U on March 19, 2013. A prequel to the horror drama television series The Walking Dead (which itself is based on the comic book series of the same name), players assume the role of Southern hunter Daryl Dixon as he, along with his brother Merle, travels through rural U.S.A. at the beginning of the zombie apocalypse.Unlike most first-person shooters involving zombies, progressing through the game requires heavy resource management as ammunition, food, and other equipment are scarce (encouraging exploration through the environment).GameplayThe Walking Dead: Survival Instinct is a first person game with survival and stealth mechanics. Players will be required to manage resources while trekking through zombie infested Georgia. Daryl is able to use both melee weapons and long ranged weapons. Ammo is scarce and the game encourages players to explore the semi-open world environments in order to find ammo and other useful objects such as bandages.Like in games such as ZombiU, one zombie can easily overcome the player. Firing a gun can attract enemies while flashing a light on a zombie will also attract it towards the player. Zombies are also sensible to the player's smell (a recurring theme in both the graphic novel and the TV series) meaning that zombies can find Daryl even if they can't see him. Daryl will be able to kill zombies in one shot by sneaking up behind them for a stealth kill.Throughout the game, players can recruit up to four survivors to join their group. Players can then send survivors to go and collect supplies. Each survivor has different stats indicating whether or not they'll be able to survive the trip for supplies. Furthermore, the story will force the players to leave survivors behind, a death sentence in zombie infested Georgia.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18419">Land of the Dead: Road to Fiddler's Green</game><game id="21534">Dead Island</game><game id="35619">ZombiU</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2428432-box_twdsi.png</image></root>