<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3892</id><name>American Conquest</name><description>American Conquest is an RTS spanning four centuries of American history. It uses the same engine as Cossacks: European Wars and much of the gameplay is the same. The major difference is that Cossacks focuses on European history, while American Conquest focuses on American history.In addition to a shift in location, several changes have been made to the base mechanics found in the Cossack games. Peasant units, once solely used for resource collection, in former Cossack games are now trained as military units by first garrisoning them in a military building and then converting them into soldiers. Further more peasant units are no longer created from town centers but from houses. Another change to the construction mechanic is that in American Conquest the cost of buildings and units increase depending on how many of that unit or building have already been created. The strategy of American Conquest is much the same as it's predecessors with the addition of the ability for infantry to garrison inside and defend buildings; as well as capture enemy buildings by means of garrison.System RequirementsOperating system:Windows® XP / Vista™ / Windows® 7Processor: 1.4 GHz CPUMemory: 512 MBHard disk space: 3.5GBVideo:Video Card with 64MB dedicated memory and DirectX 9 CompatibleSound:Sound card with DirectX 9.0 supportDirectX®:9.0 or higher</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9413">Cossacks: European Wars</game><game id="18047">Cossacks II: Napoleonic Wars</game><game id="8336">Cossacks: The Art of War</game><game id="6104">Cossacks: Back to War</game><game id="8546">Age of Empires III</game><game id="12483">Age of Empires III: The WarChiefs</game><game id="23829">Alexander</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15405/832127-american_conquest_coverart.png</image></root>