<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38933</id><name>SD Gundam G Generation Overworld</name><description> OverviewOverworld introduces lots of side-story manga. SD Gundam G Generation Overworld is yet another entry in the G Generation series of Gundam-based collect-'em-all strategy games. G Gen Overworld is very similar to its immediate predecessor SD Gundam G Generation World. In addition to World Seer, which features a variety of missions based on the various Gundam series, a new set of missions, known as "World Core," have been added. In addition, "Over Impact," yet another twist on the previous game's Generation Break, turns all of a given scenario's guest units into enemies, giving players the opportunity to capture their Mobile Suits.Overworld adds a large number of characters and Mobile Suits from Gundam sidestories, such as Gundam SEED Astray and Gundam 00V. It also adds Asemu Asuno from Gundam AGE's second arc, along with his Gundam AGE-2 Normal; no other second- or third-gen AGE content is present in the game.There is a carryover bonus for having an SD Gundam G Generation Portable and/or World save.Master Characters Asemu is stuck in his father's shadow for at least one more game.The Master Character system makes a return. Like other G Gen games, the Master Unit will receive a "Basic" version of their signature Mobile Suit. The Basic Mobile Suit is an overall weaker version of its regular counterpart; it might lack certain weapons or abilities, or it might have lower stats. Upon reaching a certain level, the suit can be upgraded to its normal version.Master Characters now receive an extra benefit. The new Master Skill system gives each pilot a bonus skill that can be activated if they are designated as a team's Master Unit. However, while most characters only receive one Master Skill when they are first recruited, a Master Character has access to all four of their Skills. All Master Characters from G Gen World returns except Mr. Bushido, who is replaced by his earlier incarnation. The debuting Master Characters are:CharacterSeriesHarry OrdTurn A Gundam Ribbons AlmarkGundam 00 Graham AkerGundam 00 Flit AsunoGundam AGE Desil GaletteGundam AGELike World, all pilots that aren't unlocked by expanding the in-game encyclopedia are available from the start.Featured SeriesMobile Suit GundamMSVMSXMobile Suit Gundam MS IglooMobile Suit Gundam MS Igloo 2Mobile Suit Gundam: The 08th MS Team Mobile Suit Gundam Side Story: The Blue Destiny Mobile Suit Gundam: Zeonic Front Mobile Suit Gundam Side Story: From Place Beyond the BlazeMobile Suit Gundam 0080: War in the Pocket Mobile Suit Gundam Battlefield Record U.C. 0081Mobile Suit Gundam 0083: Stardust MemoriesAdvance of ZMobile Suit Zeta Gundam (TV and A New Translation)Z-MSVGundam SentinelMobile Suit Gundam ZZMobile Suit Gundam: Char's CounterattackCCA-MSVM-MSVMobile Suit Gundam UnicornMobile Suit Gundam Unicorn MSVMobile Suit Gundam: Hathaway's FlashMobile Suit Gundam F90Mobile Suit Gundam Silhouette F91Mobile Suit Gundam F91F91-MSVMobile Suit Crossbone GundamMobile Suit Crossbone Gundam Skull HeartMobile Suit Crossbone Gundam Steel SevenMobile Suit Victory GundamMobile Fighter G GundamNew Mobile Report Gundam WingNew Mobile Report Gundam Wing: Endless WaltzNew Mobile Report Gundam Wing Dual Story: G-UnitAfter War Gundam XTurn A GundamMobile Suit Gundam SEEDSEED-MSVMobile Suit Gundam SEED AstrayMobile Suit Gundam SEED X AstrayMobile Suit Gundam SEED DestinySEED Destiny-MSVMobile Suit Gundam SEED C.E. 73 StargazerMobile Suit Gundam 00Mobile Suit Gundam 00 - A wakening of the TrailblazerMobile Suit Gundam 00PMobile Suit Gundam 00FMobile Suit Gundam 00VMobile Suit Gundam AGEGunpla Builders: Beginning GMobile Suit Gundam Secret Weapons: Phantom Bullet SD Gundam Gachapon/Gashapon Senshi series SD Gundam GXMobile Suit Gundam: Gihren's Greed Mobile Suit Gundam: Cross Dimension 0079G Generation Originals"Other Gundam game series" ( Dynasty Warriors Gundam)</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/16207/2261554-ggenoverworld.jpg</image></root>