<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38966</id><name>Ultima Forever: Quest for the Avatar</name><description>Ultima Forever: Quest for the Avatar is an action RPG developed by Mythic Entertainment and published by EA Games for iOS. The game is set after the events of Ultima IV: Quest of the Avatar.In U4E, a new character named Lady British is the ruler of Britannia. Players take on the role of an Earthling, summoned to Britannia to save the kingdrom the The Black Weep, a tentacle-like plague that is infecting the land.Gameplay is rendered in a 2D overhead view, featuring hack-and-slash action RPG combat. The game has a morality system; with players earning different amounts of XP based on which virtues they choose to follow in each of the game's cities, some of which value one or two virtues over others.Microtransactions come in the form of purchasable gold keys. The game has chests that can be opened with common bronze keys, uncommon silver keys, and high-end gold keys. The quality of the loot earned from opening chests will change depending on which keys you use. Keys are also used as a common currency to restore durability to equipment, fast travel between locations, and purchase moore inventory slots.DevelopmentUltima Forever was publicly announced in July 2012 by Mythic Entertainment, which at the time was known as BioWare Mythic. Later that year, Mythic shed the BioWare name. According to a 2012 GDC presentation by Mythic's creative director Paul Barnett, U4E had a troubled development and at one time was intended to be a browser-based game before transitioning to PC/iPad interoperability. The game had been scrapped and started over multiple times and -- according to Barnett -- it was once narrowly saved from EA's chopping block through the intervention of BioWare co-founder Dr. Ray Muzyka, in spite of the fact that Muzyka had been stricken with food poisoning after eating a sandwich at Mythic's offices.The game was initially expected in late 2012 but was delayed. The game was released in Canada on May 22, 2013 with a worldwide launch planned for a few months afterwards.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20803">Diablo III</game><game id="35003">Marvel Heroes</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2530742-1360668673-mzl.j.png</image></root>