<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38961</id><name>One Piece Romance Dawn: Bōken no Yoake</name><description>OverviewOne Piece Romance Dawn: Bōken no Yoake follows the early adventures of the fearless Monkey D. Luffy as he sets sail on the seas of East Blue in his quest to become the next Pirate King. It is both the first One Piece game on the PSP and the first "pure-RPG" One Piece game.One Piece Romance Dawn: Bōken no Yoake is based off the popular manga and anime series up to it's half way point featuring content from the East-blue and Grand line story arcs.CreationOriginally created by Eiichiro Oda, the One Piece franchise has become one of anime and manga's biggest and most successful franchises. In July 2012, Namco Bandai Games announced that they would be developing their first One Piece game for the PSP, the first ever pure RPG One Piece game.The game launched on December 20th 2012, it does not appear that this game will see release in the USA.Characters InvolvedMonkey D. Luffy: The fearless teenage boy who seeks to become the next Pirate King by locating the ultimate treasure known by all as the One Piece. He ingested the Devil Fruit known as the Gomu Gomu or Gum-Gum Fruit, a strange fruit which has effectively changed Luffy's body into that of a "rubberman" able to stretch, rebound from blunt strikes and inflate.Roronoa Zoro: Feared by pirates in East Blue who have bounties on their heads, Roronoa Zoro is a pirate hunter who strikes down his targets with his impressive sword skills and takes no prisoners in his quest to become the world's greatest swordsman.Nami: Crew navigator and theif of the Straw Hat Crew's ship. Her dream is to chart a map of the entire world.Usopp: A slingshot wielding marksman and compulsive liar who fights using tricks and clever planning due to his relative lack of strength.Sanji: The crew's cook, he fights primarily with kicks to protect his hands from injury.Captian Morgan: Known by everyone as "Axe-Hand Morgan", the brutal Captain Morgan of Shell Town was originally entrusted by the Marines to take over the stronghold that protects the town and keep the peace. However, he had no interest in sitting around watching over the island, and thus turned to terrorizing the inhabitants of Shell Town. At the time of the Romance Dawn Arc, Morgan has captured the infamous Pirate Hunter Roronoa Zoro and plans to have him executed by all of his loyal Marines for his crimes.Helmeppo: The spoiled son of the brutal Captain Morgan, Helmeppo treats everyone like the dirt under his feet, taking full advantage of all the benefits of being the son of a Marine Captain.Marines: The nameless ground and naval forces of the powerful World Government, the Marines are the primary source of law and order within the world of One Piece. Many men and women enlist under the banner of the Marines in the hope of being able to bring justice to the world and to put an end to the Great Pirate Age that has thrown the world into unstable seas.Arlong: The ruthless, human-hating Fishman who takes over Nami's home island to establish Arlong Park, his new base of operations in East Blue. Arlong is the captain of the Fishman Pirates and is responsible for the death of Nami's adoptive mother.Crocodile: One of the seven powerful Shichibukai who works under the World Government and the leader of the mysterious Baroque Works criminal organization, Crocodile seeks to overthrow the Kingdom of Alabasta under the guise of Mr. 0 in order to take control of the land and put it under his rule.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/11/119879/2432798-518j-bbcttl._sl500_ss500_.jpg</image></root>