<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>38991</id><name>F1 Race Stars</name><description>F1 Race Stars is developed by Codemasters. The game is described by Codemasters as being designed for entertainment rather than simulation.OverviewF1 Race Stars features various racers from around the world racing on various tracks. Each racer has different qualities that pertain to that racer. For example, one racer may get a triple ricochet bubble attack versus the normal. Much like other kart racers, this game features the staples: weapons, boost sections, shortcuts, etc. The player can choose from 1,000 CC up to 3,000 CC races.Teams and DriversF1 Race Stars features drivers from the 2012 season of Formula 1 but also includes a few characters added that are not actual racers. The list below contains all of the characters including those not a part of F1. Each team has their own unique ability that differentiates them from the others.Red Bull Racing (Slipstream Boost)Sebastian VettelMark WebberMclaren (Swap Power-up)Lewis HamiltonJenson ButtonFerrari (Backward Seeker Bubble)Fernando AlonsoFelipe MassaMercedes (Triple Pulse Bubble)Michael SchumacherNico RosbergLotus (Triple Ricochet Bubble)Kimi RäikkönenRomain GrosjeanForce India (Smart Pulse Bubble)Paul di RestaNico HulkenbergSauber (Ricochet Bubble Aim Assist)Kamui KobayashiSergio PerezToro Rosso (Piercing Seeker Bubble)Daniel RicciardoJean-Eric VergneWilliams (Ghost Boost)Pastor MaldonadoBruno SennaCaterham (Triple Trap Bubble)Heikki KovalainenVitaly PetrovHRT (Super Boost)Pedro de la RosaNarain KarthikeyanMarussia (Super Jump Boost)Timo GlockCharles PicFake CharactersRuby Power (Random Bonus)Jessica Chekker (Random Bonus)Josh Merit (Off-road)Kira Hoshihara (Off-road)Power-upsPower-up names, descriptions, images taken from the official website. Currently, there are 14 power-ups in total that players can deploy mid-race.NameDescriptionImageBalloonsDrop these balloons on the track and rivals who drive through them will find their screen covered in fun confetti!Bottle RocketTurn your car into a flying bottle of fizzy pop and fly up the track!Trap BubbleDrop this naughty bubble on the track and other drivers will become trapped when they drive into it!DRSDeploy DRS (Drag Reducing System) to become invulnerable and increase your top speed.BoostUse your Boost to get extra speed for overtaking.PulseCaught in the pack? Use Pulse to slow down the cars around you!Pulse BubbleLaunch your Pulse Bubble forward, then trigger it when you've found your targets!Rain CloudDo the rain dance! Use the Rain Cloud power-up and you'll cause a slowing shower to pour down on the car in first place!Ricochet BubbleLaunch the Ricochet Bubble forward to trap your rival's car.Safety CarCall in the Safety Car to slow up the pack!Seeker BubbleUse the Seeker Bubble to trap the driver ahead of you.StaticUse Static to disable the other drivers' power-ups!TeleportSneak up the grid - use Teleport to leap up the track!Wet WeatherWhen it rains, it pours! Trigger wet weather and slow down the drivers - except you'll have wet tires to speed past your rivals.TracksAll of the tracks featured in F1 Race Stars are inspired from their real-life counterparts. While the tracks take liberties with the overall look, fans of F1 will recognize a few iconic turns during each of them. The list of the current tracks available is contained in the list below.USA, Circuit of the Americas (Austin)Brazil, Autódromo José Carlos Pace (Interlagos)Italy, Autodromo Nazionale Monza (Monza)Britain, Silverstone (Silverstone)Monaco, Circuit de Monaco (Monte Carlo)Belgium, Circuit de Spa-Francorchamps (Spa)Germany, Hockenheimring (Hockenheim)Abu Dhabi, Yas Marina Circuit (Yas Island)Singapore, Marina Bay Street Circuit (Marina Bay)Japan, Suzuka Circuit (Suzuka)Australia, Melbourne Grand Prix Circuit (Melbourne)Powered Up Edition (Wii U Version)The Wii U version of the game, originally set to arrive by March 2013 but quietly pushed back a little while, is dubbed "Powered Up Edition" and comes with new on-disc content previously sold only as DLC in the form of nine accessory packs and all additional race tracks, namely Europe, Canada, India and China.PC System RequirementsMinimumRecommendedOS: Windows Vista / 7Processor: Intel Core 2 Duo @ 2.4Ghz or AMD Athlon X2 5400+Memory: 2GBGraphics: GeForce 8600 / Radeon HD 2600 ProDirectX®: DirectX 10Hard Drive: 5 GBSound: DirectX Compatible Soundcard or onboard audioOS: Windows Vista / 7Processor: Intel Core i7 3.0 GHz or AMD Phenom II X6 3.3 GHzMemory: 4GBGraphics: GeForce GTX 460 or ATI Radeon HD 6870DirectX®: 11Hard Drive: 5 GBSound: DirectX Compatible Soundcard or onboard audio</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="26848">ModNation Racers</game><game id="31747">Mario Kart 7</game><game id="16283">F-1 Race</game><game id="20610">WipEout HD</game><game id="37743">F1 2012</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2368436-box_f1rs.png</image></root>