<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3902</id><name>Capcom Classics Collection Remixed</name><description>OverviewCapcom Classics Collection Remixed is a compilation game developed by Digital Eclipse Software and published by Capcom for the PSP platform.GameplayThe Main Menu ScreenSince Capcom Classics Collection Remixed contains twenty different classic games the individual gameplay will vary from game to game. The games are chosen from an in-game menu system. The games in this collection contain extras, history, options, and high scores that can be accessed from this menu. Some of the games in the collection also feature wireless multiplayer.OptionsOptions for an individual game can be accessed by pressing the Square button for the selected game. The setting will vary depending on the chosen game, but all have two pre-configured options in Normal and Hardcore. In addition to these pre-set options, a custom configuration can also be created.Some of the individual game options in the game are:Lives - This option is for setting the desired number of starting lives.Difficulty - This options is for settings the desired difficulty level and will vary from game to game.Bonus Life - This option is for setting the amount of points that must be acquired to gain a bonus life.Continues - This option is for setting the desired amount of continues that the player will start with.Some of the options apply to all games in the collection. These options are:Control Setup - In this option the controls for each game can be set as desired.Save - This option is to manually save the options and unlocks for a particular game. This option is not needed unless the auto-save option is turned off.Load - This option will manually load the settings for a game.Delete - This option will delete any saved options for a game as well as any unlocks that have been previously unlocked.Reset Score - This option will reset the high score table to contain the default high scores.Auto-Save - The auto-save option can be turned on or off, if it is turned on the game will automatically save all settings. This option is a global option across all games in the collection.High ScoresThere are individual high scores for each game in the collection. To access the high score list for the selected game the Triangle button must be pressed. There are three separate high score tables for each game, one for the normal settings, one for the hardcore settings, and one for custom settings. To access the three different tables left or right on the D-Pad or Analog Stick must be pressed.MultiplayerOn the menu while highlighting a game that allows for multiplayer the R shoulder button can be pressed to join the ad-hoc multiplayer screen. Any person using their game with the wi-fi switch turned on and playing a multiplayer game will be hosting it. If a player tries to join a hosting player, that hosting player will receive a notification asking for permission to join.BonusHistory for 1941Each game in the collection contains various bonus items. These bonus items can be unlocked by meeting certain requirements in the individual game. This bonus menu can be selected by pressing the Circle button on the desired game. The types of bonus content are:Art - The art sections contains a selection of various screenshots, concept art, and more. The pictures show up in a thumbnailed gallery. To view a full size picture the analog stick is used to highlight the desired picture and then the X button is pressed.Tips - The tips section contains various tips and tricks to help in the games. Each page contains one tip, and the pages can be cycled by pressing left or right on the analog stick or D-Pad.Music - In this section the various music tracks from the games can be listened to. The tracks are in a list and can be played by pressing the X button on the highlighted song.History - This section is unlocked right from the start for every game. The history section contains stories about the background of the games, the development, or facts.List of games1941: Counter Attack1941: Counter AttackNumber of Players: 1 or 2 (co-op)Genre: Shoot 'Em UpDefault Controls:X - ShootSquare/Circle - LoopAvengersAvengersNumber of Players: 1 or 2 (co-op)Genre: Beat 'Em UpDefault Controls:X - PunchSquare/Circle - KickBionic CommandoNumber of Players: 1 or 2 (Pass Play)Genre: PlatformerDefault Controls:X - ShootSquare/Circle - HookBlack TigerBlack TigerNumber of Players: 1 or 2 (Pass Play)Genre: ActionDefault Controls:X - JumpSquare/Circle - AttackBlock BlockNumber of Players: 1 or 2 (Co-op)Genre: PuzzleDefault Controls:X/R - Release BallCaptain CommandoCaptain CommandoNumber of Players: 1 - 4 (Co-op)Genre: Beat 'Em UpDefault Controls:X - JumpSquare/Circle - AttackSquare/Circle + X - Super AttackDouble Tap Left/Right - DashFinal FightNumber of Players: 1 or 2 (Co-op)Genre: Beat 'Em UpDefault Controls:X - JumpSquare/Circle - AttackSquare/Circle + X - Super AttackForgotten WorldsNumber of Players: 1 or 2 (Co-op)Genre: Shoot 'Em UpDefault Controls:X - ShootSquare/L - Spin LeftCircle/R - Spin RightLast DuelNumber of Players: 1 or 2 (Co-op)Genre: Shoot 'Em UpDefault Controls:X - ShootSquare/Circle - Jump/ShieldLegendary WingsNumber of Players: 1 or 2 (Co-op)Genre: Shoot 'Em UpDefault Controls:X - ShootSquare/Circle - Bomb/JumpMagic SwordMagic SwordNumber of Players: 1 or 2 (Co-op)Genre: ActionDefault Controls:X - JumpSquare/Circle - AttackSquare/Circle + X - Super AttackMega TwinsMega TwinsNumber of Players: 1 or 2 (Co-op)Genre: ActionDefault Controls:X - ShootSquare/Circle - HookTriangle - Magic CrashQuiz  DragonsNumber of Players: 1 or 2 (Co-op)Genre: TriviaDefault Controls:Triangle - Answer 1Square - Answer 2Circle - Answer 3X - Answer 4Section ZNumber of Players: 1 or 2 (Pass Play)Genre: Shoot 'Em UpDefault Controls:X - ShootSquare/Circle/R/L - TurnSide Arms: Hyper DyneNumber of Players: 1 or 2 (Co-op)Genre: Shoot 'Em UpDefault Controls:Square/L - Shoot LeftCircle/R - Shoot RightX/Triangle - Switch WeaponSpeed RumblerNumber of Players: 1 or 2 (Pass Play)Genre: Shoot 'Em UpDefault Controls:X - ShootSquare/Circle - Escape/RollStreet FighterStreet FighterNumber of Players: 1 or 2 (Co-op)Genre: FightingDefault Controls:Triangle - Light PunchSquare - Strong PunchCircle - Light KickX - Strong KickStriderStriderNumber of Players: 1 or 2 (Pass Play)Genre: ActionDefault Controls:X - JumpSquare/Circle - AttackThree WondersNumber of Players: 1 or 2 (Co-op)Genre: Action, Shoot 'Em Up, PuzzleDefault Controls:Midnight WanderersX - JumpSquare/Circle - AttackChariotX - Charge AttackSquare/Circle - ShootDon't PullX/Square/Circle - PushVarthNumber of Players: 1 or 2 (Co-op)Genre: Shoot 'Em UpDefault Controls:X - AttackSquare/Circle - M. CrashPS Vita CompatibilityDespite not being in the official compatibility list, Capcom Classics Collection Remixed can be played on the PS Vita. To do this, the user must first download the game to the PS3. From there, go to Content Transfer on the PS Vita and select the game for transfer. Once complete, the game will show up on the Vita's menu.</description><genres><genre id="15">Compilation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14457">Sega Genesis Collection</game><game id="9500">Capcom Classics Collection Reloaded</game><game id="24218">Sonic's Ultimate Genesis Collection</game><game id="2138">Capcom Classics Collection</game><game id="461">Capcom Classics Collection: Volume 2</game><game id="10958">Activision Hits Remixed</game><game id="10965">EA Replay</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2345116-box_cccr.png</image></root>