<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>39035</id><name>Battlefield 4</name><description>OverviewBattlefield 4 is a modern military first person shooter developed by DICE and published by Electronic Arts. It is the first game to utilize DICE's Frostbite 3 game engine technology. Battlefield 4 will be available for PC, Xbox 360 and PS3 on October 29th 2013. It will also be available on PlayStation 4 for the console's launch November 15th 2013 (Nov 29th in EU), and the Xbox One at it's launch November 22nd, 2013.GameplayCampaignBattlefield 4's single player campaign takes place six years after the events of Battlefield 3 in the year 2020. Russia and China appear as the opposing factions.MultiplayerBattlefield 4 continues the series tradition of class based multiplayer mechanics with objective driven gameplay. Maps and modes involve both large-scale vehicular warfare, as well as smaller infantry-only scenarios. The revamped Frostbite 3 engine allows for more enhanced destruction and interactive environments. A Spectator Mode has been added if players simply want to watch the action. Players will again have the ability to rent servers to personalize the experience.Levolution"Levolution" refers to the dynamic destruction capable in multiplayer, so called because of the players increased ability to alter  interact with the physical characteristics of the map. This includes small things like being able to open  close doors, ride elevators, shoot out lights, as well as referring to much larger "events." Each map has one major Levolution event that significantly alters the terrain of the map, such as a toppling skyscraper in the map Siege of Shanghai, or a destroyer ship beaching onto an island in Paracel Storm.Commander ModeCommander Mode is back in Battlefield 4Battlefield 4 also sees the return of Commander Mode, last seen in Battlefield 2. In this mode, the player (who does not take up a spot on their team's leaderboard) provides aid to their team through intelligence and offensive support. Additionally, the Commander can select any player on their team and see a picture-in-picture view of that player's screen. This mode can even be played using mobile devices without connecting to the game via console or PC.Commander Mode is available only in Conquest, Rush, and Obliteration game modes.ClassesBattlefield 4 retains the same four classes as the previous game, with a few alterations in available capabilities  gadgets:Assault: Largely the same as before, the assault class carries assault rifles  medical packs, with the option of carrying defibrillators or grenade/smoke launchers.Engineer: The engineer's main weapon class has been changed to PDWs instead of carbines. This class is again the anti-vehicle class, with the ability to carry RPGs and mines.Support: On top of ammo packs, C4, and claymores, the support class also has remote controlled mortars available. They also have an increased ability for suppressive fire than the other classes.Recon: This class now has C4 and claymores available to them, as well as throwable motion sensors (last seen in Bad Company 2.) They also have the new ability to adjust sniper scopes to compensate for distance, known as "zeroing."Game ModesThere are 7 game modes available at launch. Five return from Battlefield 3, with two new modes (Obliteration and Defuse) introduced:ModePlayer Count (X360, PS3)Player Count (XOne, PS4, PC)DescriptionConquest2464The classic Battlefield game mode where teams battle for control of flags on the map, with the team that holds less flags bleeding respawn tickets.Rush2432The staple "attack  defend" game mode, where the attackers try to arm and destroy two MCOM stations in each zone, while the defending team defends them.Team Deathmatch2020Two teams of 10 players face-off to reach the target score of kills in a round.Squad Deathmatch2020Similar to Team Deathmatch, except 4 teams of 5 players each battle each other to reach the target score first.Domination2020Very similar to Conquest, but with smaller teams, smaller maps, and no vehicles. Also, players cannot spawn on flags, capture times are greatly decreased, and ticket bleed rates are greatly increased.Obliteration2432Two teams battle to pick up a bomb that randomly spawns on the map, and then transport that bomb to one of three enemy control points to destroy it. The first team to destroy all three enemy objectives wins.Defuse1010In this 5 vs 5 infantry-only, no respawn mode, teams win by either arming  detonating a single objective (similar to Rush's MCOM station), or eliminating the other 5 players on the opposing team. Players can be revived one time before they are permanently removed from the round. MapsThere will be ten maps available at launch. All game modes are playable on all the maps:DawnbreakerFlood ZoneGolmud RailwayHainan ResortLancang DamOperation LockerParacel StormRogue TransmissionSiege of ShanghaiZavod 311BattlepacksBattlepacks are an additional way to unlock items in multiplayer. They are awarded at set intervals by leveling up both soldiers and weapons. Much like the weapon packs in Mass Effect 3, items granted in Battlepacks are randomized. The items awarded are non-game-changing, cosmetic variants of accessories such as new knives, dog tags, soldier camouflages, weapon/vehicle paints, experience boosts, weapon accessories, and more.Items contained in Battlepacks have three levels of color-coded rarity; Standard (grey), Advanced (white), Superior (blue),  Distinguished (orange).There are three tiers of Battlepacks; Bronze, Silver,  Gold, as well as black Weapon Packs. The Bronze Pack will contain three items: two Standard ones, and one that has a chance of being Advanced. The quantity and rarity of the items increase in the Silver and Gold Packs. The Weapon Pack is aimed specifically at the noted weapon and provides weapon accessories for that weapon. SoundtrackBattlefield 3 composers, Johan Skugge  Jukka Rintamäki returned to score the fourth entry in the series.NumberNameComposerLength1.Stutter (Theme from Battlefield 4)Johan Skugge1:552.Warsaw ThemeRami2:363.The Majestic ValkyrieJohan Skugge2:004.Jin Jie's RevolutionJohan Skugge3:165.OppressionJohan Skugge3:526.A Theme for KjellJohan Skugge3:367.Rough JourneyJohan Skugge2:428.Silk VistaJohan Skugge2:379.Alone and AbandonedJohan Skugge3:2610.Fishing In BakuJohan Skugge4:5011.If Wishes Were HorsesJohan Skugge3:2012.High TideJohan Skugge1:5613.Being IrishJohan Skugge1:4214.Battlefield 4 (Beta Theme)Johan Skugge1:2315.When the Dam BreaksJohan Skugge2:3716.Dunn's DownJohan Skugge4:5217.Cyclone 2Johan Skugge1:55 Downloadable ContentThere will be five expansion packs released for Battlefield 4 that will feature new maps, game modes, weapons and more. Each expansion will be available individually for purchase, or can be bought in a bundle with a membership to Battlefield Premium.Second AssaultChina RisingNaval StrikeDragon's TeethFinal Stand Pre-UnveilingThe game was revealed during a promotion for Medal of Honor: Warfighter, allowing beta access to those who pre-order Warfighter, or purchase the Limited Edition.At a company meeting on February 19, 2013, store managers and CEO of Gamestop were given a sneak peak of Battlefield 4.Media were sent an invite via email on March 15th, 2013, to an unveiling event hosted at AMC Metreon in San Francisco.On March 20th, 2013, EA created a teaser site that would slowly show artwork from the game as more members logged into the site. A first look at gameplay was promised and shown at the March 26 unveil event.UnveilCampaign gameplay was shown to press and developers on March 27, 2013 at 7pm, during the Game Developers Conference 2013 hosted at AMC Metreon in San Francisco. A 17-minute campaign video was released to the general public.Multiplayer revealMultiplayer gameplay for Battlefield 4 was first presented at E3 2013 and was streamed live throughout the week. The map "Siege of Shanghai" was playable for the traditional Conquest mode. The demo showcased several new features including an automatic cover system, swimming underwater, "sprint swimming," and more.BetaAn open beta was launched by DICE in the beginning of October for PC, X360, and PS4. It featured the Siege of Shanghai map in the Conquest and Domination game modes. The Obliteration game mode was also added midway through the beta.The following schedule for access to the Battlefield 4 beta on PS3, X360, and PC was as follows:October 1-3: "Exclusive" early access for players who had at least one of the following:Pre-ordered the PC Digital Deluxe Edition on OriginPurchased Medal of Honor Warfighter Limited Edition or Digital Deluxe EditionPurchased Battlefield 3 PremiumOctober 4-15: Open beta access for all players.PC System Requirements MinimumOSWindows Vista 32 BitProcessorAMD Athlon X2 2.8 GHZ / Intel CORE 2 DUO 2.4 GHZRAM4 GBGraphics CardAMD Radeon HD 3870 / NVIDIA GeoFORCE 8800 GTGraphics Memory512 MBHard Drive Space30 GB RecommendedOSWindows 8 64 BitProcessorAMD Six-Core CPU / Intel QUAD-Core CPURAM8 GBGraphics CardAMD Radeon HD 7870 / NVIDIA GeoForce GTX 660Graphics Memory3 GBHard Drive Space30 GB</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="42860">Titanfall</game><game id="35383">ArmA III</game><game id="41520">Call of Duty: Ghosts</game><game id="35129">Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 3</game><game id="27863">Dust 514</game><game id="21116">MAG</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/82063/2560915-b4clean.jpg</image></root>