<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>39042</id><name>The Walking Dead Season Two</name><description>OverviewThe continuation of TellTale's first season of The Walking Dead. The season is set to be released in 2013.The choices that players made in The Walking Dead: Season One will be able to be imported into Season Two if a save file exists on the same machine. The choices from the "400 Days" DLC will also carry over.Telltale wants to tie this game into the TV series and is exploring some way of tying the characters from the game to characters from the show.Clementine will be a major part of the overall story and has been confirmed as the main protagonist. The game will also explore the fate of Kenny.System RequirementsPCMinimumOS: Windows XP Service Pack 3Processor: Core 2 Duo 2GHz or equivalentMemory: 3 GB RAMGraphics: ATI or NVidia card w/ 512 MB RAMDirectX: Version 9.0cHard Drive: 2 GB available spaceSound Card: Direct X 9.0c sound deviceAdditional Notes: Not recommended for Intel integrated graphicsRecommendedOS: Windows XP Service Pack 3Processor: Core 2 Duo 2.3 Ghz or equivalentMemory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: ATI or NVidia card w/ 1024 MB RAMDirectX: Version 9.0cHard Drive: 2 GB available spaceSound Card: Direct X 9.0c sound deviceAdditional Notes: Not recommended for Intel integrated graphicsMacMinimumOS: Snow Leopard (10.6.X)Processor: 2.3 Ghz IntelMemory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: 512 MB NVidia or ATI graphics cardHard Drive: 2 GB available spaceAdditional Notes: Not recommended for Intel integrated graphics or Mac Minis or early-generation MacBookRecommendedOS: Snow Leopard (10.6.X)Processor: Core 2 Duo 2GHzMemory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: 1024 MB NVidia or ATI graphics cardHard Drive: 2 GB available spaceAdditional Notes: Not recommended for Intel integrated graphics or Mac Minis or early-generation MacBooks</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/39/2565113-wds2_psn_pc_boxart.jpg</image></root>