<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>39077</id><name>Fart Cat!</name><description>OverviewFart Cat! is a game developed and published by Summer Camp Studios for the iPhone and iPad platforms. The game presents you with five different slots that hold various food items, from hamburgers to fish heads. You must drag the food the Fart Cat is craving (indicated by the dream cloud over its head) by dragging the food to its mouth. Feed Fart Cat the requisite number of food items and touch its belly before its owner reaches in to pet it. Fart Cat would rather eat than be loved!If the correct food type is not available, touching the cat's belly before meeting the requirement of food fed will swap your five food slots for new ones.Golden Mice give you a score bonus and will be accepted as edible by the Fart Cat at any time.FartcraftA secondary mode in Fart Cat!, Fartcraft features no time pressure or score but instead lets you mix and match different groups of ingredients to discover a bevy of scatological-related dish names.Fart NameIngredientsFartNoneU Can Has FartHamburgerOcean SprayFish HeadRoquefartStinky CheeseFrrrappjacksPancakesSqueakerMouseCall of PootyHamburger, Fish HeadJuicy LucyHamburger, Stinky CheeseStepped on a DuckHamburger, PancakesFartatouilleHamburger, MouseToot-na MeltFish Head, Stinky CheeseBrain FartFish Head, PancakesBombin' JerryFish Head, MouseSplatulaStinky Cheese, PancakesThe OdorodentStinky Cheese, MouseShart StackPancakes, MouseThat Was The DogHamburger, Fish Head, Stinky CheeseAnimal StyleHamburger, Fish Head, PancakesSmelt it, Dealt itHamburger, Fish Head, MouseBrunch BuffetHamburger, Stinky Cheese, PancakesMighty Mighty Mouse ToneHamburger, Stinky Cheese, MouseMrs. SplutterworthHamburger, Pancakes, MouseThe Deadliest SplatchFish Head, Stinky Cheese, PancakesToot in PuddleFish Head, Stinky Cheese, MouseCut the CheeseFish Head, Pancakes, MousePeeling PaintStinky Cheese, Pancakes, MouseFull English BreakfastHamburger, Fish Head, Stinky Cheese, PancakesMouse on a MotorcycleHamburger, Fish Head, Stinky Cheese, MouseThe Kitchen StinkHamburger, Fish Head, Pancakes, MouseItchy, ScratchyHamburger, Stinky Cheese, Pancakes, MouseWhere's the Beef?Fish Head, Stinky Cheese, Pancakes, MouseApocalypse MeowHamburger, Fish Head, Stinky Cheese, Pancakes, Mouse</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8960/2311958-fart_cat.jpg</image></root>