<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>39186</id><name>Combat Mission: Fortress Italy</name><description>OverviewCombat Mission: Fortress Italy is the fourth Combat Mission title using the CMx2 engine and the first using the 2.0 version of the engine. It covers the fighting in Italy, beginning with the battle for Sicily. The initial release includes the Americans, Italians, and Germans, with each army having its own campaign. The following modules will represent the rest of the war in Italy through to the end of the war.GameplayCombat Mission: Fortress Italy can be played in one of two ways. The traditional way to play is with WeGo, a turn-based mode where each player gives orders to their units and then watch the turn play out with a minute of action. During this time, no orders can be given, but the players can re-watch the turn as many times as they'd like. The other mode, introduced in Shock Force, is a real-time mode which plays out similarly to other RTS games. In this mode, depending on the difficulty selected, the player is allowed to pause the game and give new orders as often as they'd like.Each battle revolves around victory conditions assigned to each player depending on the scenario or quick battle selected. Traditionally, this has been Victory Locations, a spot on the map that must be held by the end of the battle. These locations can be as small as a single building or as large as a city block. CMx2 introduced other types of victory conditions, including destroying a location, destroying particular enemy units, low ammo usage, keeping friendly casualties low, and other variants of these. To achieve these conditions, the player must utilize the terrain to make as best use of the units allotted as possible. Overwhelming firepower can be brought down with smart use of the terrain. While ordering the units, C2 (Command and Control) must be kept in mind, as units outside outside of leadership control may not perform as well and break easier.CMx2 2.0The upgrade to the next version of CMx2 brought some long requested changes. Waypoints that can be dragged have been brought back, allowing a player to adjust a path without building it from the beginning. Unit grouping through hotkeys was also added, making real-time play more manageable. Scenarios can now be sorted by the various battle parameters, and those parameters are now listed plainly beside a scenario's picture when selected. Map making was made slightly easier by adding in the ability to import an image as an overlay on the map making screen. The last big change was the addition of pausing while playing a battle online. Alongside these changes were assorted other small tweaks, a few new orders, and a change to the rendering engine. All engine upgrades can be retroactively applied to past titles, beginning with Combat Mission: Battle for Normandy. Shock Force and Afghanistan will not receive any engine upgrades due to the many changes that were made to the engine for Battle for Normandy.Units and VehiclesTable of Organization and Equipment (TOE)German Major FormationsPanzer Grenadier Battalion (1942 type, motorized)Panzer Aufklärungs Battalion (motorized)Pionier Battalion (motorized)Panzer Battalion (3 Pz IV companies)Mixed Panzer Battalion (1 Pz IV company, 2 Pz III companies)Heavy Panzer Company (Tigers)Sturmgeschutz CompanyPanzerjäger CompanyItalian Major FormationsInfantry BattalionBlackshirt BattalionMachinegun BattalionAntitank Battalion (Cannone da 47/32)Pioneer CompanyAssault and Landing Battalion (motorized)Guastatori Battalion (motorized)Bersaglieri Battalion (Truck)Armored Car BattalionTankette BattalionMachinegun Battalion (motorized)Light Tank Battalion (L5 tank)Light Tank Battalion (R35 tank)Tank Destroyer Battalion (Semovente 47/32)Tank Destroyer Battalion (Semovente 90/53)Self-Propelled Artillery Battalion (Semovente 75/18)United States Major FormationsInfantry BattalionArmored Infantry BattalionRanger BattalionParachute BattalionEngineer BattalionArmored Engineer BattalionCavalry Reconnaissance TroopArmored Reconnaissance BattalionMedium Tank BattalionLight Tank BattalionGerman TanksTiger EarlyPz IV LatePz IV LatestPz IV H EarlyPz III MPz III NMarder IIStuG IIIF/8StuG IIIG EarliestStuG IIIG EarlyStuH 42 EarlyGerman VehiclesGrille Ausf. HWespePSW 221PSW 222PSW 223PSW 231PSW 233KubelwagonOpel BlitzProtze 70German HalftracksSdkfz 250/1 Alt HalftrackSdkfz 250/3 Alt HalftrackSdkfz 250/10 Alt HalftrackItalian TanksRenault R-35L5/21L5/30L3/33L3/35Semovente 90/53Semovente 75/18 M41Semovente 75/18 M42Semovenete 47/32Carro Comando M41Carro Comando M42Italian VehiclesAB 41AS.42 (Cannone da 47/32)AS.42 (Breda 20mm AA)AS.42 (2x Breda 8mm)AS.42 (Solothurn ATR)Fiat 626 NMAmerican TanksM4 Sherman EarlyM4 Sherman MidM4A1 Sherman EarlyM4A1 Sherman MidM5A1 StuartAmerican HalftracksT30 HMC HalftrackM3 GMC HalftrackM2 HalftrackM3 Halftrack (1x M1919)M3 Halftrack (2x M1919)M3 Halftrack (1x M2HB)M4A1 HalftrackAmerican VehiclesM7 HMC PriestM3A1 White Scout CarJeepJeep MMGJeep HMG2.5 Ton TruckGerman Large Guns/Mortar (on map)81mm GrW 34 Mortar50mm PaK 3875mm PaK 4076mm PaK 36R88mm Flak 3675mm leIG 18150mm sIG 33Italian Large Guns/Mortar (on map)45mm Brixia M35 Light Mortar81mm Mortaio da 81/14 Modello 35 Mortar47mm Cannone da 47/32 M3565mm Cannone da 65/17 M13American Large Guns/Mortars (on map)60mm M2 Mortar81mm M1 Mortar37mm M357mm M175mm M1A1 Pack HowitzerGerman Small ArmsKAR 98KKAR 98K (Schiessbecher Grenade Launcher)KAR 98K SniperMP40MG34MG42MG34P38Italian Small ArmsM1891 rifleBeretta M38M1934Breda M30Breda M37Small ArmsM1 GarandM1903A3M1903A3 (with M1 Grenade Launcher)M1903A4 SniperM1 CarbineM1A1 CarbineM1A1 ThompsonM1919A4M1917A1M2HBM1911A1Air Support (Various loadouts)GermanBF-109G6BF-109G6/U4FW-190A5AmericanA-20G HavocA-36A ApacheP-40F WarhawkArtillery SupportGerman81mm sGrw 34 Mortar120mm sGrw 42 Mortar75mm leIG 18 Infantry Gun150mm sIG 33 Infantry Gun75mm FK 38 Field Gun170mm K 18 Cannon105mm sK 18 Cannon105mm leFH 18 Howitzer150mm sFH 18 Howitzer210mm Mrs 18 Howitzer105mm Wespe150mm Grille88mm Flak 36 Flack (as indirect artillery support)150mm Nebelwerfer 41 Rocket280mm Nebelwerfer 41 Rocket210mm Nebelwerfer 42 Rocket300mm Nebelwerfer 42 RocketItalian81mm M35 Mortar47mm Cannone da 47/32 Gun65mm Cannone da 65/17 Gun75mm Obice da 75/18 Howitzer75mm Cannone da 75/27 Gun100mm Obice da 100/17 Howitzer105mm Cannone da 105/28 Gun149mm Obice da 149/13 Howitzer149mm Cannone da 149/35 Gun90mm Cannone da 90/53 (as indirect artillery support)American60mm M2 Mortar81mm M1 Mortar4.2in M2 Mortar155mm M1A1 Long Tom75mm M1A1 Pack Howitzer75mm T30 HMC105mm M2A1 Howitzer105mm M7 HMC Priest155mm M1 Howitzer4.5in T-27E2 RocketUS Navy Destroyer (various calibers)US Navy Light Cruiser (various calibers)System RequirementsSystem Requirements MINIMUM:Operating System: Windows XP/Vista/Win7Processor: Pentium IV 1.8 GHz or equivalent speed AMD processorVideo Card: GeForce 5200 or Radeon 9200 (32 Megabyte VRAM or better and must support 1024x768 or higher resolution) in OpenGLSound Card: DirectX 9 compatible Sound CardSystem Memory 256 Megabytes RAMHard Drive Space: 3.5 GBSystem Requirements SUGGESTED:Operating System: Windows XP/Vista/Win7Processor: Pentium IV 2.8 GHz or equivalent speed AMD processor or betterDirectX 9 compatible Sound CardVideo Card: GeForce 6800 or Radeon x850 (256 Megabyte VRAM or better and must support 1024x768 or higher resolution) in OpenGLSystem Memory 1 Gigabyte or more RAMHard Drive Space: 3.5 GB</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/6/63813/2282175-logo_cmfi_155.png</image></root>