<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3928</id><name>Tengai Makyou II: Manjimaru</name><description>Overview Tengai Makyou II: Manjimaru is the sequel to  Tengai Makyou: Ziria, and is a turn-based RPG originally developed by                         RED Company and was first released on the                        PC Engine CD in 1992. In 2003, the title was remade for the                       Gamecube and                      Playstation 2, and featured 3D models and environments, full motion video for cutscenes, and an enhanced soundtrack. In 2006, the                     Nintendo DS saw a port of the PC Engine original, which boasted optional stylus control, as well as the enhanced music from the remakes. The game saw one more release in 2008 on the                    PSP as part of a compilation package.  Censorship The original PC Engine game featured a bloody cutscene in which a                  character has her arm violently ripped off and face slashed. This scene was modified in the Gamecube, Playstation 2, DS and PSP releases to show less violence. A CG where a female               character's erect nipples had been slightly visible through her clothing was also altered in the ports and remakes.  SoundtrackThe soundtrack of the game was composed by Joe Hisaishi and Hirohiko Fukuda. The initial OST for the original title was released in Japan on  February 1st, 1992. A remastered OST, used in both the Gamecube and Playstation 2 remakes, was released in the same territory on October 22nd, 2003.  Track Listing Disc One01. Title02. Opening (Space)03. Manjimaru's Theme04. Taro's Theme05. Kabuki's Theme06. Kinu's Theme07. L Map (General)08. Walking Towards Ruin09. The Attack of the Root10. Steel Castle Theme11. Murderous Intention12. Boss Battle13. L Map (Those Who Possess the Saintly Sword)14. Machine Brute DEBEBE15. Demon Animal16. The Challenge Towards God17. EndingDisc Two01. A Peaceful Village02. Vigorous Castle Town03. Requiem to a Family Killed By Eden04. Tray's Theme and New Year's Day05. A Hermit's Theme06. Eden07. Intellectual Calm08. Miracle-working09. Sacred Space10. Fierce Battle11. Desperate Struggle12. There is no End to Battle13. Advance During the Calm14. Demon Lurking in the Darkness15. Wicked Heart Worship16. Into the Stomach of an Animal17. The Premonition of a Desperate Struggle18. Paradise of Evil19. Me, an Easy Going Missionary20. Gold, That's Life21. Narcissist's Theme22. Narcissist's Sword Dance23. Great Foolishness24. Highspeed Flight Vehicle25. Lightweight Ground Vehicle26. Midweight Ground Vehicle27. Heavyweight Ground Vehicle28. Submarine29. A Stupid Vehicle30. Saintly Sword is in My Hand31. Dark History32. Severe Women33. Shopping Center34. A Huge Ally Appears35. Exceed a Friends Death36. Separation With God37. Armaments38. Demon Lies Hidden in the Cave39. Kill the Nunchaku Rogue40. Manjimaru's Theme (Narration)41. EXTRA 142. EXTRA 243. Jingle Collection  </description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11753">Mother</game><game id="3775">Mother 1+2</game><game id="3864">Mother 3</game><game id="8307">EarthBound</game><game id="1164">Dragon Warrior I &amp; II</game><game id="24108">Dragon Warrior II</game><game id="16848">Dragon Warrior III</game><game id="22703">Dragon Quest IV: Chapters of the Chosen</game><game id="7197">Dragon Quest V: Hand of the Heavenly Bride</game><game id="19425">Dragon Quest VI: Realms of Revelation</game><game id="12620">Aurora Quest: Otaku no Seiza in Another World</game><game id="16246">Princess Minerva</game><game id="23987">Nostalgia</game><game id="34771">PoPoLoCrois: Tsuki no Okite no Bouken</game><game id="43947">Tengai Makyou Collection</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2365581-tg16_tengaimakyou2manjimaru_jp.jpg</image></root>