<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>39355</id><name>Primordia</name><description>OverviewPrimordia is a science fiction point-and-click adventure game that was developed by Wormwood Studios and published by Wadjet Eye Games. The sprite-based game was approved by consumers via Steam Greenlight and was released for PC through Steam and GOG on December 5, 2012.PresentationThe game is presented as a "throwback" to PC point-and-click games from the 1990s, and accordingly graphics have been referred to as "early 90s" including heavy use of pixels in the environment and characters, with no use of polygons. The game's appearance is akin to that of Revolution Software's Beneath A Steel Sky.Reception for Primordia's art style have been mixed among critics, with environments being referred to as "beautiful" as well as "sludgy".The game is fully voice-acted, with both characters commenting throughout the game.StoryIn a future world run by robots, protagonist Horatio Nullbuilt scours a post-apocalyptic wasteland searching for energy; discovering his own origin as a robot himself. Horatio's sidekick, a small, flying robot named Crispin, joins him in his adventure as they complete puzzles and other adventure-based tasks.The player is expected to unravel the story as the game is played, with no direct goal beyond accumulating energy in the beginning. Once the protagonists reach the city of Metropol the discover truths that cause them to ask many questions of life and the world around them.Characters commonly have conversations that aren't directly related to the plot or task at hand, but can be helpful in dropping indirect hints to the player as to how to proceed. The two protagonists both carry a sense of sarcasm throughout the game, giving them a human-like demeanor in a robot-ruled world.GameplayPrimordia's gameplay stays true to the point-and-click style, with little control used outside of the mouse. The keyboard is used periodically to enter numbers in-order to solve puzzles. Times of linearity in the game are rare, as hints are given as to how proceed; but rarely is the player forced to progress in any certain manner.As with other Wadjet Eye games, there is no character death/fail state. However certain different options through the narrative become available should the player successfully complete or fail to complete certain tasks or handle situations on their journey.Gameplay mechanics revolve around characters' banter and puzzle solving. The two typically go hand-in-hand, as conversations give instruction to complete tasks, or are tasks in themselves, and tasks lead to furthering conversations.PC System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows XP SP2 or aboveProcessor: Pentium or higher processorMemory: 64 MBHard disk space: 1.5 GbVideo Card: DirectX 5 or above compatibility</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10915">Beneath a Steel Sky</game><game id="33797">Gemini Rue</game><game id="23648">Machinarium</game><game id="2614">The Dig</game><game id="2235">Planescape: Torment</game><game id="10927">Loom</game><game id="3019">The Secret of Monkey Island</game><game id="10528">Monkey Island 2:  LeChuck's Revenge</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2378798-caja_primordia.jpg</image></root>