<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3939</id><name>Barbie: Vacation Adventure</name><description>OverviewBarbie decides to go on vacation around various states in the US. The game takes the form of Barbie recalling her adventures and recounting them, via letters, to the player (who will have been prompted to enter a name). PlotBarbie's trip around the US involves five different states (one of which is her home state). Before she goes anywhere, she will change outfits. The player has limited control over this.   As she travels, Barbie gains points depending on the success in her completion of minigames. Each level concludes with her explaining her exploits the player.  The places Barbie goes to visit are:  WyomingBarbie decides she wants to go camping in Wyoming. She sets up a tent through a puzzle minigame, and her other areas of interest include a bizarre hiking platforming sequence, and a photography trail.  IowaIn Iowa, Barbie attends the county carnival. She must seek a lost pig for a farmer, and play various carnival style minigames, such as knocking down cans, feeding balls to clowns and testing her strength.  FloridaBarbie's main interest in Florida is the beach, and more specifically playing volleyball against another girl. She can also go swimming for quite a lot of treasure, but an air limit is imposed on the player.  TexasAt a western ranch in Texas, Barbie can go show jumping in a race where she must clear fences. She can also play a game of horseshoes.  CaliforniaIn Barbie's home state, she returns home to find that she has been lavished with gifts from Ken. She has to find them from various places around the house and guess what they are correctly. It turns out that the small presents are just distracting Barbie and obscuring the even bigger present...</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/13636/599822-barbie_vacation_adventure_00005.jpg</image></root>