<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>39686</id><name>Super Hexagon</name><description>OverviewA scene depicting "Hyper Hexagon", the 'hyper' version of the first level.Super Hexagon is an arcade score attack game developed by distractionware. The game initially started out as a free Flash game that was simply titled Hexagon.The player must rotate a triangle around a central point (a hexagon) while avoiding line segments. The segments encroach relentlessly towards the center of the screen.The player's score is based on how long they can survive without running into the center-facing sides of the line segments. Unlike Hexagon, the player is allowed to collide with the sides of incoming segments.The music was composed by Niamh Houston, also known as Chipzel. Jenn Frank serves as the game's "slightly taunting" announcer.Difficulty LevelsThe game comes with 6 difficulty levels, with 3 unlocked from the start. The "Hyper" difficulties are unlocked by surviving for at least 60 seconds in the corresponding difficulty level. Thus, the "Hyper Hexagon" mode is identical to anything after 60 seconds of "Hexagon" mode.Hexagon - HardHexagoner - HarderHexagonest - HardestHyper Hexagon - HardesterHyper Hexagoner - HardestestHyper Hexagonest - HardestestestAfter 60 seconds of gameplay in Hyper Hexagonest, the game seamlessly transitions into another unnamed stage (referred to as The End in this article). Unlike the other levels, this stage is not accessible from the main menu. The player must finish 60 seconds of Hyper Hexagonest each time he or she wants to play The End.Each difficulty level is connected to others in some way. If the player survives long enough on one level, the game seamlessly transitions to another difficulty. The following list outlines the path each level takes.Hexagon - Hexagon, Hyper Hexagon, Hyper Hexagoner, Hyper Hexagonest, The EndHexagoner - Hexagoner, Hyper Hexagoner, Hyper Hexagonest, The EndHexagonest - Hexagonest, Hyper Hexagonest, The EndHyper Hexagon - Hyper Hexagon, Hyper Hexagoner, Hyper Hexagonest, The EndHyper Hexagoner - Hyper Hexagoner, Hyper Hexagonest, The EndHyper Hexagonest - Hyper Hexagonest, The EndSystem RequirementsPCOS: Windows XPProcessor: 2 GHzMemory: 256 MBHard Disk Space: 35 MBVideo Card: Direct X9.0c Compatible CardDirectX®: Direct X9.0cMacOS: OS X version 10.6 or laterProcessor: Intel Mac 2 GHzMemory: 256 MBHard Disk Space: 35 MBLinuxOS: Ubuntu 12.04 LTSProcessor: 2 GHzMemory: 256 MBHard Disk Space: 35 MB</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1034">Asteroids</game><game id="43076">Tektonik</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2418687-mzl.grebaimp.png</image></root>