<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>3970</id><name>Myst</name><description>OverviewMyst is a "point-and-click" adventure game created by brothers Rand and Robyn Miller. It was developed by their company, Cyan (later Cyan Worlds), and originally published by Broderbund. The game was one of the first games ever released on the CD format, and was partially responsible for the format's success, at least as far as games are concerned. Myst was the best-selling PC game of all time until Will Wright's "The Sims" broke the record in 2002. Myst has spawned four direct sequels, several spin-offs, three novels, a board game, and plans for a motion picture. There have been plans for a fourth novel for years, titled "Myst: The Book of Mirram," but it is now presumed to be canceled.GameplayA typical Myst Puzzle.The gameplay in Myst is first-person, where the player journeys through many pre-rendered scenes by clicking on locations on the screen. The player interacts with objects by clicking or dragging them. Animations are videos embedded into the pre-rendered scenes, to give more of a sense of immersion despite limited technology.Because the scenes were pre-rendered, the artists were able to portray the worlds of Myst in stunningly beautiful 3D, which wouldn't have been possible at the time had the game been rendered in real-time.The player is asked to solve many puzzles in order to progress through the game. There are no scenes of action or violence. There is no time limit and no threat of death. Instead, the world of Myst is calm and serene, drawing the player in with its atmospheric music and sounds as they uncover the secrets of the mysterious island at their on pace.The StoryMyst Island.The story of Myst begins when the player - known simply as the "Stranger" by fans and certain references to the player in the game world - discovers a mysterious book. When he opens it, and places his hand on the Linking panel on the last page, he finds himself transported to the mysterious island of Myst. There, he must explore the seemingly deserted island in search of clues to where he is, and how to get back home.The Stranger quickly stumbles upon two books - one red, one blue - that each have a person trapped inside of them. These are Sirrus and Achenar, who are brothers, and the sons of a man named Atrus. Each brother claims that the other killed Atrus, and cannot be trusted. The Stranger is thus presented with a dilemma of whom to trust. Which brother is telling the truth? This is made harder by the fact that the books that have imprisoned Sirrus and Achenar are missing most of their pages, so their images are coming through extremely fuzzy, and are very hard to understand. The Stranger is tasked with finding these missing pages in order to move the story forward.As the Stranger explores, he finds many more Linking books hidden throughout Myst island. Each book Links him to a different world - or " Age" - and he must solve the many puzzles of a particular Age before he can return to Myst island, hopefully with a red or blue page in hand.Along the way, the Stranger uncovers more clues as to what exactly happened on Myst, including messages and letters from Atrus himself to his wife Catherine, speaking of his destroyed library, and his suspicions that one of his sons is responsible.Endings*This section contains spoilers.*Myst has multiple endings. After the Stranger locates all but one of the red or blue pages, Sirrus and Achenar are able to tell him where the fifth pages are hidden. If either of them are given the fifth and final page of their book, they will be set free. However, each brother stresses the fact that the other cannot be trusted, and implores you bring only their own respective page, and not the other.Both, however, agree that you should not touch the green book that is next to the final red and blue pages. They warn you that it's another trap book, like the ones they themselves are imprisoned in.You are thus given three choices: Return the red page to Sirrus, return the blue page to Achenar, or open the green book, betraying the warnings of both of them.The Red Book (Sirrus)If you return the red page to Sirrus, you suddenly find yourself inside his book, looking out at the library. It's not hard to realize that this was a trick, and that you are now trapped. Sirrus makes a point to call you a fool, and starts ripping pages out of the book, ensuring that it is very unlikely that you will ever escape...The Blue Book (Achenar)If you return the blue page to Achenar, you suddenly find yourself inside his book, looking out at the library. It's not hard to realize that this was a trick, and that you are now trapped. Achenar laughs manically, as the somewhat unhinged individual you have seen him to be. He gleefully rips pages out of the blue book, ensuring that it is very unlikely that you will ever escape...The Green Book (Atrus)When you open green book, you are greeted by the site of a bearded man, huddled over a book in which he his writing. He asks "who the devil" you are, and is very quick to warn you not to touch the Linking panel of his book. Not yet. He has many questions for you, and his name is Atrus, father of Sirrus and Achenar. He tells you that he needs a white page from you, and that you should not come to D'ni - where he is trapped - without it.If you ignore his warning and enter the book without the white page, you end up trapped forever in D'ni with Atrus, unable to do anything except wander around the room forever.However, if you use clues you found elsewhere throughout the game in order to find the white page and bring it to Atrus, then he is able to complete the Myst book he has on his desk, and journey back to the island. He tells you that he has a difficult choice to make, but that his sons have betrayed him, so he knows what he must do. He leaves temporarily for Myst island, and when he returns, he tells you that while you surely have many questions, his writing cannot wait. His wife is being held captive in another Age, and he fears that he may need your services in the future to help him. This is the set up for the game's sequel, Riven.The only reward he can offer you is access to his library on Myst, and free exploration of the Ages. Thus, while the game is concluded, the game does not lead you to a credit sequence, and rather lets you wander around the worlds as you see fit.If you return to the library on Myst, you will notice that where the red and blue books once sat, there is now only a large burn mark in their places.Ports and RemakesThe game has been remade on the PC twice. Once remastered in 24-bit color with enhanced sound as Myst: Masterpiece Edition, and again as realMyst, which was a full recreation of the game in Cyan's real-time 3D engine called Plasma.Myst: Masterpiece Edition was released in May 2000. The Mac version was ported by Presto Studios.realMYST was released on November 15, 2000.Myst: Masterpiece Edition and realMYST are available to purchase digitally, DRM-free, courtesy of GOG.com since 2009.The game has also been ported to a variety of consoles and hand-helds, including the Sega Saturn, the Sony Playstation, the Atari Jaguar, the CD-i, the 3DO, the PlayStation Portable, and the Nintendo DS.The port of Myst for the iPhone was released for the Apple iPhone on the App Store for $5.99 on May 2nd, 2009. This copy features the full original game with improved graphics and contains the original sounds and soundtrack.The iPhone version also features auto-zoom, the original cinematics, swipe-to-turn, and all of the original ages and gameplay.A 3DS port has been announced for release on April 24, 2012 in North America. Called "Myst 3D," most of the gameplay will take place on the bottom, 2D screen, with some discovery gameplay in 3D on the top screen. This port is being handled by Maximum Family Games.SoundtrackMyst: The Soundtrack was composed by Robyn Miller and was released by Virgin Records on October 6, 1998.Myst IslandNo.Track TitleLength1."Myst Theme"1:302."Treegate"1:583."Planetarium"1:384."Shipgate"1:275."The Tower"1:436."The Last Message (Forechamber Theme)"2:34Mechanical AgeNo.Track TitleLength7."Fortress Ambience Part I"0:408."Fortress Ambience Part II"0:509."Mechanical Mystgate"2:0010."Sirrus' Cache"1:4211."Sirrus' Theme – Mechanical Age"1:3412."Achenar's Cache"1:4113."Achenar's Theme – Mechanical Age"2:11Stoneship AgeNo.Track TitleLength14."Compass Rose"1:2815."Above Stoneship (Telescope Theme)"1:3016."Sirrus' Theme – Stoneship Age"1:2517."Achenar's Theme – Stoneship Age"1:40Selentic AgeNo.Track TitleLength18."Selenitic Mystgate"1:42Channelwood AgeNo.Track TitleLength19."The Temple of Achenar"1:3520."Sirrus' Theme – Channelwood Age"1:3221."Achenar's Theme – Channelwood Age"2:07FinaleNo.Track TitleLength22."Un-Finale"1:5723."Finale"1:34Bonus TracksNo.Track TitleLength24."Fireplace Theme"0:4325."Early Selenitic Mystgate"1:1626."Original Un-Finale"1:27TOTAL LENGTH:41:24</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16298">The 7th Guest</game><game id="5576">Bad Mojo</game><game id="8759">The Longest Journey</game><game id="14097">The Neverhood</game><game id="5155">Nostradamus: The Last Prophecy</game><game id="16320">Aura: Fate of the Ages</game><game id="3234">AmerZone: The Explorer's Legacy</game><game id="19402">Beyond Time</game><game id="15711">AMBER: Journeys Beyond</game><game id="20133">Advanced Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Treasure of Tarmin Cartridge</game><game id="11471">Obsidian</game><game id="1724">The 11th Hour</game><game id="22665">The Lost Crown: A Ghost-Hunting Adventure</game><game id="20146">Shivers</game><game id="22871">Beyond Atlantis II</game><game id="15777">Timelapse</game><game id="10857">The Journeyman Project</game><game id="19758">The Journeyman Project: Turbo!</game><game id="175">The Journeyman Project: Pegasus Prime</game><game id="15324">The Journeyman Project 2: Buried in Time</game><game id="8330">The Journeyman Project 3: Legacy of Time</game><game id="10187">Zork Nemesis: The Forbidden Lands</game><game id="6515">Return to Mysterious Island</game><game id="2576">Cosmology of Kyoto</game><game id="23532">Nikopol: Secrets of the Immortals</game><game id="13230">Grim Fandango</game><game id="6728">Zak McKracken and the Alien Mindbenders</game><game id="22111">The Whispered World</game><game id="22148">Nightfall</game><game id="9980">Azrael's Tear</game><game id="3997">Lunacy</game><game id="24777">Return to Mysterious Island II</game><game id="24845">A Vampyre Story 2: A Bat's Tale</game><game id="11227">Jewels of the Oracle</game><game id="17990">Trace Memory</game><game id="21411">Theresia</game><game id="12912">NiBiRu: Age of Secrets</game><game id="17936">ECHO: Secrets of the Lost Cavern</game><game id="574">Sherlock Holmes: Nemesis</game><game id="10721">realMyst</game><game id="10375">Voyage</game><game id="5409">Black Dahlia</game><game id="3590">Millennium Auction</game><game id="18438">Dracula: The Resurrection</game><game id="17742">Mansion of Hidden Souls</game><game id="27668">The Witness</game><game id="20176">The Dark Eye</game><game id="9257">Mummy: Tomb of the Pharaoh</game><game id="510">The Crystal Key</game><game id="31615">Dark Fall: Lost Souls</game><game id="10546">Shivers 2: Harvest of Souls</game><game id="14648">Monty Python's Complete Waste of Time</game><game id="3880">Monty Python's The Meaning of Life</game><game id="17368">Morpheus</game><game id="32349">Cosmic Osmo and the Worlds Beyond the Mackerel</game><game id="12977">Qin: Tomb of the Middle Kingdom</game><game id="32841">Intrigue At Oakhaven Plantation</game><game id="8593">Safecracker: The Ultimate Puzzle Adventure</game><game id="20056">9: The Last Resort</game><game id="15951">The Mansion of Hidden Souls</game><game id="35482">Mystery Quest: Curse of the Ancient Spirits</game><game id="15225">DogDay</game><game id="36086">TRAUMA</game><game id="30687">Faust: The Seven Games of the Soul</game><game id="36399">Safecracker</game><game id="29476">Juggernaut</game><game id="17999">Prince Interactive</game><game id="24768">Fez</game><game id="38813">Coma: A Mind Adventure</game><game id="34165">Baron Wittard: Nemesis of Ragnarok</game><game id="11110">The Sacred Rings</game><game id="20362">Atlantis: The Lost Tales</game><game id="4803">Rama</game><game id="37862">Kairo</game><game id="40440">Miasmata</game><game id="41212">Xing</game><game id="22144">Spelunx and the Caves of Mr. Seudo</game><game id="8786">The Manhole</game><game id="18294">The Manhole: New and Enhanced</game><game id="41549">Fade Into Darkness</game><game id="2717">Frankenstein: Through the Eyes of the Monster</game><game id="17326">Star Trek: Borg</game><game id="43745">1953: KGB Unleashed</game><game id="44273">Obduction</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/97089/2267427-m.png</image></root>