<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>39764</id><name>Bayonetta 2</name><description>OverviewBayonetta 2 is the upcoming sequel to PlatinumGames' stylish action title Bayonetta. Production is being financed by Nintendo, and the game will be released as a Wii U exclusive. It is currently scheduled for release in 2014.Visually, Bayonetta's character design has changed, giving her a new outfit and shorter hairstyle. The producers stated that they rationalized this change in appearance as something Bayonetta would do; they see her as a woman that makes bold changes in her appearance, and hinted at the possibility that her appearance could change again in a potential future sequel down the road.StoryDetails of the story in Bayonetta 2 aren't known at this time, but one significant difference is that unlike the first game, in which Bayonetta fought primarily against angelic enemies, her adversaries in the sequel appear to be more demonic.It is also known that Jeanne is now Bayonetta's ally, and she will at times aid Bayonetta in battle. However, during a portion of the game's demo presented at shows such as E3 and PAX Prime 2013, there comes a point where a demon's powerful blow knocks Jeanne's soul out of her body, and she is captured by demons before she can return to it.GameplayUmbran ClimaxBayonetta 2 builds on the combat concepts of the original game with new features such as the Umbran Climax. This new move is tied to the magic gauge. When the gauge is filled, the Umbran Climax can be triggered by pressing the L button. While the Umbran Climax is in effect, Bayonetta's attacks will power up and she can also regain health by dealing damage.Touch ControlsBayonetta 2 offers two basic control methods. The game can be played with traditional button controls, or via the use of the Wii U's GamePad touch screen. The touch screen controls are geared toward lower difficulty levels.Cooperative MultiplayerIt has been confirmed that Bayonetta 2 will feature cooperative multiplayer of some nature.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="32687">Ninja Gaiden 3</game><game id="6681">Devil May Cry 4</game><game id="5888">God Hand</game><game id="39749">Ninja Gaiden 3: Razor's Edge</game><game id="35948">Lollipop Chainsaw</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/10354/2320941-untitledb.jpg</image></root>