<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>39822</id><name>Train Simulator 2013</name><description>OverviewA free engine update to the multi-award winning Railworks series, Train Simulator 2013 continues to realize the experience and challenges of operating virtual trains from hauling freight to commuting passengers on both fictional and recreated real world routes. Available through Steam it has career based achievements and newly integrated Workshop support offering easy access to user created scenarios. Also features the infamously long list of DLC ranging from cheaper trains and scenarios to more expensive routes. All previously owned DLC is compatible and will also carry forward to newer versions.Gameplay remains similar with a slightly refreshed driving UI and offers the player opportunity to drive route based scenarios and ranked career missions that range in complexity and time as well as an objective free quick drive mode where any train can be used on any route. You can choose from both 'simple' and 'realistic' driving controls allowing anyone to essentially pick up and play, now further encouraged by the addition of controller support.New FeaturesDrive with Xbox 360 controller, keyboard or mouse'Relay' multiplayer missions allowing two players to co-operate to complete objectivesQuick Drive menu system: drive what you like, where you likeScore your driving and join the global leader board with Career SystemInteractive maps and task listsEnhanced graphics and performanceGameplayEach route comes with several scenario or career missions that can focus on delivering passengers or hauling freight depending on the train and section of the line. Both types include a list of objectives such as a timetable and stops for passenger missions or managing loading and coupling of rolling stock for freight. Missions come with varying levels of difficulty and length, ranging from 15 minutes up to 2 hours. While simply completing objectives will pass scenario missions, career missions will score you based on adherence to rules, providing bonuses for prompt completion of objectives but penalizing for ignoring signals, exceeding the speed limit, wheel slippage and even ride comfort. A quick drive mode allows you to pick from any train and route you own and drive free from objectives.Trains come with fully modeled and dynamic cabin interiors, able to be driven with the mouse interacting with the levels, the keyboard or a controller. 'Simple' driving controls only use accelerating and braking on a single lever but the standard 'Realistic' controls generally include acceleration, direction and braking on separate levers for electric and diesel trains. Steam engines have similar controls with extra options for managing steam and coal able to be automated.Included Trains  RoutesLondon to BrightonThe London to Brighton route recreates the modern 50-mile third rail electrified route from London Victoria Station to Brighton Station, with all stations along the way including Clapham Junction and landmarks including Battersea Power Station, London Gatwick Airport, Brighton  Hove Albion stadium and Brighton Lovers Walk depot to Brighton and includes the Class 377 Electrostar.Isle of WightThe Isle of Wight route recreates the picturesque holiday island 8.5 mile Ryde Pier Head to Shanklin line running the Class 483; these ex-London Underground trains have been given a new lease of life on the Isle of Wight and are the oldest trains in mainline service anywhere in the UK. You can also drive the 1915 Kitchener Class 0-4-0ST "Invincible" on the 5 mile Smallbrook Junction to Wootton Isle of Wight Steam RailwaySherman HillSherman Hill is a 60 mile North American freight route between Cheyenne and Laramie, Wyoming well-known for the tough grades which resulted in the Union Pacific Railroad building new heavy freight locomotives to work the line. The first single track railroad was laid in 1868, passing over the summit at 8,247 feet, and the route was steadily upgraded with double tracks and stronger bridges in the following decades.Deluxe EditionA deluxe edition is also available for an addition charge which includes the brand new Munich to Augsburg route featuring the ICE3 High Speed locomotive. The deluxe edition also includes all of the routes from the standard version of the game as well. The Deluxe edition can be purchased for a discounted price for owners of the standard version of Train Simulator 2013.PC System RequirementsMinimum:OS: Windows XP / Vista / 7 / 8Processor: Processor: 2.8 GHz Core 2 Duo (3.2 GHz Core 2 Duo recommended), AMD Athlon MP (multiprocessor variant or comparable processors)Memory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: 512 MB with Pixel Shader 3.0 (AGP PCIe only)DirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 6 GB HD spaceSound: Direct X 9.0c compatibleOther Requirements: Broadband Internet connectionAdditional: Quicktime Player is required for playing the videosRecommended:Graphics: Laptop versions of these chipsets may work but are not supported. Updates to your video and sound card drivers may be requiredAdditional: QuickTime Player is required for playing the videos</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19087">Microsoft Train Simulator</game><game id="28121">Rail Simulator</game><game id="34721">Trainz Simulator 12</game><game id="44011">Train Simulator 2014</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2330869-2013.png</image></root>