<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>39950</id><name>Dragon Story: New Dawn</name><description>OverviewDragon Story: New Dawn is the second game in the Dragon Story Franchise. If you had the original Dragon Story then you can import your world into the new game.How To PlayIn Dragon Story: New Dawn, you need to hatch, feed, evolve and breed your dragons. The Dragons in return give you moneyWhen you first start the game, you need to purchase an egg. This egg needs to be hatched.HatchingTo hatch an egg, you need a nest, you can buy one for in-game currency in the beginning and any additional nests cost real money.Once the egg has hatched, you need to place your newly hatched dragon into a habitatHabitatsDragons need habitats to live on. They are purchasable in the store for in-game currency. There are different types of dragons and they each have a corresponding habitat. Mixed breed dragons can live in either habitat.FeedingTo make you dragons grow, you need to feed them. To feed them, you need to build a farm and grow food. Giving food to your dragons will increase their experience and make them level up. Once they reach level 3, 6 or 9, you need to evolve them to continue to make them grow. When your dragons level up, they start making more money.EvolutionDragons need to evolve when they reach level 3, 6 or 9 to continue to grow. To evolve a dragon, you need an evolution temple. Place your dragon in the evolution temple and wait till they evolveBreedingThe game also allows you to have mixed breed dragons. To breed dragons, you need a breeding den. Your new dragons can be placed on whichever type of habitat they are.Types of DragonsFire TypeFire type dragons are purchasable for in-game currency. Fire type dragons require Fire habitats live in.Forest TypeForest type dragons are purchasable for in-game currency. Forest type dragons require Forest habitats live in.Air TypeFire type dragons are purchasable for in-game currency. Air type dragons require Air habitats live in.Light TypeFire type dragons are purchasable for in-game currency. Light type dragons require Light habitats live in.Water TypeFire type dragons are purchasable for in-game currency. Water type dragons require Water habitats live in.Magic TypeMagic type dragons are not purchasable for in-game currency. Magic type dragons require Magic habitats live in. Even though they are not purchasable for in-game currency, you can still breed a fire and water type dragon to get one. They are not very common though.Diamond TypeDiamond type dragons are not purchasable for in-game currency. Diamond type dragons require Diamond habitats live in.List Of DragonsFireFire - FireLife - Fire, ForestTusker - Fire, LightWild - Fire, ForestForestfire - Fire, ForestLandworm - Fire, ForestFirestorm - Fire, AirEagle - Fire, AirScorpion - Fire, AirHoneybee - Fire, AirAthletic - Fire, WaterCharm - Fire, MagicTitan - Fire, MagicPlanet - Fire, MagicCrusader - Fire, DiamondLove - Fire, LightLaserlight - Fire, LightForestForest - ForestLife - Fire, ForestWild - Fire, ForestForestfire - Fire, ForestLandworm - Fire, ForestFruitful - Forest, AirFairy - Forest, AirParakeet - Forest, AirIsland - Forest, WaterSerpent - Forest, WaterAtlantis - Forest, WaterMermaid - Forest, WaterPoison - Forest, MagicFamiliar - Forest, MagicQuetzal - Forest, DiamondFuzzy - Forest, LightPegasus - Forest, LightAirAir - AirFirestorm - Fire, AirEagle - Fire, AirScorpion - Fire, AirHoneybee - Fire, AirFruitful - Forest, AirFairy - Forest, AirParakeet - Forest, AirMist - Air, WaterMindvolt - Air, WaterClown - Air, WaterSeabreeze - Air, WaterGenie - Air, MagicTrickster - Air, MagicGold - Air, DiamondSunrise - Air, LightGriffin - Air, LightWaterWater - WaterAthletic - Fire, WaterIsland - Forest, WaterSerpent - Forest, WaterAtlantis - Forest, WaterMermaid - Forest, WaterMist - Air, WaterMindvolt - Air, WaterClown - Air, WaterSeabreeze - Air, WaterCoral - Water, MagicWizard - Water, MagicMistmoth - Water, MagicAether - Water, MagicWinter - Water, LightIce Cream - Water, LightDream - Light, WaterMercury - Diamond, WaterMagicMagic - MagicCharm - Fire, MagicTitan - Fire, MagicPlanet - Fire, MagicPoison - Forest, MagicFamiliar - Forest, MagicGenie - Air, MagicTrickster - Air, MagicCoral - Water, MagicWizard - Water, MagicMistmoth - Water, MagicAether - Water, MagicLuck - Light, MagicHypnotic - Light, MagicLightLight - LightFuzzy - Forest, LightPegasus - Forest, LightFuzzy - Forest, LightPegasus - Forest, LightSunrise - Air, LightGriffin - Air, LightWinter - Water, LightIce Cream - Water, LightDream - Light, WaterLuck - Light, MagicHypnotic - Light, MagicAngel - Light, DiamondTusker - Fire, LightDiamondDiamond - DiamondCrusader - Fire, DiamondQuetzal - Forest, DiamondGold - Air, DiamondMercury - Diamond, WaterAngel - Light, DiamondInfinity - DiamondBuildingsNestUsed to Hatch EggsFarmUsed to grow dragon food. Can be upgraded to Large Farm then Enchanted Farm. Larger farms can produce for food at a timeBreeding DenUsed to breed dragons. When empty, select 2 Dragons and click breedEvolution TempleUsed to evolve dragons.</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/98169/2340268-dragon_story_new_dawn_screen.png</image></root>