<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>40052</id><name>Cosmo Police Galivan</name><description>OverviewUchuu Keiji Gyaban is a well-regarded tokusatsu (superhero) Japanese TV show known in the West as Space Sheriff Gavan, Space Cop Gabin and - in this case of this licensed game - Cosmo Police Galivan.Nihon Bussan created an Arcade game based on the TV show in 1985 and then followed it up with a slightly different take on the license for the Nintendo Famicom. It would later be followed with a SNES sequel, Cosmo Police Galivan II: Arrow of Justice. Neither game would be released outside of Japan.GameplayCosmo Police Galivan puts the player in control of a human being armed with a beam blade, which is only able to attack monsters in close proximity. As the game continues, the player character can use different powers - some ranged - to take out enemies and progress further. Eventually, the player will have the option of becoming a metal-armored officer with considerably more fire-power, though this power-up state will vanish if too much damage is taken. The player character will also level-up after destroying so many enemies, improving their health and "cosmo points" - a stat similar to mana that is used to power the player character's special attacks.The game's world is a network of caves that the player can explore for necessary items and bonus areas. The NES version expands this aspect, providing some Metroidvania-esque exploration. Some impediments are in place to restrict further exploration until the right item is found, as well.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21761">Metroid</game><game id="8152">Zillion</game><game id="19742">Zillion II: Tri Formation</game><game id="16241">Zelda II: The Adventure of Link</game><game id="15154">Kid Icarus</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/23093/2344146-cosmo_police_galivan.jpg</image></root>