<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>40197</id><name>Euro Truck Simulator 2</name><description>OverviewEuro Truck Simulator 2 (ETS2) is SCS Software's follow-up to their long running truck simulation series and a direct sequel to Euro Truck Simulator. ETS2 adds significant improvements to the series by making the game more approachable to new players, by increasing the size of the world, and by increasing the depth of the logistics management side of the game. The game also includes upgraded visuals and new forms of player progression.Euro Truck Simulator 2 is available for purchase on PC from http://www.eurotrucksimulator2.com/ and Steam.GameplayETS2 divides the player's attention between driving trucks throughout Europe to deliver goods and managing the logistics of the player's company.Driving GameplayETS2 is a truck driving simulation at it's core. On the outset, the player is tasked with choosing a load to haul. The player then sets off with a destination and expected time of delivery. Driving fatigue, fuel, cargo damage, truck damage, truck maintenance, and the rules-of-the-road must all be considered as the player makes their way to the drop off point.The trucks are meticulously simulated. Player's may dive as deep as they want into the simulation aspect of the game. Wipers, lights, high beam lights, a clutch and H-shift, transmission ranges, engine braking, engine retardation, blinkers, and trailer attachment are some of the things the player has full control over. New players, however, have many options to simplify the driving experience.Once the player reaches their destination, they have the option to park the trailer, which may be quite difficult in some situations. With the trailer successfully delivered, the player is rewarded (minus damage) with currency and experience points.Logistics ManagementMedium sized player garage.Coupled with the driving mechanic of the game is the player's business enterprise. The player chooses a starting location for their headquarters as they create their character. The player is given a tiny, run-down garage to begin their business venture. When starting fresh the player does not have access to a truck and must haul loads using a contracted truck, which lowers the amount of compensation for the haul but allows the player to quick-travel between cities to haul freight.As the player delivers loads and collects currency, the player may then purchase their own truck. This allows the player to make much more money per haul, but also adds more risk and increases the player's travel expenses. Owned trucks must undergo maintenance, be fueled by player currency, and must physically be in the pick-up city to haul a load.Further progression sees the player hire drivers, buy fleets of trucks, and expand their enterprise to multiple garages across Europe.Player ProgressionProgression is handled through a mutual interaction with the business and driving portion of the game. Successfully delivering freight gives the player experience points and currency. The currency can be used to purchase trucks, upgrades, drivers, and garages. Experience points are used to level up. The player gets one skill point per level up that they can put into skills that open up new types of contract options, increase player compensation, or increase fuel economy.Trucks and UpgradesThe player begins the game without a truck, but can take out a loan from the bank after a few deliveries to purchase their first truck. When creating a profile, the player chooses their preferred manufacturer. The main showroom for the player's preferred manufacturer is shown on the world map, and the player may instantly visit the showroom to purchase their first truck. As the player travels the world, they will discover more dealers representing different truck manufacturers.The player must visit the showroom to purchase their first five trucks after which they may purchase trucks "online" through a menu instead of having to visit the dealer.TrucksThere are seven European truck manufacturers represented in the game, with a total of eight different truck models (Renault has both a Premium and Magnum series truck available.) Each manufacturer has a unique look and feel:DAF MAN Volvo  Iveco Scania Majestic (Mercedes) Renault Premium Renault Magnum ReceptionSteam GreenlightEuro Truck Simulator 2 was Greenlit on Steam, and appeared on sale on January 16, 2013. A trial version is also available.Critical ResponseETS2 has been widely praised by numerous media outlets and by consumers. SCS Software was able to balance the simulation aspects with a larger business enterprise system to create a feeling of constant progression that was lacking in the previous trucking games in the series.Metacritic shows a rating aggregate of 80/100 for ETS2 whereas ETS1 is not listed.Additional ContentDLCDeveloper SCS Software has announced that there is at least one DLC that will be released in the future, the first one being an Eastern Europe add-on with focus on Polish cities. SCS Software have said they are looking at the possibility of releasing more DLC:s, hinting at a Scandinavic or Spanish add-on.PC System RequirementsMinimumRecommendedWindows XP/Vista/7, Dual core CPU 2.4 GHz2 GB RAM, graphics card with 256 MB memoryVideo card: GeForce 7600 GT-class equivalent or betterWindows 7, Dual core CPU 3.0 GHz4 GB RAM, graphics card with 1024 MB memoryVideo card: GeForce GTS 450-class equivalent or better</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="41127">Scania Truck Driving Simulator: The Game</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2417287-jaquette_euro_truck_simulator_2_pc_cover_avant_g_1351086645.jpg</image></root>