<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>40257</id><name>The Guided Fate Paradox</name><description>OverviewThe Guided Fate Paradox is a PS3 title created by Nippon Ichi Software that shares much of the gameplay mechanics of Zettai Hero Project, a roguelike-esque dungeon crawler previously developed by NIS in 2010 for the PSP. New mechanics include the ability to enter dungeons with a party member (allowing you to create combos and throw allies across the map much like in the Disgaea games), large bosses that take up most of the current level, three dimensional or cube-like geometry for levels, and "God Mode", a state that gives your character access to almighty power for a limited time.The game was released in Japan in January 2013, and in North America in November 2013.PlotWar has broken out between heaven and hell and, after the massacre of many angels, a new god must be chosen. On Earth, a high school student by the name of Renya Kagurazaka is walking through a mall and decides to play a lottery set up near by. He ends up winning but, unbeknownst to him, the lottery has been set up by angels and, by winning, he is chosen to become that new god. Renya is transported to heaven and there he is trained to become the almighty ruler by several angels, all inexplicably wearing maid and butler outfits, by making wishes come true for people (usually fairytale figures like Cinderella). Wishes are granted by manipulating the wisher's fate in dimensions that are copies of our own (known as the Copy World) to allow the wish to come true.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="30167">Zettai Hero Project: Unlosing Ranger vs. Darkdeath Evilman</game><game id="18540">Disgaea: Hour of Darkness</game><game id="22309">Rogue</game><game id="20541">Mystery Dungeon: Shiren the Wanderer</game><game id="39762">Pokémon Mystery Dungeon: Gates to Infinity</game><game id="5276">World of Dragon Warrior: Torneko: The Last Hope</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2536379-box_tgfp.png</image></root>