<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>40251</id><name>Fairy Bloom Freesia</name><description>StoryIn the Great Forest of Lita , lives the innocent young fairy Freesia. Freesia protects the trees and creatures of the forest from golems and humans who wish them harm. She does this with the martial art of fairy-fu which she has trained tirelessly in all her life. However the golems and humans are becomeing even more relentless with there attacks on the forest and the fight seems a hopeless one. So in order to ensure the forest survival Freesia must convince the humans to live in harmony with the forest and its creatures.CharactersFreesiaThe fairy guardian of Lita Forest and master of the art of Fairy-fu. She is also close friends with the ancient Jomon Tree.ListineA gentleman aristocrat, and master swordsman from Dharka Kingdom. He entered the Forest of Lita in search of the spirit stone which is inside the ancient Jomon Tree.ShynieA young woman from the Kingdom of Dharka, who loyally follows Listine on his quest to find the spirit stone.PlumA mysterious young girl who wields a massive sword. She is later revealed to be a fairy guardian, taken in and put through excessive experiments.VaskarHead of the Kingdom of Dharka and father of Listine, he seeks the spirits stone of Lita Forest to harness its power.System RequirementsMinimum:OS:Windows XPProcessor:Pentium4 3.0GHz or betterMemory:512 MB RAMGraphics:VGA compatible with DirectX9 or later and Shader Model 2.0 or laterDirectX®:9.0Hard Drive:250 MB HD spaceSound:DirectX9(XAudio2) compatibleRecommended:OS:Windows Vista / 7Processor:Pentium4 3.0GHz or betterMemory:1 GB RAMGraphics:VGA compatible with DirectX9 or later and Shader Model 2.0 or laterDirectX®:9.0Hard Drive:250 MB HD spaceSound:DirectX9(XAudio2) compatible</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="39770">Elsword</game><game id="28142">Chantelise</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/97089/2530475-untitled.png</image></root>