<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>40331</id><name>Eggerland: Souzouhe no Tabidachi</name><description>OverviewEggerland: Souzouhe no Tabidachi ("Eggerland: Journey to Creation") is the third Eggerland game made for a Nintendo system and the fifth game overall. Unlike the two previous Famicom games, it is of the "tower" format, where stages follow consecutively one after the other, rather than the "labyrinth" format where Lolo has some non-linear freedom as to where to go next. The tower format would also be the one adopted for the next three games - the Adventures of Lolo series.Souzouhe no Tabidachi was created as part of Nintendo's "Disk Writer" service, wherein a Nintendo Famicom Disk System owner could take a disk to a special kiosk found in video game stores and have one of a selection of games written onto it; the idea being that the player could beat the game and then have their disk rewritten with a new game for a nominal fee. Souzouhe no Tabidachi is one of the few games that could only be procured from one of these Disk Writer machines, making it a rare find for collectors.As with the other Eggerland games, the goal is to help Prince Lolo collect every heart-shaped icon on the screen and return to a key that appears once all the hearts are collected. However, many of the enemies will only become aggressive once the last heart icon is collected and the key appears, which means some strategy is required regarding which heart icons to collect in what order as well as planning a safe route to the key. Lolo has a few tools at his disposal, such as turning enemies into eggs and using the harmless Snakey creatures as shields.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17545">Sokoban</game><game id="7624">Pac-Man</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/23093/2357429-eggerland___souzouhe_no_tabidachi__19xx__hal_laboratory__0.png</image></root>