<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>40440</id><name>Miasmata</name><description>OverviewRobert Hughes, a scientist slowly dying of a plague, wakes up exiled onto a mysterious island that is used for herbalist research. Throughout this island he finds a variety of research outposts from which he finds clues towards the cure he is seeking. Armed with only a compass, wristwatch and notebook, he must find, research and synthesize botanical specimen for the sake of personal survival and navigate the lost island for the overall cure.The game was released via Steam and GOG on November 28, 2012.GameplayMovement MomentumThe game uses a simulation of momentum and balance against the characters attributes. The player will find themselves having to resist against momentum as they run uncontrollably down a steep hill or losing their momentum and sliding down some hills if they're low on strength.ResearchResearching a botanical specimen that the player plucks from within the game world can give the player clues as to what plants and fungi can be combined to make a medicine/drug. The player will also discover notes that will reveal recipes.Item CombinationsThe player can create items at specific locations by combining two botanical specimens together that will create a drug which will help the player resist and survive the fever that the character suffers from and also items that can permanently or temporarily increase the character's attributes: Strength, Endurance, Perspective.Utility itemsThe player can pick up items off the ground such as rocks, twigs, and other items that can be swung by pressing the mouse button or thrown by holding the mouse button. Some items, like wood, can be used to start fires to provide light when it gets dark.InventoryThe player can carry, on their person, one utility item in their right hand and up to three botanical items in their left hand. Within the research outposts there are storage tables where the player can store botanical items. When stored on these tables, that item is available from any other storage table in the game.Day/Night CycleThe game features a day/night cycle that can be monitored by checking the in-game wrist watch. Nightfall makes exploring even more difficult as you can't see in great distances. To skip time the player can sleep in the beds that are provided within the research outposts.Save PointsWithin the game, the player has the ability to save the game by sleeping in a bed, which will skip game time forward, or by lighting fires in designated locations such as camp fires, urns, and lanterns.The Creature"The Creature" stalks the player within the open environment between the research outposts. An audio cue of a heartbeat will sound and increase in rate as the creature gets nearer.TriangulationTriangulating Current PositionTo determine the current location on a map, find two established landmarks within view (indicated by a white triangle). With the map selected, select the two land marks and lines will be drawn on the map relative to the locations of the two landmarks. The current location is where those two lines intersect.Triangulating Unknown LandmarksStep 1: To determine the position of unknown land marks, first determine the current position (using the above guide) then mark the unknown landmark within that view (indicated by a white triangle with a plus sign). This will draw a reference mark towards the unknown location.Step 2: To establish that landmark as a "known landmark", travel away from the location in "step 1" getting a different angle on the landmark to be charted. When at a new angle, determine the current position using two established landmarks and then select the same unknown landmark you referenced earlier to establish that landmark. Where the lines of the reference mark and the new angle mark intersect will be the location of that landmark.System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows XP, Vista, 7Processor: Intel Core2 Duo, AMD Athlon64 x2, or betterMemory: 2 GB RAMGraphics: NVIDIA Geforce 8600GT, ATI Radeon HD 3670 or equivalentDirectX: 9.0Hard Drive: 3 GB HD spaceSound: DirectX compatible sound cardRecommendedOS: Windows XP, Vista, 7Processor: Intel Core i5/i7, AMD equivalent or betterMemory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: NVIDIA GeForce GTX 280, ATI Radeon HD 4870 or betterDirectX: 11Hard Drive: 3 GB HD spaceSound: DirectX compatible sound card</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="33629">Dear Esther</game><game id="20665">Far Cry 2</game><game id="3970">Myst</game><game id="39256">DayZ</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/97089/2378838-m.png</image></root>