<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4046</id><name>Atomic Runner</name><description>Atomic RunnerStoryChelnov was a young scientist. He lived and worked side-by-side with his father and his sister, and together they led a happy peaceful life. But the harmony of their lives was about to be ripped open...Late one evening Chelnov went out for a nighttime jog when all of a sudden he hears a huge explosion come from his house.With his heart pounding Chelnov rushed back to his house only to find his father lying on the floor, barely conscious."Chelnov, my son, I... I..." said the old man in a faint voice. And with his last breath, Chelnov's father explained the whole tragic story."This explosion... this is the work of the "Deathtarians"! They claim to be the original inhabitants of earth, coming from a time before the dawn of man, and now they say they have returned to reclaim what is rightfully theirs!""I've known of their existence, and their evil plans for many years. That is why I have pushed you so hard in our work, our research."Chelnov's father pointed his shaky hand towards a metal case. Chelnov listened in disbelief."In this case is a suit that will increase the strength of a normal human to super-human levels. Implanted inside the suit are various weapons and devices...""Chelnov, you must put on this suit... you must try to destroy the Deathtarians. For the sake of the world, and for the sake of your sister... You see, they have taken her away with them.""Chelmi has been kidnapped?" Asked the stunned Chelnov. "Yes. I'm counting on you, my son..." And with a final breath Chelnov's father slipped away.Shaken and confused, Chelnov opened the metal case. Inside he found a magnificent suit, just as his father had explained. Determined to avenge his father's death and his sister's abduction, Chelnov donned the suit to become the Atomic Runner.Go Atomic Runner!! Save the world from the sinister plans of a twisted band of outlaw aliens! But the sheer numbers of the Deathtarians overwhelmed the Atomic Runner, and he was soon trapped by them.He was subjected to inhuman tortures, and attempts at brainwashing. Just as the Deathtarians were about to break his will, the Atomic Runner lashed out in anger and broke free from his captors.Run on! Atomic Runner!!I will not fail!.No Enemy can put a stop to Justice!Atomic Runner, bursting through a wall of awesome!About The GameAtomic Runner is a side scrolling platformer, in which the screen is constantly moving towards the right. You have minimal control of the character, as the default action is "Run". You're able to stop, jump, run faster, shoot to the left and right (and diagonally up).There are plenty of enemies, and many ways to die. One hit will kill you, and remove one of three lives you start with. Enemies drop powerups, and extra lives, so make sure to grab them when they drop, as you can't go back for them after you've gone past. Also, make sure to shoot at "torches" and other other such inanimate objects, as on occasion you'll receive a powerup as a reward.Developed by Data East, and released for the Sega Genesis in 1992 in the US, Atomic Runner is a fantastic game that never gets old.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4350">Contra</game><game id="7227">Abuse</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/23093/2351554-atomic_runner_us_gen.jpg</image></root>