<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>40510</id><name>Tiger Woods PGA Tour 14</name><description>OverviewTiger Woods PGA Tour 14 is the sixteenth entry in the franchise. It is set for release in March 26, 2013 in North America and March 28 worldwide. Tiger 14 features 20 championship courses, 35 pro golfers, all 4 major championship events, a new LPGA career mode, a new Legends of the Majors challenge mode, and more.CoursesTiger Woods PGA Tour 14 features twenty championship courses. The Masters Historic Edition of game includes an additional five courses. Others are available via DLC.Course NameLocationAvailabilityNew?Atlanta Athletic ClubJohns Creek, GA, USAStandardNoAugusta National Golf ClubAugusta, GA, USAStandardNoAugusta National Golf Club (1934)Augusta, GA, USAHistoric EditionYesAugusta National Golf Club - Par 3 CourseAugusta, GA, USAHistoric EditionNoBanff Springs Golf ClubBanff, AB, CanadaDLCNoBethpage State Park - Black CourseLong Island, NY, USADLC (Pre-Order)NoBlackwolf RunKohler, WI, USADLCNoCeltic ManorNewport, South WalesDLCNoColonial Country ClubFort Worth, TX, USADLCYesCosta NavarinoMessenia, Pelponnese, GreeceDLCNoCrooked Stick Golf ClubCarmel, IN, USAStandardNoEast Lake Golf ClubAtlanta, GA, USAStandardNoEls ClubDubai, UAEDLCNoEmerald DragonFantasyDLCNoGreek IslesFantasyDLCNoHighlandsFantasyDLCNoKiawah Island Golf ResortKiawah Island, SC, USAStandardNoMission Hills Country ClubShenzhen, ChinaStandardYesMuirfield VillageDublin, OH, USAStandardYesOak Hill Country ClubPittsford, NY, USAStandardYesOakmont Country ClubOakmont, PA, USAStandardNoPebble Beach Golf LinksPebble Beach, CA, USAStandardNoPGA National Golf ClubPalm Beach Gardens, FL, USAStandardNoPinehurst No. 2 (Old Version)Pinehurst, NC, USADLC (Pre-Order)YesPinehurst No. 2Pinehurst, NC, USAStandardNoPredatorFantasyDLCNoRoyal Birkdale Golf ClubSouthport, Mereyside, EnglandStandardNoRoyal Country Down Golf ClubNewcastle, County Down, Northern IrelandHistoric EditionNoRoyal Melbourne Golf ClubBlack Rock, Victoria, AustraliaHistoric EditionNoRoyal Troon Golf ClubTroon, South Ayrshire, ScotlandStandardYesSheshan Golf ClubShanghai, ChinaHistoric EditionNoSpyglass Hill Golf CoursePebble Beach, CA, USAStandardNoSt. AndrewsSt. Andrews, Fife, ScotlandStandardNoTorrey Pines Golf ClubLa Jolla, CA, USAStandardNoTPC Blue Monster at DoralDoral, FL, USAHistoric EditionNoTPC BostonNorton, MA, USADLCNoTPC LouisianaAvondale, LA, USAStandardYesTPC River HighlandsCromwell, CT, USADLCNoTPC San AntonioBexar County, TX, USADLCNoTPC SawgrassPonte Vedra Beach, FL, USAStandardNoTPC ScottsdaleScottsdale, AZ, USADLCNoValhalla Golf ClubLouisville, KY, USAStandardNoWhistling StraitsHaven, WI, USADLC (Pre-Order)NoWolf Creek Golf ResortMesquite, NV, USADLCNo GolfersTiger Woods PGA Tour 14 features thirty-five current and legendary professional golfers from the PGA and LPGA.PGAFor the first time ever, the career mode now features all four officially licensed major championships.Keegan BradleyRickie FowlerDustin JohnsonBubba WatsonTiger WoodsLPGAFor the first time ever, the game features an LPGA career mode including the Kraft Nabisco Championship.Paula CreamerNatalie GulbisStacy LewisLexi ThompsonLegendsThe LegendsLegends of the Majors mode allows players to travel through time challenging the best of the best in some of golf's most historic moments.Seve BallesterosBen HoganBobby JonesJack NicklausArnold PalmerGary PlayerSam SneadLee TrevinoEA Sports Masters: Historic EditionHistoric EditionThe special edition of Tiger Woods PGA Tour 13 is officially known as EA Sports Masters: Historic Edition. It includes five additional courses not included with the regular version of the game including the 1934 version of Augusta National.The cover features Bobby Jones and Bubba Watson.Pre-Order BonusesAmazon - DLC code for Bethpage Black.Best Buy - DLC code for 1986 Jack Nicklaus.GameStop - DLC code for Pinehurst No. 2.Origin - A set of "historic" golf clubs.Target - DLC code for Minnesota Timberwolves' Kevin Love and tennis pro Andy Roddick.Walmart - DLC code for Whistling Straits.AnnouncementOn November 12, 2012, Electronic Arts officially announced Tiger Woods PGA Tour 14 by starting a promotion on Facebook that would gradually reveal the game's cover athletes. On November 15, it was revealed that "The King" Arnold Palmer would join Tiger Woods on the cover of the game.</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="28">Golf</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2472256-box_twpgat14.png</image></root>