<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>40524</id><name>Who Wants To Be A Millionaire</name><description>OverviewWho Wants To Be A Millionaire is a trivia game based on the TV show of the same name. The game was published by Ludia Inc. for the PlayStation Network platform.GameplayWho Wants To Be A Millionaire is a trivia game in which the player must answer questions. The questions have a dollar amount designated to them. Every fifth question is a safety plateau where if answered correctly then the player can not earn less than the dollar amount on that plateau. There are fifteen questions total with the last question being worth one million dollars.LifelinesDuring a game the player also has the option to use three different lifelines. These lifelines are designed to help the player on an answer that may be too tough to answer normally. Each lifeline can only be used once per game. The lifelines available are:Double Dip - The double dip lifeline allows the player to choose two answers, and as long as one of those is the correct answer then the player will pass the question and move on.Phone a Friend - In this version of the game the phone a friend lifeline will choose from a random bank of fake people that will try and help the player guess the correct answer.Ask the Audience - The ask the audience lifeline will poll the "audience" and show the player the percentages of each answer chosen by the crowd.MultiplayerWho Wants To Be A Millionaire contains a multiplayer mode which can be played locally or over the PlayStation Network. The game can be played with two to four players. Who Wants To Be A Millionaire also supports voice chat online.The multiplayer mode works slightly different than the normal single player mode. In the multiplayer mode there is always fifteen questions that will be gone through, whether or not they were answered correctly. If a player answers correctly they will be moved up a level, if it is answered incorrect they will either be moved down or stay on the current tier depending on the question difficulty.</description><genres><genre id="14">Trivia/Board Game</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/10/103881/2370780-wwtbam.png</image></root>