<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>40549</id><name>Anomaly Korea</name><description>OverviewTitle ScreenAnomaly Korea is a strategy game where you command troops to navigate through a maze of enemies. It was developed for iOS and Android by 11 Bit Studios and is a sequel to the 2011 PC game Anomaly: Warzone Earth.It was released simultaneously for both platforms on the 25th of December, 2012. There are currently no plans to develop the game for PC, though a "true sequel" is planned on PC, titled Anomaly 2.Anomaly Korea was part of the March 2013 Humble Indie Mobile Bundle, an Android-exclusive Humble Bundle. GameplayAnomaly Korea is a strong believer in color separation.Like its predecessor, Anomaly Korea's premise is centered around playing a tower defense game in reverse. Enemy "turrets" are placed across each level and the player is given a series of paths to plot a course through and reach the end objective alive. Different enemy types, allied units, and support abilities add an additional layer of strategy, with some levels requiring strict objectives or requirements to be met as well.NavigationThe tactical map.Unlikes regular tower defense games, where the player must set down defense along a pre-set path, Anomaly Korea focuses on plotting a course throughout a series of enemy-filled paths to reach the objective.To set a course, the player opens the "Tactical Map", which is a digital overhead of the entire level, and must pick a direction in a number of intersections placed across each level.A number of alternate paths are given to the player for strategic purposes, usually to avoid enemies or collect supply items. CombatPew!Anomaly Korea's combat focuses on strengths and weaknesses of units at your disposal versus the different enemy types. Unless the level gives you a specific requirement, the player will start with a set amount of money and must buy and upgrade units. Formation is key, as certain units will fare stronger at the back of the line formation than others.Defeating enemies will earn the player cash, which they can use to purchase more units to be air-dropped or upgrade the ones currently in play. Additionally, there is a collectible resource called Carusaurum that is placed in certain levels that can be collected for additional cash, though its optional nature will usually result in fighting extra enemies to acquire. AbilitiesProgression through the game's campaign will unlock abilities that can be used in combat to assist your units in and out of combat.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/12139/2395117-anomalykoreacover.png</image></root>