<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>40568</id><name>Gun Buster</name><description>OverviewTaito's Gun Buster, also known as Gunbuster, was an innovative first-person shooter (FPS) released in 1992 for the arcades, and is considered ahead of its time.GameplayIt featured on-foot gameplay and a unique control scheme that was a precursor to most modern FPS control schemes. The player character moves and strafes using an eight-direction joystick, while taking aim (and rotating left and right) using a mounted positional gun (a hybrid between a light gun and analog joystick). The controls work in a similar manner to most FPS control schemes, including WASD movement  mouse aiming on the PC, the twin-stick controls on consoles, and particularly the analog stick movement  motion control aiming on the Wii.Gun Buster was also unique in allowing two-player co-op for the mission mode, and also featured deathmatch and team deathmatch modes for up to four players, via linked arcade machines, predating the networked deathmatch modes of Doom. Gun Buster also introduced maneuvers such as strafing and circle-strafing several years before they would become popular in the FPS genre.Arcade hardware specificationsThe technical specifications of the game's custom 32-bit arcade hardware:Main CPU: Motorola 68EC020 (based on 32-bit Motorola 68020) @ 16 MHzSound CPU: Motorola 68000 (16-bit) @ 16 MHzStereo PCM sound chips: Ensoniq ES5510 DSP sound chipEnsoniq ES5505 (32-channel) @ 15.24 MHzOSC: 40 MHz, 16 MHz, 30.48 MHzCustom GPU graphics chips: Taito TC0480SCP tilemap chipTaito TC0570SPC object chipTaito TC0260DAR pallette controllerOther custom chips: Taito TC0510NIO input/output chip, Taito TC0470LINEnhanced sprite-scaling system based on Taito Z arcade board </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="31">Dual-Joystick Shooter</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre><genre id="35">Light-Gun Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7326">Doom</game><game id="40567">Last Survivor</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/13/139866/2428278-gunbuster___1992___taito__1_.jpg</image></root>