<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>40672</id><name>Stealth Bastard Deluxe</name><description>OverviewStealth Bastard: Tactical Espionage Arsehole Deluxe is an updated PC  PSN version of the original freeware version. It is a 2D stealth puzzle platformer that tasks the player with traversing a deadly environment of traps, lasers, and robots to activate switches and reach the exit door. Players must stick to the shadows and avoid the vision cones of enemies in order to make it out alive.There are three levels of visibility in the game, which are represented by the color of the character's goggles. Green goggles means the player is hidden  enemies will not attack. Orange goggles means the player is partially visible  enemies will come investigate their position. Red goggles means the player is fully visible and enemies will attack immediately.The game contains 80 new levels, new unlockable equipment, new music  graphics, and new enemies. The 80 levels are broken up into 8 chapters of 10 levels each. Upon completion of a level, the player is given a letter grade based on their speed, amount of times spotted by enemies, and deaths. Each level also contains a hidden "Helix" collectible.The first 7 levels of each chapter are standard levels, with the 8th level being a boss stage. The 9th level is only made available if the player S-Ranks the previous 8 levels. The 10th level is made available if the player collects all the Helices in levels 1 through 8 of a chapter.PlayStation VersionThe game was released on PlayStation 3 and Vita on July 23rd 2013. It was featured in the PSN Play promotion and supports cross buy  cross save.The name of the game needed to be changed to come out on the Sony platforms, and the developer held a contest to let the community come up with a "less naughty" name for the game. The winning entry was Stealth Inc: A Clone in the Dark, and the winner received their name in the credits, a copy of the game, and a PS Vita system. PC System RequirementsMinimumOS:Windows XP SP2 or better, Vista, Win7Processor:Dual Core 2.5GhzMemory:2 GB RAMGraphics:DirectX 8.0 compatibleDirectX®:8.0Hard Drive:250 MB HD space</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="36870">Stealth Bastard: Tactical Espionage Arsehole</game><game id="37615">Mark of the Ninja</game><game id="36961">Gunpoint</game><game id="22499">Trilby: The Art of Theft</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/11/117587/2501771-2378204-sbd.jpg</image></root>