<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>40806</id><name>The Walking Dead: Assault</name><description>OverviewThe Walking Dead: Assault is a squad based strategy game based on Robert Kirkman's comic book series. Broken up into "issues" like the comic the game begins at the moment when Sheriff Rick Grimes awakens in the hospital. Players assemble and upgrade their team of up to four characters and go through scenarios based around big moments in the comic. Unlike other games in The Walking Dead franchise, Assault focuses on tactically killing zombies fast for high scores.Levels•   the hospital •  main st. •  the crossroads •  the tank •  the car park •  the helipad •  the warehouse •  industrial area •  gun shop alley •  the forest •  the campCharactersRickSpecial move: Police Training- rick gets guaranteed headshotsTeam bonus: Leadership- Team more accurate when attackingShaneSpecial move: Freakout- Shane reloads twice as fast, dealing twice the damageTeam bonus: Lock  Load- team deals 25% more damageGlennSpecial move: Decoy-glen uses himself as bait to creat a distractionTeam bonus: Delivery Boy- team runs fasterAndreaSpecial move: Shroud- Camoflauges the team to move unseen amongst walkers.Team bonus: Battle Cry- Team can use their special moves more oftenCarolSpecial move: Field Medic- Heals teamTeam bonus: Rapid fire- team has increased attack rateSophiaSpecial move: Survivor- team deals 50% more damage with melee weaponsTeam bonus: Resilient- team takes 25% less damageDaleSpecial move: sharpshooter- team scores more headshotsTeam bonus: Keen Eye- attack radius of all weapons is increasedCarlSpecial move: Dodge- team evades all attacksTeam bonus: Isolation- Walkers are knocked back further when hitLoriSpecial move: Clarity- Freezes walkers for a short period of time Team bonus: Mother's Touch- team gradually heals over time MichonneSpecial move: Whirlwind- Michonne slashes her katana  killing all walkers around her.Team bonus: Silent Killer- teammates are quieter when using ranged weapons.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/99864/2385626-twd_assault.jpg</image></root>