<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>40836</id><name>Super Robot Wars UX</name><description>OverviewSuper Robot Wars UX is the first Super Robot Wars to be developed for the Nintendo 3DS. It will be the first entry on Nintendo handhelds to utilize voice acting. Players who purchase a first-run copy of the game will receive downloadable Tsume Super Robo missions.Like other recent entries in the series, UX marks the debut of several newer series; SD Gundam debuts with Brave Battle Warriors, along with Stan Lee's Heroman, the anime adaption of Demonbane, and a version of Virtual-On's Fei-Yen based on vocaloid character Hatsune Miku. The game also sees the return of Aura Battler Dunbine and Ninja Senshi Tobikage, whose last (SRPG) appearances were in Compact 3 and Impact respectively. Since the debuting Mazinkaiser SKL is the only Mazinger series in the game, UX will be the first anime-based SRW to exclude Kouji Kabuto since the introduction of human characters in Super Robot Wars 2.Featured SeriesA list of series featured in the game. Anime (and characters) that debut in the Super Robot Wars series in this game are marked with (new).Mobile Suit Gundam SEED DestinyMobile Suit Gundam 00: A Wakening of the Trailblazer (new)SD Gundam Sangokuden Brave Battle Warriors (new)Mazinkaiser SKL (new)Aura Battler DunbineThe Wings of Rean (new)Ninja Senshi TobikageFafner in the AzureFafner in the Azure: Heaven and Earth (new)Kishin Houkou Demonbane (new)Dancougar NovaLinebarrels of Iron (manga version)Macross Frontier the Movie: The False SongstressMacross Frontier the Movie: The Wings of GoodbyeHeroman (new)Cyber Troopers Virtual On series: Fei-Yen HD (new)Gameplay MechanicsSuper Robot Wars UX retains the Partner Battle System of Super Robot Wars K and L while adding a few new mechanics for unpaired units. Single units now receive an extra turn whenever they destroy at least one unit; additionally, they have access to ALL attacks. Like the ALL attacks featured in the Alpha and console Original Generation entries, ALL attacks in UX damage both the main unit and the support unit. UX also introduces the Tactician and Special Command systems. The player can elect one character to serve as their team's tactician; each tactician provides a passive effect that all members of a team can take advantage of. On the other hand, the Special Command system is similar in basic functionality to the ability of Lelouch Lamperouge in previous SRWs, but is made available to a variety of units in UX. Certain units, such as the 00 Raiser and Demonbane, can pass a stat boost to allies (or a negative effect to enemies) by activating their Special Command. These commands, like many energy-based attacks, require EN to activate.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/82063/2427666-superrobottaisenux.jpg</image></root>