<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>40884</id><name>Darkfall Unholy Wars</name><description>OverviewDarkfall Unholy Wars is an MMORPG developed and published by Aventurine S.A. and is the follow-up to Darkfall (aka Darkfall Online), which was in service from 2009 to 2012. The game is intended to overhaul many aspects which bogged down the original Darkfall, which had been developed over a long period of time (originally conceived in 1997 and entering full production in 2003). Significant changes include numerous efforts to improve accessibility (such as the GUI and new player experience) and to diversify player combat roles.Darkfall Unholy Wars will require a subscription fee and initial account/client purchase. Historically, Aventurine has not charged for any expansions or add-ons for Darkfall.World and RulesLike its predecessor, Darkfall Unholy Wars boasts a large and mostly seamless world. With the exception of dungeon portals, the entire world can be traversed seamlessly. There is no use of instancing or any limit imposed on the number of players in an area.The fantasy world of Agon consists of a large central continent (Agon) with four subcontinents: Niflheim, Yssam, Cairn and Rubaiyat. The seas surrounding these landmasses can be traversed by ships and boats (or by simply swimming).When a player is killed, his or her items are left behind in a gravestone which can be looted by any player. Players can store items in a secure bank and generally keep many sets of armor and weapons for different situations with different potential risks, therefore item loss in Darkfall should not be directly compared with other games with different mechanics.Clans (guilds) of players can fight to control cities and hamlets across the world which must be built up and defended. Villages are also found across the world and incorporate player housing with resource control and local conflict hotspots.Computer controlled monsters behave more like simple FPS-style AI bots than traditional MMORPG monsters. Larger monsters such as dragons and the kraken can roam within a large area.Mounts and player controlled vehicles, once spawned from figurine items, exist as independent objects in the world which can be destroyed or stolen.There are two servers: one in Europe and one in North America.CombatDarkfall Unholy Wars features real-time combat with character control and aiming in the style of a first person shooter. There is no target selection or lock-on and physics are simulated in more depth than in most large-scale online games.The game provides a choice of perspectives including first-person, basic third person and over-the-shoulder style third-person.Character DevelopmentLike in the previous game, there are no permanent classes in Darkfall Unholy Wars, however a 'role' system has been introduced. Player characters are able to move between these roles. Within each role, players can select two schools from that specific role. One of the schools is set by the player as the primary and the other as the secondary, and each school contains 4 skills/spells and an ultimate, the most powerful in that school.System RequirementsWindows XP Service Pack 3, 32bitIntel Core 2 Duo E6850 + orAMD Phenom II X2 +4GB RAMnVidia GeForce 8600 + orAMD or ATI 4850 +DirectX Sound Card12GB Free SpaceLinksOfficial Website</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/11/118846/2389779-darkfall_unholy_wars_box_large.jpeg</image></root>