<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>40892</id><name>Capcom Arcade Cabinet</name><description>OverviewCapcom Arcade Cabinet is a downloadable front-end for a set of 17 Capcom arcade releases. The bulk of the games are from the pre-CPS era of Capcom's arcade development. They will be offered for sale on a bi-weekly basis, with an "all-in-one" download coming at the end of the run.In addition to the regular arcade mode, players are also able to play a so-called "casual mode" which makes each game substantially easier. This is done by altering various gameplay factors. For instance, Ghost N Goblins casual mode makes item pots appear more frequently among other  changes. Players can go in and edit the settings for casual mode as well.Replays are also supported.Games SupportedCapcom Arcade Cabinet supports the following games:Black TigerAvenger1943: The Battle of MidwayGhosts n GoblinsGun.SmokeSection ZSide ArmsLegendary WingsTrojanCommandoThe Speed RumblerExed Exes1942SonSonPirate Ship HigemaruPlayers that purchase the first 15 games will gain access to two additional games, which are currently unknown.New game options, such as the ability to shoot for longer distances in Commando, will be available. PS3 users will be able to upload clips to YouTube while Xbox 360 owners are limited to posting screenshots to Facebook. Game Pack 1 – Available February 19th/20th | $4.99/€4.99/£3.99/400MSPBlack Tiger1943: Battle of MidwayAvengerBlack Tiger is FREE, with the remaining two games available individually March 5th $3.99/€3.99/£3.19 (PSN Only) Game Pack 2 – Available March 5th/6th | $9.99/€9.99/£7.99/800MSPGhosts ‘n GoblinsGun.SmokeSection ZGames available individually March 19th/20th | $3.99/€3.99/£3.19/320MSP Game Pack 3 – Available March 19th/20th | $9.99/€9.99/£7.99/800MSPSide ArmsLegendary WingsTrojanGames available individually April 2nd/3rd | $3.99/€3.99/£3.19/320MSP Game Pack 4 – Available April 2nd/3rd | $9.99/€9.99/£7.99/800MSPCommandoThe Speed RumblerExed Exes (Savage Bees)Games available individually April 16th/17th | $3.99/€3.99/£3.19/320MSP Game Pack 5 – Available April 16th/17th | $9.99/€9.99/£7.99/800MSP n1942SonSonPirate Ship HigemaruGames available individually April 30th/31st | $3.99/€3.99/£3.19/320MSP Bonus Games x2-Fans who purchase all 15 games in the Capcom Arcade Cabinet will unlock exclusive access to two FREE bonus games.All-In-One Pack – Available May 21st/22nd | $29.99/€29.99/£23.99/2000MSP-Purchase all 17 games and features in the Capcom Arcade Cabinet for a greatly reduced price.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="15">Compilation</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="48">Shoot 'Em Up</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="30021">Game Room</game><game id="32513">Pinball FX2</game><game id="36777">The Pinball Arcade</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2437063-box_cac.png</image></root>