<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>40912</id><name>Disney Infinity</name><description>GameplayDisney Infinity uses an interface in which players can place a collectible figure on the "Infinity Base" and that character appears in the game world. Players can also use "Power Discs" to add weapons, vehicles, power ups or other props to their game worlds which the player can then interact with.Disney Infinity's gameplay varies quite a lot from playset to playset. There are clear influences of previous Avalanche titles (Toy Story 3) and other popular games (Assassin's Creed 3, Red Dead Redemption). They all feel similar in control, but can actually be quite disparate in objectives. The Incredibles playset is an open world action game. The Cars playset mixes Tony Hawk style tricks and grinding with Mario Kart-esque racing. Pirates of the Caribbean takes clear inspiration from AC3's ship combat. This gameplay variety separates Infinity from other toy based video games on the market.The game also has a level creation mode in its "Toy Box" mode, which allows players to use hundreds of toys which can be collected in the different playsets (worlds) and can then be brought back into the toy box to create complex activities, including new levels, race tracks, puzzles, mini games and other activities.Characters and Playsets
The initial release had a total of seventeen character figures among five different play sets to collect and use in-game along with an initial series of twenty power discs. Additional series of power discs and characters are released in waves with many additional characters to be released in the following months. Starting in the second wave there will be toy box packs in addition to playsets. The toy box packs contain two characters and two power discs from a property. They do not have their own games and are merely for use in expanding the toy box.Wave One Playsets:Starter Pack:Pirates of the Caribbean playsetThe Incredibles playsetMonsters University playsetIndividually Sold:Cars playsetLone Ranger playsetWave One Characters:Most figures sold individually as well as in packs. * = Starter Pack, ** = included in playset, † = Villains Pack, ‡ = Sidekicks Pack, § = Girl Power Pack (Q4 '13)Pirates of the CaribbeanJack Sparrow *Davy Jones †Barbossa ‡The IncrediblesViolet §Mrs. Incredible ‡Mr. Incredible *DashSyndrome †Monsters UniversitySulley *Mike ‡Randy †CarsLightning McQueen **MaterHolley Shiftwell **Francesco BernoulliLone RangerLone Ranger **Tonto **Wave One Power Discs:Bolt's Super StrengthFix It Felix's Repair PowerC.H.R.O.M.E's Armor ShieldJack Sparrow's Pieces of EightMickey's CarCinderella's CoachKahnStich's BlasterCarl Fredericksen's CaneKing Candy's Dessert ToppingsSugar Rush SkydomeAlice in Wonderland Texture SetTulgey Wood SkydomeMarlin's Reef Texture SetNemo's Seascape SkydomeRapunzel's Kingdom Texture SetRapunzel's Birthday SkydomeDumbo the Flying ElephantAbu the ElephantAstro Blasters Space CruiserWave Two Power Discs:Ralph's Power of DestructionDr Doofenshmirtz's Damage-inatorElectro-ChargeStar Command ShieldUser Control DiscPizza Planet Delivery TruckMaximusHeadless Horseman's HorseFlamingo Croquet MalletHangin' Ten Stitch With SurfboardMike's New CarFrozen FlourishChill In The AirNew Holland SkylineVictor's ExperimentsHalloweentown SkyJack's Scary DecorationsElectric Mayhem BusCondorman GliderHook's ShipWave One Exclusive Power Discs / Future Waves' Discs:The release date of these is a bit murky. They're treated as Toys R Us or EB Games exclusives during wave one, but are actually discs from future waves.Surfboard StitchMike's CarHook's ShipTron TerrainTron SkyScrooge McDuck's Lucky DimeMerlin's SummonEmperor Zurg's WrathUser Control (Tron)C.H.R.O.M.E.'s Damage IncreaserFuture Waves' Playsets:Individually Sold:Toy Story in Space (Oct 22)Future Waves' Toy Box Packs:FrozenWreck-It RalphFuture Waves' Characters:All dates are US. Most figures sold individually as well as in packs. ** = included in playset, § = Girl Power Pack, || = included in toy box packToy Story in SpaceBuzz Lightyear ** (Oct 22)Jessie ** (Oct 22)Sheriff Woody (Oct 1)Phineas and FerbPhineas FlynnPerry the PlatypusWreck-It RalphWreck-It Ralph ||Vanellope Von Schweetz || §The Nightmare Before ChristmasJack Skellington (Oct 5)TangledRapunzel §FrozenAnna || (Nov 26)Elsa || (Nov 26)FantasiaSorcerer's Apprentice Mickey Mouse (Jan, 2014)Rare special edition figure (different paint job) was handed out at D23 Expo 2013.Future Waves' Power Discs:Angus (Brave)Calico CopterChernabog StrengthCondorman GliderCruella DeVille's CarDr Doofinschmirtz DamageElectro ChargeFlamingo MalletFrankenweenie TexturesFrankenweenie SkydomeFrozen TexturesFrozen SkydomeMickey's Sorcerer HatMidway Mania GunDragon Fireworks CannonElectric Mayhem BusNightmare Before Christmas TexturesNightmare Before Christmas SkydomeParking Lot TramPhillipe (Beauty and the Beast)Phineas and Ferb TexturesPhineas and Ferb SkydomePizza Planet TruckRapunzel's HealingSleepy Hollow HorseStar Command ShieldMaximus (Tangled)Tantor (Tarzan)Violet's ForcefieldWALL-E Fire ExtinguisherWALL-E TexturesWALL-E SkydomeWreck-It Ralph DamagePricing Structure (US MSRP)Starter Pack: $74.99Booster Pack: $34.99Individual Character Packs: $12.99Character 3 Packs: $29.992-Disc "Blind" Packs: $4.99</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="37417">Skylanders Giants</game><game id="34129">Skylanders: Spyro's Adventure</game><game id="30039">Toy Story 3: The Video Game</game><game id="35461">Disney Universe</game><game id="41485">Skylanders SWAP Force</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/16324/2414629-disney_infinity_logo.jpg</image></root>