<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>41017</id><name>Knights of Pen and Paper</name><description>OverviewKnights of Pen and Paper is an iOs and Android game, where you take control of up to five players and embark on an adventure via your dungeon master, who is guiding you through the story. You can literally see the players sitting at the table at any point, wearing masks (which determine their classes) and talking to the dungeon master. This concept allows not only the fantasy story to be told, but also some meta-narration (for example a "real world" snacks can be bought and placed on the table and they provide time limited boosts for the actual game). As the game progresses, player earns gold, which can be spent on various items and activities, from upgrading your party's equipment to speeding up the crafting processes. This app also contains in-app purchases, but there is no roadblock preventing you from moving along without spending more real money, everything can be bought with gold earned in-game. There are six classes when you first start the game, but only five chairs at the table and additional classes become unlocked via the story progression, which allows player to switch party members (which leads to resetting player level to 1) or differentiating multiple playthroughs. A PC version of the game also came out on Steam on June 2013.System RequirementsPCOS: Windows XP or later Processor: 2000 MHz Memory: 512 MB RAM Graphics: 640x480 minimum resolution (Direct3D/OpenGL compatible card with at least 128MB) DirectX®: 9.0c Hard Drive: 100 MB HD space Sound: 2D sound compatible cardMacOS: OS X 10.4 or later Processor: 2000 MHz Memory: 512 MB RAM Graphics: 640x480 minimum resolution (Direct3D/OpenGL compatible card with at least 128MB) Hard Drive: 100 MB HD space Sound: 2D sound compatible cardLinuxOS: Ubuntu 10 or later Processor: 2000 MHz Memory: 512 MB RAM Graphics: 640x480 minimum resolution (Direct3D/OpenGL compatible card with at least 128MB) Hard Drive: 100 MB HD space Sound: 2D sound compatible card</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/17/171291/2554076-3714385729-KoPP_.png</image></root>