<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>41082</id><name>Kentucky Route Zero</name><description>OverviewDeveloped by indie developer duo Cardboard Computer, Kentucky Route Zero is a five-part episodic adventure game set along an underground highway in the caves of Kentucky. It promises classic adventure gameplay with a heavy focus on story and atmosphere. The soundtrack features traditional bluegrass music.The game was successfully funded via a Kickstarter campaign launched January 7th 2011 exceeding its goal of $6,500 by raising $8,583 by February 6th of that year. This puts the successful funding date of Kentucky Route Zero a full year prior to the now famous launch of the Double Fine Adventure campaign, widely thought of as a progenitor to Kickstarter being a viable funding platform for game development.ActsAct I was released on January 7th, 2013, in a DRM-free version for PC, Mac, and Linux platforms. 5 Acts are currently planned to be released throughout 2013. Acts can be purchased individually or as a bundle containing all 5 acts. As of February 18th, 2013, the option for purchasing Act I and any future individually has been discontinued.Act II was released on May 31, 2013.MusicKentucky Route Zero features an ambient electronic soundtrack by Ben Babbitt "along with a suite of old hymns  bluegrass standards" recorded by The Bedquilt Ramblers. The soundtrack for Act I can be purchased individually or comes free as a bonus to anyone who purchases the 5 act bundle.System RequirementsPC System RequirementsMinimum:OS:Windows 7Processor:1 GHzMemory:512 MB RAMGraphics:Directx 9.0c compatible video cardDirectX®:9.0cHard Drive:250 MB HD spaceRecommended:OS:Windows 7Processor:1 GHzMemory:1 GB RAMGraphics:Directx 9.0c compatible video cardDirectX®:9.0cHard Drive:250 MB HD spaceMac Minimum System RequirementsOS:OSX 10.5 LeopardProcessor:1 GHz CPUMemory:512 MB RAMGraphics:OpenGL 3.0+ compatible video cardHard Drive:250 MB HD spaceLinux Minimum System RequirementsProcessor:1 GHz CPUMemory:512 MB RAMGraphics:OpenGL 3.0+ compatible video cardHard Drive:250 MB HD space</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="42355">The Samaritan Paradox</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/81005/2409605-.png</image></root>