<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>41090</id><name>LEGO Marvel Super Heroes</name><description>OverviewThe first Marvel based LEGO game, this title ambitiously takes on the entirety of the Marvel universe. In a story created for the game, Loki desires the throne of Asgard once again, and has begun to build a team of super villains to help him accomplish this task, while at the same time, Galactus is on his way to Earth hoping to succeed in consuming it once and for all. Now the heroes of the Marvel universe must band together in order to put a stop to these massive threats to their planet.GameplayThis new title will play similarly to TT Games previous superhero game LEGO Batman 2: DC Super Heroes, but on a much larger scale than before. Gameplay will be fairly similar to other LEGO titles, with each hero and villain having their own unique way of fighting and solving puzzles. The game will have an Open World for the characters to explore, while also having level to level based missions as in previous LEGO games, as well as Side Quests and of course a large amount of unlockables and collectibles.CharactersLEGO Marvel Super Heroes will feature over 150 playable Marvel heroes and villains with a fully voiced cast.HeroesCharacterAlternate FormsWeapons/AbilitiesA-Bomb (DLC)Rick JonesSuper StrengthThunderclapCan create and throw rock massesWall SmashHazard ProtectionRoarCan transform between Jones and A-BombAgent Coulsonn/aThe DestroyerAnt-Mann/aShrinkArchangeln/aFlightRazor FeathersAunt Mayn/aHandbagBeastn/aClawsComputer HackingDigEnhanced SensesBeta Ray Bill (DLC)n/aStormbreakerFlightLightningThrow StormbreakerBlack Boltn/aFlightSonic ScreamTelekinesisBlack Panthern/aClawsBlack Widown/aGunsInvisibilityBladen/aSwordCaptain AmericaClassicShieldThrow ShieldActivate SlotsRedirect Enemy FireShield ProtectionCaptain Britainn/aFlightEnergy BlastsTelekinesisEnhanced SensesColossusn/aSuper StrengthFastball SpecialCyclopsAstonishingOptic BlastsDamage Controln/a Daredeviln/aBatonCan swing on poles with batonEnhanced SensesDeadpooln/aGunsKatanasDoctor Strangen/aMagicDrax the Destroyern/aSaiElektran/aSaiEmma Frostn/aDiamond SkinFalcon (DLC)n/aFlightRazor FeathersFandral (DLC)n/a Gambitn/aBo StaffEnergy Throwing CardsGamoran/a Ghost Ridern/aChainsShoot FirePenance StareGrootn/aSuper StrengthGwen Stacyn/a Havokn/a HawkeyeClassic (DLC)Bow  ArrowSpecialty ArrowsHeimdalln/aSwordH.E.R.B.I.E.n/aShockHogun (DLC)n/a Howard the Duckn/aRocket LauncherHulkBruce BannerSuper StrengthCreate and throw rock massesWall SmashHazard ProtectionThunder ClapRoarTransform between Banner and HulkComputer Hacking (As Banner)Human TorchJohnny StormFlightFlame OnFire BlastFireballsIcemann/aIcebeamGlide on Ice PathIce BlastsInvisible WomanFuture FoundationCreate Force FieldInvisibilityTelekinetic BlastsIron Fistn/a Iron ManHeroic AgeMk. IMk. VIMk. VIIMk. XVIIMk. XLIITony StarkTony Stark (Underwear)HulkbusterFlightRepulsor BlastsMissilesGround SlamComputer HackingUni-BeamLimited Flight (As Mk.I)Laser Cutter (As Mk. VII, XLII)Super Strength (As Hulkbuster)J. Jonah Jamesonn/a Jane Foster (DLC)n/a Jean GreyPhoenixDark Phoenix (DLC)GlideFlight (As Phoenix)TelekinesisCan create Force FieldsFire Blasts (As Phoenix)Lady LibertyGiant (Unplayable) Lady Sif (DLC)n/a Luke Cagen/a Maria Hilln/aGunMary Jane Watsonn/a Moon Knightn/aBoomerangsMr. FantasticFuture FoundationTurn in to a TeapotGlideGrappleComputer HackingPass through gratesSpecial transformationsMs. Marveln/aFlightEnergy BeamEnergy BlastsNick Furyn/aGunsInvisibilityNovan/aFlightEnergy BlastsEnergy BeamOdin (DLC)n/aStaffPolarisn/aMagnetismLevitationShoot Metal BallsProfessor Charles Xaviern/a Psylocken/aPsychic BladeCan Create Force FieldsTelekinesisPunishern/aMachine GunRescuePepper PottsFlightRocket Raccoonn/aGreat WeaponShe-Hulkn/aSuper StrengthThunderclapWall SmashCan create and throw rock massesS.H.I.E.L.D. Agentn/aGunSilver Surfern/aSurfboardFlightPower CosmicSpider-ManPeter ParkerFuture FoundationSuperiorSymbiote (DLC)Wall CrawlingSpider SenseWeb SwingingPull Objects with websShoot Web BallsCan change between Peter and SpideySpider-Womann/aFlightSpider SenseSquirrel Girln/aGlideThrow SquirrelsSummon Squirrels to attack enemiesStan LeeStan HulkAdamantium SkeletonTransform in to Stan HulkGrappleWeb SwingingHeat VisionTelekinesisPull Objects with websShoot Web BallsWall CrawlingShoot Hammers out of handsMind ControlSpider SenseComputer HackingMagnetic PowersStarlordn/aElement GunStormn/aLevitationLightningTornadoesThingFuture FoundationSuper StrengthCan create and throw rock massesWall SmashThorClassicMjolnirFlightLightningThrow MjolnirUnion Jackn/aGunsVolstagg (DLC)n/a War MachineIron PatriotFlightMissilesChaingunWaspn/aFlightShrinkEnergy BlastsWolverineCowlClawsAdamantium SkeletonEnhanced SensesDigWall ClimbingWall CutVillainsCharactersAlternate FormsWeapons/AbilitiesAbominationn/aSuper StrengthThunderclapCan create and throw rock massesToxic BreathWall SmashAbsorbing Mann/aWrecking BallA.I.M. Agentn/aGunAldrich Killiann/a Arnim Zolan/aLaser BeamBeetlen/aFlightEnergy BlastsEnergy BeamBlack Catn/aEnhanced SensesGrappling HookBlobn/aSuper StrengthThunderclapCan create and throw rock massesWall SmashBullseyen/aThrowing CardsCarnagen/aShoot Web BallsWeb SwingingSpider SenseCan travel through Symbiote sludgeDestroyerGiant (Unplayable)Laser BeamDoctor Doomn/aLightningDoctor OctopusUltimateTentaclesEnhanced SensesDoombotV-SeriesLaser GunDormammun/a ElectroUltimateElectricityFlightExtremis Soldiern/a Frost Giantn/aSwordGalactusGiant (Unplayable) Green GoblinUltimatePumpkin BombsGoblin GliderTransform in to UltimateSuper Strength (As Ultimate)HYDRA Agentn/a Juggernautn/aSuper StrengthKingpinn/aCaneKingpin  Henchmann/a Kraven the Huntern/aSpearKurseThor: The Dark World (DLC)Super StrengthLaufeyn/a Leadern/aLaser GunCan Create Force FieldsMind ControlLizardCurt ConnorsSuper StrengthTransform in to ConnorsComputer Hacking (As Connors)Lokin/aStaffMind ControlMagneton/aMagnetisimLevitationShoot Metal BallsMagneto  AcolyteMaleFemaleElectricityMalekith the AccursedThor: The Dark World (DLC) MandarinFilm Mastermindn/aMind ControlM.O.D.O.K.n/aFlightMind BlastMysterion/aIllusion BlastsIllusion BeamComputer HackingMystiquen/aGunShape ShiftingNightmaren/a Prisonern/a Pyron/aShoot FireRed HulkGeneral RossSuper StrengthThunderclapCan create and throw rock massesHazard ProtectionWall SmashRoarTransform in to General RossGun (As Ross)Red Skulln/aGunRhinon/aSuper StrengthHornChargeRonan the Accusern/aHammerEnergy BlastsRoxxon Guardn/aGunSabretoothn/aClawsEnhanced SensesDigWall ClimbWall CutSandmann/aSand PowersTransform in to CannonActivate Sand PitsTransform in to Sand CastleSandman Goonn/a SentinelGiant (Unplayable)FlightShockern/a Silver Samurain/aSwordSuper-Skrulln/aFlightFire BlastFireballsSuper StrengthPass through gratesGlideGrappleCan Create Force FieldsInvisibilitySymbiote ScientistSymbiote  Scientist (Hazmat) Taskmastern/aSwordShieldBow  ArrowThanos (DLC)n/aEnergy BlastsSuper StrengthToadn/aTongueVenomUltimateSpider SenseWeb SwingingTransform in to UltimateSuper Strength (As Ultimate)Can travel through Symbiote sludgeVipern/aGunVulturen/aFlightWhiplashn/aElectric WhipsGrapple with WhipsElectrify with WhipsPull objects with WhipsWinter Soldier (DLC)n/aRifleWizardn/a StagesStagePlayable CharactersLocationsEnemiesBossesSand Central StationThe HulkIron Man (Mk. VI)Spider-ManOutside Grand Central StationGrand Central StationRooftopsSand EnemyAbominationSandmanTimes Square OffCaptain AmericaMr. FantasticSpider-ManThe Baxter BuildingRoofThe Daily BugleRoofTimes SquareOctobotsDoctor OctopusExploratory LaboratorySpider-ManBlack WidowHawkeye Oscorp TowerOscorp LabsSymbiote  ScientistSymbiote  Scientist (Hazmat)Green GoblinVenomRock Up at the Lock UpIron ManThe HulkWolverineThe RaftPrisonersLeaderWhiplashAbominationSabretoothMagnetoMystiqueRebooted, ResuitedThe HulkIron Man (Mk. I)Iron Man (Mk. XLII)Tony StarkCaptain AmericaStark TowerBasementExtremis SoldiersAldrich KillianIron Man (Hulkbuster)The MandarinRed Head DetentionHawkeyeBlack WidowCaptain AmericaHuman TorchHYDRA BaseHYDRA AgentsThe Red SkullArnim ZolaBifrosty ReceptionThorWolverineCaptain AmericaHuman TorchAsgardBifrostThrone RoomFrost GiantsLokiDestroyerJuggernauts and CrossesJean GreyWolverineCyclopsStormIcemanBeastX-MansionMagneto AcolytesJuggernautToadPyroDoctor in the HouseMr. FantasticInvisible WomanThingHuman TorchNick FuryLatveriaDoom CastleDoombotsGreen GoblinDoctor DoomThat Sinking FeelingIron Man (Mk. XLII)ThorSpider-ManJean GreyA.I.M. BattleshipSeafloorA.I.M. AgentsM.O.D.O.K.Taking LiberitesMr. FantasticHulkWolverineThe Statue of LibertyMagneto AcolytesMastermindRapturous RiseCaptain AmericaThingStormSavage Land (Antarctica)Magneto  AcolytesVelociraptorsRhinoMystiqueMagnetoMagnetic PersonalityIron Man (Mk. XLII)ThorSpider-ManCaptain AmericaThingStormAsteroid MMagneto  AcolytesMagnetoA Doom With a ViewSpider-ManCaptain AmericaThingStorm Asteroid MMagneto  AcolytesDoombotsDoombot (V-Series)LokiDoctor DoomThe Good, the Bad and the HungrySpider-ManThingGreen GoblinMystiqueIron Man (Mk. XLII)Human TorchAbominationVenomCaptain AmericaDoctor OctopusMr. FantasticNick FuryDoctor DoomMagnetoCyclopsStorm S.H.I.E.L.D. Helicarrier n/aLokiGalactusSide MissionsStagePlayable CharactersLocationsEnemiesBossesA Shock WithdrawalIron Man (Mk. VI)Captain AmericaSpider-ManBankPrisonersElectroShockerFeeling FiskyCaptain AmericaSpider-ManDaredevilFisk TowerKingpin  HenchmenElektraBullseyeKingpinThe Thrill of the ChessMagnetoMystiqueThe RaftPrisonersMysterioPut up your DukesWolverineJean GreyGymn/aBlobTabloid Tidy UpAgent CoulsonDoctor OctopusDaily Buglen/an/aStunt Show SurpriseHawkeyeBlack WidowIcemanCircusSkeletonsNightmareReptilian RuckusSpider-ManThingReptile Sanctuaryn/aLizardBro-tunheimThorLokiAsgardFrost GiantsMalekithLaufeyNuff SaidSpider-ManMr. FantasticMarvel HQPrisonersVultureHoward the DuckHouse Party ProtocolIron Man (Mk. XLII)War Machine  Stark Tower n/a n/a Stranger DangerInvisible WomanHuman TorchDoctor StrangeSanctum SantorumSkeletonsDormammu VehiclesVehicleCharacter BasedTypeBattle VanPunisherLandCloud RiderHawkeyeLand/AirDeadpool ScooterDeadpoolLandFantasticarFantastic FourAirHell CycleGhost RiderLandMagneto MobileMagnetoUnknownPumpkin ChopperGreen GoblinAirSpider Buggy (DLC)Spider-ManLandSpider CopterSpider-ManAirSky-Cycle (DLC)HawkeyeAirUnion Jack's CarUnion JackLandX-JetX-MenAirSystem RequirementsColumn HeadColumn HeadOS: Windows®XP SP3, Windows Vista/7/8 with latest service packs and updates installedOS: Windows XP/Vista/7/8Processor: AMD Athlon 64 X2 EE 3800+ (2*2000 Mhz) or similar Intel CPU, such as Intel Pentium Dual Core E2180 (2*2000 Mhz)Processor: AMD or Intel Quad Core running at 4*2600 MhzMemory: 2 GB RAMMemory: 4 GB RAMGraphics: NVIDIA GeForce 7600 GS or ATI Radeon X1950 Pro or betterGraphics: NVIDIA GeForce GTX 480 or ATI Radeon HD 5850 or betterDirectX: Version 10DirectX: Version 11Network: Broadband Internet connectionNetwork: Broadband Internet connectionHard Drive: 7 GB available spaceHard Drive: 8 GB available space</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="36898">LEGO Batman 2: DC Super Heroes</game><game id="20822">LEGO Batman: The Videogame</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2549847-box_legomsh.png</image></root>