<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4125</id><name>The Lost World: Jurassic Park</name><description>OverviewThe Lost World: Jurassic Park is a game based on the movie of the same name. Taking inspiration from the old Genisis/Megadrive game, you once again play as a dinosaur, but this time you play as multiple dinosaurs and not just as the T-Rex.Here, 120 million years of predatory evolution converge into a single moment in time. Isolated on a remote island, modern man comes face to face with dozens of species of genetically engineered dinosaurs. Now it is survival of the fittest. Deadly predators from opposite ends of Earth's history now find themselves locked in an epic struggle.This game contains a password save system only, even on the PlayStation where memory cards were common.Power UpsAll Characters1-UpAwards an additional life.DNA KeyEvery level has a DNA Key. Collect them all to earn a Gallery Password when you complete the levels for a particular character. The Gallery Password unlocks a gallery of behind-the-scenes images. There is a gallery for each of the five player characters. However, if you miss any of the DNA Keys at any time, you are locked out of the gallery for the current character and all those that follow. Collect all the DNA Keys in all the levels to unlock a secret ending!Dinosaur CharactersPartial Instinct BoostAdds 25% to instinct.Full InstinctBoosts instinct to 100%Human CharactersPartial Health BoostAdds 25% health.Full HealthRestores 100% health.Tranquilizer DartsHunter's standard ammunition -- veterinary grade tranquilizers, unlimited ammo.Rapid Fire Tracer AmmoQuick-firing phosphate coated bullet.Time-Delay GrenadeSelf propelled explosive with a short automatic timer.Nerve GasCreates a fast-acting toxic cloud of deadly BMD-2 gas.Rocket Propelled GrenadeExtremely powerful, high-velocity incendiary ammunition.Flame-thrower fuelProvides a steady stream of fiery napalm.Emergency Rescue FlareBrightly burning flares useful for distracting large bipedal creatures.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7434">Universal Studios Theme Park Adventure</game><game id="32826">Jurassic Park: Survival</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2285733-box_tlwjp.png</image></root>