<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>41335</id><name>Star Conflict</name><description>OverviewStar Conflict is a Free to Play online space combat game featuring multiple Objective-Based Team Gameplay modes, three main factions with 2 respective sub factions each, and an array of ship customization and three types of ships complete with there own ship tree and skill tree.GameplayGameplay consists of two teams fighting each other in competitive game modes, either in domination or a deathmatch esque game mode. The team with the most points at the end of the round or the first to eliminate the other team wins.Before a match you are in the hangar screen where you can select your ship, purchase new equipment (Guns, Rockets, Special Weapons, Active Modules, Passive Modules, Ship Modifiers, Weapon Modifiers) purchase new ships, set skills, sign contracts, view corporation rosters and ranking, as well as repairing ships and refilling ammunition.After a match you gain reputation as well as in game currency at the end of every match. Reputation is used to increase in rank which allows you to purchase higher tier ships, and sign higher ranking faction contracts that gives you bonus reputation and currency once the requirements are fulfilled.FactionsEmpireProud and Strong. Expanding the boundaries of the Emperor’s power is their main priority. Sub factions include Legion and Wardens.FederationTrade is the Federation’s power. High quality ships are well equipped, speedy, and convenient for travel and transportation. Sub factions include Armada and Vanguard.JerichoMost technically equipped faction. Exiles from earth. Leading in the field of cyber genetics. Sub factions include Raid and Techs.ShipsInterceptorsLight class ships with high maneuverability and fast speeds. Equipped with a two cannon system.Attack ShipsMedium class ships with solid all around stats. Equipped with a four cannon system.FrigatesHeavy class ships with slow speeds, high firepower and solid armor. equipped with a six cannon system.Game ModesArcadeCombat ReconnaissanceThis mode features a last man standing style deathmatch where the opposing team must eliminate the opposing teams captain which provides the team with unlimited respawn and vice-versa. Once the captain has been destroyed you must eliminate the rest of the opposing team. In the case of both team captains surviving the duration of the match the team with the most points win.DominationEach team must capture, hold, and defend three beacons. Each beacon is defended by sentries that you must destroy before you can capture. The first team to reach 100 or the most points at the end of the round wins.RegularBeacon CaptureCapture, hold and defend beacons. Both teams have a limited number of spawns.System RequirementsRecommended (PC)Recommended (Mac)OS: Windows XP SP3, Vista, Windows 7CPU: Intel Core 2 Duo or AMD Athlon 64 X2System RAM: 1 GBVideo card: Pixel Shader 3.0 compliant, 512 MB (Nvidia GeForce 260 GT or better)Sound Card: DirectX 9.0c compatibleHard Drive: 2 GBOS: Snow Leopard (10.6.X)Processor: 2.3 GHz IntelGraphics: 512 MB NVidia GeForce 285 / NVidia GeForce 9600 / ATI 5750 or higher graphics cardHard Drive: 2 GB  </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/10935/2418792-star_conflict_header_530x298.jpg</image></root>