<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>41592</id><name>Sweet Fuse: At Your Side</name><description>OverviewSweet Fuse: At Your Side is an otome game developed by Idea Factory and Comcept for the PSP. It is being released in North America by Aksys Games. The protagonist is Saki Inafune, the niece of legendary game designer Keiji Inafune.StorySaki InafuneSaki Inafune is excited when she receives an invitation to the opening ceremonies for her uncle's theme park. As she is getting ready for a fun day at the park, the evil Count Hogstein shows up. Hogstein blows up the ferris wheel and takes the park management as hostage. He announces the beginning of a deadly series of games. Desperate to save her uncle, Saki volunteers to participate in the deadly competitions. Saki must team up with other participants who are all available bachelors and try to save her uncle from the clutches of Hogstein.GameplayFeatures a branching story with many story paths and 14 endingsSolve dangerous puzzles that will determine Saki and her friends fatesChoose how to deal with conversations either keeping your cool or blowing your fuse when dealing with characters</description><genres><genre id="36">Text Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19409">Phoenix Wright: Ace Attorney</game><game id="1159">Hotel Dusk: Room 215</game><game id="24237">Again</game><game id="28028">Ghost Trick: Phantom Detective</game><game id="36959">Corpse Party: Book of Shadows</game><game id="37377">Analogue: A Hate Story</game><game id="2885">Remember 11: The Age of Infinity</game><game id="28224">Steins;Gate</game><game id="32194">Radiant Historia</game><game id="37813">Detective Saburo Jinguji: Rondo of Vengeance</game><game id="27266">999: 9 Hours, 9 Persons, 9 Doors</game><game id="36237">Zero Escape: Virtue's Last Reward</game><game id="35857">Hakuoki: Demon of the Fleeting Blossom</game><game id="23452">Angelique</game><game id="23451">Yo-Jin-Bo: The Bodyguards</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2525242-box_sfays.png</image></root>