<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>41690</id><name>Killzone: Shadow Fall</name><description>StoryIt's been 30 years since the events of Killzone 3 took place and the world is a very different place. Both the Vektans  the Helghan live side by side in a futuristic city divided by a wall. Tensions are high as both sides continue to attack each others city. You play as Lucan Kellan, a Shadow Marshall, the most special of special forces and are tasked to keep the balance of these two cities in check.When a surprise attack levels a peaceful square on the Vektan side and Helghan stealth troops lay waste to the fallen, you take up arms. After a harrowing ride on a Helghan ship, you find yourself literally standing on the wall, Vektan and Helghan craft converging on both sides of you, the epicenter of the conflict.MultiplayerShadow falls brings back the iconic Warzone game mode which mashes a bunch of different game modes into one match. Multiplayer matches will be capped at 24 players and features three classes: Assault, Support, and Scout. The game runs at a native 1080p at 60 frames per second "most of the time" according to the developers. Among the new features in Shadow Fall's multiplayer is the inclusion of user created game modes akin to games like Halo 3. There will be 22 weapons in total and all will be unlocked from the start. Instead, players will unlock attachments through the game's over 1500 challenges.All map packs will be free to Playstation Plus subscribers but a Season Pass has been also been announced. The Season Pass will include access to a new horde style co-op mode, three online co-op maps, and two multiplayer expansion packs. An exclusive OWL combat skin and unique multiplayer Spotlight move will be available to players who purchase the pass day one.  </description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="42860">Titanfall</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/82063/2560906-killzoneclean.jpg</image></root>