<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>42205</id><name>Age of Empires II: The Conquerors Expansion</name><description>Continue your empire building and conquering with this expansion pack to Age of Empires II. Five new civilizations are introduced, including the Aztecs, Huns, Koreans, Mayans, and Spanish, each offering new units and unique technologies to master. There are 26 new technologies in total; seven are general economic and military upgrades, while one or two are civilization specific. All 18 civilizations also feature distinct starting bonuses in areas such as buildings, combat, advancements, and upgrades. Other additions include four maps based on real-world geographical locations, nine fictional maps, and three new game types: King of the Hill, Wonder Race, and Defend the Wonder.

The 11 new units consist of the following: Conquistadors, Eagle Warriors, Halberdiers, Hussars, Jaguar Warriors, Missionaries, Petards, Plumed Archers, Tarkans, Turtle Ships, and War Wagons. Four campaigns let you recreate historical battles as Attila the Hun, El Cid, and Montezuma. Improved multiplayer chatting includes color-coded text and specific player targeting for messages. Another new option, friend or foe colors, offers a simpler scheme for differentiating between allies and enemies. For players in single missions, the chat interface can now be used to send commands to allied players under computer control. The full version of Age of Empires II is required to play the new content from the expansion.

Age of Empires II: The Conquerors Expansion is the official add-on to the award-winning, best-selling real-time strategy game Age of Empires II: The Age of Kings. 

Focusing on legendary leaders, The Conquerors will challenge veterans and novices to wage war on an epic scale with all-new civilizations, unique units and technologies, and campaigns based on infamous conquerors such as Attila the Hun, El Cid and Montezuma.</description><genres><genre>Strategy</genre></genres><image>http://thegamesdb.net/banners/boxart/thumb/original/front/13006-1.jpg</image></root>