<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4241</id><name>Total Overdose</name><description>OverviewTotal Overdose is an action-adventure-shooter game by Danish developers Deadline Games. It was released in September 2005. The game stars a guy by the name of Ramiro Cruz, the son of a famous agent for the Mexican government who got shot and killed on one of his mission, the story revolves around Ramiro while he tries to find out who killed his father and why. The game takes place in an open world similar to that of the GTA series. What makes Total Overdose unique is the inclusion of a set of stylish shooting mechanics, which mix the bullet time ability of the Max Payne series with a set of acrobatic moves, such as doing a 180-degree flip off a wall. The game also features a robust combo system, with named 'trick' moves, akin to the Tony Hawk series, in which kills done using the aforementioned acrobatic and time-manipulating mechanics, or simply in quick succession reward you bonus points. Accumulation of points earn the player "Loco Moves"; which are a set of super attacks that look very stylish and are very powerful.PlotThe player assumes control of Ramiro "Ram" Cruz; once a lowlife criminal, now a lowlife DEA agent. He has been sent in to the Mexican city Los Toros by his twin brother Timmy, who wants Ram to find out who killed their father Ernesto, who was suddenly killed during a mission. The player is tasked with infiltrating Mexico's biggest drug cartel and will battle it out with Mexican drug dealers, luchadores, guerrilla soldiers and many more insane things.CharactersRamiro "Ram" CruzThe character you will play as for most of the game. Ram does not believe in doing things "by the book," and as such he creates an incredible amount of destruction everywhere he goes. During the course of the game, Ram's enemies will refer to him as "Gringo Loco." Ram calls calls himself Gringo Loco a number of times during the game aswell.Tomas "Tommy" CruzTommy is Ram's twin brother. Tommy is a high-ranking who has devoted his entire career to taking down the Morales Drug Cartel and clearing his fathers name. His mission is quickly comprised, though, when he is paralyzed by a grenade, forcing him to spend the rest of his life in a wheelchair. Therefore, he busts his brother out of jail so he can finish the job for him.Papa MuerteA mysterious druglord who is responsible for the death of Ernesto Cruz (Tomas and Ram's father).Commander TrustCommander Trust is Tommy's boss, and he is not happy about sending Ram in to take down the Morales Drug Cartel.Marco the RatOwner of Marco's Junkyard in Los Toros.Cesar MoralesCesar Morales is the head of the Morales Drug Cartel.AngelAngel is Cesar Morales' truck driver. She is also a cop and helps out Ram with taking down Morales.Special Agent JohnsonSpecial Agent Johnson is Ernesto's former partner, and has put a lot of effort into finding Ernesto's murderer, but with no result. Wears a cowboy hat and packs a humongous revolver.Special Agent PierssonSpecial Agent Piersson also worked with Ernesto. Piersson was killed in an ambush set by Papa Muerte.General MontanezA high-ranking leader in the Mexican Army, currently employed by Papa Muerte.Elvez GonzalesElvez Gonzales is a wealthy playboy, a good friend of Cesar Morales and is also a weapons dealer.SoundtrackMolotov:"Que No Te Haga Bobo Jacobo" (in the opening credits before accessing the main menu)"Karmara""Molotov Cocktail Party""Matate Tete""Step Off""Cerdo""No Manches Mi Vida""Apocalypshit""El Mundo""Crazy Gringo"Control Machete:"Humanos Mexicanos""Comprendes Mendes?""Cheve"Delinquent Habits:"Beijing""Downtown""Freedom Band""House of the Rising Drum""I Can't Forget it""It's the Delinquents""Return of the Tres (main menu music)""Sick Syde Drop""Station 13""This is L.A.""Hey Tell 'Em"Others:"El Rey" - by Jose Alfredo Jimenez"La Cucaracha" - by Alvero Gomez Oruzco"Duelo de Pistolas" - by Steven John"Mexican Nights" - by David Snell"Rio Grande" - by David Snell Chili Con CarnageTotal Overdose was ported to the PSP in 2007. It released under the title Chili Con Carnage, presumably to avoid association with Total Overdose since it was not critically or financially successful.Minimum System RequirementsWindows XP / Vista / 7 / 81.8 GHz Processor512 MB RAM (1 GB recommended)3D graphics card compatible with DirectX 9.0cSound card compatible with DirectX 9.0c2 GB HDDMouseKeyboard</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18163">Just Cause</game><game id="2414">Max Payne</game><game id="18411">Dead to Rights II</game><game id="17036">Grand Theft Auto: Vice City</game><game id="5618">Saints Row</game><game id="19080">Chili Con Carnage</game><game id="16355">Nitro Family</game><game id="11490">Torrente</game><game id="13942">John Woo presents Stranglehold</game><game id="8176">Starsky &amp; Hutch</game><game id="11153">True Crime: Streets of LA</game><game id="8799">El Matador</game><game id="20679">Saints Row 2</game><game id="21984">WET</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2179516-box_to.png</image></root>