<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>42572</id><name>Rayman M</name><description>Rayman M, later released as Rayman Arena in North America, is a multiplayer party game developed and published by Ubisoft. It consists of two modes: an arena fighting mode, and a racing mode. It is a 1-4 player game, or one can play with 1 player vs. the computer. There are three levels of difficulty: Beginner, Pro, and an unlockable Master. There are also 4 cups to be won in both the Battle and Race modes.

There are 5 game modes (only Championship Mode has multiplayer support):
Championship Mode: The player competes with a computer-controlled character (or a second human player if multiplayer is on), to finish 3 laps before the opponent to win. One victory in Championship Mode unlocks Lums Mode for the same track. With multiplayer, the screen is divided vertically.
Lums Mode: Only available once the corresponding level has been unlocked in Championship Mode. In this mode, many Yellow Lums are spread around the maps, which the player must compete with a computer-controlled character and win the 3-lap race. At the same time, collect as many Lums as possible. If the challenging player wins, the corresponding level will be unlocked in the Target Mode, Depending on the number of Lums collected, a time bonus for Target Mode will be awarded.
Target Mode: Only available once the corresponding level has been unlocked in Lums Mode, a single player will race alone against the clock, shooting at butterflies that are spread around the level. Each butterfly shot gives extra time.
Time Attack Mode: A single player will run one lap on their own. The aim is to reach the next checkpoint before the timer reaches 0.
Training Mode: This mode serves only as a means of familiarizing new players with the tracks, allowing them to practice and master the game controls and tricks before a real challenge.</description><genres><genre>Platform</genre></genres><image>http://thegamesdb.net/banners/boxart/thumb/original/front/17956-1.jpg</image></root>