<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4319</id><name>Delta Force</name><description>SettingIn Delta Force, you play as a member of Delta Force, a counter terrorist force that specializes in the use of small units and advanced weaponry, in fictional conflicts across the globe. You and your team are given missions in different parts of the world, including the following.  -South America, where Delta Force helps eliminate a drug lord's cartel and his empire.-Northern Russia, where Delta Force eliminates a paramilitary organization with access to nuclear Weapons.-The Middle East, where Delta Force hunts terrorists in the desert. GameplayThe player is assigned with a different mission in each of around 20 locales. Some involve actions such as the escort of a VIP, searching for nuclear weapons, or destroying an enemy HQ. At the start of each mission the player chooses from a series of weapons and equipment including,-M16 Grenadier with acog scope     -Fragmentation Grenade-Bolt Action M24 sniper rifle               -Smoke Grenade-Silenced MP5                                     - Rocket Launcher-Beretta 50. Sal sniper rifle               - Combat Knife -SAW machine gun                            - M18 Claymore Anti-PersonnelHe'll be dead in a second! Many missions require the use of stealth and night vision goggles, this affects your starting gear, but retains customization of equipment. Multiple objectives are assigned to the player, however they can choose to ignore secondary and tertiary one and approach the main in any way they choose. Sticking close to your squad is often essential in surviving combat scenarios.  Artificial IntelligenceEnemies are not very smart when it comes to fighting off Delta Force, meaning the player does not have a very difficult time so long as he is careful.  The player can dispatch of an enemy from long range yet the unit standing next to him will not be alerted. Enemy helicopters have a tendency to fire constantly at the last known position of an enemy, allowing the player to maneuver around and hit it from behind, at which point the vehicle will break off it's engagement and attack the player directly again. The player encounters various enemies throughout the game although almost all use AK-47s and differ only in the color of their camouflage.  Squad MechanicsOne to three squads are present in most missions acting as support for the objectives. They are named according to their call sign, Alpha Team, Bravo Team, and Charlie Team. These squads act autonomously from the player and can be killed by the enemy. The player's squad will follow a set order of objectives, the player may follow along or simply go rogue. At times the player recieves support from a Uh-60 Black hawk helicopter which also acts as the extraction point for Delta Force. The player undergoes a variety of missions spanning the glove, from defending a South American president's limo to locating Nuclear Bombs in a former Russian military base. Some missions have time limits while others demand total stealth.The game uses an early 3D engine allowing for large maps with foliage and various textures.     System Requirements    PC CD-ROM, Windows® 95/98/NTMMX or PII RequiredCPU: Minimum Pentium® 166 MMX Required (PII recommended)Memory: 32 MB minimumCD-ROM Drive: Quad speedVideo: Windows® 95/98/NTMouse Hardware Supported  Sound Cards: Windows® 95/98 compatibleDirectX™(included on CD) Multiplayer Requirements       Windows® 95, 98 Internet Play: 8** players or up to 32 simultaneous players via NovaWorld Free* servers (Internet service provider needed)Direct serial play: Requires null modem cable (2 players)†For modem play: Minimum 14.4 Kbps modem (2 players)†For network play: IPX network adapter (up to 8 players)† † Min. DirectX™ (DirectX™ included)    Windows® NT Internet Play: 8** players or up to 32 simultaneous players via NovaWorld Free* servers (Internet service provider needed)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8732">Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon</game><game id="7887">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six</game><game id="5333">Operation Flashpoint: Cold War Crisis</game><game id="178">ArmA: Combat Operations</game><game id="6246">SOCOM: U.S. Navy SEALs</game><game id="21912">Planetside: Core Combat</game><game id="11364">Project IGI 2: Covert Strike</game><game id="8616">Project I.G.I.: I'm Going In</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1987/701660-delta_force_manual.jpg</image></root>