<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4391</id><name>Age of Empires: The Rise of Rome</name><description>As the expansion to Ensemble Studio’s Age of Empires, Rise of Rome introduced four additional playable civilizations to add to the twelve from the original game. These were the Carthaginians, Macedonians, Palmyrans and the Romans. Along with this a new Roman-style architecture was introduced for these new civilizations. There were also minor changes to the game play such as the introduction of unit queuing and an increase to the population limit.  New Civilizations Carthaginians Transports 30% Faster  Fire Galley  25% Attack Academy and Elephants  25      Hit Points  Macedonians Academy Units  2 vs.      Slinger, Ballista, Heleoplis missile weapon Hand-to-hand Attack Units       2 Range of sight Siege Workshop Units cost      50% less Units 4 times more      resistant to conversions  Palmyrans Free Tribute Gold per Trade Ship doubled      Villagers cost 50% more,      but have armor and work 20% faster Camel Riders 25% Faster  Romans Buildings Cost 25% Less -      Except Walls, Towers and Wonders Towers Cost 50% Less Swordsmen Attack 30% Faster       New Units   Armoured      Elephant Camel      RiderScythed      ChariotFire      Galley Slinger New Upgrades Logistics      – Barracks units only count as half units towards your populations Martyrdom      – Lets you instantly convert a unit by sacrificing a priestMedicine      – Increases priest healingTower      Shield – Increases resistance to ballista attacks</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13076">Age of Mythology</game><game id="11993">Rise of Nations</game><game id="6164">World in Conflict</game><game id="8546">Age of Empires III</game><game id="20580">Sid Meier's Civilization Revolution</game><game id="2846">Age of Empires II: The Age of Kings</game><game id="18901">Star Wars: Galactic Battlegrounds</game><game id="18072">Command &amp; Conquer: Red Alert 2</game><game id="5550">Command &amp; Conquer: Yuri's Revenge</game><game id="582">Colosseum: Road to Freedom</game><game id="14291">Stronghold Crusader</game><game id="22846">Stronghold Crusader Extreme</game><game id="7701">The Lord of the Rings: The Battle for Middle-earth</game><game id="24890">Warfare Incorporated</game><game id="20952">World in Conflict: Soviet Assault</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/7439/710936-age_of_empires___the_rise_of_rome_coverart.jpg</image></root>