<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4403</id><name>Post Mortem</name><description>OverviewMysterious womanA tale of danger and deception that starts with a horribly gruesome double murder at the Orphee Hotel in Paris. An American couple by the name of Whyte has been murdered, and when the French police can't seem to get anywhere with the case, a mysterious American woman Sophia Blake hires a former New York detective Gus McPherson to the case, to dig out the truth behind the murder of her sister and brother-in-law. The investigation leads McPherson into unexpected avenues, new revelations regarding the victims as well as his employer turns the case upside down and inside out.CharactersGus and the beardGustav McPherson Gustav McPherson is a former New York detective, who was forced to flee to Europe to begin a new life after being wrongly accused of homicide in New York. While Gus is staying in Paris and pursuing the life of a painter, a case too interesting to pass by crosses his path. An American couple, the Whytes, murdered and gruesomely beheaded in a close by hotel. Gus is hired on the case by a sensuous woman to investigate the death of her sister and brother-in-law.Sophia BlakeA mysterious and wealthy American woman who hires Gus to investigate the double murder of her sister and brother-in-law.System RequirementsProcessor : Pentium III 350 MHz16X CD-ROM drive64MB RAM3D video card compatible Direct X8.1, 16MBDirect Sound compatible sound card500 MB of hard disk space</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7276">Pathologic</game><game id="23594">Still Life 2</game><game id="3141">Still Life</game><game id="16965">Syberia</game><game id="1975">Syberia II</game><game id="3234">AmerZone: The Explorer's Legacy</game><game id="574">Sherlock Holmes: Nemesis</game><game id="235">The Black Mirror</game><game id="4897">The Moment of Silence</game><game id="29119">Giften</game><game id="21304">Heavy Rain</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/13292/827760-561419_51301_front.jpg</image></root>