<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>445</id><name>Endless Ocean</name><description>IntroductionEndless Ocean is a diving simulator for the Wii developed by Arika. The game boasts a large expansive ocean with 100 creatures to "collect" in the players aquarium. When the player is on the boat they can do one of several things, they can check up on seals, dolphins, boobies or penguins hanging around on the boat. The player can change the location of the boat via the steering wheel, the player can also teach one of their dolphin companion tricks by touching a fin/mouth and wiggling the wii-mote at the screen. The player can also check email, skip time, talk to the marine biologist who can't swim or listen to music while staring at the sky. But once the player dives the "endlessnes" begins, the player can go anywhere once they are released down to dive within a certain large perimeter around the boat. They can also dive with a partner [dolphin], draw things with an underwater pen and pet fish. Most of the game IS about petting fish and exploring the sea, every-time you see an area while diving the area is drawn in on your map, while every-time you pet/rub a fish the fish is put as a sticker in a brown book in your cabin. The game also allow 2 players to dive together via Nintendo Wifi.StructureEndelss Ocean although it not being its main focus has a single player mode in which you will be send on various missions that will make you venture the different rich locations that the game has to offer. Most of the mission make you guide tourist who want to see specific fish in the water completing these will earn you new gear. The main story missions will make you look for the legendary mother whale who is believed to swim the waters.ControlsIn order to play Endless Ocean only the wii remote is needed. You change direction by pointing the IR sensor to the different sides of the screen and interact with animals with the A button. The B button makes the player's character swim forward but it is also possible to "lock" the B button in sort of a auto swim mode. The game also allows the player to do a quick demi-loop making with a single button press and to spread fish feed with another one. Once the "water pencils" unlocked the player can press (needs verification) at any time to make a drawing or to write a message underwater which is useful when playing the game online with a friends.List of Sea LifeList of sea lifeCommon Name: Oriental butterflyfishScientific Name: Chaetodon auripesCommon Name: Teardrop butterflyfishScientific Name: Chaetodon unimaculatusCommon Name: Pyramid butterflyfishScientific Name: Hemitaurichthys polylepisCommon Name: Emperor angelfishScientific Name: Pomacanthus imperatorCommon Name: Blue tangScientific Name: Paracanthus hepatusCommon Name: Powder blue tangScientific Name: Acanthurus leucosternonCommon Name: Golden spadefishScientific Name: Platax boersiiCommon Name: Lined surgeonfishScientific Name: Acanthurus lineatusCommon Name: Sailfin tangScientific Name: Zebrasoma veliferumCommon Name: Yellow tangScientific Name: Zebrasoma flavescensCommon Name: Goldeye rockfishScientific Name: Sebastes thompsoniCommon Name: Samurai squirrelfishScientific Name: Sargocentron ittodaiCommon Name: Orange-lined triggerfishScientific Name: Balistapus undulatusCommon Name: Clown triggerfishScientific Name: Balistoides conspicillumCommon Name: Orangespine unicornfishScientific Name: Naso lituratusCommon Name: Luna lionfishScientific Name: Pterois lunulataCommon Name: Whitemargin unicornfishScientific Name: Naso annulatusCommon Name: Clown wrasseScientific Name: Coris gaimardCommon Name: Blackspotted pufferfishScientific Name: Arothron nigropunctatusCommon Name: Bicolour parrotfishScientific Name: Cetoscarus bicolorCommon Name: Bower's parrotfishScientific Name: Chlorurus bowersiCommon Name: John doryScientific Name: Zeus faberCommon Name: Japanese sardineScientific Name: Sardinops sagaxCommon Name: Chub mackerelScientific Name: Scomber japonicusCommon Name: Red Sea breamScientific Name: Pagrus majorCommon Name: Japanese jack mackerelScientific Name: Trachurus japonicusCommon Name: Japanese flying fishScientific Name: Cypselurus agooCommon Name: Golden trevallyScientific Name: Gnathanodon speciosusCommon Name: Bigeye trevallyScientific Name: Caranx sexfasciatusCommon Name: Miniata grouperScientific Name: Cephalopholis miniataCommon Name: Multicolourfin rainbowfishScientific Name: Halichoeres poecilopterusCommon Name: Red gurnardScientific Name: Chelidonichthys spinosusCommon Name: FlatheadScientific Name: Platycephalus sp.Common Name: RemoraScientific Name: Echeneis naucratesCommon Name: Horseshoe crabScientific Name: Tachypleus tridentatusCommon Name: Bigfin reef squidScientific Name: Sepioteuthis lessonianaCommon Name: Broadclub cuttlefishScientific Name: Sepia latimanusCommon Name: Common octopusScientific Name: Octopus vulgarisCommon Name: Ornate rock lobsterScientific Name: Panulirus ornatusCommon Name: Crown-of-thomas starfishScientific Name: Acanthaster planciCommon Name: Clown anemonefishScientific Name: Amphiprion ocellarisCommon Name: Yellowtail clownfishScientific Name: Amphiprion clarkiiCommon Name: Tomato clownfishScientific Name: Amphiprion frenatusCommon Name: Yellow clownfishScientific Name: Amphiprion sandaracinosCommon Name: Sapphire devilScientific Name: Chrysiptera cyaneaCommon Name: Starck's demoiselleScientific Name: Chrysiptera starckiCommon Name: Goldtail demoiselleScientific Name: Chrysiptera parasemaCommon Name: Blue-green chromisScientific Name: Chromis viridisCommon Name: Three-spot dascyllusScientific Name: Dascyllus trimaculatusCommon Name: Bicolor angelfishScientific Name: Centropyge bicolorCommon Name: Banded angelfishScientific Name: Apolemichthys arcuatusCommon Name: Royal angelfishScientific Name: Pygoplites diacanthusCommon Name: Yellow longnose butterflyfishScientific Name: Forcipiger flavissimusCommon Name: Moorish idolScientific Name: Zanclus cornutusCommon Name: Singular bannerfishScientific Name: Heniochus singulariusCommon Name: Threadfin butterflyfishScientific Name: Chaetodon aurigaCommon Name: Bluelashed butterflyfishScientific Name: Chaetodon bennettiCommon Name: Brown-and-white butterflyfishScientific Name: Hemitaurichthys zosterCommon Name: MandarinfishScientific Name: Synchiropus splendidusCommon Name: Rippled rockskipperScientific Name: Istiblennius edentulusCommon Name: Red-spotted blennyScientific Name: Blenniella chrysospilosCommon Name: Bicolor blennyScientific Name: Ecsenius bicolorCommon Name: IsoginpoScientific Name: Parablennius yatabeiCommon Name: Fire gobyScientific Name: Nemateleotris magnificaName: Elegant firefishScientific Name: Nemateleotris decoraElegant firefishCommon Name: Yellow shrimp gobyScientific Name: Cryptocentrus cinctusCommon Name: Singapore prawn gobyScientific Name: Cryptocentrus singapurensisCommon Name: Yellow clown gobyScientific Name: Gobiodon okinawaeCommon Name: Red-spotted gobyScientific Name: Gobiodon sp. 2Common Name: Five-lined coral gobyScientific Name: Gobiodon quinquestrigatusCommon Name: Oblong gobyScientific Name: Gobiodon sp. 1Common Name: Monster shrimp gobyScientific Name: Tomiyamichthys oniCommon Name: Painted frogfishScientific Name: Antennarius pictusCommon Name: Warty frogfishScientific Name: Antennarius maculatusCommon Name: Striated frogfishScientific Name: Antennarius striatusCommon Name: Sea goldieScientific Name: Pseudanthias squamipinnisCommon Name: Stocky anthiasScientific Name: Pseudanthias hypselosomaCommon Name: Sunset anthiasScientific Name: Pseudanthias parvirostrisCommon Name: SakuradaiScientific Name: Sacura margaritaceaCommon Name: Southern orange-lined cardinalScientific Name: Apogon properuptusCommon Name: Humpback grouperScientific Name: Cromileptes altivelisCommon Name: Yellow boxfishScientific Name: Ostracion cubicusCommon Name: Whitespotted boxfishScientific Name: Ostracion meleagrisCommon Name: Long-spine porcupinefishScientific Name: Diodon holocanthusCommon Name: Harlequin sweetlipsScientific Name: Plectorhinchus chaetodonoidesCommon Name: Orange sea slugScientific Name: Thecacera pacificaCommon Name: Orange-and-black sea slugScientific Name: Thecacera sp.Common Name: Festival sea slugScientific Name: Hypselodoris festivaCommon Name: Spotted white sea slugScientific Name: Chromodoris orientalisCommon Name: Striped white sea slugScientific Name: Chromodoris willaniCommon Name: Cinderella sea slugScientific Name: Hypselodoris apolegmaCommon Name: Strigate chromodorisScientific Name: Chromodoris strigataCommon Name: Luminescent sea slugScientific Name: Plocamopherus tilesiiCommon Name: Parade-float sea slugScientific Name: Kalinga ornataCommon Name: Branched sea slugScientific Name: Kaloplocamus ramosusCommon Name: Blue sea starScientific Name: Linckia laevigataCommon Name: Sea starScientific Name: Certonardoa semiregularisCommon Name: Leafy seadragonScientific Name: Phycodurus eques</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11853">Scuba Dive</game><game id="18434">Deep Blue Sea</game><game id="22265">Sealife Safari</game><game id="12675">Everblue 2</game><game id="22126">Everblue</game><game id="21236">Afrika</game><game id="10024">Pokémon Snap</game><game id="1849">Barbie's Ocean Discovery</game><game id="25919">Fantasy Aquarium World</game><game id="5213">Sea Monsters: A Prehistoric Adventure</game><game id="25493">Aquanaut's Holiday: Hidden Memories</game><game id="41905">Reef Shot</game><game id="23954">Endless Ocean: Blue World</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1836581-box_eocean.png</image></root>