<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4481</id><name>Antz Racing</name><description>OverviewAntz Racing is a racing game developed by RFX Interactive and published by Electronic Arts (Acclaim in the UK) for the Game Boy Color platform. Antz Racing is a licensed title based on the movie Antz.Language SelectionAntz Racing Language SelectAntz Racing supports the ability to choose from six different languages:EnglishDeutschNederlandsEspanolFrancaisItalianoDifficulty LevelsThere are three different selectable difficulty levels in Antz Racing:BeginnerMediumProGameplayAntz Racing plays much like other kart racers. The goal of each race is to pass the finish line before the other players. There are various power ups to use to try and stop the other racers.ControlsBecause this game is on the Game Boy Color the controls are very simple to use:A Button - The A button is used to accelerate.B Button - The B button is for using the currently held power up.D-Pad Up - Pressing up on the D-Pad will perform a jump.D-Pad Down - Pressing down on the D-Pad will brake.D-Pad Left/Right - Pressing either left or right on the D-Pad will steer in that direction.Select - The select button is not used in Antz RacingStart - The start button will pause the game.Game ModesThe mode select screenThere are only two different modes of play in Antz Racing.4 Seasons - The 4 Seasons mode is the campaign mode of the game. There are a series of races played in a row. The races go through the various seasons with the tracks reflecting the current season. There are passwords that are given after every completed race.Quick Race - Quick race mode is a single race. The player gets to choose the character to race as and then the game will randomly choose a level.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5309">Battle Bugs</game><game id="18026">Rock 'n Roll Racing</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/10831/475040-580033_61065_front.jpg</image></root>