<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4529</id><name>Adventures of Lolo 3</name><description>The GameAdventures of Lolo 3 is a puzzle game by HAL Corporationin 1991 for the Nintendo Entertainment System. It is the sequal to Adventures of Lolo 2and contains nearly all the same gameplay from the previous two games. Unlike the other two games, It has not been released on the Wii's virtual consoleas of yet.PlotThe game strays away from the story of the previous two games. This time King Egger has turned all the inhabitants of Eggerland to stone (except for Loloand Lala). The player has the option to switch between playing as Lolo or Lala during this game. The game ends with a final face off against the King Egger ( the Great Devil).CharactersLoloLoloThe protagonist and star. Lolo works his way through dungeons full of puzzles to save Eggerland.LalaLalaThe alternate protagonist and star. Lala acts exactly the same way as Lolo does in this gameSnakey  SnakeyThough Snakey's true intentions are unknown to the player, he is not hostile to Lolo in any way. Snakey plays an important part of many puzzles throughout the Lolo franchise. Snakey can be used to block Medusas or Gols from shooting projectiles. Snakeys can be used to stop other characters from reaching Lolo. Snakey can also be egged and ridden down rivers or be used to block character spawns.Gol  GolGol sits as a neutral character until all the heart framers in a level have been collected. After this, Gol becomes hostile and works very similarly to a Medusa. The only difference between Gol and Medusa at this point is that Medusa's projectiles can not be dodged, but Gol's projectiles are avoidable.Leeper  LeeperAn enemy that hops around and falls asleep when he touches Lolo. Leepers are mostly harmless enemies, but their main goal is to block Lolo into an area that he'll be unable to escape. Leepers are incapable of crossing long grass areas.Skull  SkullSimilarly to Gol, Skulls wake up after collecting all the heart framers in the level. Skulls do not chase after Lolo, they wander around the level and try to run into him. If they do manage to run into Lolo it's instant death.Rocky  RockyAn enemy that, like leeper, tries to trap Lolo; however, unlike Leeper, he will still chase after you if you somehow escape his trap.Alma  AlmaAn enemy that chases Lolo, like Leeper or Rocky, but if he catches Lolo, Lolo dies.MedusaMedusaAn enemy that cannot move, but will instantly kill Lolo if Lolo crosses its path. He can be blocked by a rock, block, or another enemy.Don Medusa Don MedusaAn enemy that is exactly like Medusa, except he moves. It looks like he is wearing roller skates. Don Medusa either moves from side to side or up and down. His projectiles can still be blocked by rocks, blocks, or other enemies.MobyAppears in underwater levels. Uses an attack similar to a Medusa that sucks up Lolo. It doesn't kill but it has the possiblity of getting Lolo stuck.King EggerKing Egger (The Great Devil)The main boss that has turned everyone in Eggerland to stone. King Egger is the final boss of the game and is killed in an epic final battle.ObjectsHeart FramersHeart FramersHeart Framers are scattered throughout the levels and it is Lolo's job to collect them. Once all the Heart Framers on a level have been collected, the Chest opens up. Heart Framers will occasionally contain shots. Lolo uses shots to turn enemies into eggs which he can push around to block things. Alternatively he can shoot the egg again to kill the enemy.ChestChestsChests open up when all the heart framers in the level are collected. At this point many of the enemies in the level will wake up and chase Lolo. Once Lolo collects the chest in the level, all the enemies will disappear and the exit door will open for Lolo to go through.BlocksBlocksBlocks are in most levels and are pushed around by Lolo to block Medusas or other enemies .</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6770">Chip's Challenge</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2361123-nes_adventuresoflolo3_de.jpg</image></root>