<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4561</id><name>Team Fortress Classic</name><description>Overview Team Fortress Classic is class-based multiplayer FPS developed as a mod for the original          Half-Life. There are ten      classes to choose from, each of them with varying strengths, weaknesses and abilities, although one of them is literally useless and only appears in one game mode as a target. There is a heavy emphasis on teamwork between players of different classes requiring a well-balanced offence and defence.  The game modes can revolve around capture the flag, territory capture, or protecting a VIP. Typically, players have the choice of two teams (         red and blue) with a maximum of 32 players in any one game. ClassesScout Health: 75Scout Armor: 50Weaponry: Crowbar, Single-barrel Shotgun, NailgunGrenades: Caltrops, Concussion grenadesSpeed: Very FastThe weakest but fastest class in TFC, the Scout is the ideal for players who would rather run than gun their way to victory. The Scout is armed the games’ three weakest weapons, the crowbar, a single-barrel shotgun, and a nailgun. With this kind of armament, it’s obvious why Scouts are traditionally used for flag running than actual combat. However, despite being given the least amount of health, armour, and weaponry, the Scout is still able to hold his own in the hands of a skilled player.In addition to his gun assortment, the Scout also carries two types of grenades. The first type of grenade is caltrops. A Scout who’s on the run with the enemy flag would have a higher rate of success by leaving a few of these behind along his trail. Any enemy unlucky enough to stumble upon these will be stricken with sudden inability to run or even walk. Instead they will embarrassingly waddle their way back to the nearest health pack.The second type of grenade is the  Concussion grenade, or “Conc.,” which the Medic class also possesses. Concussion grenades serve Scouts in two ways. The first, when a Concussion grenade is detonated it will disorientate any player’s vision and aim in its blast radius. This allows Scouts to simply run away while his enemy is busy trying to regain his aim and footing. The second, Concussion grenades will blast a Scout several hundred feet across a map with the use of a well-timed jump, this became known as “Conc. Jumping.” Players accomplish this by “cooking” the grenade until right before it goes off. As the grenade goes off, the player will use the blast radius of the Conc. to essentially fly in whatever direction he jumped in. Players can also throw the Conc. out into the map instead of holding the grenade until detonation. Medic Health: 100Medic  Armor: 100Weaponry: Medkit, Single-barrel Shotgun, Super Shotgun, Super NailgunGrenades: Frag grenades, Concussion grenadesSpeed: FastOriginally designed as a support class, the Medic quickly became the offensive class of choice for high-level players. Coupled with the class’ generous health, armour, and hefty weaponry, the medic is a class to be reckoned with. The Medic class is both TFC’s second fastest class and also one of the most versatile. The Medic comes armed with a Medkit, a Super Nailgun, a single-barrel shotgun and Super Shotgun. The Medkit is a class specific weapon to the Medic and has two different uses. Primarily, the Medkit is used to provide on-the-fly first aid to damaged teammates. With one click, teammates were charged back to full health regardless of how much damage they had originally suffered. Also, if the Medkit was used on a teammate for a longer period of time, that teammate would gain a health boost above  their normal class' HP. However, as soon as the teammate was no longer being charged up by a Medkit, their HP would gradually fall back down to normal levels.The second use of the Medkit is much more devious. When used against enemy opponents, the Medic would be able to spread an infection, inflicting damage over time on his opponent. Also, if the enemy opponent went near any of their own teammates, they would also be stricken with the infection and so on. This tactic not only annoyed the enemy team, but also weakened them because of their ever constant failing health.Like the Scout, the Medic possesses Concussion grenades, giving them the same Conc. Jumping abilities as the Scout. However, the Medic holds several advantages over the Scout class. In addition to the class’ beefier weapons set, the Medic also possesses fragmentation (frag) grenades. Frag grenades inflict large amounts of damage when used effectively. The Medic’s grenades, coupled with the Medic’s speed and weaponry, players quickly understood why the Medic was so effective on offence.Demoman Health: 90Demoman   Armor: 120Weaponry: Crowbar, Single-barrel Shotgun, Grenade Launcher, Pipebomb LauncherGrenades: Frag grenades, MIRV grenadesSpeed: MediumThe Demoman, short for Demolitions Expert, is an expert in the field of reducing his enemies to a substance resembling chunky salsa. The Demoman is armed to the teeth with explosives including a grenade launcher, a pipebomb launcher, and both frag and MIRV grenades. Because of this class’ armament, the Demoman, like the Soldier class, could be used effectively both on offense or defense.  On defense, a Demoman’s main role was to plant pipebombs either along choke points, their team’s flag point in Capture the Flag or whatever point the enemy team may have managed to get his team’s flag to. A Demoman would watch from afar and detonate the bombs whenever an enemy happened to cross his trap. Piping” choke points was an extremely effective tactic considering on most TFC maps, there would only be 2-3 entrances. A single skilled Demoman could hold one entrance by himself for an extended amount of time. Piping flag points was also essential because due to the fact that enemies are forced to pick up the flag to stop it from resetting.  On offense, a Demoman could cause huge headaches for the enemy team. With both pipebomb and grenade launchers and grenades, a Demoman’s main role was to “spam” the enemy to non-existence.  The Demoman could also utilize a “pipe-jump.” This basically consisted of a Demoman laying down 2-3 pipebombs, depending on how far and how high they wanted to go, onto the map. Then, using a timed jump, they would detonate the pipebombs and launch themselves to whatever point they were aiming for. This was extremely useful on CTF maps if a Demoman on offensive was carrying the enemy flag and wanted a quick escape. This tactic could also be used to capture points on Attack/Defend maps such as Dustbowl. If a server had friendly fire off (which most did) a Demoman could use this same tactic to launch his teammates to capture points. The one special ability the Demoman class had was to lay down what was called a “Detpack” or Detonation Pack. The Detpack was essentially a very large bomb that would go off in the time specified by the player. The player could set the Detpack to go off in either 5, 20, or 50 seconds. When the Detpack went off, it killed or destroyed everything within a sizable radius. With friendly fire off, it would simply launch teammates into the sky. The Detpack could also be used on a small number of Attack/Defend maps to blow new entrances for the attacking team to attack from. The original Demoman character model featured an eye-patch and a lit cigarette in the model’s mouth. The eye-patch aspect of the model was carried over to the Team Fortress 2 Demoman model, while the lit cigarette found its way to the Team Fortress 2 Spy model.   Engineer Health: 80Engineer  Armor: 50Weaponry: Wrench, Rail Gun, Super ShotgunGrenades: Frag grenades, EMP grenadesSpeed: MediumThe Engineer is easily the most specialized class in Team Fortress Classic considering the class’ various building abilities. The Engineer could build a Sentry Gun (SG), a Dispenser for ammunition, and later with the TFC 1.5 patch, Teleporters. An Engineer was mainly considered to be a defense-based class considering his ability to build SGs and low health. A player who used the Engineer class on offense was often no more than a slight annoyance to the other team.  The Engineer is the only class that carries the EMP or Electro-Magnetic-Pulse grenade. What the EMP did was essentially blow up any ammunition that happened to be in its blast radius when it went off. The EMP was extremely effective on Attack/Defend chokepoints where dead enemy ammo packs would build up. An Engineer would throw an EMP into the chokepoint and often times kill 5-6 enemies because of the amount of ammunition on the ground. EMPs were also effective to use against classes who carried large amounts of ammo themselves, mainly HW Guys and Pyros.  The Engineer is also the only class to carry the Rail Gun. However, this was no Quake Rail Gun. The TFC Engineer’s Rail Gun was the smaller, less satisfying, less-endowed version of the Quake Rail Gun. While the Rail Gun could do large amounts of damage, the slow rate of fire often made it a last-ditch effort, even behind the Engineer’s wrench.Sentry Gun (SG)An Engineer’s best friend and weapon was nothing in his inventory, it was his SG. A well-placed SG coupled with a skilled Engineer would become the bane of many opposing enemies’ existence.  The SG had three separate levels of upgrade, with each level requiring the Engineer to hit the SG with his wrench with 200 “ammo.”  A Level 1 SG was easy to take out and fired at a semi-automatic pace. This type of SG would prove to be no match for virtually any class. Most skilled players would be able to take out a Level 1 SG without dying no matter what class they may be using. A Level 2 SG was a huge upgrade over a Level 1. The SG became a fully-automatic turret and could easily stop several enemies attacking at once. The Level 2 SG in-game model also featured a “shark-face” on the barrel.  A Level 3 SG proved to be a huge obstacle for any skill level of player. This type of SG not only featured fully-automatic fire, but also fired rockets at its enemies. Needless to say, a Level 3 SG could make short work of unsuspecting enemies unaware of its presence. Due to the limitations of the engine, an SG would block all incoming attacks if the player was crouched behind it. Therefore it was possible to keep the SG alive during a sustained attack by crouching behind it and continually hitting it with the engineer's wrench.  This would work for as long as the engineer had metal to repair the SG with. Again, due to the engine, grenades which landed directly under the tripod of the SG would have an enhanced explosive effect, allowing a level three SG to be taken down with one grenade, and with the explosion of both the grenade and SG any unsuspecting engineer would also be likely to be taken out in the blast. Dispenser The SG was not the only “weapon” per se an Engineer could build. In addition to dispensing ammunition to teammates and automatically refilling itself, an Engineer could use a Dispenser as basically a remote mine. Whenever an enemy came across your Dispenser, the game would notify you that “Enemies are using your Dispenser!” If the player was quick enough, they could bring up the build menu and hit the “Detonate Dispenser” key to blow the enemy apart. The explosion of the Dispenser depended on the amount of ammunition that was in it at the time of explosion. The more ammo there was, the bigger the boom. Skilled players learned that this was a valuable asset and would bind a key on their keyboard to function as their “Detonate Dispenser” key. If the player was unsuccessful in killing the enemy with the explosion, they would at least know the whereabouts of the incoming enemy. Teleporters Teleporters were a new addition to Team Fortress Classic with the TFC 1.5 patch in June 2000. Engineers could now build a teleporter entrance and exit for himself and teammates to get around maps quickly. This would prove invaluable in several situations, especially on Attack/Defend maps. Teleporters would allow recently respawned Engineers to quickly teleport back to their SGs. It would also enable teammates to quickly get back to the front lines and get back on defense.  Players who used their Engineer’s teleporters would leave a “residue trail” behind them. This would give enemies a clue as to where the other teams’ teleporters were located.   Heavy Weapons Guy Health: 100Heavy Weapons Guy  Armor: 300  Weaponry: Crowbar, AC (Assault-Cannon), Single-barrel Shotgun Super Shotgun  Grenades: Frag grenades, MIRV grenades  Speed: Very SlowLovingly known as the “Fatty” class, the HW was an army unto himself. With his high health and armor, and 200-bullet capacity AC, the HW was not a class players wanted to run into. The HW class is mainly considered to be a defense based class. The HW in the hands of a skilled player, like the Demoman, is able to hold entire chokepoints on maps by himself. Because the AC does more and more damage as enemies get closer, a skilled HW would normally position himself in such a way that it would force enemies to come to him. If the enemy wanted to get by, this would enable him to deal loads of damage as the enemy attempts to run by.  Also in TFC when firing the AC, the HW’s speed wasn't slowed down. This was changed in Team Fortress 2, due mainly to complaints that the TFC version of the HW was overpowered.  In advanced play, it was not uncommon to see players who used the HW jumping up and down constantly as they fired their AC. What this did was essentially allow them to cover more area with their bullets while not having to move their cursor around, thus allowing them to fixate on a single point with their mouse. Advanced players would also constantly keep their AC “spinning.” There is a slight warm-up period for the AC to fire up before the player could actually start firing bullets. Players would do this by constantly clicking and slightly holding their mouse button down to get the AC spinning. This pre-spinning of the AC allowed the HW to fire more quickly upon their enemies. This pre-spinning tactic was actually implemented as a gameplay aspect in Team Fortress 2. HWs in TF2 could hold the right-click on their mouse to keep the AC spinning in anticipation of incoming enemies.   Pyro Health: 100Pyro Armor: 150Weaponry: Crowbar, Single-barrel Shotgun, Flamethrower, Incendiary Cannon (IC)Grenades: Frag grenades, Napalm grenadesSpeed: MediumWidely considered to be the coolest, yet lamest class in all of TFC, the Pyro was disappointingly underpowered. The Pyro is the second weakest class behind the Scout. This is sad considering the Pyro has one huge advantage going for him over the Scout and that is his use of fire. Fire, however, does hardly any damage to enemies in the world of TFC.  The Pyro was rarely used on either offence or defence. Players who used the Pyro were most likely new to the game or were veterans looking for a way to grief players. The Flamethrower had the ability to burn and light enemies on fire, eating away at their health until the fire was extinguished or until they reached a Medic or health pack. The flames would also hamper the enemy’s vision. However, the Flamethrower did such little damage that players were more annoyed than scared of a crazed Pyro running straight at them firing his Flamethrower.  The Incendiary Cannon (IC) was basically a weaker, slower and less threatening version of the Soldier’s Rocket Launcher. The IC could only hold 20 rockets at a time and even with a direct hit, did not do much damage. It did however, do more damage than a Flamethrower. Also like the Flamethrower, enemies within the IC’s splash damage radius were lit on fire. However, the IC’s rockets moved so slowly, enemies could easily move out of the way of the rocket. The one weapon that the Pyro did have going for him were his Napalm grenades. These grenades would ignite a certain radius of land on fire for a certain amount of time. The Napalm grenade was actually the Pyro’s most damaging weapon in his arsenal outside of the Frag grenades. The Pyro could often at least help slow down an enemy’s assault because enemies did not wish to suffer through the Napalm and suffer the annoyances of being on fire. The Pyro class received a huge overhaul in the switch over to Team Fortress 2. The Pyro became a legitimate class in terms of both offense and defense. However, a major complaint, at least in the as-of-yet un-patched Xbox 360 version of TF2 is that the Flamethrower is overpowered. A Pyro equipped with a Flamethrower could easily stop and kill an entire enemy team by simply strafing and spamming his Flamethrower.  Spy Health: 90Spy Armor: 100Weaponry: Knife, Tranquilizer Pistol, Super Shotgun, Nail Gun, Single-Barrel ShotgunGrenades: Frag Grenades, Hallucination GrenadesSpeed: MediumThe Spy class was for players who wanted to sprinkle a little bit of stealth into their shooters. This class was almost played exclusively for offensive purposes. If you ever encountered a Spy playing defense, you were most likely playing in a newbie-friendly public server. Armed with the ability to feign death, disguise as enemies and instantly-kill opponents with a single backstab with their knife, skilled spies were a nightmare to deal with.  The Spy class’ various abilities gave the player a much more open type of game play. Because players could feign death, enemies would often mistake the “dead” spy as another corpse on the battlefield. Little did they know that as soon as they turned their back, the spy would come back to life and the enemy would end up with a knife in their back. The ability to feign death was removed in the move to Team Fortress 2 (Though somewhat returned with the new unlock able item: The Dead Ringer). Instead, in TF2 the Spy class is now afforded the ability to cloak themselves invisible for several seconds to sneak behind enemy lines.  With the Spy’s ability to disguise as enemy classes, this gave players a chance to fool their enemies into thinking that the spy was simply another teammate. This could afford the Spy to do several things. They could either let the enemy pass and sneak by or of course stab the enemy in the back for an instant kill. Another big perk when disguised as the enemy is that enemy SGs would treat you as a normal teammate, thus allowing you to sneak by them unharmed.  The Spy also had the Tranquilizer Pistol and Hallucination Grenades in his arsenal. The Tranquilizer Pistol lives up to its name and would tranquilize enemies. When hit by a tranquilizer, the enemy would find themselves walking extremely slowly. This gave Spies a chance to sneak up on the docile enemy and go for a back stab. Hallucination Grenades were basically giant pills that would cause great amounts of damage if enemies found themselves stuck in the hallucinogenic cloud that the grenade spewed out. An enemy hallucinated several things including the game warning the player was either on fire, running out of air, or was getting shot from multiple sides even though these warnings of course were only hallucinations.  Sniper Health: 90Sniper Armor: 50 Weaponry: Crowbar, Sniper Rifle, Automatic Rifle, NailgunGrenades: Frag GrenadesSpeed: MediumIn the hands of a skilled player, the Sniper was probably the worst thing an enemy could see across the battlefield.  TFC’s Sniper class played slightly different from perhaps other Sniper-esque classes in the shooter genre. In TFC, each shot that came from the Sniper Rifle had to be charged. The longer the charge, the more damage the shot caused. In fact, with a full charge, Snipers could take out every single class except one, the Heavy, with a single shot. Fully charged shots could also take out Sentry Guns, Dispensers and Teleporters. Considering that getting a full charge only took a few seconds, you can now understand why skilled Snipers were so deadly. Also, if a Sniper managed to get a headshot, a fully charged bullet was no longer necessary as headshots did more damage. Snipers could also charge and fire their shots without having to scope in and disrupt their field of vision. This allowed them to scout the entire field before zooming in and hitting their target.  This gameplay aspect however was changed in the move to Team Fortress 2 as it was deemed too powerful. Snipers in TF2 now must scope in with their rifle before they are able to charge a shot. Also, if Snipers in TF2 scope out, they lose their charge. This was put in to help balance the class and the game.  Snipers were effective on both sides of the ball. A skilled offensive Sniper was extremely valuable to teams, predominantly while playing Attack/Defend maps. Defensive Snipers could almost keep an entire team at bay because of their long-range and high damage capabilities. However, in close range combat, Snipers were often mincemeat due to their low armor and lack of useful weapons up close. However, again skilled Snipers could hold their own using a series of quick-charge shots to take out close quarter enemies.  Soldier Health: 100   Soldier Armor: 200 Weaponry: Crowbar, Single-barrel Shotgun, Super Shotgun, Rocket LauncherGrenades: Frag Grenades, Nail GrenadesSpeed: SlowThe Soldier is the default class to use if you don’t know if you want to play offence or defence; the class is well suited for both. The Soldier comes armed with both the Rocket Launcher and Super Shotgun, probably the most potent weapon combination in the game. Players would often use their Rocket Launcher to deal significant damage to enemies before switching to their Super Shotgun to finish them off. The Soldier also has both high armor and high health stats, which both help while playing offence or defence.  The Rocket Launcher also affords the Soldier class a multitude of options while attacking. The weapon allows the Soldier to take out enemy defenses, such as Sentry Guns, from long range without being detected by the SG. Soldiers can also perform Rocket Jumps, allowing them to get to areas of the enemy base unreachable by other classes. Also, by Rocket Jumping to different enemy base entrances gave the Soldier the element of surprise.  While playing defense, the Soldier is extremely capable of holding an entire entrance by himself. The Rocket Launcher in TFC launched and juggled enemies much more effectively than what you see now in Team Fortress 2. Enemies who were unfortunate enough to find themselves caught in a Soldier’s rocket juggle were as good as dead. Soldiers could also fire rockets to simply launch enemies out of position.  The Soldier class is also the only class to have the Nail Grenade in their arsenal. This grenade, which thrown out, would float slightly above the ground and begin firing nails in a circular fashion. Nail Grenades were extremely effective in taking out enemy SG placements and large groups of enemies.  Civilian Health: 50Civilian Armor: NoneWeaponry: CrowbarGrenades: NoneSpeed: MediumThe Civilian class, also known as the "Prez", has low health, an average speed, and is armed only with a melee weapon, essentially making the randomly-selected player stuck with the role totally helpless. Fortunately, the Civilian is only playable on Assassination maps, where the Civilian's team must protect them from the other team, who seek to kill the Civilian at all costs. The Civilian character model was a slightly overweight man with a thin moustache wearing a blue suit with team-coloured armbands, and carrying an umbrella. Despite the model carrying an umbrella, the user playing as the Civilian would still see a crowbar, due to the relatively primitive game design. The Civilian is the only class not to make an appearance in    Team Fortress 2; although it was planned at one point, as seen from certain files within the game's code, the closest the Civilian has come to an actual appearance is in the promotional "Meet the Sniper" video, in which the Sniper has a bobblehead figure in his van in the original Civilian's image. Game TypesCapture the Flag (CTF) Capture the flag in TFC was standard fare. Two teams, usually red and blue, would fight to the death trying to get the most flag captures in a single game.Reverse Capture the Flag Reverse Capture the Flag was a slightly different take on traditional CTF. Instead of grabbing the enemy flag and returning it to your base, you had to bring your flag to the enemy base to score points. This gave the game a slightly different feel because when trying to bring your flag to the enemy base, you would be constantly bombarded by enemies because well... you're going to the enemy base. Assassination On Assassination maps, there would be three teams instead of two; the Assassins, who were all Snipers, the Bodyguards which consisted of Heavys, Medics and Soldiers, and the Civilian (The Prez.) On most Assassination maps, there could only ever be 5 Assassins and 1 Prez at a time. Depending on the server size, the rest of the player slots were filled by Bodyguards. The Assassins' goal was to kill the Prez while the Bodyguards' was to protect him. In order for the Bodyguards to score a point, they would have to escort the Prez to a specified point on the map while Assassins just had to kill the Prez any way they could.Control PointsThe Control Points game type were what you would expect. Teams would fight over different points on the map that would give them strategic advantages, such as spawn points closer to enemy territory, allowing players to keep the frontline stocked. A variation of the control point game type was seen in the map Canalzone2. In this map, teams would still fight over points, however in order to capture the point your team had to bring your team's flag to the point to capture it. In Canalzone2 specifically, flag carriers would be slowed down substantially. This was very different from other control point maps, such as Warpath, where players simply had to touch the control point to capture it for their team. This was changed in Team Fortress 2. In TF2, teams have to remain on a control point long enough to capture it without having enemies disrupt the capture time. Over time, the capture time would also decrease if no other teammates could reach the control point to keep the capture time moving.Attack/DefendAttack/Defend maps were likely the most second popular game type due to the popularity of the map Dustbowl. In most Attack/Defend maps, the Blue team started out as Attackers while the Reds played as Defenders. In Attack/Defend maps, there would be three different capture points. With each successive capture, the Attacking team would respawn in closer and closer to the enemy. Dustbowl itself was comprised of three smaller maps, each with their own capture point. When the Attacking team captured the first point, both teams would respawn into the second capture point area and so on until the third and final capture point. Also in all Attack/Defend maps, there would be a "set-up" period that allowed the Defenders to set up their defenses before having to face the advancement from the attackers. In some Attack/Defend maps, Attackers were required to bring their team's flag to a point in order to capture it and advance.  System Requirements Minimum: 500 mhz processor, 96mb ram, 16mb video card, Windows 2000/XP, Mouse, Keyboard, Internet ConnectionRecommended: 800 mhz processor, 128mb ram, 32mb  video card, Windows 2000/XP, Mouse, Keyboard, Internet Connection </description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18162">Team Fortress 2</game><game id="18883">Enemy Territory: Quake Wars</game><game id="11339">Counter-Strike: Source</game><game id="17729">The Orange Box</game><game id="21218">Black Powder | Red Earth</game><game id="22609">Soldier Front</game><game id="17491">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six 3: Black Arrow</game><game id="7747">John Romero's Daikatana</game><game id="21912">Planetside: Core Combat</game><game id="11254">Savage 2: A Tortured Soul</game><game id="11663">Half-Life: Counter-Strike</game><game id="11940">No One Lives Forever 2: A Spy in H.A.R.M.'s Way</game><game id="25740">Eliminate</game><game id="30740">Gang Garrison 2</game><game id="35307">Gotham City Impostors</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14741/1047035-team_fortress_classic_box.jpg</image></root>