<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4618</id><name>Ratchet &amp; Clank: Going Commando</name><description>OverviewRatchet and Clank going Commando!Ratchet  Clank: Going Commando is the second game of the Ratchet  Clank series, the game was developed by Insomniac Games and published by Sony Computer Entertainment for the PlayStation 2 in 2003. The story of Going Commando takes place a year after Ratchet and Clank first save the Solana Galaxy from Ultimate Supreme Executive Chairman Drek. now both Ratchet and Clank are hired by the Megacorp Company to find a blue-fuzzball creature that was stolen from the company's lab. As Ratchet finds out about the thief's plans, he learns that the creature called the "Protopet" is dangerous monster that can destroyed the whole Bogan Galaxy, now Ratchet and Clank must save the galaxy once again.StoryAfter the events of first Ratchet  Clank game, where they defeated Ultimate Supreme Executive Chairman Drek, they became galactic celebrities. Everything was fine for nearly a year. Both Ratchet and Clank appeared in an interview for Behind the Hero, a HoloVision show in the game, and were teleported to the Bogon Galaxy by Abercrombie Fizzwidget, the founder and CEO of Megacorp. It appeared that a mysterious masked mastermind had stolen a valuable experiment, a cute blue fuzzball.LocationsGoing Commando takes place in the Bogon Galaxy, a neighboring galaxy to Solana. The galaxy's leading weapon manufacturing company is Megacorp, based on planet Yeedil and headed by the CEO Abercrombie Fizzwidget.WeaponsBlitz GunBomb GloveBouncerChopperClank ZapperDecoy GloveGravity BombHoverbomb GunLancerLava GunMinirocket TubeMiniturret GlovePlasma CoilPulse RifleRYNO IISeeker GunSheepinatorShield ChargerSpiderbot GloveSynthenoidTesla ClawVisibomb GunWalloperZodiacGadgetsInformationAppearanceSwingshot In Clank's Apartment on Endako.SwingshotDynamo The entrance to Megacorp Store on Oozla.DynamoElectrolyzer By winning a match in a Megacorp Games on Maktar Nebula.ElectrolyzerHypnomatic By finding the threes parts and paying it for 10,000 bolts from the Hypnotist on Damisel.HypnomaticInfiltrator By winning a match in a Megacorp Games on Joba.Need ImageThermanator By purchasing from Gadgetron dealer for 1,000 bolts on Barlow.ThermanatorTractor Beam By purchasing from Tractor Beam scientist for 1,000 bolts on Oozla.Tractor BeamGlider Go through the facility in Tabora.GliderLevitator By purchasing from Shady Salesman Billy for 20,000 bolts on Joba.LevitatorCharge Boots By winning the HoverBike Race in Job.Charge BootsGravity Boots By winning another match on Megacorp Games in Joba.Gravity BootsGrind Boots In Clank's Apartment on Endako.Grind BootsArmorInformationDamage ReductionCostAvailable inAppearanceCommando Suit0%N/AAranosCommando SuitTetrafiberThe Tetrafiber Armor is the first upgrade armor for the Commando Suit, the armor is a blue color armor that used Megacorp's patented titanium technology.33%25,000 boltsDobboTetrafiber ArmorDuraplate Armor50%100,000 boltsBoldanElectrosteel66%250,000 boltsSnivelakCarbonox Armor90%1,000,000 boltsGrelbinCarbonox Armor</description><genres><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10384">Jak II</game><game id="15353">Sly Cooper and the Thievius Raccoonus</game><game id="2931">Super Mario 64</game><game id="15835">Beyond Good &amp; Evil</game><game id="3438">MediEvil II</game><game id="4228">Haven: Call of the King</game><game id="11407">Vexx</game><game id="15573">Sly 2: Band of Thieves</game><game id="1563">Spyro 2: Ripto's Rage</game><game id="6134">The Legend of Spyro: The Eternal Night</game><game id="14258">MediEvil Resurrection</game><game id="8006">Metal Arms: Glitch in the System</game><game id="3457">MediEvil</game><game id="7804">Rocket: Robot on Wheels</game><game id="20330">Gex 3: Deep Cover Gecko</game><game id="15991">Chameleon Twist 2</game><game id="14623">Jak and Daxter: The Precursor Legacy</game><game id="9669">Jak 3</game><game id="14604">Daxter</game><game id="18376">Looney Tunes Back in Action</game><game id="2727">Star Fox Assault</game><game id="21000">Secret Agent Clank</game><game id="1653">Ninja Gaiden</game><game id="1850">Ninja Gaiden III: The Ancient Ship of Doom</game><game id="7212">Klonoa 2: Lunatea's Veil</game><game id="14582">Legend of Kay</game><game id="7301">Toy Story 2: Buzz Lightyear to the Rescue!</game><game id="21115">Ratchet &amp; Clank Future: Quest for Booty</game><game id="10983">Kingdom Hearts</game><game id="24969">Tokobot Plus: Mysteries of the Karakuri</game><game id="25720">Jak and Daxter: The Lost Frontier</game><game id="19388">Ape Escape 3</game><game id="11470">Scaler</game><game id="30746">Ruff Trigger: The Vanocore Conspiracy</game><game id="35545">Fuse</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1832158-box_racgc.png</image></root>