<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4635</id><name>Twisted Metal III</name><description>OverviewTwisted Metal III is the third game in the Twisted Metal franchise. Players battle it out with a variety of weapons over an assortment of maps that spans across the globe.StorylineFlower Power SpecialTwisted Metal III takes place two years after the events of Twisted Metal 2 and is a continuation of the previous game’s story. A mysterious man that goes by the name of Calypso returns with his Twisted Metal tournament in which the winner is granted one wish. Calypso tends to twist the winner's wish, leaving them with an unfortunate demise.GameplayThumper goes Boom!In this tournament, players are to engage in battle with opponents using various ballistic projectiles such as rockets. Players are also able to obtain various pick-ups strewn across the map to use to their advantage. The game sets down a survival of the fittest objective, in which the last man standing wins. Players can choose to either play against bots in a series of matches in story mode, or battle up to four friends in a split screen versus mode.DevelopmentInstead of being developed by Single Trac, the developer for the first two games, or Incog Inc, the developers of Black and Head On, Twisted Metal 3 was developed by Sony's in-house studio, 989 Studios, along with Twisted Metal 4. Because of this, most hardcore Twisted Metal fans don't see Twisted Metal 3 or 4 as true Twisted Metal games.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7468">Vigilante 8: 2nd Offense</game><game id="13200">Vigilante 8</game><game id="10616">Streets of SimCity</game><game id="4315">WWE Crush Hour</game><game id="14204">Mashed: Drive to Survive</game><game id="23277">Vigilante 8 Arcade</game><game id="9733">RoadKill</game><game id="23527">Hardware 2</game><game id="16728">Powerslide</game><game id="25512">Clutch</game><game id="23930">Wild Metal</game><game id="5917">Cyber Sled</game><game id="18499">Motor Mayhem</game><game id="12975">Super Chase H.Q.</game><game id="16473">Breakneck</game><game id="37266">Smash 'n' Survive</game><game id="28960">Metal Drift</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2011581-box_tmetal3.png</image></root>