<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4659</id><name>NFL 2K</name><description>OverviewThe first "2K" game released, NFL 2K was introduced by Sega for the Dreamcast when EA Sports decided not to publish its Madden NFL series on the new system. The game's cover athlete was Minnesota Vikings wide receivers Randy MossGameplayNFL 2K featured the popular Maximum Passing mechanic, allowing players to lead receivers with their passes. The controls, like other 2K sports games that came after, were simple and easy to pick up and play. The Dreamcast also allowed for realistic player and ball physics; passes could be tipped at the line and tackles had to account for player weight. For a launch title, NFL 2K was surprisingly full featured with game modes including;PracticeTournamentSeasonFantasy DraftExhibitionCreate-a-PlayerPlayoffsAudioCommentary featured the fictional team of Dan Stevens and Peter O'Keefe voiced by Terry McGovern and Jay Styne respectively. Both would go on to provide their voices for all seven 2K football game, the last being the unlicensed All-Pro Football 2K8. Critics praised McGovern and Styne's commentary as a great alternative to sports video games that featured real commentary teams.FeaturesOver 1,500 Motion-captured movesPhysics-based 3D collisionsVMU play callingPlayer-specific detailThe most complete voice-over ever in a sports video gameAll 31 stadiums accurately modeled in 3DDetailed stat tracking, player trading, team-specific playbooks, fantasy draft, play editor and more1-4 playersVMU compatible: 185 blocksJump Pack compatible</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="21">Football</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8480">All-Pro Football 2K8</game><game id="21413">Madden NFL 08</game><game id="21713">NFL Fever 2003</game><game id="20848">NCAA Football 09</game><game id="7848">NFL GameDay '99</game><game id="2356">NFL GameDay 2001</game><game id="9640">NFL GameDay 2000</game><game id="98">John Elway's Quarterback</game><game id="8073">NFL Sports Talk Football '93 Starring Joe Montana</game><game id="16405">NFL GameDay 2003</game><game id="26470">NFL Fever 2000</game><game id="29744">Madden NFL 11</game><game id="5898">Jimmy Johnson's VR Football '98</game><game id="33906">Madden NFL 12</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8272/859193-198138_16492_front.jpg</image></root>