<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4660</id><name>Mario Party 4</name><description>OverviewThe game's title screen with the entire crew. Mario Party 4 is the fourth game in the  Mario Party franchise. It is the first installment for the Nintendo GameCube, as well. The game was released on October 21, 2002 in North America, on November 8, 2002 in Japan, and on November 29, 2002 in PAL regions. Mario Party 4 was developed by  Hudson Soft and published by  Nintendo. The game is largely similar to previous installments in the franchise, leading to complaints from critics and fans for lack of originality. Despite this, the game was praised for its simplistic-but-fun minigames, graphical improvement, and whimsical music. Mario Party 4 holds a 74% average rating on Game Rankings and a 70% average rating on Metacritic.The plot of the game involves several characters from the game finding a "Party Cube," which can be used to create a party and game boards revolving around their dreams.  Bowser, naturally, decides to be the rotten apple by spoiling everything with his own game board.GameplayAn example of a minigame.Mario Party 4 uses the same traditional gameplay as the three previous games in the franchise. The game takes place on a variety of boards, on which an individual "board game" takes place. Characters from the Mario franchise traverse these boards, with goals depending on what board and mode it is. In the single-player story mode, one player plays against several computer-controlled opponents, while in the multiplayer mode, several players play against one another. Squares on the board do different effects, such as triggering a minigame, giving coins, opening a shop, or triggering the opportunity to gain a star (the goal of the game). There are only a few other items in the game, mostly available for purchase, but Mini and Mega Mushrooms can be gained by stepping on the right square.There are several different types of minigames in Mario Party 4. Each minigame awards coins for the player, which can be saved and then used to purchase a star. The types of minigames are four player minigames, one versus three minigames, two versus two minigames, battle minigames, Bowser minigames, story minigames, and Extra Room minigames. Four player, one versus three, and two versus two are all played with the corresponding amount of players. Battle minigames are where the players all contribute to an award "pot," of which the winner gets a large percentage. Bowser minigames are encountered towards the end of the game, while story minigames are only available during the single-player mode. Extra Room minigames can be accessed in the Extra Room.One of the 6 gameboards in Mario Party 4, Bowser's Gnarly Party. There are six boards and eight playable characters in the game. The playable characters are  Mario,  Luigi,  Yoshi,  Princess Peach,  Wario,  Donkey Kong (his last appearance as a playable character, as he begins running the Donkey Kong minigames in  Mario Party 5),  Princess Daisy, and  Waluigi. Princess Daisy and Waluigi were previously only available in certain areas, so they are technically new additions. The six boards are Toad's Midway Madness, Koopa's Seaside Soiree, Goomba's Greedy Gala, Boo's Haunted Bash, Shy Guy's Jungle Jam, and Bowser's Gnarly Party. Each of these boards has a specific theme, with features reflecting on the setting of the board (such as a roulette in the casino board). Various locales of interest on the board include Events (which are scattered about the board), Lottery Shops (essentially gambling coins ), and Boo Houses (the Boo can be paid to steal from other players). Most other spaces are either red or blue (which subtract or add coins).MinigamesFour player minigames Avalanche!Bob-omb BreakersBooksquirmDominationLong Claw of the LawManta Rings Mario MedleyMario SpeedwagonsMr. Blizzard's BrigadeParatrooper PlungePhoto FinishSlime TimeStamp Out!Take a BreatherThree ThrowToad's Quick Draw One versus three minigamesBlame it on the CraneCandlelight FlightFish n' DripsGOOOOOOOAL!! Hide and Go BOOM!Hop or PopMakin' WavesMoney BeltsTree Stomp Two versus two minigamesCheep Cheep SweepCliffhangersDungeon DuosOrder UpPair-a-SailingReverse-a-BombRight Oar Left?Team Treasure TrekThe Great Deflate Battle minigames Bowser's Bigger BlastButterfly BlitzChain Chomp FeverPaths of PerilRumble FishingTrace Race Other mini-gamesMega Board MayhemMini Board Mad-Dash Panels Of DoomBowser WrestlingThe Final Battle! Archaeologuess Bowser BopGoomba's Chip FlipKareening KoopasMystic Match 'Em BooksquirmPanel PanicBarrel BaronBob-omb X-ingDoors of DoomGoomba StompJigsaw JittersMushroom MedicBeach Volley Folley  Balloon of DoomDarts of DoomFruits of Doom </description><genres><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21617">Rayman: Raving Rabbids</game><game id="13685">WarioWare: Smooth Moves</game><game id="8753">Bomberman Land Touch!</game><game id="15952">Crash Bash</game><game id="2819">Sonic Shuffle</game><game id="23732">Bomberman Land Touch! 2</game><game id="16650">Fuzion Frenzy</game><game id="404">Disney's Party</game><game id="7669">Cartoon Network Block Party</game><game id="17156">My Street</game><game id="31210">Wii Party</game><game id="33914">Doraemon Wii: Himitsu Douguou Ketteisen!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2129488-box_mparty4.png</image></root>