<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4719</id><name>Alien Breed</name><description>While gameplay follows a similar tradition to games such as Gauntlet, this game is known for it's unique dark atmosphere and futuristic sci-fi setting.Your survival in Alien Breed depends on your health, lives, ammo, credits and keys. Most of these can be replenished at one of the computer stations scattered throughout each level. The player can also purchase various types of guns from these computers.Alien Breed is the first game in the Alien Breed franchise. An enhanced port with updated graphics and new levels was released on PlayStation Mobile in November 2012. A PSN version of the game for PS3 and Vita is due out in February 2013, featuring cross platform online co-op and cloud saves.In 1992 an updated version was released on the Amiga, titled Alien Breed: Special Edition '92, including the Tower Assault expansion, plus many other new levels. All the original levels were also reworked, drastically changing the pacing from having the player shoot their way through alien hordes to a much slower paced and methodical style where the alien encounters were rarer and much more dangerous. The Special Edition '92 content was not included in the 1993 PC port (re-released in 2012 on GOG), but is available as optional modes in the PlayStation 3 and Vita versions released in 2013.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9203">Shadowgrounds</game><game id="17722">Shadowgrounds Survivor</game><game id="8594">Gauntlet</game><game id="646">Laser Squad</game><game id="19858">Paradroid</game><game id="739">Captain Fizz Meets the Blaster-Trons</game><game id="7227">Abuse</game><game id="3819">Zombie Shooter</game><game id="16238">Alien Shooter 2</game><game id="12245">Gauntlet Legends</game><game id="648">Gauntlet II</game><game id="2702">Gauntlet III: The Final Quest</game><game id="16449">Gauntlet: Seven Sorrows</game><game id="13991">Gauntlet: Dark Legacy</game><game id="1206">Gauntlet 4</game><game id="13636">Gauntlet: The Third Encounter</game><game id="11192">Gauntlet: The Deeper Dungeons</game><game id="29464">Dysnomia</game><game id="948">The Chaos Engine</game><game id="12025">Snipes</game><game id="31207">Murky Horizon</game><game id="12237">Cytron</game><game id="14180">Project Firestart</game><game id="37389">Pineapple Smash Crew</game><game id="26940">Larva Mortus</game><game id="32098">Alien Swarm</game><game id="15574">Machine Hunter</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5150/1220677-alienbreed.jpg</image></root>