<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4750</id><name>Company of Heroes: Opposing Fronts</name><description>Overview     Company of Heroes: Opposing Fronts is a stand-alone expansion pack for                                                                                                          Company of Heroes. It was developed by                                                                                                         Relic Entertainment and published by                                                        THQ. Opposing Fronts adds two entire new armies to the game: The British and the Panzer Elite as well as two new full length campaigns, The Liberation of Caen and Operation: Market Garden - The original Company of Heroes only had one full length campaign.  Dynamic Environmental Effects SystemThe expansion added a Dynamic Weather Effects system to the game, which  consists primarily of real time weather effects and day-to-night time  transitions. In addition to these enhancements, certain birds sing at  various times of the day and during specific weather patterns.  CompatabilityCompany of Heroes: Opposing Fronts is a stand-alone expansion, meaning that you don't need the original Company of Heroes to play this game, this also mean that you can't play the campaign from the first game or as the armies from that game, the American and Wehrmacht, however, you can still play multiplayer against or with these factions as either a team-mate or an enemy.The British 2nd Army        The British are one of the two new factions in Company of Heroes: Opposing Fronts. They characterize themselves by being a very defensive faction with the ability to construct emplacements, defensive structures, a defensive doctrine and lots of artillery. The aforementioned is currently a common misconception held by many players. Not only is company of heroes decidedly not a defensive game, in recent patches British emplacements received a significant Nerf.  Additionally at most the British have access to 2 kinds of artillery which is a number matched by most factions.  Base Building The British don't have the ability to construct buildings like every other faction does, instead they have a series of mobile trucks that function like unit producing buildings, this is also how they progress in tiers.    When a Command Truck is unpacked it can provide a bonus to the resource of the sector that it's unpacked in (if a Command Truck is unpacked in a  10 Fuel sector, it boosts that income to  16 Fuel). Any truck can have this bonus, but only one truck is allowed to have it (for example if you upgrade your Field Support Truck with secured resourcing your HQ will lose it). You can also pack a Command Truck so it becomes mobile, when it's packed, you are unable to produce units from it and gain the resource bonus. You always start with a HQ Command Truck, which can train a Lieuetenant. A Lieutenant is required in order to call in the next Command Truck, the Field Support Truck. This truck can train the Captain which is required in order to call in the last truck, the Armored Command Truck. Each truck can also be upgraded with speed governors which increase the trucks speed by 2.5 times.These are the trucks and the units that they each can produce:  HQ Command Truck  HQ Command Truck, unpacked     The British HQ Command Truck is the first building available to the  British; from it, they can build the rest of their army. The British HQ truck is one of the the most unique  units in the game, as it is a mobile HQ and can move anywhere around the  map. Once the HQ is deployed to a territory it will increase that  sector's resource output by the same amount an Observation Post.      You start with this truck in the start of the match.    HQ Command Truck Units:Infantry Section  The Backbone of the British Army.Infantry   Sections (Tommies) are the  basic infantry unit for the British, they   are built from the HQ and can  construct various field defenses   including trenches, HMG emplacements  and mortar emplacements. Tommies   move very slowly in neutral and enemy  territory unless a Lieutenant is   nearby to provide them with a speed  boost or they are upgraded to a recon section; in captured territory the   Tommies will move at the same pace as  normal infantry.    Available Upgrades    There are 3 available upgrades for Tommy squads.  Recon Section This upgrade will allow the selected squad to move at normal speed through neutral and enemy territory, in order to ensure point capturing parity your first Tommy squad will start with the recon upgrade. At the cost of 35 munitions this is the cheapest upgrade available to your infantry. Recon Sections can also use the ability deploy marksmen which, for 25 munitions, will allow member of the squad to snipe a targeted unit.  That being said Recon Sections are decidedly worse at combat than even unupgraded Infantry Sections. Bren Gun Bren guns cost 75 munitions but they are money well spent. Not only do Bren guns chew up infantry at close range. Additionally for 25 munitions a Bren squad can button an enemy vehicle causing it to lose line of sight, move slower, and shoot less often this makes for a deadly combination with the powerful but inaccurate PIATs. All of this comes with one Caveat, the squad member using the Bren gun must be standing still. Happily for the British this can be overcome by putting the Bren squad in a Bren carrier. Rifle Grenades Rifle grenades also cost 75 munitions, and like their description implies will allow your units to more effectively negate infantry in cover. While the smoke grenade ability that they get is excellent for helping flanks when compared with the ability to button vehicles from a Bren carrier that can also drive behind whatever cover your enemy is using there's a reason why Rifle grenades are rarely used.Lieutenant   The Offensive Support Units of the British Army.The  Lieutenant are unique to the British,  they are the  veterans of the  British and provide bonuses to nearby  infantry while  also having a  fuel cost and being a tech requirement to  gain better  units. They have the same function as a veterancy point of other factions. Getting a lieutenant to veterancy rank 3 will immediately give the British player a free command point and increase their population capacity by 4. It is important to note that while not all of the benefits given by LT's stack some do, so a semi effective counter to veteran axis infantry is a massive group of infantry and lieutenants.  Bren Carrier  The Bren Carrier is the armored transport unit for  the British that can  be upgraded for extra firepower. It's  primary  use is to transport  infantry or commanders around the  battlefield.  While a unit is  garrisoned inside a Bren also gains the ability to  capture  strategic  points.  The Bren Carrier can, for a nominal munitions cost, self repair while temporarily losing some speed. The ability to self repair combined with the lack of reliable AT in the early game makes Bren Carriers incredibly dangerous early game. This combined with their ability to quickly and safely get slow British infantry into optimal combat range, and button vehicles makes them a must have.  Field Support Truck  Field Support Truck, unpacked     The Field Support Truck is the Tier 2  building for the British. The Field Support Truck The Field Support  Truck houses the only effective anti-vehicle/armor the British have  early on.   A Lieuetenant is required in order to call in this truck   Field Support Truck Units:Sappers   The Sapper is essentially a tier 2  construction unit   for the British that allows them to construct more  powerful defensive   and artillery  emplacements. They are also the only  unit in the British   army capable  of repairing vehicles, making  them one of the core  units  of a  late-game British force. Along with  their construction and   repair  abilities, Sappers are also able to be  upgraded with weaponry   and  equipment that make them suitable for the  roles of anti-tank   infantry,  mine clearing, and even further  specializing in repairing   vehicles and  emplacements.  Available Upgrades   PIAT The Projector Infantry Anti Tank weapon is the only infantry anti tank weapon available to the British for 75 munitions. PIAT squads can ambush when standing in cover which allows them to turn invisible until they attack. Because PIATs arc they are capable of attacking units over low walls and hedges, and hit tanks that they are facing in the rear. However because of their long arc and travel time they have a hard time hitting units that are moving quickly, which is where button comes in handy. Additionally due to an issue that PIAT projectile types currently face PIAT rounds that are fired roll along the ground until they explode on contact with a target. Which has the maddening habit of causing PIAT squads picking up a kill or two against dedicated anti-infantry squads.  Disposal and Detection Section For 50 munitions this squad can detect and remove mines, as well as plant explosives to blow up bridges or buildings in much the same way as the American Engineer.  Expert Engineers For 75 munitions Sappers with this upgrade can repair faster and over repair any vehicle giving the vehicle health boost that degrades over time. In previous patches due to the strength of over repair Expert Engineers was a popular upgrade, however now that the health boost degrades relatively quickly the AT offered by PIATs is a much more popular choice.Captain   The Defensive Support Units of the British Army.Captain   a defensive officer which can boost  the health of emplacements and   infantry units in the same sector, the  Captain may also act as a   retreat point instead of the standard HQ.    Stuart Light Tank  The Stuart Light Tank is designed   specifically for the role of  dealing with enemy light vehicles. Its  speed and  armor make it fast  and impervious to most damage dealt by  light  vehicles and its gun is  capable of devastating enemy light  tanks, although it is not as  effective against enemy infantry. Like  other light tanks, It is also not   reliable against heavier vehicles,  due to it's thinner armor and  smaller gun.   The Stuart can also use the delightfully random Canister shot against light infantry. Sometimes this shot will do minimal damage, while other times it will eliminate entire veteran squads.    Armored Command Truck  Armored Command Truck, packed     This truck is the Tier 3  unit  production building for the British. It   allows them to  deploy Heavy Armor.   A Captain is required in order to call in this truck.       Armored Command Truck Units: Cromwell      The Cromwell is the main all-around  battle tank  for the British, it's  reasonably armored for a tank and has  average  damage against infantry,  vehicles, and enemy armor alike, making them  great multi-purpose tanks.  Able to engage both  armor and infantry in  combat situations, Cromwells  have the added benefit of being slightly  cheaper than the  American  Sherman and Wehrmacht Panzer 4's. Cromwells  can use their Flank Speed  ability to circle enemy tanks or run over  enemy infantry units in mass.   Cromwell Command Tank   The Cromwell Command Tank will provide a  veterancy bonuses to all nearby  tanks within  it's command radius,  which increases their effectiveness  in combat. The  command tank also has medium crush.     Sherman Firefly  The                                Sherman Firefly is the best British  Anti-Tank armor in the game.  It's main gun is similar to the German  Panther with massive range, great  frontal  penetration value and high  damage output. The Firefly can be   used in combination with a command  tank to not only increase their   sight range, but firing range as well.  This gives them a great advantage  as they can shoot much  further than  enemy tanks and get off one or two  shots before they are even  in the  opposing tank's firing range. With  the firefly's high frontal armor  penetration, it  can easily take enemy  tanks head-on. However, although  the tank is not as effective against  enemy infantry units.        British StructuresBritish Structures  Slit Trench An infantry section can dig in making the  squad almost impervious to incoming fire, whether it is artillery, tank  shells or small arms fire. Units inside trenches are still vulnerable to  flamethrowers and grenades. In fact they take increased damage while inside, when combined with the bonus damage Infantry Sections take due to their armour_soldier type makes for a disastrous result. It's important to note that british have no non doctrinal way to remove enemies from their trench. Which is why any Brit worth his salt taps delete twice to destroy the trench before abandoning it.   HMG EmplacementThe HMG emplacement is the only  available MG to the British early on. The British do not have a mobile MG; instead, they can build an  HMG emplacement. The HMG emplacement is great for setting up near enemy  strategic points, cutting them off from map resources. Since Tommy  squads can make this HMG emplacement, it can be placed offensively as  well as defensively depending on the flow of the game.   The Mortar Emplacement Every other army in  Company of Heroes has access to mobile mortar units early in the game,  but the British again are limited to having a "building" as their  mortar. However, the British mortar has distinct differences in that it  is much more resistant to enemy mortar fire and not nearly as vulnerable  to small arms fire, making it very useful to lock down an area from  almost all infantry attack.  Bofors 40mm Cannon  The Bofors is an  emplacement designed for both the role of anti-vehicle and anti-air.  However, due to the angle of the gun, it is not effective against enemy  infantry.  Also given the relatively weak gun the weapon is only effective at taking on light vehicles. Which, it should be noted, it does an amazing job at doing.  17 Pounder Anti Tank EmplacementThe 17 Pounder AT Gun,  although quite possibly the most fearsome AT Gun in the game,  is  only limited by the fact that it is a stationary weapon. The weapon has a  range about 2cm shorter than a Marder III and is the stationary  equivalent of Sherman Firefly, the gun can also traverse 360* but it is  unable to shoot (and is rather slow) while turning.     25 Pounder Artillery BatteryThe 25 Pounder is the  hallmark artillery piece of the British Army. It can fire over long  distances making it ideal for softening up the resistance, or likewise  bombarding attackers and forcing them to retreat. This emplacement  becomes even more powerful through the Royal Canadian Artillery  Regiment, giving it access to various abilities and strategic options  such as the powerful Creeping Barrage.     Casualty Clearing StationThis clearing  station is unique to the British as in not only does it retrieve injured  units and bring them back to the station like the Wehrmacht Medic  Bunker, but it also has a healing radius just like the American Triage  Center. This healing is only activated for a short period following a small expenditure of munitions. British DoctrinesRoyal Artillery SupportThe best  artillery commander in all of  Company of Heroes, lay down   devastating creeping barrages from  priests, 25 pounders or howitzer   bombardments from any British  officer. Royal Canadian Artillery focuses   on improving every artillery  unit available to the Brits, supercharged   rounds will increase the  distance that all artillery units, even mortar   pits can fire, while  abilities like counter barrage make sure that  enemy  artillery won't be  able to fight back without being pummeled to  death.BarrageConcentrationForward   Observation Officers 2 Commands  Points 150 Munitions This ability  allows  officers such as  lieutenants and captains to call in artillery  on a  section of the map  that's not covered by the fog of war. The  artillery  is full of  destruction and can lay waste to a lot of  infantry bunched  up together.  Alternatively you can use the barrage  and cancel it  quickly to make the  flares fall and make enemy infantry  retreat,  without losing any  munitions. Forward Observation Officers  also gives  the command tank the  ability to lay a creeping smoke  barrage for 50  munitions, this can  almost instantly conceal a large  group of friendly  tanks in smoke,  protecting them from getting hit  while making an  assault, or allowing  them to retreat unharmed. More importantly while most artillery takes 1.75 seconds to drop the first part of the officer barrage drops near instantly suppressing the infantry forcing either a retreat or massive casualties.    Supercharged Rounds 2 Command  Points This ability allows the 25 pounder  and  mortar emplacements to fire much further than they normally would,  it  almost doubles the range of both artillery emplacements. The Priest   105mm is also affected by this ability, allowing it to fire much further   than it normally would. Supercharged rounds is the most crucial  ability  for an Artillery Commander to obtain, if an early 25 pounder or  mortar  emplacement is built, it will allow these units to fire much  further  than usual. An early mortar can be built near a Headquarters  and still  be able to reach the front lines most of the time and it's  the same case  with the 25 pounder later on.      Creeping Barrage 2 Command  Points 150 MunitionsThis ability costs  150   munitions and requires the player to at least have a 25 pounder or   105mm  Priest to fire and once used, will put the artillery unit's   standard  fire ability on cooldown. It's a considerable price to pay but   the  potential destruction and large amount of manpower taken away  from  the  enemy once a creeping barrage is used can be more than worth  it.    Overwatch Artillery 2 Command Points  Any artillery  unit can be set to  use overwatch Artillery, it will then automatically  fire at any units  that enter the overwatch area, this is great for  covering victory points  at late-game stages or simply covering a high  resource point when an  enemy unit attempts to capture it.   Priest 105mm Howitzer 3  Command Points 625 ManpowerThe Priest 105mm is  the only   mobile artillery piece available to the British and can  quickly redeploy   from the back of the field to the front lines for  more accurate   artillery fire, and then back again to safety, it can  deal around 40%   more damage and can redeploy to safety if a base is  overrun, unlike the   howitzer which is a building.      Counter Battery 3 Command PointsCounter  Battery is the ultimate  artillery-destroyer, any artillery unit  available to the British can be  toggled to activate counter battery and  while the ability is active the  unit will instantly fire back at any  enemy artillery that has fired on  the map. This ability is excellent  for taking out pesky mortar teams,  Nebelwerfers or mortar halftracks,  the mighty 25 pounder and Priest can  even fire back at enemy Hummels.                                                     Royal  Commandos SupportGlider's fly from the skies and onto the  battlefield  providing powerful units and offensive reinforcement  positions,  powerful artillery and recon intelligence abilities help to  confuse the  enemy and allow the British commander to prepare for any  combat  situation long before the enemy is seen. Royal commandos support  is by  far the most offensive Commander of the three choices and as  such is one  of the most popular. Combined with the defensive natures of  the British, Commandos support allows the British to strike fast, hard  and  hit the enemy where it hurts.Coup de MainIntelligence  Glider-Borne   Commandos Commandos are the most expensive infantry unit  to buy  in the whole game. With the ability to be   deployed anywhere on the  battlefield and have the glider they came down   in provide  reinforcements, Commandos can change the outcome of any   battle at the  snap of a finger. They're armed with weapons that are   excellent at  dealing damage close-up and have enough armor to close   that distance  easily.     Radio   Triangulation Detection 1 Command   PointThis ability allows a  Commandos player to keep track   of enemy units on the minimap even while  they're in the fog of war.   Any British infantry unit can build a  detector and once all 3 detectors   are built, any enemy unit within the  triangle will be viewable on the   minimap making ability great for  anticipating where the enemy will   strike next. Make sure the detectors  are spread out and very far away   from each other even in enemy   territory.                                                                                Tetrach  Tank 2 Command Points  450  ManpowerThe Tetrarch can be instantly  deployed to any   location on the battlefield, it wields an accurate gun  which is   excellent at destroying enemy vehicles and is even capable of  flanking   and damage enemy tanks from the rear, the weapon can even be  upgraded   for better penetration. The Tetrarch fills a very limited  purpose on  the  battlefield, it's average against infantry and good  against  vehicles  but comes pretty late in the game at 5 Command Points  and  costing 450  Manpower, use the Tetrarch if you're desperate for   ant-tank firepower or  need to quickly dispose of a halftrack or light   vehicle away from the  main battle.  Ultra  Decryption 1 Command PointOne  of the most  useful abilities for finding  out what units and strategy  your opponent  is doing ingame, this ability  will let you know when an  enemy unit is  produced and what unit it is,  what upgrades are bought,  or building  that have been finished. It allows  any British player to  be prepared  for whatever comes next for the rest  of the game, and at a  cheap price  of 1 CP.    Glider HQ 2 Command Points 340 ManpowerThe   Glider Headquarters, capable of producing   commando teams specialized   in anti-infantry and anti-tank combat for a   cheap price. This is the   most expensive building in the game and  should  be deployed with care   as it's very weak, the units that come  from it are  very cheap and  have  high survivability in combat, which  will eventually  make up the   initial manpower cost of this buildings.  You can train a HMG  Commando team, PIAT Commando team and a Mortar Commando team from this  Glider HQ.  Decoy Artillery 2 Command Points 125 MunitionsThis   ability is split up into 2  types of  artillery, the first will lay a   short but extremely powerful artillery  barrage that covers a small  area  and for a very cheap cost, it's great  for destroying complete  squads  that are capturing a strategic point  while your enemy isn't  looking.   The second artillery is completely  fake, flares will come  down as if  the artillery is about to land on  enemy units, but nothing  will happen.     Royal Engineers SupportDown the right hand  side of Royal Engineers are powerful tank call-ins, the main tank is  the Churchill infantry tank which has a turret mounted main gun backed  up with heavy armor. The 2 other tanks available are both hybrid's of  the first one, the Churchill AVRE has a mounted gun that can fire  devastating mortar rounds while the final tank is a Churchill with a  flamethrower mounted on it. Down the left hand side is an ability to  improve emplacements, make tanks much harder to destroy in combat and an  ability that improves command vehicles to produce a larger amount of  resources and decrease production times.Field ImprovementsTank SupportImproved Emplacements 2  Command Points  This  ability does exactly what  it says  on the tin, it improves all British  emplacements so that they  receive  25% less damage from all enemy units,  all emplacements will  also  receive a 50% boost to their maximum amount  of health. This  ability is  great to use if a British player is going to  make a lot of   emplacements such as a mortar pit, Bofors or 17 pounder AT  gun   emplacement. Use this ability in combo with the defensive bonus  that   the British captain provides, and emplacements will be extremely  hard   for any unit to destroy.                                                              Churchill   3 Command Points 600  ManpowerThe first tank available to the royal engineers   commander only costs 3 command points and is a valuable asset to any   British player's early to mid-game fighting force. The great thing about   this tank is not only does it do good damage to infantry and vehicles   alike, it has a large amount of frontal armor and hit points making it   one of the toughest tanks around until late-game situations, The   Churchill comes with the 'Tank Shock' ability which suppresses targeted   infantry nearby, it's useful for either assaulting enemy infantry or   retreating out of danger since the shock effect happens almost   instantly.   Hull  Down 2 Command Points  This gives all  British tanks the ability to  'hull down', which makes  them more  resilient to all kinds of damage.  Hull down takes hardly any  time for a  tank to activate and once it is  active the unit will  receive 25% less  damage and 25% less penetration  making it much more  tougher in all  combat situations. However while in  hull down mode, the  unit will not be  able to move at all until the  ability has been  deactivated, so use it  wisely.     Churchill  AVRE 2 Command Point 600  ManpowerThe AVRE is a unique artillery piece  that instead  of having a regular mounted gun, it has an ability that  fires a large  mortar round for a cost of 35 munitions each use. When  fired it does a  massive amount of damage to any unit within the area,  great for using  against blobs of infantry.     Improved  Command Vehicles 2 Command  Points This  ability  simply increases the amount of  resource produced from sectors  that have  command vehicles on, it's a  great way to boost munitions  income for  special late-game abilities  especially in team games. It also  improves  the production speed of all  units by 25%.    Churchill Crocodile 2 Command Points 800 ManpowerThe  Churchill crocodile tank is  like a beefed up version of the original  Churchill, it has more  hitpoints and added to the front of the tank is a  new flamethrower. The  flamethrower does some great damage to infantry  but what really makes it  shine is it's massive range, it's able to  throw out flames almost as  far as the regular gun can shoot which is  great for staying well out of  trouble while burning enemy infantry, The  downside to the flamethrower  is it can only be used from the front of  the tank  The German Panzer Elite The Panzer Elite have among the most  mobile units in the game.  All weapons crews that would normally have a  separate infantry crew is now in vehicle form.  For example, while the  Americans have an MG team, a mortar team, and an AT gun, the Panzer  Elite have an infantry halftrack with a mounted machine gun, a mortar  halftrack, and a Marder III, with a mounted AT gun.  They  supplement this idea of 'mobility' by lacking a specialist for each  field, sacrificing different types of infantry for a base unit called  the 'Panzer Grenadier,' which can be specialized to serve as long range anti  infantry (G43), close range anti infantry (MP44), or Anti-Tank  (Panzerschrek).  Adding to this mobility is the fact that all Panzer  Grenadiers can repair vehicles, which allows the Panzer Elite to keep on the offensive and  not have to fall back to repair. The doctrine choices of the Panzer  Elite are Scorched Earth, Luftwaffe and Tank Hunters.  The Scorched  Earth doctrine allows the player to construct environmental defenses  which can be used to block roads and also lay booby traps on  buildings and strategic points.  The Luftwaffe doctrine allows players  to construct specialized defenses such as Flakvierling and  Flak 88s as  well as Wirbelwind anti-aircraft vehicles.  The Tank Hunter doctrine can  allow infantry to deploy with more Panzerschreks and anti-tank grenades  as well as the ability to deploy the fearsome Jagdpanther or "Hunting  Panther".      Infantry  Panzer Grenadiers  Panzer Grenadiers are the main infantry unit in the Panzer Elite army, equipped with a                             Kar98k rifle. They are a highly versatile infantry, not only capable of fighting the enemy, but also Panzer Elite's only unit capable of constructing buildings and repair. You can upgrade these units with either a                            Gewehr 43 rifle,                           MP44 or a                          Panzerschreck. You can also train some different variants of this unit in other structures which come with another set of weapons: Assault Grenadier Heavy Infantry wields MP44s, and Tank Buster Heavy Infantry wields Panzerschrecks.  Vehicles Kettenkrad  This nimble halftrack vehicle serves some of the most important functions of the Panzer Elite army. It's one of the first two units that can be deployed from the HQ. It is mainly used to capture strategic points and scout with. It is extremely effective to capture strategic points, while your more combat-friendly units focuses on the combat.  The Kettenkrad gains different benefits based upon which command tree, or doctrine, the player chooses. The different benefits can be seen below:  Scorched Earth Tactics: Booby trap strategic point. Luftwaffe Tactics: Camouflage. Tank Destroyer Tactics: Advanced Repair.  Scout Car  The Scout Car serves as a reconnaissance and logistic duty. The Scout Car is also the cheapest  armoured fighting vehicle of the  Panzer Elite army. It can  capture a strategic point without special upgrade and secure a sector with an upgrade, also giving the given sector a resource boosts.  Funkwagen 'Vampire' Halftrack  A halftrack that can steal resources. Munitions Halftrack A halftrack that removes cooldown on nearby units abilities.  Infantry Halftrack  This halftrack serves as a armored transport for infantry. You can also reinforce squads close to the Infantry Halftrack Mortar Halftrack  A mobile mortar emplacement. Light AT Halftrack   A Light AT gun on top of a halftrack.  Armored Car   A quite deadly armored car against infantry and other light vehicles, equipped with a cannon.  Marder III  The Marder III is a German tank destroyer, it is a turretless tank with weak armor, a deadly cannon and range. You can activate its Lock Down ability at the cost of its mobility, giving it even more range and double the fire rate.Panzer IV Infantry Support Tank   Armed with the short, low velocity cannon and a MG42 light machine gun on the chassis, the Panzer IV Infantry Support Tank is also known as the "Stubby" for its short cannon. It may not have the armor penetrating capabilities of the standard Panzer IV, the low velocity gun that fires the HE(High Explosive) round is designed kill multiple infantry units with a single shot.   Panther  The 75mm                        KwK 42 cannon  equipped on the                       Panther  will destroy allied armor without flinching.  The Panther is a lumbering  hulk of tank-killing machinery and not even  the Pershing can reliably  deal with it. Luckily for the Allies, the  Panther's total devotion to  anti-tank weaponry makes it an easy target  for infantry if they can get  around it with strong enough AT guns, also the side armor is very thin, and is therefore very vulnerable to flanking attacks. This  flaw in the Panther's design  is exacerbated by its slow turning speed  and acceleration. If a Panther  gets stuck, Allied forces would be wise  to take as many potshots as  possible before it can turn its steel era  death ray back towards them.   Bergetiger Repair and Recovery Vehicle  The Bergetiger is a heavily modified version of the                  Tiger tank, it has a crane instead of a gun and is able to "resurrect" already destroyed vehicles back to functionallity. The Bergetiger can recover both ally  and axis  vehicles, but the  vehicles  remain in control of their original user. This means that recovering an   allied   vehicle  is not a good idea!    Defensive Emplacements  Flakvierling 38    The Flakvierling provides excellent base defense, being able to cover both air and ground forces with its devastating quad flak cannons.  88mm Flak 36   The fearsome     88mm Flak can target and destroy aircraft and heavy armor. Panzer Elite DoctrinesScorched Earth TacticsArea DenialScorched EarthBooby Trap Building  1 Command Point  Panzer Elite infantry can be ordered to plant deadly booby traps inside any building on the map. Enemy infantry entering the building will suffer extreme consequences. Roadblocks  1 Command Point Massive roadblocks can be built that cannot be crushed by any unit, forcing the enemy to direct combat resourced to destroy the barricade.                            Booby Trap Strategic Point  1 Command Point Panzer Elite infantry can be ordered to booby trap any strategic point on the map. Booby traps are triggered by enemy units attempting to capture the point. Scorched Earth  3 Command Points  Following the ancient doctrine of scorched earth, Strategic Points can be disabled, denying their use to the enemy. Sector Artillery  3 Command Points  A selected sector is monitored for enemy activity. When enemy units are detected, the area is saturated with artillery until that enemy activity ceases    Hummel Self-Propelled Artillery  3 Command Points  A Hummel Self-Propelled 150mm howitzer can devastate large swaths of ground at long range with its massive shells.    Luftwaffe TacticsAir PowerAir DefenseFallschirmjager Infiltration  3 Command Points  Fallschirmjager squads can be ordered to reveal themselves from pre-infiltrated hiding locations in buildings. Fallschirmjager squads camouflage automatically when in heavy cover.                                  Luftwaffe Ground Forces  1 Command Point Luftwaffe ground forces are adequate soldiers who can construct light defenses and, more importantly, the devastating AA weapons, Falkviervling Quad 20mm Cannon and the Flak 36 88mm Cannon.Butterfly Bombs  1 Command Point Low flying aircraft can drop fields of SD-2 Butterfly Bombs to disrupt the movement of enemy infantry and light vehicles.    Wirbelwind Flakpanzer   3 Command Points Order a dangerous Wirbelwind Flakpanzer that can provide mobile AA coverage, or engage enemy infantry and light vehicles. Henschel Combat Air Patrol  3 Command Points  Henschel Hs. 129 ground attack aircraft will provide tactical air-cover with their powerful 75mm cannons. The aircraft will monitor targeted locations for enemy vehicles or tanks, and strike when movement is detected. Flak 36 88mm Cannon   2 Command Points Luftwaffe Ground Forces are able to construct the fearsome            88mm Flak 38, a dual role weapon capable of targeting both air and ground units at long ranges.    Tank Destroyer TacticsTank HunterTank DestroyerTeller Mines  1 Command Point  Panzer Elite infantry can deploy Teller Mines. These weapons require great mass to trigger, meaning only vehicles will cause the mine to explode.Tank Awareness  1 Command Point Panzer Elite infantry use their improved battlefield skills to detect enemy tanks at ranges beyond which they can see.   Hetzer Tank  3 Command Points  A Hetzer Tank Hunter is available for reinforcement. These maneuverable tanks have thick sloping armor, and they small size means they are easily camouflages.  APCR Rounds  3 Command Points AT guns and main tank guns are issued the more powerfull APCR (Armor Piercing Composite Rigid) Panzergranate 40 ammunition that will improve armor penetration.    Double Infantry AT Efforts  3 Command Points          Panzerschreck upgrades now provide two Panzerschrecks, and AT grenade abilities now throw two AT grenades.      Jagdpanther Tank Destroyer  4 Command Points A  very rare and powerful           Jagdpanther is allocated once to each commander. Extremely well armed and armored, the Jagdpanther is capable of tackling all enemy units.     System RequirmentsMinimum:Supported OS: Windows® XP or Vista.  Processor: 2.0Ghz Intel Pentium IV or equivalent or AMD  Athlon XP or equivalent. SSE capable processor required.  Memory: 512MB RAM; Vista users require 1GB of RAM to play  the game  Graphics: DirectX 9.0c compatible 64MB video card with  Pixel Shader 1.1 support or equivalent and latest manufacturer drivers  Sound: DirectX® 9.0c compatible 16-bit sound card  Input Devices: Keyboard, Mouse  Hard Drive: 9GB of uncompressed free hard drive  spaceRecommended:Processor: 3.0Ghz Intel Pentium IV or equivalent  Memory: 1GB RAM  Graphics: 256MB NVIDIA GeForce 6800 series or  betterRequired for Multiplayer:RAM: 1GB RAM required for Multiplayer and Skirmish  Internet (TCP/IP) and LAN (TCP/IP) play supported.  1 game license per computer. </description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2115">Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War</game><game id="11993">Rise of Nations</game><game id="5681">Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War - Dark Crusade</game><game id="13062">StarCraft</game><game id="21175">Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War II</game><game id="19335">Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War - Winter Assault</game><game id="10883">Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War - Soulstorm</game><game id="14805">KKND2: Krossfire</game><game id="22821">Axis &amp; Allies</game><game id="20793">Warhammer: Battle March</game><game id="3537">Conflict Zone</game><game id="25651">R.U.S.E.</game><game id="26487">Order of War</game><game id="12202">Joint Task Force</game><game id="30367">Order of War: Challenge</game><game id="33907">APOX</game><game id="31579">Men of War: Vietnam</game><game id="39305">Wargame: AirLand Battle</game><game id="16537">COPS 2170: The Power of Law</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2531059-box_cohof.png</image></root>