<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4776</id><name>Mega Man X7</name><description>OverviewMega Man X7 was a big leap forward for the X series.  It was the first X game on the PlayStation 2, it featured 3-D cel-shaded graphics, and it featured 3-D gameplay segments.  During gameplay, the game would transition from 2-D gameplay to 3-D gameplay on the fly.  X7 was the second game in the series to feature English voice acting (the first was Mega Man X4).  The last big difference was the introduction of a new main character,       Axl.  Axl was a refugee from vigilante group Red Alert who seeks to join the Maverick Hunters.  Axl was introduced as     Zero's new partner due to      X moving to an HQ postion of the Maverick Hunters.  Axl had the abillity to copy enemy powers, hover, and used two pistols to fight his enemies.ReceptionMega Man X7 recieved one of the wosrt receptions for any X series game from both fans and game critics.  It was most criticized for the 3-D gameplay segments, due to a poor camera and controls.  X7's vehicle segments were also poorly recieved.  The game was also criticized for X's personality change.  X was always uneasy about violence, but in X7 he was so against violence he stopped working in the field and was purely in an HQ position.  Because of this, X was not a main playable character and had to be unlocked.Soundtrack      The soundtrack for Mega Man X7, like other soundtracks in the series, was only released in Japan as Rockman X7 - Original Soundtrack. . Tracklist 01. Title Call  Soundtrack cover   02. Conflict - Escape Stage   03. Awake Road Again - Highway Stage  04. Burning Water - Kombinat Stage  05. Underground - Tunnel Base Stage   06. Mod Electric Wave - Radio Tower Stage  07. Naval Battle - Battleship Stage  08. Ruins'n Vains - Deep Forest Stage  09. Higher The Air - Air Force Stage  10. Cyber Geometry - Cyber Field Stage  11. Bomb Recovery - Central Circuit Stage  12. Just Before Red - Palace Road Stage  13. Infiltration - Crimson Palace Stage 1  14. Soul Asylum - Crimson Palace Stage 2  15. Combination - vs Mega Scorpio  16. Decisive Battle - vs Boss  17. Relation - vs Red  18. Our Blood Boils - vs Sigma 1st  19. Conclusion - vs Sigma Final  20. Stage Select 1  21. Stage Start  22. Stage Clear  23. Result  24. Option  25. Stage Select 2  26. Provocation  27. Theme Of Signas  28. Beginning - Theme Of Red  29. Revealing  30. Suffering  31. Black Plotting  32. Fate - Theme Of Sigma  33. Theme Of Alia  34. Theme Of X  35. Tragedy  36. Thorny Path  37. Night Mare - Ending Of Zero  38. A Naughty Boy - Theme Of Axel  39. Opening  40. Ending  41. Lazy Mind  42. X SE  43. Axel SE  44. Zero SE  45. Sigma SE  46. No Holdin' Back - Demo Of Megaman X7 (Bonus Track)  </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2525215-box_mmx7.png</image></root>