<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4785</id><name>Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon: Desert Siege</name><description>PlotIn the wake of the upheaval in Russia, a series of small brushfire wars have ignited around the globe. One of the deadliest being the resumption of hostilities between the forces of Ethiopia and Eritrea, which have been spurred on by a coup in Addis Ababa. Armed with the latest Russian weaponry, and led by General Tesfaye Wolde, the Ethiopian military makes a grab for the Eritrean coastline. This sudden Ethiopian offensive sends the Eritreans into a swift retreat. Shipping on the Red Sea ceases. Relief efforts on the interior come to a swift halt. At the request of the Eritrean government, an international coalition is formed to combat the violence plaguing the two countries. The Ghosts are once again called to action to lead the charge as the spearhead of the operational forces. Armed with new weapons and new specialists it's up to them to push the Ethiopian military back across the border. OverviewTom Clancy's Ghost Recon: Desert Siege is an expansion of the original Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon. It consists of an all new single-player campaign as well as various new weapons, enemies and multiplayer maps.New Additions include:A multiplayer leaderboard2 new multiplayer game modes5 new multiplayer maps8 mission single-player campaign set in the Horn of AfricaNew weapons for multiplayer battlesNew enemies and vehiclesNew and improved specialist charactersAs in the original Ghost Recon, completing secondary objectives will reward you with all new specialist characters. Some objectives will be time-based; others will involve escorting civilian vehicles across maps filled with hostiles.WeaponsThere are 9 new weapons available for use in Desert Siege. Some will appear in the hands of unlocked Specialist characters while others may only be available in Multiplayer or Quick Mission modes.New weapons include:Rifleman KitsAN 947.62mm CarbineGroza/GP 25Support KitsM-60PKMDemolitions KitsA-91Bizon 9mmSniper KitsM987.62mm Sniper RifleMinimum Requirements (PC)CPU: Pentium 2 with 450MHz or equivalentMemory: 128MB of RAMOperation System: Windows 9X/ME/2000/XPDirectX: DirectX 8.0 or higher (Included with Retail Version)Video Card: 16MB DirectX 8 compatible 3D CardHard Drive Space: 500MB MinimumCD-ROM: 4X or betterAudio: DirectX 8.0 or compatibleSound Card: DirectX 8.0 or compatibleInternet/Network Play: TCP/IP Internet or LAN ConnectionOriginal Ghost Recon is Required</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7288">SWAT 4</game><game id="7747">John Romero's Daikatana</game><game id="21912">Planetside: Core Combat</game><game id="22960">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six: Lone Wolf</game><game id="22948">Specnaz: Project Wolf</game><game id="24023">Insurgency</game><game id="26423">Call of Duty: Black Ops</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2546/842983-dspic.jpg</image></root>