<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>4791</id><name>Vanguard: Saga of Heroes</name><description>HistoryVanguard was created by a company called Sigil Games Online. A company Started By Jeff Butler and Brad Mquaid that were well known for playing key roles in The MMORPG Everquest. They started Sigil in 2002 where they would begin production on their first game Vanguard. Originally the game has plans to be published by Microsoft however rumors began to surface that Microsoft began to pressure Sigil to release the game before it was done. Then in 2006 Sigil required the rights to their game and announced the Sony Online Entertainment (SOE) would be a co-publisher of Vanguard.Vanguard was a very ambitious game. It brought many new features into the MMORPG genre such as Open world housing (where certain areas would be designated for crafters to build houses for people and these houses could be used as a store front or whatever means the owner chose.) as well as a new type of play style called Diplomacy ( a card game used to influence game play for cities and those inside the city)Vanguard was hailed as the Spiritual Successor to Everquest 1 by many hardcore fans of the series because of its return to the difficult play style things that hadn't been used in current MMORPG's such as corpse runs (A death penalty for when you die your armor and weapons are left on your "corpse" and in order to retrieve your armor you must get back to the area of where you died even if it was deep inside of a dungeon) as well as the group centric nature of the game.In August of 2005 Beta testing began and lasted until January 23rd 2007. The game would soon launch January 30th 2007 to the public. The launch started fairly well with 14 servers with 242,000 in first month sales. However unfinished zones, broken quests, and lack of polish only left about half of the initial subscribers to become active subscribers past the first free month.Mixed reviews from websites like Gamespy awarded it with the "Biggest disappointment” award and MMORPG.com gave it an award for being the "Lamest launch" . Another plague that Vanguard Encountered was the recent release of "The Burning Crusade" and expansion for the MMORPG "World of Warcraft"On May 15th 2007. Sony Online Entertainment (SOE) acquired all the rights for Vanguard as well as Sigil. Sony took the initiative and began a major overhaul on Vanguard from start to finish. They fixed many bugs and performance issues as well as adjusted many game mechanics including the "Corpse run" system.To this day Vanguard retains only 4 servers and a much lower subscription number. However this wasn't the end for Vanguard. Rereviews of the game in its current state in comparison with many current games has given Vanguard very favorable reviews. Websites like MMORPG.com giving the game a 7.6 after almost 2 years, its previous score being 6.8.Progression:Progression in Vanguard is referred to as Spheres.These spheres areAdventuring (a typical leveling system that consists of defeating enemies in combat and completing quests for adventuring experience)There are 15 Adventuring classes in Vanguard: Saga of Heroes. They are divided into a set of archetypes. Vanguard is a game in which the characters have set group roles in the game.Tanks: These characters take damage in combat; their goal for the group is to keep people from getting damaged.Warrior: This is the basic tank class.Paladin: This tank class is a hybrid that is able to both tank and heal for a group.Dread Knight : This tank is a hybrid class that specializes in using stuns and life taps to control the battleMelee based DPS: These classes use melee weapons to cause damage to their opponents. While they are better protected than Mana based classes they cannot with stand straight head to head combat as well as tanks.Rogue: (This class is a stealth based attacker which is able to attack its opponent from behind for immense damageRanger (a master of ranged combat, stealth, dual wielding, with the ability to use some Druidic spells.Monk (A master of martial arts. At level 15 he/she gets to choose a specialization in either- Drunken Style - Tank version of the monk with better defenses than other monks- Harmonious Style- A monk that specializes in debuffs.- Dragon Monk- A monk that specializes in DPSBard - A group utility class. Has the ability to make its own song with its own effects by taking various parts and combining them. In order to keep songs from being to powerful each song component is separated into a "Part" A part can come in many different forms and you acquire more parts as you level. Each part requires a use of power so to be sure the bard isn’t quickly depleted of power it uses a rest. (Example of a song. A bard wishes to make a song for in uses combat. He knows he will be in a group of Melee DPSHealers: These classes cast healing spells that help their allies in combat, healing the damage they have received.Disciple ( A monk like healer, does not require mana as it uses "Jin" )Blood Mage ( A light armor wearing healer, The blood mage steals health from enemies to heal his group.)Shaman (Can wear medium armor, Wards off damage, Group buffs)Cleric (Can wear heavy armor. Uses big spike heals, Has good group buffs.Mana based DPS: These classes cast spells that damage enemies.Sorcerer (A high DPS spell caster)Necromancer (Master of undeath. Able to summon undead pets to help it. Uses lifetaps)Druid (A high dps caster that uses the forces of nature to help it. Druids also have small heals)Psionicist (Crowd control and a utility class for mages)Crafting Sphere ( A complex crafting system that involves taking recipes and raw materials and combing them to be any from something as simple as a sword to be a house, guild hall, or even a play driven ship.) There are 3 crafting classes and 2 specialization classes per crafting class. The player chooses a specialization upon reaching level 11 in their crafting sphere.Outfitter:Tailor- Makes light armor as well as other things like backpacksLeatherworker- Makes medium armors as well as saddlebags for mountsArtificer:Carpenter- Play a key role in making Ships, houses, and wooden weaponryMineralogist- Makes jewelry, stone weapons, and many items used for house buildingBlacksmith:Armorsmith- Used for making Heavy plate armor and horseshoesWeaponsmith- Used for making metal weapons and also has the ability to make horseshoesDiplomacy:Diplomacy is a new form of progression unique to Vanguard. Diplomacy is based off traditional trading card games. Diplomats play the game based off the pushes and pulls of typical conversation. Diplomats enter into a Parlay with members of a town and depending on your level and gear you are assigned a base amount of Dialogue points. The goal is to use abilities “Aggressive statement” and “truth be told” to influence your opponents Dialogue points to 0. Diplomacy is typically used in cities and diplomats will parlay members of the city to create citywide buffs for crafter or adventurers therefore making people of those archetypes flock to the city as the buffs last. Diplomats also play a vital role in end game content like buying a guild hall and unlocking some places of power.PC System RequirementsMinimum:OS:Windows® 7, Windows® XP Service Pack 2 or Windows® VistaProcessor:Pentium® 4 equivalent or greaterMemory:1 GB RAMGraphics:NVidia GeForce 7800/ATI Radeon X800 ProDirectX®:9.0cHard Drive:20 GB HD spaceSound:DirectX compatible Sound CardOther Requirements:Broadband Internet connectionRecommended:OS:Windows® 7, Windows® XP Service Pack 2 or Windows® VistaProcessor:Pentium® Core 2 Duo or greaterMemory:2 GB RAMGraphics:NVidia GeForce 460 GTX/AMD Radeon HD 4850DirectX®:9.0cHard Drive:20 GB HD spaceSound:DirectX compatible Sound CardOther Requirements:Broadband Internet connection</description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10796">EverQuest</game><game id="11142">Final Fantasy XI Online</game><game id="12149">Dark Age of Camelot</game><game id="18547">EverQuest II</game><game id="14901">EverQuest II: Echoes of Faydwer</game><game id="21707">Fury</game><game id="18603">World of Warcraft: The Burning Crusade</game><game id="20701">World of Warcraft: Wrath of the Lich King</game><game id="26641">Ultima Online: Stygian Abyss</game><game id="26770">Rift</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1992/1076773-vanguard.jpg</image></root>