<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5026</id><name>Adventures of Lolo</name><description>OverviewAdventures of Lolo is a puzzle game developed and published by HAL Corporation in 1989 for the Nintendo Entertainment System. It has also been released on the Wii's Virtual Console for 500 points. Because Adventures of Lolo is largely comprised of levels taken from earlier NES Eggerland games, which were Japan-only titles, Adventures of Lolo was never released in Japan; as a result, the sequel was titled Adventures of Lolo in Japan.PlotLala, Lolo's pink blob friend, has been captured by the King Egger of Eggerland. Lolo must travel through five rooms in each of the ten levels in this castle to face off against the King Egger .CharactersLoloLoloThe protagonist and star. Lolo works his way through dungeons full of puzzles to rescue his princess. Sometimes, collecting heart framers will sometimes give him a Power-UpLalaLalaThe "Princess Peach" to Lolo. Lala is kidnapped by King Egger at the beginning of the game and it is Lolo's mission to rescue her.SnakeySnakeyThough Snakey's true intentions are unknown to the player, he is not hostile to Lolo in any way. Snakey plays an important part of many puzzles throughout the Lolo franchise. Snakey can be used to block Medusas or Gols from shooting projectiles. Snakeys can be used to stop other characters from reaching Lolo. Snakey can also be egged and ridden down rivers or be used to block character spawns. If Snakey is killed, and something is blocking his spawn, he will respawn elsewhere.GolGolGol sits as a neutral character until all the heart framers in a level have been collected. After this, Gol becomes hostile and works very similarly to a Medusa. The only difference between Gol and Medusa at this point is that Medusa's projectiles can not be dodged, but Gol's fireballs are avoidable.LeeperLeeperAn enemy that hops around and falls asleep when he touches Lolo. Leepers are mostly harmless enemies, but their main goal is to trap Lolo into an area that he'll be unable to escape. Leepers are incapable of crossing grass areas. Lolo can cleverly use Leeper's falling asleep ability to place him infront of other enemies, blocking them.SkullSkullSimilarly to Gol, Skulls wake up after Lolo collects all of the heart framers in the level. Skulls do not move directly towards Lolo, but are rather like the ghosts in Pac-man-- slowly making their way towards their prey. If they do manage to run into Lolo, he dies instantly.RockyRockyAn enemy that, like leeper, tries to trap Lolo; however, unlike Leeper, he will still chase after you if you somehow escape his trap. If Lolo crosses his line of sight, he will charge in a straight line in that direction. Rocky's a dick.AlmaAlmaAn enemy that chases Lolo. If he catches Lolo, Lolo dies instantly.MedusaMedusaAn enemy that cannot move, but will instantly kill Lolo if Lolo crosses its path. His attack can be blocked by a rock, block, or another enemy. It looks like he is shooting a laser, though he is probably just petrifying Lolo.Don MedusaDon MedusaAn enemy that is exactly like Medusa, except he moves. Don Medusa either moves from side to side or up and down. His knives can be blocked by rocks, blocks, or other enemies. It looks like he is wearing roller skates.King EggerKing EggerThe main boss that captures Lala. King Egger only appears in cut scenes.ObjectsHeart FramersHeart FramersHeart Framers are scattered throughout the levels and it is Lolo's job to collect them. Once all the Heart Framers on a level have been collected, the Chest opens up. Heart Framers will occasionally contain shots. Lolo uses shots to turn enemies into eggs which he can push around to block things. Alternatively he can shoot the egg again to kill the enemy. In some levels, collecting a certain amount of Heart Framers will give Lolo a Power-Up.ChestsChestChests open up when all the heart framers in the level are collected. At this point many of the enemies in the level will wake up and chase Lolo. Once Lolo collects the chest in the level, all the enemies will disappear and the exit door will open for Lolo to go through.Emerald FramerBlocksEmerald Framer are in most levels and are pushed around by Lolo to block Medusas or other enemies. What Emerald Framers are made of is a hotly debated topic.One Way PassThese appear as arrows on the ground. Lolo can not move or push a block across the arrow opposite the direction the arrow is pointing.Power-UpsPower-Ups are obtained by collecting a certain amount of Heat Framers in a level. Not all levels contain Power-Ups.HammerAllows Lolo to destroy a rock.BridgeAllows Lolo to create a bridge across water or lava.One Way ReverseSwitches a One Way Pass so that it is pointing a different direction.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3758">Kickle Cubicle</game><game id="6770">Chip's Challenge</game><game id="33376">RUSH</game><game id="8514">Flappy</game><game id="42957">Janken Disk Shiro</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2361122-nes_theadventuresoflolo.jpg</image></root>