<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5057</id><name>Lumines: Puzzle Fusion</name><description>Overview  Lumines in Action     One of the PSP's most lauded launch titles, Lumines is a classic example of rhythm action developer Tetsuya Mizuguchi's development style, combining engrossing gameplay with heavy beats to produce a unique experience. Lumines is basically Tetris in a Tokyo dance club. The puzzle aspect is simple enough: The player has to move and rotate falling squares made up of four blocks each. Each of these four blocks can be one of two colors, and creating a square of four same-colored blocks will cause that square to be cleared from the game board when it's swept over by a line which continually crosses the screen from left to right. Connecting multiple matches into a larger shape before it's cleared by the line will result in combos that yield more points.  Lumines' energetic techno soundtrack is a major draw; it features an eclectic mix of Japanese artists like Mondo Grosso working in a variety of electronic musical styles. Each time the song changes, the background and block graphics change to a new visual style corresponding to the style of the new song. More importantly, the music has a direct impact on the gameplay, in that the speed of the falling blocks and the line sweeping the screen are tailored to the tempo of the current song.Mode List Challenge Mode:Background skins and music will  changes you progress in the game. This game mode does not have a time limit.Single skin mode:Select a background skin and use the skin throughout the entire game. The background will not change unless the player selects a new skin.Time attack mode:This mode has a time limit of 60, 180, 300 or 600 seconds2P Vs Mode:The playing field is split into two. The more squares you eliminate the larger your part of the field becomes, making it harder for your opponent.Vs CPU Mode:Play by yourself against the CPU opponent in Vs 2 player style gameplay.Puzzle Mode: The CPU will create puzzles with obstacles to overcome. Score limitThe maximum score in the game is 999 999 points. This is supposedly due to the limited battery life of the PSP. Had the maximum score been higher, players might have had problems reaching it because the battery would have run out. Song List Shinin' by     Mondo Grosso  Urbanization by     Brainstorm     Round About by     Brainstorm     Slipping by     Brainstorm  Shake Ya Body by     Brainstorm     Square Dance by     Brainstorm  Talk 2 You by     Brainstorm  Just... by     Brainstorm  I Hear The Music In My Soul by     Eri Nobuchika     Dark Side Beside The River by     Brainstorm      Aback by     Brainstorm  Working In he Hole by     Brainstorm     Sister Walk by     Brainstorm  Da-Di-Do by     Brainstorm  Strangers by     Brainstorm  Holiday In Sumer by     Brainstorm  Take A Dog Out A Walk by     Brainstorm  Big Elpaso by     Brainstorm  My Generation by     Brainstorm  Meguro by     Brainstorm  Spirits by     Brainstorm  Get Up And Go by     Brainstorm  Fly Into The Sky by     Brainstorm  Lights by     Eri Nobuchika     Japanese Form by     Brainstorm  Auto Mobile Industry by     Brainstorm  Please Return My CD by     Brainstorm  Bird Singing In Night by     Brainstorm  Mekong by     Brainstorm  Whoop-De-Do by     Brainstorm  The Spy Loves Me by     Brainstorm  Brash by     Brainstorm  Chinese Restaurant by     Brainstorm      Moon Beam by     Brainstorm  Tin Toy by     Brainstorm  Water, Flower  Lights by     Brainstorm  45 Degrees by     Brainstorm  Prime Factor by     Brainstorm  Rodent by     Brainstorm  Morning Beats by     Brainstorm  Custom Firmware Infamy  Lumines is well known as one of several games that can be used to install a custom firmware onto the console. It is possible to exploit a buffer overflow in the game code by loading a fake game save containing firmware loading code.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10385">Meteos</game><game id="17578">Rez</game><game id="20681">Poker Smash</game><game id="20623">TiQal</game><game id="1896">Tetris</game><game id="21253">Aurora Feint</game><game id="20320">Synaesthete</game><game id="14615">Every Extend</game><game id="8887">Every Extend Extra</game><game id="2320">Every Extend Extra Extreme</game><game id="21181">PixelJunk Eden</game><game id="22034">Rez HD</game><game id="22319">Super Collapse! 3</game><game id="12562">Tetris 2</game><game id="15464">Polarium Advance</game><game id="8669">Exit</game><game id="6382">Archer Maclean's Mercury</game><game id="10673">PQ: Practical Intelligence Quotient</game><game id="1710">Mercury Meltdown</game><game id="20589">Bomberman</game><game id="9046">Capcom Puzzle World</game><game id="20566">PQ: Practical Intelligence Quotient 2</game><game id="25808">Blokus Portable: Steambot Championship</game><game id="28974">Auditorium</game><game id="29086">Unify</game><game id="25127">Space Invaders Extreme 2</game><game id="22383">Otocky</game><game id="23234">Tetris Party</game><game id="26661">0D Beat Drop</game><game id="26861">Tetris 64</game><game id="29186">Chime</game><game id="27236">Numblast</game><game id="29417">Kurulin Fusion</game><game id="11442">Dr. Robotnik's Mean Bean Machine</game><game id="31232">Fractal: Make Blooms Not War</game><game id="30013">Tetris Party Live</game><game id="34287">Chime Super Deluxe</game><game id="37318">AVSEQ</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1837502-box_lumines.png</image></root>