<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5092</id><name>Bully: Scholarship Edition</name><description>OverviewBully: Scholarship Edition is a direct port of Canis Canem Edit, or  Bully as it was also known, from the Playstation 2. The Xbox 360 version of this game has been noted for being quite buggy and glitchy. Generally, the most well known way to fix glitches that occur on the 360 version of the game is to install it to the hard drive. There was additionally a patch released which fixed some, albeit not all of the issues of the game. The main appeal of the 'Scholarship Edition' version of the game is that it features some additional missions and classes that did not appear in the original release of the game.StoryPlayers take on the role of 15 year old student  Jimmy Hopkins. The game opens with his mother and stepfather arriving at the Bullwroth Academy, where they offload Jimmy. The two are intending to go off on an idyllic cruise, and they offload Jimmy at the boarding school in New England. Jimmy has something of a reputation as a troublemaker, and his mother apparently has remarried several times because of him.Bullworth Academy.The game begins with you learning the ropes of the school. Along the way you meet the cliques of the school, and will meet up with  Gary and  Peter. They act as your guides for much of the game opening, and eventually, Gary tries to stab you in the back. Once this happens, as Jimmy, you must earn the respect of each of the cliques and get revenge on Gary. The game is split into six main chapters, though you need only complete the first five to see the credits roll. Below is the general aim of each chapter:Chapter One: Making New Friends and Enemies.Learn the basics of Bullworth Academy, and meet up with Gary and Petey. This is the easiest, and shortest, chapter of the game. This is also the chapter in which Gary betrays both you and Petey.Chapter Two: Rich Kid BluesWhile Jimmy has become a more popular student at the school by this stage, the Preppies still look down on him. During this chapter you must deal with this aspect of school life at Bullworth.Chapter Three: Love Makes the World Go Round.This chapter is set around Christmas at the school. Jimmy manages to get himself involved in a situation with the Greasers' leader, Johnny Vincent and his girlfriend, Lola.Chapter Four: A Healthy Mind in a Healthy Body and Other Lies.This chapter revolves around trying to take on the Jocks at the school. However, to even stand a chance against the Jocks, Jimmy must enlist the help of the Nerds.Chapter Five: The Rise and Fall of Jimmy Hopkins, Aged 15.This is the final chapter of story in the game, and with all the school cliques behind you, you need to take down Gary, and find out who is responsible for the ongoings at the schoolChapter Six: Endless SummerThis is merely the end mode of the game. Basically, you have no story and may complete side missions etc.GameplayBully features some different gameplay from other Rockstar titles. The game relies heavily on minigames that take the role of different school classes. Each class has its own benefit for succeeding. For example, being proficient in English means you can talk your way out of a misdemeanor.You may also earn weapons as your progress. However, unlike in Grand Theft Auto, you do not earn guns. You get weapons a schoolboy may possess, such as a Slingshot. Rather than killing other characters as well, you merely knock them out. Fighting in Bully is an important part of the gameplay, although violence against girls, authority, and younger pupils has very severeHopkins and the Dr. Crabblesnitchconsequences. Not only this, but you may earn different vehicles too. Initially you get a Skateboard early in the game, but you will eventually get bikes as well. You can also win a Go Kart, and purchase a Scooter. As you progress you earn the ability to buy more clothing and equipment for Jimmy. Eventually you can also purchase tattoos for him. You will unlock different areas of the town through game progression, and these areas are:Bullworth TownTrailer ParkAsylumAs you progress through Bully, you will earn money, which you can spend on different equipment. For example, you may purchase Stinkbombs and other such goods to resupply your inventory. Not only this, but there is a fair that opens up when you reach the town area, and take part in one of the Preppie missions. At the fair you can take part in different fairground activities, which will earn you tickets. These tickets can then be redeemed at the store in the fair for exclusive prizes, such as the Scooter, and different posters which can decorate Jimmy's room in the school. Should you choose to purchase a bike in-game, apart from the Scooter (which is the fastest bike you can get), the best all round bike is the Aquaberry, as it has the best blend of stats. Generally, most of the AI opponents will not be using the Aquaberry Bike, which already puts you at an advantage.ClassesThere are 10 different classes in Bully: Scholarship Edition, and they all have five levels each. This means there are 50 individual lessons you are tasked with completing. They must be completed to earn the full 100%.MathematicsMaths questions are given to the player and you must complete a set number within time. Questions range from general sums to basic equations, and are always multiple choice.EnglishYou are given some letters and must form a set number of words to pass the level of the class. It becomes harder with each lesson.ChemistryYou must press the correct button as each prompt passes.BiologyUsing the given tools you must dissect an animal in a suitable manner. Animals range from a rat to a pig, and become harderHopkins in Musiceach level.ArtYou must guide a line around the art paper, and avoid enemies. It plays a lot like the arcade game  Qix, and enemies become more common as you progress.MusicYou must press the correct button as notes pass through them, ala Guitar Hero.GeographyYou must match the names of countries to different countries. This is commonly regarded as the hardest lesson in the game.PhotographyYou are given a camera and are tasked with snapping images of different things.GymThe game has two different Gym lessons. The first lesson is wrestling, where you are taught new moves and given an opportunity to try these moves on an AI character. The other version is Dodgeball, where you are put on the Nerds team, and must beat the other teams.ShopYou simply have to press the buttons in rhythm as they appear on the screen. This is a simple enough class, and as you progress through it, button presses become more complex.CliquesThere are different cliques that all co-exist in Bullworth Academy, and they all have their own leaders and styles. Below is a comprehensive breakdown of each group:NerdsLeader:  Earnest JonesThe Nerds are the weakest clique, but they have the best weapons, and are the most intelligent. They all wear green colored school tops, and are generally bullied by all the other cliques.JocksThis is a Jock. Who happens to be flooring Jimmy.Leader:  Ted ThompsonThe Jocks are physically the strongest clique, and they can withstand a ridiculous amount of damage. However they do not use any weapons, so they are easily outclassed at range with the Slingshot and other such weapons. Jocks are easily found around the football field.GreasersLeader:  Johnny VincentThe Greasers wear leather jackets and look like Grease rejects. However, they are the poorer clique and can be found around the Shop area of the school, as well as in the Trailer Park.PreppiesLeader:  Derby HarringtonThe Preppies are the richest group in the entire school, and wear expensive looking clothing. They are fond of boxing and can be found at the boxing club in Bullworth Town, as well as at the Aquaberry clothing store.BulliesLeader:  Russell NorthropThe Bullies wear white school shirts, which are untucked, and delight in bullying students. They will start fights regardless of their odds of winning.CollectiblesLike all Rockstar games, there are a multitude of different collectibles for you to hunt down. Unsurprisingly, they are all needed for the 100% completion. Bully: Scholarship Edition makes this an easier task through the inclusion of the Geography class, which awards the player with item locations on their map as they progress through the class.Rubber BandsAround the world you may find blue rubber bands. There are 75 of them, and when you collect all of them you get a rubber band ball. This ball is the best weapon in the game as it one hits everyone, including Jocks.Grottos and Gremlins CardsThere are hidden cards from a game the Nerd clique loves, called Goblins and Gremlins (reference to Dungeons and Dragons, clearly). Once you collect all these cards you receive a unique themed costume.GnomesAround the area of Bullworth there are 25 gnomes. Destroying all of them will earn you a gnome costume.TransistorsThere are six radio transistors that you should aim to collect. For every transistor delivered you learn a new, powerful melee attack.Cover ArtCover Art for the Scholarship Edition of the game is the same across all regions. However, it does vary from the art used for  Canis Canem Edit.The art used for the Scholarship Edition of Bully shows artwork of Jimmy Hopkins in a 'staredown' with the school's headmaster,  Doctor Crabblesnitch. This artwork is layered over the background, which is the school crest.TriviaThe original PAL release name for the game was Canis Canem Edit (Latin for "Dog Eat Dog"), as the name Bully was denied by the UK government. For an unknown reason they allowed the Scholarship Edition to pass with the name of Bully.In the Greasers' workshop, you can see the shell of a  Stallion car from GTA. This can also be seen in the manual, where it breaks down the different groups.PC System RequirementsCPU: Intel Pentium 4 (3+ GHZ) / AMD Athlon 3000+RAM: 1GB RAMGPU: DirectX 9.0c Shader 3.0 supported, Nvidia 6800 or 7300 or better, ATI Radeon X1300 or betterOS: Windows XP / Windows VistaHDD: 4.7GB free spaceSound: DirectX 9-compatible sound cardPC PatchThe latest patch (1.200) can be downloaded  here.</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5618">Saints Row</game><game id="20679">Saints Row 2</game><game id="10781">The Godfather: Blackhand Edition</game><game id="9966">Scarface: The World is Yours</game><game id="10953">Driver 2: The Wheelman is Back</game><game id="27256">Kenka Bancho: Badass Rumble</game><game id="22766">Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince</game><game id="16206">The Warriors</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2345920-box_bullyse.png</image></root>