<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5153</id><name>Sacred</name><description>OverviewSacred is an action RPG in the vein of Diablo set in the fantasy world of Ancaria and players can explore a vast 3D overworld and accept quests from the many denizens of Ancaria to gain experience and gold.StoryThe Plot of Sacred follows a necromancer named Shaddar unleashing a Sakkara Demon upon the world. The player takes on the role of the hero that has to rescue the world!GameplayUnlike many RPGs Sacred does not use a mana system for spells and abilities instead utilizing a cooldown system.ClassesPlayers can Choose their character class from one of six character classes:Class nameDescriptionGladiatorA melee focused character.Battle MageA spellcasting focused character.VampiressA melee character that could switch between human and vampire forms.Wood ElfA ranged damage focused character that used bows.Dark ElfA melee character that dual wields blade weapons.SeraphimA divine warrior that uses holy magic. This class was added with the expansion.ExpansionsAn expansion for the game named "Sacred: Underworld" was released in 2005 and added a lot of new content and classes to play. The combined package of the original game and the expansion was later sold as 'Sacred Gold' and is available in that version via digital download platforms like steam and GoG.A sequel was released in 2008 called Sacred 2: Fallen Angel.PC RequirementsSupported OS: Windows 2000/XPProcessor: Intel Pentium® III 800 MHzMemory: 256 MB RAMGraphics: 16 MB DirectX 8 compatible graphics cardDirectX: DirectX® 9.0c Sound: DirectX compatible sound cardHard Drive: 2 GB HD Space</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20803">Diablo III</game><game id="5985">Diablo</game><game id="11806">Silverfall</game><game id="13217">Champions of Norrath</game><game id="8638">Titan Quest</game><game id="13762">Titan Quest: Immortal Throne</game><game id="1119">Diablo II</game><game id="1727">Dungeon Siege II</game><game id="11345">Depths of Peril</game><game id="4673">Fate</game><game id="11583">SpellForce 2: Shadow Wars</game><game id="24818">Orient: A Hero's Heritage</game><game id="25983">Torchlight</game><game id="9789">Beyond Divinity</game><game id="20718">Dungeon Siege III</game><game id="1714">Throne of Darkness</game><game id="15589">Diablo II: Lord of Destruction</game><game id="33494">Dungeons &amp; Dragons Daggerdale</game><game id="32562">Path of Exile</game><game id="5776">Legend of the North: Konung</game><game id="3549">Konung 2: Blood of Titans</game><game id="31832">Konung III: Ties of the Dynasty</game><game id="12">Blade &amp; Sword</game><game id="2059">Dungeon Siege</game><game id="8590">Dawn of Magic</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15693/622685-915057_front_1_.jpg</image></root>