<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5208</id><name>Wrath Unleashed</name><description>General Wrath Unleashed is a strategy game at its root.   Similar to chess pieces the characters are maneuvered around a hex map according to their capabilities (number of hexes allowed per turn, allowed to travel over water/pits, etc) with the objective of capturing the opposing sides temples.  When two combatants meet on a hex battle is engaged in the form of a 3D real-time brawl - the loser is not pre-determined as in chess.   Combat takes place in varying environments depending on the terrain type of the hex and characters sharing the elemental alignment will get a boost, while opposing alignments will suffer a penalty;  neutral alignments get neither.  The battle environments provide cover, manna recharging stations and hazards.  Some characters can cast spells as part of their move as long as they aren't in combat.  Alignments and Characters There are four elemental alignments in Wrath Unleashed:  Air (Dark Chaos Order), Water (Light Order), Fire (Light Chaos Order), and Earth (Dark Order).    Each is represented by a god and a balanced collection of combatants, and playing each alignment is a different experience and strategy due to the difference in character abilities.  Dark Chaos Order (Air) Helamis(god) - Capable of spell-casting: and can heal troops, teleport them across the board, or destroy nearby enemies. Cyclops – Might attacker. Chaos Demon - Attack with lightning attacks and claws. Nightmare Adept - A powerful warlock riding a squid/horse beast, can use the beast to charge attach or a powerful magical attack.  Can cast spells in non-combat turns. Wind Elemental - The wind elemental can be summoned by either Helamis or a Nightmare Adept's spell to attack an enemy on a hex within the caster’s range. Djinn - This floating savage can attack with either a lightning attack, or pummel an enemy with objects hurled via telekinesis. Able to float over voids and water during movement. Spirit Armor - A fierce warrior that attacks with a brutal axe. Dark Wind Unicorn - Can teleport over gaps in the board, and teleport away from enemies in battle, as well as summoning lighting. Wind Centabra - Attacks with a battle axe and lightning-blasts. Dark Order (Earth) Durlock(god) - Capable of spell-casting: can heal troops, teleport them across the board, or destroy nearby enemies. Iron Golem – A mighty attack. Archdemon – Have an earthquake attack and deadly claws. Nightmare Adept - A powerful sorcerer riding a squid/horse-like beast, can use the beast to charge attach or a powerful magical attack.  Can cast spells in non-combat turns. Earth Elemental - The earth elemental can be summoned by either Durlock or a Nightmare Adept's spell to attack an enemy on a hex within the caster’s range. Djinn - This floating savage can attack with either earth magic, or pummel an enemy with objects hurled via telekinesis. Able to float over voids and water during movement. Spirit Armour – A fierce warrior that attacks with a brutal axe. Dark Earth Unicorn - Can teleport over gaps in the board, and teleport away from enemies in battle, as well as summoning earthquakes. Earth Centabra - Attacks with a battle axe and seismic-blasts. Light Chaos Order (Fire) Epothos(god) - Capable of spell-casting: can heal troops, teleport them across the board, destroy nearby enemies. Fire Giant – Lava giants capable of throwing spheres of lava and have massive physical attacks. Flame Dragon - Flying dragons which attack with fierce talons and burning breath. Juggernaut Adept - A powerful sorcerer riding a boar-like beast, can use the beast to charge attach or a magical attack.  Can cast spells in non-combat turns. Fire Elemental - The fire elemental can be summoned by either Epothos or a Juggernaut Adept's spell to attack an enemy on a hex within the caster’s range. Genie - This floating warrior can attack with either fire magic, or pummel an enemy with objects hurled via telekinesis. Able to float over voids and water during movement. Fire Giantess – A fierce warrior that attacks with a huge warhammer. Fire Unicorn - Can teleport over gaps in the board, and teleport away from enemies in battle, as well as using flame on enemies. Fire Centaur - Attacks with a battle axe and fire-blasts. Light Order (Water) Aenna (god) - capable of spell-casting.  Can heal troops, teleport them across the board, destroy nearby enemies. Ogre Mage– Ogres are fierce combatants and can use ice magic.  Frost Dragon – flying dragons with fierce talons and freezing breath.   Juggernaut Adept - A powerful sorcer riding a golden rhino-like beast. Attacks with ice magic and a rhino-charge. Can cast spells in non-combat turns. Water Elemental - A being of pure water, the Elemental is summoned by either Aenna or a Juggernaut Adept's spell for immediate attack on a hex. Genie - This floating warrior can attack with either ice magic, or pummel an enemy with objects hurled via telekinesis. Able to float over voids and water during movement. Frost Giantess – Uses a warhammer to pummel. Water Unicorn - Can teleport over gaps in the board, and teleport away from enemies in battle, as well as summoning freezing rain upon enemies.  Water Centaur - Attacks with a battle axe and water-blasts.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3036">Archon: The Light and the Dark</game><game id="3465">The Unholy War</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2199437-box_wrathun.png</image></root>