<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>522</id><name>Worms 3D</name><description>Gameplay and OverviewThe classic worms gameplay remains untouched in this game. Players still control a team composed of at least 1 worm in a turn based action strategy game. Within their turn players can move their Worm flying around in his jet packworm about using whatever utilities they have until either their time runs out or they execute an attack with a weapon (some weapons allow for 2 uses per turn). After the player finishes their turn either the computer or another player gets his next turn until all teams except one are dead or the fame time runs out.Shotgun being used in First PersonThe worms gameplay was translated directly into 3D without major hiccups however it did suffer a bit from its differences to its predecessors. It was also the first worms game to be released over a large number of consoles which produced very different playing experiences in between them. The ninja rope became very difficult to use, as well as well placed bazooka shootings were difficult to manage with a 3 dimensional wind to consider. Other simpler weapons translated quite well, like the homing pigeon, the air strike, and the jet pack. The vast repertoire of weapons that were quite common before was replaced by a far smaller menu of weapons, but it still retained quite a few classics like the flying sheep, the holy hand grenade, and the concrete donkey.This game also uses both first and third person viewing modes to allow the player to either target more accurately or be able to move through distances in a much easier way. As well as a large overworld view of the map similar to RTS games to command air strikes or teleport through the map.Wind mechanics affect tactical weapons like parachutes! Air Strike en route!Wind mechanics continue to affect many weapons which makes them more devastating but harder to control. The player can see through their interface the current wind speed and direction, as well as other information such as the team's overall health the enemy worms' health and their current position in a map.Playing with friends was still as fun as ever however there was a limit of only up to four teams in play and 6 worms per team total, resulting in much smaller teams and battles. The game still retained many of the old gameplay modes and features, like sudden death, or the rising water in the scenarios, as well as mines and oil drums. Crates still drop from the skies filled with goodies which an experienced player can pick up and use. Also the much higher learning curve in the new 3D environment makes a little difficult for first time players to get a hang of it in contrast of the 2D versions.StoryThere's little to no story in any of the worms games, and this one is no exception. The campaign mode has a very simple story that serves only as a loose connection in between the campaign missions which focuses on the exploits of your team of worms against another team of worms in the never ending worm war. At the end of each stage in the campaign you are treated to a funny cinematic which may or may not include, worms, donkeys, pigeons, sheep, and old ladies.PC System Requirements   Minimum System Requirements:Microsoft Windows 98, Me, 2000 or XP (95/NT unsupported)800 MHz Intel Pentium III or AMD Athlon processor256 MB System RAM8 x CD-ROM/DVD-ROM drive 32 MB video card with 100% OpenGL 1.4 compatibilitySound card with 100% DirectX 9.0a compatibility1.5 GB hard disk space Microsoft Windows 100% compatible keyboard and mouse    Recommended System Requirements:  1 GHz Intel Pentium III or AMD Athlon processor 512 MB System RAM16 x CD-ROM/DVD-ROM drive64 MB video card with OpenGL 1.4 compatibility3D sound card with 100% DirectX 9.0a compatibilityNetwork connection for LAN play56 kbps modem or faster for Wormnet play via GameSpy Arcade16 button, 4 axis game pad with DirectX 9.0a driver (optional) </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16885">Hogs of War</game><game id="2613">Pocket Tanks</game><game id="5413">Future Tactics: The Uprising</game><game id="11999">Worms Forts: Under Siege</game><game id="22008">Raze's Hell</game><game id="14073">Warcraft III: The Frozen Throne</game><game id="21184">Fat Princess</game><game id="21142">FLOCK!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2360881-box_worms3d.png</image></root>