<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5222</id><name>Assault Heroes</name><description>OverviewGame logoAssault Heroes is an arcade-style scrolling dual-joystick shooter where the player drives 4x4s or speedboats, sometimes moving around on-foot. Developed by Wanako Games and published by Sierra Online, the game was originally released as a Xbox Live Arcade game for the Xbox Live Marketplace for 800 msp ($10). Later, it was added to the Arcade Hits category of the Xbox Live Marketplace, dropping its price to 400 msp ($5). The game was also released as a retail package for the PC platform and a downloadable game on the PlayStation Network for $9.99. A sequel, Assault Heroes 2, was also developed for the Xbox Live Marketplace, adding new vehicles, enemies, and the ability to hijack enemy vehicles.The plot is very minimal in this game. As the only surviving member left of an elite forces unit, you're searching for a certain secret laboratory to destroy.GameplayLike most dual-joystick shooters, one stick controls the movement of the player while the right stick directs your gunfire. The objective of the game is to progress through each level, defeating enemies and huge bosses. Vehicle and player health slowly regenerate, while vehicles can be instantly repaired with a special pick-up item. Once your vehicle is destroyed, you run around on foot. You're limited to a weak machine gun, but get double points for destroyed enemies. Once you lose all your health, you lose a life. After about 10 seconds of being on foot, your vehicle respawns.WeaponsThere are three upgradeable weapon types for vehicles:Minigun - Your default weapon. Low damage per bullet, but a high rate of fire. Upgrades increase both the rate of fire and the damage per round.Flamethrower - An arcing, powerful short-ranged weapon. Upgrades increase both the range and damage of the flame.Flak Cannon - Despite its low rate of fire, it can take out armored enemies with relative ease. Upgrades increase the damage per round and the shrapnel caused for each explosion. (Which is a second attack)Setting off a nukeThese weapons are upgraded up to three times each by collecting weapon-specific power-ups on the field. Even if your vehicle explodes, your upgrades remain, and can only be lost when you lose a life.Besides the standard weapons, players can use grenades, nukes, and automatic-firing missile upgrades to deal with enemies. Grenades are more common and can be lobbed at short distances, while nukes are rare radial attacks. Grenades, nukes, and missile upgrades are collected on the field as power-ups.LevelsOne of the game's boss fightsThe main game mode consists of 17 areas, separated into five zones, each ending with a boss fight.Each zone in the game also has a special underground bonus area that can only be accessed by foot. Health is non-regenerating, but there are health packs scattered across the area. Completing these areas earn the player extra lives and count towards the Lair Slayer achievement / trophy.PC System RequirementsWindows 2000/XP/Vista/7Pentium or AMD 1.4GHz Processor512MB RAM60MB Hard Disk SpaceDirectX 9.0c64MB DirectX 9.0c Compatible Video CardDirectX 9.0c Compatible Card</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="31">Dual-Joystick Shooter</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11099">Geometry Wars: Retro Evolved</game><game id="15273">Aegis Wing</game><game id="1619">Ikari Warriors</game><game id="9183">Jackal</game><game id="20467">Wolf of the Battlefield: Commando 3</game><game id="20775">Mutant Storm Empire</game><game id="13155">Heavy Weapon Deluxe</game><game id="10360">Mercs</game><game id="16194">Smash TV</game><game id="19512">Undertow</game><game id="10858">Robotron 64</game><game id="20600">Blast Factor</game><game id="20657">Assault Heroes 2</game><game id="21750">Heavy Weapon: Atomic Tank</game><game id="6823">Apocalypse</game><game id="28063">Zombies 2.0</game><game id="30990">Aqua</game><game id="34423">Gatling Gears</game><game id="34619">Renegade Ops</game><game id="42843">Halo: Spartan Assault</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1169/271313-post_337052_1194908506.jpg</image></root>