<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5269</id><name>Oddworld: Abe's Oddysee</name><description>OverviewOddworld: Abe's Oddysee is the first title in the Oddworld series of games. Originally released in 1997, the game is a side-scrolling 2D platformer that places an emphasis on lateral thinking and solving puzzles. The game was well-received by reviewers, who praised its innovative Gamespeak function and its graphical style. It has spawned multiple successful sequels.PlotThe player first meets Abe, a slave in the meat processing factory Rupture Farms 1029. Abe is a Mudokon, and he with many other Mudokons are slaves to Molluck the Glukkon the owner of Rupture Farms 1029. Abe is a floor waxer for the meat processing plant, and one night he overhears a board meeting.The board meetingDuring this board meeting, Abe overhears the board members talking about their lack of resources for their food. To solve this problem, Molluck proposes to take his Mudokon slaves, and make them into a new product: New N' Tasty Mudokon Pops.Abe manages to escape from Rupture Farms, but accidentally falls off of a cliff. He awakens at the bottom of the cliff with the large moon in sight. Abe see's that a Mudokon handprint is on the surface of the moon. Immediately afterward, a giant floating head appears in front of Abe, and tells him that his name is Big Face.Big Face tells him that he must rescue the other Mudokons from Rupture Farms, before they are made into food. To do this, Abe must travel to the Monsaic Lines and If Abe is able to complete the tests of both temples, Big Face will give Abe a 'scar' on Abe's hand that will allow him to become a powerful being called a Shrykull.Abe returns to Rupture Farms 1029 after both scars are given to him by Big Face. Once Abe returns to Rupture Farms, Abe can rescue at least 50 Mudokons before going to defeat Molluck. Once the player goes to face Molluck, Abe is captured, tied up, and is not able to use his Shrykull Powers. Molluck decides to throw you into a prison cell before making you into the first Modokun Pop.Big Face talks to the other Mudukons and asks them whether or not they want to free you or notEndingAbe's Oddysee has two endings, dependent on the number of Mudokons Abe rescues:If Abe rescues more than fifty Mudokons (like Big Face asked him to do), then the Mudokons will rescue him from Molluck. The Mudokons will use their power of lightning to knock out Molluck, and then Big Face will teleport you, and the other Mudokons out of Rupture Farms into the forest.If Abe does not rescue more than fifty Mudokons, Big Face, and the few Mudokons that escaped from Rupture Farms will not help Abe, and let Molluck put him into the meat grinder in the factory.GamespeakGamespeak commandsOne of the most innovative aspects of Abe's Oddysee's gameplay was the inclusion of the Gamespeak feature. Using Gamespeak, the player is able to interact with, amuse and irritate nearby NPCs. The primary function of Gamespeak in Abe's Oddysee is for Abe to communicate with his Mudokon co-workers and lead them to safety. It can also be used to encourage Mudokons to assist in the solving of puzzles.Possessing creatures such as Sligs brings with it an alternate set of Gamespeak commands specific to that creature. This is largely for entertainment purposes in Abe's Oddysee, but would go on to become an important aspect of puzzle solving in its direct sequel, Abe's Exoddus.SoundtrackThe original score for Abe's Oddysee was composed by Ellen Meijers and Josh Gabriel.Track #Song TitleRunning Time01GT Interactive Logo00.0902Oddworld Inhabitants Logo00.1103Opening00.3004So Get Over it!00.1105This is RuptureFarms03.4206Wanted00.2107RuptureFarms08.1208Barrel Ride00.2509Tension01.1210Slig Action01.0511Free-Fire Zone03.2812Abe's Moon01.2913Monsaic Lines05.4514Entering Paramonia00.1815Paramonia10.0316Entering the Paramonian Temple00.1617Paramonian Temple03.4518Paramonian Slig Action01.0719Paramonian Nest02.1520Paramonian Trials Completed00.2421Entering Scrabania00.1822Scrabania03.0223Entering the Scrabanian Temple00.2024Scrabanian Slig Action00.5625Scrabanian Temple02.4826Scrabanian Nest02.4227Scrabanian Trials Completed00.2328Shrykull Revealed00.1829Board Room00.1730The Factory Halts00.2131Captured00.3432Bad Ending00.2933Good Ending01.2334Bonus Ending: teaser00.3135Credits01.09PC RequirementsPentium 120 MHz (Min.), Pentium 166 (Rec.)SVGA hicolor (16 bit)4x CDROM8MB RAM (Min.), 16MB (Rec.)100% Sound Blaster compatible sound card (Min.), Wavetable sound card (Rec.)Digital Re-releaseThe game was re-released on various digital distribution services like PSN, Steam and GOG.com. Also, a full-blown HD remake with 3D support is on its way for PS3, PS Vita, PC and Xbox 360 in autumn 2013.</description><genres><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="758">Heart of Darkness</game><game id="1066">Flashback: The Quest for Identity</game><game id="17483">Out of This World</game><game id="17785">Heart of the Alien: Out of this World Parts I and II</game><game id="20330">Gex 3: Deep Cover Gecko</game><game id="16167">Dark Castle</game><game id="5729">The Curse of Monkey Island</game><game id="30125">Kahoots</game><game id="36447">Rocketbirds: Hardboiled Chicken</game><game id="35489">The War of the Worlds</game><game id="30380">Limbo</game><game id="36870">Stealth Bastard: Tactical Espionage Arsehole</game><game id="37262">Deadlight</game><game id="23648">Machinarium</game><game id="31721">Rayman Origins</game><game id="24739">Trine</game><game id="31661">Trine 2</game><game id="32314">Dustforce</game><game id="34034">Rochard</game><game id="8896">The Feeble Files</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4938/872380-abe.png</image></root>