<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>53</id><name>Final Fantasy XI Online: Treasures of Aht Urhgan</name><description> Overview   The third expansion in the series was released on April 18, 2006  Highlights of the expansion  Adds three new jobs Blue      Mage, Corsair and Puppetmaster Adds Chocobo Raising,      Chocobo Racing, Chocobo Circuit Adds new battle field called      Pankration Adds Assault, Besieged,      Salvage and Einherjar batlefields Adds 12 new adversaries New mission story line      called Treasures of Aht Urhgan Missions Tons of new quest and      equipment    New Jobs     Puppetmaster     Puppetmaster   Puppetmaster's are able to control a "automation" for entertainment or for combat purposes.  Puppetmaster can also use hand to hand combat in a need raises.  Corsair   Corsairs use a weapon called a "Hexagun", basically a multi-barreled revolver.  They also are good party buffers when it comes to their luck based abilites which they can roll dice and change the way a battle plays out.   Blue Mage    Blue Mages are able to use the abilities of monster found across Vana'diel.  They usually are duel wielders that will fight on the front line and using magic attacks to kill their enemies.    New Battle Systems  Many unique new battle systems were added with this expansion:  Assault  - Instanced battlefield      areas where the player, and a group of 3 to 6 people level 50 or higher,      perform assigned tasks ranging from clearing an area of enemies, to      finding captured NPCs. Players are rewarded with Assault Points which can      be used to obtain items specific to each zone. One specific Assault area, known      as Nyzul Isle, has player ascending 100 floors and completing a randomly      set task on each floor. You can obtain many very good armor pieces after      defeating the bosses at every twenty floor interval, and you also could      receive a weapon upon completion of the 100th floor, which is the base      plate of a newer "relic" type weapon. Besieged  - The lower ward of Aht      Urhgan known as Al Zahbi is under attack by the beastmen armies, looking      to capture the mysterious Astral Candescence. Players battle in the area against      the enemy along with many NPCs, which, if not fallen/captured in the      course of battle, provide players with many helpful items. Defeat of the      five Serpent General, will allow for the door sealing the Astral      Candescence to open and allow of the beastmen to take it. If this occurs,      players much head out into the dangerous enemy strongholds, and get it      back. Salvage  - Taking place in one of      the five wings of the Alzadaal Undersea Ruins, Salvage is a true test of      teamwork for a group of 6 to 18 players. As soon as the group enters, the      Pathos of Alzadaal limits the abilities of all players who enter,      including the ability to equip armor. Players must find key items to      unlock their abilities again, and make their way up the five floors to      defeat the boss at the end. Some monsters within the zones drop level 15,      25, and 35 armor pieces which are required to complete a quest to obtain      level 75 armor pieces, some of which are the considered the best pieces      available thus far for certain jobs. Einherjar  - The Hazhalm Testing      Grounds are the site of this large scale battlefield area. Designed for      groups of up to 36 people level 60 and up, Einherjar is a race against the      clock to defeat enemy swarms, and a final boss monster. There are four      wings, and three chambers within the first three  wings for players      to navigate. You must complete each chamber in a wing to advance to the      next wing. Rewards are given for the amount of monsters cleared in the      form of "Therion Ichor", which are accumulated to obtain items,      and also items are given for completion of the chamber. Ascent to the      final chamber will have you fight a very well known character in the Final      Fantasy series, Odin. Defeat of him rewards you handsomely with Abjuration      items which can be upgraded into superior armor pieces.   Soundtrack   The Treasures of Aht Urhgan soundtrack was released on May 29, 2006, and was re-released as part of the FINAL FANTASY XI Premium Box on March 27, 2008   01 - Bustle of the Capital 02 - Eastward Bound... 03 - Bandits' Market 04 - Illusions in the Mist 05 - Mercenaries' Delight 06 - Jeweled Boughs 07 - Ululations from Beyond 08 - Rapid Onslaught -Assault- 09 - Fated Strife -Besieged- 10 - Delve 11 - Whispers of the Gods 12 - Circuit de Chocobo13 - Run Chocobo, Run! 14 - The Colosseum 15 - Black Coffin 16 - A Puppet's Slumber 17 - Ever-Turning Wheels 18 - Forbidden Seal 19 - Hellriders 20 - Eternal Gravestone  21 - Vana'diel March #4 </description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22997">The Lord of the Rings Online: Mines of Moria</game><game id="6204">EverQuest: The Shadows of Luclin</game><game id="21458">White Knight Chronicles: International Edition</game><game id="27896">World of Warcraft: Cataclysm</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4086/201815-tau_box.jpg</image></root>