<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5409</id><name>Black Dahlia</name><description>Black Dahlia is a PC adventure game released on February 28th, 1998 by Take-Two Interactive. The Story, while fictional, was inspired by the real life Cleveland Torso Murderer and the infamous murder Elizabeth Short in Los Angeles.The game is a puzzle based FMV adventure game that ties Elizabeth Short's murder to Nazi's and occult rituals, which the player has to investigate. While the game features Dennis Hopper and Teri Garr, they only appear briefy in the game.PlotAgent Pearson is the newest member of the COI, and is somewhat  dejected to find the job not as glamorous as he was initially told.  After being given a case where a local munitions manufacturer was  invited to join the Thule society, Pearson is puzzled by the apparent  connections with Nazi occultism. Along the way he encounters Agent  Winslow, apparently a bumbling Federal agent who is more concerned with  his press appearance than solving cases. After making a connection between the Thule society and the Cleveland  torso murders, Pearson leads a local detective to the butchers lair  after finding bizzare Gaelic documents left by his predecessor regarding  a ritual involving Odin and a gemstone called the Black Dahlia, which  is a key instrument that can render a ritual user the ability to control  dreams. Years later, Pearson is a member of the OSI, and recovers the Dahlia  from a Nazi bunker, but it is quickly snatched away and then sold on the  black market by a corrupt quartermaster. Following the Dahlia, Pearson  again encounters Winslow, a Nazi SS operative following the final orders  of Hitler to perform the Dahlia ritual. Pearson pursues Winslow across the USA, finally cornering him in a  California home, where Winslow has just completed the final ritual  murders regarding the Dahlia. After tearing out his own eye and  performing the remainder of the ritual, the player has one choice with  his pistol. If he shoots Winslow or hesitates, Winslow stabs himself,  and possesses Pearson, becoming an American version of Hitler, and able  to control large portions of the populace through their dreams. If  Pearson destroys the Dahlia, Winslow dies and Pearson is blamed for the  locals spree of killings, though he is overjoyed and content with having  stopped the Nazi plot to take over the world.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17544">Broken Sword: The Shadow of the Templars</game><game id="3970">Myst</game><game id="17368">Morpheus</game><game id="15611">Ripper</game><game id="20056">9: The Last Resort</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/6/64555/1197730-balck_dahlia_cover.png</image></root>