<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5464</id><name>Grind Session</name><description>OverviewGrind Session is a skateboarding game developed by Shaba Games and published by Sony Computer Entertainment on April 29, 2000 exclusively for the PlayStation. It was developed as a console-exclusive competitor to the then-extremely popular Tony Hawk's Pro Skater. The game was grounded in more realistic physics, featured a host of real-world parks and the original concept of "trick lines". The trick lines in the game were similar to the gaps in the Tony Hawk games, except the trick lines gained you "respect", the game's progression system. Respect is what unlocks levels. The game was received by critics with an average-to-good response but, commercially, wasn't as big a seller as Sony had hoped. The game was criticized for it's limited re-playability and extremely short list of pro skaters.The developer, Shaba Games, went on to develop the PlayStation entries of Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3 and 4 in collaboration with Neversoft.Pro SkatersWilly SantosDaewon SongEd TempletonCara-beth BurnsidePigpenJohn CardielSecret SkatersGrind Session had a large cast of interesting secret characters. Each secret character was unlocked by unlocking the photo shoot and getting 8000 points in one trick.Pro SkaterSecret CharacterDescriptionWilly SantosSkatora RobotCara-BethHangmana chalk drawn stick manEd TempletonDemona demonJohn CardielStanleyan green alien with a large head and black eyesDaewon SongRexa Tyrannosaurus RexPigpenDave CarnieEditor in Chief of Big Brother MagazineMale CustomStingerHumanoid BeemanFemale CustomGolgothaHuman like monsterLevelsTraining LevelDa Banks (NYC)S.F. MissionBurnsideSlam City JamAtlantaPlaystation Park LondonDetroitHuntingtonDreamhouseSoundtrackIn the Mind Of A Bourgeois Reader - Sonic YouthLinoleum - NOFXGalaxie Express - CorneliusRise Above - Black FlagBlue Flowers (Technical Difficulties) - Dr. OctagonPublicity - GZAJayou - JurassicOut For Fame - KRS-oneMan or Astro-man? - Television FissionRaida's Theme - The X-ecutionersEmpty Heart - Zen Guerrilla</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="23">Skateboarding</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2101">Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 4</game><game id="2341">Mat Hoffman's Pro BMX</game><game id="18624">Thrasher Presents: Skate and Destroy</game><game id="22106">3 Xtreme</game><game id="37026">Tony Hawk's Pro Skater HD</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/26/1165782-grindsession.jpg</image></root>