<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5471</id><name>Shin Nekketsu Kouha Kunio-kun: Kunio-tachi no Banka</name><description>Shin Nekketsu Kouha Kunio-kun: Kunio-tachi no Banka (New Hotblooded Rowdy Kunio-Kun: The Eulogy of Kunio's Friends) is a beat-em-up released in 1994 for the Super Famicom by Technos Japan. The game was one of the last games in the long-running Kunio-kun series to be developed and published by Technos Japan. Notable for being a dark, gritty reboot of the then incredibly popular (in Japan) Kunio-kun franchise, Kunio-tachi no Banka has players fighting their way through a murder mystery.StoryA young couple is murdered in a brutal hit-and-run accident and juvenile delinquents Kunio and Riki are falsely accused of the couple's death. Thrown into a juvenile crime center for a crime they swear they did not commit, Kunio and Riki must escape incarceration and beat the crap out of everyone they can in order to find out who was really behind the hit and run accident.The story and feel of the game is overwhelmingly dark, a stark contrast to the lighthearted whimsy found in other Kunio-kun titles. The main characters use swear words often, the violence is less cartoony and more gritty, and the characters seem a lot edgier than in past Kunio-kun titles.GameplayKunio-tachi no Banka is your standard beat-em-up. Players get the requiste punch, kick, jump, and block buttons, plus can access a special attack by pressing block and any attack button at the same time. In addition to this, players have a "back attack" button which allows them to attack enemies that get behind them, and by pressing select players can cycle between different playable characters. The game contains four playable characters: Series mascot Kunio and his girlfriend Misako for player 1, and sometime Series antagonist Riki and his girlfriend Kyouko.Bike racing scenes are sprinkled throughout the game to give the player a break from beating stuff up on foot and play somewhat similar to the video game Road Rash.LegacyKunio-tachi no Banka would wind up being, as of this date, the very last original non-sports game in the Kunio-kun series. The game was not released in non-Japanese territories and was followed by two more titles, the food-themed puzzle game Kunio no Oden and a King of Fighters-esque remake of Super Dodge Ball for the Neo Geo. Neo Geo Dodgeball would become the company's last name, and members of the Kunio-kun would later go on to form Million, who would eventually by the rights to the games back and remake/re-release many classics from the series's heyday.An English translation was released by fantranslation group Aeon Genesis in 2002.Also, the action racing game Super Mad Champ was based on the motorcycle levels of Kunio-tachi no Banka.SoundtrackTrack:Title:Length:01Midnight Run01:5502Mode Select00:2003Going to Jail00:2804Inside Prison01:2505Jail Fight01:4006Escape Plan00:4907Kunio's Breakout01:4308Great Escape00:2509Misako's Theme01:1310Nekketsu High School01:5611Confrontation00:3312School Fight01:3713Enemy Territory02:2014Amusement Park01:3815Roller Coaster02:2316Heated Battle02:2317Bike Scene01:4718Docks02:2819Underground02:2920Shinji's Hideout02:2921Encounter00:3322Beauty and the Beast02:0523Disco Almanic02:2724Yakuza Battle01:5925Misuzu's Theme01:4526Vanishing Tears02:3527Kunio's Eulogy04:0528Countryside02:1729Sabu's Mansion02:2930Battle Against Ken02:0831Ending Theme02:1032Game Over00:04b01Unused Song 102:29b02Unused Song 200:43</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6608">River City Ransom</game><game id="19366">Battletoads &amp; Double Dragon: The Ultimate Team</game><game id="22857">Battletoads</game><game id="20436">Streets of Rage</game><game id="5423">Double Dragon II</game><game id="34840">GP Fight</game><game id="37279">Super Mad Champ</game><game id="7711">Super Double Dragon</game><game id="37255">Rokudenashi Blues</game><game id="6722">Final Fight</game><game id="33387">UFO Kamen Yakisoban: Kettler no Kuroi Inbou</game><game id="33254">Zoku: The Legend of Bishin</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/14/149200/2097893-kunio001.jpg</image></root>