<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5541</id><name>Hard Truck 2</name><description>OverviewHard Truck 2 is a continuous driving simulator. You play the role of a trucker making a living delivering products from city to city in a region covered by a continuous network of roads. Every town has a depot where orders for goods and materials are made. Profit margins depend on the shortage or surplus of each product so the driver who gets to the destination first will be rewarded. There are no levels to attain or complete. You simply travel from job to job, scratching out a living while trying to get ahead. You'll experience day and night driving as well as various weather conditions. Your pager will notify you of the races that are held occasionally. By delivering an order first or by winning a race, you will be awarded a license to hire a new driver to start a company. You're not alone however, as there are other business owners looking to control the market. The first one to 51% wins.FeaturesContinuous network of road ways with a variety of surfaces as well as hidden paths.Dynamic weather and a day/night cycle.Realistic (for its time) 3D graphics, including dynamic lighting.Many special effects, including tire marks, exhaust, lens flare, rain, and fog.Realistic physics.Complete built-in economic system.Three different multi-player modes.Travel to 11 different depots, from an airport, to a harbor, to a secret military base.Several drivable trucks by popular manufacturers, such as; Peterbuilt, Mack, Kenworth, Renault, Volvo, Freightliner, and Mercedes-Benz</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12732">Hard Truck: Road to Victory</game><game id="16901">Hard Truck: 18 Wheels of Steel</game><game id="7342">18 Wheels of Steel: Pedal to the Metal</game><game id="14758">18 Wheels of Steel: Across America</game><game id="5486">Bus Driver</game><game id="21324">18 Wheels Of Steel: Haulin'</game><game id="22153">Rig'n'Roll</game><game id="22077">Hard Truck</game><game id="4005">King of the Road</game><game id="24376">Rig Racer 2</game><game id="25587">18 Wheels of Steel American Long Haul</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8991/227738-hardtruck2cover.jpg</image></root>