<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5552</id><name>Warriors Orochi</name><description>OverviewWarriors Orochi is a hack and slash video game developed by Koei and Omega Force. It is a crossover of the Dynasty Warriors and Samurai Warriors series. The game was released in Japan on March 21, 2007 and the following September in the US, Europe, Australia and New Zealand.In the game's story mode there are four different storylines: Wei, Wu, Shu and the Samurai Warriors storyline. The player can play as any of the 77 characters from the Dynasty Warriors and Samurai Warriors series.Gameplay is focused around a Team Battle System introduced in the game that allows the player to go into battle with a team of three characters. At any time, one warrior will be fighting while the other two are resting, restoring their health and Musou. The player can switch out the active character for a reserve at the press of a button.The game also introduced a new Weapon Fusion system, allowing the player to combine attributes from different weapons to make a single, more powerful weapon.There is also a Free Mode, allowing the player to play any previously cleared scenario with teams comprised of any characters that have been unlocked.Xbox 360 InstallationThe amount of memory it takes to install this game is 5.7 GB.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20816">Dynasty Warriors 6</game><game id="10139">Samurai Warriors</game><game id="20871">Samurai Warriors 2: Xtreme Legends</game><game id="10040">N3: Ninety-Nine Nights</game><game id="6597">Dynasty Warriors 4</game><game id="3757">Dynasty Warriors 5</game><game id="1224">Dynasty Warriors 3</game><game id="21424">Dynasty Warriors: Gundam</game><game id="21972">Samurai Warriors 2: Empires</game><game id="21742">Dynasty Warriors 4: Xtreme Legends</game><game id="6513">Bladestorm: The Hundred Years' War</game><game id="15569">Genji: Days of the Blade</game><game id="23748">Dynasty Warriors Online: Dance of the Divine General</game><game id="23198">Samurai Warriors 2</game><game id="26881">Warriors: Legends of Troy</game><game id="26379">Witches</game><game id="23839">Devil Kings</game><game id="23946">Sengoku Basara: Battle Heroes</game><game id="26889">Undead Knights</game><game id="15413">Dynasty Warriors 2</game><game id="35701">Sengoku Basara Chronicle Heroes</game><game id="36291">One Piece: Pirate Warriors</game><game id="37103">Sengoku Basara 3 Utage</game><game id="38478">Sengoku Basara HD Collection</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2126458-box_worochi.png</image></root>