<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5607</id><name>Project Gotham Racing 4</name><description>Driving in the rainProject Gotham Racing 4 is an Xbox 360 racing game developed by Bizarre Creations and published by Microsoft. It is the last Project Gotham game to be developed by Bizarre Creations, who were acquired by Activision Blizzard in 2007. Bizzare Creations released a statement through Activision the same year announcing that PGR 4 will be their last game produced for Microsoft Game Studios, who own the rights to the Project Gotham Racing brand, so any future releases to the series will not be Bizarre Creations-developed.PGR4 features 120 licensed vehicles, with motorcycles making their first appearance in the series. The makeup of the vehicle selection is more reminiscent of the first two games in the series than of PGR3, which features more supercars than actual production vehicles.Online modes include the usual ranked and player/custom matches, as well as daily and weekly tournaments, which must first be qualified for by setting a fast lap. The tournaments then run on a knockout basis over multiple rounds.The PGR series is also known for the Geometry Wars games, including them as extra content, generally through a virtual coin-op in the player's garage. PGR4 is no different, with a new version of the modern classic SHMUP, in Geometry Wars Waves, which was later included in Geometry Wars: Retro Evolved 2 on the XBLA.New FeaturesCareer ModeThe Biggest change to the game over its predecessor was the expansion of the career mode. Users no longer just compete for trophies, but there is now a proper calendar system in place, with various tournaments and majors taking place throughout the year, along with invitationals to special events in order to win cars and gain access to higher races.Advanced Weather SystemThe other big change over PGR 3 was the new weather system, a first for the franchise, which affected the look of the game and the physics of the cars on the track. The weather can change from sun to rain to snow to hail within a single race. The game simulates ten types of weather, including clear days, clouds, light to stormy rain, fog, snow and ice. In user-created races, weather is fully customizable along with all other race features. During the career mode the weather is predetermined, rather then generated at random.TracksThe game brings back all of the tracks from PGR 3, and introduces new tracks based in Shanghai, St. Petersburg, Macau, and Quebec City, as well as the Michellin Test Track.Track ListLas VegasBig Apple LoopFlamingo StraitsBuccaneer LoopTropicana TourSpring Mountain TurnsSouth Strip LoopLas Vegas Boulevard TourBoulevard StraitsShort RunNorth Vegas RunSouth Vegas RunThe Grand RunLondonHer Majesty's PleasureThe BirdcageEmbankment RushWhitehall StraitsThe BulldogThe Old City LoopWestminister TourTrafalgar TourDown the MallThornbury CornerOld City EastSt James ParkNew YorkWorth  Walker StreetBroadway RunCity Hall ParkThe OutskirtsPark RowBrooklyn Bridge StraitThe Bridge TourPark to TillaryCenter  BroadwayFoley Square LoopWhite Street BendsChapel Street CornerNurburgringHalf F1 CircuitFull F1 CircuitNordschleife LongThe BehemothSchwedenkreuzWippermanFuchsrohreSchwalbenschwanzKlostertalMetzgesfeldAntoniousbuchePflanzgarten LongTokyoShinjuku Kabukicho LoopTochomae LoopThe Good TomorrowEkimae LoopBark To The SunNishiguchi ShortShinjuku SpeedwayShinjuku SkyscraperOedo ChaseThe Triangle BuildingShinjuku TourCrazy TurnsMacauInstituto PolitecnicoAvenida da AmizadeGuia Hill ParkEstrada de S. FranciscoAvenida de Dr. RodriguesEstrada de CacilhasAvenida de M. BaptistaGuia HairpinHotel LisboaAvenida da Praia GrandeGrand Prix BuildingShanghaiThe Grand TheatreNeon TourB-CircuitPeople's RaceShanghai Old TownXizhang RoadShanghai Grand SlamJiu Fu LoopLandmark TourPeople's AvenueOn the BundMuseum LoopShanghai OpenSt. PetersburgNevskiy RunEmbankments and ParksThe Hermitage RacePushkin's PlacesKazanskiy CathedralMoika TurnsThe AdmiraltyThe City Center LoopChannel TourGreat Peter's WalkArtist's Square CirclePalace SquareQuebecLa Haute-VilleGrand City TourAbraham's BattlefieldRampart RunLa Basse-VilleOld Port ShortLa Grande AllaeChateau FrontenacTwisted Old PortCity Hall DetourFountain SquareParliament HillMichelin Test TrackThe OvalThe Short TestThe Medium TestThe Long TestThe Complex TestThe Ultimate TestSkid PanCar ListAlfa Romeo1989 SZAriel2006 Atom 300 SuperchargedAston Martin1961 DB4 GT Zagato2004 DBR92005 V8 Vantage2007 Vanquish S V122008 DBSAudi2006 RS42007 R8Austin1964 Mini Cooper SBentley2004 Continental GTBMW1979 M1 Procar2004 M5 (E60)2005 K1200R2006 F800SBSA1961 Goldstar DBD34Buell1988 RR 1200Buick1987 Regal GNXCadillac2003 Sixteen ConceptCallaway1988 Sledgehammer Twin TurboCaparo2007 T1Caterham2000 R500Chevrolet1963 Corvette Stingray1969 Camaro Z281995 Corvette C4 ZR-12006 Corvette C6 Z06Dodge1998 Viper GT2 Championship Edition2003 Viper Competition Coupe2006 Challenger ConceptDMC1981 DeLorean DMC-12Ducati2001 9982005 Monster S4RS Testastretta2005 999R Xerox2006 Sports Classic Paul Smart Edition 1000 LEFerrari1962 250 GTO1968 Ferrari 365 GTB/41987 F401988 288 GTO Evoluzione1988 Testarossa1996 F50 GT1998 F355 F1 GTS2003 Enzo2004 F4302005 FXX2006 599 GTB ForianoFord1966 GT40 Mk II1968 Mustang Fastback GT1986 Sierra Cosworth RS500 Cosworth2005 GTGMC1991 SycloneGumpert2005 ApolloHarley Davidson1994 VR 1000Honda1960 RC1611992 NSX-R1992 NR750 (RC40)2005 CBR 600RRJaguar1955 D-Type1993 XJ220 SJoss2004 SupercarKawasaki2007 Ninja ZX-14Koenigsegg2006 CCXLamborghini1972 Miura P400 SV1978 Countache LP4002000 Diablo V.T. 6.0 SE2004 Gallardo2006 Murcialago R-GT2006 M-Concept2007 Murcialago LP640Lancia1973 Stratos HF1991 Delta Integrale EvoluzioneLCC2006 RocketLotus1964 Cortina1966 Europa S11981 Esprit Essex Turbo2008 Exige GT3RRMaserati1957 250F2004 MC12MazdaRX-7MX-5McLaren1995 F1 LMMercedes1998 CLK GTR SuperSport2005 SLR2006 CLK-DTM AMG (C209)Mitsubishi2006 Lancer Evolution VIII FQ400MTT2006 Turbine SuperbikeMV Agusta2006 F4 Brutale 910R2006 F4 SennaNorton1962 500 ManxPagani2005 Zonda FPalmer Sport2003 Palmer Jaguar JP1Panoz1997 GTR-1Peugeot2007 Flux ConceptPlymouth1970 Hemi CudaPontiac1983 FirebirdRadical2004 SR3 Turbo2006 SR9 LMP2Rossion2007 Q1RUF2087 CTR "Yellowbird"2005 Supercar Concept2005 RGT2006 RT122007 RK CoupeSaleen2005 S7 Twin Turbo2006 S281 ExtremeShelby1966 Cobra 427 S/C1967 GT500ESpyker2003 C8 Laviolette LWBSSC2007 Ultimate Aero TTSubaru1998 Impreza 22B STiSuzuki2006 GSX-R1300R Hayabusa Limited Edition2006 GSX-R600 K62006 GSX-R1000 K5Tesla2008 RoadsterToyota1967 2000GT1993 Supra1998 GT-oneTriumph1970 Trident2005 Speed TripleTVR2004 Sagaris2005 TyphonUltima2006 GTRVanwall2005 GPR V12Yamaha2007 YZF-R6Downloadable ContentTwo downloadable content packs were released for PGR4 on February 14, 2008. The Free Challenge Pack includes one new car, the 2007 Peugeot Flux, as well as two new online game types. The first, Tourist Mode, is essentially a sandbox mode for the game. It allows you to roam around each city freely for a set amount of time. Whoever has the most Kudos when the time runs out is considered the "winner," but the mode is more about exploring the city and making up game types than actually competing for Kudos. The second mode is Free Roam Cat  Mouse, which, as the name suggests, takes PGR4's cat  mouse mode and puts it in a free-roaming environment.The Premium Challenge Pack costs 400 Microsoft points, and includes everything featured in the Free Challenge Pack, as well as six additional cars--the 1987 BMW M3 E30 DTM, 2008 Callaway C16 Speedster, 2008 Chevrolet Camaro Convertible Concept, 2007 Ferrari 430 Scuderia, 2008 Honda S2000 CR, and 2007 Volkswagen Golf GTI W12-650--three additional bikes--1995 Aprilia RS 250, 1998 Aprilia RSV 1000 Tuono R, and 2007 Yamaha YZF-R1--and another mode: World Challenge Mode. World Challenge Mode contains 20 arcade events split into three chapters. The first chapter, Platinum Plus, is an Arcade chapter featuring extremely hard challenges. The second chapter, DLC Challenge, limits vehicle choice to those included in the Premium Challenge Pack, and the third chapter, Arcade Challenge, is similar to the Arcade events that shipped with the game.The downloadable content also adds 10 new achievements. Seven of these can be obtained with only the Free Challenge Pack, but three require you to purchase the Premium Challenge Pack in order to earn them.Soundtrack120 Days - Come Out Come Down Fade Out Be GoneAuto Aggression - The Sky Is Not YoursBeethoven - Symphony No. 5Bloc Party - PrayerBlue Scholars - Sagaba (Remix)Chick Corea Elektric Band - Check Blast!!! - Heart of HeartsCovenant - The MenCrystal Method - Keep Hope Alive (There Is Hope Mix)Disturbed - StrickenE Da Boss - Go LeftEdge of Dawn - EleganceFlesh Field - Forgotten TraumaGoldfrapp - Lovely 2 C U (T. Raumschmiere Remix)Goose - Black GlovesGrieg - In the Hall of the Mountain KingGrits - Bobbin' Bouncin'Hot Chip - Over And OverHummel - Rondo in E FlatIncubus - Light GrenadesInsekt - IsolatedKaiser Chiefs - RubyKarl Denson's Tiny Universe - The BridgeKittie - Funeral for YesterdayLady Sovereign - Blah BlahLCD Soundsystem - Watch the TapesLily Allen - Take What You TakeLiszt - Hungarian Waltz No. 2Lupe Fiasco - The InstrumentalMaximo Park - Our VelocityMendelssohn - Violin Concerto in E MinorMetro - Mr FruityMind.In.A.Box. - IdentityMozart - Eine Kleine NachtmusicMozart - Sonata - alla TurcaMy Chemical Romance - House of WolvesNatacha Atlas - BathaddakOjos De Brujo - ColorOjos De Brujo - Todo TiendePride and Fall - Border (Club Edit)Priestess - Everything That You AreProphet Omega - Hit the DeckRImsky Korsakov - Flight of the BumblebeeRotersand - DTLRussell Gunn - East St. LouisSaliva - King of the StereoSeabound - Scorch the Ground (Rotersand Mix)Soma Rasa - One Hand HighSquarepusher - ExcitonThe Pinker Tones - In Pea We NutsThe Roots - Here I ComeThe Shins - AustraliaTV On the Radio - Wolf Like MeWagner - The Ride of the ValkyriesWolfmother - DimensionZeke - Ride to LiveZuco103 - GarganteiroXbox 360 Game InstallationProject Gotham Racing 4 requires 6.0GB of space to be installed on an Xbox 360 HDD.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2213169-box_pgr4.png</image></root>