<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5618</id><name>Saints Row</name><description>OverviewSaints RowSaints Row is an Xbox 360 title that takes its influences from the Grand Theft Auto and Getaway games. The story follows the player in his quest to help the Third Street Saints try to earn respect and territory in Stilwater, a fictional city that is plagued by gang violence. The Xbox 360 exclusive game was released on August 29, 2006 in the US, although a port for the PlayStation 3 was announced, it was shorty thereafter canceled. All of Volition's resources were shifted to work on the game's sequel, Saints Row 2 , which was released on October 14th, 2008. At the time of the game's release it was critically acclaimed for its graphics, mainly because it was the first next-gen sandbox/GTA-like game. Producer Dan Sutton has claimed the reason for the PlayStation 3 version's cancellation was that Volition couldn't grasp the PlayStation 3's cell processor, claiming it was simply too complicated. Luckily, Sony assisted Volition with the harder parts of the cell allowing the studio to develop Saints Row 2 for the PlayStation 3.Borrowed and Improved ElementsMany game elements were borrowed and improved upon from games from the Grand Theft Auto and Getaway franchises:The "Forgive and Forget" which is used to get rid of the players wanted level, is similar to the Pay'n'Spray from the  Grand Theft Auto series.In addition to a police wanted system, similar to GTA, there is also a wanted system for with whatever gang/faction is chasing you.A  GPS system was added to make navigating to mission targets easier and less time consuming.Restarting a mission could be done with one hit of a button, to avoid having to drive/walk all the way to the mission start point again.Players can now fully create and customize their character from the get-go, giving the player creation much more depth than it's competitors.Cars are more customizable, allowing players to add new parts and different types of paint to their rides.Garages are more expansive, allowing players to store more vehiclesThe player character can not only  swim, but has the ability to warp to dry land as soon as he sets foot in the water.StillwaterPlayer stealing a car. Stilwater is a fictional east-coast-like US city that is troubled with gang violence. The city is ruled by three gangs: Los Carnales, Westside Rollerz, and the Vice Kings. The Third Street Saints are trying to take back the power and respect that they once had and seek revenge on the other gangs. The player's goal is to assist the Third Street Saints in achieving this.PlotIn Saints Row you play as a nameless and (almost) silent character. In the beginning of the game you are caught in a gang fight between Los Carnales, the Vice Kings, and the Westside Rollerz Over A Graffiti. However, you are saved and immediately recruited by Julius, leader of the 3rd Street Saints. Throughout the game your goal is to take over enemy areas In enemy strongholds, and kill all of the gang kingpins so the 3rd Street Saints can, once again, take over Stilwater. Each of three rival gangs (Los Carnales, Westside Rollerz, Vice Kings) have their own mission path and the player can do each of them at any time during the game.Gangs 3rd Street SaintsLeader: Julius LittleSpecialty: StrongholdsTurf: 3rd Street  Los CarnalesLeaders: Hector and Angelo LopezSpecialty: Weapons And DrugsTurf: South Side Industrial and the Airport  Vice KingsLeader: Benjamin King, Warren Williams and Anthony Green a.k.a Fat TonySpecialty: ExtortionTurf: Red Light District, Museum District, and Retail District  West Side RollerzLeader: Joseph Price and William SharpSpecialty: Pimping VehiclesTurf: Chinatown, Sub-Urbs, and the ArenaActivitiesIn Saints Row, you need to earn respect in order to play storyline missions and strongholds. Respect is earned primarily through activities.1. SnatchDrive around Stilwater and steal "hoes" from pimps.2. HijackingThe name says it all. In this activity, you need to jack vehicles by damaging them just enough to force the driver out, then escape, usually with cops or other gangs on your tail.3. Insurance FraudIn Insurance Fraud, you dive into incoming traffic to score points. However, you have to stay inside a specific area to do so.4. Chop ShopYou need to find the cars the shop orders, and then modify them according to guidelines. Some of the rarer cars can be really hard to find though.5. RacingIt's a race. You need to get to the finish line before the other Racers. I'm sure you've heard of the concept.6. Drug TraffickingYou ride shotgun as a dealer makes his rounds. It can get really intense in later levels, as you'll be harassed from every angle.7. HostageTo start Hostage, simply jack a car that has an extra passenger inside. You need to avoid cops and maintain your speed to keep the hostage from escaping. If you keep this up long enough, you'll earn some money and respect.8. HitmanA very challenging activity. You need to activate targets in the menu, which will cause them to appear as a crosshair on the minimap if you get close enough to them. Not only are they very hard and time-consuming, but you also have to kill them with a specific weapon! You're going to need a lot of patience for this one.9. MayhemIn Mayhem, you simply attempt to do as much damage to Stilwater as possible. Anything will give you points, running people and stuff over, blowing up cars, etc. You can get a combo by taking out stuff in rapid succession to help boost your score.10. EscortIn Escort, you drive around while a hooker does her thing in the back. The clients don't like media attention though, so you must avoid them at all costs. WeaponsMeleeFistsBaseball BatCrowbarKnifeNightstickPistolsVice 9NR4.44 ShepherdGDHC .50SMGsSKR-7 SpreeT3K UrbanShotguns12 GaugeAS12 RiotPimp CaneTombstoneRiflesAR-40 XtndK6 KrukovMcManusSpecialRPGThrownMolotov CocktailGrenadePipe BombMultiplayerThe game features many multiplayer modes, including several co-op missions.Protect the PimpIn Protect the Pimp, the goal is to kill the pimp of the opposing team, while your team attempts to defend your own pimp.Big Ass ChainsA mode in which the players need to kill another player, pick up their chain, and deliver it to the drop off point to earn points.Gangsta Brawl and Team Gangsta BrawlThese are deathmatch and team deathmatch modes respectively.The game also allows players to create gangs and join gangs online. CollectiblesThere are many collectibles in Saints Row. There are 60 CDs to collect and (just like GTA games in the past) it has many tagging spots too. The CDs will get you both an achievement and a new song for every 10 you receive while the tags will give you respect to allow you to begin new missions and will also give you an achievement.SoundtrackSaints Row features a licensed soundtrack of over 130 songs covering a wide variety of genres from Classical composers such as Beethoven to newer rock bands such as Fall Out Boy. The songs can be heard on various radio stations while driving through Stilwater. Songs can also be bought from the record store "Scratch That Music" to create a custom playlist.Classical Beethoven - Sym. No. 7 4th movtBeethoven – Egmont OvertureBeethoven – Für EliseBeethoven – Sonata No. 14 1st movtBeethoven – Sonata No. 14 3rd movtBeethoven – Sonata No. 23 1st movtBeethoven – Sym. No. 1 – FinaleBeethoven – Sym. No. 5 1st movtBeethoven – Sym. No. 6 1st movtBeethoven – Sym. No. 9 4th movtChopin – Ballade No. 1Chopin – Concerto No. 2 1st movtChopin – Concerto No. 2 3rd movtChopin – Etude No. 11Chopin – Etude No. 3Chopin – ImpromptuChopin – Prelude No. 15Chopin – Prelude No. 17Chopin – Prelude No. 3Chopin – Waltz No. 6Delibes – Lakme Flower DuetHandel – Halleluja from MessiahJ. Strauss – Die Fledermaus OvertureJ. Strauss – Leichtes Blut FastJ. Strauss – Tritsch TristschJ.S. Bach – Concerto No. 5J.S. Bach – Fantasy and FugueJ.S. Bach – Partita No 1. – GigueLiszt – FuneraillesLiszt – Hungarian Rhapsody No. 2Liszt – Liebestraum No. 2Mendelssohn – Violin Concerto 3rd movt Mozart – Concerto No. 21 2nd movtMozart – Eine Kleine Nachtmusik 2nd movtMozart – Turkish MarchMussorgksy – Bare MountainOffenbach – Gaiete Parisienne – Can CanPachelbel – Canon in DPaganini – 24 CapricesRossini – The Barber of SevilleRossini – The Thieving MagpieRossini – Wilhelm Tell OvertureS. Joplin – Maple Leaf RagS. Joplin – The EntertainerTschaikovksy – 1812 overtureTschaikovksy – The Reed FlutesTschaikovksy – The Sugar Plum FairyTschaikovksy – Violin Concerto 1st movtTschaikovksy – Violin Concerto 3rd movtVerdi – La TraviataVerdi – RigolettoVivaldi – Four Seasons No. 1Vivaldi – Four Seasons No. 2Vivaldi – Four Seasons No. 4Wagner – Lohengrin OvertureWagner – Ride of the ValkyriesWagner – Rienzi OvertureWagner – Tannhaesuer OvertureWagner – Twilight of the Gods Easy ListeningClemens Schweikhart  Matthias Wittwer – GroovemobDick Walter – Playground of the StarsDidier Heinrich  Jose Le Gall – Hello JackEric Casper  Janko Nilovic – Bossa New LookEric Casper  Janko Nilovic – Super Week-EndEric Casper  Janko Nilovic – Week-End PopFred Marius  Jurgen Jaenner – Adventure in SpeedGerhard Narholz – Bossa CubanaGerhard Narholz – Holiday RoadHendric Haydegg – Italian SummerJan Schneeberg – LoopingJoey Johnson – Alpenrose MemoriesJoey Johnson – Emily’s Happy HopJurgen Jaenner – Quicka NegraLarz Kurz  H.C. Mylla – Bratwurst PolkaLarz Kurz  H.C. Mylla – I und du BMarc Durst – Cocktail BossaMarc Durst - Holiday Bossa NovaMarc Durst – Nice SwingMarc Durst – Shopping GirlsMarc Durst – Tutti Flutti SwingNicolas Folmer – Running SwingOtto Sieben – Curley ShirleyOtto Sieben – Western PostPer Bluitgen Andreasen  Yannick Kalfayan – Peyi La DoucePeter Sander – Autumn SunPeter Sander – SweetnessRenato Bui  Martha Wild – Yodel of JoyRonald Sekura  Otto Sieben – Pepito From TampicoStephane Doukhan, Marc Durst  Edouard Miffre – Glamour Bossa NovaStephane Hugeunin, C. Padovan  Yves Sanna – Quando Sei Vicinio A TeUmberto Pagnini – Slapstick Duck TwistWerner Eraerds – O leichtman das Jodeln ElectronicaCaro – My Little PonyDieselboy and Kaos – Barrier BreakEvil Nine – We have the EnergyFreq Nasty - AmpedILS – Ill LogicILS – Tiny ToyILS – West CoastKoma and Bones – Questo Y SporcoKoma and Bones – Twisted StreetsPsychatronX – TwistedRythym Division – UziSkynet – Catherine WheelSkynet - StingrayStratus – You Must FollowStyles of Beyond - Subculture MetalBang Tango – Dancin on’ CoalsBang Tango – Love InjectionBang Tango – Someone Like YouGreat White – Once Bitten Twice ShyL.A. Guns – Ballad of Jayne Ratt – Back Fore MoreRatt – Round and RoundRatt – Way Cool Jr.Slaugher – Mad About YouSlaughter – Spend my LifeSlaughter – Up all NightWinger – Easy Come Easy GoWinger - Seventeen ReggaeAfrifcan Roots Act 1 – Addis Adaba DubBeat Pharmacy – Slow DownEek-A-Mouse – JamaicaneseHorace Andy – Live in the CityHorace Andy – Stop The FussJah Batta – InformaJah Woosh – Riding MelodyLove Joys – All I Can SayPrince Douglas – Tongue Shall Tell DubScotty –Draw your BrakesSugar Minott – International HerbTapper Zukie – Man Ah WarriorThe Pioneers – Time HardU-Roy – Way Down SouthWayne Jarett – You and I RockAberdeen City – God is Going to Get Sick Of MeAfghan Wings – Conjure MeAlec Empire – Kiss of DeathArt Brut – Bang Bang Rock And RollBad Brains – Banned in DCBear vs. Shark – 5,6 KidsCodeseven – Roped And TiedCruiserweight – To Be Quite HonestDanko Jones – Home to HellEditors - MunichFall Out Boy – Of All The Gin Joints…Hockey Night – For Guys’ Eyes OnlyHuge – Happiness EverydayHusker Du – Could You Be The OneIdelwild – Too Long AwakeIf I Were King - CauteriseIggy Pop – Wild AmericaJanes Addiction – Mountain SongJet By Day – Meet Me In The DarkKinski – Hiding Drugs In The TempleLocal H – Bound for the FloorMastodon – Blood And ThunderMen Woman and Children – Friday Night Fist NightMotion City Soundtrack – Everything is AllrightMy Awesome Compilation – Put Up A FightNew Years Day – Ready, Aim, MisfireOrange Park – Make up Your MindPaint It Black - PanicReggie  The Full Effect – Get Well SoonRock-N-Roll Soldiers – AnthemSeemless - Lay My Burden DownShelby – The Golden BoyStereophonics - GirlTempercalm – I Need A Co-PilotThe Adored – TV RiotThe Aquabats Look At Me, I’m a WinnerThe Fall of Troy – F.C.P.R.E.M.I.X.The Letters Organize – Don’t MoveThe Loved Ones – 100KThe Oranges Band – AtmosphereVendetta Red – Silhouette SerenadeYoung Offenders Institute – We’re the Young Offenders Hip-HopAirborn Audio – Inside the GlobeAisha – Bounce Like My ChecksAisha – Leave the HoBathgate – Everything’s A GoBisc One - CrumbsBlack Market Militia – Hood LullabyeBlack Market Militia feat. Dead Prez - Audobun BallroomBlack Milk - DangerBlack Sheep – Flavor of the MonthCamp Lo – GlowClipse - GrindinCopywrite – Beautiful TrainwreckDe La Soul – Rock Co. Kane FlowEric B. and Rakim – Paid In FullExile feat. Slum Village – Time has ComeGrafh – Get Shot BoyJin – GoldenKenn Starr – What UpLikwit Junkies – Keep Doin ItLittle Brother – Shake itM.E.D. - NightlifeMadvillian – Money FolderMasta Ace – Take a WalkMasta Ace feat. Jean Grae – Soda SoapMasta Killa – Digi WarfareMasta Killa feat. Ghostface and Raekwon – D.T.D.Masta Killa featuring ODB  RZA – Old ManMathematics – Spot Lite ft. Wu Tang ClanMathematics – Two Shots of HennyMathematics feat. Ghostface and Raekwon – Real NiggazMathematics feat. Method Man – John 3 16MC Lyte – Paper ThinMHE Ghostface feat. Trife – Milk ‘EmPlanet Asia feat. Prodigy – Stick and MoveRA the Rugged Man – Black and WhiteRich Medina – Holdin’ UpSa-Ra feat. Pharoahe Monch – Fish FilletThe Alchemist feat. Lloyd Banks – BangersThree 6 Mafia feat. Trillville  Lil Wyte – Who is I?Turf Talk – Do The RobotTwista – Overnight CelebrityVordul Mega - SpitamaticWordsworth – Gotta PlayExclusive/UnlockableXzhibit featuring Strong Army Steady - Hurry, HurryGhostface Killah And Trife Da God - Man UpRhymefest - Shut You DownDavid Banner - Saints RowDaz Dillinger - Git Out My WaySy Smith - Leave The HoSy Smith - DFM Like I'm Your WifeSy Smith - Bounce Like My Checks Xbox 360 Game InstallationSaints Row requires 6.8GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD.Playstation 3 Release CancelledA release for the Playstation 3 was scheduled but cancelled in May of 2007</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17036">Grand Theft Auto: Vice City</game><game id="10281">Bully</game><game id="4065">Crackdown</game><game id="9966">Scarface: The World is Yours</game><game id="18163">Just Cause</game><game id="3345">True Crime: New York City</game><game id="11153">True Crime: Streets of LA</game><game id="1470">The Getaway</game><game id="14491">Driv3r</game><game id="15879">Mafia</game><game id="5092">Bully: Scholarship Edition</game><game id="10781">The Godfather: Blackhand Edition</game><game id="7180">Yakuza</game><game id="22427">2 Days to Vegas</game><game id="20989">CrimeCraft</game><game id="21100">Grand Theft Auto: Chinatown Wars</game><game id="20853">Hei$t</game><game id="10593">Grand Theft Auto 2</game><game id="1375">Crime Life: Gang Wars</game><game id="22353">The Godfather: The Don's Edition</game><game id="23346">The Godfather II</game><game id="14785">The Getaway: Black Monday</game><game id="10264">Grand Theft Auto: Vice City Stories</game><game id="4241">Total Overdose</game><game id="21155">Postal III</game><game id="457">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Double Agent</game><game id="13567">Grand Theft Auto</game><game id="20638">This Is Vegas</game><game id="20599">inFamous</game><game id="26568">Revolution</game><game id="20742">Just Cause 2</game><game id="26790">Crackdown 2</game><game id="3157">The Simpsons: Hit &amp; Run</game><game id="20679">Saints Row 2</game><game id="16255">50 Cent: Bulletproof</game><game id="38237">Gangstar Rio: City of Saints</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1824060-box_sr1.png</image></root>