<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5625</id><name>RollerCoaster Tycoon 3</name><description>OverviewRide your Own RollerCoasters with CoasterCamRollerCoaster Tycoon 3 is the third game in the popular RollerCoaster Tycoon series. Like previous games the objective is to manage and maintain a theme park. This game is quite different visually than the other two games of the series. Instead of having 4 isometric viewing angles, RCT3 offers full 3D rotation of the camera. There is also an on-ride camera called " CoasterCam" which basically means you can experience the roller coasters and rides for yourself. This adds a lot to the fun of the game and is very enjoyable designing your own coasters and then trying them out.GameplayThe gameplay in RCT 3 has not fundamentally changed since the first game in the franchise. You are the owner of an amusement park, and you have to build rides and attractions that will bring "peeps" into your park from which you profit from. In RollerCoaster Tycoon you complete a series of preset scenarios by successfully building and maintaining theme parks. There is a huge variety of rides you can choose to build. There is a massive amount of different types of roller coasters to choose from as well as gentle rides and thrill rides. When building RollerCoasters you can choose from preset designs or customize your own design. There is a large number of preset designs available but some you will need to unlock by completing the games various career mode scenarios. You can completely customize the parks landscape by adding hills, valleys and also bodies of water. Players have the responsibility of managing the parks financials. You can advertise, take out loans and buy and sell land.Another new addition to the series is fireworks displays. Players can manage fully featured fireworks displays. You build the displays using a timeline editor where you choose a type of firework and apply it to a certain part of the automated fireworks display apparatus. Once you have created the display simply add music, preset or custom and then schedule the display to go on weekly for example. Fireworks displays are expensive and are best suited for larger parks. Themes and scenery of your park now play a larger role than before. For example, if a player creates a sci-fi themed area but places random pirate treasure chests around with all the sci-fi themed objects, peeps will get confused about it and the player will be notified.Game ModesThere are two main modes in the game.Career ModePlayers will have to unlock scenarios with mission objectives divided into three sets: Apprentice, Entrepreneur, and Tycoon. In order to complete the scenario, players must fulfill the goals of each level, unlocking the next set. The objectives usually consist of such things as keeping the park rating above a certain level for a certain length of time or having 2 rollercoasters with an excitement rating of at least 7.Sandbox ModePlayers are given unlimited cash and a large amount of land so they can build their dream park. This is where a lot of the players creativity will go in RCT3. Unlike Career Mode you are given all items already "researched". All different designs and types of roller coasters are available to you from the start. This means you can really have a variety of rides in your park in a very short period of time.Expansion PacksFrontier developed two retail expansion packs after the game's release. The expansion packs are called Soaked and Wild.Soaked! adds the ability to create water parks with rides, swimming pools and other pool objects such as hot tubs and lounge chairs. This expansion pack also included a feature that was in an update for RCT3 which gave players the ability to have underground pathways for tracks and rides. This ability was present in previous games too.Wild! gives you the ability to add animal enclosures and safari-like attractions, as well as animatronic prehistoric creatures. The expansion also allows you to place custom shops, which are shops and custom logos.Custom Scenery/Flat RidesThe Rollercoaster Tycoon 3 community now makes its own custom scenery and flat rides for the game.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1153">NoLimits Roller Coaster Simulation</game><game id="7434">Universal Studios Theme Park Adventure</game><game id="6562">Theme Park</game><game id="18956">Thrillville</game><game id="18407">Thrillville: Off the Rails</game><game id="4736">SimCity 4</game><game id="10999">Chris Sawyer's Locomotion</game><game id="19003">SimCoaster</game><game id="17736">Mall Tycoon 2</game><game id="17948">Mall Tycoon</game><game id="23208">Rollercoaster World</game><game id="23256">Roller Coaster Funfare</game><game id="9515">Transport Tycoon</game><game id="19819">Trailer Park Tycoon</game><game id="27413">Sim Theme Park</game><game id="24458">Tropico 3</game><game id="33312">Game Dev Story 2</game><game id="33263">Hyper Rails</game><game id="22462">Ultimate Ride: Disney Coaster</game><game id="32326">Tropico 4</game><game id="44473">Adventure Park</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4938/658805-2003191717543722808_rs.jpg</image></root>