<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5738</id><name>Wario World</name><description>OverviewIn Wario World, you play as Wario as he attempt to reclaim his riches from the grasp of the evil creature inside the Black Jewel. The gameplay consists of Wario defeating opponents and jumping around stages in order to reach the last area. The game also has a hub area where you start, from which you can enter one of the four themed areas. These themed areas consist of a few stages each and all end with an epic boss confrontation. The goal of the game is to finally beat all four of those bosses in order to finally come face to face with the Black Jewel, a seemingly cursed object which spawned monsters all around Wario's newly built castle. The game is very combat oriented, with small puzzle areas reachable by going through trap doors supplying most of the mental challenge. These areas are necessary in order to finish the level, as you need 4 gems which can only be obtained by successfully finishing the puzzles. The game also has a unique approach to death. When Wario runs out of health, you can simply pay a large sum of gold acquired through playing the game to revive yourself. The game received overall decent reviews, but it's primary criticism was it's lack of variety and short length. The game also has connectivity with the Gameboy Advance title " Wario Ware, Inc: Mega Microgames".Other InfoPlayer(s): 1Memory blocks needed: 10Gameboy Advance compatibleProgressive Scan compatible (480p)Dolby Surround Pro Logic II</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14117">Goemon's Great Adventure</game><game id="8112">Viewtiful Joe 2</game><game id="13158">Sonic Adventure DX: Director's Cut</game><game id="9523">Sonic Heroes</game><game id="11669">Tak: The Great Juju Challenge</game><game id="1605">I-Ninja</game><game id="17133">Tak and the Power of Juju</game><game id="9551">Disney's Donald Duck: Goin' Quackers</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4344/650832-wario_world.jpg</image></root>